<filme>
 <id>
  1
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0114709
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Toy Story
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A cowboy doll is profoundly threatened and jealous when a new spaceman figure supplants him as top toy in a boy's room.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A little boy named Andy loves to be in his room, playing with his toys, especially his doll named "Woody". But, what do the toys do when Andy is not with them, they come to life. Woody believes that he has life (as a toy) good. However, he must worry about Andy's family moving, and what Woody does not know is about Andy's birthday party. Woody does not realize that Andy's mother gave him an action figure known as Buzz Lightyear, who does not believe that he is a toy, and quickly becomes Andy's new favorite toy. Woody, who is now consumed with jealousy, tries to get rid of Buzz. Then, both Woody and Buzz are now lost. They must find a way to get back to Andy before he moves without them, but they will have to pass through a ruthless toy killer, Sid Phillips.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Animation
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   toy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   boy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   new toy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   baby
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   birthday party
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   John Lasseter
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   John Lasseter
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Pete Docter
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Tom Hanks
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Tim Allen
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Don Rickles
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rafiek-awad
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was great and very enjoyable, my whole family loved the scenes and the summary. Every moment was hilarious and lovable, while all scenes were playing you could feel the relationship between Woody and buzz growing and growing and at the end it reaches the height of a giant tree and as sweet as a majestic day. Most of the movie was about how friends should stick together and how bad it gets when the separate from each other and it takes several days, years etc till there relationship sticks back together. I really appreciate the efforts which Disney production put in to make a wonderful movie and here it is shown in every role and screen play. Special thanks to all the people who took part in making this happy film!!.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Captivating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kpayne032
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is at least 18 years old and still is able to capture young audiences from around the world. How did Pixar do it? How did they create a movie that has one of the greatest story lines to it? Who knows but I'm sure that Dreamworks will never be able to top it. Not once. By the way, if you have not already seen this movie my only question is "how?" Almost every living body has seen this movie it's alive and it's active yet you still have not seen it? Wow, you most indeed live one depressing life. Anyways, even if you have watched this movie you should already know that it's good but if you just wanted to see reviews fine by me, but don't come yelling at me if you don't agree with what I'm saying, it's pointless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nostalgic start to Pixar's best film franchise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I very fondly remember watching this film as a child and to this day it it still one of Pixar's finest efforts, especially if it's their first feature-length animation. As for the animation, it is pretty impressive for 1995 and the most realistically-modelled toys are Etch-A-Sketch and Mr Potato Head, although the main toys Woody and Buzz are well-designed as well. There are some funny moments such as Mr Potato Head pretending to be a Picasso painting and Sid's sister Hannah dressing Buzz up as a woman and naming him Mrs Nesbitt at a tea party as well as some dark, sinister moments such as Sid making mutant toys that eventually scare him off and the tense moment of Woody and Buzz's rivalry including the memorable, "You are a toy!" line. Other lines I remember from this film are Buzz's catchphrase "To infinity and beyond" and Woody's many phrases such as "You're my favourite deputy" and "There's a snake in my boots" to name just two. The opening scene involving Andy playing with Woody accompanied by Randy Newman's 'You've Got A Friend In Me' is one of the film's most captivating parts and I liked the product placement of toy manufacturers (Rex being made by Mattel and Mr Potato Head being made by Playskool). Overall, this is a dark and funny start to my favourite trilogy of animated films. 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reminds me of my childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    izzybeth7777
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched Toy story when I was little and it was my favorite childhood movie and I really love it because it made me think a lot and when I was little I used to tip toe up the steps and down the hall and peek into my room to see if my toys were moving but they never were but I just thought they were really good and I used to talk to them all the time about my life which you will most likely think I'm weird because I talked to my toys but I talked to my dog to and you want to know why well because I love to talked and everybody was annoyed so I just talked to my stuff. But this is off subject so basically to some this up I love this movie and you should watch it and you should spread it even know everybody has most likely already watched it so you should watch it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I never really thought this was the best movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Katie P
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Toy Story is a good movie. It has good characters and a decent story. But is it really worth the hype? Yes, it's the first fully computer animated movie ever made and that's very impressive. For that reason alone, it will stand out in history. But I certainly never really thought it was the brilliant classic everyone else thought it was. Its animation is great but the story suffers from major pacing issues. There are entire moments of the movie right in the middle that bore me every time and don't stop boring me until I get to the film's climax, when it picks up again. A lot of trimming should have been done in the middle. Toy Story is good but its sequels are a lot better. So is it bad? No. But it's not brilliant. If this were 2-D, I doubt it would receive this high praise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Toy Story" - One of animation's finest films for good reason
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a child, have you ever wondered at one point in your life what might happen in your room full of toys and dolls while you weren't in it? In Disney-Pixar's landmark 1995 computer animated feature Toy Story, we get that possible answer as the film is about toys that come to life while the owner is out of their room. In case you don't know why Toy Story is an important American film and why it's one of only two animated films to make the AFI's list of the 100 greatest films of all time, allow me to fill you in. It was the first full-length computer animated feature ever made and arguably the best in my opinion. Toy Story was so popular that it is solely responsible for Pixar's big streak of success with other computer animated features such as Up (2009), WALL-E (2008), and The Incredibles (2004). Enough said. In Toy Story, a group of toys that belong to a young kid named Andy come to life while he's out of the room. They're all led by Andy's favorite toy, a cowboy doll named Woody (Tom Hanks). They've just learned that Andy and his family will be moving away to another neighborhood. Not only that, but his birthday party is being celebrated earlier than expected, which means new toys will be joining them for sure, much to the horror of the other toys. They're afraid that the new toys will be so cool that Andy will no longer want to play with them anymore. Despite this, Woody assures the other toys that everything will be alright and no one will be forgotten. That is until he discovers Andy's newest toy Buzz Lightyear (Tim Allen), a space ranger action figure who thinks he's the real space ranger that he's based on. Woody basically becomes so jealous over how cool a toy he is that he tries to do whatever he can to become Andy's favorite toy again. When one of his attempts at getting noticed by Andy accidentally goes too far (meaning Buzz gets transported out of the house), Woody tries to rescue him and re-earn the trust of his fellow toys. But through a series of circumstances, Woody gets lost as well right alongside Buzz and they are accidentally found by Andy's next door neighbor, Sid. This is a problem for both of these toys since Sid really enjoys torturing and destroying toys. So now Woody and Buzz must get over their differences and work together to get out of Sid's house and back to Andy before he moves. Basically, what we have here story wise is your typical buddy comedy in animated form. But in my opinion, it's the buddy comedy done right. I'm not saying it just because it's told through a new form of animation, but because the film handles this type of story in the most imaginative and least contrived way. In other words, the basic plot seems to play out naturally and comes off as if Pixar was inventing this type of plot for the first time. There are no plot devices that are forced to the point where it's painfully obvious, everything on screen works within the fabric of the story. The comedic bits, along with being humorous, are very well handled and are necessary contributions to the plot. I loved how in one scene when Woody talks to the toys in Andy's room from Sid's house, the other toys think that Woody murdered Buzz by the end of the scene. That scene and similar scenes were very funny and well done. There's another crucial reason why the plot for this picture works as well as it does and that is the vocal cast itself. Tom Hanks and Tim Allen are irreplaceable as Woody and Buzz, respectively, since they bring so much to the chemistry and dialogue between each other to the point where it's impossible to top them. They do a perfect enough job with what they bring into each of their roles that you couldn't picture hearing any other actors play these two characters. The same can also be said for the supporting cast as well, particularly Don Rickles as Mr. Potato Head and Wallace Shawn as Rex. In other words, the actors do a convincing job at bringing each of their characters to life and putting so much personality into them that they help enhance the story further as good acting should be doing. The way Pixar handles its characters in this movie is also worth noting. For example, even though Sid is having fun destroying toys and is considered evil by the toys, they don't necessarily make him the main villain. In other words, the characters created here aren't exactly clear cut heroes and villains, but they're simply individuals with different personalities. Woody isn't a bad guy because he technically gets Buzz and himself into trouble, he's simply afraid of being forgotten by Andy. That aspect about Woody makes us relate to him even more since we do learn from the mistakes that Woody makes over this misunderstanding. Buzz Lightyear makes for an enjoyable fish-out-of-water type character in that he strongly believes he's the real Buzz Lightyear to the point that being told that he's actually a toy would be nonsense in his mind. In other words, Pixar cares a great deal about its story and characters here. As you can tell, Toy Story is simply much more than an innovative American film with its groundbreaking animation or even an entertaining family film. It's a film about characters that I'm sure most of us can relate to or identify with. It's a film for everybody to cherish for different reasons whether it be the animation, the humor, the story or the characters. I'll argue that it's still the finest film Pixar's produced yet. In a pinch, Toy Story is a film you should check out immediately if you haven't already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stonedouttamymind
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has something for everyone in the family. It is funny, has action, has a life story, and the characters will touch your heart. These are not just toys, this is a friendship, siblings, relationship or just a way of thinking sometimes. It is a real story on so many levels. It is a heart-warming story about a child and his toys and the relationships between the toys. In Toy Story, the two main characters are Buzz and Woody. At first Buzz and Woody can not stand each other and the two of them fight for the love of their owner Andy. Throughout the story these two show that fighting, arguing, and not getting along will get you no where in life and finally come together to help each other get back to their owner so that they can get back to their home. After all the trials and tribunals these two go through they become the best of friends and go on for two more movies to be a heroic team.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Andy is a young boy that has to give up his childhood toys. But the toys won't accept that they figure out a way to get back to Andy and stay with him.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nickiastar16
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was my favorite movie growing up. It shows what a kids toys would do if they had to be given up and could really talk. Andy is a sweet kid and he wants to keep his favorite toy but can't and I don't remember why. But all in all it is an amazing movie with a great story line. Andy would not give up his toys without a reason. They are in ways his best friends. He loves the toys as much as they love him but some how or another they get separated and the toys won't accept that. They do everything they can to get back to their best friend and don't give up till they get back to Andy. And is so happy when he gets his toys back and he tries his hardest not to lose them again. It is like losing your best friend because they move across the country.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Siddartha RO
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amazing! I have just seen Toy Story. The first one. For the first time. And it's like I'm seeing it back in the days before Toy Story 2 got out on the big screen. The only thing I wouldn't have known was the future story of Apple Inc. This is a wonderful one hour advertisement where you can see branded toys. The only thing that is original in this one hour waste is the way Steve Jobs' employees created a toy universe. It was so yesterday to create a new line of cheap plastics than do some silly adventure. It was called an adventure so people won't have any issue leaving the children alone for one or two hours of advertisements. It sounds so much more educative to have cartoon adventure instead of having cartoon characters selling you stuff. And, instead of a real actor, the cartoon has precisely zero morals: it can sell plutonium to a 5 year old or to some radical terrorist group without blinking. Unless the art director thinks the blink would raise the quantity at least 10 percent. Now about the creative part. Steve Jobs' employees never bothered to create something like say Hanna-Barbera. They just pushed older toys into this new advertisement. And here's where the creativity ends. What's even better is the world imagined. A world where children are isolated. Where they depend on their branded toys. And watch out for the bad kid! He is real creative. But the toys are working together to bring back what the lower case 'c' in a circle meant: a toy identical with million others on the shelves. Oh! And don't forget! A good kid would preserve all the junk: large useless wasteful boxes with advertisements for the whole line of plastic somethings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Toy Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - B This was a good movie as it has a fun story, good characters, and is entertaining for kids and some adults. The film shows us the life of toys at a little kids house and how they all do their own little things behind our backs. Then a new toy, the new spaceman comes and Woody, the leader of the crew, feels like he's being replaced. The conflict is this space ranger thinking he is a real one and not a toy and Woody trying to show him who he really is and trying to still be Andy's favorite. The film is cute with Woody and Buzz as great characters. The score is good, but not the whole story is impressive. I liked it when at home and not running around town as it seemed unreal. I thought the neighbor kid was stupid to have but the animation was incredible. A good family film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rafiek-awad
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was great and very enjoyable, my whole family loved the scenes and the summary. Every moment was hilarious and lovable, while all scenes were playing you could feel the relationship between Woody and buzz growing and growing and at the end it reaches the height of a giant tree and as sweet as a majestic day. Most of the movie was about how friends should stick together and how bad it gets when the separate from each other and it takes several days, years etc till there relationship sticks back together. I really appreciate the efforts which Disney production put in to make a wonderful movie and here it is shown in every role and screen play. Special thanks to all the people who took part in making this happy film!!.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Captivating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kpayne032
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is at least 18 years old and still is able to capture young audiences from around the world. How did Pixar do it? How did they create a movie that has one of the greatest story lines to it? Who knows but I'm sure that Dreamworks will never be able to top it. Not once. By the way, if you have not already seen this movie my only question is "how?" Almost every living body has seen this movie it's alive and it's active yet you still have not seen it? Wow, you most indeed live one depressing life. Anyways, even if you have watched this movie you should already know that it's good but if you just wanted to see reviews fine by me, but don't come yelling at me if you don't agree with what I'm saying, it's pointless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nostalgic start to Pixar's best film franchise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I very fondly remember watching this film as a child and to this day it it still one of Pixar's finest efforts, especially if it's their first feature-length animation. As for the animation, it is pretty impressive for 1995 and the most realistically-modelled toys are Etch-A-Sketch and Mr Potato Head, although the main toys Woody and Buzz are well-designed as well. There are some funny moments such as Mr Potato Head pretending to be a Picasso painting and Sid's sister Hannah dressing Buzz up as a woman and naming him Mrs Nesbitt at a tea party as well as some dark, sinister moments such as Sid making mutant toys that eventually scare him off and the tense moment of Woody and Buzz's rivalry including the memorable, "You are a toy!" line. Other lines I remember from this film are Buzz's catchphrase "To infinity and beyond" and Woody's many phrases such as "You're my favourite deputy" and "There's a snake in my boots" to name just two. The opening scene involving Andy playing with Woody accompanied by Randy Newman's 'You've Got A Friend In Me' is one of the film's most captivating parts and I liked the product placement of toy manufacturers (Rex being made by Mattel and Mr Potato Head being made by Playskool). Overall, this is a dark and funny start to my favourite trilogy of animated films. 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reminds me of my childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    izzybeth7777
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched Toy story when I was little and it was my favorite childhood movie and I really love it because it made me think a lot and when I was little I used to tip toe up the steps and down the hall and peek into my room to see if my toys were moving but they never were but I just thought they were really good and I used to talk to them all the time about my life which you will most likely think I'm weird because I talked to my toys but I talked to my dog to and you want to know why well because I love to talked and everybody was annoyed so I just talked to my stuff. But this is off subject so basically to some this up I love this movie and you should watch it and you should spread it even know everybody has most likely already watched it so you should watch it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I never really thought this was the best movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Katie P
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Toy Story is a good movie. It has good characters and a decent story. But is it really worth the hype? Yes, it's the first fully computer animated movie ever made and that's very impressive. For that reason alone, it will stand out in history. But I certainly never really thought it was the brilliant classic everyone else thought it was. Its animation is great but the story suffers from major pacing issues. There are entire moments of the movie right in the middle that bore me every time and don't stop boring me until I get to the film's climax, when it picks up again. A lot of trimming should have been done in the middle. Toy Story is good but its sequels are a lot better. So is it bad? No. But it's not brilliant. If this were 2-D, I doubt it would receive this high praise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Toy Story" - One of animation's finest films for good reason
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a child, have you ever wondered at one point in your life what might happen in your room full of toys and dolls while you weren't in it? In Disney-Pixar's landmark 1995 computer animated feature Toy Story, we get that possible answer as the film is about toys that come to life while the owner is out of their room. In case you don't know why Toy Story is an important American film and why it's one of only two animated films to make the AFI's list of the 100 greatest films of all time, allow me to fill you in. It was the first full-length computer animated feature ever made and arguably the best in my opinion. Toy Story was so popular that it is solely responsible for Pixar's big streak of success with other computer animated features such as Up (2009), WALL-E (2008), and The Incredibles (2004). Enough said. In Toy Story, a group of toys that belong to a young kid named Andy come to life while he's out of the room. They're all led by Andy's favorite toy, a cowboy doll named Woody (Tom Hanks). They've just learned that Andy and his family will be moving away to another neighborhood. Not only that, but his birthday party is being celebrated earlier than expected, which means new toys will be joining them for sure, much to the horror of the other toys. They're afraid that the new toys will be so cool that Andy will no longer want to play with them anymore. Despite this, Woody assures the other toys that everything will be alright and no one will be forgotten. That is until he discovers Andy's newest toy Buzz Lightyear (Tim Allen), a space ranger action figure who thinks he's the real space ranger that he's based on. Woody basically becomes so jealous over how cool a toy he is that he tries to do whatever he can to become Andy's favorite toy again. When one of his attempts at getting noticed by Andy accidentally goes too far (meaning Buzz gets transported out of the house), Woody tries to rescue him and re-earn the trust of his fellow toys. But through a series of circumstances, Woody gets lost as well right alongside Buzz and they are accidentally found by Andy's next door neighbor, Sid. This is a problem for both of these toys since Sid really enjoys torturing and destroying toys. So now Woody and Buzz must get over their differences and work together to get out of Sid's house and back to Andy before he moves. Basically, what we have here story wise is your typical buddy comedy in animated form. But in my opinion, it's the buddy comedy done right. I'm not saying it just because it's told through a new form of animation, but because the film handles this type of story in the most imaginative and least contrived way. In other words, the basic plot seems to play out naturally and comes off as if Pixar was inventing this type of plot for the first time. There are no plot devices that are forced to the point where it's painfully obvious, everything on screen works within the fabric of the story. The comedic bits, along with being humorous, are very well handled and are necessary contributions to the plot. I loved how in one scene when Woody talks to the toys in Andy's room from Sid's house, the other toys think that Woody murdered Buzz by the end of the scene. That scene and similar scenes were very funny and well done. There's another crucial reason why the plot for this picture works as well as it does and that is the vocal cast itself. Tom Hanks and Tim Allen are irreplaceable as Woody and Buzz, respectively, since they bring so much to the chemistry and dialogue between each other to the point where it's impossible to top them. They do a perfect enough job with what they bring into each of their roles that you couldn't picture hearing any other actors play these two characters. The same can also be said for the supporting cast as well, particularly Don Rickles as Mr. Potato Head and Wallace Shawn as Rex. In other words, the actors do a convincing job at bringing each of their characters to life and putting so much personality into them that they help enhance the story further as good acting should be doing. The way Pixar handles its characters in this movie is also worth noting. For example, even though Sid is having fun destroying toys and is considered evil by the toys, they don't necessarily make him the main villain. In other words, the characters created here aren't exactly clear cut heroes and villains, but they're simply individuals with different personalities. Woody isn't a bad guy because he technically gets Buzz and himself into trouble, he's simply afraid of being forgotten by Andy. That aspect about Woody makes us relate to him even more since we do learn from the mistakes that Woody makes over this misunderstanding. Buzz Lightyear makes for an enjoyable fish-out-of-water type character in that he strongly believes he's the real Buzz Lightyear to the point that being told that he's actually a toy would be nonsense in his mind. In other words, Pixar cares a great deal about its story and characters here. As you can tell, Toy Story is simply much more than an innovative American film with its groundbreaking animation or even an entertaining family film. It's a film about characters that I'm sure most of us can relate to or identify with. It's a film for everybody to cherish for different reasons whether it be the animation, the humor, the story or the characters. I'll argue that it's still the finest film Pixar's produced yet. In a pinch, Toy Story is a film you should check out immediately if you haven't already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stonedouttamymind
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has something for everyone in the family. It is funny, has action, has a life story, and the characters will touch your heart. These are not just toys, this is a friendship, siblings, relationship or just a way of thinking sometimes. It is a real story on so many levels. It is a heart-warming story about a child and his toys and the relationships between the toys. In Toy Story, the two main characters are Buzz and Woody. At first Buzz and Woody can not stand each other and the two of them fight for the love of their owner Andy. Throughout the story these two show that fighting, arguing, and not getting along will get you no where in life and finally come together to help each other get back to their owner so that they can get back to their home. After all the trials and tribunals these two go through they become the best of friends and go on for two more movies to be a heroic team.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Andy is a young boy that has to give up his childhood toys. But the toys won't accept that they figure out a way to get back to Andy and stay with him.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nickiastar16
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was my favorite movie growing up. It shows what a kids toys would do if they had to be given up and could really talk. Andy is a sweet kid and he wants to keep his favorite toy but can't and I don't remember why. But all in all it is an amazing movie with a great story line. Andy would not give up his toys without a reason. They are in ways his best friends. He loves the toys as much as they love him but some how or another they get separated and the toys won't accept that. They do everything they can to get back to their best friend and don't give up till they get back to Andy. And is so happy when he gets his toys back and he tries his hardest not to lose them again. It is like losing your best friend because they move across the country.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Siddartha RO
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amazing! I have just seen Toy Story. The first one. For the first time. And it's like I'm seeing it back in the days before Toy Story 2 got out on the big screen. The only thing I wouldn't have known was the future story of Apple Inc. This is a wonderful one hour advertisement where you can see branded toys. The only thing that is original in this one hour waste is the way Steve Jobs' employees created a toy universe. It was so yesterday to create a new line of cheap plastics than do some silly adventure. It was called an adventure so people won't have any issue leaving the children alone for one or two hours of advertisements. It sounds so much more educative to have cartoon adventure instead of having cartoon characters selling you stuff. And, instead of a real actor, the cartoon has precisely zero morals: it can sell plutonium to a 5 year old or to some radical terrorist group without blinking. Unless the art director thinks the blink would raise the quantity at least 10 percent. Now about the creative part. Steve Jobs' employees never bothered to create something like say Hanna-Barbera. They just pushed older toys into this new advertisement. And here's where the creativity ends. What's even better is the world imagined. A world where children are isolated. Where they depend on their branded toys. And watch out for the bad kid! He is real creative. But the toys are working together to bring back what the lower case 'c' in a circle meant: a toy identical with million others on the shelves. Oh! And don't forget! A good kid would preserve all the junk: large useless wasteful boxes with advertisements for the whole line of plastic somethings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Toy Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - B This was a good movie as it has a fun story, good characters, and is entertaining for kids and some adults. The film shows us the life of toys at a little kids house and how they all do their own little things behind our backs. Then a new toy, the new spaceman comes and Woody, the leader of the crew, feels like he's being replaced. The conflict is this space ranger thinking he is a real one and not a toy and Woody trying to show him who he really is and trying to still be Andy's favorite. The film is cute with Woody and Buzz as great characters. The score is good, but not the whole story is impressive. I liked it when at home and not running around town as it seemed unreal. I thought the neighbor kid was stupid to have but the animation was incredible. A good family film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rafiek-awad
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was great and very enjoyable, my whole family loved the scenes and the summary. Every moment was hilarious and lovable, while all scenes were playing you could feel the relationship between Woody and buzz growing and growing and at the end it reaches the height of a giant tree and as sweet as a majestic day. Most of the movie was about how friends should stick together and how bad it gets when the separate from each other and it takes several days, years etc till there relationship sticks back together. I really appreciate the efforts which Disney production put in to make a wonderful movie and here it is shown in every role and screen play. Special thanks to all the people who took part in making this happy film!!.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Captivating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kpayne032
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is at least 18 years old and still is able to capture young audiences from around the world. How did Pixar do it? How did they create a movie that has one of the greatest story lines to it? Who knows but I'm sure that Dreamworks will never be able to top it. Not once. By the way, if you have not already seen this movie my only question is "how?" Almost every living body has seen this movie it's alive and it's active yet you still have not seen it? Wow, you most indeed live one depressing life. Anyways, even if you have watched this movie you should already know that it's good but if you just wanted to see reviews fine by me, but don't come yelling at me if you don't agree with what I'm saying, it's pointless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nostalgic start to Pixar's best film franchise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I very fondly remember watching this film as a child and to this day it it still one of Pixar's finest efforts, especially if it's their first feature-length animation. As for the animation, it is pretty impressive for 1995 and the most realistically-modelled toys are Etch-A-Sketch and Mr Potato Head, although the main toys Woody and Buzz are well-designed as well. There are some funny moments such as Mr Potato Head pretending to be a Picasso painting and Sid's sister Hannah dressing Buzz up as a woman and naming him Mrs Nesbitt at a tea party as well as some dark, sinister moments such as Sid making mutant toys that eventually scare him off and the tense moment of Woody and Buzz's rivalry including the memorable, "You are a toy!" line. Other lines I remember from this film are Buzz's catchphrase "To infinity and beyond" and Woody's many phrases such as "You're my favourite deputy" and "There's a snake in my boots" to name just two. The opening scene involving Andy playing with Woody accompanied by Randy Newman's 'You've Got A Friend In Me' is one of the film's most captivating parts and I liked the product placement of toy manufacturers (Rex being made by Mattel and Mr Potato Head being made by Playskool). Overall, this is a dark and funny start to my favourite trilogy of animated films. 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reminds me of my childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    izzybeth7777
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched Toy story when I was little and it was my favorite childhood movie and I really love it because it made me think a lot and when I was little I used to tip toe up the steps and down the hall and peek into my room to see if my toys were moving but they never were but I just thought they were really good and I used to talk to them all the time about my life which you will most likely think I'm weird because I talked to my toys but I talked to my dog to and you want to know why well because I love to talked and everybody was annoyed so I just talked to my stuff. But this is off subject so basically to some this up I love this movie and you should watch it and you should spread it even know everybody has most likely already watched it so you should watch it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I never really thought this was the best movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Katie P
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Toy Story is a good movie. It has good characters and a decent story. But is it really worth the hype? Yes, it's the first fully computer animated movie ever made and that's very impressive. For that reason alone, it will stand out in history. But I certainly never really thought it was the brilliant classic everyone else thought it was. Its animation is great but the story suffers from major pacing issues. There are entire moments of the movie right in the middle that bore me every time and don't stop boring me until I get to the film's climax, when it picks up again. A lot of trimming should have been done in the middle. Toy Story is good but its sequels are a lot better. So is it bad? No. But it's not brilliant. If this were 2-D, I doubt it would receive this high praise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Toy Story" - One of animation's finest films for good reason
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a child, have you ever wondered at one point in your life what might happen in your room full of toys and dolls while you weren't in it? In Disney-Pixar's landmark 1995 computer animated feature Toy Story, we get that possible answer as the film is about toys that come to life while the owner is out of their room. In case you don't know why Toy Story is an important American film and why it's one of only two animated films to make the AFI's list of the 100 greatest films of all time, allow me to fill you in. It was the first full-length computer animated feature ever made and arguably the best in my opinion. Toy Story was so popular that it is solely responsible for Pixar's big streak of success with other computer animated features such as Up (2009), WALL-E (2008), and The Incredibles (2004). Enough said. In Toy Story, a group of toys that belong to a young kid named Andy come to life while he's out of the room. They're all led by Andy's favorite toy, a cowboy doll named Woody (Tom Hanks). They've just learned that Andy and his family will be moving away to another neighborhood. Not only that, but his birthday party is being celebrated earlier than expected, which means new toys will be joining them for sure, much to the horror of the other toys. They're afraid that the new toys will be so cool that Andy will no longer want to play with them anymore. Despite this, Woody assures the other toys that everything will be alright and no one will be forgotten. That is until he discovers Andy's newest toy Buzz Lightyear (Tim Allen), a space ranger action figure who thinks he's the real space ranger that he's based on. Woody basically becomes so jealous over how cool a toy he is that he tries to do whatever he can to become Andy's favorite toy again. When one of his attempts at getting noticed by Andy accidentally goes too far (meaning Buzz gets transported out of the house), Woody tries to rescue him and re-earn the trust of his fellow toys. But through a series of circumstances, Woody gets lost as well right alongside Buzz and they are accidentally found by Andy's next door neighbor, Sid. This is a problem for both of these toys since Sid really enjoys torturing and destroying toys. So now Woody and Buzz must get over their differences and work together to get out of Sid's house and back to Andy before he moves. Basically, what we have here story wise is your typical buddy comedy in animated form. But in my opinion, it's the buddy comedy done right. I'm not saying it just because it's told through a new form of animation, but because the film handles this type of story in the most imaginative and least contrived way. In other words, the basic plot seems to play out naturally and comes off as if Pixar was inventing this type of plot for the first time. There are no plot devices that are forced to the point where it's painfully obvious, everything on screen works within the fabric of the story. The comedic bits, along with being humorous, are very well handled and are necessary contributions to the plot. I loved how in one scene when Woody talks to the toys in Andy's room from Sid's house, the other toys think that Woody murdered Buzz by the end of the scene. That scene and similar scenes were very funny and well done. There's another crucial reason why the plot for this picture works as well as it does and that is the vocal cast itself. Tom Hanks and Tim Allen are irreplaceable as Woody and Buzz, respectively, since they bring so much to the chemistry and dialogue between each other to the point where it's impossible to top them. They do a perfect enough job with what they bring into each of their roles that you couldn't picture hearing any other actors play these two characters. The same can also be said for the supporting cast as well, particularly Don Rickles as Mr. Potato Head and Wallace Shawn as Rex. In other words, the actors do a convincing job at bringing each of their characters to life and putting so much personality into them that they help enhance the story further as good acting should be doing. The way Pixar handles its characters in this movie is also worth noting. For example, even though Sid is having fun destroying toys and is considered evil by the toys, they don't necessarily make him the main villain. In other words, the characters created here aren't exactly clear cut heroes and villains, but they're simply individuals with different personalities. Woody isn't a bad guy because he technically gets Buzz and himself into trouble, he's simply afraid of being forgotten by Andy. That aspect about Woody makes us relate to him even more since we do learn from the mistakes that Woody makes over this misunderstanding. Buzz Lightyear makes for an enjoyable fish-out-of-water type character in that he strongly believes he's the real Buzz Lightyear to the point that being told that he's actually a toy would be nonsense in his mind. In other words, Pixar cares a great deal about its story and characters here. As you can tell, Toy Story is simply much more than an innovative American film with its groundbreaking animation or even an entertaining family film. It's a film about characters that I'm sure most of us can relate to or identify with. It's a film for everybody to cherish for different reasons whether it be the animation, the humor, the story or the characters. I'll argue that it's still the finest film Pixar's produced yet. In a pinch, Toy Story is a film you should check out immediately if you haven't already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stonedouttamymind
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has something for everyone in the family. It is funny, has action, has a life story, and the characters will touch your heart. These are not just toys, this is a friendship, siblings, relationship or just a way of thinking sometimes. It is a real story on so many levels. It is a heart-warming story about a child and his toys and the relationships between the toys. In Toy Story, the two main characters are Buzz and Woody. At first Buzz and Woody can not stand each other and the two of them fight for the love of their owner Andy. Throughout the story these two show that fighting, arguing, and not getting along will get you no where in life and finally come together to help each other get back to their owner so that they can get back to their home. After all the trials and tribunals these two go through they become the best of friends and go on for two more movies to be a heroic team.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Andy is a young boy that has to give up his childhood toys. But the toys won't accept that they figure out a way to get back to Andy and stay with him.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nickiastar16
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was my favorite movie growing up. It shows what a kids toys would do if they had to be given up and could really talk. Andy is a sweet kid and he wants to keep his favorite toy but can't and I don't remember why. But all in all it is an amazing movie with a great story line. Andy would not give up his toys without a reason. They are in ways his best friends. He loves the toys as much as they love him but some how or another they get separated and the toys won't accept that. They do everything they can to get back to their best friend and don't give up till they get back to Andy. And is so happy when he gets his toys back and he tries his hardest not to lose them again. It is like losing your best friend because they move across the country.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Siddartha RO
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amazing! I have just seen Toy Story. The first one. For the first time. And it's like I'm seeing it back in the days before Toy Story 2 got out on the big screen. The only thing I wouldn't have known was the future story of Apple Inc. This is a wonderful one hour advertisement where you can see branded toys. The only thing that is original in this one hour waste is the way Steve Jobs' employees created a toy universe. It was so yesterday to create a new line of cheap plastics than do some silly adventure. It was called an adventure so people won't have any issue leaving the children alone for one or two hours of advertisements. It sounds so much more educative to have cartoon adventure instead of having cartoon characters selling you stuff. And, instead of a real actor, the cartoon has precisely zero morals: it can sell plutonium to a 5 year old or to some radical terrorist group without blinking. Unless the art director thinks the blink would raise the quantity at least 10 percent. Now about the creative part. Steve Jobs' employees never bothered to create something like say Hanna-Barbera. They just pushed older toys into this new advertisement. And here's where the creativity ends. What's even better is the world imagined. A world where children are isolated. Where they depend on their branded toys. And watch out for the bad kid! He is real creative. But the toys are working together to bring back what the lower case 'c' in a circle meant: a toy identical with million others on the shelves. Oh! And don't forget! A good kid would preserve all the junk: large useless wasteful boxes with advertisements for the whole line of plastic somethings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Toy Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - B This was a good movie as it has a fun story, good characters, and is entertaining for kids and some adults. The film shows us the life of toys at a little kids house and how they all do their own little things behind our backs. Then a new toy, the new spaceman comes and Woody, the leader of the crew, feels like he's being replaced. The conflict is this space ranger thinking he is a real one and not a toy and Woody trying to show him who he really is and trying to still be Andy's favorite. The film is cute with Woody and Buzz as great characters. The score is good, but not the whole story is impressive. I liked it when at home and not running around town as it seemed unreal. I thought the neighbor kid was stupid to have but the animation was incredible. A good family film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rafiek-awad
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was great and very enjoyable, my whole family loved the scenes and the summary. Every moment was hilarious and lovable, while all scenes were playing you could feel the relationship between Woody and buzz growing and growing and at the end it reaches the height of a giant tree and as sweet as a majestic day. Most of the movie was about how friends should stick together and how bad it gets when the separate from each other and it takes several days, years etc till there relationship sticks back together. I really appreciate the efforts which Disney production put in to make a wonderful movie and here it is shown in every role and screen play. Special thanks to all the people who took part in making this happy film!!.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Captivating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kpayne032
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is at least 18 years old and still is able to capture young audiences from around the world. How did Pixar do it? How did they create a movie that has one of the greatest story lines to it? Who knows but I'm sure that Dreamworks will never be able to top it. Not once. By the way, if you have not already seen this movie my only question is "how?" Almost every living body has seen this movie it's alive and it's active yet you still have not seen it? Wow, you most indeed live one depressing life. Anyways, even if you have watched this movie you should already know that it's good but if you just wanted to see reviews fine by me, but don't come yelling at me if you don't agree with what I'm saying, it's pointless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nostalgic start to Pixar's best film franchise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I very fondly remember watching this film as a child and to this day it it still one of Pixar's finest efforts, especially if it's their first feature-length animation. As for the animation, it is pretty impressive for 1995 and the most realistically-modelled toys are Etch-A-Sketch and Mr Potato Head, although the main toys Woody and Buzz are well-designed as well. There are some funny moments such as Mr Potato Head pretending to be a Picasso painting and Sid's sister Hannah dressing Buzz up as a woman and naming him Mrs Nesbitt at a tea party as well as some dark, sinister moments such as Sid making mutant toys that eventually scare him off and the tense moment of Woody and Buzz's rivalry including the memorable, "You are a toy!" line. Other lines I remember from this film are Buzz's catchphrase "To infinity and beyond" and Woody's many phrases such as "You're my favourite deputy" and "There's a snake in my boots" to name just two. The opening scene involving Andy playing with Woody accompanied by Randy Newman's 'You've Got A Friend In Me' is one of the film's most captivating parts and I liked the product placement of toy manufacturers (Rex being made by Mattel and Mr Potato Head being made by Playskool). Overall, this is a dark and funny start to my favourite trilogy of animated films. 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reminds me of my childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    izzybeth7777
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched Toy story when I was little and it was my favorite childhood movie and I really love it because it made me think a lot and when I was little I used to tip toe up the steps and down the hall and peek into my room to see if my toys were moving but they never were but I just thought they were really good and I used to talk to them all the time about my life which you will most likely think I'm weird because I talked to my toys but I talked to my dog to and you want to know why well because I love to talked and everybody was annoyed so I just talked to my stuff. But this is off subject so basically to some this up I love this movie and you should watch it and you should spread it even know everybody has most likely already watched it so you should watch it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I never really thought this was the best movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Katie P
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Toy Story is a good movie. It has good characters and a decent story. But is it really worth the hype? Yes, it's the first fully computer animated movie ever made and that's very impressive. For that reason alone, it will stand out in history. But I certainly never really thought it was the brilliant classic everyone else thought it was. Its animation is great but the story suffers from major pacing issues. There are entire moments of the movie right in the middle that bore me every time and don't stop boring me until I get to the film's climax, when it picks up again. A lot of trimming should have been done in the middle. Toy Story is good but its sequels are a lot better. So is it bad? No. But it's not brilliant. If this were 2-D, I doubt it would receive this high praise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Toy Story" - One of animation's finest films for good reason
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a child, have you ever wondered at one point in your life what might happen in your room full of toys and dolls while you weren't in it? In Disney-Pixar's landmark 1995 computer animated feature Toy Story, we get that possible answer as the film is about toys that come to life while the owner is out of their room. In case you don't know why Toy Story is an important American film and why it's one of only two animated films to make the AFI's list of the 100 greatest films of all time, allow me to fill you in. It was the first full-length computer animated feature ever made and arguably the best in my opinion. Toy Story was so popular that it is solely responsible for Pixar's big streak of success with other computer animated features such as Up (2009), WALL-E (2008), and The Incredibles (2004). Enough said. In Toy Story, a group of toys that belong to a young kid named Andy come to life while he's out of the room. They're all led by Andy's favorite toy, a cowboy doll named Woody (Tom Hanks). They've just learned that Andy and his family will be moving away to another neighborhood. Not only that, but his birthday party is being celebrated earlier than expected, which means new toys will be joining them for sure, much to the horror of the other toys. They're afraid that the new toys will be so cool that Andy will no longer want to play with them anymore. Despite this, Woody assures the other toys that everything will be alright and no one will be forgotten. That is until he discovers Andy's newest toy Buzz Lightyear (Tim Allen), a space ranger action figure who thinks he's the real space ranger that he's based on. Woody basically becomes so jealous over how cool a toy he is that he tries to do whatever he can to become Andy's favorite toy again. When one of his attempts at getting noticed by Andy accidentally goes too far (meaning Buzz gets transported out of the house), Woody tries to rescue him and re-earn the trust of his fellow toys. But through a series of circumstances, Woody gets lost as well right alongside Buzz and they are accidentally found by Andy's next door neighbor, Sid. This is a problem for both of these toys since Sid really enjoys torturing and destroying toys. So now Woody and Buzz must get over their differences and work together to get out of Sid's house and back to Andy before he moves. Basically, what we have here story wise is your typical buddy comedy in animated form. But in my opinion, it's the buddy comedy done right. I'm not saying it just because it's told through a new form of animation, but because the film handles this type of story in the most imaginative and least contrived way. In other words, the basic plot seems to play out naturally and comes off as if Pixar was inventing this type of plot for the first time. There are no plot devices that are forced to the point where it's painfully obvious, everything on screen works within the fabric of the story. The comedic bits, along with being humorous, are very well handled and are necessary contributions to the plot. I loved how in one scene when Woody talks to the toys in Andy's room from Sid's house, the other toys think that Woody murdered Buzz by the end of the scene. That scene and similar scenes were very funny and well done. There's another crucial reason why the plot for this picture works as well as it does and that is the vocal cast itself. Tom Hanks and Tim Allen are irreplaceable as Woody and Buzz, respectively, since they bring so much to the chemistry and dialogue between each other to the point where it's impossible to top them. They do a perfect enough job with what they bring into each of their roles that you couldn't picture hearing any other actors play these two characters. The same can also be said for the supporting cast as well, particularly Don Rickles as Mr. Potato Head and Wallace Shawn as Rex. In other words, the actors do a convincing job at bringing each of their characters to life and putting so much personality into them that they help enhance the story further as good acting should be doing. The way Pixar handles its characters in this movie is also worth noting. For example, even though Sid is having fun destroying toys and is considered evil by the toys, they don't necessarily make him the main villain. In other words, the characters created here aren't exactly clear cut heroes and villains, but they're simply individuals with different personalities. Woody isn't a bad guy because he technically gets Buzz and himself into trouble, he's simply afraid of being forgotten by Andy. That aspect about Woody makes us relate to him even more since we do learn from the mistakes that Woody makes over this misunderstanding. Buzz Lightyear makes for an enjoyable fish-out-of-water type character in that he strongly believes he's the real Buzz Lightyear to the point that being told that he's actually a toy would be nonsense in his mind. In other words, Pixar cares a great deal about its story and characters here. As you can tell, Toy Story is simply much more than an innovative American film with its groundbreaking animation or even an entertaining family film. It's a film about characters that I'm sure most of us can relate to or identify with. It's a film for everybody to cherish for different reasons whether it be the animation, the humor, the story or the characters. I'll argue that it's still the finest film Pixar's produced yet. In a pinch, Toy Story is a film you should check out immediately if you haven't already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stonedouttamymind
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has something for everyone in the family. It is funny, has action, has a life story, and the characters will touch your heart. These are not just toys, this is a friendship, siblings, relationship or just a way of thinking sometimes. It is a real story on so many levels. It is a heart-warming story about a child and his toys and the relationships between the toys. In Toy Story, the two main characters are Buzz and Woody. At first Buzz and Woody can not stand each other and the two of them fight for the love of their owner Andy. Throughout the story these two show that fighting, arguing, and not getting along will get you no where in life and finally come together to help each other get back to their owner so that they can get back to their home. After all the trials and tribunals these two go through they become the best of friends and go on for two more movies to be a heroic team.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Andy is a young boy that has to give up his childhood toys. But the toys won't accept that they figure out a way to get back to Andy and stay with him.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nickiastar16
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was my favorite movie growing up. It shows what a kids toys would do if they had to be given up and could really talk. Andy is a sweet kid and he wants to keep his favorite toy but can't and I don't remember why. But all in all it is an amazing movie with a great story line. Andy would not give up his toys without a reason. They are in ways his best friends. He loves the toys as much as they love him but some how or another they get separated and the toys won't accept that. They do everything they can to get back to their best friend and don't give up till they get back to Andy. And is so happy when he gets his toys back and he tries his hardest not to lose them again. It is like losing your best friend because they move across the country.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Siddartha RO
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amazing! I have just seen Toy Story. The first one. For the first time. And it's like I'm seeing it back in the days before Toy Story 2 got out on the big screen. The only thing I wouldn't have known was the future story of Apple Inc. This is a wonderful one hour advertisement where you can see branded toys. The only thing that is original in this one hour waste is the way Steve Jobs' employees created a toy universe. It was so yesterday to create a new line of cheap plastics than do some silly adventure. It was called an adventure so people won't have any issue leaving the children alone for one or two hours of advertisements. It sounds so much more educative to have cartoon adventure instead of having cartoon characters selling you stuff. And, instead of a real actor, the cartoon has precisely zero morals: it can sell plutonium to a 5 year old or to some radical terrorist group without blinking. Unless the art director thinks the blink would raise the quantity at least 10 percent. Now about the creative part. Steve Jobs' employees never bothered to create something like say Hanna-Barbera. They just pushed older toys into this new advertisement. And here's where the creativity ends. What's even better is the world imagined. A world where children are isolated. Where they depend on their branded toys. And watch out for the bad kid! He is real creative. But the toys are working together to bring back what the lower case 'c' in a circle meant: a toy identical with million others on the shelves. Oh! And don't forget! A good kid would preserve all the junk: large useless wasteful boxes with advertisements for the whole line of plastic somethings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Toy Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - B This was a good movie as it has a fun story, good characters, and is entertaining for kids and some adults. The film shows us the life of toys at a little kids house and how they all do their own little things behind our backs. Then a new toy, the new spaceman comes and Woody, the leader of the crew, feels like he's being replaced. The conflict is this space ranger thinking he is a real one and not a toy and Woody trying to show him who he really is and trying to still be Andy's favorite. The film is cute with Woody and Buzz as great characters. The score is good, but not the whole story is impressive. I liked it when at home and not running around town as it seemed unreal. I thought the neighbor kid was stupid to have but the animation was incredible. A good family film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rafiek-awad
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was great and very enjoyable, my whole family loved the scenes and the summary. Every moment was hilarious and lovable, while all scenes were playing you could feel the relationship between Woody and buzz growing and growing and at the end it reaches the height of a giant tree and as sweet as a majestic day. Most of the movie was about how friends should stick together and how bad it gets when the separate from each other and it takes several days, years etc till there relationship sticks back together. I really appreciate the efforts which Disney production put in to make a wonderful movie and here it is shown in every role and screen play. Special thanks to all the people who took part in making this happy film!!.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Captivating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kpayne032
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is at least 18 years old and still is able to capture young audiences from around the world. How did Pixar do it? How did they create a movie that has one of the greatest story lines to it? Who knows but I'm sure that Dreamworks will never be able to top it. Not once. By the way, if you have not already seen this movie my only question is "how?" Almost every living body has seen this movie it's alive and it's active yet you still have not seen it? Wow, you most indeed live one depressing life. Anyways, even if you have watched this movie you should already know that it's good but if you just wanted to see reviews fine by me, but don't come yelling at me if you don't agree with what I'm saying, it's pointless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nostalgic start to Pixar's best film franchise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I very fondly remember watching this film as a child and to this day it it still one of Pixar's finest efforts, especially if it's their first feature-length animation. As for the animation, it is pretty impressive for 1995 and the most realistically-modelled toys are Etch-A-Sketch and Mr Potato Head, although the main toys Woody and Buzz are well-designed as well. There are some funny moments such as Mr Potato Head pretending to be a Picasso painting and Sid's sister Hannah dressing Buzz up as a woman and naming him Mrs Nesbitt at a tea party as well as some dark, sinister moments such as Sid making mutant toys that eventually scare him off and the tense moment of Woody and Buzz's rivalry including the memorable, "You are a toy!" line. Other lines I remember from this film are Buzz's catchphrase "To infinity and beyond" and Woody's many phrases such as "You're my favourite deputy" and "There's a snake in my boots" to name just two. The opening scene involving Andy playing with Woody accompanied by Randy Newman's 'You've Got A Friend In Me' is one of the film's most captivating parts and I liked the product placement of toy manufacturers (Rex being made by Mattel and Mr Potato Head being made by Playskool). Overall, this is a dark and funny start to my favourite trilogy of animated films. 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reminds me of my childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    izzybeth7777
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched Toy story when I was little and it was my favorite childhood movie and I really love it because it made me think a lot and when I was little I used to tip toe up the steps and down the hall and peek into my room to see if my toys were moving but they never were but I just thought they were really good and I used to talk to them all the time about my life which you will most likely think I'm weird because I talked to my toys but I talked to my dog to and you want to know why well because I love to talked and everybody was annoyed so I just talked to my stuff. But this is off subject so basically to some this up I love this movie and you should watch it and you should spread it even know everybody has most likely already watched it so you should watch it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I never really thought this was the best movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Katie P
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Toy Story is a good movie. It has good characters and a decent story. But is it really worth the hype? Yes, it's the first fully computer animated movie ever made and that's very impressive. For that reason alone, it will stand out in history. But I certainly never really thought it was the brilliant classic everyone else thought it was. Its animation is great but the story suffers from major pacing issues. There are entire moments of the movie right in the middle that bore me every time and don't stop boring me until I get to the film's climax, when it picks up again. A lot of trimming should have been done in the middle. Toy Story is good but its sequels are a lot better. So is it bad? No. But it's not brilliant. If this were 2-D, I doubt it would receive this high praise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Toy Story" - One of animation's finest films for good reason
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a child, have you ever wondered at one point in your life what might happen in your room full of toys and dolls while you weren't in it? In Disney-Pixar's landmark 1995 computer animated feature Toy Story, we get that possible answer as the film is about toys that come to life while the owner is out of their room. In case you don't know why Toy Story is an important American film and why it's one of only two animated films to make the AFI's list of the 100 greatest films of all time, allow me to fill you in. It was the first full-length computer animated feature ever made and arguably the best in my opinion. Toy Story was so popular that it is solely responsible for Pixar's big streak of success with other computer animated features such as Up (2009), WALL-E (2008), and The Incredibles (2004). Enough said. In Toy Story, a group of toys that belong to a young kid named Andy come to life while he's out of the room. They're all led by Andy's favorite toy, a cowboy doll named Woody (Tom Hanks). They've just learned that Andy and his family will be moving away to another neighborhood. Not only that, but his birthday party is being celebrated earlier than expected, which means new toys will be joining them for sure, much to the horror of the other toys. They're afraid that the new toys will be so cool that Andy will no longer want to play with them anymore. Despite this, Woody assures the other toys that everything will be alright and no one will be forgotten. That is until he discovers Andy's newest toy Buzz Lightyear (Tim Allen), a space ranger action figure who thinks he's the real space ranger that he's based on. Woody basically becomes so jealous over how cool a toy he is that he tries to do whatever he can to become Andy's favorite toy again. When one of his attempts at getting noticed by Andy accidentally goes too far (meaning Buzz gets transported out of the house), Woody tries to rescue him and re-earn the trust of his fellow toys. But through a series of circumstances, Woody gets lost as well right alongside Buzz and they are accidentally found by Andy's next door neighbor, Sid. This is a problem for both of these toys since Sid really enjoys torturing and destroying toys. So now Woody and Buzz must get over their differences and work together to get out of Sid's house and back to Andy before he moves. Basically, what we have here story wise is your typical buddy comedy in animated form. But in my opinion, it's the buddy comedy done right. I'm not saying it just because it's told through a new form of animation, but because the film handles this type of story in the most imaginative and least contrived way. In other words, the basic plot seems to play out naturally and comes off as if Pixar was inventing this type of plot for the first time. There are no plot devices that are forced to the point where it's painfully obvious, everything on screen works within the fabric of the story. The comedic bits, along with being humorous, are very well handled and are necessary contributions to the plot. I loved how in one scene when Woody talks to the toys in Andy's room from Sid's house, the other toys think that Woody murdered Buzz by the end of the scene. That scene and similar scenes were very funny and well done. There's another crucial reason why the plot for this picture works as well as it does and that is the vocal cast itself. Tom Hanks and Tim Allen are irreplaceable as Woody and Buzz, respectively, since they bring so much to the chemistry and dialogue between each other to the point where it's impossible to top them. They do a perfect enough job with what they bring into each of their roles that you couldn't picture hearing any other actors play these two characters. The same can also be said for the supporting cast as well, particularly Don Rickles as Mr. Potato Head and Wallace Shawn as Rex. In other words, the actors do a convincing job at bringing each of their characters to life and putting so much personality into them that they help enhance the story further as good acting should be doing. The way Pixar handles its characters in this movie is also worth noting. For example, even though Sid is having fun destroying toys and is considered evil by the toys, they don't necessarily make him the main villain. In other words, the characters created here aren't exactly clear cut heroes and villains, but they're simply individuals with different personalities. Woody isn't a bad guy because he technically gets Buzz and himself into trouble, he's simply afraid of being forgotten by Andy. That aspect about Woody makes us relate to him even more since we do learn from the mistakes that Woody makes over this misunderstanding. Buzz Lightyear makes for an enjoyable fish-out-of-water type character in that he strongly believes he's the real Buzz Lightyear to the point that being told that he's actually a toy would be nonsense in his mind. In other words, Pixar cares a great deal about its story and characters here. As you can tell, Toy Story is simply much more than an innovative American film with its groundbreaking animation or even an entertaining family film. It's a film about characters that I'm sure most of us can relate to or identify with. It's a film for everybody to cherish for different reasons whether it be the animation, the humor, the story or the characters. I'll argue that it's still the finest film Pixar's produced yet. In a pinch, Toy Story is a film you should check out immediately if you haven't already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stonedouttamymind
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has something for everyone in the family. It is funny, has action, has a life story, and the characters will touch your heart. These are not just toys, this is a friendship, siblings, relationship or just a way of thinking sometimes. It is a real story on so many levels. It is a heart-warming story about a child and his toys and the relationships between the toys. In Toy Story, the two main characters are Buzz and Woody. At first Buzz and Woody can not stand each other and the two of them fight for the love of their owner Andy. Throughout the story these two show that fighting, arguing, and not getting along will get you no where in life and finally come together to help each other get back to their owner so that they can get back to their home. After all the trials and tribunals these two go through they become the best of friends and go on for two more movies to be a heroic team.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Andy is a young boy that has to give up his childhood toys. But the toys won't accept that they figure out a way to get back to Andy and stay with him.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nickiastar16
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was my favorite movie growing up. It shows what a kids toys would do if they had to be given up and could really talk. Andy is a sweet kid and he wants to keep his favorite toy but can't and I don't remember why. But all in all it is an amazing movie with a great story line. Andy would not give up his toys without a reason. They are in ways his best friends. He loves the toys as much as they love him but some how or another they get separated and the toys won't accept that. They do everything they can to get back to their best friend and don't give up till they get back to Andy. And is so happy when he gets his toys back and he tries his hardest not to lose them again. It is like losing your best friend because they move across the country.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Siddartha RO
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amazing! I have just seen Toy Story. The first one. For the first time. And it's like I'm seeing it back in the days before Toy Story 2 got out on the big screen. The only thing I wouldn't have known was the future story of Apple Inc. This is a wonderful one hour advertisement where you can see branded toys. The only thing that is original in this one hour waste is the way Steve Jobs' employees created a toy universe. It was so yesterday to create a new line of cheap plastics than do some silly adventure. It was called an adventure so people won't have any issue leaving the children alone for one or two hours of advertisements. It sounds so much more educative to have cartoon adventure instead of having cartoon characters selling you stuff. And, instead of a real actor, the cartoon has precisely zero morals: it can sell plutonium to a 5 year old or to some radical terrorist group without blinking. Unless the art director thinks the blink would raise the quantity at least 10 percent. Now about the creative part. Steve Jobs' employees never bothered to create something like say Hanna-Barbera. They just pushed older toys into this new advertisement. And here's where the creativity ends. What's even better is the world imagined. A world where children are isolated. Where they depend on their branded toys. And watch out for the bad kid! He is real creative. But the toys are working together to bring back what the lower case 'c' in a circle meant: a toy identical with million others on the shelves. Oh! And don't forget! A good kid would preserve all the junk: large useless wasteful boxes with advertisements for the whole line of plastic somethings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Toy Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - B This was a good movie as it has a fun story, good characters, and is entertaining for kids and some adults. The film shows us the life of toys at a little kids house and how they all do their own little things behind our backs. Then a new toy, the new spaceman comes and Woody, the leader of the crew, feels like he's being replaced. The conflict is this space ranger thinking he is a real one and not a toy and Woody trying to show him who he really is and trying to still be Andy's favorite. The film is cute with Woody and Buzz as great characters. The score is good, but not the whole story is impressive. I liked it when at home and not running around town as it seemed unreal. I thought the neighbor kid was stupid to have but the animation was incredible. A good family film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rafiek-awad
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was great and very enjoyable, my whole family loved the scenes and the summary. Every moment was hilarious and lovable, while all scenes were playing you could feel the relationship between Woody and buzz growing and growing and at the end it reaches the height of a giant tree and as sweet as a majestic day. Most of the movie was about how friends should stick together and how bad it gets when the separate from each other and it takes several days, years etc till there relationship sticks back together. I really appreciate the efforts which Disney production put in to make a wonderful movie and here it is shown in every role and screen play. Special thanks to all the people who took part in making this happy film!!.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Captivating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kpayne032
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is at least 18 years old and still is able to capture young audiences from around the world. How did Pixar do it? How did they create a movie that has one of the greatest story lines to it? Who knows but I'm sure that Dreamworks will never be able to top it. Not once. By the way, if you have not already seen this movie my only question is "how?" Almost every living body has seen this movie it's alive and it's active yet you still have not seen it? Wow, you most indeed live one depressing life. Anyways, even if you have watched this movie you should already know that it's good but if you just wanted to see reviews fine by me, but don't come yelling at me if you don't agree with what I'm saying, it's pointless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nostalgic start to Pixar's best film franchise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I very fondly remember watching this film as a child and to this day it it still one of Pixar's finest efforts, especially if it's their first feature-length animation. As for the animation, it is pretty impressive for 1995 and the most realistically-modelled toys are Etch-A-Sketch and Mr Potato Head, although the main toys Woody and Buzz are well-designed as well. There are some funny moments such as Mr Potato Head pretending to be a Picasso painting and Sid's sister Hannah dressing Buzz up as a woman and naming him Mrs Nesbitt at a tea party as well as some dark, sinister moments such as Sid making mutant toys that eventually scare him off and the tense moment of Woody and Buzz's rivalry including the memorable, "You are a toy!" line. Other lines I remember from this film are Buzz's catchphrase "To infinity and beyond" and Woody's many phrases such as "You're my favourite deputy" and "There's a snake in my boots" to name just two. The opening scene involving Andy playing with Woody accompanied by Randy Newman's 'You've Got A Friend In Me' is one of the film's most captivating parts and I liked the product placement of toy manufacturers (Rex being made by Mattel and Mr Potato Head being made by Playskool). Overall, this is a dark and funny start to my favourite trilogy of animated films. 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reminds me of my childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    izzybeth7777
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched Toy story when I was little and it was my favorite childhood movie and I really love it because it made me think a lot and when I was little I used to tip toe up the steps and down the hall and peek into my room to see if my toys were moving but they never were but I just thought they were really good and I used to talk to them all the time about my life which you will most likely think I'm weird because I talked to my toys but I talked to my dog to and you want to know why well because I love to talked and everybody was annoyed so I just talked to my stuff. But this is off subject so basically to some this up I love this movie and you should watch it and you should spread it even know everybody has most likely already watched it so you should watch it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I never really thought this was the best movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Katie P
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Toy Story is a good movie. It has good characters and a decent story. But is it really worth the hype? Yes, it's the first fully computer animated movie ever made and that's very impressive. For that reason alone, it will stand out in history. But I certainly never really thought it was the brilliant classic everyone else thought it was. Its animation is great but the story suffers from major pacing issues. There are entire moments of the movie right in the middle that bore me every time and don't stop boring me until I get to the film's climax, when it picks up again. A lot of trimming should have been done in the middle. Toy Story is good but its sequels are a lot better. So is it bad? No. But it's not brilliant. If this were 2-D, I doubt it would receive this high praise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Toy Story" - One of animation's finest films for good reason
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a child, have you ever wondered at one point in your life what might happen in your room full of toys and dolls while you weren't in it? In Disney-Pixar's landmark 1995 computer animated feature Toy Story, we get that possible answer as the film is about toys that come to life while the owner is out of their room. In case you don't know why Toy Story is an important American film and why it's one of only two animated films to make the AFI's list of the 100 greatest films of all time, allow me to fill you in. It was the first full-length computer animated feature ever made and arguably the best in my opinion. Toy Story was so popular that it is solely responsible for Pixar's big streak of success with other computer animated features such as Up (2009), WALL-E (2008), and The Incredibles (2004). Enough said. In Toy Story, a group of toys that belong to a young kid named Andy come to life while he's out of the room. They're all led by Andy's favorite toy, a cowboy doll named Woody (Tom Hanks). They've just learned that Andy and his family will be moving away to another neighborhood. Not only that, but his birthday party is being celebrated earlier than expected, which means new toys will be joining them for sure, much to the horror of the other toys. They're afraid that the new toys will be so cool that Andy will no longer want to play with them anymore. Despite this, Woody assures the other toys that everything will be alright and no one will be forgotten. That is until he discovers Andy's newest toy Buzz Lightyear (Tim Allen), a space ranger action figure who thinks he's the real space ranger that he's based on. Woody basically becomes so jealous over how cool a toy he is that he tries to do whatever he can to become Andy's favorite toy again. When one of his attempts at getting noticed by Andy accidentally goes too far (meaning Buzz gets transported out of the house), Woody tries to rescue him and re-earn the trust of his fellow toys. But through a series of circumstances, Woody gets lost as well right alongside Buzz and they are accidentally found by Andy's next door neighbor, Sid. This is a problem for both of these toys since Sid really enjoys torturing and destroying toys. So now Woody and Buzz must get over their differences and work together to get out of Sid's house and back to Andy before he moves. Basically, what we have here story wise is your typical buddy comedy in animated form. But in my opinion, it's the buddy comedy done right. I'm not saying it just because it's told through a new form of animation, but because the film handles this type of story in the most imaginative and least contrived way. In other words, the basic plot seems to play out naturally and comes off as if Pixar was inventing this type of plot for the first time. There are no plot devices that are forced to the point where it's painfully obvious, everything on screen works within the fabric of the story. The comedic bits, along with being humorous, are very well handled and are necessary contributions to the plot. I loved how in one scene when Woody talks to the toys in Andy's room from Sid's house, the other toys think that Woody murdered Buzz by the end of the scene. That scene and similar scenes were very funny and well done. There's another crucial reason why the plot for this picture works as well as it does and that is the vocal cast itself. Tom Hanks and Tim Allen are irreplaceable as Woody and Buzz, respectively, since they bring so much to the chemistry and dialogue between each other to the point where it's impossible to top them. They do a perfect enough job with what they bring into each of their roles that you couldn't picture hearing any other actors play these two characters. The same can also be said for the supporting cast as well, particularly Don Rickles as Mr. Potato Head and Wallace Shawn as Rex. In other words, the actors do a convincing job at bringing each of their characters to life and putting so much personality into them that they help enhance the story further as good acting should be doing. The way Pixar handles its characters in this movie is also worth noting. For example, even though Sid is having fun destroying toys and is considered evil by the toys, they don't necessarily make him the main villain. In other words, the characters created here aren't exactly clear cut heroes and villains, but they're simply individuals with different personalities. Woody isn't a bad guy because he technically gets Buzz and himself into trouble, he's simply afraid of being forgotten by Andy. That aspect about Woody makes us relate to him even more since we do learn from the mistakes that Woody makes over this misunderstanding. Buzz Lightyear makes for an enjoyable fish-out-of-water type character in that he strongly believes he's the real Buzz Lightyear to the point that being told that he's actually a toy would be nonsense in his mind. In other words, Pixar cares a great deal about its story and characters here. As you can tell, Toy Story is simply much more than an innovative American film with its groundbreaking animation or even an entertaining family film. It's a film about characters that I'm sure most of us can relate to or identify with. It's a film for everybody to cherish for different reasons whether it be the animation, the humor, the story or the characters. I'll argue that it's still the finest film Pixar's produced yet. In a pinch, Toy Story is a film you should check out immediately if you haven't already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stonedouttamymind
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has something for everyone in the family. It is funny, has action, has a life story, and the characters will touch your heart. These are not just toys, this is a friendship, siblings, relationship or just a way of thinking sometimes. It is a real story on so many levels. It is a heart-warming story about a child and his toys and the relationships between the toys. In Toy Story, the two main characters are Buzz and Woody. At first Buzz and Woody can not stand each other and the two of them fight for the love of their owner Andy. Throughout the story these two show that fighting, arguing, and not getting along will get you no where in life and finally come together to help each other get back to their owner so that they can get back to their home. After all the trials and tribunals these two go through they become the best of friends and go on for two more movies to be a heroic team.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Andy is a young boy that has to give up his childhood toys. But the toys won't accept that they figure out a way to get back to Andy and stay with him.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nickiastar16
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was my favorite movie growing up. It shows what a kids toys would do if they had to be given up and could really talk. Andy is a sweet kid and he wants to keep his favorite toy but can't and I don't remember why. But all in all it is an amazing movie with a great story line. Andy would not give up his toys without a reason. They are in ways his best friends. He loves the toys as much as they love him but some how or another they get separated and the toys won't accept that. They do everything they can to get back to their best friend and don't give up till they get back to Andy. And is so happy when he gets his toys back and he tries his hardest not to lose them again. It is like losing your best friend because they move across the country.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Siddartha RO
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amazing! I have just seen Toy Story. The first one. For the first time. And it's like I'm seeing it back in the days before Toy Story 2 got out on the big screen. The only thing I wouldn't have known was the future story of Apple Inc. This is a wonderful one hour advertisement where you can see branded toys. The only thing that is original in this one hour waste is the way Steve Jobs' employees created a toy universe. It was so yesterday to create a new line of cheap plastics than do some silly adventure. It was called an adventure so people won't have any issue leaving the children alone for one or two hours of advertisements. It sounds so much more educative to have cartoon adventure instead of having cartoon characters selling you stuff. And, instead of a real actor, the cartoon has precisely zero morals: it can sell plutonium to a 5 year old or to some radical terrorist group without blinking. Unless the art director thinks the blink would raise the quantity at least 10 percent. Now about the creative part. Steve Jobs' employees never bothered to create something like say Hanna-Barbera. They just pushed older toys into this new advertisement. And here's where the creativity ends. What's even better is the world imagined. A world where children are isolated. Where they depend on their branded toys. And watch out for the bad kid! He is real creative. But the toys are working together to bring back what the lower case 'c' in a circle meant: a toy identical with million others on the shelves. Oh! And don't forget! A good kid would preserve all the junk: large useless wasteful boxes with advertisements for the whole line of plastic somethings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Toy Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - B This was a good movie as it has a fun story, good characters, and is entertaining for kids and some adults. The film shows us the life of toys at a little kids house and how they all do their own little things behind our backs. Then a new toy, the new spaceman comes and Woody, the leader of the crew, feels like he's being replaced. The conflict is this space ranger thinking he is a real one and not a toy and Woody trying to show him who he really is and trying to still be Andy's favorite. The film is cute with Woody and Buzz as great characters. The score is good, but not the whole story is impressive. I liked it when at home and not running around town as it seemed unreal. I thought the neighbor kid was stupid to have but the animation was incredible. A good family film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rafiek-awad
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was great and very enjoyable, my whole family loved the scenes and the summary. Every moment was hilarious and lovable, while all scenes were playing you could feel the relationship between Woody and buzz growing and growing and at the end it reaches the height of a giant tree and as sweet as a majestic day. Most of the movie was about how friends should stick together and how bad it gets when the separate from each other and it takes several days, years etc till there relationship sticks back together. I really appreciate the efforts which Disney production put in to make a wonderful movie and here it is shown in every role and screen play. Special thanks to all the people who took part in making this happy film!!.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Captivating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kpayne032
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is at least 18 years old and still is able to capture young audiences from around the world. How did Pixar do it? How did they create a movie that has one of the greatest story lines to it? Who knows but I'm sure that Dreamworks will never be able to top it. Not once. By the way, if you have not already seen this movie my only question is "how?" Almost every living body has seen this movie it's alive and it's active yet you still have not seen it? Wow, you most indeed live one depressing life. Anyways, even if you have watched this movie you should already know that it's good but if you just wanted to see reviews fine by me, but don't come yelling at me if you don't agree with what I'm saying, it's pointless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nostalgic start to Pixar's best film franchise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I very fondly remember watching this film as a child and to this day it it still one of Pixar's finest efforts, especially if it's their first feature-length animation. As for the animation, it is pretty impressive for 1995 and the most realistically-modelled toys are Etch-A-Sketch and Mr Potato Head, although the main toys Woody and Buzz are well-designed as well. There are some funny moments such as Mr Potato Head pretending to be a Picasso painting and Sid's sister Hannah dressing Buzz up as a woman and naming him Mrs Nesbitt at a tea party as well as some dark, sinister moments such as Sid making mutant toys that eventually scare him off and the tense moment of Woody and Buzz's rivalry including the memorable, "You are a toy!" line. Other lines I remember from this film are Buzz's catchphrase "To infinity and beyond" and Woody's many phrases such as "You're my favourite deputy" and "There's a snake in my boots" to name just two. The opening scene involving Andy playing with Woody accompanied by Randy Newman's 'You've Got A Friend In Me' is one of the film's most captivating parts and I liked the product placement of toy manufacturers (Rex being made by Mattel and Mr Potato Head being made by Playskool). Overall, this is a dark and funny start to my favourite trilogy of animated films. 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reminds me of my childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    izzybeth7777
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched Toy story when I was little and it was my favorite childhood movie and I really love it because it made me think a lot and when I was little I used to tip toe up the steps and down the hall and peek into my room to see if my toys were moving but they never were but I just thought they were really good and I used to talk to them all the time about my life which you will most likely think I'm weird because I talked to my toys but I talked to my dog to and you want to know why well because I love to talked and everybody was annoyed so I just talked to my stuff. But this is off subject so basically to some this up I love this movie and you should watch it and you should spread it even know everybody has most likely already watched it so you should watch it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I never really thought this was the best movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Katie P
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Toy Story is a good movie. It has good characters and a decent story. But is it really worth the hype? Yes, it's the first fully computer animated movie ever made and that's very impressive. For that reason alone, it will stand out in history. But I certainly never really thought it was the brilliant classic everyone else thought it was. Its animation is great but the story suffers from major pacing issues. There are entire moments of the movie right in the middle that bore me every time and don't stop boring me until I get to the film's climax, when it picks up again. A lot of trimming should have been done in the middle. Toy Story is good but its sequels are a lot better. So is it bad? No. But it's not brilliant. If this were 2-D, I doubt it would receive this high praise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Toy Story" - One of animation's finest films for good reason
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a child, have you ever wondered at one point in your life what might happen in your room full of toys and dolls while you weren't in it? In Disney-Pixar's landmark 1995 computer animated feature Toy Story, we get that possible answer as the film is about toys that come to life while the owner is out of their room. In case you don't know why Toy Story is an important American film and why it's one of only two animated films to make the AFI's list of the 100 greatest films of all time, allow me to fill you in. It was the first full-length computer animated feature ever made and arguably the best in my opinion. Toy Story was so popular that it is solely responsible for Pixar's big streak of success with other computer animated features such as Up (2009), WALL-E (2008), and The Incredibles (2004). Enough said. In Toy Story, a group of toys that belong to a young kid named Andy come to life while he's out of the room. They're all led by Andy's favorite toy, a cowboy doll named Woody (Tom Hanks). They've just learned that Andy and his family will be moving away to another neighborhood. Not only that, but his birthday party is being celebrated earlier than expected, which means new toys will be joining them for sure, much to the horror of the other toys. They're afraid that the new toys will be so cool that Andy will no longer want to play with them anymore. Despite this, Woody assures the other toys that everything will be alright and no one will be forgotten. That is until he discovers Andy's newest toy Buzz Lightyear (Tim Allen), a space ranger action figure who thinks he's the real space ranger that he's based on. Woody basically becomes so jealous over how cool a toy he is that he tries to do whatever he can to become Andy's favorite toy again. When one of his attempts at getting noticed by Andy accidentally goes too far (meaning Buzz gets transported out of the house), Woody tries to rescue him and re-earn the trust of his fellow toys. But through a series of circumstances, Woody gets lost as well right alongside Buzz and they are accidentally found by Andy's next door neighbor, Sid. This is a problem for both of these toys since Sid really enjoys torturing and destroying toys. So now Woody and Buzz must get over their differences and work together to get out of Sid's house and back to Andy before he moves. Basically, what we have here story wise is your typical buddy comedy in animated form. But in my opinion, it's the buddy comedy done right. I'm not saying it just because it's told through a new form of animation, but because the film handles this type of story in the most imaginative and least contrived way. In other words, the basic plot seems to play out naturally and comes off as if Pixar was inventing this type of plot for the first time. There are no plot devices that are forced to the point where it's painfully obvious, everything on screen works within the fabric of the story. The comedic bits, along with being humorous, are very well handled and are necessary contributions to the plot. I loved how in one scene when Woody talks to the toys in Andy's room from Sid's house, the other toys think that Woody murdered Buzz by the end of the scene. That scene and similar scenes were very funny and well done. There's another crucial reason why the plot for this picture works as well as it does and that is the vocal cast itself. Tom Hanks and Tim Allen are irreplaceable as Woody and Buzz, respectively, since they bring so much to the chemistry and dialogue between each other to the point where it's impossible to top them. They do a perfect enough job with what they bring into each of their roles that you couldn't picture hearing any other actors play these two characters. The same can also be said for the supporting cast as well, particularly Don Rickles as Mr. Potato Head and Wallace Shawn as Rex. In other words, the actors do a convincing job at bringing each of their characters to life and putting so much personality into them that they help enhance the story further as good acting should be doing. The way Pixar handles its characters in this movie is also worth noting. For example, even though Sid is having fun destroying toys and is considered evil by the toys, they don't necessarily make him the main villain. In other words, the characters created here aren't exactly clear cut heroes and villains, but they're simply individuals with different personalities. Woody isn't a bad guy because he technically gets Buzz and himself into trouble, he's simply afraid of being forgotten by Andy. That aspect about Woody makes us relate to him even more since we do learn from the mistakes that Woody makes over this misunderstanding. Buzz Lightyear makes for an enjoyable fish-out-of-water type character in that he strongly believes he's the real Buzz Lightyear to the point that being told that he's actually a toy would be nonsense in his mind. In other words, Pixar cares a great deal about its story and characters here. As you can tell, Toy Story is simply much more than an innovative American film with its groundbreaking animation or even an entertaining family film. It's a film about characters that I'm sure most of us can relate to or identify with. It's a film for everybody to cherish for different reasons whether it be the animation, the humor, the story or the characters. I'll argue that it's still the finest film Pixar's produced yet. In a pinch, Toy Story is a film you should check out immediately if you haven't already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stonedouttamymind
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has something for everyone in the family. It is funny, has action, has a life story, and the characters will touch your heart. These are not just toys, this is a friendship, siblings, relationship or just a way of thinking sometimes. It is a real story on so many levels. It is a heart-warming story about a child and his toys and the relationships between the toys. In Toy Story, the two main characters are Buzz and Woody. At first Buzz and Woody can not stand each other and the two of them fight for the love of their owner Andy. Throughout the story these two show that fighting, arguing, and not getting along will get you no where in life and finally come together to help each other get back to their owner so that they can get back to their home. After all the trials and tribunals these two go through they become the best of friends and go on for two more movies to be a heroic team.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Andy is a young boy that has to give up his childhood toys. But the toys won't accept that they figure out a way to get back to Andy and stay with him.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nickiastar16
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was my favorite movie growing up. It shows what a kids toys would do if they had to be given up and could really talk. Andy is a sweet kid and he wants to keep his favorite toy but can't and I don't remember why. But all in all it is an amazing movie with a great story line. Andy would not give up his toys without a reason. They are in ways his best friends. He loves the toys as much as they love him but some how or another they get separated and the toys won't accept that. They do everything they can to get back to their best friend and don't give up till they get back to Andy. And is so happy when he gets his toys back and he tries his hardest not to lose them again. It is like losing your best friend because they move across the country.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Siddartha RO
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amazing! I have just seen Toy Story. The first one. For the first time. And it's like I'm seeing it back in the days before Toy Story 2 got out on the big screen. The only thing I wouldn't have known was the future story of Apple Inc. This is a wonderful one hour advertisement where you can see branded toys. The only thing that is original in this one hour waste is the way Steve Jobs' employees created a toy universe. It was so yesterday to create a new line of cheap plastics than do some silly adventure. It was called an adventure so people won't have any issue leaving the children alone for one or two hours of advertisements. It sounds so much more educative to have cartoon adventure instead of having cartoon characters selling you stuff. And, instead of a real actor, the cartoon has precisely zero morals: it can sell plutonium to a 5 year old or to some radical terrorist group without blinking. Unless the art director thinks the blink would raise the quantity at least 10 percent. Now about the creative part. Steve Jobs' employees never bothered to create something like say Hanna-Barbera. They just pushed older toys into this new advertisement. And here's where the creativity ends. What's even better is the world imagined. A world where children are isolated. Where they depend on their branded toys. And watch out for the bad kid! He is real creative. But the toys are working together to bring back what the lower case 'c' in a circle meant: a toy identical with million others on the shelves. Oh! And don't forget! A good kid would preserve all the junk: large useless wasteful boxes with advertisements for the whole line of plastic somethings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Toy Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - B This was a good movie as it has a fun story, good characters, and is entertaining for kids and some adults. The film shows us the life of toys at a little kids house and how they all do their own little things behind our backs. Then a new toy, the new spaceman comes and Woody, the leader of the crew, feels like he's being replaced. The conflict is this space ranger thinking he is a real one and not a toy and Woody trying to show him who he really is and trying to still be Andy's favorite. The film is cute with Woody and Buzz as great characters. The score is good, but not the whole story is impressive. I liked it when at home and not running around town as it seemed unreal. I thought the neighbor kid was stupid to have but the animation was incredible. A good family film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rafiek-awad
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was great and very enjoyable, my whole family loved the scenes and the summary. Every moment was hilarious and lovable, while all scenes were playing you could feel the relationship between Woody and buzz growing and growing and at the end it reaches the height of a giant tree and as sweet as a majestic day. Most of the movie was about how friends should stick together and how bad it gets when the separate from each other and it takes several days, years etc till there relationship sticks back together. I really appreciate the efforts which Disney production put in to make a wonderful movie and here it is shown in every role and screen play. Special thanks to all the people who took part in making this happy film!!.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Captivating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kpayne032
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is at least 18 years old and still is able to capture young audiences from around the world. How did Pixar do it? How did they create a movie that has one of the greatest story lines to it? Who knows but I'm sure that Dreamworks will never be able to top it. Not once. By the way, if you have not already seen this movie my only question is "how?" Almost every living body has seen this movie it's alive and it's active yet you still have not seen it? Wow, you most indeed live one depressing life. Anyways, even if you have watched this movie you should already know that it's good but if you just wanted to see reviews fine by me, but don't come yelling at me if you don't agree with what I'm saying, it's pointless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nostalgic start to Pixar's best film franchise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I very fondly remember watching this film as a child and to this day it it still one of Pixar's finest efforts, especially if it's their first feature-length animation. As for the animation, it is pretty impressive for 1995 and the most realistically-modelled toys are Etch-A-Sketch and Mr Potato Head, although the main toys Woody and Buzz are well-designed as well. There are some funny moments such as Mr Potato Head pretending to be a Picasso painting and Sid's sister Hannah dressing Buzz up as a woman and naming him Mrs Nesbitt at a tea party as well as some dark, sinister moments such as Sid making mutant toys that eventually scare him off and the tense moment of Woody and Buzz's rivalry including the memorable, "You are a toy!" line. Other lines I remember from this film are Buzz's catchphrase "To infinity and beyond" and Woody's many phrases such as "You're my favourite deputy" and "There's a snake in my boots" to name just two. The opening scene involving Andy playing with Woody accompanied by Randy Newman's 'You've Got A Friend In Me' is one of the film's most captivating parts and I liked the product placement of toy manufacturers (Rex being made by Mattel and Mr Potato Head being made by Playskool). Overall, this is a dark and funny start to my favourite trilogy of animated films. 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reminds me of my childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    izzybeth7777
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched Toy story when I was little and it was my favorite childhood movie and I really love it because it made me think a lot and when I was little I used to tip toe up the steps and down the hall and peek into my room to see if my toys were moving but they never were but I just thought they were really good and I used to talk to them all the time about my life which you will most likely think I'm weird because I talked to my toys but I talked to my dog to and you want to know why well because I love to talked and everybody was annoyed so I just talked to my stuff. But this is off subject so basically to some this up I love this movie and you should watch it and you should spread it even know everybody has most likely already watched it so you should watch it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I never really thought this was the best movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Katie P
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Toy Story is a good movie. It has good characters and a decent story. But is it really worth the hype? Yes, it's the first fully computer animated movie ever made and that's very impressive. For that reason alone, it will stand out in history. But I certainly never really thought it was the brilliant classic everyone else thought it was. Its animation is great but the story suffers from major pacing issues. There are entire moments of the movie right in the middle that bore me every time and don't stop boring me until I get to the film's climax, when it picks up again. A lot of trimming should have been done in the middle. Toy Story is good but its sequels are a lot better. So is it bad? No. But it's not brilliant. If this were 2-D, I doubt it would receive this high praise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Toy Story" - One of animation's finest films for good reason
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a child, have you ever wondered at one point in your life what might happen in your room full of toys and dolls while you weren't in it? In Disney-Pixar's landmark 1995 computer animated feature Toy Story, we get that possible answer as the film is about toys that come to life while the owner is out of their room. In case you don't know why Toy Story is an important American film and why it's one of only two animated films to make the AFI's list of the 100 greatest films of all time, allow me to fill you in. It was the first full-length computer animated feature ever made and arguably the best in my opinion. Toy Story was so popular that it is solely responsible for Pixar's big streak of success with other computer animated features such as Up (2009), WALL-E (2008), and The Incredibles (2004). Enough said. In Toy Story, a group of toys that belong to a young kid named Andy come to life while he's out of the room. They're all led by Andy's favorite toy, a cowboy doll named Woody (Tom Hanks). They've just learned that Andy and his family will be moving away to another neighborhood. Not only that, but his birthday party is being celebrated earlier than expected, which means new toys will be joining them for sure, much to the horror of the other toys. They're afraid that the new toys will be so cool that Andy will no longer want to play with them anymore. Despite this, Woody assures the other toys that everything will be alright and no one will be forgotten. That is until he discovers Andy's newest toy Buzz Lightyear (Tim Allen), a space ranger action figure who thinks he's the real space ranger that he's based on. Woody basically becomes so jealous over how cool a toy he is that he tries to do whatever he can to become Andy's favorite toy again. When one of his attempts at getting noticed by Andy accidentally goes too far (meaning Buzz gets transported out of the house), Woody tries to rescue him and re-earn the trust of his fellow toys. But through a series of circumstances, Woody gets lost as well right alongside Buzz and they are accidentally found by Andy's next door neighbor, Sid. This is a problem for both of these toys since Sid really enjoys torturing and destroying toys. So now Woody and Buzz must get over their differences and work together to get out of Sid's house and back to Andy before he moves. Basically, what we have here story wise is your typical buddy comedy in animated form. But in my opinion, it's the buddy comedy done right. I'm not saying it just because it's told through a new form of animation, but because the film handles this type of story in the most imaginative and least contrived way. In other words, the basic plot seems to play out naturally and comes off as if Pixar was inventing this type of plot for the first time. There are no plot devices that are forced to the point where it's painfully obvious, everything on screen works within the fabric of the story. The comedic bits, along with being humorous, are very well handled and are necessary contributions to the plot. I loved how in one scene when Woody talks to the toys in Andy's room from Sid's house, the other toys think that Woody murdered Buzz by the end of the scene. That scene and similar scenes were very funny and well done. There's another crucial reason why the plot for this picture works as well as it does and that is the vocal cast itself. Tom Hanks and Tim Allen are irreplaceable as Woody and Buzz, respectively, since they bring so much to the chemistry and dialogue between each other to the point where it's impossible to top them. They do a perfect enough job with what they bring into each of their roles that you couldn't picture hearing any other actors play these two characters. The same can also be said for the supporting cast as well, particularly Don Rickles as Mr. Potato Head and Wallace Shawn as Rex. In other words, the actors do a convincing job at bringing each of their characters to life and putting so much personality into them that they help enhance the story further as good acting should be doing. The way Pixar handles its characters in this movie is also worth noting. For example, even though Sid is having fun destroying toys and is considered evil by the toys, they don't necessarily make him the main villain. In other words, the characters created here aren't exactly clear cut heroes and villains, but they're simply individuals with different personalities. Woody isn't a bad guy because he technically gets Buzz and himself into trouble, he's simply afraid of being forgotten by Andy. That aspect about Woody makes us relate to him even more since we do learn from the mistakes that Woody makes over this misunderstanding. Buzz Lightyear makes for an enjoyable fish-out-of-water type character in that he strongly believes he's the real Buzz Lightyear to the point that being told that he's actually a toy would be nonsense in his mind. In other words, Pixar cares a great deal about its story and characters here. As you can tell, Toy Story is simply much more than an innovative American film with its groundbreaking animation or even an entertaining family film. It's a film about characters that I'm sure most of us can relate to or identify with. It's a film for everybody to cherish for different reasons whether it be the animation, the humor, the story or the characters. I'll argue that it's still the finest film Pixar's produced yet. In a pinch, Toy Story is a film you should check out immediately if you haven't already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stonedouttamymind
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has something for everyone in the family. It is funny, has action, has a life story, and the characters will touch your heart. These are not just toys, this is a friendship, siblings, relationship or just a way of thinking sometimes. It is a real story on so many levels. It is a heart-warming story about a child and his toys and the relationships between the toys. In Toy Story, the two main characters are Buzz and Woody. At first Buzz and Woody can not stand each other and the two of them fight for the love of their owner Andy. Throughout the story these two show that fighting, arguing, and not getting along will get you no where in life and finally come together to help each other get back to their owner so that they can get back to their home. After all the trials and tribunals these two go through they become the best of friends and go on for two more movies to be a heroic team.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Andy is a young boy that has to give up his childhood toys. But the toys won't accept that they figure out a way to get back to Andy and stay with him.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nickiastar16
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was my favorite movie growing up. It shows what a kids toys would do if they had to be given up and could really talk. Andy is a sweet kid and he wants to keep his favorite toy but can't and I don't remember why. But all in all it is an amazing movie with a great story line. Andy would not give up his toys without a reason. They are in ways his best friends. He loves the toys as much as they love him but some how or another they get separated and the toys won't accept that. They do everything they can to get back to their best friend and don't give up till they get back to Andy. And is so happy when he gets his toys back and he tries his hardest not to lose them again. It is like losing your best friend because they move across the country.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Siddartha RO
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amazing! I have just seen Toy Story. The first one. For the first time. And it's like I'm seeing it back in the days before Toy Story 2 got out on the big screen. The only thing I wouldn't have known was the future story of Apple Inc. This is a wonderful one hour advertisement where you can see branded toys. The only thing that is original in this one hour waste is the way Steve Jobs' employees created a toy universe. It was so yesterday to create a new line of cheap plastics than do some silly adventure. It was called an adventure so people won't have any issue leaving the children alone for one or two hours of advertisements. It sounds so much more educative to have cartoon adventure instead of having cartoon characters selling you stuff. And, instead of a real actor, the cartoon has precisely zero morals: it can sell plutonium to a 5 year old or to some radical terrorist group without blinking. Unless the art director thinks the blink would raise the quantity at least 10 percent. Now about the creative part. Steve Jobs' employees never bothered to create something like say Hanna-Barbera. They just pushed older toys into this new advertisement. And here's where the creativity ends. What's even better is the world imagined. A world where children are isolated. Where they depend on their branded toys. And watch out for the bad kid! He is real creative. But the toys are working together to bring back what the lower case 'c' in a circle meant: a toy identical with million others on the shelves. Oh! And don't forget! A good kid would preserve all the junk: large useless wasteful boxes with advertisements for the whole line of plastic somethings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Toy Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - B This was a good movie as it has a fun story, good characters, and is entertaining for kids and some adults. The film shows us the life of toys at a little kids house and how they all do their own little things behind our backs. Then a new toy, the new spaceman comes and Woody, the leader of the crew, feels like he's being replaced. The conflict is this space ranger thinking he is a real one and not a toy and Woody trying to show him who he really is and trying to still be Andy's favorite. The film is cute with Woody and Buzz as great characters. The score is good, but not the whole story is impressive. I liked it when at home and not running around town as it seemed unreal. I thought the neighbor kid was stupid to have but the animation was incredible. A good family film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rafiek-awad
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was great and very enjoyable, my whole family loved the scenes and the summary. Every moment was hilarious and lovable, while all scenes were playing you could feel the relationship between Woody and buzz growing and growing and at the end it reaches the height of a giant tree and as sweet as a majestic day. Most of the movie was about how friends should stick together and how bad it gets when the separate from each other and it takes several days, years etc till there relationship sticks back together. I really appreciate the efforts which Disney production put in to make a wonderful movie and here it is shown in every role and screen play. Special thanks to all the people who took part in making this happy film!!.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Captivating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kpayne032
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is at least 18 years old and still is able to capture young audiences from around the world. How did Pixar do it? How did they create a movie that has one of the greatest story lines to it? Who knows but I'm sure that Dreamworks will never be able to top it. Not once. By the way, if you have not already seen this movie my only question is "how?" Almost every living body has seen this movie it's alive and it's active yet you still have not seen it? Wow, you most indeed live one depressing life. Anyways, even if you have watched this movie you should already know that it's good but if you just wanted to see reviews fine by me, but don't come yelling at me if you don't agree with what I'm saying, it's pointless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nostalgic start to Pixar's best film franchise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I very fondly remember watching this film as a child and to this day it it still one of Pixar's finest efforts, especially if it's their first feature-length animation. As for the animation, it is pretty impressive for 1995 and the most realistically-modelled toys are Etch-A-Sketch and Mr Potato Head, although the main toys Woody and Buzz are well-designed as well. There are some funny moments such as Mr Potato Head pretending to be a Picasso painting and Sid's sister Hannah dressing Buzz up as a woman and naming him Mrs Nesbitt at a tea party as well as some dark, sinister moments such as Sid making mutant toys that eventually scare him off and the tense moment of Woody and Buzz's rivalry including the memorable, "You are a toy!" line. Other lines I remember from this film are Buzz's catchphrase "To infinity and beyond" and Woody's many phrases such as "You're my favourite deputy" and "There's a snake in my boots" to name just two. The opening scene involving Andy playing with Woody accompanied by Randy Newman's 'You've Got A Friend In Me' is one of the film's most captivating parts and I liked the product placement of toy manufacturers (Rex being made by Mattel and Mr Potato Head being made by Playskool). Overall, this is a dark and funny start to my favourite trilogy of animated films. 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reminds me of my childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    izzybeth7777
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched Toy story when I was little and it was my favorite childhood movie and I really love it because it made me think a lot and when I was little I used to tip toe up the steps and down the hall and peek into my room to see if my toys were moving but they never were but I just thought they were really good and I used to talk to them all the time about my life which you will most likely think I'm weird because I talked to my toys but I talked to my dog to and you want to know why well because I love to talked and everybody was annoyed so I just talked to my stuff. But this is off subject so basically to some this up I love this movie and you should watch it and you should spread it even know everybody has most likely already watched it so you should watch it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I never really thought this was the best movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Katie P
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Toy Story is a good movie. It has good characters and a decent story. But is it really worth the hype? Yes, it's the first fully computer animated movie ever made and that's very impressive. For that reason alone, it will stand out in history. But I certainly never really thought it was the brilliant classic everyone else thought it was. Its animation is great but the story suffers from major pacing issues. There are entire moments of the movie right in the middle that bore me every time and don't stop boring me until I get to the film's climax, when it picks up again. A lot of trimming should have been done in the middle. Toy Story is good but its sequels are a lot better. So is it bad? No. But it's not brilliant. If this were 2-D, I doubt it would receive this high praise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Toy Story" - One of animation's finest films for good reason
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a child, have you ever wondered at one point in your life what might happen in your room full of toys and dolls while you weren't in it? In Disney-Pixar's landmark 1995 computer animated feature Toy Story, we get that possible answer as the film is about toys that come to life while the owner is out of their room. In case you don't know why Toy Story is an important American film and why it's one of only two animated films to make the AFI's list of the 100 greatest films of all time, allow me to fill you in. It was the first full-length computer animated feature ever made and arguably the best in my opinion. Toy Story was so popular that it is solely responsible for Pixar's big streak of success with other computer animated features such as Up (2009), WALL-E (2008), and The Incredibles (2004). Enough said. In Toy Story, a group of toys that belong to a young kid named Andy come to life while he's out of the room. They're all led by Andy's favorite toy, a cowboy doll named Woody (Tom Hanks). They've just learned that Andy and his family will be moving away to another neighborhood. Not only that, but his birthday party is being celebrated earlier than expected, which means new toys will be joining them for sure, much to the horror of the other toys. They're afraid that the new toys will be so cool that Andy will no longer want to play with them anymore. Despite this, Woody assures the other toys that everything will be alright and no one will be forgotten. That is until he discovers Andy's newest toy Buzz Lightyear (Tim Allen), a space ranger action figure who thinks he's the real space ranger that he's based on. Woody basically becomes so jealous over how cool a toy he is that he tries to do whatever he can to become Andy's favorite toy again. When one of his attempts at getting noticed by Andy accidentally goes too far (meaning Buzz gets transported out of the house), Woody tries to rescue him and re-earn the trust of his fellow toys. But through a series of circumstances, Woody gets lost as well right alongside Buzz and they are accidentally found by Andy's next door neighbor, Sid. This is a problem for both of these toys since Sid really enjoys torturing and destroying toys. So now Woody and Buzz must get over their differences and work together to get out of Sid's house and back to Andy before he moves. Basically, what we have here story wise is your typical buddy comedy in animated form. But in my opinion, it's the buddy comedy done right. I'm not saying it just because it's told through a new form of animation, but because the film handles this type of story in the most imaginative and least contrived way. In other words, the basic plot seems to play out naturally and comes off as if Pixar was inventing this type of plot for the first time. There are no plot devices that are forced to the point where it's painfully obvious, everything on screen works within the fabric of the story. The comedic bits, along with being humorous, are very well handled and are necessary contributions to the plot. I loved how in one scene when Woody talks to the toys in Andy's room from Sid's house, the other toys think that Woody murdered Buzz by the end of the scene. That scene and similar scenes were very funny and well done. There's another crucial reason why the plot for this picture works as well as it does and that is the vocal cast itself. Tom Hanks and Tim Allen are irreplaceable as Woody and Buzz, respectively, since they bring so much to the chemistry and dialogue between each other to the point where it's impossible to top them. They do a perfect enough job with what they bring into each of their roles that you couldn't picture hearing any other actors play these two characters. The same can also be said for the supporting cast as well, particularly Don Rickles as Mr. Potato Head and Wallace Shawn as Rex. In other words, the actors do a convincing job at bringing each of their characters to life and putting so much personality into them that they help enhance the story further as good acting should be doing. The way Pixar handles its characters in this movie is also worth noting. For example, even though Sid is having fun destroying toys and is considered evil by the toys, they don't necessarily make him the main villain. In other words, the characters created here aren't exactly clear cut heroes and villains, but they're simply individuals with different personalities. Woody isn't a bad guy because he technically gets Buzz and himself into trouble, he's simply afraid of being forgotten by Andy. That aspect about Woody makes us relate to him even more since we do learn from the mistakes that Woody makes over this misunderstanding. Buzz Lightyear makes for an enjoyable fish-out-of-water type character in that he strongly believes he's the real Buzz Lightyear to the point that being told that he's actually a toy would be nonsense in his mind. In other words, Pixar cares a great deal about its story and characters here. As you can tell, Toy Story is simply much more than an innovative American film with its groundbreaking animation or even an entertaining family film. It's a film about characters that I'm sure most of us can relate to or identify with. It's a film for everybody to cherish for different reasons whether it be the animation, the humor, the story or the characters. I'll argue that it's still the finest film Pixar's produced yet. In a pinch, Toy Story is a film you should check out immediately if you haven't already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stonedouttamymind
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has something for everyone in the family. It is funny, has action, has a life story, and the characters will touch your heart. These are not just toys, this is a friendship, siblings, relationship or just a way of thinking sometimes. It is a real story on so many levels. It is a heart-warming story about a child and his toys and the relationships between the toys. In Toy Story, the two main characters are Buzz and Woody. At first Buzz and Woody can not stand each other and the two of them fight for the love of their owner Andy. Throughout the story these two show that fighting, arguing, and not getting along will get you no where in life and finally come together to help each other get back to their owner so that they can get back to their home. After all the trials and tribunals these two go through they become the best of friends and go on for two more movies to be a heroic team.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Andy is a young boy that has to give up his childhood toys. But the toys won't accept that they figure out a way to get back to Andy and stay with him.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nickiastar16
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was my favorite movie growing up. It shows what a kids toys would do if they had to be given up and could really talk. Andy is a sweet kid and he wants to keep his favorite toy but can't and I don't remember why. But all in all it is an amazing movie with a great story line. Andy would not give up his toys without a reason. They are in ways his best friends. He loves the toys as much as they love him but some how or another they get separated and the toys won't accept that. They do everything they can to get back to their best friend and don't give up till they get back to Andy. And is so happy when he gets his toys back and he tries his hardest not to lose them again. It is like losing your best friend because they move across the country.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Siddartha RO
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amazing! I have just seen Toy Story. The first one. For the first time. And it's like I'm seeing it back in the days before Toy Story 2 got out on the big screen. The only thing I wouldn't have known was the future story of Apple Inc. This is a wonderful one hour advertisement where you can see branded toys. The only thing that is original in this one hour waste is the way Steve Jobs' employees created a toy universe. It was so yesterday to create a new line of cheap plastics than do some silly adventure. It was called an adventure so people won't have any issue leaving the children alone for one or two hours of advertisements. It sounds so much more educative to have cartoon adventure instead of having cartoon characters selling you stuff. And, instead of a real actor, the cartoon has precisely zero morals: it can sell plutonium to a 5 year old or to some radical terrorist group without blinking. Unless the art director thinks the blink would raise the quantity at least 10 percent. Now about the creative part. Steve Jobs' employees never bothered to create something like say Hanna-Barbera. They just pushed older toys into this new advertisement. And here's where the creativity ends. What's even better is the world imagined. A world where children are isolated. Where they depend on their branded toys. And watch out for the bad kid! He is real creative. But the toys are working together to bring back what the lower case 'c' in a circle meant: a toy identical with million others on the shelves. Oh! And don't forget! A good kid would preserve all the junk: large useless wasteful boxes with advertisements for the whole line of plastic somethings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Toy Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - B This was a good movie as it has a fun story, good characters, and is entertaining for kids and some adults. The film shows us the life of toys at a little kids house and how they all do their own little things behind our backs. Then a new toy, the new spaceman comes and Woody, the leader of the crew, feels like he's being replaced. The conflict is this space ranger thinking he is a real one and not a toy and Woody trying to show him who he really is and trying to still be Andy's favorite. The film is cute with Woody and Buzz as great characters. The score is good, but not the whole story is impressive. I liked it when at home and not running around town as it seemed unreal. I thought the neighbor kid was stupid to have but the animation was incredible. A good family film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rafiek-awad
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was great and very enjoyable, my whole family loved the scenes and the summary. Every moment was hilarious and lovable, while all scenes were playing you could feel the relationship between Woody and buzz growing and growing and at the end it reaches the height of a giant tree and as sweet as a majestic day. Most of the movie was about how friends should stick together and how bad it gets when the separate from each other and it takes several days, years etc till there relationship sticks back together. I really appreciate the efforts which Disney production put in to make a wonderful movie and here it is shown in every role and screen play. Special thanks to all the people who took part in making this happy film!!.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Captivating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kpayne032
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is at least 18 years old and still is able to capture young audiences from around the world. How did Pixar do it? How did they create a movie that has one of the greatest story lines to it? Who knows but I'm sure that Dreamworks will never be able to top it. Not once. By the way, if you have not already seen this movie my only question is "how?" Almost every living body has seen this movie it's alive and it's active yet you still have not seen it? Wow, you most indeed live one depressing life. Anyways, even if you have watched this movie you should already know that it's good but if you just wanted to see reviews fine by me, but don't come yelling at me if you don't agree with what I'm saying, it's pointless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nostalgic start to Pixar's best film franchise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I very fondly remember watching this film as a child and to this day it it still one of Pixar's finest efforts, especially if it's their first feature-length animation. As for the animation, it is pretty impressive for 1995 and the most realistically-modelled toys are Etch-A-Sketch and Mr Potato Head, although the main toys Woody and Buzz are well-designed as well. There are some funny moments such as Mr Potato Head pretending to be a Picasso painting and Sid's sister Hannah dressing Buzz up as a woman and naming him Mrs Nesbitt at a tea party as well as some dark, sinister moments such as Sid making mutant toys that eventually scare him off and the tense moment of Woody and Buzz's rivalry including the memorable, "You are a toy!" line. Other lines I remember from this film are Buzz's catchphrase "To infinity and beyond" and Woody's many phrases such as "You're my favourite deputy" and "There's a snake in my boots" to name just two. The opening scene involving Andy playing with Woody accompanied by Randy Newman's 'You've Got A Friend In Me' is one of the film's most captivating parts and I liked the product placement of toy manufacturers (Rex being made by Mattel and Mr Potato Head being made by Playskool). Overall, this is a dark and funny start to my favourite trilogy of animated films. 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reminds me of my childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    izzybeth7777
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched Toy story when I was little and it was my favorite childhood movie and I really love it because it made me think a lot and when I was little I used to tip toe up the steps and down the hall and peek into my room to see if my toys were moving but they never were but I just thought they were really good and I used to talk to them all the time about my life which you will most likely think I'm weird because I talked to my toys but I talked to my dog to and you want to know why well because I love to talked and everybody was annoyed so I just talked to my stuff. But this is off subject so basically to some this up I love this movie and you should watch it and you should spread it even know everybody has most likely already watched it so you should watch it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I never really thought this was the best movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Katie P
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Toy Story is a good movie. It has good characters and a decent story. But is it really worth the hype? Yes, it's the first fully computer animated movie ever made and that's very impressive. For that reason alone, it will stand out in history. But I certainly never really thought it was the brilliant classic everyone else thought it was. Its animation is great but the story suffers from major pacing issues. There are entire moments of the movie right in the middle that bore me every time and don't stop boring me until I get to the film's climax, when it picks up again. A lot of trimming should have been done in the middle. Toy Story is good but its sequels are a lot better. So is it bad? No. But it's not brilliant. If this were 2-D, I doubt it would receive this high praise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Toy Story" - One of animation's finest films for good reason
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a child, have you ever wondered at one point in your life what might happen in your room full of toys and dolls while you weren't in it? In Disney-Pixar's landmark 1995 computer animated feature Toy Story, we get that possible answer as the film is about toys that come to life while the owner is out of their room. In case you don't know why Toy Story is an important American film and why it's one of only two animated films to make the AFI's list of the 100 greatest films of all time, allow me to fill you in. It was the first full-length computer animated feature ever made and arguably the best in my opinion. Toy Story was so popular that it is solely responsible for Pixar's big streak of success with other computer animated features such as Up (2009), WALL-E (2008), and The Incredibles (2004). Enough said. In Toy Story, a group of toys that belong to a young kid named Andy come to life while he's out of the room. They're all led by Andy's favorite toy, a cowboy doll named Woody (Tom Hanks). They've just learned that Andy and his family will be moving away to another neighborhood. Not only that, but his birthday party is being celebrated earlier than expected, which means new toys will be joining them for sure, much to the horror of the other toys. They're afraid that the new toys will be so cool that Andy will no longer want to play with them anymore. Despite this, Woody assures the other toys that everything will be alright and no one will be forgotten. That is until he discovers Andy's newest toy Buzz Lightyear (Tim Allen), a space ranger action figure who thinks he's the real space ranger that he's based on. Woody basically becomes so jealous over how cool a toy he is that he tries to do whatever he can to become Andy's favorite toy again. When one of his attempts at getting noticed by Andy accidentally goes too far (meaning Buzz gets transported out of the house), Woody tries to rescue him and re-earn the trust of his fellow toys. But through a series of circumstances, Woody gets lost as well right alongside Buzz and they are accidentally found by Andy's next door neighbor, Sid. This is a problem for both of these toys since Sid really enjoys torturing and destroying toys. So now Woody and Buzz must get over their differences and work together to get out of Sid's house and back to Andy before he moves. Basically, what we have here story wise is your typical buddy comedy in animated form. But in my opinion, it's the buddy comedy done right. I'm not saying it just because it's told through a new form of animation, but because the film handles this type of story in the most imaginative and least contrived way. In other words, the basic plot seems to play out naturally and comes off as if Pixar was inventing this type of plot for the first time. There are no plot devices that are forced to the point where it's painfully obvious, everything on screen works within the fabric of the story. The comedic bits, along with being humorous, are very well handled and are necessary contributions to the plot. I loved how in one scene when Woody talks to the toys in Andy's room from Sid's house, the other toys think that Woody murdered Buzz by the end of the scene. That scene and similar scenes were very funny and well done. There's another crucial reason why the plot for this picture works as well as it does and that is the vocal cast itself. Tom Hanks and Tim Allen are irreplaceable as Woody and Buzz, respectively, since they bring so much to the chemistry and dialogue between each other to the point where it's impossible to top them. They do a perfect enough job with what they bring into each of their roles that you couldn't picture hearing any other actors play these two characters. The same can also be said for the supporting cast as well, particularly Don Rickles as Mr. Potato Head and Wallace Shawn as Rex. In other words, the actors do a convincing job at bringing each of their characters to life and putting so much personality into them that they help enhance the story further as good acting should be doing. The way Pixar handles its characters in this movie is also worth noting. For example, even though Sid is having fun destroying toys and is considered evil by the toys, they don't necessarily make him the main villain. In other words, the characters created here aren't exactly clear cut heroes and villains, but they're simply individuals with different personalities. Woody isn't a bad guy because he technically gets Buzz and himself into trouble, he's simply afraid of being forgotten by Andy. That aspect about Woody makes us relate to him even more since we do learn from the mistakes that Woody makes over this misunderstanding. Buzz Lightyear makes for an enjoyable fish-out-of-water type character in that he strongly believes he's the real Buzz Lightyear to the point that being told that he's actually a toy would be nonsense in his mind. In other words, Pixar cares a great deal about its story and characters here. As you can tell, Toy Story is simply much more than an innovative American film with its groundbreaking animation or even an entertaining family film. It's a film about characters that I'm sure most of us can relate to or identify with. It's a film for everybody to cherish for different reasons whether it be the animation, the humor, the story or the characters. I'll argue that it's still the finest film Pixar's produced yet. In a pinch, Toy Story is a film you should check out immediately if you haven't already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stonedouttamymind
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has something for everyone in the family. It is funny, has action, has a life story, and the characters will touch your heart. These are not just toys, this is a friendship, siblings, relationship or just a way of thinking sometimes. It is a real story on so many levels. It is a heart-warming story about a child and his toys and the relationships between the toys. In Toy Story, the two main characters are Buzz and Woody. At first Buzz and Woody can not stand each other and the two of them fight for the love of their owner Andy. Throughout the story these two show that fighting, arguing, and not getting along will get you no where in life and finally come together to help each other get back to their owner so that they can get back to their home. After all the trials and tribunals these two go through they become the best of friends and go on for two more movies to be a heroic team.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Andy is a young boy that has to give up his childhood toys. But the toys won't accept that they figure out a way to get back to Andy and stay with him.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nickiastar16
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was my favorite movie growing up. It shows what a kids toys would do if they had to be given up and could really talk. Andy is a sweet kid and he wants to keep his favorite toy but can't and I don't remember why. But all in all it is an amazing movie with a great story line. Andy would not give up his toys without a reason. They are in ways his best friends. He loves the toys as much as they love him but some how or another they get separated and the toys won't accept that. They do everything they can to get back to their best friend and don't give up till they get back to Andy. And is so happy when he gets his toys back and he tries his hardest not to lose them again. It is like losing your best friend because they move across the country.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Siddartha RO
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amazing! I have just seen Toy Story. The first one. For the first time. And it's like I'm seeing it back in the days before Toy Story 2 got out on the big screen. The only thing I wouldn't have known was the future story of Apple Inc. This is a wonderful one hour advertisement where you can see branded toys. The only thing that is original in this one hour waste is the way Steve Jobs' employees created a toy universe. It was so yesterday to create a new line of cheap plastics than do some silly adventure. It was called an adventure so people won't have any issue leaving the children alone for one or two hours of advertisements. It sounds so much more educative to have cartoon adventure instead of having cartoon characters selling you stuff. And, instead of a real actor, the cartoon has precisely zero morals: it can sell plutonium to a 5 year old or to some radical terrorist group without blinking. Unless the art director thinks the blink would raise the quantity at least 10 percent. Now about the creative part. Steve Jobs' employees never bothered to create something like say Hanna-Barbera. They just pushed older toys into this new advertisement. And here's where the creativity ends. What's even better is the world imagined. A world where children are isolated. Where they depend on their branded toys. And watch out for the bad kid! He is real creative. But the toys are working together to bring back what the lower case 'c' in a circle meant: a toy identical with million others on the shelves. Oh! And don't forget! A good kid would preserve all the junk: large useless wasteful boxes with advertisements for the whole line of plastic somethings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Toy Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - B This was a good movie as it has a fun story, good characters, and is entertaining for kids and some adults. The film shows us the life of toys at a little kids house and how they all do their own little things behind our backs. Then a new toy, the new spaceman comes and Woody, the leader of the crew, feels like he's being replaced. The conflict is this space ranger thinking he is a real one and not a toy and Woody trying to show him who he really is and trying to still be Andy's favorite. The film is cute with Woody and Buzz as great characters. The score is good, but not the whole story is impressive. I liked it when at home and not running around town as it seemed unreal. I thought the neighbor kid was stupid to have but the animation was incredible. A good family film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
