<filme>
 <id>
  1000
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110353
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Rapidinho no Gatilho
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Lightning Jack Kane is an Australian outlaw in the wild west. During a bungled bank robbery he picks up mute Ben Doyle as a hostage. The two become good friends, with Jack teaching Ben how ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Lightning Jack Kane is an Australian outlaw in the wild west. During a bungled bank robbery he picks up mute Ben Doyle as a hostage. The two become good friends, with Jack teaching Ben how to rob banks, while they plan Jack's last heist.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Western
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   bank robbery
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   outlaw
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   street shootout
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   australian western
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   gunfighter
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Simon Wincer
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Paul Hogan
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Paul Hogan
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Cuba Gooding Jr.
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Beverly D'Angelo
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Thank goodness western-comedies are a rare thing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are tons of comedies made every year. Not too many of them are about the old west It's also not a mix that really ever works out, without becoming a spoof of the genre and use all of its formulaic elements. The story seems to lack a clear purpose. It's hard to say what the movie is really about and were its heading to. One top of that, things just don't ever flow well in the movie. Everything seems to happen suddenly and without a reason for the rest of the story. On its comical level its also a rather weak one. For a comedy it surely has some few real laughs. It's one of those comedies that keeps you waiting for a punch-line that just never comes. On top of that the situations in this movie just aren't humorous. Guess they thought that the movie would already be strong and funny enough by making it a buddy-flick, about an old bandit and a mute bandit-wannabe. Paul Hogan isn't too bad in this movie, although he was clearly far too old for his role at the time. He provides the movie with its best comical moments and some good funny dialog. The Cuba Gooding Jr. character is a bit of a weird one. He's a mute who works at a store and he obviously feel that he is above the simple town-folk and then for some unexplained reasons decides to become a bandit and team-up with, the obviously incapable, bandit Lightning Jack Kane. It also makes you wonder what's the challenging thing for a character to play a mute character. Cuba Gooding Jr. really isn't a bad actors but he too often appears in such weak movies and uninteresting comical roles, that it makes you wonder why he keeps doing it. Guess that he just has fun playing in these type of movies. I'm happy that at least someone had fun. Pat Hingle is also in this movie, in a typical Pat Hingle role. Too bad that they didn't gave his character more screen time, though they potentially really could had done that. The movie is rather good looking and it doesn't look like some cheap attempt. The costume were especially nice. The musical score on the other hand didn't seemed fitting. It's one of those simplistic scores that sound as if it was completed months before the movie finished shooting and therefor doesn't fit or add anything to the images. Has its moments but overall a below average and totally uninteresting comedy attempt. 5/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilorious, Paul Hogan
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PatMan99
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I watched this movie a little while ago , and I am only now getting around to writing a comment on it. I never use to be that big on Paul Hogan, I never liked him all that much to be honest. But not after watching this. This movie was funny say the least, And when I first pop ed in the movie I was thinking that it was going to be some old movie that was just thrown out there in hopes of having a little money. But Honsitly I was surprised , it was enjoyable, and it wasn't boring. I also liked the idea that Cuba Gooding Jr's Character, wasn't able to speak, and how Lighting Jack wasn't able to read without his glasses , but how he tried to hide it from everyone. For anyone who hasn't seen this movie, and they like a good comedy, or Paul Hogan for that matter. What are you waiting for....? Go rent it ! If Anyone has any questions or anything like that my email is pguiney_@hotmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An amalgamation of misfires and stupid ideas packaged into a "Croc Dundee"-type "comedy".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MovieAddict2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Paul Hogan used to be quite funny, but he wore his whole "naive Aussie" shtick into the ground after the first "Crocodile Dundee" came out -- the first was an utter disaster and the third (and worst), which came out long after everything had forgotten about the series, was downright hideous and one of the worst examples of a cash-in I've ever witnessed. Hogan's attempts at crossing over into the American movie-making market continued with this lame-brain cowboy farce co-starring a mute Cuba Gooding, Jr. (who I once found funny, and now find annoying and as lame as this movie). Beverly D'Angelo is wasted as the "clean-as-white-bread-whore-with-a-heart-of-gold" - stick to the "Vacation" movies, Bev! Honestly, this isn't as bad as I had expected (it used to have a 3.6/10 rating on IMDb and was on the "low 100" - its rating has now risen considerably over the past few years) but it's still extremely poor by almost any standards and I think I smiled once, chuckled once or twice, and laughed zero times. It's not funny at all, and even as a lazy Sunday afternoon flick it barely delivers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Continuous Thunder, But No Real Storm.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tfrizzell
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funny little time burner has Paul Hogan starring as an Australian outlaw in the U.S. old west. A robbery leads to him kidnapping a young black mute man (Cuba Gooding, Jr.). They become the strangest of friends and have the wildest adventures as they try to become known criminals in a time and place that just does not seem to care about them. High-class prostitutes Beverly D'Angelo and Kamala Lopez-Dawson are also along as the duo's love interests. The film uses its gimmick well early, but then starts to drag as it hits its latter acts. Hogan and Gooding make a surprisingly impressive team, but really they were not given enough material to run with. The rest of the cast is touch and go as once again Hogan is left to carry a production and he is only minimally successfully. 2.5 out of 5 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Average film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Madelle
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lightning Jack is an average Western Comedy that has a few laughs. It though a lot of the well known and established formulas and is neither better nor worse, than a lot of other comedies out there. Paul Hogan stars as Jack Kane a veteran outlaw who finds himself part of a dying breed an unable to get a decent headline. Cuba Gooding Jr. stars as the mute clerk Ben Doyle who wants to join up with Kane and become an outlaw. The acting is average. Hogan seems to run on much of his routine from Crocodile Dundee. Some of the time though he seems to have trouble delivering his lines convincingly. Cuba Gooding Jr. is amusing as the mute Doyle but occasionally overacted to the point where it made me cringe. The chemistry between the two isn't bad, but it isn't great either. Much like the film itself. There's nothing noteworthy about the direction or cinematography. The story moves along alright, but the script is mediocre and gives us a few completely unnecessary scenes. There is rarely any musical score to take note of, and what little there is, is average stuff to enhance the comedic elements. The film is not a complete waste of time. Some of the jokes do hit their mark, and Hogan has charm. There are several better Western comedies out there though, such as Maverick, but if you're looking for some mild entertainment some rainy day, Lightning Jack can prove to be entertaining enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An underrated Western Comedy Gem.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    btkfan
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It may have received some scathing reviews, but overall, Lightning Jack is DAMN funny movie. Paul Hogan's stiff acting is an asset here, Cuba Gooding Jr steals the show hilariously, without saying a single word. I dare anyone to not laugh when Doyle(Gooding Jr) shoots himself in the foot. Far from flawless, but overall, if you dont take it seriously, fun to watch. 6.5 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A real hoot!SPOILER
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rainbow4142000
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The idea that Cuba Gooding Jr.doesn't say a single word in the whole movie is good enough,and quite honestly I think he stole the movie, I saw it for the first time on USA Wed. afternoon.......smileyfish says hello from oHIo......... :-){
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Memorable and enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RayHandley (ray@handley.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The humor is just as fresh today as it was when I first saw it several years ago. Goodings shows a depth of talent that this viewer really appreciates. His expressions are nearly as plastic as Jim Carrey's and spontaneous enough to steal the show without any lines.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Alright for a raining Sunday
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pimpin` Critic 69
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film isn't good but it isn't bad either. It's just a normal movie with some nice jokes in it. The characters are lovable, the performances are good, and it has it's share of funny scenes. Not bad for a raining Sunday. 2 1/2(**1/2)out of 4(****)stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    lacking in freshness but watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Special-K88
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lightning Jack Kane (Hogan) is an elusive but aging Australian outlaw living in the Old West who doesn't get the respect he feels he deserves. He contemplates retirement, but before that can happen he has one final wish to make major headlines. When a bank robbery goes awry, he takes a mute store clerk (Gooding) hostage, but they unexpectedly bond, develop a genuine friendship, then try to help each other out by forming an unlikely partnership to try and pull off a big score that will attract the necessary attention. The two leads make a surprisingly engaging team, and there are some enjoyable moments, but the whole thing is familiar and obvious. **&frac12;
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Thank goodness western-comedies are a rare thing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are tons of comedies made every year. Not too many of them are about the old west It's also not a mix that really ever works out, without becoming a spoof of the genre and use all of its formulaic elements. The story seems to lack a clear purpose. It's hard to say what the movie is really about and were its heading to. One top of that, things just don't ever flow well in the movie. Everything seems to happen suddenly and without a reason for the rest of the story. On its comical level its also a rather weak one. For a comedy it surely has some few real laughs. It's one of those comedies that keeps you waiting for a punch-line that just never comes. On top of that the situations in this movie just aren't humorous. Guess they thought that the movie would already be strong and funny enough by making it a buddy-flick, about an old bandit and a mute bandit-wannabe. Paul Hogan isn't too bad in this movie, although he was clearly far too old for his role at the time. He provides the movie with its best comical moments and some good funny dialog. The Cuba Gooding Jr. character is a bit of a weird one. He's a mute who works at a store and he obviously feel that he is above the simple town-folk and then for some unexplained reasons decides to become a bandit and team-up with, the obviously incapable, bandit Lightning Jack Kane. It also makes you wonder what's the challenging thing for a character to play a mute character. Cuba Gooding Jr. really isn't a bad actors but he too often appears in such weak movies and uninteresting comical roles, that it makes you wonder why he keeps doing it. Guess that he just has fun playing in these type of movies. I'm happy that at least someone had fun. Pat Hingle is also in this movie, in a typical Pat Hingle role. Too bad that they didn't gave his character more screen time, though they potentially really could had done that. The movie is rather good looking and it doesn't look like some cheap attempt. The costume were especially nice. The musical score on the other hand didn't seemed fitting. It's one of those simplistic scores that sound as if it was completed months before the movie finished shooting and therefor doesn't fit or add anything to the images. Has its moments but overall a below average and totally uninteresting comedy attempt. 5/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilorious, Paul Hogan
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PatMan99
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I watched this movie a little while ago , and I am only now getting around to writing a comment on it. I never use to be that big on Paul Hogan, I never liked him all that much to be honest. But not after watching this. This movie was funny say the least, And when I first pop ed in the movie I was thinking that it was going to be some old movie that was just thrown out there in hopes of having a little money. But Honsitly I was surprised , it was enjoyable, and it wasn't boring. I also liked the idea that Cuba Gooding Jr's Character, wasn't able to speak, and how Lighting Jack wasn't able to read without his glasses , but how he tried to hide it from everyone. For anyone who hasn't seen this movie, and they like a good comedy, or Paul Hogan for that matter. What are you waiting for....? Go rent it ! If Anyone has any questions or anything like that my email is pguiney_@hotmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An amalgamation of misfires and stupid ideas packaged into a "Croc Dundee"-type "comedy".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MovieAddict2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Paul Hogan used to be quite funny, but he wore his whole "naive Aussie" shtick into the ground after the first "Crocodile Dundee" came out -- the first was an utter disaster and the third (and worst), which came out long after everything had forgotten about the series, was downright hideous and one of the worst examples of a cash-in I've ever witnessed. Hogan's attempts at crossing over into the American movie-making market continued with this lame-brain cowboy farce co-starring a mute Cuba Gooding, Jr. (who I once found funny, and now find annoying and as lame as this movie). Beverly D'Angelo is wasted as the "clean-as-white-bread-whore-with-a-heart-of-gold" - stick to the "Vacation" movies, Bev! Honestly, this isn't as bad as I had expected (it used to have a 3.6/10 rating on IMDb and was on the "low 100" - its rating has now risen considerably over the past few years) but it's still extremely poor by almost any standards and I think I smiled once, chuckled once or twice, and laughed zero times. It's not funny at all, and even as a lazy Sunday afternoon flick it barely delivers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Continuous Thunder, But No Real Storm.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tfrizzell
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funny little time burner has Paul Hogan starring as an Australian outlaw in the U.S. old west. A robbery leads to him kidnapping a young black mute man (Cuba Gooding, Jr.). They become the strangest of friends and have the wildest adventures as they try to become known criminals in a time and place that just does not seem to care about them. High-class prostitutes Beverly D'Angelo and Kamala Lopez-Dawson are also along as the duo's love interests. The film uses its gimmick well early, but then starts to drag as it hits its latter acts. Hogan and Gooding make a surprisingly impressive team, but really they were not given enough material to run with. The rest of the cast is touch and go as once again Hogan is left to carry a production and he is only minimally successfully. 2.5 out of 5 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Average film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Madelle
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lightning Jack is an average Western Comedy that has a few laughs. It though a lot of the well known and established formulas and is neither better nor worse, than a lot of other comedies out there. Paul Hogan stars as Jack Kane a veteran outlaw who finds himself part of a dying breed an unable to get a decent headline. Cuba Gooding Jr. stars as the mute clerk Ben Doyle who wants to join up with Kane and become an outlaw. The acting is average. Hogan seems to run on much of his routine from Crocodile Dundee. Some of the time though he seems to have trouble delivering his lines convincingly. Cuba Gooding Jr. is amusing as the mute Doyle but occasionally overacted to the point where it made me cringe. The chemistry between the two isn't bad, but it isn't great either. Much like the film itself. There's nothing noteworthy about the direction or cinematography. The story moves along alright, but the script is mediocre and gives us a few completely unnecessary scenes. There is rarely any musical score to take note of, and what little there is, is average stuff to enhance the comedic elements. The film is not a complete waste of time. Some of the jokes do hit their mark, and Hogan has charm. There are several better Western comedies out there though, such as Maverick, but if you're looking for some mild entertainment some rainy day, Lightning Jack can prove to be entertaining enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An underrated Western Comedy Gem.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    btkfan
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It may have received some scathing reviews, but overall, Lightning Jack is DAMN funny movie. Paul Hogan's stiff acting is an asset here, Cuba Gooding Jr steals the show hilariously, without saying a single word. I dare anyone to not laugh when Doyle(Gooding Jr) shoots himself in the foot. Far from flawless, but overall, if you dont take it seriously, fun to watch. 6.5 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A real hoot!SPOILER
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rainbow4142000
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The idea that Cuba Gooding Jr.doesn't say a single word in the whole movie is good enough,and quite honestly I think he stole the movie, I saw it for the first time on USA Wed. afternoon.......smileyfish says hello from oHIo......... :-){
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Memorable and enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RayHandley (ray@handley.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The humor is just as fresh today as it was when I first saw it several years ago. Goodings shows a depth of talent that this viewer really appreciates. His expressions are nearly as plastic as Jim Carrey's and spontaneous enough to steal the show without any lines.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Alright for a raining Sunday
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pimpin` Critic 69
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film isn't good but it isn't bad either. It's just a normal movie with some nice jokes in it. The characters are lovable, the performances are good, and it has it's share of funny scenes. Not bad for a raining Sunday. 2 1/2(**1/2)out of 4(****)stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    lacking in freshness but watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Special-K88
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lightning Jack Kane (Hogan) is an elusive but aging Australian outlaw living in the Old West who doesn't get the respect he feels he deserves. He contemplates retirement, but before that can happen he has one final wish to make major headlines. When a bank robbery goes awry, he takes a mute store clerk (Gooding) hostage, but they unexpectedly bond, develop a genuine friendship, then try to help each other out by forming an unlikely partnership to try and pull off a big score that will attract the necessary attention. The two leads make a surprisingly engaging team, and there are some enjoyable moments, but the whole thing is familiar and obvious. **&frac12;
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
