<filme>
 <id>
  1005
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0101765
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1991
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Dupla Vida de V&eacute;ronique
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Weronika lives in Poland. V&eacute;ronique lives in Paris. They don't know each other. Weronika gets a place in a music school, works hard, but collapses and dies on her first performance. At this... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Weronika lives in Poland. V&eacute;ronique lives in Paris. They don't know each other. Weronika gets a place in a music school, works hard, but collapses and dies on her first performance. At this point, V&eacute;ronique's life seems to take a turn and she decides not to be a singer...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Music
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   singer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   marionette
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   railwayman
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   avant garde
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   twins
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Krzysztof Kieslowski
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Krzysztof Kieslowski
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Krzysztof Piesiewicz
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Ir&egrave;ne Jacob
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Wladyslaw Kowalski
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Halina Gryglaszewska
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It has an effect for everybody in some way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Harsanyi
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film just inspired me to watch more older films. In the summer i was in a Christian camp where they showed the main scene (for me it is) when Alexandre Fabbri is playing with the marionette ballerina. When I arrived home I immediately started searching for this film and finally i found it! It took me 3 days to watch it. This became my favorite film of all my life. There are scenes and quotes that mean so much to me. I feel I am not the only one with this feeling because as I can see, there are events that are alternative, and has effects that are different for you and your friends either.What is the most interesting thing what i've ever seen/heard? There is only one music in the film and makes you happy or sad depending on the scene. The cameraman's work is excellent too! :) I absolutely would nominate this for Golden Globe of all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Condemned to death
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    randomchoice
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I hated this movie while watching it.After much debating with myself and a friend I have come to the conclusion that this movie is about death. While I still have no sympathy for anyone or anything in the movie, I think the movie is nevertheless a lot more coherent than I initially thought, and for this - and also for the excellent filmography - I am giving it an 8/10. (1) A friend of mine suggested this movie is about the various possibilities of existence which cannot be realized simultaneously in real life. I felt this wasn't right but I didn't have another interpretation to offer. But now I do. Let's see what Weronika and Veronique are all about: (a) Similarities They are both sickly creatures. They have a father, they don't have a mother. They are both engaged with music. They know and interact with a series of characters of no consequence (the aunt, the colleague from school, etc.) They both appear in a love relationship where their lovers are more involved than themselves. They both dismiss those lovers. They both have a plastic (?) ball and are fascinated by what the world looks like as reflected through it. They both watch an old woman through the window. They both seem to drift without touching the world around them. They both see their doppelg&auml;nger. (b) Differences Weronika lives in Poland. She is not independent (lives with her dad / aunt). She seems young and inexperienced. She moves to another city for the sake of her aunt. Feels that she is not alone in the world. She dies singing. Veronique lives in France. She is financially independent (she lives on her own, has her own job). She seems more mature, and already anchored in music (she has a music teacher, she teaches music). She quits her music lessons although her teacher thinks she has a great talent. She feels alone in the world. She falls in love (Weronika never seems in love; talking to her aunt, she seems excited to have slept with that guy but abandons him). She accepts the game played on her by the anonymous stalker. She becomes acquainted with her puppeteer. She sees her doppelg&auml;nger, in the end. She begins to see how he may be the one manipulating her. Veronique's story begins as Weronika dies. This chronological details is supported by the photo / negative from Poland, which is the moment when the stories of the two girls become anchored in reality and aligned in a particular chronological order. So far, what does this movie seem to be about? Let's say that Veronique's first apparition and inexplicable grief is a premonition of what might happen to her if she continues taking music lessons / trying to make a career in music. This premonition leads her to abandon her existential possibility of realizing her potential through music. Having abandoned this possibility (I don't feel like it should be called her 'ideal' - Veronique doesn't really seem to have a passion, a dream, an ideal!), she somehow loses her path. Is she the ballerina who breaks her leg and then turns into a butterfly, as the ballerina in the puppeteer's story? This seems rather to be Weronika's story. Veronique refuses to break her leg, so there's no question of her turning into a butterfly. Is, then, the movie about a character with a talent for music to whom her talent is fatal, and for whom abandoning the talent would lead to perdition all the same? If yes, then the movie does make sense, although I'm still not sure about the puppeteer. It's as if the puppeteer had somehow condemned both these girls to death, and loves them when they have accepted their sentence. (Antek too could be some kind of a puppeteer: he tells Weronika he loves her only after she had come to the city and was already pursuing her talent! Likewise, Alexandre too tells Veronique he loves her only after she had accepted to enter the game of the anonymous caller.) If this death sentence were the true meaning of the movie, then it also would be easier to understand why Veronique has two lovers (the first, unnamed one, and then, Alexandre), and Weronika only one: Veronique quits music and drives away her first lover, and this could be a rejection of dying for her talent. Her condemnation to death is, however, still there: having failed to kill her through music, the puppeteer steps in himself. The weird thing about this interpretation is that, although both girls do seem to have some relation to music, neither of them gives the impression that music is the biggest thing in their lives. Music is just something they happen to be good at, good enough to be remarked and regretted when they cannot / refuse to pursue it. For the rest, these girls look like lambs brought to the slaughterhouse. For example, when Weronika's aunt asks her how her audition had gone, Weronika answers something like (I don't remember the exact wording): it went TOO well. Apathetic... (2) My conclusion about the movie After lots of thinking, here's, then, my conclusion regarding what this movie is about: I think it is about condemnation to death, regardless of other life details. This idea seems supported by that episode where Veronique holds the shoestring across the graph paper in a straight line over her recent EKG graph. The straight line of an EKG = death. Everything else in the movie is ballast. The doppelg&auml;nger thing is rather a red herring: it muddles the waters without any pay-off, really. Now I understand why the music is throughout so sad / sinister. Also, why there is so much ballast, so many gestures of no consequence. So many attempts at a plot but with no actual realization. The characters are doomed, and that's all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Cinematic, cinematographic, psychological and lyrical..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Polish screenwriter and director Krzysztof Kieslowski's ninth feature film which he co-wrote with Polish screenwriter Krzysztof Piesiewicz, premiered In competition at the 44th Cannes International Film Festival in 1991, was shot on location in France and Poland and is a France-Poland-Norway co-production which was produced by producer Leonardo De La Fuente. It tells the story about and educated singer and pianist named Weronika who lives in an apartment in Poland and who is in a relationship with a man named Antek. After experiencing a feeling of not being alone which she is instigated to act upon, Weronika travels to Krakow where her aunt lives and when she gets there she notices a woman whom she has never seen before and who bears a striking resemblance to herself. Distinctly and subtly directed by Polish filmmaker Krzysztof Kieslowski, this finely tuned fictional tale which is narrated mostly from the two main character's point of view, draws a virtuous portrayal of the life of a Polish woman named Weronika and a French woman named Veroniqu&eacute; who are identical and who one day coincidentally or determined by destiny crosses paths. While notable for it's naturalistic and atmospheric milieu depictions, distinct production design by production designer Patrice Mercier, cinematography by polish cinematographer Slawomir Idziak, costume design by costume designers Laurence Brignon, Claudy Fellous and Elzbieta Radke, fine editing by French film editor Jacques Witta and use of colors and light, this character-driven and narrative-driven story where the director could focus more on the cinematic aspects of his film and less on the political which was characteristic in many of his previous productions due to the political situation in his country, depicts two interrelated and empathic studies of character and contains a great score by Polish composer Zbigniew Preisner. This dramatic, literary, somewhat surreal, romantic and humanistic drama from the early 1990s about identity and faith which is the last feature film Krzysztof Kieslowski made before ending his career with the Three Colours trilogy which consisted of "Blue" (1993), "White" (1994) and "Red" (1994) and which is set in the capital city of France and the capital city of Poland in the early 1990s and where a music teacher for children named Veroniqu&eacute; who lives in France experiences a feeling of being alone, is impelled and reinforced by it's brilliant narrative structure, substantial character development, subtle continuity, interrelated stories, endearing characters, poetic scenes and the memorable acting performance by French actress Ir&egrave;ne Jacob. A cinematic, cinematographic, psychological and lyrical mystery which gained, among numerous other awards, the FIPRESCI Prize Krzysztof Kieslowski, the Prize of the Ecumenical Jury and the award for Best Actress Ir&egrave;ne Jacob at the 44th Cannes Film Festival in 1991.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    levelllll5
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "All my life I've felt like I was here and somewhere else at the same time" Weronika lives in Poland. She lost her mother as a kid. She has a gift for music, and especially singing. She likes to apply a golden ring around her eye. She runs a lot. She is always breathless because of a heart defect that she is unaware of. She is searching for love. Veronique lives in France. She lost her mother as a kid. She has a gift for music, and she teaches it to young children. She likes to apply a golden ring around her eye. She runs a lot. She is always breathless because of a heart defect that has just been found out. She is searching for love. Weronika sees V&eacute;ronique in Krakow, the city she lives in. She stops in the middle of a place crowded with people demonstrating and riot squads. Her alter ego is getting on a bus which will take her back to France. Before the bus leaves, V&eacute;ronique has time to take pictures of the place and of Weronika, but she does not see her. During the first half-hour of the film, the subjective shots which represent Weronika's vision are unsteady, the fisheye angle twists the perspectives, until Weronika herself collapses, on the stage, among the music instruments and in front of the audience, in the middle of a song. After Weronika's death, we follow V&eacute;ronique. She is making love with a man, and, right after it, she feels an immense sadness. She says to her lover &laquo; It's as if I were grieving &raquo; but she is unable to explain why. She decides to give up on the concert she was preparing, the same concert, we can imagine, during which Weronika died. V&eacute;ronique follows her intuition, and Weronika's death prevents her from dying herself. In the school where V&eacute;ronique teaches, a man manipulates puppets for the children. He makes the puppet die and become a sort of angel. Later on, V&eacute;tonique receives an anonymous phone call, then she gets a lace in the mail, and then an audio tape thanks to which she finds the place from where the anonymous man sends his objects to her. She finds him in a bar in the Gare Saint Lazare in Paris. She recognizes the puppeteer. In a hotel, after they have made love, and confessed their love, she empties her purse on the bed because he wants to know her better. He looks at the photos she took during her trip in Eastern Europe. He says that she is pretty on the pictures. She notices Weronika for the first time. She starts to cry. Weeks, maybe months later, she wakes up in the middle of the night and finds her lover making a second puppet of herself. She asks why he made two puppets of her, and he says that it is because they get damaged. She manipulates one puppet, while the other is lying motionless. The puppeteer reads to her the first version of a tale he is writing about two women on two different continents who are in fact two versions of the same person. This focus on the puppets reminded me of an essay written by Furio Jesi on Rilke's poetry. Jesi writes: the doll, in its form, tragically announces to men that it is her, not them, who will survive in the Infinite. &raquo;. To me, the puppets are a reminder of the fate that awaits V&eacute;ronique as well, that is death. The two women will disappear in death but the two puppets will remain. There is a very important dreamlike dimension in the film which features a dwarf who is also a lawyer, an old exhibitionnist, conversations of secondary characters with no beginning and no end, a subjective shot of the dead Weronika being buried. The film is also very poetic. I think of two shots in particular: the two versions of the old lady crossing the screen, and the image of the old church reflected backwards in a plastic ball. To appreciate this film, you need to get rid of the need to understand and analyze everything, and accept the absurd side of reality. My sister saw the film with me, and at one point she said: &laquo; there is something in this film that is us. &raquo; That &laquo; something &raquo; can be defined as the atmosphere, the setting, the green and red colors. the light. Kieslowski's movie addresses that part of our brain that is the center of our emotions, of our sensations, and of the memories of those sensations. It remains with us like an old dream that we had forgotten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Double Life of V&eacute;ronique
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Krzysztof Kieslowski (Dekalog: The Ten Commandments, Three Colours: Blue), I read a little about this film before watching it, and obviously it was in the book 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die, so I was hoping it was going to be a deserving placement. Basically the story starts in Poland with the life of young Polish woman Weronika (Ir&egrave;ne Jacob) who has a keen ambition to become a singer, and aside caring for her sick Aunt (Halina Gryglaszewska) in Krak&oacute;w, she is prepared to leave most things to achieve this dream, including spending time with her boyfriend Antek (Jerzy Gudejko). She gets noticed by turning up at a concert rehearsal session, impressing the musical director with her beautiful high soprano voice and offered an audition, and eventually she is successful, and she reconnects with Antek who has been following her somewhat, but when she finally gets on stage to enchant an audience with her she sings her parts, but collapses and dies during performance. The story then shifts to Paris where on the same day young French woman V&eacute;ronique (Ir&egrave;ne Jacob), a doppelg&auml;nger who in a sudden moment feels grief and sadness, she teaches music and takes her class to see a musical piece by the same composer who performed with Weronika, conductor Van den Budenmayer (Aleksander Bardini), and in a few instances she hears more of his music playing in places. The next day she tells her father that she is in love, all of the sudden with a man she has never met, after receiving an odd shoelace in a letter envelope she believes it is from a puppeteer she has seen a few times, also a children's book author who in one his stories mentions a shoelace, Alexandre Fabbri (Philippe Volter), and she reads more of his work, and also hears more Budenmayer music, including sounds of a car accident. V&eacute;ronique feels manipulated finding out that it was Alexandre wanting to gain her attention and meet again, she eventually lets him off and they sleep together and make love, and the next morning he finds a photo of Weronika that obviously looks just like V&eacute;ronique, but she denies it is her as he is the one who took the photo. The end of the film sees Alexandre working on a new book, focusing on the lives of two women born on the same day in different cities of the world with a strange connection, obviously based on what he found falling with V&eacute;ronique and finding out about Weronika. Also starring Kalina Jedrusik as Gaudy woman, Wladyslaw Kowalski as Weronika's father, Janusz Sterninski as Lawyer, Sandrine Dumas as Catherine and Louis Ducreux as Teacher. As the two identical women Jacob gives a performance worth watching, but I will be honest and say that I much preferred the first woman more than her second because she has an extraordinary singing voice that goes perfectly with the opera music, the second performance for lacked as much depth, in fact, I found after the first woman's death the rest of the film was a tiny bit slowed down, nevertheless overall it is a worthwhile drama. It was nominated the Golden Globe for Best Foreign Language Film. Good, in my opinion!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Makes You Feel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brtndr
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It makes you feel like you've fallen asleep and entered into someone else's surrealistic dream world. Fortunately, there are two beautiful young women Veronique and Veronicka (both played by Irene Jacobs) who are at the center of that alien dream world you've entered into. And, you are just as engaged in the lives of the two woman as you would be if your own life was passing before your eyes. The two lives of Veronique and Veronicka reflect each other, but are only subconsciously aware of it, which is eerie in its very nature. Two people who have two entirely different lives, obviously destined to never really meet, but unexpectedly spot each other across a crowded court yard one day. The experience briefly hypnotically paralyzes them both as they stare in amazement at the sight of one another. A moment that appears to confirm for both woman what they've always felt, but could never bring themselves to believe until then. This encounter between the two ends as quickly as it accidentally occurred, and they continue on with their separate lives without ever really acknowledging the entire breadth and depth of their shared accidental encounter. However, after the experience neither one of them are the same physically or emotionally again. There is so much going on both visually and emotionally in the film which makes 'The Double Life of Veronique' one of the most worthy films for endless coffee house discussions and analysis. A highly recommended A+ excellent foreign movie that you'll enjoy discussing for hours afterwards with cinema enthusiast. Perhaps, while enjoying a cup of Mocha Espresso with a dollop of milk?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reflections from the looking glass
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Artimidor Federkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here's a kind of movie that helps you think outside the proverbial box: Meet V&eacute;ronique,the French protagonist who chances upon a most unusual face - en passant, in a fleeting moment, like a reminder from another life. The face of the person she sees is her own. Somewhere on Polish plaza, to briefly surface and drown again in the crowd. "La Double vie de V&eacute;ronique" teaches you to appreciate escaping the comfort zone of trusted logic, recognize its pitfalls and see a strange, maybe even absurd fantastic premise in an otherwise realistic picture as a chance to discover something that cannot be named. Sure, Kieslowski pictures are always a combination of beautiful images, evocative music and a strong cerebral component, but "La double vie de V&eacute;ronique" is his most enigmatic, thought provoking work. Various threads are spun by writer and director which appeal to the viewer's imagination, so that they may be connected or respected just the way they are. Or perhaps seen as a whole in the eye of the beholder in front of the screen: Two different lives, one face, strings attached or mere coincidence? Is there fate? Does the demiurge work as puppeteer or are our actions influencing others in a way we would never anticipate? There are no metaphors in my work, Kiesloswki once said. Sounds challenging? Feel free to connect your own dots in this magical adventure of parallelism seen through the looking glass! Just one thing: The purpose of art is not to provide answers and be prescriptive in its implications, be they moral, social, historic or otherwise, but rather to open up new pathways and perspectives and question what we've been used to take for granted. In this respect Kieslowski succeeds indubitably and delivers a dazzling work of art to be looked at. Again and again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ethereal Irene Jacob
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The premise of this film is based on the old legend that we all have a twin somewhere in the world. Weronika is a Polish opera singer who while performing at an outdoor concert, continues to sing in a heavy rainstorm. Afterwards, she meets her boyfriend, Antek, and they get it on. She tells her father that she does not feel alone in the world. She visits her aunt in Krakow and meets a friend at a concert rehearsal. While listening, she sings along and the director is so impressed with her voice that he asks her to audition. While walking down a street during a protest rally, she notices a woman taking photos of the crowd. The lady looks like her twin. Her double gets on a bus which drives away. She passes the audition and the following night, and while singing a solo at a concert, collapses and dies on stage. Her spirit travels over the audience. That same day in Paris, Veronique(Irene Jacob), feels a great sadness for no apparent reason. Later, at her classroom, she leads her students in a classical piece by the same composer that Weronika was performing when she died., Veronique falls in love with a puppeteer and writer named Alexandre and as the couple go through a photo album, he sees a picture which looks like her. Veronique explains that it can't possibly be her, since she took the photo. There is no real ending for Double Life, but Irene Jacob in the dual role, makes it work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spooky-wooky does not a movie make
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xXBoss-EbertXx
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Seinfeld said his show was about "nothing," but it had the contents of the Encyclopedia Britannica compared to this movie. Quelle waste of time sitting through this! It moved at the speed of a glacier and made absolutely no sense at all. To it's credit, La double vie de V&eacute;ronique is FAR from what you'd ever see in an American theatre, but in this case, that might not be a good thing. This film is an exercise in banality compared to the remake, I Know Who Killed Me (2007), a modern day erotic masterpiece. I would also like to add that the picture quality here wasn't that great either. It is just a poor release of this film in almost every area. ...disjointed script bordering on HBO style "erotica", with probably the worse subtitling I have ever seen. The movie ends abruptly like they just simply ran out of film. Avoid this one. For the amount of money the producers spent on this, the movie's quality is terrible. Everything is underlit and murky as if the film was dropped in a swamp prior to being developed, and that's when you're lucky enough to view a scene that's actually in-focus. The sound is poorly dubbed, much of the music is awkward and the editing is god awful. Let's not kid ourselves here, all ye art students, film-school nerds, and other self-loathing "cinema l'arte" snobs: had this exact same movie been released under the banner "directed by Pier Paolo Pasolini" you would have loved it - sorry: CLAIMED to have loved it - and praised it to high heaven, espousing its virtues in long essays, justifying its extreme sex and violence through some b.s. semantic pseudo-intellectual movie-critic-jargon mumbo-jumbo. A corny, historically inaccurate, fairy-tale-like piece of crap like "Gandhi" gets world-wide recognition, while a brutally realistic film about another historical figure, called "Caligula" gets the finger. Go figure. Go on, admit it. No-one will laugh. We promise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Down Memory Lane.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Traversa
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Have you seen, read or heard "The Glass Menagerie" by Tennesse Williams? If you remember, the play is told by the main character in the present time, he tells us about his past life, lost forever, as well as the characters that were essential in his life at that time, "This play is memory" he says. Well, my review for this film is also memory, since I saw it at the time of its premiere and never again. I happened to be listening a program on France culture radio on the Internet and they mentioned this film, it instantly came back to my memory: One of the best films I had ever seen, next to "Tous les matins du monde", "Barry Lyndon", "Tom Jones" and a few others. I should see it again to experience that sometimes disappointing sensation of coming down with a sad feeling of having outgrown an old film that in our memory was fantastic. On the other hand, there are also those old films that when seeing them again after so many years, they are as fresh as ever, as I'm sure is the case with this one. I remember that I was mesmerized at the end of the projection (I saw it at a movie house in Barcelona) and thought at the time that it was a perfect movie, something so rare and unusual to find. So far, and --again-- in my memory, it it one of the best films I have ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It has an effect for everybody in some way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Harsanyi
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film just inspired me to watch more older films. In the summer i was in a Christian camp where they showed the main scene (for me it is) when Alexandre Fabbri is playing with the marionette ballerina. When I arrived home I immediately started searching for this film and finally i found it! It took me 3 days to watch it. This became my favorite film of all my life. There are scenes and quotes that mean so much to me. I feel I am not the only one with this feeling because as I can see, there are events that are alternative, and has effects that are different for you and your friends either.What is the most interesting thing what i've ever seen/heard? There is only one music in the film and makes you happy or sad depending on the scene. The cameraman's work is excellent too! :) I absolutely would nominate this for Golden Globe of all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Condemned to death
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    randomchoice
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I hated this movie while watching it.After much debating with myself and a friend I have come to the conclusion that this movie is about death. While I still have no sympathy for anyone or anything in the movie, I think the movie is nevertheless a lot more coherent than I initially thought, and for this - and also for the excellent filmography - I am giving it an 8/10. (1) A friend of mine suggested this movie is about the various possibilities of existence which cannot be realized simultaneously in real life. I felt this wasn't right but I didn't have another interpretation to offer. But now I do. Let's see what Weronika and Veronique are all about: (a) Similarities They are both sickly creatures. They have a father, they don't have a mother. They are both engaged with music. They know and interact with a series of characters of no consequence (the aunt, the colleague from school, etc.) They both appear in a love relationship where their lovers are more involved than themselves. They both dismiss those lovers. They both have a plastic (?) ball and are fascinated by what the world looks like as reflected through it. They both watch an old woman through the window. They both seem to drift without touching the world around them. They both see their doppelg&auml;nger. (b) Differences Weronika lives in Poland. She is not independent (lives with her dad / aunt). She seems young and inexperienced. She moves to another city for the sake of her aunt. Feels that she is not alone in the world. She dies singing. Veronique lives in France. She is financially independent (she lives on her own, has her own job). She seems more mature, and already anchored in music (she has a music teacher, she teaches music). She quits her music lessons although her teacher thinks she has a great talent. She feels alone in the world. She falls in love (Weronika never seems in love; talking to her aunt, she seems excited to have slept with that guy but abandons him). She accepts the game played on her by the anonymous stalker. She becomes acquainted with her puppeteer. She sees her doppelg&auml;nger, in the end. She begins to see how he may be the one manipulating her. Veronique's story begins as Weronika dies. This chronological details is supported by the photo / negative from Poland, which is the moment when the stories of the two girls become anchored in reality and aligned in a particular chronological order. So far, what does this movie seem to be about? Let's say that Veronique's first apparition and inexplicable grief is a premonition of what might happen to her if she continues taking music lessons / trying to make a career in music. This premonition leads her to abandon her existential possibility of realizing her potential through music. Having abandoned this possibility (I don't feel like it should be called her 'ideal' - Veronique doesn't really seem to have a passion, a dream, an ideal!), she somehow loses her path. Is she the ballerina who breaks her leg and then turns into a butterfly, as the ballerina in the puppeteer's story? This seems rather to be Weronika's story. Veronique refuses to break her leg, so there's no question of her turning into a butterfly. Is, then, the movie about a character with a talent for music to whom her talent is fatal, and for whom abandoning the talent would lead to perdition all the same? If yes, then the movie does make sense, although I'm still not sure about the puppeteer. It's as if the puppeteer had somehow condemned both these girls to death, and loves them when they have accepted their sentence. (Antek too could be some kind of a puppeteer: he tells Weronika he loves her only after she had come to the city and was already pursuing her talent! Likewise, Alexandre too tells Veronique he loves her only after she had accepted to enter the game of the anonymous caller.) If this death sentence were the true meaning of the movie, then it also would be easier to understand why Veronique has two lovers (the first, unnamed one, and then, Alexandre), and Weronika only one: Veronique quits music and drives away her first lover, and this could be a rejection of dying for her talent. Her condemnation to death is, however, still there: having failed to kill her through music, the puppeteer steps in himself. The weird thing about this interpretation is that, although both girls do seem to have some relation to music, neither of them gives the impression that music is the biggest thing in their lives. Music is just something they happen to be good at, good enough to be remarked and regretted when they cannot / refuse to pursue it. For the rest, these girls look like lambs brought to the slaughterhouse. For example, when Weronika's aunt asks her how her audition had gone, Weronika answers something like (I don't remember the exact wording): it went TOO well. Apathetic... (2) My conclusion about the movie After lots of thinking, here's, then, my conclusion regarding what this movie is about: I think it is about condemnation to death, regardless of other life details. This idea seems supported by that episode where Veronique holds the shoestring across the graph paper in a straight line over her recent EKG graph. The straight line of an EKG = death. Everything else in the movie is ballast. The doppelg&auml;nger thing is rather a red herring: it muddles the waters without any pay-off, really. Now I understand why the music is throughout so sad / sinister. Also, why there is so much ballast, so many gestures of no consequence. So many attempts at a plot but with no actual realization. The characters are doomed, and that's all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Cinematic, cinematographic, psychological and lyrical..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Polish screenwriter and director Krzysztof Kieslowski's ninth feature film which he co-wrote with Polish screenwriter Krzysztof Piesiewicz, premiered In competition at the 44th Cannes International Film Festival in 1991, was shot on location in France and Poland and is a France-Poland-Norway co-production which was produced by producer Leonardo De La Fuente. It tells the story about and educated singer and pianist named Weronika who lives in an apartment in Poland and who is in a relationship with a man named Antek. After experiencing a feeling of not being alone which she is instigated to act upon, Weronika travels to Krakow where her aunt lives and when she gets there she notices a woman whom she has never seen before and who bears a striking resemblance to herself. Distinctly and subtly directed by Polish filmmaker Krzysztof Kieslowski, this finely tuned fictional tale which is narrated mostly from the two main character's point of view, draws a virtuous portrayal of the life of a Polish woman named Weronika and a French woman named Veroniqu&eacute; who are identical and who one day coincidentally or determined by destiny crosses paths. While notable for it's naturalistic and atmospheric milieu depictions, distinct production design by production designer Patrice Mercier, cinematography by polish cinematographer Slawomir Idziak, costume design by costume designers Laurence Brignon, Claudy Fellous and Elzbieta Radke, fine editing by French film editor Jacques Witta and use of colors and light, this character-driven and narrative-driven story where the director could focus more on the cinematic aspects of his film and less on the political which was characteristic in many of his previous productions due to the political situation in his country, depicts two interrelated and empathic studies of character and contains a great score by Polish composer Zbigniew Preisner. This dramatic, literary, somewhat surreal, romantic and humanistic drama from the early 1990s about identity and faith which is the last feature film Krzysztof Kieslowski made before ending his career with the Three Colours trilogy which consisted of "Blue" (1993), "White" (1994) and "Red" (1994) and which is set in the capital city of France and the capital city of Poland in the early 1990s and where a music teacher for children named Veroniqu&eacute; who lives in France experiences a feeling of being alone, is impelled and reinforced by it's brilliant narrative structure, substantial character development, subtle continuity, interrelated stories, endearing characters, poetic scenes and the memorable acting performance by French actress Ir&egrave;ne Jacob. A cinematic, cinematographic, psychological and lyrical mystery which gained, among numerous other awards, the FIPRESCI Prize Krzysztof Kieslowski, the Prize of the Ecumenical Jury and the award for Best Actress Ir&egrave;ne Jacob at the 44th Cannes Film Festival in 1991.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    levelllll5
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "All my life I've felt like I was here and somewhere else at the same time" Weronika lives in Poland. She lost her mother as a kid. She has a gift for music, and especially singing. She likes to apply a golden ring around her eye. She runs a lot. She is always breathless because of a heart defect that she is unaware of. She is searching for love. Veronique lives in France. She lost her mother as a kid. She has a gift for music, and she teaches it to young children. She likes to apply a golden ring around her eye. She runs a lot. She is always breathless because of a heart defect that has just been found out. She is searching for love. Weronika sees V&eacute;ronique in Krakow, the city she lives in. She stops in the middle of a place crowded with people demonstrating and riot squads. Her alter ego is getting on a bus which will take her back to France. Before the bus leaves, V&eacute;ronique has time to take pictures of the place and of Weronika, but she does not see her. During the first half-hour of the film, the subjective shots which represent Weronika's vision are unsteady, the fisheye angle twists the perspectives, until Weronika herself collapses, on the stage, among the music instruments and in front of the audience, in the middle of a song. After Weronika's death, we follow V&eacute;ronique. She is making love with a man, and, right after it, she feels an immense sadness. She says to her lover &laquo; It's as if I were grieving &raquo; but she is unable to explain why. She decides to give up on the concert she was preparing, the same concert, we can imagine, during which Weronika died. V&eacute;ronique follows her intuition, and Weronika's death prevents her from dying herself. In the school where V&eacute;ronique teaches, a man manipulates puppets for the children. He makes the puppet die and become a sort of angel. Later on, V&eacute;tonique receives an anonymous phone call, then she gets a lace in the mail, and then an audio tape thanks to which she finds the place from where the anonymous man sends his objects to her. She finds him in a bar in the Gare Saint Lazare in Paris. She recognizes the puppeteer. In a hotel, after they have made love, and confessed their love, she empties her purse on the bed because he wants to know her better. He looks at the photos she took during her trip in Eastern Europe. He says that she is pretty on the pictures. She notices Weronika for the first time. She starts to cry. Weeks, maybe months later, she wakes up in the middle of the night and finds her lover making a second puppet of herself. She asks why he made two puppets of her, and he says that it is because they get damaged. She manipulates one puppet, while the other is lying motionless. The puppeteer reads to her the first version of a tale he is writing about two women on two different continents who are in fact two versions of the same person. This focus on the puppets reminded me of an essay written by Furio Jesi on Rilke's poetry. Jesi writes: the doll, in its form, tragically announces to men that it is her, not them, who will survive in the Infinite. &raquo;. To me, the puppets are a reminder of the fate that awaits V&eacute;ronique as well, that is death. The two women will disappear in death but the two puppets will remain. There is a very important dreamlike dimension in the film which features a dwarf who is also a lawyer, an old exhibitionnist, conversations of secondary characters with no beginning and no end, a subjective shot of the dead Weronika being buried. The film is also very poetic. I think of two shots in particular: the two versions of the old lady crossing the screen, and the image of the old church reflected backwards in a plastic ball. To appreciate this film, you need to get rid of the need to understand and analyze everything, and accept the absurd side of reality. My sister saw the film with me, and at one point she said: &laquo; there is something in this film that is us. &raquo; That &laquo; something &raquo; can be defined as the atmosphere, the setting, the green and red colors. the light. Kieslowski's movie addresses that part of our brain that is the center of our emotions, of our sensations, and of the memories of those sensations. It remains with us like an old dream that we had forgotten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Double Life of V&eacute;ronique
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Krzysztof Kieslowski (Dekalog: The Ten Commandments, Three Colours: Blue), I read a little about this film before watching it, and obviously it was in the book 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die, so I was hoping it was going to be a deserving placement. Basically the story starts in Poland with the life of young Polish woman Weronika (Ir&egrave;ne Jacob) who has a keen ambition to become a singer, and aside caring for her sick Aunt (Halina Gryglaszewska) in Krak&oacute;w, she is prepared to leave most things to achieve this dream, including spending time with her boyfriend Antek (Jerzy Gudejko). She gets noticed by turning up at a concert rehearsal session, impressing the musical director with her beautiful high soprano voice and offered an audition, and eventually she is successful, and she reconnects with Antek who has been following her somewhat, but when she finally gets on stage to enchant an audience with her she sings her parts, but collapses and dies during performance. The story then shifts to Paris where on the same day young French woman V&eacute;ronique (Ir&egrave;ne Jacob), a doppelg&auml;nger who in a sudden moment feels grief and sadness, she teaches music and takes her class to see a musical piece by the same composer who performed with Weronika, conductor Van den Budenmayer (Aleksander Bardini), and in a few instances she hears more of his music playing in places. The next day she tells her father that she is in love, all of the sudden with a man she has never met, after receiving an odd shoelace in a letter envelope she believes it is from a puppeteer she has seen a few times, also a children's book author who in one his stories mentions a shoelace, Alexandre Fabbri (Philippe Volter), and she reads more of his work, and also hears more Budenmayer music, including sounds of a car accident. V&eacute;ronique feels manipulated finding out that it was Alexandre wanting to gain her attention and meet again, she eventually lets him off and they sleep together and make love, and the next morning he finds a photo of Weronika that obviously looks just like V&eacute;ronique, but she denies it is her as he is the one who took the photo. The end of the film sees Alexandre working on a new book, focusing on the lives of two women born on the same day in different cities of the world with a strange connection, obviously based on what he found falling with V&eacute;ronique and finding out about Weronika. Also starring Kalina Jedrusik as Gaudy woman, Wladyslaw Kowalski as Weronika's father, Janusz Sterninski as Lawyer, Sandrine Dumas as Catherine and Louis Ducreux as Teacher. As the two identical women Jacob gives a performance worth watching, but I will be honest and say that I much preferred the first woman more than her second because she has an extraordinary singing voice that goes perfectly with the opera music, the second performance for lacked as much depth, in fact, I found after the first woman's death the rest of the film was a tiny bit slowed down, nevertheless overall it is a worthwhile drama. It was nominated the Golden Globe for Best Foreign Language Film. Good, in my opinion!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Makes You Feel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brtndr
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It makes you feel like you've fallen asleep and entered into someone else's surrealistic dream world. Fortunately, there are two beautiful young women Veronique and Veronicka (both played by Irene Jacobs) who are at the center of that alien dream world you've entered into. And, you are just as engaged in the lives of the two woman as you would be if your own life was passing before your eyes. The two lives of Veronique and Veronicka reflect each other, but are only subconsciously aware of it, which is eerie in its very nature. Two people who have two entirely different lives, obviously destined to never really meet, but unexpectedly spot each other across a crowded court yard one day. The experience briefly hypnotically paralyzes them both as they stare in amazement at the sight of one another. A moment that appears to confirm for both woman what they've always felt, but could never bring themselves to believe until then. This encounter between the two ends as quickly as it accidentally occurred, and they continue on with their separate lives without ever really acknowledging the entire breadth and depth of their shared accidental encounter. However, after the experience neither one of them are the same physically or emotionally again. There is so much going on both visually and emotionally in the film which makes 'The Double Life of Veronique' one of the most worthy films for endless coffee house discussions and analysis. A highly recommended A+ excellent foreign movie that you'll enjoy discussing for hours afterwards with cinema enthusiast. Perhaps, while enjoying a cup of Mocha Espresso with a dollop of milk?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reflections from the looking glass
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Artimidor Federkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here's a kind of movie that helps you think outside the proverbial box: Meet V&eacute;ronique,the French protagonist who chances upon a most unusual face - en passant, in a fleeting moment, like a reminder from another life. The face of the person she sees is her own. Somewhere on Polish plaza, to briefly surface and drown again in the crowd. "La Double vie de V&eacute;ronique" teaches you to appreciate escaping the comfort zone of trusted logic, recognize its pitfalls and see a strange, maybe even absurd fantastic premise in an otherwise realistic picture as a chance to discover something that cannot be named. Sure, Kieslowski pictures are always a combination of beautiful images, evocative music and a strong cerebral component, but "La double vie de V&eacute;ronique" is his most enigmatic, thought provoking work. Various threads are spun by writer and director which appeal to the viewer's imagination, so that they may be connected or respected just the way they are. Or perhaps seen as a whole in the eye of the beholder in front of the screen: Two different lives, one face, strings attached or mere coincidence? Is there fate? Does the demiurge work as puppeteer or are our actions influencing others in a way we would never anticipate? There are no metaphors in my work, Kiesloswki once said. Sounds challenging? Feel free to connect your own dots in this magical adventure of parallelism seen through the looking glass! Just one thing: The purpose of art is not to provide answers and be prescriptive in its implications, be they moral, social, historic or otherwise, but rather to open up new pathways and perspectives and question what we've been used to take for granted. In this respect Kieslowski succeeds indubitably and delivers a dazzling work of art to be looked at. Again and again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ethereal Irene Jacob
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The premise of this film is based on the old legend that we all have a twin somewhere in the world. Weronika is a Polish opera singer who while performing at an outdoor concert, continues to sing in a heavy rainstorm. Afterwards, she meets her boyfriend, Antek, and they get it on. She tells her father that she does not feel alone in the world. She visits her aunt in Krakow and meets a friend at a concert rehearsal. While listening, she sings along and the director is so impressed with her voice that he asks her to audition. While walking down a street during a protest rally, she notices a woman taking photos of the crowd. The lady looks like her twin. Her double gets on a bus which drives away. She passes the audition and the following night, and while singing a solo at a concert, collapses and dies on stage. Her spirit travels over the audience. That same day in Paris, Veronique(Irene Jacob), feels a great sadness for no apparent reason. Later, at her classroom, she leads her students in a classical piece by the same composer that Weronika was performing when she died., Veronique falls in love with a puppeteer and writer named Alexandre and as the couple go through a photo album, he sees a picture which looks like her. Veronique explains that it can't possibly be her, since she took the photo. There is no real ending for Double Life, but Irene Jacob in the dual role, makes it work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spooky-wooky does not a movie make
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xXBoss-EbertXx
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Seinfeld said his show was about "nothing," but it had the contents of the Encyclopedia Britannica compared to this movie. Quelle waste of time sitting through this! It moved at the speed of a glacier and made absolutely no sense at all. To it's credit, La double vie de V&eacute;ronique is FAR from what you'd ever see in an American theatre, but in this case, that might not be a good thing. This film is an exercise in banality compared to the remake, I Know Who Killed Me (2007), a modern day erotic masterpiece. I would also like to add that the picture quality here wasn't that great either. It is just a poor release of this film in almost every area. ...disjointed script bordering on HBO style "erotica", with probably the worse subtitling I have ever seen. The movie ends abruptly like they just simply ran out of film. Avoid this one. For the amount of money the producers spent on this, the movie's quality is terrible. Everything is underlit and murky as if the film was dropped in a swamp prior to being developed, and that's when you're lucky enough to view a scene that's actually in-focus. The sound is poorly dubbed, much of the music is awkward and the editing is god awful. Let's not kid ourselves here, all ye art students, film-school nerds, and other self-loathing "cinema l'arte" snobs: had this exact same movie been released under the banner "directed by Pier Paolo Pasolini" you would have loved it - sorry: CLAIMED to have loved it - and praised it to high heaven, espousing its virtues in long essays, justifying its extreme sex and violence through some b.s. semantic pseudo-intellectual movie-critic-jargon mumbo-jumbo. A corny, historically inaccurate, fairy-tale-like piece of crap like "Gandhi" gets world-wide recognition, while a brutally realistic film about another historical figure, called "Caligula" gets the finger. Go figure. Go on, admit it. No-one will laugh. We promise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Down Memory Lane.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Traversa
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Have you seen, read or heard "The Glass Menagerie" by Tennesse Williams? If you remember, the play is told by the main character in the present time, he tells us about his past life, lost forever, as well as the characters that were essential in his life at that time, "This play is memory" he says. Well, my review for this film is also memory, since I saw it at the time of its premiere and never again. I happened to be listening a program on France culture radio on the Internet and they mentioned this film, it instantly came back to my memory: One of the best films I had ever seen, next to "Tous les matins du monde", "Barry Lyndon", "Tom Jones" and a few others. I should see it again to experience that sometimes disappointing sensation of coming down with a sad feeling of having outgrown an old film that in our memory was fantastic. On the other hand, there are also those old films that when seeing them again after so many years, they are as fresh as ever, as I'm sure is the case with this one. I remember that I was mesmerized at the end of the projection (I saw it at a movie house in Barcelona) and thought at the time that it was a perfect movie, something so rare and unusual to find. So far, and --again-- in my memory, it it one of the best films I have ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It has an effect for everybody in some way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Harsanyi
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film just inspired me to watch more older films. In the summer i was in a Christian camp where they showed the main scene (for me it is) when Alexandre Fabbri is playing with the marionette ballerina. When I arrived home I immediately started searching for this film and finally i found it! It took me 3 days to watch it. This became my favorite film of all my life. There are scenes and quotes that mean so much to me. I feel I am not the only one with this feeling because as I can see, there are events that are alternative, and has effects that are different for you and your friends either.What is the most interesting thing what i've ever seen/heard? There is only one music in the film and makes you happy or sad depending on the scene. The cameraman's work is excellent too! :) I absolutely would nominate this for Golden Globe of all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Condemned to death
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    randomchoice
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I hated this movie while watching it.After much debating with myself and a friend I have come to the conclusion that this movie is about death. While I still have no sympathy for anyone or anything in the movie, I think the movie is nevertheless a lot more coherent than I initially thought, and for this - and also for the excellent filmography - I am giving it an 8/10. (1) A friend of mine suggested this movie is about the various possibilities of existence which cannot be realized simultaneously in real life. I felt this wasn't right but I didn't have another interpretation to offer. But now I do. Let's see what Weronika and Veronique are all about: (a) Similarities They are both sickly creatures. They have a father, they don't have a mother. They are both engaged with music. They know and interact with a series of characters of no consequence (the aunt, the colleague from school, etc.) They both appear in a love relationship where their lovers are more involved than themselves. They both dismiss those lovers. They both have a plastic (?) ball and are fascinated by what the world looks like as reflected through it. They both watch an old woman through the window. They both seem to drift without touching the world around them. They both see their doppelg&auml;nger. (b) Differences Weronika lives in Poland. She is not independent (lives with her dad / aunt). She seems young and inexperienced. She moves to another city for the sake of her aunt. Feels that she is not alone in the world. She dies singing. Veronique lives in France. She is financially independent (she lives on her own, has her own job). She seems more mature, and already anchored in music (she has a music teacher, she teaches music). She quits her music lessons although her teacher thinks she has a great talent. She feels alone in the world. She falls in love (Weronika never seems in love; talking to her aunt, she seems excited to have slept with that guy but abandons him). She accepts the game played on her by the anonymous stalker. She becomes acquainted with her puppeteer. She sees her doppelg&auml;nger, in the end. She begins to see how he may be the one manipulating her. Veronique's story begins as Weronika dies. This chronological details is supported by the photo / negative from Poland, which is the moment when the stories of the two girls become anchored in reality and aligned in a particular chronological order. So far, what does this movie seem to be about? Let's say that Veronique's first apparition and inexplicable grief is a premonition of what might happen to her if she continues taking music lessons / trying to make a career in music. This premonition leads her to abandon her existential possibility of realizing her potential through music. Having abandoned this possibility (I don't feel like it should be called her 'ideal' - Veronique doesn't really seem to have a passion, a dream, an ideal!), she somehow loses her path. Is she the ballerina who breaks her leg and then turns into a butterfly, as the ballerina in the puppeteer's story? This seems rather to be Weronika's story. Veronique refuses to break her leg, so there's no question of her turning into a butterfly. Is, then, the movie about a character with a talent for music to whom her talent is fatal, and for whom abandoning the talent would lead to perdition all the same? If yes, then the movie does make sense, although I'm still not sure about the puppeteer. It's as if the puppeteer had somehow condemned both these girls to death, and loves them when they have accepted their sentence. (Antek too could be some kind of a puppeteer: he tells Weronika he loves her only after she had come to the city and was already pursuing her talent! Likewise, Alexandre too tells Veronique he loves her only after she had accepted to enter the game of the anonymous caller.) If this death sentence were the true meaning of the movie, then it also would be easier to understand why Veronique has two lovers (the first, unnamed one, and then, Alexandre), and Weronika only one: Veronique quits music and drives away her first lover, and this could be a rejection of dying for her talent. Her condemnation to death is, however, still there: having failed to kill her through music, the puppeteer steps in himself. The weird thing about this interpretation is that, although both girls do seem to have some relation to music, neither of them gives the impression that music is the biggest thing in their lives. Music is just something they happen to be good at, good enough to be remarked and regretted when they cannot / refuse to pursue it. For the rest, these girls look like lambs brought to the slaughterhouse. For example, when Weronika's aunt asks her how her audition had gone, Weronika answers something like (I don't remember the exact wording): it went TOO well. Apathetic... (2) My conclusion about the movie After lots of thinking, here's, then, my conclusion regarding what this movie is about: I think it is about condemnation to death, regardless of other life details. This idea seems supported by that episode where Veronique holds the shoestring across the graph paper in a straight line over her recent EKG graph. The straight line of an EKG = death. Everything else in the movie is ballast. The doppelg&auml;nger thing is rather a red herring: it muddles the waters without any pay-off, really. Now I understand why the music is throughout so sad / sinister. Also, why there is so much ballast, so many gestures of no consequence. So many attempts at a plot but with no actual realization. The characters are doomed, and that's all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Cinematic, cinematographic, psychological and lyrical..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Polish screenwriter and director Krzysztof Kieslowski's ninth feature film which he co-wrote with Polish screenwriter Krzysztof Piesiewicz, premiered In competition at the 44th Cannes International Film Festival in 1991, was shot on location in France and Poland and is a France-Poland-Norway co-production which was produced by producer Leonardo De La Fuente. It tells the story about and educated singer and pianist named Weronika who lives in an apartment in Poland and who is in a relationship with a man named Antek. After experiencing a feeling of not being alone which she is instigated to act upon, Weronika travels to Krakow where her aunt lives and when she gets there she notices a woman whom she has never seen before and who bears a striking resemblance to herself. Distinctly and subtly directed by Polish filmmaker Krzysztof Kieslowski, this finely tuned fictional tale which is narrated mostly from the two main character's point of view, draws a virtuous portrayal of the life of a Polish woman named Weronika and a French woman named Veroniqu&eacute; who are identical and who one day coincidentally or determined by destiny crosses paths. While notable for it's naturalistic and atmospheric milieu depictions, distinct production design by production designer Patrice Mercier, cinematography by polish cinematographer Slawomir Idziak, costume design by costume designers Laurence Brignon, Claudy Fellous and Elzbieta Radke, fine editing by French film editor Jacques Witta and use of colors and light, this character-driven and narrative-driven story where the director could focus more on the cinematic aspects of his film and less on the political which was characteristic in many of his previous productions due to the political situation in his country, depicts two interrelated and empathic studies of character and contains a great score by Polish composer Zbigniew Preisner. This dramatic, literary, somewhat surreal, romantic and humanistic drama from the early 1990s about identity and faith which is the last feature film Krzysztof Kieslowski made before ending his career with the Three Colours trilogy which consisted of "Blue" (1993), "White" (1994) and "Red" (1994) and which is set in the capital city of France and the capital city of Poland in the early 1990s and where a music teacher for children named Veroniqu&eacute; who lives in France experiences a feeling of being alone, is impelled and reinforced by it's brilliant narrative structure, substantial character development, subtle continuity, interrelated stories, endearing characters, poetic scenes and the memorable acting performance by French actress Ir&egrave;ne Jacob. A cinematic, cinematographic, psychological and lyrical mystery which gained, among numerous other awards, the FIPRESCI Prize Krzysztof Kieslowski, the Prize of the Ecumenical Jury and the award for Best Actress Ir&egrave;ne Jacob at the 44th Cannes Film Festival in 1991.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    levelllll5
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "All my life I've felt like I was here and somewhere else at the same time" Weronika lives in Poland. She lost her mother as a kid. She has a gift for music, and especially singing. She likes to apply a golden ring around her eye. She runs a lot. She is always breathless because of a heart defect that she is unaware of. She is searching for love. Veronique lives in France. She lost her mother as a kid. She has a gift for music, and she teaches it to young children. She likes to apply a golden ring around her eye. She runs a lot. She is always breathless because of a heart defect that has just been found out. She is searching for love. Weronika sees V&eacute;ronique in Krakow, the city she lives in. She stops in the middle of a place crowded with people demonstrating and riot squads. Her alter ego is getting on a bus which will take her back to France. Before the bus leaves, V&eacute;ronique has time to take pictures of the place and of Weronika, but she does not see her. During the first half-hour of the film, the subjective shots which represent Weronika's vision are unsteady, the fisheye angle twists the perspectives, until Weronika herself collapses, on the stage, among the music instruments and in front of the audience, in the middle of a song. After Weronika's death, we follow V&eacute;ronique. She is making love with a man, and, right after it, she feels an immense sadness. She says to her lover &laquo; It's as if I were grieving &raquo; but she is unable to explain why. She decides to give up on the concert she was preparing, the same concert, we can imagine, during which Weronika died. V&eacute;ronique follows her intuition, and Weronika's death prevents her from dying herself. In the school where V&eacute;ronique teaches, a man manipulates puppets for the children. He makes the puppet die and become a sort of angel. Later on, V&eacute;tonique receives an anonymous phone call, then she gets a lace in the mail, and then an audio tape thanks to which she finds the place from where the anonymous man sends his objects to her. She finds him in a bar in the Gare Saint Lazare in Paris. She recognizes the puppeteer. In a hotel, after they have made love, and confessed their love, she empties her purse on the bed because he wants to know her better. He looks at the photos she took during her trip in Eastern Europe. He says that she is pretty on the pictures. She notices Weronika for the first time. She starts to cry. Weeks, maybe months later, she wakes up in the middle of the night and finds her lover making a second puppet of herself. She asks why he made two puppets of her, and he says that it is because they get damaged. She manipulates one puppet, while the other is lying motionless. The puppeteer reads to her the first version of a tale he is writing about two women on two different continents who are in fact two versions of the same person. This focus on the puppets reminded me of an essay written by Furio Jesi on Rilke's poetry. Jesi writes: the doll, in its form, tragically announces to men that it is her, not them, who will survive in the Infinite. &raquo;. To me, the puppets are a reminder of the fate that awaits V&eacute;ronique as well, that is death. The two women will disappear in death but the two puppets will remain. There is a very important dreamlike dimension in the film which features a dwarf who is also a lawyer, an old exhibitionnist, conversations of secondary characters with no beginning and no end, a subjective shot of the dead Weronika being buried. The film is also very poetic. I think of two shots in particular: the two versions of the old lady crossing the screen, and the image of the old church reflected backwards in a plastic ball. To appreciate this film, you need to get rid of the need to understand and analyze everything, and accept the absurd side of reality. My sister saw the film with me, and at one point she said: &laquo; there is something in this film that is us. &raquo; That &laquo; something &raquo; can be defined as the atmosphere, the setting, the green and red colors. the light. Kieslowski's movie addresses that part of our brain that is the center of our emotions, of our sensations, and of the memories of those sensations. It remains with us like an old dream that we had forgotten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Double Life of V&eacute;ronique
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Krzysztof Kieslowski (Dekalog: The Ten Commandments, Three Colours: Blue), I read a little about this film before watching it, and obviously it was in the book 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die, so I was hoping it was going to be a deserving placement. Basically the story starts in Poland with the life of young Polish woman Weronika (Ir&egrave;ne Jacob) who has a keen ambition to become a singer, and aside caring for her sick Aunt (Halina Gryglaszewska) in Krak&oacute;w, she is prepared to leave most things to achieve this dream, including spending time with her boyfriend Antek (Jerzy Gudejko). She gets noticed by turning up at a concert rehearsal session, impressing the musical director with her beautiful high soprano voice and offered an audition, and eventually she is successful, and she reconnects with Antek who has been following her somewhat, but when she finally gets on stage to enchant an audience with her she sings her parts, but collapses and dies during performance. The story then shifts to Paris where on the same day young French woman V&eacute;ronique (Ir&egrave;ne Jacob), a doppelg&auml;nger who in a sudden moment feels grief and sadness, she teaches music and takes her class to see a musical piece by the same composer who performed with Weronika, conductor Van den Budenmayer (Aleksander Bardini), and in a few instances she hears more of his music playing in places. The next day she tells her father that she is in love, all of the sudden with a man she has never met, after receiving an odd shoelace in a letter envelope she believes it is from a puppeteer she has seen a few times, also a children's book author who in one his stories mentions a shoelace, Alexandre Fabbri (Philippe Volter), and she reads more of his work, and also hears more Budenmayer music, including sounds of a car accident. V&eacute;ronique feels manipulated finding out that it was Alexandre wanting to gain her attention and meet again, she eventually lets him off and they sleep together and make love, and the next morning he finds a photo of Weronika that obviously looks just like V&eacute;ronique, but she denies it is her as he is the one who took the photo. The end of the film sees Alexandre working on a new book, focusing on the lives of two women born on the same day in different cities of the world with a strange connection, obviously based on what he found falling with V&eacute;ronique and finding out about Weronika. Also starring Kalina Jedrusik as Gaudy woman, Wladyslaw Kowalski as Weronika's father, Janusz Sterninski as Lawyer, Sandrine Dumas as Catherine and Louis Ducreux as Teacher. As the two identical women Jacob gives a performance worth watching, but I will be honest and say that I much preferred the first woman more than her second because she has an extraordinary singing voice that goes perfectly with the opera music, the second performance for lacked as much depth, in fact, I found after the first woman's death the rest of the film was a tiny bit slowed down, nevertheless overall it is a worthwhile drama. It was nominated the Golden Globe for Best Foreign Language Film. Good, in my opinion!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Makes You Feel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brtndr
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It makes you feel like you've fallen asleep and entered into someone else's surrealistic dream world. Fortunately, there are two beautiful young women Veronique and Veronicka (both played by Irene Jacobs) who are at the center of that alien dream world you've entered into. And, you are just as engaged in the lives of the two woman as you would be if your own life was passing before your eyes. The two lives of Veronique and Veronicka reflect each other, but are only subconsciously aware of it, which is eerie in its very nature. Two people who have two entirely different lives, obviously destined to never really meet, but unexpectedly spot each other across a crowded court yard one day. The experience briefly hypnotically paralyzes them both as they stare in amazement at the sight of one another. A moment that appears to confirm for both woman what they've always felt, but could never bring themselves to believe until then. This encounter between the two ends as quickly as it accidentally occurred, and they continue on with their separate lives without ever really acknowledging the entire breadth and depth of their shared accidental encounter. However, after the experience neither one of them are the same physically or emotionally again. There is so much going on both visually and emotionally in the film which makes 'The Double Life of Veronique' one of the most worthy films for endless coffee house discussions and analysis. A highly recommended A+ excellent foreign movie that you'll enjoy discussing for hours afterwards with cinema enthusiast. Perhaps, while enjoying a cup of Mocha Espresso with a dollop of milk?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reflections from the looking glass
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Artimidor Federkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here's a kind of movie that helps you think outside the proverbial box: Meet V&eacute;ronique,the French protagonist who chances upon a most unusual face - en passant, in a fleeting moment, like a reminder from another life. The face of the person she sees is her own. Somewhere on Polish plaza, to briefly surface and drown again in the crowd. "La Double vie de V&eacute;ronique" teaches you to appreciate escaping the comfort zone of trusted logic, recognize its pitfalls and see a strange, maybe even absurd fantastic premise in an otherwise realistic picture as a chance to discover something that cannot be named. Sure, Kieslowski pictures are always a combination of beautiful images, evocative music and a strong cerebral component, but "La double vie de V&eacute;ronique" is his most enigmatic, thought provoking work. Various threads are spun by writer and director which appeal to the viewer's imagination, so that they may be connected or respected just the way they are. Or perhaps seen as a whole in the eye of the beholder in front of the screen: Two different lives, one face, strings attached or mere coincidence? Is there fate? Does the demiurge work as puppeteer or are our actions influencing others in a way we would never anticipate? There are no metaphors in my work, Kiesloswki once said. Sounds challenging? Feel free to connect your own dots in this magical adventure of parallelism seen through the looking glass! Just one thing: The purpose of art is not to provide answers and be prescriptive in its implications, be they moral, social, historic or otherwise, but rather to open up new pathways and perspectives and question what we've been used to take for granted. In this respect Kieslowski succeeds indubitably and delivers a dazzling work of art to be looked at. Again and again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ethereal Irene Jacob
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The premise of this film is based on the old legend that we all have a twin somewhere in the world. Weronika is a Polish opera singer who while performing at an outdoor concert, continues to sing in a heavy rainstorm. Afterwards, she meets her boyfriend, Antek, and they get it on. She tells her father that she does not feel alone in the world. She visits her aunt in Krakow and meets a friend at a concert rehearsal. While listening, she sings along and the director is so impressed with her voice that he asks her to audition. While walking down a street during a protest rally, she notices a woman taking photos of the crowd. The lady looks like her twin. Her double gets on a bus which drives away. She passes the audition and the following night, and while singing a solo at a concert, collapses and dies on stage. Her spirit travels over the audience. That same day in Paris, Veronique(Irene Jacob), feels a great sadness for no apparent reason. Later, at her classroom, she leads her students in a classical piece by the same composer that Weronika was performing when she died., Veronique falls in love with a puppeteer and writer named Alexandre and as the couple go through a photo album, he sees a picture which looks like her. Veronique explains that it can't possibly be her, since she took the photo. There is no real ending for Double Life, but Irene Jacob in the dual role, makes it work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spooky-wooky does not a movie make
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xXBoss-EbertXx
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Seinfeld said his show was about "nothing," but it had the contents of the Encyclopedia Britannica compared to this movie. Quelle waste of time sitting through this! It moved at the speed of a glacier and made absolutely no sense at all. To it's credit, La double vie de V&eacute;ronique is FAR from what you'd ever see in an American theatre, but in this case, that might not be a good thing. This film is an exercise in banality compared to the remake, I Know Who Killed Me (2007), a modern day erotic masterpiece. I would also like to add that the picture quality here wasn't that great either. It is just a poor release of this film in almost every area. ...disjointed script bordering on HBO style "erotica", with probably the worse subtitling I have ever seen. The movie ends abruptly like they just simply ran out of film. Avoid this one. For the amount of money the producers spent on this, the movie's quality is terrible. Everything is underlit and murky as if the film was dropped in a swamp prior to being developed, and that's when you're lucky enough to view a scene that's actually in-focus. The sound is poorly dubbed, much of the music is awkward and the editing is god awful. Let's not kid ourselves here, all ye art students, film-school nerds, and other self-loathing "cinema l'arte" snobs: had this exact same movie been released under the banner "directed by Pier Paolo Pasolini" you would have loved it - sorry: CLAIMED to have loved it - and praised it to high heaven, espousing its virtues in long essays, justifying its extreme sex and violence through some b.s. semantic pseudo-intellectual movie-critic-jargon mumbo-jumbo. A corny, historically inaccurate, fairy-tale-like piece of crap like "Gandhi" gets world-wide recognition, while a brutally realistic film about another historical figure, called "Caligula" gets the finger. Go figure. Go on, admit it. No-one will laugh. We promise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Down Memory Lane.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Traversa
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Have you seen, read or heard "The Glass Menagerie" by Tennesse Williams? If you remember, the play is told by the main character in the present time, he tells us about his past life, lost forever, as well as the characters that were essential in his life at that time, "This play is memory" he says. Well, my review for this film is also memory, since I saw it at the time of its premiere and never again. I happened to be listening a program on France culture radio on the Internet and they mentioned this film, it instantly came back to my memory: One of the best films I had ever seen, next to "Tous les matins du monde", "Barry Lyndon", "Tom Jones" and a few others. I should see it again to experience that sometimes disappointing sensation of coming down with a sad feeling of having outgrown an old film that in our memory was fantastic. On the other hand, there are also those old films that when seeing them again after so many years, they are as fresh as ever, as I'm sure is the case with this one. I remember that I was mesmerized at the end of the projection (I saw it at a movie house in Barcelona) and thought at the time that it was a perfect movie, something so rare and unusual to find. So far, and --again-- in my memory, it it one of the best films I have ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It has an effect for everybody in some way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Harsanyi
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film just inspired me to watch more older films. In the summer i was in a Christian camp where they showed the main scene (for me it is) when Alexandre Fabbri is playing with the marionette ballerina. When I arrived home I immediately started searching for this film and finally i found it! It took me 3 days to watch it. This became my favorite film of all my life. There are scenes and quotes that mean so much to me. I feel I am not the only one with this feeling because as I can see, there are events that are alternative, and has effects that are different for you and your friends either.What is the most interesting thing what i've ever seen/heard? There is only one music in the film and makes you happy or sad depending on the scene. The cameraman's work is excellent too! :) I absolutely would nominate this for Golden Globe of all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Condemned to death
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    randomchoice
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I hated this movie while watching it.After much debating with myself and a friend I have come to the conclusion that this movie is about death. While I still have no sympathy for anyone or anything in the movie, I think the movie is nevertheless a lot more coherent than I initially thought, and for this - and also for the excellent filmography - I am giving it an 8/10. (1) A friend of mine suggested this movie is about the various possibilities of existence which cannot be realized simultaneously in real life. I felt this wasn't right but I didn't have another interpretation to offer. But now I do. Let's see what Weronika and Veronique are all about: (a) Similarities They are both sickly creatures. They have a father, they don't have a mother. They are both engaged with music. They know and interact with a series of characters of no consequence (the aunt, the colleague from school, etc.) They both appear in a love relationship where their lovers are more involved than themselves. They both dismiss those lovers. They both have a plastic (?) ball and are fascinated by what the world looks like as reflected through it. They both watch an old woman through the window. They both seem to drift without touching the world around them. They both see their doppelg&auml;nger. (b) Differences Weronika lives in Poland. She is not independent (lives with her dad / aunt). She seems young and inexperienced. She moves to another city for the sake of her aunt. Feels that she is not alone in the world. She dies singing. Veronique lives in France. She is financially independent (she lives on her own, has her own job). She seems more mature, and already anchored in music (she has a music teacher, she teaches music). She quits her music lessons although her teacher thinks she has a great talent. She feels alone in the world. She falls in love (Weronika never seems in love; talking to her aunt, she seems excited to have slept with that guy but abandons him). She accepts the game played on her by the anonymous stalker. She becomes acquainted with her puppeteer. She sees her doppelg&auml;nger, in the end. She begins to see how he may be the one manipulating her. Veronique's story begins as Weronika dies. This chronological details is supported by the photo / negative from Poland, which is the moment when the stories of the two girls become anchored in reality and aligned in a particular chronological order. So far, what does this movie seem to be about? Let's say that Veronique's first apparition and inexplicable grief is a premonition of what might happen to her if she continues taking music lessons / trying to make a career in music. This premonition leads her to abandon her existential possibility of realizing her potential through music. Having abandoned this possibility (I don't feel like it should be called her 'ideal' - Veronique doesn't really seem to have a passion, a dream, an ideal!), she somehow loses her path. Is she the ballerina who breaks her leg and then turns into a butterfly, as the ballerina in the puppeteer's story? This seems rather to be Weronika's story. Veronique refuses to break her leg, so there's no question of her turning into a butterfly. Is, then, the movie about a character with a talent for music to whom her talent is fatal, and for whom abandoning the talent would lead to perdition all the same? If yes, then the movie does make sense, although I'm still not sure about the puppeteer. It's as if the puppeteer had somehow condemned both these girls to death, and loves them when they have accepted their sentence. (Antek too could be some kind of a puppeteer: he tells Weronika he loves her only after she had come to the city and was already pursuing her talent! Likewise, Alexandre too tells Veronique he loves her only after she had accepted to enter the game of the anonymous caller.) If this death sentence were the true meaning of the movie, then it also would be easier to understand why Veronique has two lovers (the first, unnamed one, and then, Alexandre), and Weronika only one: Veronique quits music and drives away her first lover, and this could be a rejection of dying for her talent. Her condemnation to death is, however, still there: having failed to kill her through music, the puppeteer steps in himself. The weird thing about this interpretation is that, although both girls do seem to have some relation to music, neither of them gives the impression that music is the biggest thing in their lives. Music is just something they happen to be good at, good enough to be remarked and regretted when they cannot / refuse to pursue it. For the rest, these girls look like lambs brought to the slaughterhouse. For example, when Weronika's aunt asks her how her audition had gone, Weronika answers something like (I don't remember the exact wording): it went TOO well. Apathetic... (2) My conclusion about the movie After lots of thinking, here's, then, my conclusion regarding what this movie is about: I think it is about condemnation to death, regardless of other life details. This idea seems supported by that episode where Veronique holds the shoestring across the graph paper in a straight line over her recent EKG graph. The straight line of an EKG = death. Everything else in the movie is ballast. The doppelg&auml;nger thing is rather a red herring: it muddles the waters without any pay-off, really. Now I understand why the music is throughout so sad / sinister. Also, why there is so much ballast, so many gestures of no consequence. So many attempts at a plot but with no actual realization. The characters are doomed, and that's all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Cinematic, cinematographic, psychological and lyrical..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Polish screenwriter and director Krzysztof Kieslowski's ninth feature film which he co-wrote with Polish screenwriter Krzysztof Piesiewicz, premiered In competition at the 44th Cannes International Film Festival in 1991, was shot on location in France and Poland and is a France-Poland-Norway co-production which was produced by producer Leonardo De La Fuente. It tells the story about and educated singer and pianist named Weronika who lives in an apartment in Poland and who is in a relationship with a man named Antek. After experiencing a feeling of not being alone which she is instigated to act upon, Weronika travels to Krakow where her aunt lives and when she gets there she notices a woman whom she has never seen before and who bears a striking resemblance to herself. Distinctly and subtly directed by Polish filmmaker Krzysztof Kieslowski, this finely tuned fictional tale which is narrated mostly from the two main character's point of view, draws a virtuous portrayal of the life of a Polish woman named Weronika and a French woman named Veroniqu&eacute; who are identical and who one day coincidentally or determined by destiny crosses paths. While notable for it's naturalistic and atmospheric milieu depictions, distinct production design by production designer Patrice Mercier, cinematography by polish cinematographer Slawomir Idziak, costume design by costume designers Laurence Brignon, Claudy Fellous and Elzbieta Radke, fine editing by French film editor Jacques Witta and use of colors and light, this character-driven and narrative-driven story where the director could focus more on the cinematic aspects of his film and less on the political which was characteristic in many of his previous productions due to the political situation in his country, depicts two interrelated and empathic studies of character and contains a great score by Polish composer Zbigniew Preisner. This dramatic, literary, somewhat surreal, romantic and humanistic drama from the early 1990s about identity and faith which is the last feature film Krzysztof Kieslowski made before ending his career with the Three Colours trilogy which consisted of "Blue" (1993), "White" (1994) and "Red" (1994) and which is set in the capital city of France and the capital city of Poland in the early 1990s and where a music teacher for children named Veroniqu&eacute; who lives in France experiences a feeling of being alone, is impelled and reinforced by it's brilliant narrative structure, substantial character development, subtle continuity, interrelated stories, endearing characters, poetic scenes and the memorable acting performance by French actress Ir&egrave;ne Jacob. A cinematic, cinematographic, psychological and lyrical mystery which gained, among numerous other awards, the FIPRESCI Prize Krzysztof Kieslowski, the Prize of the Ecumenical Jury and the award for Best Actress Ir&egrave;ne Jacob at the 44th Cannes Film Festival in 1991.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    levelllll5
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "All my life I've felt like I was here and somewhere else at the same time" Weronika lives in Poland. She lost her mother as a kid. She has a gift for music, and especially singing. She likes to apply a golden ring around her eye. She runs a lot. She is always breathless because of a heart defect that she is unaware of. She is searching for love. Veronique lives in France. She lost her mother as a kid. She has a gift for music, and she teaches it to young children. She likes to apply a golden ring around her eye. She runs a lot. She is always breathless because of a heart defect that has just been found out. She is searching for love. Weronika sees V&eacute;ronique in Krakow, the city she lives in. She stops in the middle of a place crowded with people demonstrating and riot squads. Her alter ego is getting on a bus which will take her back to France. Before the bus leaves, V&eacute;ronique has time to take pictures of the place and of Weronika, but she does not see her. During the first half-hour of the film, the subjective shots which represent Weronika's vision are unsteady, the fisheye angle twists the perspectives, until Weronika herself collapses, on the stage, among the music instruments and in front of the audience, in the middle of a song. After Weronika's death, we follow V&eacute;ronique. She is making love with a man, and, right after it, she feels an immense sadness. She says to her lover &laquo; It's as if I were grieving &raquo; but she is unable to explain why. She decides to give up on the concert she was preparing, the same concert, we can imagine, during which Weronika died. V&eacute;ronique follows her intuition, and Weronika's death prevents her from dying herself. In the school where V&eacute;ronique teaches, a man manipulates puppets for the children. He makes the puppet die and become a sort of angel. Later on, V&eacute;tonique receives an anonymous phone call, then she gets a lace in the mail, and then an audio tape thanks to which she finds the place from where the anonymous man sends his objects to her. She finds him in a bar in the Gare Saint Lazare in Paris. She recognizes the puppeteer. In a hotel, after they have made love, and confessed their love, she empties her purse on the bed because he wants to know her better. He looks at the photos she took during her trip in Eastern Europe. He says that she is pretty on the pictures. She notices Weronika for the first time. She starts to cry. Weeks, maybe months later, she wakes up in the middle of the night and finds her lover making a second puppet of herself. She asks why he made two puppets of her, and he says that it is because they get damaged. She manipulates one puppet, while the other is lying motionless. The puppeteer reads to her the first version of a tale he is writing about two women on two different continents who are in fact two versions of the same person. This focus on the puppets reminded me of an essay written by Furio Jesi on Rilke's poetry. Jesi writes: the doll, in its form, tragically announces to men that it is her, not them, who will survive in the Infinite. &raquo;. To me, the puppets are a reminder of the fate that awaits V&eacute;ronique as well, that is death. The two women will disappear in death but the two puppets will remain. There is a very important dreamlike dimension in the film which features a dwarf who is also a lawyer, an old exhibitionnist, conversations of secondary characters with no beginning and no end, a subjective shot of the dead Weronika being buried. The film is also very poetic. I think of two shots in particular: the two versions of the old lady crossing the screen, and the image of the old church reflected backwards in a plastic ball. To appreciate this film, you need to get rid of the need to understand and analyze everything, and accept the absurd side of reality. My sister saw the film with me, and at one point she said: &laquo; there is something in this film that is us. &raquo; That &laquo; something &raquo; can be defined as the atmosphere, the setting, the green and red colors. the light. Kieslowski's movie addresses that part of our brain that is the center of our emotions, of our sensations, and of the memories of those sensations. It remains with us like an old dream that we had forgotten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Double Life of V&eacute;ronique
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Krzysztof Kieslowski (Dekalog: The Ten Commandments, Three Colours: Blue), I read a little about this film before watching it, and obviously it was in the book 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die, so I was hoping it was going to be a deserving placement. Basically the story starts in Poland with the life of young Polish woman Weronika (Ir&egrave;ne Jacob) who has a keen ambition to become a singer, and aside caring for her sick Aunt (Halina Gryglaszewska) in Krak&oacute;w, she is prepared to leave most things to achieve this dream, including spending time with her boyfriend Antek (Jerzy Gudejko). She gets noticed by turning up at a concert rehearsal session, impressing the musical director with her beautiful high soprano voice and offered an audition, and eventually she is successful, and she reconnects with Antek who has been following her somewhat, but when she finally gets on stage to enchant an audience with her she sings her parts, but collapses and dies during performance. The story then shifts to Paris where on the same day young French woman V&eacute;ronique (Ir&egrave;ne Jacob), a doppelg&auml;nger who in a sudden moment feels grief and sadness, she teaches music and takes her class to see a musical piece by the same composer who performed with Weronika, conductor Van den Budenmayer (Aleksander Bardini), and in a few instances she hears more of his music playing in places. The next day she tells her father that she is in love, all of the sudden with a man she has never met, after receiving an odd shoelace in a letter envelope she believes it is from a puppeteer she has seen a few times, also a children's book author who in one his stories mentions a shoelace, Alexandre Fabbri (Philippe Volter), and she reads more of his work, and also hears more Budenmayer music, including sounds of a car accident. V&eacute;ronique feels manipulated finding out that it was Alexandre wanting to gain her attention and meet again, she eventually lets him off and they sleep together and make love, and the next morning he finds a photo of Weronika that obviously looks just like V&eacute;ronique, but she denies it is her as he is the one who took the photo. The end of the film sees Alexandre working on a new book, focusing on the lives of two women born on the same day in different cities of the world with a strange connection, obviously based on what he found falling with V&eacute;ronique and finding out about Weronika. Also starring Kalina Jedrusik as Gaudy woman, Wladyslaw Kowalski as Weronika's father, Janusz Sterninski as Lawyer, Sandrine Dumas as Catherine and Louis Ducreux as Teacher. As the two identical women Jacob gives a performance worth watching, but I will be honest and say that I much preferred the first woman more than her second because she has an extraordinary singing voice that goes perfectly with the opera music, the second performance for lacked as much depth, in fact, I found after the first woman's death the rest of the film was a tiny bit slowed down, nevertheless overall it is a worthwhile drama. It was nominated the Golden Globe for Best Foreign Language Film. Good, in my opinion!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Makes You Feel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brtndr
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It makes you feel like you've fallen asleep and entered into someone else's surrealistic dream world. Fortunately, there are two beautiful young women Veronique and Veronicka (both played by Irene Jacobs) who are at the center of that alien dream world you've entered into. And, you are just as engaged in the lives of the two woman as you would be if your own life was passing before your eyes. The two lives of Veronique and Veronicka reflect each other, but are only subconsciously aware of it, which is eerie in its very nature. Two people who have two entirely different lives, obviously destined to never really meet, but unexpectedly spot each other across a crowded court yard one day. The experience briefly hypnotically paralyzes them both as they stare in amazement at the sight of one another. A moment that appears to confirm for both woman what they've always felt, but could never bring themselves to believe until then. This encounter between the two ends as quickly as it accidentally occurred, and they continue on with their separate lives without ever really acknowledging the entire breadth and depth of their shared accidental encounter. However, after the experience neither one of them are the same physically or emotionally again. There is so much going on both visually and emotionally in the film which makes 'The Double Life of Veronique' one of the most worthy films for endless coffee house discussions and analysis. A highly recommended A+ excellent foreign movie that you'll enjoy discussing for hours afterwards with cinema enthusiast. Perhaps, while enjoying a cup of Mocha Espresso with a dollop of milk?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reflections from the looking glass
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Artimidor Federkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here's a kind of movie that helps you think outside the proverbial box: Meet V&eacute;ronique,the French protagonist who chances upon a most unusual face - en passant, in a fleeting moment, like a reminder from another life. The face of the person she sees is her own. Somewhere on Polish plaza, to briefly surface and drown again in the crowd. "La Double vie de V&eacute;ronique" teaches you to appreciate escaping the comfort zone of trusted logic, recognize its pitfalls and see a strange, maybe even absurd fantastic premise in an otherwise realistic picture as a chance to discover something that cannot be named. Sure, Kieslowski pictures are always a combination of beautiful images, evocative music and a strong cerebral component, but "La double vie de V&eacute;ronique" is his most enigmatic, thought provoking work. Various threads are spun by writer and director which appeal to the viewer's imagination, so that they may be connected or respected just the way they are. Or perhaps seen as a whole in the eye of the beholder in front of the screen: Two different lives, one face, strings attached or mere coincidence? Is there fate? Does the demiurge work as puppeteer or are our actions influencing others in a way we would never anticipate? There are no metaphors in my work, Kiesloswki once said. Sounds challenging? Feel free to connect your own dots in this magical adventure of parallelism seen through the looking glass! Just one thing: The purpose of art is not to provide answers and be prescriptive in its implications, be they moral, social, historic or otherwise, but rather to open up new pathways and perspectives and question what we've been used to take for granted. In this respect Kieslowski succeeds indubitably and delivers a dazzling work of art to be looked at. Again and again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ethereal Irene Jacob
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The premise of this film is based on the old legend that we all have a twin somewhere in the world. Weronika is a Polish opera singer who while performing at an outdoor concert, continues to sing in a heavy rainstorm. Afterwards, she meets her boyfriend, Antek, and they get it on. She tells her father that she does not feel alone in the world. She visits her aunt in Krakow and meets a friend at a concert rehearsal. While listening, she sings along and the director is so impressed with her voice that he asks her to audition. While walking down a street during a protest rally, she notices a woman taking photos of the crowd. The lady looks like her twin. Her double gets on a bus which drives away. She passes the audition and the following night, and while singing a solo at a concert, collapses and dies on stage. Her spirit travels over the audience. That same day in Paris, Veronique(Irene Jacob), feels a great sadness for no apparent reason. Later, at her classroom, she leads her students in a classical piece by the same composer that Weronika was performing when she died., Veronique falls in love with a puppeteer and writer named Alexandre and as the couple go through a photo album, he sees a picture which looks like her. Veronique explains that it can't possibly be her, since she took the photo. There is no real ending for Double Life, but Irene Jacob in the dual role, makes it work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spooky-wooky does not a movie make
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xXBoss-EbertXx
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Seinfeld said his show was about "nothing," but it had the contents of the Encyclopedia Britannica compared to this movie. Quelle waste of time sitting through this! It moved at the speed of a glacier and made absolutely no sense at all. To it's credit, La double vie de V&eacute;ronique is FAR from what you'd ever see in an American theatre, but in this case, that might not be a good thing. This film is an exercise in banality compared to the remake, I Know Who Killed Me (2007), a modern day erotic masterpiece. I would also like to add that the picture quality here wasn't that great either. It is just a poor release of this film in almost every area. ...disjointed script bordering on HBO style "erotica", with probably the worse subtitling I have ever seen. The movie ends abruptly like they just simply ran out of film. Avoid this one. For the amount of money the producers spent on this, the movie's quality is terrible. Everything is underlit and murky as if the film was dropped in a swamp prior to being developed, and that's when you're lucky enough to view a scene that's actually in-focus. The sound is poorly dubbed, much of the music is awkward and the editing is god awful. Let's not kid ourselves here, all ye art students, film-school nerds, and other self-loathing "cinema l'arte" snobs: had this exact same movie been released under the banner "directed by Pier Paolo Pasolini" you would have loved it - sorry: CLAIMED to have loved it - and praised it to high heaven, espousing its virtues in long essays, justifying its extreme sex and violence through some b.s. semantic pseudo-intellectual movie-critic-jargon mumbo-jumbo. A corny, historically inaccurate, fairy-tale-like piece of crap like "Gandhi" gets world-wide recognition, while a brutally realistic film about another historical figure, called "Caligula" gets the finger. Go figure. Go on, admit it. No-one will laugh. We promise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Down Memory Lane.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Traversa
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Have you seen, read or heard "The Glass Menagerie" by Tennesse Williams? If you remember, the play is told by the main character in the present time, he tells us about his past life, lost forever, as well as the characters that were essential in his life at that time, "This play is memory" he says. Well, my review for this film is also memory, since I saw it at the time of its premiere and never again. I happened to be listening a program on France culture radio on the Internet and they mentioned this film, it instantly came back to my memory: One of the best films I had ever seen, next to "Tous les matins du monde", "Barry Lyndon", "Tom Jones" and a few others. I should see it again to experience that sometimes disappointing sensation of coming down with a sad feeling of having outgrown an old film that in our memory was fantastic. On the other hand, there are also those old films that when seeing them again after so many years, they are as fresh as ever, as I'm sure is the case with this one. I remember that I was mesmerized at the end of the projection (I saw it at a movie house in Barcelona) and thought at the time that it was a perfect movie, something so rare and unusual to find. So far, and --again-- in my memory, it it one of the best films I have ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It has an effect for everybody in some way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Harsanyi
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film just inspired me to watch more older films. In the summer i was in a Christian camp where they showed the main scene (for me it is) when Alexandre Fabbri is playing with the marionette ballerina. When I arrived home I immediately started searching for this film and finally i found it! It took me 3 days to watch it. This became my favorite film of all my life. There are scenes and quotes that mean so much to me. I feel I am not the only one with this feeling because as I can see, there are events that are alternative, and has effects that are different for you and your friends either.What is the most interesting thing what i've ever seen/heard? There is only one music in the film and makes you happy or sad depending on the scene. The cameraman's work is excellent too! :) I absolutely would nominate this for Golden Globe of all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Condemned to death
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    randomchoice
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I hated this movie while watching it.After much debating with myself and a friend I have come to the conclusion that this movie is about death. While I still have no sympathy for anyone or anything in the movie, I think the movie is nevertheless a lot more coherent than I initially thought, and for this - and also for the excellent filmography - I am giving it an 8/10. (1) A friend of mine suggested this movie is about the various possibilities of existence which cannot be realized simultaneously in real life. I felt this wasn't right but I didn't have another interpretation to offer. But now I do. Let's see what Weronika and Veronique are all about: (a) Similarities They are both sickly creatures. They have a father, they don't have a mother. They are both engaged with music. They know and interact with a series of characters of no consequence (the aunt, the colleague from school, etc.) They both appear in a love relationship where their lovers are more involved than themselves. They both dismiss those lovers. They both have a plastic (?) ball and are fascinated by what the world looks like as reflected through it. They both watch an old woman through the window. They both seem to drift without touching the world around them. They both see their doppelg&auml;nger. (b) Differences Weronika lives in Poland. She is not independent (lives with her dad / aunt). She seems young and inexperienced. She moves to another city for the sake of her aunt. Feels that she is not alone in the world. She dies singing. Veronique lives in France. She is financially independent (she lives on her own, has her own job). She seems more mature, and already anchored in music (she has a music teacher, she teaches music). She quits her music lessons although her teacher thinks she has a great talent. She feels alone in the world. She falls in love (Weronika never seems in love; talking to her aunt, she seems excited to have slept with that guy but abandons him). She accepts the game played on her by the anonymous stalker. She becomes acquainted with her puppeteer. She sees her doppelg&auml;nger, in the end. She begins to see how he may be the one manipulating her. Veronique's story begins as Weronika dies. This chronological details is supported by the photo / negative from Poland, which is the moment when the stories of the two girls become anchored in reality and aligned in a particular chronological order. So far, what does this movie seem to be about? Let's say that Veronique's first apparition and inexplicable grief is a premonition of what might happen to her if she continues taking music lessons / trying to make a career in music. This premonition leads her to abandon her existential possibility of realizing her potential through music. Having abandoned this possibility (I don't feel like it should be called her 'ideal' - Veronique doesn't really seem to have a passion, a dream, an ideal!), she somehow loses her path. Is she the ballerina who breaks her leg and then turns into a butterfly, as the ballerina in the puppeteer's story? This seems rather to be Weronika's story. Veronique refuses to break her leg, so there's no question of her turning into a butterfly. Is, then, the movie about a character with a talent for music to whom her talent is fatal, and for whom abandoning the talent would lead to perdition all the same? If yes, then the movie does make sense, although I'm still not sure about the puppeteer. It's as if the puppeteer had somehow condemned both these girls to death, and loves them when they have accepted their sentence. (Antek too could be some kind of a puppeteer: he tells Weronika he loves her only after she had come to the city and was already pursuing her talent! Likewise, Alexandre too tells Veronique he loves her only after she had accepted to enter the game of the anonymous caller.) If this death sentence were the true meaning of the movie, then it also would be easier to understand why Veronique has two lovers (the first, unnamed one, and then, Alexandre), and Weronika only one: Veronique quits music and drives away her first lover, and this could be a rejection of dying for her talent. Her condemnation to death is, however, still there: having failed to kill her through music, the puppeteer steps in himself. The weird thing about this interpretation is that, although both girls do seem to have some relation to music, neither of them gives the impression that music is the biggest thing in their lives. Music is just something they happen to be good at, good enough to be remarked and regretted when they cannot / refuse to pursue it. For the rest, these girls look like lambs brought to the slaughterhouse. For example, when Weronika's aunt asks her how her audition had gone, Weronika answers something like (I don't remember the exact wording): it went TOO well. Apathetic... (2) My conclusion about the movie After lots of thinking, here's, then, my conclusion regarding what this movie is about: I think it is about condemnation to death, regardless of other life details. This idea seems supported by that episode where Veronique holds the shoestring across the graph paper in a straight line over her recent EKG graph. The straight line of an EKG = death. Everything else in the movie is ballast. The doppelg&auml;nger thing is rather a red herring: it muddles the waters without any pay-off, really. Now I understand why the music is throughout so sad / sinister. Also, why there is so much ballast, so many gestures of no consequence. So many attempts at a plot but with no actual realization. The characters are doomed, and that's all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Cinematic, cinematographic, psychological and lyrical..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Polish screenwriter and director Krzysztof Kieslowski's ninth feature film which he co-wrote with Polish screenwriter Krzysztof Piesiewicz, premiered In competition at the 44th Cannes International Film Festival in 1991, was shot on location in France and Poland and is a France-Poland-Norway co-production which was produced by producer Leonardo De La Fuente. It tells the story about and educated singer and pianist named Weronika who lives in an apartment in Poland and who is in a relationship with a man named Antek. After experiencing a feeling of not being alone which she is instigated to act upon, Weronika travels to Krakow where her aunt lives and when she gets there she notices a woman whom she has never seen before and who bears a striking resemblance to herself. Distinctly and subtly directed by Polish filmmaker Krzysztof Kieslowski, this finely tuned fictional tale which is narrated mostly from the two main character's point of view, draws a virtuous portrayal of the life of a Polish woman named Weronika and a French woman named Veroniqu&eacute; who are identical and who one day coincidentally or determined by destiny crosses paths. While notable for it's naturalistic and atmospheric milieu depictions, distinct production design by production designer Patrice Mercier, cinematography by polish cinematographer Slawomir Idziak, costume design by costume designers Laurence Brignon, Claudy Fellous and Elzbieta Radke, fine editing by French film editor Jacques Witta and use of colors and light, this character-driven and narrative-driven story where the director could focus more on the cinematic aspects of his film and less on the political which was characteristic in many of his previous productions due to the political situation in his country, depicts two interrelated and empathic studies of character and contains a great score by Polish composer Zbigniew Preisner. This dramatic, literary, somewhat surreal, romantic and humanistic drama from the early 1990s about identity and faith which is the last feature film Krzysztof Kieslowski made before ending his career with the Three Colours trilogy which consisted of "Blue" (1993), "White" (1994) and "Red" (1994) and which is set in the capital city of France and the capital city of Poland in the early 1990s and where a music teacher for children named Veroniqu&eacute; who lives in France experiences a feeling of being alone, is impelled and reinforced by it's brilliant narrative structure, substantial character development, subtle continuity, interrelated stories, endearing characters, poetic scenes and the memorable acting performance by French actress Ir&egrave;ne Jacob. A cinematic, cinematographic, psychological and lyrical mystery which gained, among numerous other awards, the FIPRESCI Prize Krzysztof Kieslowski, the Prize of the Ecumenical Jury and the award for Best Actress Ir&egrave;ne Jacob at the 44th Cannes Film Festival in 1991.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    levelllll5
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "All my life I've felt like I was here and somewhere else at the same time" Weronika lives in Poland. She lost her mother as a kid. She has a gift for music, and especially singing. She likes to apply a golden ring around her eye. She runs a lot. She is always breathless because of a heart defect that she is unaware of. She is searching for love. Veronique lives in France. She lost her mother as a kid. She has a gift for music, and she teaches it to young children. She likes to apply a golden ring around her eye. She runs a lot. She is always breathless because of a heart defect that has just been found out. She is searching for love. Weronika sees V&eacute;ronique in Krakow, the city she lives in. She stops in the middle of a place crowded with people demonstrating and riot squads. Her alter ego is getting on a bus which will take her back to France. Before the bus leaves, V&eacute;ronique has time to take pictures of the place and of Weronika, but she does not see her. During the first half-hour of the film, the subjective shots which represent Weronika's vision are unsteady, the fisheye angle twists the perspectives, until Weronika herself collapses, on the stage, among the music instruments and in front of the audience, in the middle of a song. After Weronika's death, we follow V&eacute;ronique. She is making love with a man, and, right after it, she feels an immense sadness. She says to her lover &laquo; It's as if I were grieving &raquo; but she is unable to explain why. She decides to give up on the concert she was preparing, the same concert, we can imagine, during which Weronika died. V&eacute;ronique follows her intuition, and Weronika's death prevents her from dying herself. In the school where V&eacute;ronique teaches, a man manipulates puppets for the children. He makes the puppet die and become a sort of angel. Later on, V&eacute;tonique receives an anonymous phone call, then she gets a lace in the mail, and then an audio tape thanks to which she finds the place from where the anonymous man sends his objects to her. She finds him in a bar in the Gare Saint Lazare in Paris. She recognizes the puppeteer. In a hotel, after they have made love, and confessed their love, she empties her purse on the bed because he wants to know her better. He looks at the photos she took during her trip in Eastern Europe. He says that she is pretty on the pictures. She notices Weronika for the first time. She starts to cry. Weeks, maybe months later, she wakes up in the middle of the night and finds her lover making a second puppet of herself. She asks why he made two puppets of her, and he says that it is because they get damaged. She manipulates one puppet, while the other is lying motionless. The puppeteer reads to her the first version of a tale he is writing about two women on two different continents who are in fact two versions of the same person. This focus on the puppets reminded me of an essay written by Furio Jesi on Rilke's poetry. Jesi writes: the doll, in its form, tragically announces to men that it is her, not them, who will survive in the Infinite. &raquo;. To me, the puppets are a reminder of the fate that awaits V&eacute;ronique as well, that is death. The two women will disappear in death but the two puppets will remain. There is a very important dreamlike dimension in the film which features a dwarf who is also a lawyer, an old exhibitionnist, conversations of secondary characters with no beginning and no end, a subjective shot of the dead Weronika being buried. The film is also very poetic. I think of two shots in particular: the two versions of the old lady crossing the screen, and the image of the old church reflected backwards in a plastic ball. To appreciate this film, you need to get rid of the need to understand and analyze everything, and accept the absurd side of reality. My sister saw the film with me, and at one point she said: &laquo; there is something in this film that is us. &raquo; That &laquo; something &raquo; can be defined as the atmosphere, the setting, the green and red colors. the light. Kieslowski's movie addresses that part of our brain that is the center of our emotions, of our sensations, and of the memories of those sensations. It remains with us like an old dream that we had forgotten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Double Life of V&eacute;ronique
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Krzysztof Kieslowski (Dekalog: The Ten Commandments, Three Colours: Blue), I read a little about this film before watching it, and obviously it was in the book 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die, so I was hoping it was going to be a deserving placement. Basically the story starts in Poland with the life of young Polish woman Weronika (Ir&egrave;ne Jacob) who has a keen ambition to become a singer, and aside caring for her sick Aunt (Halina Gryglaszewska) in Krak&oacute;w, she is prepared to leave most things to achieve this dream, including spending time with her boyfriend Antek (Jerzy Gudejko). She gets noticed by turning up at a concert rehearsal session, impressing the musical director with her beautiful high soprano voice and offered an audition, and eventually she is successful, and she reconnects with Antek who has been following her somewhat, but when she finally gets on stage to enchant an audience with her she sings her parts, but collapses and dies during performance. The story then shifts to Paris where on the same day young French woman V&eacute;ronique (Ir&egrave;ne Jacob), a doppelg&auml;nger who in a sudden moment feels grief and sadness, she teaches music and takes her class to see a musical piece by the same composer who performed with Weronika, conductor Van den Budenmayer (Aleksander Bardini), and in a few instances she hears more of his music playing in places. The next day she tells her father that she is in love, all of the sudden with a man she has never met, after receiving an odd shoelace in a letter envelope she believes it is from a puppeteer she has seen a few times, also a children's book author who in one his stories mentions a shoelace, Alexandre Fabbri (Philippe Volter), and she reads more of his work, and also hears more Budenmayer music, including sounds of a car accident. V&eacute;ronique feels manipulated finding out that it was Alexandre wanting to gain her attention and meet again, she eventually lets him off and they sleep together and make love, and the next morning he finds a photo of Weronika that obviously looks just like V&eacute;ronique, but she denies it is her as he is the one who took the photo. The end of the film sees Alexandre working on a new book, focusing on the lives of two women born on the same day in different cities of the world with a strange connection, obviously based on what he found falling with V&eacute;ronique and finding out about Weronika. Also starring Kalina Jedrusik as Gaudy woman, Wladyslaw Kowalski as Weronika's father, Janusz Sterninski as Lawyer, Sandrine Dumas as Catherine and Louis Ducreux as Teacher. As the two identical women Jacob gives a performance worth watching, but I will be honest and say that I much preferred the first woman more than her second because she has an extraordinary singing voice that goes perfectly with the opera music, the second performance for lacked as much depth, in fact, I found after the first woman's death the rest of the film was a tiny bit slowed down, nevertheless overall it is a worthwhile drama. It was nominated the Golden Globe for Best Foreign Language Film. Good, in my opinion!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Makes You Feel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brtndr
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It makes you feel like you've fallen asleep and entered into someone else's surrealistic dream world. Fortunately, there are two beautiful young women Veronique and Veronicka (both played by Irene Jacobs) who are at the center of that alien dream world you've entered into. And, you are just as engaged in the lives of the two woman as you would be if your own life was passing before your eyes. The two lives of Veronique and Veronicka reflect each other, but are only subconsciously aware of it, which is eerie in its very nature. Two people who have two entirely different lives, obviously destined to never really meet, but unexpectedly spot each other across a crowded court yard one day. The experience briefly hypnotically paralyzes them both as they stare in amazement at the sight of one another. A moment that appears to confirm for both woman what they've always felt, but could never bring themselves to believe until then. This encounter between the two ends as quickly as it accidentally occurred, and they continue on with their separate lives without ever really acknowledging the entire breadth and depth of their shared accidental encounter. However, after the experience neither one of them are the same physically or emotionally again. There is so much going on both visually and emotionally in the film which makes 'The Double Life of Veronique' one of the most worthy films for endless coffee house discussions and analysis. A highly recommended A+ excellent foreign movie that you'll enjoy discussing for hours afterwards with cinema enthusiast. Perhaps, while enjoying a cup of Mocha Espresso with a dollop of milk?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reflections from the looking glass
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Artimidor Federkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here's a kind of movie that helps you think outside the proverbial box: Meet V&eacute;ronique,the French protagonist who chances upon a most unusual face - en passant, in a fleeting moment, like a reminder from another life. The face of the person she sees is her own. Somewhere on Polish plaza, to briefly surface and drown again in the crowd. "La Double vie de V&eacute;ronique" teaches you to appreciate escaping the comfort zone of trusted logic, recognize its pitfalls and see a strange, maybe even absurd fantastic premise in an otherwise realistic picture as a chance to discover something that cannot be named. Sure, Kieslowski pictures are always a combination of beautiful images, evocative music and a strong cerebral component, but "La double vie de V&eacute;ronique" is his most enigmatic, thought provoking work. Various threads are spun by writer and director which appeal to the viewer's imagination, so that they may be connected or respected just the way they are. Or perhaps seen as a whole in the eye of the beholder in front of the screen: Two different lives, one face, strings attached or mere coincidence? Is there fate? Does the demiurge work as puppeteer or are our actions influencing others in a way we would never anticipate? There are no metaphors in my work, Kiesloswki once said. Sounds challenging? Feel free to connect your own dots in this magical adventure of parallelism seen through the looking glass! Just one thing: The purpose of art is not to provide answers and be prescriptive in its implications, be they moral, social, historic or otherwise, but rather to open up new pathways and perspectives and question what we've been used to take for granted. In this respect Kieslowski succeeds indubitably and delivers a dazzling work of art to be looked at. Again and again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ethereal Irene Jacob
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The premise of this film is based on the old legend that we all have a twin somewhere in the world. Weronika is a Polish opera singer who while performing at an outdoor concert, continues to sing in a heavy rainstorm. Afterwards, she meets her boyfriend, Antek, and they get it on. She tells her father that she does not feel alone in the world. She visits her aunt in Krakow and meets a friend at a concert rehearsal. While listening, she sings along and the director is so impressed with her voice that he asks her to audition. While walking down a street during a protest rally, she notices a woman taking photos of the crowd. The lady looks like her twin. Her double gets on a bus which drives away. She passes the audition and the following night, and while singing a solo at a concert, collapses and dies on stage. Her spirit travels over the audience. That same day in Paris, Veronique(Irene Jacob), feels a great sadness for no apparent reason. Later, at her classroom, she leads her students in a classical piece by the same composer that Weronika was performing when she died., Veronique falls in love with a puppeteer and writer named Alexandre and as the couple go through a photo album, he sees a picture which looks like her. Veronique explains that it can't possibly be her, since she took the photo. There is no real ending for Double Life, but Irene Jacob in the dual role, makes it work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spooky-wooky does not a movie make
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xXBoss-EbertXx
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Seinfeld said his show was about "nothing," but it had the contents of the Encyclopedia Britannica compared to this movie. Quelle waste of time sitting through this! It moved at the speed of a glacier and made absolutely no sense at all. To it's credit, La double vie de V&eacute;ronique is FAR from what you'd ever see in an American theatre, but in this case, that might not be a good thing. This film is an exercise in banality compared to the remake, I Know Who Killed Me (2007), a modern day erotic masterpiece. I would also like to add that the picture quality here wasn't that great either. It is just a poor release of this film in almost every area. ...disjointed script bordering on HBO style "erotica", with probably the worse subtitling I have ever seen. The movie ends abruptly like they just simply ran out of film. Avoid this one. For the amount of money the producers spent on this, the movie's quality is terrible. Everything is underlit and murky as if the film was dropped in a swamp prior to being developed, and that's when you're lucky enough to view a scene that's actually in-focus. The sound is poorly dubbed, much of the music is awkward and the editing is god awful. Let's not kid ourselves here, all ye art students, film-school nerds, and other self-loathing "cinema l'arte" snobs: had this exact same movie been released under the banner "directed by Pier Paolo Pasolini" you would have loved it - sorry: CLAIMED to have loved it - and praised it to high heaven, espousing its virtues in long essays, justifying its extreme sex and violence through some b.s. semantic pseudo-intellectual movie-critic-jargon mumbo-jumbo. A corny, historically inaccurate, fairy-tale-like piece of crap like "Gandhi" gets world-wide recognition, while a brutally realistic film about another historical figure, called "Caligula" gets the finger. Go figure. Go on, admit it. No-one will laugh. We promise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Down Memory Lane.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Traversa
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Have you seen, read or heard "The Glass Menagerie" by Tennesse Williams? If you remember, the play is told by the main character in the present time, he tells us about his past life, lost forever, as well as the characters that were essential in his life at that time, "This play is memory" he says. Well, my review for this film is also memory, since I saw it at the time of its premiere and never again. I happened to be listening a program on France culture radio on the Internet and they mentioned this film, it instantly came back to my memory: One of the best films I had ever seen, next to "Tous les matins du monde", "Barry Lyndon", "Tom Jones" and a few others. I should see it again to experience that sometimes disappointing sensation of coming down with a sad feeling of having outgrown an old film that in our memory was fantastic. On the other hand, there are also those old films that when seeing them again after so many years, they are as fresh as ever, as I'm sure is the case with this one. I remember that I was mesmerized at the end of the projection (I saw it at a movie house in Barcelona) and thought at the time that it was a perfect movie, something so rare and unusual to find. So far, and --again-- in my memory, it it one of the best films I have ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It has an effect for everybody in some way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Harsanyi
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film just inspired me to watch more older films. In the summer i was in a Christian camp where they showed the main scene (for me it is) when Alexandre Fabbri is playing with the marionette ballerina. When I arrived home I immediately started searching for this film and finally i found it! It took me 3 days to watch it. This became my favorite film of all my life. There are scenes and quotes that mean so much to me. I feel I am not the only one with this feeling because as I can see, there are events that are alternative, and has effects that are different for you and your friends either.What is the most interesting thing what i've ever seen/heard? There is only one music in the film and makes you happy or sad depending on the scene. The cameraman's work is excellent too! :) I absolutely would nominate this for Golden Globe of all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Condemned to death
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    randomchoice
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I hated this movie while watching it.After much debating with myself and a friend I have come to the conclusion that this movie is about death. While I still have no sympathy for anyone or anything in the movie, I think the movie is nevertheless a lot more coherent than I initially thought, and for this - and also for the excellent filmography - I am giving it an 8/10. (1) A friend of mine suggested this movie is about the various possibilities of existence which cannot be realized simultaneously in real life. I felt this wasn't right but I didn't have another interpretation to offer. But now I do. Let's see what Weronika and Veronique are all about: (a) Similarities They are both sickly creatures. They have a father, they don't have a mother. They are both engaged with music. They know and interact with a series of characters of no consequence (the aunt, the colleague from school, etc.) They both appear in a love relationship where their lovers are more involved than themselves. They both dismiss those lovers. They both have a plastic (?) ball and are fascinated by what the world looks like as reflected through it. They both watch an old woman through the window. They both seem to drift without touching the world around them. They both see their doppelg&auml;nger. (b) Differences Weronika lives in Poland. She is not independent (lives with her dad / aunt). She seems young and inexperienced. She moves to another city for the sake of her aunt. Feels that she is not alone in the world. She dies singing. Veronique lives in France. She is financially independent (she lives on her own, has her own job). She seems more mature, and already anchored in music (she has a music teacher, she teaches music). She quits her music lessons although her teacher thinks she has a great talent. She feels alone in the world. She falls in love (Weronika never seems in love; talking to her aunt, she seems excited to have slept with that guy but abandons him). She accepts the game played on her by the anonymous stalker. She becomes acquainted with her puppeteer. She sees her doppelg&auml;nger, in the end. She begins to see how he may be the one manipulating her. Veronique's story begins as Weronika dies. This chronological details is supported by the photo / negative from Poland, which is the moment when the stories of the two girls become anchored in reality and aligned in a particular chronological order. So far, what does this movie seem to be about? Let's say that Veronique's first apparition and inexplicable grief is a premonition of what might happen to her if she continues taking music lessons / trying to make a career in music. This premonition leads her to abandon her existential possibility of realizing her potential through music. Having abandoned this possibility (I don't feel like it should be called her 'ideal' - Veronique doesn't really seem to have a passion, a dream, an ideal!), she somehow loses her path. Is she the ballerina who breaks her leg and then turns into a butterfly, as the ballerina in the puppeteer's story? This seems rather to be Weronika's story. Veronique refuses to break her leg, so there's no question of her turning into a butterfly. Is, then, the movie about a character with a talent for music to whom her talent is fatal, and for whom abandoning the talent would lead to perdition all the same? If yes, then the movie does make sense, although I'm still not sure about the puppeteer. It's as if the puppeteer had somehow condemned both these girls to death, and loves them when they have accepted their sentence. (Antek too could be some kind of a puppeteer: he tells Weronika he loves her only after she had come to the city and was already pursuing her talent! Likewise, Alexandre too tells Veronique he loves her only after she had accepted to enter the game of the anonymous caller.) If this death sentence were the true meaning of the movie, then it also would be easier to understand why Veronique has two lovers (the first, unnamed one, and then, Alexandre), and Weronika only one: Veronique quits music and drives away her first lover, and this could be a rejection of dying for her talent. Her condemnation to death is, however, still there: having failed to kill her through music, the puppeteer steps in himself. The weird thing about this interpretation is that, although both girls do seem to have some relation to music, neither of them gives the impression that music is the biggest thing in their lives. Music is just something they happen to be good at, good enough to be remarked and regretted when they cannot / refuse to pursue it. For the rest, these girls look like lambs brought to the slaughterhouse. For example, when Weronika's aunt asks her how her audition had gone, Weronika answers something like (I don't remember the exact wording): it went TOO well. Apathetic... (2) My conclusion about the movie After lots of thinking, here's, then, my conclusion regarding what this movie is about: I think it is about condemnation to death, regardless of other life details. This idea seems supported by that episode where Veronique holds the shoestring across the graph paper in a straight line over her recent EKG graph. The straight line of an EKG = death. Everything else in the movie is ballast. The doppelg&auml;nger thing is rather a red herring: it muddles the waters without any pay-off, really. Now I understand why the music is throughout so sad / sinister. Also, why there is so much ballast, so many gestures of no consequence. So many attempts at a plot but with no actual realization. The characters are doomed, and that's all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Cinematic, cinematographic, psychological and lyrical..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Polish screenwriter and director Krzysztof Kieslowski's ninth feature film which he co-wrote with Polish screenwriter Krzysztof Piesiewicz, premiered In competition at the 44th Cannes International Film Festival in 1991, was shot on location in France and Poland and is a France-Poland-Norway co-production which was produced by producer Leonardo De La Fuente. It tells the story about and educated singer and pianist named Weronika who lives in an apartment in Poland and who is in a relationship with a man named Antek. After experiencing a feeling of not being alone which she is instigated to act upon, Weronika travels to Krakow where her aunt lives and when she gets there she notices a woman whom she has never seen before and who bears a striking resemblance to herself. Distinctly and subtly directed by Polish filmmaker Krzysztof Kieslowski, this finely tuned fictional tale which is narrated mostly from the two main character's point of view, draws a virtuous portrayal of the life of a Polish woman named Weronika and a French woman named Veroniqu&eacute; who are identical and who one day coincidentally or determined by destiny crosses paths. While notable for it's naturalistic and atmospheric milieu depictions, distinct production design by production designer Patrice Mercier, cinematography by polish cinematographer Slawomir Idziak, costume design by costume designers Laurence Brignon, Claudy Fellous and Elzbieta Radke, fine editing by French film editor Jacques Witta and use of colors and light, this character-driven and narrative-driven story where the director could focus more on the cinematic aspects of his film and less on the political which was characteristic in many of his previous productions due to the political situation in his country, depicts two interrelated and empathic studies of character and contains a great score by Polish composer Zbigniew Preisner. This dramatic, literary, somewhat surreal, romantic and humanistic drama from the early 1990s about identity and faith which is the last feature film Krzysztof Kieslowski made before ending his career with the Three Colours trilogy which consisted of "Blue" (1993), "White" (1994) and "Red" (1994) and which is set in the capital city of France and the capital city of Poland in the early 1990s and where a music teacher for children named Veroniqu&eacute; who lives in France experiences a feeling of being alone, is impelled and reinforced by it's brilliant narrative structure, substantial character development, subtle continuity, interrelated stories, endearing characters, poetic scenes and the memorable acting performance by French actress Ir&egrave;ne Jacob. A cinematic, cinematographic, psychological and lyrical mystery which gained, among numerous other awards, the FIPRESCI Prize Krzysztof Kieslowski, the Prize of the Ecumenical Jury and the award for Best Actress Ir&egrave;ne Jacob at the 44th Cannes Film Festival in 1991.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    levelllll5
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "All my life I've felt like I was here and somewhere else at the same time" Weronika lives in Poland. She lost her mother as a kid. She has a gift for music, and especially singing. She likes to apply a golden ring around her eye. She runs a lot. She is always breathless because of a heart defect that she is unaware of. She is searching for love. Veronique lives in France. She lost her mother as a kid. She has a gift for music, and she teaches it to young children. She likes to apply a golden ring around her eye. She runs a lot. She is always breathless because of a heart defect that has just been found out. She is searching for love. Weronika sees V&eacute;ronique in Krakow, the city she lives in. She stops in the middle of a place crowded with people demonstrating and riot squads. Her alter ego is getting on a bus which will take her back to France. Before the bus leaves, V&eacute;ronique has time to take pictures of the place and of Weronika, but she does not see her. During the first half-hour of the film, the subjective shots which represent Weronika's vision are unsteady, the fisheye angle twists the perspectives, until Weronika herself collapses, on the stage, among the music instruments and in front of the audience, in the middle of a song. After Weronika's death, we follow V&eacute;ronique. She is making love with a man, and, right after it, she feels an immense sadness. She says to her lover &laquo; It's as if I were grieving &raquo; but she is unable to explain why. She decides to give up on the concert she was preparing, the same concert, we can imagine, during which Weronika died. V&eacute;ronique follows her intuition, and Weronika's death prevents her from dying herself. In the school where V&eacute;ronique teaches, a man manipulates puppets for the children. He makes the puppet die and become a sort of angel. Later on, V&eacute;tonique receives an anonymous phone call, then she gets a lace in the mail, and then an audio tape thanks to which she finds the place from where the anonymous man sends his objects to her. She finds him in a bar in the Gare Saint Lazare in Paris. She recognizes the puppeteer. In a hotel, after they have made love, and confessed their love, she empties her purse on the bed because he wants to know her better. He looks at the photos she took during her trip in Eastern Europe. He says that she is pretty on the pictures. She notices Weronika for the first time. She starts to cry. Weeks, maybe months later, she wakes up in the middle of the night and finds her lover making a second puppet of herself. She asks why he made two puppets of her, and he says that it is because they get damaged. She manipulates one puppet, while the other is lying motionless. The puppeteer reads to her the first version of a tale he is writing about two women on two different continents who are in fact two versions of the same person. This focus on the puppets reminded me of an essay written by Furio Jesi on Rilke's poetry. Jesi writes: the doll, in its form, tragically announces to men that it is her, not them, who will survive in the Infinite. &raquo;. To me, the puppets are a reminder of the fate that awaits V&eacute;ronique as well, that is death. The two women will disappear in death but the two puppets will remain. There is a very important dreamlike dimension in the film which features a dwarf who is also a lawyer, an old exhibitionnist, conversations of secondary characters with no beginning and no end, a subjective shot of the dead Weronika being buried. The film is also very poetic. I think of two shots in particular: the two versions of the old lady crossing the screen, and the image of the old church reflected backwards in a plastic ball. To appreciate this film, you need to get rid of the need to understand and analyze everything, and accept the absurd side of reality. My sister saw the film with me, and at one point she said: &laquo; there is something in this film that is us. &raquo; That &laquo; something &raquo; can be defined as the atmosphere, the setting, the green and red colors. the light. Kieslowski's movie addresses that part of our brain that is the center of our emotions, of our sensations, and of the memories of those sensations. It remains with us like an old dream that we had forgotten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Double Life of V&eacute;ronique
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Krzysztof Kieslowski (Dekalog: The Ten Commandments, Three Colours: Blue), I read a little about this film before watching it, and obviously it was in the book 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die, so I was hoping it was going to be a deserving placement. Basically the story starts in Poland with the life of young Polish woman Weronika (Ir&egrave;ne Jacob) who has a keen ambition to become a singer, and aside caring for her sick Aunt (Halina Gryglaszewska) in Krak&oacute;w, she is prepared to leave most things to achieve this dream, including spending time with her boyfriend Antek (Jerzy Gudejko). She gets noticed by turning up at a concert rehearsal session, impressing the musical director with her beautiful high soprano voice and offered an audition, and eventually she is successful, and she reconnects with Antek who has been following her somewhat, but when she finally gets on stage to enchant an audience with her she sings her parts, but collapses and dies during performance. The story then shifts to Paris where on the same day young French woman V&eacute;ronique (Ir&egrave;ne Jacob), a doppelg&auml;nger who in a sudden moment feels grief and sadness, she teaches music and takes her class to see a musical piece by the same composer who performed with Weronika, conductor Van den Budenmayer (Aleksander Bardini), and in a few instances she hears more of his music playing in places. The next day she tells her father that she is in love, all of the sudden with a man she has never met, after receiving an odd shoelace in a letter envelope she believes it is from a puppeteer she has seen a few times, also a children's book author who in one his stories mentions a shoelace, Alexandre Fabbri (Philippe Volter), and she reads more of his work, and also hears more Budenmayer music, including sounds of a car accident. V&eacute;ronique feels manipulated finding out that it was Alexandre wanting to gain her attention and meet again, she eventually lets him off and they sleep together and make love, and the next morning he finds a photo of Weronika that obviously looks just like V&eacute;ronique, but she denies it is her as he is the one who took the photo. The end of the film sees Alexandre working on a new book, focusing on the lives of two women born on the same day in different cities of the world with a strange connection, obviously based on what he found falling with V&eacute;ronique and finding out about Weronika. Also starring Kalina Jedrusik as Gaudy woman, Wladyslaw Kowalski as Weronika's father, Janusz Sterninski as Lawyer, Sandrine Dumas as Catherine and Louis Ducreux as Teacher. As the two identical women Jacob gives a performance worth watching, but I will be honest and say that I much preferred the first woman more than her second because she has an extraordinary singing voice that goes perfectly with the opera music, the second performance for lacked as much depth, in fact, I found after the first woman's death the rest of the film was a tiny bit slowed down, nevertheless overall it is a worthwhile drama. It was nominated the Golden Globe for Best Foreign Language Film. Good, in my opinion!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Makes You Feel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brtndr
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It makes you feel like you've fallen asleep and entered into someone else's surrealistic dream world. Fortunately, there are two beautiful young women Veronique and Veronicka (both played by Irene Jacobs) who are at the center of that alien dream world you've entered into. And, you are just as engaged in the lives of the two woman as you would be if your own life was passing before your eyes. The two lives of Veronique and Veronicka reflect each other, but are only subconsciously aware of it, which is eerie in its very nature. Two people who have two entirely different lives, obviously destined to never really meet, but unexpectedly spot each other across a crowded court yard one day. The experience briefly hypnotically paralyzes them both as they stare in amazement at the sight of one another. A moment that appears to confirm for both woman what they've always felt, but could never bring themselves to believe until then. This encounter between the two ends as quickly as it accidentally occurred, and they continue on with their separate lives without ever really acknowledging the entire breadth and depth of their shared accidental encounter. However, after the experience neither one of them are the same physically or emotionally again. There is so much going on both visually and emotionally in the film which makes 'The Double Life of Veronique' one of the most worthy films for endless coffee house discussions and analysis. A highly recommended A+ excellent foreign movie that you'll enjoy discussing for hours afterwards with cinema enthusiast. Perhaps, while enjoying a cup of Mocha Espresso with a dollop of milk?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reflections from the looking glass
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Artimidor Federkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here's a kind of movie that helps you think outside the proverbial box: Meet V&eacute;ronique,the French protagonist who chances upon a most unusual face - en passant, in a fleeting moment, like a reminder from another life. The face of the person she sees is her own. Somewhere on Polish plaza, to briefly surface and drown again in the crowd. "La Double vie de V&eacute;ronique" teaches you to appreciate escaping the comfort zone of trusted logic, recognize its pitfalls and see a strange, maybe even absurd fantastic premise in an otherwise realistic picture as a chance to discover something that cannot be named. Sure, Kieslowski pictures are always a combination of beautiful images, evocative music and a strong cerebral component, but "La double vie de V&eacute;ronique" is his most enigmatic, thought provoking work. Various threads are spun by writer and director which appeal to the viewer's imagination, so that they may be connected or respected just the way they are. Or perhaps seen as a whole in the eye of the beholder in front of the screen: Two different lives, one face, strings attached or mere coincidence? Is there fate? Does the demiurge work as puppeteer or are our actions influencing others in a way we would never anticipate? There are no metaphors in my work, Kiesloswki once said. Sounds challenging? Feel free to connect your own dots in this magical adventure of parallelism seen through the looking glass! Just one thing: The purpose of art is not to provide answers and be prescriptive in its implications, be they moral, social, historic or otherwise, but rather to open up new pathways and perspectives and question what we've been used to take for granted. In this respect Kieslowski succeeds indubitably and delivers a dazzling work of art to be looked at. Again and again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ethereal Irene Jacob
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The premise of this film is based on the old legend that we all have a twin somewhere in the world. Weronika is a Polish opera singer who while performing at an outdoor concert, continues to sing in a heavy rainstorm. Afterwards, she meets her boyfriend, Antek, and they get it on. She tells her father that she does not feel alone in the world. She visits her aunt in Krakow and meets a friend at a concert rehearsal. While listening, she sings along and the director is so impressed with her voice that he asks her to audition. While walking down a street during a protest rally, she notices a woman taking photos of the crowd. The lady looks like her twin. Her double gets on a bus which drives away. She passes the audition and the following night, and while singing a solo at a concert, collapses and dies on stage. Her spirit travels over the audience. That same day in Paris, Veronique(Irene Jacob), feels a great sadness for no apparent reason. Later, at her classroom, she leads her students in a classical piece by the same composer that Weronika was performing when she died., Veronique falls in love with a puppeteer and writer named Alexandre and as the couple go through a photo album, he sees a picture which looks like her. Veronique explains that it can't possibly be her, since she took the photo. There is no real ending for Double Life, but Irene Jacob in the dual role, makes it work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spooky-wooky does not a movie make
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xXBoss-EbertXx
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Seinfeld said his show was about "nothing," but it had the contents of the Encyclopedia Britannica compared to this movie. Quelle waste of time sitting through this! It moved at the speed of a glacier and made absolutely no sense at all. To it's credit, La double vie de V&eacute;ronique is FAR from what you'd ever see in an American theatre, but in this case, that might not be a good thing. This film is an exercise in banality compared to the remake, I Know Who Killed Me (2007), a modern day erotic masterpiece. I would also like to add that the picture quality here wasn't that great either. It is just a poor release of this film in almost every area. ...disjointed script bordering on HBO style "erotica", with probably the worse subtitling I have ever seen. The movie ends abruptly like they just simply ran out of film. Avoid this one. For the amount of money the producers spent on this, the movie's quality is terrible. Everything is underlit and murky as if the film was dropped in a swamp prior to being developed, and that's when you're lucky enough to view a scene that's actually in-focus. The sound is poorly dubbed, much of the music is awkward and the editing is god awful. Let's not kid ourselves here, all ye art students, film-school nerds, and other self-loathing "cinema l'arte" snobs: had this exact same movie been released under the banner "directed by Pier Paolo Pasolini" you would have loved it - sorry: CLAIMED to have loved it - and praised it to high heaven, espousing its virtues in long essays, justifying its extreme sex and violence through some b.s. semantic pseudo-intellectual movie-critic-jargon mumbo-jumbo. A corny, historically inaccurate, fairy-tale-like piece of crap like "Gandhi" gets world-wide recognition, while a brutally realistic film about another historical figure, called "Caligula" gets the finger. Go figure. Go on, admit it. No-one will laugh. We promise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Down Memory Lane.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Traversa
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Have you seen, read or heard "The Glass Menagerie" by Tennesse Williams? If you remember, the play is told by the main character in the present time, he tells us about his past life, lost forever, as well as the characters that were essential in his life at that time, "This play is memory" he says. Well, my review for this film is also memory, since I saw it at the time of its premiere and never again. I happened to be listening a program on France culture radio on the Internet and they mentioned this film, it instantly came back to my memory: One of the best films I had ever seen, next to "Tous les matins du monde", "Barry Lyndon", "Tom Jones" and a few others. I should see it again to experience that sometimes disappointing sensation of coming down with a sad feeling of having outgrown an old film that in our memory was fantastic. On the other hand, there are also those old films that when seeing them again after so many years, they are as fresh as ever, as I'm sure is the case with this one. I remember that I was mesmerized at the end of the projection (I saw it at a movie house in Barcelona) and thought at the time that it was a perfect movie, something so rare and unusual to find. So far, and --again-- in my memory, it it one of the best films I have ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It has an effect for everybody in some way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Harsanyi
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film just inspired me to watch more older films. In the summer i was in a Christian camp where they showed the main scene (for me it is) when Alexandre Fabbri is playing with the marionette ballerina. When I arrived home I immediately started searching for this film and finally i found it! It took me 3 days to watch it. This became my favorite film of all my life. There are scenes and quotes that mean so much to me. I feel I am not the only one with this feeling because as I can see, there are events that are alternative, and has effects that are different for you and your friends either.What is the most interesting thing what i've ever seen/heard? There is only one music in the film and makes you happy or sad depending on the scene. The cameraman's work is excellent too! :) I absolutely would nominate this for Golden Globe of all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Condemned to death
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    randomchoice
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I hated this movie while watching it.After much debating with myself and a friend I have come to the conclusion that this movie is about death. While I still have no sympathy for anyone or anything in the movie, I think the movie is nevertheless a lot more coherent than I initially thought, and for this - and also for the excellent filmography - I am giving it an 8/10. (1) A friend of mine suggested this movie is about the various possibilities of existence which cannot be realized simultaneously in real life. I felt this wasn't right but I didn't have another interpretation to offer. But now I do. Let's see what Weronika and Veronique are all about: (a) Similarities They are both sickly creatures. They have a father, they don't have a mother. They are both engaged with music. They know and interact with a series of characters of no consequence (the aunt, the colleague from school, etc.) They both appear in a love relationship where their lovers are more involved than themselves. They both dismiss those lovers. They both have a plastic (?) ball and are fascinated by what the world looks like as reflected through it. They both watch an old woman through the window. They both seem to drift without touching the world around them. They both see their doppelg&auml;nger. (b) Differences Weronika lives in Poland. She is not independent (lives with her dad / aunt). She seems young and inexperienced. She moves to another city for the sake of her aunt. Feels that she is not alone in the world. She dies singing. Veronique lives in France. She is financially independent (she lives on her own, has her own job). She seems more mature, and already anchored in music (she has a music teacher, she teaches music). She quits her music lessons although her teacher thinks she has a great talent. She feels alone in the world. She falls in love (Weronika never seems in love; talking to her aunt, she seems excited to have slept with that guy but abandons him). She accepts the game played on her by the anonymous stalker. She becomes acquainted with her puppeteer. She sees her doppelg&auml;nger, in the end. She begins to see how he may be the one manipulating her. Veronique's story begins as Weronika dies. This chronological details is supported by the photo / negative from Poland, which is the moment when the stories of the two girls become anchored in reality and aligned in a particular chronological order. So far, what does this movie seem to be about? Let's say that Veronique's first apparition and inexplicable grief is a premonition of what might happen to her if she continues taking music lessons / trying to make a career in music. This premonition leads her to abandon her existential possibility of realizing her potential through music. Having abandoned this possibility (I don't feel like it should be called her 'ideal' - Veronique doesn't really seem to have a passion, a dream, an ideal!), she somehow loses her path. Is she the ballerina who breaks her leg and then turns into a butterfly, as the ballerina in the puppeteer's story? This seems rather to be Weronika's story. Veronique refuses to break her leg, so there's no question of her turning into a butterfly. Is, then, the movie about a character with a talent for music to whom her talent is fatal, and for whom abandoning the talent would lead to perdition all the same? If yes, then the movie does make sense, although I'm still not sure about the puppeteer. It's as if the puppeteer had somehow condemned both these girls to death, and loves them when they have accepted their sentence. (Antek too could be some kind of a puppeteer: he tells Weronika he loves her only after she had come to the city and was already pursuing her talent! Likewise, Alexandre too tells Veronique he loves her only after she had accepted to enter the game of the anonymous caller.) If this death sentence were the true meaning of the movie, then it also would be easier to understand why Veronique has two lovers (the first, unnamed one, and then, Alexandre), and Weronika only one: Veronique quits music and drives away her first lover, and this could be a rejection of dying for her talent. Her condemnation to death is, however, still there: having failed to kill her through music, the puppeteer steps in himself. The weird thing about this interpretation is that, although both girls do seem to have some relation to music, neither of them gives the impression that music is the biggest thing in their lives. Music is just something they happen to be good at, good enough to be remarked and regretted when they cannot / refuse to pursue it. For the rest, these girls look like lambs brought to the slaughterhouse. For example, when Weronika's aunt asks her how her audition had gone, Weronika answers something like (I don't remember the exact wording): it went TOO well. Apathetic... (2) My conclusion about the movie After lots of thinking, here's, then, my conclusion regarding what this movie is about: I think it is about condemnation to death, regardless of other life details. This idea seems supported by that episode where Veronique holds the shoestring across the graph paper in a straight line over her recent EKG graph. The straight line of an EKG = death. Everything else in the movie is ballast. The doppelg&auml;nger thing is rather a red herring: it muddles the waters without any pay-off, really. Now I understand why the music is throughout so sad / sinister. Also, why there is so much ballast, so many gestures of no consequence. So many attempts at a plot but with no actual realization. The characters are doomed, and that's all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Cinematic, cinematographic, psychological and lyrical..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Polish screenwriter and director Krzysztof Kieslowski's ninth feature film which he co-wrote with Polish screenwriter Krzysztof Piesiewicz, premiered In competition at the 44th Cannes International Film Festival in 1991, was shot on location in France and Poland and is a France-Poland-Norway co-production which was produced by producer Leonardo De La Fuente. It tells the story about and educated singer and pianist named Weronika who lives in an apartment in Poland and who is in a relationship with a man named Antek. After experiencing a feeling of not being alone which she is instigated to act upon, Weronika travels to Krakow where her aunt lives and when she gets there she notices a woman whom she has never seen before and who bears a striking resemblance to herself. Distinctly and subtly directed by Polish filmmaker Krzysztof Kieslowski, this finely tuned fictional tale which is narrated mostly from the two main character's point of view, draws a virtuous portrayal of the life of a Polish woman named Weronika and a French woman named Veroniqu&eacute; who are identical and who one day coincidentally or determined by destiny crosses paths. While notable for it's naturalistic and atmospheric milieu depictions, distinct production design by production designer Patrice Mercier, cinematography by polish cinematographer Slawomir Idziak, costume design by costume designers Laurence Brignon, Claudy Fellous and Elzbieta Radke, fine editing by French film editor Jacques Witta and use of colors and light, this character-driven and narrative-driven story where the director could focus more on the cinematic aspects of his film and less on the political which was characteristic in many of his previous productions due to the political situation in his country, depicts two interrelated and empathic studies of character and contains a great score by Polish composer Zbigniew Preisner. This dramatic, literary, somewhat surreal, romantic and humanistic drama from the early 1990s about identity and faith which is the last feature film Krzysztof Kieslowski made before ending his career with the Three Colours trilogy which consisted of "Blue" (1993), "White" (1994) and "Red" (1994) and which is set in the capital city of France and the capital city of Poland in the early 1990s and where a music teacher for children named Veroniqu&eacute; who lives in France experiences a feeling of being alone, is impelled and reinforced by it's brilliant narrative structure, substantial character development, subtle continuity, interrelated stories, endearing characters, poetic scenes and the memorable acting performance by French actress Ir&egrave;ne Jacob. A cinematic, cinematographic, psychological and lyrical mystery which gained, among numerous other awards, the FIPRESCI Prize Krzysztof Kieslowski, the Prize of the Ecumenical Jury and the award for Best Actress Ir&egrave;ne Jacob at the 44th Cannes Film Festival in 1991.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    levelllll5
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "All my life I've felt like I was here and somewhere else at the same time" Weronika lives in Poland. She lost her mother as a kid. She has a gift for music, and especially singing. She likes to apply a golden ring around her eye. She runs a lot. She is always breathless because of a heart defect that she is unaware of. She is searching for love. Veronique lives in France. She lost her mother as a kid. She has a gift for music, and she teaches it to young children. She likes to apply a golden ring around her eye. She runs a lot. She is always breathless because of a heart defect that has just been found out. She is searching for love. Weronika sees V&eacute;ronique in Krakow, the city she lives in. She stops in the middle of a place crowded with people demonstrating and riot squads. Her alter ego is getting on a bus which will take her back to France. Before the bus leaves, V&eacute;ronique has time to take pictures of the place and of Weronika, but she does not see her. During the first half-hour of the film, the subjective shots which represent Weronika's vision are unsteady, the fisheye angle twists the perspectives, until Weronika herself collapses, on the stage, among the music instruments and in front of the audience, in the middle of a song. After Weronika's death, we follow V&eacute;ronique. She is making love with a man, and, right after it, she feels an immense sadness. She says to her lover &laquo; It's as if I were grieving &raquo; but she is unable to explain why. She decides to give up on the concert she was preparing, the same concert, we can imagine, during which Weronika died. V&eacute;ronique follows her intuition, and Weronika's death prevents her from dying herself. In the school where V&eacute;ronique teaches, a man manipulates puppets for the children. He makes the puppet die and become a sort of angel. Later on, V&eacute;tonique receives an anonymous phone call, then she gets a lace in the mail, and then an audio tape thanks to which she finds the place from where the anonymous man sends his objects to her. She finds him in a bar in the Gare Saint Lazare in Paris. She recognizes the puppeteer. In a hotel, after they have made love, and confessed their love, she empties her purse on the bed because he wants to know her better. He looks at the photos she took during her trip in Eastern Europe. He says that she is pretty on the pictures. She notices Weronika for the first time. She starts to cry. Weeks, maybe months later, she wakes up in the middle of the night and finds her lover making a second puppet of herself. She asks why he made two puppets of her, and he says that it is because they get damaged. She manipulates one puppet, while the other is lying motionless. The puppeteer reads to her the first version of a tale he is writing about two women on two different continents who are in fact two versions of the same person. This focus on the puppets reminded me of an essay written by Furio Jesi on Rilke's poetry. Jesi writes: the doll, in its form, tragically announces to men that it is her, not them, who will survive in the Infinite. &raquo;. To me, the puppets are a reminder of the fate that awaits V&eacute;ronique as well, that is death. The two women will disappear in death but the two puppets will remain. There is a very important dreamlike dimension in the film which features a dwarf who is also a lawyer, an old exhibitionnist, conversations of secondary characters with no beginning and no end, a subjective shot of the dead Weronika being buried. The film is also very poetic. I think of two shots in particular: the two versions of the old lady crossing the screen, and the image of the old church reflected backwards in a plastic ball. To appreciate this film, you need to get rid of the need to understand and analyze everything, and accept the absurd side of reality. My sister saw the film with me, and at one point she said: &laquo; there is something in this film that is us. &raquo; That &laquo; something &raquo; can be defined as the atmosphere, the setting, the green and red colors. the light. Kieslowski's movie addresses that part of our brain that is the center of our emotions, of our sensations, and of the memories of those sensations. It remains with us like an old dream that we had forgotten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Double Life of V&eacute;ronique
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Krzysztof Kieslowski (Dekalog: The Ten Commandments, Three Colours: Blue), I read a little about this film before watching it, and obviously it was in the book 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die, so I was hoping it was going to be a deserving placement. Basically the story starts in Poland with the life of young Polish woman Weronika (Ir&egrave;ne Jacob) who has a keen ambition to become a singer, and aside caring for her sick Aunt (Halina Gryglaszewska) in Krak&oacute;w, she is prepared to leave most things to achieve this dream, including spending time with her boyfriend Antek (Jerzy Gudejko). She gets noticed by turning up at a concert rehearsal session, impressing the musical director with her beautiful high soprano voice and offered an audition, and eventually she is successful, and she reconnects with Antek who has been following her somewhat, but when she finally gets on stage to enchant an audience with her she sings her parts, but collapses and dies during performance. The story then shifts to Paris where on the same day young French woman V&eacute;ronique (Ir&egrave;ne Jacob), a doppelg&auml;nger who in a sudden moment feels grief and sadness, she teaches music and takes her class to see a musical piece by the same composer who performed with Weronika, conductor Van den Budenmayer (Aleksander Bardini), and in a few instances she hears more of his music playing in places. The next day she tells her father that she is in love, all of the sudden with a man she has never met, after receiving an odd shoelace in a letter envelope she believes it is from a puppeteer she has seen a few times, also a children's book author who in one his stories mentions a shoelace, Alexandre Fabbri (Philippe Volter), and she reads more of his work, and also hears more Budenmayer music, including sounds of a car accident. V&eacute;ronique feels manipulated finding out that it was Alexandre wanting to gain her attention and meet again, she eventually lets him off and they sleep together and make love, and the next morning he finds a photo of Weronika that obviously looks just like V&eacute;ronique, but she denies it is her as he is the one who took the photo. The end of the film sees Alexandre working on a new book, focusing on the lives of two women born on the same day in different cities of the world with a strange connection, obviously based on what he found falling with V&eacute;ronique and finding out about Weronika. Also starring Kalina Jedrusik as Gaudy woman, Wladyslaw Kowalski as Weronika's father, Janusz Sterninski as Lawyer, Sandrine Dumas as Catherine and Louis Ducreux as Teacher. As the two identical women Jacob gives a performance worth watching, but I will be honest and say that I much preferred the first woman more than her second because she has an extraordinary singing voice that goes perfectly with the opera music, the second performance for lacked as much depth, in fact, I found after the first woman's death the rest of the film was a tiny bit slowed down, nevertheless overall it is a worthwhile drama. It was nominated the Golden Globe for Best Foreign Language Film. Good, in my opinion!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Makes You Feel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brtndr
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It makes you feel like you've fallen asleep and entered into someone else's surrealistic dream world. Fortunately, there are two beautiful young women Veronique and Veronicka (both played by Irene Jacobs) who are at the center of that alien dream world you've entered into. And, you are just as engaged in the lives of the two woman as you would be if your own life was passing before your eyes. The two lives of Veronique and Veronicka reflect each other, but are only subconsciously aware of it, which is eerie in its very nature. Two people who have two entirely different lives, obviously destined to never really meet, but unexpectedly spot each other across a crowded court yard one day. The experience briefly hypnotically paralyzes them both as they stare in amazement at the sight of one another. A moment that appears to confirm for both woman what they've always felt, but could never bring themselves to believe until then. This encounter between the two ends as quickly as it accidentally occurred, and they continue on with their separate lives without ever really acknowledging the entire breadth and depth of their shared accidental encounter. However, after the experience neither one of them are the same physically or emotionally again. There is so much going on both visually and emotionally in the film which makes 'The Double Life of Veronique' one of the most worthy films for endless coffee house discussions and analysis. A highly recommended A+ excellent foreign movie that you'll enjoy discussing for hours afterwards with cinema enthusiast. Perhaps, while enjoying a cup of Mocha Espresso with a dollop of milk?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reflections from the looking glass
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Artimidor Federkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here's a kind of movie that helps you think outside the proverbial box: Meet V&eacute;ronique,the French protagonist who chances upon a most unusual face - en passant, in a fleeting moment, like a reminder from another life. The face of the person she sees is her own. Somewhere on Polish plaza, to briefly surface and drown again in the crowd. "La Double vie de V&eacute;ronique" teaches you to appreciate escaping the comfort zone of trusted logic, recognize its pitfalls and see a strange, maybe even absurd fantastic premise in an otherwise realistic picture as a chance to discover something that cannot be named. Sure, Kieslowski pictures are always a combination of beautiful images, evocative music and a strong cerebral component, but "La double vie de V&eacute;ronique" is his most enigmatic, thought provoking work. Various threads are spun by writer and director which appeal to the viewer's imagination, so that they may be connected or respected just the way they are. Or perhaps seen as a whole in the eye of the beholder in front of the screen: Two different lives, one face, strings attached or mere coincidence? Is there fate? Does the demiurge work as puppeteer or are our actions influencing others in a way we would never anticipate? There are no metaphors in my work, Kiesloswki once said. Sounds challenging? Feel free to connect your own dots in this magical adventure of parallelism seen through the looking glass! Just one thing: The purpose of art is not to provide answers and be prescriptive in its implications, be they moral, social, historic or otherwise, but rather to open up new pathways and perspectives and question what we've been used to take for granted. In this respect Kieslowski succeeds indubitably and delivers a dazzling work of art to be looked at. Again and again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ethereal Irene Jacob
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The premise of this film is based on the old legend that we all have a twin somewhere in the world. Weronika is a Polish opera singer who while performing at an outdoor concert, continues to sing in a heavy rainstorm. Afterwards, she meets her boyfriend, Antek, and they get it on. She tells her father that she does not feel alone in the world. She visits her aunt in Krakow and meets a friend at a concert rehearsal. While listening, she sings along and the director is so impressed with her voice that he asks her to audition. While walking down a street during a protest rally, she notices a woman taking photos of the crowd. The lady looks like her twin. Her double gets on a bus which drives away. She passes the audition and the following night, and while singing a solo at a concert, collapses and dies on stage. Her spirit travels over the audience. That same day in Paris, Veronique(Irene Jacob), feels a great sadness for no apparent reason. Later, at her classroom, she leads her students in a classical piece by the same composer that Weronika was performing when she died., Veronique falls in love with a puppeteer and writer named Alexandre and as the couple go through a photo album, he sees a picture which looks like her. Veronique explains that it can't possibly be her, since she took the photo. There is no real ending for Double Life, but Irene Jacob in the dual role, makes it work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spooky-wooky does not a movie make
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xXBoss-EbertXx
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Seinfeld said his show was about "nothing," but it had the contents of the Encyclopedia Britannica compared to this movie. Quelle waste of time sitting through this! It moved at the speed of a glacier and made absolutely no sense at all. To it's credit, La double vie de V&eacute;ronique is FAR from what you'd ever see in an American theatre, but in this case, that might not be a good thing. This film is an exercise in banality compared to the remake, I Know Who Killed Me (2007), a modern day erotic masterpiece. I would also like to add that the picture quality here wasn't that great either. It is just a poor release of this film in almost every area. ...disjointed script bordering on HBO style "erotica", with probably the worse subtitling I have ever seen. The movie ends abruptly like they just simply ran out of film. Avoid this one. For the amount of money the producers spent on this, the movie's quality is terrible. Everything is underlit and murky as if the film was dropped in a swamp prior to being developed, and that's when you're lucky enough to view a scene that's actually in-focus. The sound is poorly dubbed, much of the music is awkward and the editing is god awful. Let's not kid ourselves here, all ye art students, film-school nerds, and other self-loathing "cinema l'arte" snobs: had this exact same movie been released under the banner "directed by Pier Paolo Pasolini" you would have loved it - sorry: CLAIMED to have loved it - and praised it to high heaven, espousing its virtues in long essays, justifying its extreme sex and violence through some b.s. semantic pseudo-intellectual movie-critic-jargon mumbo-jumbo. A corny, historically inaccurate, fairy-tale-like piece of crap like "Gandhi" gets world-wide recognition, while a brutally realistic film about another historical figure, called "Caligula" gets the finger. Go figure. Go on, admit it. No-one will laugh. We promise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Down Memory Lane.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Traversa
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Have you seen, read or heard "The Glass Menagerie" by Tennesse Williams? If you remember, the play is told by the main character in the present time, he tells us about his past life, lost forever, as well as the characters that were essential in his life at that time, "This play is memory" he says. Well, my review for this film is also memory, since I saw it at the time of its premiere and never again. I happened to be listening a program on France culture radio on the Internet and they mentioned this film, it instantly came back to my memory: One of the best films I had ever seen, next to "Tous les matins du monde", "Barry Lyndon", "Tom Jones" and a few others. I should see it again to experience that sometimes disappointing sensation of coming down with a sad feeling of having outgrown an old film that in our memory was fantastic. On the other hand, there are also those old films that when seeing them again after so many years, they are as fresh as ever, as I'm sure is the case with this one. I remember that I was mesmerized at the end of the projection (I saw it at a movie house in Barcelona) and thought at the time that it was a perfect movie, something so rare and unusual to find. So far, and --again-- in my memory, it it one of the best films I have ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It has an effect for everybody in some way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Harsanyi
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film just inspired me to watch more older films. In the summer i was in a Christian camp where they showed the main scene (for me it is) when Alexandre Fabbri is playing with the marionette ballerina. When I arrived home I immediately started searching for this film and finally i found it! It took me 3 days to watch it. This became my favorite film of all my life. There are scenes and quotes that mean so much to me. I feel I am not the only one with this feeling because as I can see, there are events that are alternative, and has effects that are different for you and your friends either.What is the most interesting thing what i've ever seen/heard? There is only one music in the film and makes you happy or sad depending on the scene. The cameraman's work is excellent too! :) I absolutely would nominate this for Golden Globe of all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Condemned to death
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    randomchoice
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I hated this movie while watching it.After much debating with myself and a friend I have come to the conclusion that this movie is about death. While I still have no sympathy for anyone or anything in the movie, I think the movie is nevertheless a lot more coherent than I initially thought, and for this - and also for the excellent filmography - I am giving it an 8/10. (1) A friend of mine suggested this movie is about the various possibilities of existence which cannot be realized simultaneously in real life. I felt this wasn't right but I didn't have another interpretation to offer. But now I do. Let's see what Weronika and Veronique are all about: (a) Similarities They are both sickly creatures. They have a father, they don't have a mother. They are both engaged with music. They know and interact with a series of characters of no consequence (the aunt, the colleague from school, etc.) They both appear in a love relationship where their lovers are more involved than themselves. They both dismiss those lovers. They both have a plastic (?) ball and are fascinated by what the world looks like as reflected through it. They both watch an old woman through the window. They both seem to drift without touching the world around them. They both see their doppelg&auml;nger. (b) Differences Weronika lives in Poland. She is not independent (lives with her dad / aunt). She seems young and inexperienced. She moves to another city for the sake of her aunt. Feels that she is not alone in the world. She dies singing. Veronique lives in France. She is financially independent (she lives on her own, has her own job). She seems more mature, and already anchored in music (she has a music teacher, she teaches music). She quits her music lessons although her teacher thinks she has a great talent. She feels alone in the world. She falls in love (Weronika never seems in love; talking to her aunt, she seems excited to have slept with that guy but abandons him). She accepts the game played on her by the anonymous stalker. She becomes acquainted with her puppeteer. She sees her doppelg&auml;nger, in the end. She begins to see how he may be the one manipulating her. Veronique's story begins as Weronika dies. This chronological details is supported by the photo / negative from Poland, which is the moment when the stories of the two girls become anchored in reality and aligned in a particular chronological order. So far, what does this movie seem to be about? Let's say that Veronique's first apparition and inexplicable grief is a premonition of what might happen to her if she continues taking music lessons / trying to make a career in music. This premonition leads her to abandon her existential possibility of realizing her potential through music. Having abandoned this possibility (I don't feel like it should be called her 'ideal' - Veronique doesn't really seem to have a passion, a dream, an ideal!), she somehow loses her path. Is she the ballerina who breaks her leg and then turns into a butterfly, as the ballerina in the puppeteer's story? This seems rather to be Weronika's story. Veronique refuses to break her leg, so there's no question of her turning into a butterfly. Is, then, the movie about a character with a talent for music to whom her talent is fatal, and for whom abandoning the talent would lead to perdition all the same? If yes, then the movie does make sense, although I'm still not sure about the puppeteer. It's as if the puppeteer had somehow condemned both these girls to death, and loves them when they have accepted their sentence. (Antek too could be some kind of a puppeteer: he tells Weronika he loves her only after she had come to the city and was already pursuing her talent! Likewise, Alexandre too tells Veronique he loves her only after she had accepted to enter the game of the anonymous caller.) If this death sentence were the true meaning of the movie, then it also would be easier to understand why Veronique has two lovers (the first, unnamed one, and then, Alexandre), and Weronika only one: Veronique quits music and drives away her first lover, and this could be a rejection of dying for her talent. Her condemnation to death is, however, still there: having failed to kill her through music, the puppeteer steps in himself. The weird thing about this interpretation is that, although both girls do seem to have some relation to music, neither of them gives the impression that music is the biggest thing in their lives. Music is just something they happen to be good at, good enough to be remarked and regretted when they cannot / refuse to pursue it. For the rest, these girls look like lambs brought to the slaughterhouse. For example, when Weronika's aunt asks her how her audition had gone, Weronika answers something like (I don't remember the exact wording): it went TOO well. Apathetic... (2) My conclusion about the movie After lots of thinking, here's, then, my conclusion regarding what this movie is about: I think it is about condemnation to death, regardless of other life details. This idea seems supported by that episode where Veronique holds the shoestring across the graph paper in a straight line over her recent EKG graph. The straight line of an EKG = death. Everything else in the movie is ballast. The doppelg&auml;nger thing is rather a red herring: it muddles the waters without any pay-off, really. Now I understand why the music is throughout so sad / sinister. Also, why there is so much ballast, so many gestures of no consequence. So many attempts at a plot but with no actual realization. The characters are doomed, and that's all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Cinematic, cinematographic, psychological and lyrical..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Polish screenwriter and director Krzysztof Kieslowski's ninth feature film which he co-wrote with Polish screenwriter Krzysztof Piesiewicz, premiered In competition at the 44th Cannes International Film Festival in 1991, was shot on location in France and Poland and is a France-Poland-Norway co-production which was produced by producer Leonardo De La Fuente. It tells the story about and educated singer and pianist named Weronika who lives in an apartment in Poland and who is in a relationship with a man named Antek. After experiencing a feeling of not being alone which she is instigated to act upon, Weronika travels to Krakow where her aunt lives and when she gets there she notices a woman whom she has never seen before and who bears a striking resemblance to herself. Distinctly and subtly directed by Polish filmmaker Krzysztof Kieslowski, this finely tuned fictional tale which is narrated mostly from the two main character's point of view, draws a virtuous portrayal of the life of a Polish woman named Weronika and a French woman named Veroniqu&eacute; who are identical and who one day coincidentally or determined by destiny crosses paths. While notable for it's naturalistic and atmospheric milieu depictions, distinct production design by production designer Patrice Mercier, cinematography by polish cinematographer Slawomir Idziak, costume design by costume designers Laurence Brignon, Claudy Fellous and Elzbieta Radke, fine editing by French film editor Jacques Witta and use of colors and light, this character-driven and narrative-driven story where the director could focus more on the cinematic aspects of his film and less on the political which was characteristic in many of his previous productions due to the political situation in his country, depicts two interrelated and empathic studies of character and contains a great score by Polish composer Zbigniew Preisner. This dramatic, literary, somewhat surreal, romantic and humanistic drama from the early 1990s about identity and faith which is the last feature film Krzysztof Kieslowski made before ending his career with the Three Colours trilogy which consisted of "Blue" (1993), "White" (1994) and "Red" (1994) and which is set in the capital city of France and the capital city of Poland in the early 1990s and where a music teacher for children named Veroniqu&eacute; who lives in France experiences a feeling of being alone, is impelled and reinforced by it's brilliant narrative structure, substantial character development, subtle continuity, interrelated stories, endearing characters, poetic scenes and the memorable acting performance by French actress Ir&egrave;ne Jacob. A cinematic, cinematographic, psychological and lyrical mystery which gained, among numerous other awards, the FIPRESCI Prize Krzysztof Kieslowski, the Prize of the Ecumenical Jury and the award for Best Actress Ir&egrave;ne Jacob at the 44th Cannes Film Festival in 1991.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    levelllll5
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "All my life I've felt like I was here and somewhere else at the same time" Weronika lives in Poland. She lost her mother as a kid. She has a gift for music, and especially singing. She likes to apply a golden ring around her eye. She runs a lot. She is always breathless because of a heart defect that she is unaware of. She is searching for love. Veronique lives in France. She lost her mother as a kid. She has a gift for music, and she teaches it to young children. She likes to apply a golden ring around her eye. She runs a lot. She is always breathless because of a heart defect that has just been found out. She is searching for love. Weronika sees V&eacute;ronique in Krakow, the city she lives in. She stops in the middle of a place crowded with people demonstrating and riot squads. Her alter ego is getting on a bus which will take her back to France. Before the bus leaves, V&eacute;ronique has time to take pictures of the place and of Weronika, but she does not see her. During the first half-hour of the film, the subjective shots which represent Weronika's vision are unsteady, the fisheye angle twists the perspectives, until Weronika herself collapses, on the stage, among the music instruments and in front of the audience, in the middle of a song. After Weronika's death, we follow V&eacute;ronique. She is making love with a man, and, right after it, she feels an immense sadness. She says to her lover &laquo; It's as if I were grieving &raquo; but she is unable to explain why. She decides to give up on the concert she was preparing, the same concert, we can imagine, during which Weronika died. V&eacute;ronique follows her intuition, and Weronika's death prevents her from dying herself. In the school where V&eacute;ronique teaches, a man manipulates puppets for the children. He makes the puppet die and become a sort of angel. Later on, V&eacute;tonique receives an anonymous phone call, then she gets a lace in the mail, and then an audio tape thanks to which she finds the place from where the anonymous man sends his objects to her. She finds him in a bar in the Gare Saint Lazare in Paris. She recognizes the puppeteer. In a hotel, after they have made love, and confessed their love, she empties her purse on the bed because he wants to know her better. He looks at the photos she took during her trip in Eastern Europe. He says that she is pretty on the pictures. She notices Weronika for the first time. She starts to cry. Weeks, maybe months later, she wakes up in the middle of the night and finds her lover making a second puppet of herself. She asks why he made two puppets of her, and he says that it is because they get damaged. She manipulates one puppet, while the other is lying motionless. The puppeteer reads to her the first version of a tale he is writing about two women on two different continents who are in fact two versions of the same person. This focus on the puppets reminded me of an essay written by Furio Jesi on Rilke's poetry. Jesi writes: the doll, in its form, tragically announces to men that it is her, not them, who will survive in the Infinite. &raquo;. To me, the puppets are a reminder of the fate that awaits V&eacute;ronique as well, that is death. The two women will disappear in death but the two puppets will remain. There is a very important dreamlike dimension in the film which features a dwarf who is also a lawyer, an old exhibitionnist, conversations of secondary characters with no beginning and no end, a subjective shot of the dead Weronika being buried. The film is also very poetic. I think of two shots in particular: the two versions of the old lady crossing the screen, and the image of the old church reflected backwards in a plastic ball. To appreciate this film, you need to get rid of the need to understand and analyze everything, and accept the absurd side of reality. My sister saw the film with me, and at one point she said: &laquo; there is something in this film that is us. &raquo; That &laquo; something &raquo; can be defined as the atmosphere, the setting, the green and red colors. the light. Kieslowski's movie addresses that part of our brain that is the center of our emotions, of our sensations, and of the memories of those sensations. It remains with us like an old dream that we had forgotten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Double Life of V&eacute;ronique
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Krzysztof Kieslowski (Dekalog: The Ten Commandments, Three Colours: Blue), I read a little about this film before watching it, and obviously it was in the book 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die, so I was hoping it was going to be a deserving placement. Basically the story starts in Poland with the life of young Polish woman Weronika (Ir&egrave;ne Jacob) who has a keen ambition to become a singer, and aside caring for her sick Aunt (Halina Gryglaszewska) in Krak&oacute;w, she is prepared to leave most things to achieve this dream, including spending time with her boyfriend Antek (Jerzy Gudejko). She gets noticed by turning up at a concert rehearsal session, impressing the musical director with her beautiful high soprano voice and offered an audition, and eventually she is successful, and she reconnects with Antek who has been following her somewhat, but when she finally gets on stage to enchant an audience with her she sings her parts, but collapses and dies during performance. The story then shifts to Paris where on the same day young French woman V&eacute;ronique (Ir&egrave;ne Jacob), a doppelg&auml;nger who in a sudden moment feels grief and sadness, she teaches music and takes her class to see a musical piece by the same composer who performed with Weronika, conductor Van den Budenmayer (Aleksander Bardini), and in a few instances she hears more of his music playing in places. The next day she tells her father that she is in love, all of the sudden with a man she has never met, after receiving an odd shoelace in a letter envelope she believes it is from a puppeteer she has seen a few times, also a children's book author who in one his stories mentions a shoelace, Alexandre Fabbri (Philippe Volter), and she reads more of his work, and also hears more Budenmayer music, including sounds of a car accident. V&eacute;ronique feels manipulated finding out that it was Alexandre wanting to gain her attention and meet again, she eventually lets him off and they sleep together and make love, and the next morning he finds a photo of Weronika that obviously looks just like V&eacute;ronique, but she denies it is her as he is the one who took the photo. The end of the film sees Alexandre working on a new book, focusing on the lives of two women born on the same day in different cities of the world with a strange connection, obviously based on what he found falling with V&eacute;ronique and finding out about Weronika. Also starring Kalina Jedrusik as Gaudy woman, Wladyslaw Kowalski as Weronika's father, Janusz Sterninski as Lawyer, Sandrine Dumas as Catherine and Louis Ducreux as Teacher. As the two identical women Jacob gives a performance worth watching, but I will be honest and say that I much preferred the first woman more than her second because she has an extraordinary singing voice that goes perfectly with the opera music, the second performance for lacked as much depth, in fact, I found after the first woman's death the rest of the film was a tiny bit slowed down, nevertheless overall it is a worthwhile drama. It was nominated the Golden Globe for Best Foreign Language Film. Good, in my opinion!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Makes You Feel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brtndr
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It makes you feel like you've fallen asleep and entered into someone else's surrealistic dream world. Fortunately, there are two beautiful young women Veronique and Veronicka (both played by Irene Jacobs) who are at the center of that alien dream world you've entered into. And, you are just as engaged in the lives of the two woman as you would be if your own life was passing before your eyes. The two lives of Veronique and Veronicka reflect each other, but are only subconsciously aware of it, which is eerie in its very nature. Two people who have two entirely different lives, obviously destined to never really meet, but unexpectedly spot each other across a crowded court yard one day. The experience briefly hypnotically paralyzes them both as they stare in amazement at the sight of one another. A moment that appears to confirm for both woman what they've always felt, but could never bring themselves to believe until then. This encounter between the two ends as quickly as it accidentally occurred, and they continue on with their separate lives without ever really acknowledging the entire breadth and depth of their shared accidental encounter. However, after the experience neither one of them are the same physically or emotionally again. There is so much going on both visually and emotionally in the film which makes 'The Double Life of Veronique' one of the most worthy films for endless coffee house discussions and analysis. A highly recommended A+ excellent foreign movie that you'll enjoy discussing for hours afterwards with cinema enthusiast. Perhaps, while enjoying a cup of Mocha Espresso with a dollop of milk?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reflections from the looking glass
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Artimidor Federkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here's a kind of movie that helps you think outside the proverbial box: Meet V&eacute;ronique,the French protagonist who chances upon a most unusual face - en passant, in a fleeting moment, like a reminder from another life. The face of the person she sees is her own. Somewhere on Polish plaza, to briefly surface and drown again in the crowd. "La Double vie de V&eacute;ronique" teaches you to appreciate escaping the comfort zone of trusted logic, recognize its pitfalls and see a strange, maybe even absurd fantastic premise in an otherwise realistic picture as a chance to discover something that cannot be named. Sure, Kieslowski pictures are always a combination of beautiful images, evocative music and a strong cerebral component, but "La double vie de V&eacute;ronique" is his most enigmatic, thought provoking work. Various threads are spun by writer and director which appeal to the viewer's imagination, so that they may be connected or respected just the way they are. Or perhaps seen as a whole in the eye of the beholder in front of the screen: Two different lives, one face, strings attached or mere coincidence? Is there fate? Does the demiurge work as puppeteer or are our actions influencing others in a way we would never anticipate? There are no metaphors in my work, Kiesloswki once said. Sounds challenging? Feel free to connect your own dots in this magical adventure of parallelism seen through the looking glass! Just one thing: The purpose of art is not to provide answers and be prescriptive in its implications, be they moral, social, historic or otherwise, but rather to open up new pathways and perspectives and question what we've been used to take for granted. In this respect Kieslowski succeeds indubitably and delivers a dazzling work of art to be looked at. Again and again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ethereal Irene Jacob
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The premise of this film is based on the old legend that we all have a twin somewhere in the world. Weronika is a Polish opera singer who while performing at an outdoor concert, continues to sing in a heavy rainstorm. Afterwards, she meets her boyfriend, Antek, and they get it on. She tells her father that she does not feel alone in the world. She visits her aunt in Krakow and meets a friend at a concert rehearsal. While listening, she sings along and the director is so impressed with her voice that he asks her to audition. While walking down a street during a protest rally, she notices a woman taking photos of the crowd. The lady looks like her twin. Her double gets on a bus which drives away. She passes the audition and the following night, and while singing a solo at a concert, collapses and dies on stage. Her spirit travels over the audience. That same day in Paris, Veronique(Irene Jacob), feels a great sadness for no apparent reason. Later, at her classroom, she leads her students in a classical piece by the same composer that Weronika was performing when she died., Veronique falls in love with a puppeteer and writer named Alexandre and as the couple go through a photo album, he sees a picture which looks like her. Veronique explains that it can't possibly be her, since she took the photo. There is no real ending for Double Life, but Irene Jacob in the dual role, makes it work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spooky-wooky does not a movie make
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xXBoss-EbertXx
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Seinfeld said his show was about "nothing," but it had the contents of the Encyclopedia Britannica compared to this movie. Quelle waste of time sitting through this! It moved at the speed of a glacier and made absolutely no sense at all. To it's credit, La double vie de V&eacute;ronique is FAR from what you'd ever see in an American theatre, but in this case, that might not be a good thing. This film is an exercise in banality compared to the remake, I Know Who Killed Me (2007), a modern day erotic masterpiece. I would also like to add that the picture quality here wasn't that great either. It is just a poor release of this film in almost every area. ...disjointed script bordering on HBO style "erotica", with probably the worse subtitling I have ever seen. The movie ends abruptly like they just simply ran out of film. Avoid this one. For the amount of money the producers spent on this, the movie's quality is terrible. Everything is underlit and murky as if the film was dropped in a swamp prior to being developed, and that's when you're lucky enough to view a scene that's actually in-focus. The sound is poorly dubbed, much of the music is awkward and the editing is god awful. Let's not kid ourselves here, all ye art students, film-school nerds, and other self-loathing "cinema l'arte" snobs: had this exact same movie been released under the banner "directed by Pier Paolo Pasolini" you would have loved it - sorry: CLAIMED to have loved it - and praised it to high heaven, espousing its virtues in long essays, justifying its extreme sex and violence through some b.s. semantic pseudo-intellectual movie-critic-jargon mumbo-jumbo. A corny, historically inaccurate, fairy-tale-like piece of crap like "Gandhi" gets world-wide recognition, while a brutally realistic film about another historical figure, called "Caligula" gets the finger. Go figure. Go on, admit it. No-one will laugh. We promise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Down Memory Lane.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Traversa
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Have you seen, read or heard "The Glass Menagerie" by Tennesse Williams? If you remember, the play is told by the main character in the present time, he tells us about his past life, lost forever, as well as the characters that were essential in his life at that time, "This play is memory" he says. Well, my review for this film is also memory, since I saw it at the time of its premiere and never again. I happened to be listening a program on France culture radio on the Internet and they mentioned this film, it instantly came back to my memory: One of the best films I had ever seen, next to "Tous les matins du monde", "Barry Lyndon", "Tom Jones" and a few others. I should see it again to experience that sometimes disappointing sensation of coming down with a sad feeling of having outgrown an old film that in our memory was fantastic. On the other hand, there are also those old films that when seeing them again after so many years, they are as fresh as ever, as I'm sure is the case with this one. I remember that I was mesmerized at the end of the projection (I saw it at a movie house in Barcelona) and thought at the time that it was a perfect movie, something so rare and unusual to find. So far, and --again-- in my memory, it it one of the best films I have ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It has an effect for everybody in some way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Harsanyi
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film just inspired me to watch more older films. In the summer i was in a Christian camp where they showed the main scene (for me it is) when Alexandre Fabbri is playing with the marionette ballerina. When I arrived home I immediately started searching for this film and finally i found it! It took me 3 days to watch it. This became my favorite film of all my life. There are scenes and quotes that mean so much to me. I feel I am not the only one with this feeling because as I can see, there are events that are alternative, and has effects that are different for you and your friends either.What is the most interesting thing what i've ever seen/heard? There is only one music in the film and makes you happy or sad depending on the scene. The cameraman's work is excellent too! :) I absolutely would nominate this for Golden Globe of all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Condemned to death
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    randomchoice
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I hated this movie while watching it.After much debating with myself and a friend I have come to the conclusion that this movie is about death. While I still have no sympathy for anyone or anything in the movie, I think the movie is nevertheless a lot more coherent than I initially thought, and for this - and also for the excellent filmography - I am giving it an 8/10. (1) A friend of mine suggested this movie is about the various possibilities of existence which cannot be realized simultaneously in real life. I felt this wasn't right but I didn't have another interpretation to offer. But now I do. Let's see what Weronika and Veronique are all about: (a) Similarities They are both sickly creatures. They have a father, they don't have a mother. They are both engaged with music. They know and interact with a series of characters of no consequence (the aunt, the colleague from school, etc.) They both appear in a love relationship where their lovers are more involved than themselves. They both dismiss those lovers. They both have a plastic (?) ball and are fascinated by what the world looks like as reflected through it. They both watch an old woman through the window. They both seem to drift without touching the world around them. They both see their doppelg&auml;nger. (b) Differences Weronika lives in Poland. She is not independent (lives with her dad / aunt). She seems young and inexperienced. She moves to another city for the sake of her aunt. Feels that she is not alone in the world. She dies singing. Veronique lives in France. She is financially independent (she lives on her own, has her own job). She seems more mature, and already anchored in music (she has a music teacher, she teaches music). She quits her music lessons although her teacher thinks she has a great talent. She feels alone in the world. She falls in love (Weronika never seems in love; talking to her aunt, she seems excited to have slept with that guy but abandons him). She accepts the game played on her by the anonymous stalker. She becomes acquainted with her puppeteer. She sees her doppelg&auml;nger, in the end. She begins to see how he may be the one manipulating her. Veronique's story begins as Weronika dies. This chronological details is supported by the photo / negative from Poland, which is the moment when the stories of the two girls become anchored in reality and aligned in a particular chronological order. So far, what does this movie seem to be about? Let's say that Veronique's first apparition and inexplicable grief is a premonition of what might happen to her if she continues taking music lessons / trying to make a career in music. This premonition leads her to abandon her existential possibility of realizing her potential through music. Having abandoned this possibility (I don't feel like it should be called her 'ideal' - Veronique doesn't really seem to have a passion, a dream, an ideal!), she somehow loses her path. Is she the ballerina who breaks her leg and then turns into a butterfly, as the ballerina in the puppeteer's story? This seems rather to be Weronika's story. Veronique refuses to break her leg, so there's no question of her turning into a butterfly. Is, then, the movie about a character with a talent for music to whom her talent is fatal, and for whom abandoning the talent would lead to perdition all the same? If yes, then the movie does make sense, although I'm still not sure about the puppeteer. It's as if the puppeteer had somehow condemned both these girls to death, and loves them when they have accepted their sentence. (Antek too could be some kind of a puppeteer: he tells Weronika he loves her only after she had come to the city and was already pursuing her talent! Likewise, Alexandre too tells Veronique he loves her only after she had accepted to enter the game of the anonymous caller.) If this death sentence were the true meaning of the movie, then it also would be easier to understand why Veronique has two lovers (the first, unnamed one, and then, Alexandre), and Weronika only one: Veronique quits music and drives away her first lover, and this could be a rejection of dying for her talent. Her condemnation to death is, however, still there: having failed to kill her through music, the puppeteer steps in himself. The weird thing about this interpretation is that, although both girls do seem to have some relation to music, neither of them gives the impression that music is the biggest thing in their lives. Music is just something they happen to be good at, good enough to be remarked and regretted when they cannot / refuse to pursue it. For the rest, these girls look like lambs brought to the slaughterhouse. For example, when Weronika's aunt asks her how her audition had gone, Weronika answers something like (I don't remember the exact wording): it went TOO well. Apathetic... (2) My conclusion about the movie After lots of thinking, here's, then, my conclusion regarding what this movie is about: I think it is about condemnation to death, regardless of other life details. This idea seems supported by that episode where Veronique holds the shoestring across the graph paper in a straight line over her recent EKG graph. The straight line of an EKG = death. Everything else in the movie is ballast. The doppelg&auml;nger thing is rather a red herring: it muddles the waters without any pay-off, really. Now I understand why the music is throughout so sad / sinister. Also, why there is so much ballast, so many gestures of no consequence. So many attempts at a plot but with no actual realization. The characters are doomed, and that's all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Cinematic, cinematographic, psychological and lyrical..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Polish screenwriter and director Krzysztof Kieslowski's ninth feature film which he co-wrote with Polish screenwriter Krzysztof Piesiewicz, premiered In competition at the 44th Cannes International Film Festival in 1991, was shot on location in France and Poland and is a France-Poland-Norway co-production which was produced by producer Leonardo De La Fuente. It tells the story about and educated singer and pianist named Weronika who lives in an apartment in Poland and who is in a relationship with a man named Antek. After experiencing a feeling of not being alone which she is instigated to act upon, Weronika travels to Krakow where her aunt lives and when she gets there she notices a woman whom she has never seen before and who bears a striking resemblance to herself. Distinctly and subtly directed by Polish filmmaker Krzysztof Kieslowski, this finely tuned fictional tale which is narrated mostly from the two main character's point of view, draws a virtuous portrayal of the life of a Polish woman named Weronika and a French woman named Veroniqu&eacute; who are identical and who one day coincidentally or determined by destiny crosses paths. While notable for it's naturalistic and atmospheric milieu depictions, distinct production design by production designer Patrice Mercier, cinematography by polish cinematographer Slawomir Idziak, costume design by costume designers Laurence Brignon, Claudy Fellous and Elzbieta Radke, fine editing by French film editor Jacques Witta and use of colors and light, this character-driven and narrative-driven story where the director could focus more on the cinematic aspects of his film and less on the political which was characteristic in many of his previous productions due to the political situation in his country, depicts two interrelated and empathic studies of character and contains a great score by Polish composer Zbigniew Preisner. This dramatic, literary, somewhat surreal, romantic and humanistic drama from the early 1990s about identity and faith which is the last feature film Krzysztof Kieslowski made before ending his career with the Three Colours trilogy which consisted of "Blue" (1993), "White" (1994) and "Red" (1994) and which is set in the capital city of France and the capital city of Poland in the early 1990s and where a music teacher for children named Veroniqu&eacute; who lives in France experiences a feeling of being alone, is impelled and reinforced by it's brilliant narrative structure, substantial character development, subtle continuity, interrelated stories, endearing characters, poetic scenes and the memorable acting performance by French actress Ir&egrave;ne Jacob. A cinematic, cinematographic, psychological and lyrical mystery which gained, among numerous other awards, the FIPRESCI Prize Krzysztof Kieslowski, the Prize of the Ecumenical Jury and the award for Best Actress Ir&egrave;ne Jacob at the 44th Cannes Film Festival in 1991.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    levelllll5
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "All my life I've felt like I was here and somewhere else at the same time" Weronika lives in Poland. She lost her mother as a kid. She has a gift for music, and especially singing. She likes to apply a golden ring around her eye. She runs a lot. She is always breathless because of a heart defect that she is unaware of. She is searching for love. Veronique lives in France. She lost her mother as a kid. She has a gift for music, and she teaches it to young children. She likes to apply a golden ring around her eye. She runs a lot. She is always breathless because of a heart defect that has just been found out. She is searching for love. Weronika sees V&eacute;ronique in Krakow, the city she lives in. She stops in the middle of a place crowded with people demonstrating and riot squads. Her alter ego is getting on a bus which will take her back to France. Before the bus leaves, V&eacute;ronique has time to take pictures of the place and of Weronika, but she does not see her. During the first half-hour of the film, the subjective shots which represent Weronika's vision are unsteady, the fisheye angle twists the perspectives, until Weronika herself collapses, on the stage, among the music instruments and in front of the audience, in the middle of a song. After Weronika's death, we follow V&eacute;ronique. She is making love with a man, and, right after it, she feels an immense sadness. She says to her lover &laquo; It's as if I were grieving &raquo; but she is unable to explain why. She decides to give up on the concert she was preparing, the same concert, we can imagine, during which Weronika died. V&eacute;ronique follows her intuition, and Weronika's death prevents her from dying herself. In the school where V&eacute;ronique teaches, a man manipulates puppets for the children. He makes the puppet die and become a sort of angel. Later on, V&eacute;tonique receives an anonymous phone call, then she gets a lace in the mail, and then an audio tape thanks to which she finds the place from where the anonymous man sends his objects to her. She finds him in a bar in the Gare Saint Lazare in Paris. She recognizes the puppeteer. In a hotel, after they have made love, and confessed their love, she empties her purse on the bed because he wants to know her better. He looks at the photos she took during her trip in Eastern Europe. He says that she is pretty on the pictures. She notices Weronika for the first time. She starts to cry. Weeks, maybe months later, she wakes up in the middle of the night and finds her lover making a second puppet of herself. She asks why he made two puppets of her, and he says that it is because they get damaged. She manipulates one puppet, while the other is lying motionless. The puppeteer reads to her the first version of a tale he is writing about two women on two different continents who are in fact two versions of the same person. This focus on the puppets reminded me of an essay written by Furio Jesi on Rilke's poetry. Jesi writes: the doll, in its form, tragically announces to men that it is her, not them, who will survive in the Infinite. &raquo;. To me, the puppets are a reminder of the fate that awaits V&eacute;ronique as well, that is death. The two women will disappear in death but the two puppets will remain. There is a very important dreamlike dimension in the film which features a dwarf who is also a lawyer, an old exhibitionnist, conversations of secondary characters with no beginning and no end, a subjective shot of the dead Weronika being buried. The film is also very poetic. I think of two shots in particular: the two versions of the old lady crossing the screen, and the image of the old church reflected backwards in a plastic ball. To appreciate this film, you need to get rid of the need to understand and analyze everything, and accept the absurd side of reality. My sister saw the film with me, and at one point she said: &laquo; there is something in this film that is us. &raquo; That &laquo; something &raquo; can be defined as the atmosphere, the setting, the green and red colors. the light. Kieslowski's movie addresses that part of our brain that is the center of our emotions, of our sensations, and of the memories of those sensations. It remains with us like an old dream that we had forgotten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Double Life of V&eacute;ronique
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Krzysztof Kieslowski (Dekalog: The Ten Commandments, Three Colours: Blue), I read a little about this film before watching it, and obviously it was in the book 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die, so I was hoping it was going to be a deserving placement. Basically the story starts in Poland with the life of young Polish woman Weronika (Ir&egrave;ne Jacob) who has a keen ambition to become a singer, and aside caring for her sick Aunt (Halina Gryglaszewska) in Krak&oacute;w, she is prepared to leave most things to achieve this dream, including spending time with her boyfriend Antek (Jerzy Gudejko). She gets noticed by turning up at a concert rehearsal session, impressing the musical director with her beautiful high soprano voice and offered an audition, and eventually she is successful, and she reconnects with Antek who has been following her somewhat, but when she finally gets on stage to enchant an audience with her she sings her parts, but collapses and dies during performance. The story then shifts to Paris where on the same day young French woman V&eacute;ronique (Ir&egrave;ne Jacob), a doppelg&auml;nger who in a sudden moment feels grief and sadness, she teaches music and takes her class to see a musical piece by the same composer who performed with Weronika, conductor Van den Budenmayer (Aleksander Bardini), and in a few instances she hears more of his music playing in places. The next day she tells her father that she is in love, all of the sudden with a man she has never met, after receiving an odd shoelace in a letter envelope she believes it is from a puppeteer she has seen a few times, also a children's book author who in one his stories mentions a shoelace, Alexandre Fabbri (Philippe Volter), and she reads more of his work, and also hears more Budenmayer music, including sounds of a car accident. V&eacute;ronique feels manipulated finding out that it was Alexandre wanting to gain her attention and meet again, she eventually lets him off and they sleep together and make love, and the next morning he finds a photo of Weronika that obviously looks just like V&eacute;ronique, but she denies it is her as he is the one who took the photo. The end of the film sees Alexandre working on a new book, focusing on the lives of two women born on the same day in different cities of the world with a strange connection, obviously based on what he found falling with V&eacute;ronique and finding out about Weronika. Also starring Kalina Jedrusik as Gaudy woman, Wladyslaw Kowalski as Weronika's father, Janusz Sterninski as Lawyer, Sandrine Dumas as Catherine and Louis Ducreux as Teacher. As the two identical women Jacob gives a performance worth watching, but I will be honest and say that I much preferred the first woman more than her second because she has an extraordinary singing voice that goes perfectly with the opera music, the second performance for lacked as much depth, in fact, I found after the first woman's death the rest of the film was a tiny bit slowed down, nevertheless overall it is a worthwhile drama. It was nominated the Golden Globe for Best Foreign Language Film. Good, in my opinion!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Makes You Feel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brtndr
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It makes you feel like you've fallen asleep and entered into someone else's surrealistic dream world. Fortunately, there are two beautiful young women Veronique and Veronicka (both played by Irene Jacobs) who are at the center of that alien dream world you've entered into. And, you are just as engaged in the lives of the two woman as you would be if your own life was passing before your eyes. The two lives of Veronique and Veronicka reflect each other, but are only subconsciously aware of it, which is eerie in its very nature. Two people who have two entirely different lives, obviously destined to never really meet, but unexpectedly spot each other across a crowded court yard one day. The experience briefly hypnotically paralyzes them both as they stare in amazement at the sight of one another. A moment that appears to confirm for both woman what they've always felt, but could never bring themselves to believe until then. This encounter between the two ends as quickly as it accidentally occurred, and they continue on with their separate lives without ever really acknowledging the entire breadth and depth of their shared accidental encounter. However, after the experience neither one of them are the same physically or emotionally again. There is so much going on both visually and emotionally in the film which makes 'The Double Life of Veronique' one of the most worthy films for endless coffee house discussions and analysis. A highly recommended A+ excellent foreign movie that you'll enjoy discussing for hours afterwards with cinema enthusiast. Perhaps, while enjoying a cup of Mocha Espresso with a dollop of milk?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reflections from the looking glass
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Artimidor Federkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here's a kind of movie that helps you think outside the proverbial box: Meet V&eacute;ronique,the French protagonist who chances upon a most unusual face - en passant, in a fleeting moment, like a reminder from another life. The face of the person she sees is her own. Somewhere on Polish plaza, to briefly surface and drown again in the crowd. "La Double vie de V&eacute;ronique" teaches you to appreciate escaping the comfort zone of trusted logic, recognize its pitfalls and see a strange, maybe even absurd fantastic premise in an otherwise realistic picture as a chance to discover something that cannot be named. Sure, Kieslowski pictures are always a combination of beautiful images, evocative music and a strong cerebral component, but "La double vie de V&eacute;ronique" is his most enigmatic, thought provoking work. Various threads are spun by writer and director which appeal to the viewer's imagination, so that they may be connected or respected just the way they are. Or perhaps seen as a whole in the eye of the beholder in front of the screen: Two different lives, one face, strings attached or mere coincidence? Is there fate? Does the demiurge work as puppeteer or are our actions influencing others in a way we would never anticipate? There are no metaphors in my work, Kiesloswki once said. Sounds challenging? Feel free to connect your own dots in this magical adventure of parallelism seen through the looking glass! Just one thing: The purpose of art is not to provide answers and be prescriptive in its implications, be they moral, social, historic or otherwise, but rather to open up new pathways and perspectives and question what we've been used to take for granted. In this respect Kieslowski succeeds indubitably and delivers a dazzling work of art to be looked at. Again and again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ethereal Irene Jacob
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The premise of this film is based on the old legend that we all have a twin somewhere in the world. Weronika is a Polish opera singer who while performing at an outdoor concert, continues to sing in a heavy rainstorm. Afterwards, she meets her boyfriend, Antek, and they get it on. She tells her father that she does not feel alone in the world. She visits her aunt in Krakow and meets a friend at a concert rehearsal. While listening, she sings along and the director is so impressed with her voice that he asks her to audition. While walking down a street during a protest rally, she notices a woman taking photos of the crowd. The lady looks like her twin. Her double gets on a bus which drives away. She passes the audition and the following night, and while singing a solo at a concert, collapses and dies on stage. Her spirit travels over the audience. That same day in Paris, Veronique(Irene Jacob), feels a great sadness for no apparent reason. Later, at her classroom, she leads her students in a classical piece by the same composer that Weronika was performing when she died., Veronique falls in love with a puppeteer and writer named Alexandre and as the couple go through a photo album, he sees a picture which looks like her. Veronique explains that it can't possibly be her, since she took the photo. There is no real ending for Double Life, but Irene Jacob in the dual role, makes it work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spooky-wooky does not a movie make
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xXBoss-EbertXx
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Seinfeld said his show was about "nothing," but it had the contents of the Encyclopedia Britannica compared to this movie. Quelle waste of time sitting through this! It moved at the speed of a glacier and made absolutely no sense at all. To it's credit, La double vie de V&eacute;ronique is FAR from what you'd ever see in an American theatre, but in this case, that might not be a good thing. This film is an exercise in banality compared to the remake, I Know Who Killed Me (2007), a modern day erotic masterpiece. I would also like to add that the picture quality here wasn't that great either. It is just a poor release of this film in almost every area. ...disjointed script bordering on HBO style "erotica", with probably the worse subtitling I have ever seen. The movie ends abruptly like they just simply ran out of film. Avoid this one. For the amount of money the producers spent on this, the movie's quality is terrible. Everything is underlit and murky as if the film was dropped in a swamp prior to being developed, and that's when you're lucky enough to view a scene that's actually in-focus. The sound is poorly dubbed, much of the music is awkward and the editing is god awful. Let's not kid ourselves here, all ye art students, film-school nerds, and other self-loathing "cinema l'arte" snobs: had this exact same movie been released under the banner "directed by Pier Paolo Pasolini" you would have loved it - sorry: CLAIMED to have loved it - and praised it to high heaven, espousing its virtues in long essays, justifying its extreme sex and violence through some b.s. semantic pseudo-intellectual movie-critic-jargon mumbo-jumbo. A corny, historically inaccurate, fairy-tale-like piece of crap like "Gandhi" gets world-wide recognition, while a brutally realistic film about another historical figure, called "Caligula" gets the finger. Go figure. Go on, admit it. No-one will laugh. We promise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Down Memory Lane.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Traversa
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Have you seen, read or heard "The Glass Menagerie" by Tennesse Williams? If you remember, the play is told by the main character in the present time, he tells us about his past life, lost forever, as well as the characters that were essential in his life at that time, "This play is memory" he says. Well, my review for this film is also memory, since I saw it at the time of its premiere and never again. I happened to be listening a program on France culture radio on the Internet and they mentioned this film, it instantly came back to my memory: One of the best films I had ever seen, next to "Tous les matins du monde", "Barry Lyndon", "Tom Jones" and a few others. I should see it again to experience that sometimes disappointing sensation of coming down with a sad feeling of having outgrown an old film that in our memory was fantastic. On the other hand, there are also those old films that when seeing them again after so many years, they are as fresh as ever, as I'm sure is the case with this one. I remember that I was mesmerized at the end of the projection (I saw it at a movie house in Barcelona) and thought at the time that it was a perfect movie, something so rare and unusual to find. So far, and --again-- in my memory, it it one of the best films I have ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It has an effect for everybody in some way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Harsanyi
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film just inspired me to watch more older films. In the summer i was in a Christian camp where they showed the main scene (for me it is) when Alexandre Fabbri is playing with the marionette ballerina. When I arrived home I immediately started searching for this film and finally i found it! It took me 3 days to watch it. This became my favorite film of all my life. There are scenes and quotes that mean so much to me. I feel I am not the only one with this feeling because as I can see, there are events that are alternative, and has effects that are different for you and your friends either.What is the most interesting thing what i've ever seen/heard? There is only one music in the film and makes you happy or sad depending on the scene. The cameraman's work is excellent too! :) I absolutely would nominate this for Golden Globe of all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Condemned to death
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    randomchoice
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I hated this movie while watching it.After much debating with myself and a friend I have come to the conclusion that this movie is about death. While I still have no sympathy for anyone or anything in the movie, I think the movie is nevertheless a lot more coherent than I initially thought, and for this - and also for the excellent filmography - I am giving it an 8/10. (1) A friend of mine suggested this movie is about the various possibilities of existence which cannot be realized simultaneously in real life. I felt this wasn't right but I didn't have another interpretation to offer. But now I do. Let's see what Weronika and Veronique are all about: (a) Similarities They are both sickly creatures. They have a father, they don't have a mother. They are both engaged with music. They know and interact with a series of characters of no consequence (the aunt, the colleague from school, etc.) They both appear in a love relationship where their lovers are more involved than themselves. They both dismiss those lovers. They both have a plastic (?) ball and are fascinated by what the world looks like as reflected through it. They both watch an old woman through the window. They both seem to drift without touching the world around them. They both see their doppelg&auml;nger. (b) Differences Weronika lives in Poland. She is not independent (lives with her dad / aunt). She seems young and inexperienced. She moves to another city for the sake of her aunt. Feels that she is not alone in the world. She dies singing. Veronique lives in France. She is financially independent (she lives on her own, has her own job). She seems more mature, and already anchored in music (she has a music teacher, she teaches music). She quits her music lessons although her teacher thinks she has a great talent. She feels alone in the world. She falls in love (Weronika never seems in love; talking to her aunt, she seems excited to have slept with that guy but abandons him). She accepts the game played on her by the anonymous stalker. She becomes acquainted with her puppeteer. She sees her doppelg&auml;nger, in the end. She begins to see how he may be the one manipulating her. Veronique's story begins as Weronika dies. This chronological details is supported by the photo / negative from Poland, which is the moment when the stories of the two girls become anchored in reality and aligned in a particular chronological order. So far, what does this movie seem to be about? Let's say that Veronique's first apparition and inexplicable grief is a premonition of what might happen to her if she continues taking music lessons / trying to make a career in music. This premonition leads her to abandon her existential possibility of realizing her potential through music. Having abandoned this possibility (I don't feel like it should be called her 'ideal' - Veronique doesn't really seem to have a passion, a dream, an ideal!), she somehow loses her path. Is she the ballerina who breaks her leg and then turns into a butterfly, as the ballerina in the puppeteer's story? This seems rather to be Weronika's story. Veronique refuses to break her leg, so there's no question of her turning into a butterfly. Is, then, the movie about a character with a talent for music to whom her talent is fatal, and for whom abandoning the talent would lead to perdition all the same? If yes, then the movie does make sense, although I'm still not sure about the puppeteer. It's as if the puppeteer had somehow condemned both these girls to death, and loves them when they have accepted their sentence. (Antek too could be some kind of a puppeteer: he tells Weronika he loves her only after she had come to the city and was already pursuing her talent! Likewise, Alexandre too tells Veronique he loves her only after she had accepted to enter the game of the anonymous caller.) If this death sentence were the true meaning of the movie, then it also would be easier to understand why Veronique has two lovers (the first, unnamed one, and then, Alexandre), and Weronika only one: Veronique quits music and drives away her first lover, and this could be a rejection of dying for her talent. Her condemnation to death is, however, still there: having failed to kill her through music, the puppeteer steps in himself. The weird thing about this interpretation is that, although both girls do seem to have some relation to music, neither of them gives the impression that music is the biggest thing in their lives. Music is just something they happen to be good at, good enough to be remarked and regretted when they cannot / refuse to pursue it. For the rest, these girls look like lambs brought to the slaughterhouse. For example, when Weronika's aunt asks her how her audition had gone, Weronika answers something like (I don't remember the exact wording): it went TOO well. Apathetic... (2) My conclusion about the movie After lots of thinking, here's, then, my conclusion regarding what this movie is about: I think it is about condemnation to death, regardless of other life details. This idea seems supported by that episode where Veronique holds the shoestring across the graph paper in a straight line over her recent EKG graph. The straight line of an EKG = death. Everything else in the movie is ballast. The doppelg&auml;nger thing is rather a red herring: it muddles the waters without any pay-off, really. Now I understand why the music is throughout so sad / sinister. Also, why there is so much ballast, so many gestures of no consequence. So many attempts at a plot but with no actual realization. The characters are doomed, and that's all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Cinematic, cinematographic, psychological and lyrical..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Polish screenwriter and director Krzysztof Kieslowski's ninth feature film which he co-wrote with Polish screenwriter Krzysztof Piesiewicz, premiered In competition at the 44th Cannes International Film Festival in 1991, was shot on location in France and Poland and is a France-Poland-Norway co-production which was produced by producer Leonardo De La Fuente. It tells the story about and educated singer and pianist named Weronika who lives in an apartment in Poland and who is in a relationship with a man named Antek. After experiencing a feeling of not being alone which she is instigated to act upon, Weronika travels to Krakow where her aunt lives and when she gets there she notices a woman whom she has never seen before and who bears a striking resemblance to herself. Distinctly and subtly directed by Polish filmmaker Krzysztof Kieslowski, this finely tuned fictional tale which is narrated mostly from the two main character's point of view, draws a virtuous portrayal of the life of a Polish woman named Weronika and a French woman named Veroniqu&eacute; who are identical and who one day coincidentally or determined by destiny crosses paths. While notable for it's naturalistic and atmospheric milieu depictions, distinct production design by production designer Patrice Mercier, cinematography by polish cinematographer Slawomir Idziak, costume design by costume designers Laurence Brignon, Claudy Fellous and Elzbieta Radke, fine editing by French film editor Jacques Witta and use of colors and light, this character-driven and narrative-driven story where the director could focus more on the cinematic aspects of his film and less on the political which was characteristic in many of his previous productions due to the political situation in his country, depicts two interrelated and empathic studies of character and contains a great score by Polish composer Zbigniew Preisner. This dramatic, literary, somewhat surreal, romantic and humanistic drama from the early 1990s about identity and faith which is the last feature film Krzysztof Kieslowski made before ending his career with the Three Colours trilogy which consisted of "Blue" (1993), "White" (1994) and "Red" (1994) and which is set in the capital city of France and the capital city of Poland in the early 1990s and where a music teacher for children named Veroniqu&eacute; who lives in France experiences a feeling of being alone, is impelled and reinforced by it's brilliant narrative structure, substantial character development, subtle continuity, interrelated stories, endearing characters, poetic scenes and the memorable acting performance by French actress Ir&egrave;ne Jacob. A cinematic, cinematographic, psychological and lyrical mystery which gained, among numerous other awards, the FIPRESCI Prize Krzysztof Kieslowski, the Prize of the Ecumenical Jury and the award for Best Actress Ir&egrave;ne Jacob at the 44th Cannes Film Festival in 1991.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    levelllll5
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "All my life I've felt like I was here and somewhere else at the same time" Weronika lives in Poland. She lost her mother as a kid. She has a gift for music, and especially singing. She likes to apply a golden ring around her eye. She runs a lot. She is always breathless because of a heart defect that she is unaware of. She is searching for love. Veronique lives in France. She lost her mother as a kid. She has a gift for music, and she teaches it to young children. She likes to apply a golden ring around her eye. She runs a lot. She is always breathless because of a heart defect that has just been found out. She is searching for love. Weronika sees V&eacute;ronique in Krakow, the city she lives in. She stops in the middle of a place crowded with people demonstrating and riot squads. Her alter ego is getting on a bus which will take her back to France. Before the bus leaves, V&eacute;ronique has time to take pictures of the place and of Weronika, but she does not see her. During the first half-hour of the film, the subjective shots which represent Weronika's vision are unsteady, the fisheye angle twists the perspectives, until Weronika herself collapses, on the stage, among the music instruments and in front of the audience, in the middle of a song. After Weronika's death, we follow V&eacute;ronique. She is making love with a man, and, right after it, she feels an immense sadness. She says to her lover &laquo; It's as if I were grieving &raquo; but she is unable to explain why. She decides to give up on the concert she was preparing, the same concert, we can imagine, during which Weronika died. V&eacute;ronique follows her intuition, and Weronika's death prevents her from dying herself. In the school where V&eacute;ronique teaches, a man manipulates puppets for the children. He makes the puppet die and become a sort of angel. Later on, V&eacute;tonique receives an anonymous phone call, then she gets a lace in the mail, and then an audio tape thanks to which she finds the place from where the anonymous man sends his objects to her. She finds him in a bar in the Gare Saint Lazare in Paris. She recognizes the puppeteer. In a hotel, after they have made love, and confessed their love, she empties her purse on the bed because he wants to know her better. He looks at the photos she took during her trip in Eastern Europe. He says that she is pretty on the pictures. She notices Weronika for the first time. She starts to cry. Weeks, maybe months later, she wakes up in the middle of the night and finds her lover making a second puppet of herself. She asks why he made two puppets of her, and he says that it is because they get damaged. She manipulates one puppet, while the other is lying motionless. The puppeteer reads to her the first version of a tale he is writing about two women on two different continents who are in fact two versions of the same person. This focus on the puppets reminded me of an essay written by Furio Jesi on Rilke's poetry. Jesi writes: the doll, in its form, tragically announces to men that it is her, not them, who will survive in the Infinite. &raquo;. To me, the puppets are a reminder of the fate that awaits V&eacute;ronique as well, that is death. The two women will disappear in death but the two puppets will remain. There is a very important dreamlike dimension in the film which features a dwarf who is also a lawyer, an old exhibitionnist, conversations of secondary characters with no beginning and no end, a subjective shot of the dead Weronika being buried. The film is also very poetic. I think of two shots in particular: the two versions of the old lady crossing the screen, and the image of the old church reflected backwards in a plastic ball. To appreciate this film, you need to get rid of the need to understand and analyze everything, and accept the absurd side of reality. My sister saw the film with me, and at one point she said: &laquo; there is something in this film that is us. &raquo; That &laquo; something &raquo; can be defined as the atmosphere, the setting, the green and red colors. the light. Kieslowski's movie addresses that part of our brain that is the center of our emotions, of our sensations, and of the memories of those sensations. It remains with us like an old dream that we had forgotten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Double Life of V&eacute;ronique
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Krzysztof Kieslowski (Dekalog: The Ten Commandments, Three Colours: Blue), I read a little about this film before watching it, and obviously it was in the book 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die, so I was hoping it was going to be a deserving placement. Basically the story starts in Poland with the life of young Polish woman Weronika (Ir&egrave;ne Jacob) who has a keen ambition to become a singer, and aside caring for her sick Aunt (Halina Gryglaszewska) in Krak&oacute;w, she is prepared to leave most things to achieve this dream, including spending time with her boyfriend Antek (Jerzy Gudejko). She gets noticed by turning up at a concert rehearsal session, impressing the musical director with her beautiful high soprano voice and offered an audition, and eventually she is successful, and she reconnects with Antek who has been following her somewhat, but when she finally gets on stage to enchant an audience with her she sings her parts, but collapses and dies during performance. The story then shifts to Paris where on the same day young French woman V&eacute;ronique (Ir&egrave;ne Jacob), a doppelg&auml;nger who in a sudden moment feels grief and sadness, she teaches music and takes her class to see a musical piece by the same composer who performed with Weronika, conductor Van den Budenmayer (Aleksander Bardini), and in a few instances she hears more of his music playing in places. The next day she tells her father that she is in love, all of the sudden with a man she has never met, after receiving an odd shoelace in a letter envelope she believes it is from a puppeteer she has seen a few times, also a children's book author who in one his stories mentions a shoelace, Alexandre Fabbri (Philippe Volter), and she reads more of his work, and also hears more Budenmayer music, including sounds of a car accident. V&eacute;ronique feels manipulated finding out that it was Alexandre wanting to gain her attention and meet again, she eventually lets him off and they sleep together and make love, and the next morning he finds a photo of Weronika that obviously looks just like V&eacute;ronique, but she denies it is her as he is the one who took the photo. The end of the film sees Alexandre working on a new book, focusing on the lives of two women born on the same day in different cities of the world with a strange connection, obviously based on what he found falling with V&eacute;ronique and finding out about Weronika. Also starring Kalina Jedrusik as Gaudy woman, Wladyslaw Kowalski as Weronika's father, Janusz Sterninski as Lawyer, Sandrine Dumas as Catherine and Louis Ducreux as Teacher. As the two identical women Jacob gives a performance worth watching, but I will be honest and say that I much preferred the first woman more than her second because she has an extraordinary singing voice that goes perfectly with the opera music, the second performance for lacked as much depth, in fact, I found after the first woman's death the rest of the film was a tiny bit slowed down, nevertheless overall it is a worthwhile drama. It was nominated the Golden Globe for Best Foreign Language Film. Good, in my opinion!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Makes You Feel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brtndr
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It makes you feel like you've fallen asleep and entered into someone else's surrealistic dream world. Fortunately, there are two beautiful young women Veronique and Veronicka (both played by Irene Jacobs) who are at the center of that alien dream world you've entered into. And, you are just as engaged in the lives of the two woman as you would be if your own life was passing before your eyes. The two lives of Veronique and Veronicka reflect each other, but are only subconsciously aware of it, which is eerie in its very nature. Two people who have two entirely different lives, obviously destined to never really meet, but unexpectedly spot each other across a crowded court yard one day. The experience briefly hypnotically paralyzes them both as they stare in amazement at the sight of one another. A moment that appears to confirm for both woman what they've always felt, but could never bring themselves to believe until then. This encounter between the two ends as quickly as it accidentally occurred, and they continue on with their separate lives without ever really acknowledging the entire breadth and depth of their shared accidental encounter. However, after the experience neither one of them are the same physically or emotionally again. There is so much going on both visually and emotionally in the film which makes 'The Double Life of Veronique' one of the most worthy films for endless coffee house discussions and analysis. A highly recommended A+ excellent foreign movie that you'll enjoy discussing for hours afterwards with cinema enthusiast. Perhaps, while enjoying a cup of Mocha Espresso with a dollop of milk?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reflections from the looking glass
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Artimidor Federkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here's a kind of movie that helps you think outside the proverbial box: Meet V&eacute;ronique,the French protagonist who chances upon a most unusual face - en passant, in a fleeting moment, like a reminder from another life. The face of the person she sees is her own. Somewhere on Polish plaza, to briefly surface and drown again in the crowd. "La Double vie de V&eacute;ronique" teaches you to appreciate escaping the comfort zone of trusted logic, recognize its pitfalls and see a strange, maybe even absurd fantastic premise in an otherwise realistic picture as a chance to discover something that cannot be named. Sure, Kieslowski pictures are always a combination of beautiful images, evocative music and a strong cerebral component, but "La double vie de V&eacute;ronique" is his most enigmatic, thought provoking work. Various threads are spun by writer and director which appeal to the viewer's imagination, so that they may be connected or respected just the way they are. Or perhaps seen as a whole in the eye of the beholder in front of the screen: Two different lives, one face, strings attached or mere coincidence? Is there fate? Does the demiurge work as puppeteer or are our actions influencing others in a way we would never anticipate? There are no metaphors in my work, Kiesloswki once said. Sounds challenging? Feel free to connect your own dots in this magical adventure of parallelism seen through the looking glass! Just one thing: The purpose of art is not to provide answers and be prescriptive in its implications, be they moral, social, historic or otherwise, but rather to open up new pathways and perspectives and question what we've been used to take for granted. In this respect Kieslowski succeeds indubitably and delivers a dazzling work of art to be looked at. Again and again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ethereal Irene Jacob
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The premise of this film is based on the old legend that we all have a twin somewhere in the world. Weronika is a Polish opera singer who while performing at an outdoor concert, continues to sing in a heavy rainstorm. Afterwards, she meets her boyfriend, Antek, and they get it on. She tells her father that she does not feel alone in the world. She visits her aunt in Krakow and meets a friend at a concert rehearsal. While listening, she sings along and the director is so impressed with her voice that he asks her to audition. While walking down a street during a protest rally, she notices a woman taking photos of the crowd. The lady looks like her twin. Her double gets on a bus which drives away. She passes the audition and the following night, and while singing a solo at a concert, collapses and dies on stage. Her spirit travels over the audience. That same day in Paris, Veronique(Irene Jacob), feels a great sadness for no apparent reason. Later, at her classroom, she leads her students in a classical piece by the same composer that Weronika was performing when she died., Veronique falls in love with a puppeteer and writer named Alexandre and as the couple go through a photo album, he sees a picture which looks like her. Veronique explains that it can't possibly be her, since she took the photo. There is no real ending for Double Life, but Irene Jacob in the dual role, makes it work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spooky-wooky does not a movie make
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xXBoss-EbertXx
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Seinfeld said his show was about "nothing," but it had the contents of the Encyclopedia Britannica compared to this movie. Quelle waste of time sitting through this! It moved at the speed of a glacier and made absolutely no sense at all. To it's credit, La double vie de V&eacute;ronique is FAR from what you'd ever see in an American theatre, but in this case, that might not be a good thing. This film is an exercise in banality compared to the remake, I Know Who Killed Me (2007), a modern day erotic masterpiece. I would also like to add that the picture quality here wasn't that great either. It is just a poor release of this film in almost every area. ...disjointed script bordering on HBO style "erotica", with probably the worse subtitling I have ever seen. The movie ends abruptly like they just simply ran out of film. Avoid this one. For the amount of money the producers spent on this, the movie's quality is terrible. Everything is underlit and murky as if the film was dropped in a swamp prior to being developed, and that's when you're lucky enough to view a scene that's actually in-focus. The sound is poorly dubbed, much of the music is awkward and the editing is god awful. Let's not kid ourselves here, all ye art students, film-school nerds, and other self-loathing "cinema l'arte" snobs: had this exact same movie been released under the banner "directed by Pier Paolo Pasolini" you would have loved it - sorry: CLAIMED to have loved it - and praised it to high heaven, espousing its virtues in long essays, justifying its extreme sex and violence through some b.s. semantic pseudo-intellectual movie-critic-jargon mumbo-jumbo. A corny, historically inaccurate, fairy-tale-like piece of crap like "Gandhi" gets world-wide recognition, while a brutally realistic film about another historical figure, called "Caligula" gets the finger. Go figure. Go on, admit it. No-one will laugh. We promise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Down Memory Lane.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Traversa
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Have you seen, read or heard "The Glass Menagerie" by Tennesse Williams? If you remember, the play is told by the main character in the present time, he tells us about his past life, lost forever, as well as the characters that were essential in his life at that time, "This play is memory" he says. Well, my review for this film is also memory, since I saw it at the time of its premiere and never again. I happened to be listening a program on France culture radio on the Internet and they mentioned this film, it instantly came back to my memory: One of the best films I had ever seen, next to "Tous les matins du monde", "Barry Lyndon", "Tom Jones" and a few others. I should see it again to experience that sometimes disappointing sensation of coming down with a sad feeling of having outgrown an old film that in our memory was fantastic. On the other hand, there are also those old films that when seeing them again after so many years, they are as fresh as ever, as I'm sure is the case with this one. I remember that I was mesmerized at the end of the projection (I saw it at a movie house in Barcelona) and thought at the time that it was a perfect movie, something so rare and unusual to find. So far, and --again-- in my memory, it it one of the best films I have ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
