<filme>
 <id>
  1008
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116594
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Um Tiro Para Andy Warhol
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Based on the true story of Valerie Solanas who was a 60s radical preaching hatred toward men in her "Scum" manifesto. She wrote a screenplay for a film that she wanted Andy Warhol to ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Based on the true story of Valerie Solanas who was a 60s radical preaching hatred toward men in her "Scum" manifesto. She wrote a screenplay for a film that she wanted Andy Warhol to produce, but he continued to ignore her. So she shot him. This is Valerie's story.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Biography
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   hatred
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   manifesto
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   voyeur
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   footsie under the table
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   shooting
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Mary Harron
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Jeremiah Newton
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Diane Tucker
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Lili Taylor
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jared Harris
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Martha Plimpton
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Her Fifteen Minutes Of Fame
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lechuguilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you shoot someone whom others consider "important" I suppose some filmmaker will want to make a movie about you. I can think of no other reason why anyone would want to make a film about Valerie Solanas (Lili Taylor), the spunky, chain-smoking, foul-mouthed, self-centered, lesbian feminist who, in the summer of 1968, shot Andy Warhol (Jared Harris). Warhol was a New York City painter/artist ... or something ... and guru of all things avant-garde, who attracted the chic and the trendy to his New York City "Factory", the center of counterculture pop art. In the film Solanas, who harbors an enormous grudge against men, comes across initially as assertive and resourceful. She makes a living hustling the streets: "Pardon me sir, you got 15 cents? Pardon me sir ..." On the rooftop of a high-rise she types her S.C.U.M. "manifesto", outlining her complaints against the male species. But whereas Solanas is passionate about her cause, Warhol is a study in emotional detachment and indifference. He, and those in his orbit, sees Solanas more as a hanger-on. At one point, Solanas shows Warhol her typed manifesto. Warhol flips through it and responds in a deadpan manner: "Did you type this yourself? I'm so impressed. You should come type for us." Marvelous. The film's best element is the acting. Lili Taylor is terrific. She really gets into the Solanas persona. Jared Harris also gives a splendid performance. The film's tone teeters between seriousness and tongue-in-cheek humor. Costumes, prod design, music, and lighting are all credible. For modern day feminists, "I Shot Andy Warhol" probably is required viewing. For others, the film offers a cinematic study into the mindset of a quirky, sincere, but ultimately self-deceptive and delusional young woman who got her fifteen minutes of fame by carrying her political cause a little too far.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    thought provoking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CountZero313
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lili Taylor gives a savagely kinetic performance in this representation of a disturbed individual who may just also have been a genius despite, or because of, her treatment at the hands of various men throughout her life. Judging biopics in terms of historical accuracy is for the most part a futile exercise. There is no 'truth', only interpretation, but if you want to get closer to the facts you really should be in the library, not the movie theatre. The story of Valerie Solanas is especially vexing in this case, because were this a work of complete fiction, the script would never have been made. The 'so what?' factor is superseded by the fact that this actually happened, and the legacy of Solanas still divides contemporary feminists. As cinema, the film succeeds through the charisma exuded in Taylor's performance. Her descent into madness is sudden, vicious and uncompromising. The depiction of the shooting, the moment the film has been leading up to, shows a human being divorced absolutely from her conscience. The groovy scene around Warhol's the Factory is both decadent and, viewed from the 21st century, slightly twee. The pastiche of Sixties nostalgia is less foregrounded than Solanas's brutal victimhood. The film begins with a reading of her psychiatric evaluation, where a litany of unpunished crimes inflicted upon this woman by various men is laid out. The female director sets her stall out straight away - what you are hearing now leads through a direct line of cause and effect to the monstrous act you will see committed by Solanas later. If the film has a major flaw, it is the title. Audiences could be mistaken for thinking it is about a documentarian of Warhol's life and work. Solanas and her SCUM manifesto, for better or worse, have made their mark, and perhaps 'Solanas' would have been a more fitting (if less marketable) title. Did it take the shooting for that to be the case? A polemical moment in recent history relayed straightforwardly, this is competent, entertaining, edifying cinema.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Culturally Significant but only Marginally Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gpeevers
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of Valerie Solanas who as the title indicates was responsible for shooting pop artist Andy Warhol. Solanas was a highly intelligent radical feminist but was she also obviously deeply disturbed. The film also functions secondarily as a portrayal of the fringe culture that was attracted to Andy Warhol and his well known open studio The Factory. The film is for the most part a study of a deranged mind and a portrait of self destruction as Valerie spirals out of control. We are informed that Valerie may have been psychologically damaged by abuse from her childhood but that's not dealt with in the scope of the film. Due to the films focus it is difficult to sympathize with Valerie and there is little opportunity to get to know any of the other characters very well, as a result I didn't really connect with the film. As to the positives, Lilli Taylor gives a very compelling performance that while not very appealing or attractive as a human being is a very effective portrayal. The rest of the cast is by and large good though I found some of the performances or perhaps the characters very typically indie as they strove to standout sometimes at the expensive of character development. I also found that the score did not always seem appropriate to the material, it starts off somewhat symphonic and other times it just seemed jarring. Valerie Solanas's opus per se was the Scum Manifesto which spelled out her vision of an all-female society brought about by violent revolution.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    here's what happens when people take to the underworld
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had never heard of Valerie Solanas before seeing "I Shot Andy Warhol", but the movie does a very good job telling the story. We see Valerie as a misunderstood - but strong-willed - person disenchanted with the world around her. Lili Taylor does a really good job showing what sort of person Solanas was. The movie doesn't try to deify Solanas in any way, it shows what kind of world she came from, and that she tried to make a new life for herself. Above all, one gets a sense of how weird (and mildly depraved) it must have been in Andy Warhol's world. I recommend the film. Also starring Jared Harris. Director Mary Harron later directed "American Psycho".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent recreation on film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    encyes
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although 'I shot Andy Warhol' might not be everyone's cup of tea, it is a nice, slick film that grabs the viewers' attention right from the start. It is however Lily Taylor's performance that makes the movie. She commands every scene and displays her brilliance as an actress whether she comes off as angry, confused, ignorant or naive. The film flows very well except for the party scene which drags on slightly. The only negative piece to it is that the watchers never learns the fates of all those involved in this crazy time. Otherwise, 'Andy Warhol' is an intriguing drop into the world of one woman's insanity and it's resulting effects.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Indeed a Scum's manifesto
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rose-294
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A movie about Valerie Solanas, 1960s radical feminist who worked with the pop artist Andy Warhol and - you guessed it - tried to kill him. Sewer-mouthed tomboy who works as a whore and hates men and femininity, she writes SCUM manifesto - no, not her biography, albeit the name is apt, but militant feminist ramblings - and tries to do the murderous deed. (No, it is not really a spoiler, it is mentioned in the title.) Albeit suffering later from paranoia and mental illness, which is always a tragedy, her totally disgusting personality makes her anything but sympathetic. Not that other characters would be more interesting or likable. Blech.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie, Bad Subject
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Karl Self
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great movie which took me to a lot of exotic destinations such as 1960ies New York, the Factory family and the emerging transgender scene. The movie also does an excellent job of portraying the fragmented life and difficult personality of Valerie Solanas convincingly. My only problem with this movie is this: you don't have to be Andy Warhol's biggest fan to think that the fact that Solanas tried to wipe out three people in cold blood (that she only wounded two wasn't for lack of trying) is an at best insufficient reason for turning the lime light on to her. Making a movie about the Factory scene from Valerie Solanas' perspective is like making a movie about the Beatles as seen through the eyes of Mark Chapman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fairly interesting story about a deranged moron.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fedor8
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I Shot Andy Warhol"... And what a loss it would have been, too, to the world of TRUE ART if she had succeeded in murdering him. A giant. A genius. Or maybe just a hyped-up talentless little autistic freak. The movie title could also be misinterpreted to be about one of Andy's many gay lovers. "I Shot My Load Right Into Andy Warhol's Apathetic Face". As for Valerie S., this woman clearly could not have had a high level of intelligence, while the opposite has been suggested here, rather groundlessly. And as far as being a genius, as some people consider her to be, she was just as much a genius as Warhol. (Look, Warhol seems to have been a nice guy, but everything he did was pure b******t-orama.) That she was molested by her father I do not accept as a fact, as this excuse has been so over-used in the recent decades to the extent that it has lost all believability - which just serves to harm the real victims. The funniest moment in the film (or rather, the only funny moment) was at the very end in the epilogue; here I am informed that Valerie's manifesto is today considered a feminist classic! Funny that, but I was banking on the fact that it must today be considered as funny (or sad) as any other extreme left-wing or right-wing piece of writing, and is hence dismissed even by ardent feminists as irrelevant ravings of a pathetic lunatic. But, as it turns out, I have once again underestimated the tinniness of a modern feminist's brain. Valerie's manifesto seems to be merely a laughable and hateful series of emotionally-induced hallucinations of one woman's twisted view of the world, based solely on her hatred of men. (And if you see how ugly this dog really looked, you'd partly understand why.) It seems to have been enough for her to learn about the chromosome difference between men and women to start arriving to bizarrely idiotic conclusions. A really intelligent person presents their case with logic and facts, not with silly generalizations and theories that have as much of a scientific basis as the infamous babblings of Hitler's and Stalin's medical and biology scientists, with their ideology-driven b******t research. A highly intelligent person in her place - insane or not - would first ask themselves why they hate men so much. She simply hated them, without analyzing herself. How do I know that? Well, she seems to treat everything else with superficiality; judging from this film - and there are plenty of quotes from her junk writings to form a relatively clear picture of her. Her only way of approaching any idea or concept was to disregard all facts, but instead go full steam ahead with emotion, and emotional thinking is the most essential ingredient in arriving to irrational and absurd conclusions. Ironically, with her unceasing emotionalism and lack of logic she was in fact only giving more support to all the male chauvinists of this world who consider women to be emotional and illogical, while she was trying to prove the opposite - that it is men who are inferior. But whether it's men or women, one thing is for sure: the most inferior species of people on this planet are fanatics, radicals and other morons who view the world in black and white terms. And I am not talking about politicians who oversimplify to achieve their goals without actually believing in the ideologies they are selling themselves - I am talking about the real believers, the low-life losers like Valerie S.; pitiful and bitter sods whose intensity of their beliefs should never be mistaken for genius. Perhaps the chauvinists are right; it does seem that women have a surplus of illogicality and emotionalist thinking; after all, it's no coincidence that the late 20th century feminist movement is one that exceeds in stupidity more then any other contemporary movement I can think of - except maybe the Green movement and PETA. But, the again, they are also run by women; there you have it. Anyway... The film is interesting mainly due to Taylor's convincing performance, and the dialog is interesting enough. If you're interested in reading my extensive satire on modern/abstract art, "Picasso", contact me by e-mail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Movie; but who or what is 'Genius'?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vmbicu
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie without doubt was great, but why do they call Andy Warhol a genius, did he invent something or discover something outstanding? I ask this because in our society or the Art world, someone will take simple dog feces from the street, freshly 'produced' and create a design on canvas with it and this person will be labeled for life, a genius! This kind of thing makes me wonder, for I can see people use regular paint that is used on canvas paintings and paint their faces and body with it. How many will also take freshly produced dog feces and paint their faces and body with it?! As for the movie, I only have one question, how is it that this girl walks over to Andy Warhol, fires one shot misses or just wounds Andy, and the other two that were there just do nothing! I mean this is a girl they know, petite and according to the movie, she just stood rigid with the gun pointed to Andy. Then when she fires a shot closer to Andy and he falls, she slowly walks to him, points the gun to his chest and shoots. You think there was no time for two guys to rush her and pin her petite body down and wrestle the gun away? After all, Andy was revered as a genius? What other opinions are there on this? Or did the director of the movie take some liberties to show the frame of her mind when she shot Andy Warhol?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Looks and sounds amazing, but the narrative lags...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lili Taylor plays Valerie Solanas, an educated loose cannon, guerrilla female activist and self-described 'bull dyke', who was taken into custody in June 1968 after shooting and wounding Andy Warhol at his New York City office/hangout The Factory. Good-looking movie investigates a hazy chapter in history, yet leaves some unanswered questions in its wake (I wasn't aware that apparently an assistant was also shot, though the film makes no attempt to explain what happened to him). However, this small-budgeted film captures a decadently apathetic, coolly indifferent time and place quite vividly, as good as any post-'60s movie has yet managed. Taylor is appropriately forceful and ungainly in her role, which is more complex than one might think, and yet hers is the least interesting or intriguing character on display. Stephen Dorff does a pretty terrific job as transvestite Candy Darling, Tahnee Welch is unrecognizable as Warhol's most famous starlet Viva, and Jared Harris is flawless as Warhol (he nails it). Terrific art direction and composition, but the film lags a bit in the narrative department, with Solanas meeting an anti-bourgeois activist which doesn't come to much and has a facetious, puzzling relationship with publisher Maurice Girodias which seems half-baked. **1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Her Fifteen Minutes Of Fame
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lechuguilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you shoot someone whom others consider "important" I suppose some filmmaker will want to make a movie about you. I can think of no other reason why anyone would want to make a film about Valerie Solanas (Lili Taylor), the spunky, chain-smoking, foul-mouthed, self-centered, lesbian feminist who, in the summer of 1968, shot Andy Warhol (Jared Harris). Warhol was a New York City painter/artist ... or something ... and guru of all things avant-garde, who attracted the chic and the trendy to his New York City "Factory", the center of counterculture pop art. In the film Solanas, who harbors an enormous grudge against men, comes across initially as assertive and resourceful. She makes a living hustling the streets: "Pardon me sir, you got 15 cents? Pardon me sir ..." On the rooftop of a high-rise she types her S.C.U.M. "manifesto", outlining her complaints against the male species. But whereas Solanas is passionate about her cause, Warhol is a study in emotional detachment and indifference. He, and those in his orbit, sees Solanas more as a hanger-on. At one point, Solanas shows Warhol her typed manifesto. Warhol flips through it and responds in a deadpan manner: "Did you type this yourself? I'm so impressed. You should come type for us." Marvelous. The film's best element is the acting. Lili Taylor is terrific. She really gets into the Solanas persona. Jared Harris also gives a splendid performance. The film's tone teeters between seriousness and tongue-in-cheek humor. Costumes, prod design, music, and lighting are all credible. For modern day feminists, "I Shot Andy Warhol" probably is required viewing. For others, the film offers a cinematic study into the mindset of a quirky, sincere, but ultimately self-deceptive and delusional young woman who got her fifteen minutes of fame by carrying her political cause a little too far.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    thought provoking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CountZero313
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lili Taylor gives a savagely kinetic performance in this representation of a disturbed individual who may just also have been a genius despite, or because of, her treatment at the hands of various men throughout her life. Judging biopics in terms of historical accuracy is for the most part a futile exercise. There is no 'truth', only interpretation, but if you want to get closer to the facts you really should be in the library, not the movie theatre. The story of Valerie Solanas is especially vexing in this case, because were this a work of complete fiction, the script would never have been made. The 'so what?' factor is superseded by the fact that this actually happened, and the legacy of Solanas still divides contemporary feminists. As cinema, the film succeeds through the charisma exuded in Taylor's performance. Her descent into madness is sudden, vicious and uncompromising. The depiction of the shooting, the moment the film has been leading up to, shows a human being divorced absolutely from her conscience. The groovy scene around Warhol's the Factory is both decadent and, viewed from the 21st century, slightly twee. The pastiche of Sixties nostalgia is less foregrounded than Solanas's brutal victimhood. The film begins with a reading of her psychiatric evaluation, where a litany of unpunished crimes inflicted upon this woman by various men is laid out. The female director sets her stall out straight away - what you are hearing now leads through a direct line of cause and effect to the monstrous act you will see committed by Solanas later. If the film has a major flaw, it is the title. Audiences could be mistaken for thinking it is about a documentarian of Warhol's life and work. Solanas and her SCUM manifesto, for better or worse, have made their mark, and perhaps 'Solanas' would have been a more fitting (if less marketable) title. Did it take the shooting for that to be the case? A polemical moment in recent history relayed straightforwardly, this is competent, entertaining, edifying cinema.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Culturally Significant but only Marginally Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gpeevers
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of Valerie Solanas who as the title indicates was responsible for shooting pop artist Andy Warhol. Solanas was a highly intelligent radical feminist but was she also obviously deeply disturbed. The film also functions secondarily as a portrayal of the fringe culture that was attracted to Andy Warhol and his well known open studio The Factory. The film is for the most part a study of a deranged mind and a portrait of self destruction as Valerie spirals out of control. We are informed that Valerie may have been psychologically damaged by abuse from her childhood but that's not dealt with in the scope of the film. Due to the films focus it is difficult to sympathize with Valerie and there is little opportunity to get to know any of the other characters very well, as a result I didn't really connect with the film. As to the positives, Lilli Taylor gives a very compelling performance that while not very appealing or attractive as a human being is a very effective portrayal. The rest of the cast is by and large good though I found some of the performances or perhaps the characters very typically indie as they strove to standout sometimes at the expensive of character development. I also found that the score did not always seem appropriate to the material, it starts off somewhat symphonic and other times it just seemed jarring. Valerie Solanas's opus per se was the Scum Manifesto which spelled out her vision of an all-female society brought about by violent revolution.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    here's what happens when people take to the underworld
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had never heard of Valerie Solanas before seeing "I Shot Andy Warhol", but the movie does a very good job telling the story. We see Valerie as a misunderstood - but strong-willed - person disenchanted with the world around her. Lili Taylor does a really good job showing what sort of person Solanas was. The movie doesn't try to deify Solanas in any way, it shows what kind of world she came from, and that she tried to make a new life for herself. Above all, one gets a sense of how weird (and mildly depraved) it must have been in Andy Warhol's world. I recommend the film. Also starring Jared Harris. Director Mary Harron later directed "American Psycho".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent recreation on film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    encyes
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although 'I shot Andy Warhol' might not be everyone's cup of tea, it is a nice, slick film that grabs the viewers' attention right from the start. It is however Lily Taylor's performance that makes the movie. She commands every scene and displays her brilliance as an actress whether she comes off as angry, confused, ignorant or naive. The film flows very well except for the party scene which drags on slightly. The only negative piece to it is that the watchers never learns the fates of all those involved in this crazy time. Otherwise, 'Andy Warhol' is an intriguing drop into the world of one woman's insanity and it's resulting effects.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Indeed a Scum's manifesto
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rose-294
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A movie about Valerie Solanas, 1960s radical feminist who worked with the pop artist Andy Warhol and - you guessed it - tried to kill him. Sewer-mouthed tomboy who works as a whore and hates men and femininity, she writes SCUM manifesto - no, not her biography, albeit the name is apt, but militant feminist ramblings - and tries to do the murderous deed. (No, it is not really a spoiler, it is mentioned in the title.) Albeit suffering later from paranoia and mental illness, which is always a tragedy, her totally disgusting personality makes her anything but sympathetic. Not that other characters would be more interesting or likable. Blech.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie, Bad Subject
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Karl Self
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great movie which took me to a lot of exotic destinations such as 1960ies New York, the Factory family and the emerging transgender scene. The movie also does an excellent job of portraying the fragmented life and difficult personality of Valerie Solanas convincingly. My only problem with this movie is this: you don't have to be Andy Warhol's biggest fan to think that the fact that Solanas tried to wipe out three people in cold blood (that she only wounded two wasn't for lack of trying) is an at best insufficient reason for turning the lime light on to her. Making a movie about the Factory scene from Valerie Solanas' perspective is like making a movie about the Beatles as seen through the eyes of Mark Chapman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fairly interesting story about a deranged moron.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fedor8
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I Shot Andy Warhol"... And what a loss it would have been, too, to the world of TRUE ART if she had succeeded in murdering him. A giant. A genius. Or maybe just a hyped-up talentless little autistic freak. The movie title could also be misinterpreted to be about one of Andy's many gay lovers. "I Shot My Load Right Into Andy Warhol's Apathetic Face". As for Valerie S., this woman clearly could not have had a high level of intelligence, while the opposite has been suggested here, rather groundlessly. And as far as being a genius, as some people consider her to be, she was just as much a genius as Warhol. (Look, Warhol seems to have been a nice guy, but everything he did was pure b******t-orama.) That she was molested by her father I do not accept as a fact, as this excuse has been so over-used in the recent decades to the extent that it has lost all believability - which just serves to harm the real victims. The funniest moment in the film (or rather, the only funny moment) was at the very end in the epilogue; here I am informed that Valerie's manifesto is today considered a feminist classic! Funny that, but I was banking on the fact that it must today be considered as funny (or sad) as any other extreme left-wing or right-wing piece of writing, and is hence dismissed even by ardent feminists as irrelevant ravings of a pathetic lunatic. But, as it turns out, I have once again underestimated the tinniness of a modern feminist's brain. Valerie's manifesto seems to be merely a laughable and hateful series of emotionally-induced hallucinations of one woman's twisted view of the world, based solely on her hatred of men. (And if you see how ugly this dog really looked, you'd partly understand why.) It seems to have been enough for her to learn about the chromosome difference between men and women to start arriving to bizarrely idiotic conclusions. A really intelligent person presents their case with logic and facts, not with silly generalizations and theories that have as much of a scientific basis as the infamous babblings of Hitler's and Stalin's medical and biology scientists, with their ideology-driven b******t research. A highly intelligent person in her place - insane or not - would first ask themselves why they hate men so much. She simply hated them, without analyzing herself. How do I know that? Well, she seems to treat everything else with superficiality; judging from this film - and there are plenty of quotes from her junk writings to form a relatively clear picture of her. Her only way of approaching any idea or concept was to disregard all facts, but instead go full steam ahead with emotion, and emotional thinking is the most essential ingredient in arriving to irrational and absurd conclusions. Ironically, with her unceasing emotionalism and lack of logic she was in fact only giving more support to all the male chauvinists of this world who consider women to be emotional and illogical, while she was trying to prove the opposite - that it is men who are inferior. But whether it's men or women, one thing is for sure: the most inferior species of people on this planet are fanatics, radicals and other morons who view the world in black and white terms. And I am not talking about politicians who oversimplify to achieve their goals without actually believing in the ideologies they are selling themselves - I am talking about the real believers, the low-life losers like Valerie S.; pitiful and bitter sods whose intensity of their beliefs should never be mistaken for genius. Perhaps the chauvinists are right; it does seem that women have a surplus of illogicality and emotionalist thinking; after all, it's no coincidence that the late 20th century feminist movement is one that exceeds in stupidity more then any other contemporary movement I can think of - except maybe the Green movement and PETA. But, the again, they are also run by women; there you have it. Anyway... The film is interesting mainly due to Taylor's convincing performance, and the dialog is interesting enough. If you're interested in reading my extensive satire on modern/abstract art, "Picasso", contact me by e-mail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Movie; but who or what is 'Genius'?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vmbicu
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie without doubt was great, but why do they call Andy Warhol a genius, did he invent something or discover something outstanding? I ask this because in our society or the Art world, someone will take simple dog feces from the street, freshly 'produced' and create a design on canvas with it and this person will be labeled for life, a genius! This kind of thing makes me wonder, for I can see people use regular paint that is used on canvas paintings and paint their faces and body with it. How many will also take freshly produced dog feces and paint their faces and body with it?! As for the movie, I only have one question, how is it that this girl walks over to Andy Warhol, fires one shot misses or just wounds Andy, and the other two that were there just do nothing! I mean this is a girl they know, petite and according to the movie, she just stood rigid with the gun pointed to Andy. Then when she fires a shot closer to Andy and he falls, she slowly walks to him, points the gun to his chest and shoots. You think there was no time for two guys to rush her and pin her petite body down and wrestle the gun away? After all, Andy was revered as a genius? What other opinions are there on this? Or did the director of the movie take some liberties to show the frame of her mind when she shot Andy Warhol?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Looks and sounds amazing, but the narrative lags...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lili Taylor plays Valerie Solanas, an educated loose cannon, guerrilla female activist and self-described 'bull dyke', who was taken into custody in June 1968 after shooting and wounding Andy Warhol at his New York City office/hangout The Factory. Good-looking movie investigates a hazy chapter in history, yet leaves some unanswered questions in its wake (I wasn't aware that apparently an assistant was also shot, though the film makes no attempt to explain what happened to him). However, this small-budgeted film captures a decadently apathetic, coolly indifferent time and place quite vividly, as good as any post-'60s movie has yet managed. Taylor is appropriately forceful and ungainly in her role, which is more complex than one might think, and yet hers is the least interesting or intriguing character on display. Stephen Dorff does a pretty terrific job as transvestite Candy Darling, Tahnee Welch is unrecognizable as Warhol's most famous starlet Viva, and Jared Harris is flawless as Warhol (he nails it). Terrific art direction and composition, but the film lags a bit in the narrative department, with Solanas meeting an anti-bourgeois activist which doesn't come to much and has a facetious, puzzling relationship with publisher Maurice Girodias which seems half-baked. **1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Her Fifteen Minutes Of Fame
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lechuguilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you shoot someone whom others consider "important" I suppose some filmmaker will want to make a movie about you. I can think of no other reason why anyone would want to make a film about Valerie Solanas (Lili Taylor), the spunky, chain-smoking, foul-mouthed, self-centered, lesbian feminist who, in the summer of 1968, shot Andy Warhol (Jared Harris). Warhol was a New York City painter/artist ... or something ... and guru of all things avant-garde, who attracted the chic and the trendy to his New York City "Factory", the center of counterculture pop art. In the film Solanas, who harbors an enormous grudge against men, comes across initially as assertive and resourceful. She makes a living hustling the streets: "Pardon me sir, you got 15 cents? Pardon me sir ..." On the rooftop of a high-rise she types her S.C.U.M. "manifesto", outlining her complaints against the male species. But whereas Solanas is passionate about her cause, Warhol is a study in emotional detachment and indifference. He, and those in his orbit, sees Solanas more as a hanger-on. At one point, Solanas shows Warhol her typed manifesto. Warhol flips through it and responds in a deadpan manner: "Did you type this yourself? I'm so impressed. You should come type for us." Marvelous. The film's best element is the acting. Lili Taylor is terrific. She really gets into the Solanas persona. Jared Harris also gives a splendid performance. The film's tone teeters between seriousness and tongue-in-cheek humor. Costumes, prod design, music, and lighting are all credible. For modern day feminists, "I Shot Andy Warhol" probably is required viewing. For others, the film offers a cinematic study into the mindset of a quirky, sincere, but ultimately self-deceptive and delusional young woman who got her fifteen minutes of fame by carrying her political cause a little too far.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    thought provoking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CountZero313
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lili Taylor gives a savagely kinetic performance in this representation of a disturbed individual who may just also have been a genius despite, or because of, her treatment at the hands of various men throughout her life. Judging biopics in terms of historical accuracy is for the most part a futile exercise. There is no 'truth', only interpretation, but if you want to get closer to the facts you really should be in the library, not the movie theatre. The story of Valerie Solanas is especially vexing in this case, because were this a work of complete fiction, the script would never have been made. The 'so what?' factor is superseded by the fact that this actually happened, and the legacy of Solanas still divides contemporary feminists. As cinema, the film succeeds through the charisma exuded in Taylor's performance. Her descent into madness is sudden, vicious and uncompromising. The depiction of the shooting, the moment the film has been leading up to, shows a human being divorced absolutely from her conscience. The groovy scene around Warhol's the Factory is both decadent and, viewed from the 21st century, slightly twee. The pastiche of Sixties nostalgia is less foregrounded than Solanas's brutal victimhood. The film begins with a reading of her psychiatric evaluation, where a litany of unpunished crimes inflicted upon this woman by various men is laid out. The female director sets her stall out straight away - what you are hearing now leads through a direct line of cause and effect to the monstrous act you will see committed by Solanas later. If the film has a major flaw, it is the title. Audiences could be mistaken for thinking it is about a documentarian of Warhol's life and work. Solanas and her SCUM manifesto, for better or worse, have made their mark, and perhaps 'Solanas' would have been a more fitting (if less marketable) title. Did it take the shooting for that to be the case? A polemical moment in recent history relayed straightforwardly, this is competent, entertaining, edifying cinema.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Culturally Significant but only Marginally Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gpeevers
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of Valerie Solanas who as the title indicates was responsible for shooting pop artist Andy Warhol. Solanas was a highly intelligent radical feminist but was she also obviously deeply disturbed. The film also functions secondarily as a portrayal of the fringe culture that was attracted to Andy Warhol and his well known open studio The Factory. The film is for the most part a study of a deranged mind and a portrait of self destruction as Valerie spirals out of control. We are informed that Valerie may have been psychologically damaged by abuse from her childhood but that's not dealt with in the scope of the film. Due to the films focus it is difficult to sympathize with Valerie and there is little opportunity to get to know any of the other characters very well, as a result I didn't really connect with the film. As to the positives, Lilli Taylor gives a very compelling performance that while not very appealing or attractive as a human being is a very effective portrayal. The rest of the cast is by and large good though I found some of the performances or perhaps the characters very typically indie as they strove to standout sometimes at the expensive of character development. I also found that the score did not always seem appropriate to the material, it starts off somewhat symphonic and other times it just seemed jarring. Valerie Solanas's opus per se was the Scum Manifesto which spelled out her vision of an all-female society brought about by violent revolution.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    here's what happens when people take to the underworld
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had never heard of Valerie Solanas before seeing "I Shot Andy Warhol", but the movie does a very good job telling the story. We see Valerie as a misunderstood - but strong-willed - person disenchanted with the world around her. Lili Taylor does a really good job showing what sort of person Solanas was. The movie doesn't try to deify Solanas in any way, it shows what kind of world she came from, and that she tried to make a new life for herself. Above all, one gets a sense of how weird (and mildly depraved) it must have been in Andy Warhol's world. I recommend the film. Also starring Jared Harris. Director Mary Harron later directed "American Psycho".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent recreation on film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    encyes
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although 'I shot Andy Warhol' might not be everyone's cup of tea, it is a nice, slick film that grabs the viewers' attention right from the start. It is however Lily Taylor's performance that makes the movie. She commands every scene and displays her brilliance as an actress whether she comes off as angry, confused, ignorant or naive. The film flows very well except for the party scene which drags on slightly. The only negative piece to it is that the watchers never learns the fates of all those involved in this crazy time. Otherwise, 'Andy Warhol' is an intriguing drop into the world of one woman's insanity and it's resulting effects.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Indeed a Scum's manifesto
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rose-294
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A movie about Valerie Solanas, 1960s radical feminist who worked with the pop artist Andy Warhol and - you guessed it - tried to kill him. Sewer-mouthed tomboy who works as a whore and hates men and femininity, she writes SCUM manifesto - no, not her biography, albeit the name is apt, but militant feminist ramblings - and tries to do the murderous deed. (No, it is not really a spoiler, it is mentioned in the title.) Albeit suffering later from paranoia and mental illness, which is always a tragedy, her totally disgusting personality makes her anything but sympathetic. Not that other characters would be more interesting or likable. Blech.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie, Bad Subject
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Karl Self
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great movie which took me to a lot of exotic destinations such as 1960ies New York, the Factory family and the emerging transgender scene. The movie also does an excellent job of portraying the fragmented life and difficult personality of Valerie Solanas convincingly. My only problem with this movie is this: you don't have to be Andy Warhol's biggest fan to think that the fact that Solanas tried to wipe out three people in cold blood (that she only wounded two wasn't for lack of trying) is an at best insufficient reason for turning the lime light on to her. Making a movie about the Factory scene from Valerie Solanas' perspective is like making a movie about the Beatles as seen through the eyes of Mark Chapman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fairly interesting story about a deranged moron.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fedor8
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I Shot Andy Warhol"... And what a loss it would have been, too, to the world of TRUE ART if she had succeeded in murdering him. A giant. A genius. Or maybe just a hyped-up talentless little autistic freak. The movie title could also be misinterpreted to be about one of Andy's many gay lovers. "I Shot My Load Right Into Andy Warhol's Apathetic Face". As for Valerie S., this woman clearly could not have had a high level of intelligence, while the opposite has been suggested here, rather groundlessly. And as far as being a genius, as some people consider her to be, she was just as much a genius as Warhol. (Look, Warhol seems to have been a nice guy, but everything he did was pure b******t-orama.) That she was molested by her father I do not accept as a fact, as this excuse has been so over-used in the recent decades to the extent that it has lost all believability - which just serves to harm the real victims. The funniest moment in the film (or rather, the only funny moment) was at the very end in the epilogue; here I am informed that Valerie's manifesto is today considered a feminist classic! Funny that, but I was banking on the fact that it must today be considered as funny (or sad) as any other extreme left-wing or right-wing piece of writing, and is hence dismissed even by ardent feminists as irrelevant ravings of a pathetic lunatic. But, as it turns out, I have once again underestimated the tinniness of a modern feminist's brain. Valerie's manifesto seems to be merely a laughable and hateful series of emotionally-induced hallucinations of one woman's twisted view of the world, based solely on her hatred of men. (And if you see how ugly this dog really looked, you'd partly understand why.) It seems to have been enough for her to learn about the chromosome difference between men and women to start arriving to bizarrely idiotic conclusions. A really intelligent person presents their case with logic and facts, not with silly generalizations and theories that have as much of a scientific basis as the infamous babblings of Hitler's and Stalin's medical and biology scientists, with their ideology-driven b******t research. A highly intelligent person in her place - insane or not - would first ask themselves why they hate men so much. She simply hated them, without analyzing herself. How do I know that? Well, she seems to treat everything else with superficiality; judging from this film - and there are plenty of quotes from her junk writings to form a relatively clear picture of her. Her only way of approaching any idea or concept was to disregard all facts, but instead go full steam ahead with emotion, and emotional thinking is the most essential ingredient in arriving to irrational and absurd conclusions. Ironically, with her unceasing emotionalism and lack of logic she was in fact only giving more support to all the male chauvinists of this world who consider women to be emotional and illogical, while she was trying to prove the opposite - that it is men who are inferior. But whether it's men or women, one thing is for sure: the most inferior species of people on this planet are fanatics, radicals and other morons who view the world in black and white terms. And I am not talking about politicians who oversimplify to achieve their goals without actually believing in the ideologies they are selling themselves - I am talking about the real believers, the low-life losers like Valerie S.; pitiful and bitter sods whose intensity of their beliefs should never be mistaken for genius. Perhaps the chauvinists are right; it does seem that women have a surplus of illogicality and emotionalist thinking; after all, it's no coincidence that the late 20th century feminist movement is one that exceeds in stupidity more then any other contemporary movement I can think of - except maybe the Green movement and PETA. But, the again, they are also run by women; there you have it. Anyway... The film is interesting mainly due to Taylor's convincing performance, and the dialog is interesting enough. If you're interested in reading my extensive satire on modern/abstract art, "Picasso", contact me by e-mail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Movie; but who or what is 'Genius'?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vmbicu
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie without doubt was great, but why do they call Andy Warhol a genius, did he invent something or discover something outstanding? I ask this because in our society or the Art world, someone will take simple dog feces from the street, freshly 'produced' and create a design on canvas with it and this person will be labeled for life, a genius! This kind of thing makes me wonder, for I can see people use regular paint that is used on canvas paintings and paint their faces and body with it. How many will also take freshly produced dog feces and paint their faces and body with it?! As for the movie, I only have one question, how is it that this girl walks over to Andy Warhol, fires one shot misses or just wounds Andy, and the other two that were there just do nothing! I mean this is a girl they know, petite and according to the movie, she just stood rigid with the gun pointed to Andy. Then when she fires a shot closer to Andy and he falls, she slowly walks to him, points the gun to his chest and shoots. You think there was no time for two guys to rush her and pin her petite body down and wrestle the gun away? After all, Andy was revered as a genius? What other opinions are there on this? Or did the director of the movie take some liberties to show the frame of her mind when she shot Andy Warhol?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Looks and sounds amazing, but the narrative lags...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lili Taylor plays Valerie Solanas, an educated loose cannon, guerrilla female activist and self-described 'bull dyke', who was taken into custody in June 1968 after shooting and wounding Andy Warhol at his New York City office/hangout The Factory. Good-looking movie investigates a hazy chapter in history, yet leaves some unanswered questions in its wake (I wasn't aware that apparently an assistant was also shot, though the film makes no attempt to explain what happened to him). However, this small-budgeted film captures a decadently apathetic, coolly indifferent time and place quite vividly, as good as any post-'60s movie has yet managed. Taylor is appropriately forceful and ungainly in her role, which is more complex than one might think, and yet hers is the least interesting or intriguing character on display. Stephen Dorff does a pretty terrific job as transvestite Candy Darling, Tahnee Welch is unrecognizable as Warhol's most famous starlet Viva, and Jared Harris is flawless as Warhol (he nails it). Terrific art direction and composition, but the film lags a bit in the narrative department, with Solanas meeting an anti-bourgeois activist which doesn't come to much and has a facetious, puzzling relationship with publisher Maurice Girodias which seems half-baked. **1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Her Fifteen Minutes Of Fame
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lechuguilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you shoot someone whom others consider "important" I suppose some filmmaker will want to make a movie about you. I can think of no other reason why anyone would want to make a film about Valerie Solanas (Lili Taylor), the spunky, chain-smoking, foul-mouthed, self-centered, lesbian feminist who, in the summer of 1968, shot Andy Warhol (Jared Harris). Warhol was a New York City painter/artist ... or something ... and guru of all things avant-garde, who attracted the chic and the trendy to his New York City "Factory", the center of counterculture pop art. In the film Solanas, who harbors an enormous grudge against men, comes across initially as assertive and resourceful. She makes a living hustling the streets: "Pardon me sir, you got 15 cents? Pardon me sir ..." On the rooftop of a high-rise she types her S.C.U.M. "manifesto", outlining her complaints against the male species. But whereas Solanas is passionate about her cause, Warhol is a study in emotional detachment and indifference. He, and those in his orbit, sees Solanas more as a hanger-on. At one point, Solanas shows Warhol her typed manifesto. Warhol flips through it and responds in a deadpan manner: "Did you type this yourself? I'm so impressed. You should come type for us." Marvelous. The film's best element is the acting. Lili Taylor is terrific. She really gets into the Solanas persona. Jared Harris also gives a splendid performance. The film's tone teeters between seriousness and tongue-in-cheek humor. Costumes, prod design, music, and lighting are all credible. For modern day feminists, "I Shot Andy Warhol" probably is required viewing. For others, the film offers a cinematic study into the mindset of a quirky, sincere, but ultimately self-deceptive and delusional young woman who got her fifteen minutes of fame by carrying her political cause a little too far.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    thought provoking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CountZero313
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lili Taylor gives a savagely kinetic performance in this representation of a disturbed individual who may just also have been a genius despite, or because of, her treatment at the hands of various men throughout her life. Judging biopics in terms of historical accuracy is for the most part a futile exercise. There is no 'truth', only interpretation, but if you want to get closer to the facts you really should be in the library, not the movie theatre. The story of Valerie Solanas is especially vexing in this case, because were this a work of complete fiction, the script would never have been made. The 'so what?' factor is superseded by the fact that this actually happened, and the legacy of Solanas still divides contemporary feminists. As cinema, the film succeeds through the charisma exuded in Taylor's performance. Her descent into madness is sudden, vicious and uncompromising. The depiction of the shooting, the moment the film has been leading up to, shows a human being divorced absolutely from her conscience. The groovy scene around Warhol's the Factory is both decadent and, viewed from the 21st century, slightly twee. The pastiche of Sixties nostalgia is less foregrounded than Solanas's brutal victimhood. The film begins with a reading of her psychiatric evaluation, where a litany of unpunished crimes inflicted upon this woman by various men is laid out. The female director sets her stall out straight away - what you are hearing now leads through a direct line of cause and effect to the monstrous act you will see committed by Solanas later. If the film has a major flaw, it is the title. Audiences could be mistaken for thinking it is about a documentarian of Warhol's life and work. Solanas and her SCUM manifesto, for better or worse, have made their mark, and perhaps 'Solanas' would have been a more fitting (if less marketable) title. Did it take the shooting for that to be the case? A polemical moment in recent history relayed straightforwardly, this is competent, entertaining, edifying cinema.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Culturally Significant but only Marginally Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gpeevers
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of Valerie Solanas who as the title indicates was responsible for shooting pop artist Andy Warhol. Solanas was a highly intelligent radical feminist but was she also obviously deeply disturbed. The film also functions secondarily as a portrayal of the fringe culture that was attracted to Andy Warhol and his well known open studio The Factory. The film is for the most part a study of a deranged mind and a portrait of self destruction as Valerie spirals out of control. We are informed that Valerie may have been psychologically damaged by abuse from her childhood but that's not dealt with in the scope of the film. Due to the films focus it is difficult to sympathize with Valerie and there is little opportunity to get to know any of the other characters very well, as a result I didn't really connect with the film. As to the positives, Lilli Taylor gives a very compelling performance that while not very appealing or attractive as a human being is a very effective portrayal. The rest of the cast is by and large good though I found some of the performances or perhaps the characters very typically indie as they strove to standout sometimes at the expensive of character development. I also found that the score did not always seem appropriate to the material, it starts off somewhat symphonic and other times it just seemed jarring. Valerie Solanas's opus per se was the Scum Manifesto which spelled out her vision of an all-female society brought about by violent revolution.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    here's what happens when people take to the underworld
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had never heard of Valerie Solanas before seeing "I Shot Andy Warhol", but the movie does a very good job telling the story. We see Valerie as a misunderstood - but strong-willed - person disenchanted with the world around her. Lili Taylor does a really good job showing what sort of person Solanas was. The movie doesn't try to deify Solanas in any way, it shows what kind of world she came from, and that she tried to make a new life for herself. Above all, one gets a sense of how weird (and mildly depraved) it must have been in Andy Warhol's world. I recommend the film. Also starring Jared Harris. Director Mary Harron later directed "American Psycho".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent recreation on film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    encyes
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although 'I shot Andy Warhol' might not be everyone's cup of tea, it is a nice, slick film that grabs the viewers' attention right from the start. It is however Lily Taylor's performance that makes the movie. She commands every scene and displays her brilliance as an actress whether she comes off as angry, confused, ignorant or naive. The film flows very well except for the party scene which drags on slightly. The only negative piece to it is that the watchers never learns the fates of all those involved in this crazy time. Otherwise, 'Andy Warhol' is an intriguing drop into the world of one woman's insanity and it's resulting effects.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Indeed a Scum's manifesto
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rose-294
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A movie about Valerie Solanas, 1960s radical feminist who worked with the pop artist Andy Warhol and - you guessed it - tried to kill him. Sewer-mouthed tomboy who works as a whore and hates men and femininity, she writes SCUM manifesto - no, not her biography, albeit the name is apt, but militant feminist ramblings - and tries to do the murderous deed. (No, it is not really a spoiler, it is mentioned in the title.) Albeit suffering later from paranoia and mental illness, which is always a tragedy, her totally disgusting personality makes her anything but sympathetic. Not that other characters would be more interesting or likable. Blech.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie, Bad Subject
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Karl Self
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great movie which took me to a lot of exotic destinations such as 1960ies New York, the Factory family and the emerging transgender scene. The movie also does an excellent job of portraying the fragmented life and difficult personality of Valerie Solanas convincingly. My only problem with this movie is this: you don't have to be Andy Warhol's biggest fan to think that the fact that Solanas tried to wipe out three people in cold blood (that she only wounded two wasn't for lack of trying) is an at best insufficient reason for turning the lime light on to her. Making a movie about the Factory scene from Valerie Solanas' perspective is like making a movie about the Beatles as seen through the eyes of Mark Chapman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fairly interesting story about a deranged moron.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fedor8
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I Shot Andy Warhol"... And what a loss it would have been, too, to the world of TRUE ART if she had succeeded in murdering him. A giant. A genius. Or maybe just a hyped-up talentless little autistic freak. The movie title could also be misinterpreted to be about one of Andy's many gay lovers. "I Shot My Load Right Into Andy Warhol's Apathetic Face". As for Valerie S., this woman clearly could not have had a high level of intelligence, while the opposite has been suggested here, rather groundlessly. And as far as being a genius, as some people consider her to be, she was just as much a genius as Warhol. (Look, Warhol seems to have been a nice guy, but everything he did was pure b******t-orama.) That she was molested by her father I do not accept as a fact, as this excuse has been so over-used in the recent decades to the extent that it has lost all believability - which just serves to harm the real victims. The funniest moment in the film (or rather, the only funny moment) was at the very end in the epilogue; here I am informed that Valerie's manifesto is today considered a feminist classic! Funny that, but I was banking on the fact that it must today be considered as funny (or sad) as any other extreme left-wing or right-wing piece of writing, and is hence dismissed even by ardent feminists as irrelevant ravings of a pathetic lunatic. But, as it turns out, I have once again underestimated the tinniness of a modern feminist's brain. Valerie's manifesto seems to be merely a laughable and hateful series of emotionally-induced hallucinations of one woman's twisted view of the world, based solely on her hatred of men. (And if you see how ugly this dog really looked, you'd partly understand why.) It seems to have been enough for her to learn about the chromosome difference between men and women to start arriving to bizarrely idiotic conclusions. A really intelligent person presents their case with logic and facts, not with silly generalizations and theories that have as much of a scientific basis as the infamous babblings of Hitler's and Stalin's medical and biology scientists, with their ideology-driven b******t research. A highly intelligent person in her place - insane or not - would first ask themselves why they hate men so much. She simply hated them, without analyzing herself. How do I know that? Well, she seems to treat everything else with superficiality; judging from this film - and there are plenty of quotes from her junk writings to form a relatively clear picture of her. Her only way of approaching any idea or concept was to disregard all facts, but instead go full steam ahead with emotion, and emotional thinking is the most essential ingredient in arriving to irrational and absurd conclusions. Ironically, with her unceasing emotionalism and lack of logic she was in fact only giving more support to all the male chauvinists of this world who consider women to be emotional and illogical, while she was trying to prove the opposite - that it is men who are inferior. But whether it's men or women, one thing is for sure: the most inferior species of people on this planet are fanatics, radicals and other morons who view the world in black and white terms. And I am not talking about politicians who oversimplify to achieve their goals without actually believing in the ideologies they are selling themselves - I am talking about the real believers, the low-life losers like Valerie S.; pitiful and bitter sods whose intensity of their beliefs should never be mistaken for genius. Perhaps the chauvinists are right; it does seem that women have a surplus of illogicality and emotionalist thinking; after all, it's no coincidence that the late 20th century feminist movement is one that exceeds in stupidity more then any other contemporary movement I can think of - except maybe the Green movement and PETA. But, the again, they are also run by women; there you have it. Anyway... The film is interesting mainly due to Taylor's convincing performance, and the dialog is interesting enough. If you're interested in reading my extensive satire on modern/abstract art, "Picasso", contact me by e-mail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Movie; but who or what is 'Genius'?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vmbicu
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie without doubt was great, but why do they call Andy Warhol a genius, did he invent something or discover something outstanding? I ask this because in our society or the Art world, someone will take simple dog feces from the street, freshly 'produced' and create a design on canvas with it and this person will be labeled for life, a genius! This kind of thing makes me wonder, for I can see people use regular paint that is used on canvas paintings and paint their faces and body with it. How many will also take freshly produced dog feces and paint their faces and body with it?! As for the movie, I only have one question, how is it that this girl walks over to Andy Warhol, fires one shot misses or just wounds Andy, and the other two that were there just do nothing! I mean this is a girl they know, petite and according to the movie, she just stood rigid with the gun pointed to Andy. Then when she fires a shot closer to Andy and he falls, she slowly walks to him, points the gun to his chest and shoots. You think there was no time for two guys to rush her and pin her petite body down and wrestle the gun away? After all, Andy was revered as a genius? What other opinions are there on this? Or did the director of the movie take some liberties to show the frame of her mind when she shot Andy Warhol?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Looks and sounds amazing, but the narrative lags...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lili Taylor plays Valerie Solanas, an educated loose cannon, guerrilla female activist and self-described 'bull dyke', who was taken into custody in June 1968 after shooting and wounding Andy Warhol at his New York City office/hangout The Factory. Good-looking movie investigates a hazy chapter in history, yet leaves some unanswered questions in its wake (I wasn't aware that apparently an assistant was also shot, though the film makes no attempt to explain what happened to him). However, this small-budgeted film captures a decadently apathetic, coolly indifferent time and place quite vividly, as good as any post-'60s movie has yet managed. Taylor is appropriately forceful and ungainly in her role, which is more complex than one might think, and yet hers is the least interesting or intriguing character on display. Stephen Dorff does a pretty terrific job as transvestite Candy Darling, Tahnee Welch is unrecognizable as Warhol's most famous starlet Viva, and Jared Harris is flawless as Warhol (he nails it). Terrific art direction and composition, but the film lags a bit in the narrative department, with Solanas meeting an anti-bourgeois activist which doesn't come to much and has a facetious, puzzling relationship with publisher Maurice Girodias which seems half-baked. **1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
