<filme>
 <id>
  1010
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0115632
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Basquiat - Tra&ccedil;os de Uma Vida
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Basquiat tells the story of the meteoric rise of youthful artist Jean-Michel Basquiat. Starting out as a street artist, living in Thompkins Square Park in a cardboard box, Jean-Michel is "... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Basquiat tells the story of the meteoric rise of youthful artist Jean-Michel Basquiat. Starting out as a street artist, living in Thompkins Square Park in a cardboard box, Jean-Michel is "discovered" by Andy Warhol's art world and becomes a star. But success has a high price, and Basquiat pays with friendship, love, and eventually, his life.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Biography
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   artist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   friendship
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   street artist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   art
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   andy warhol
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Julian Schnabel
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Lech Majewski
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   John Bowe
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jeffrey Wright
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Michael Wincott
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Benicio Del Toro
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful! One of my fav movies of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doveniki
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jeffery Wright became Basquiat! He should have won the Oscar for this. If only it was made after Halle Berry's Monsters Ball. Brilliant casting, some of the best Soundtracks ever. I love this movie for so many reasons. It is artistic as the people it portraits. It also manages to put the viewer in the shoes of the characters. Although I don't do drugs I totally got lost as if I was high together in the room with Basquiat when he painted the tires. Every artist knows, that mentally you go to an other place while painting. Somehow each time I see this movie it manages to transfers me into Basquiats strange world. I know its horrible to be an addict, but this flick somehow showed the beauty of it.. I don't know, maybe you have to be an artist, a bit avanguart, in love with new york and music to totally appreciate this #
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just to note
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dusan-22
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am putting my comment on this movie just to emphasize childish level of the voters and visitors of this site. One great film like this deserves much more than attention of semi-infantile audience that is running around IMDb site. I can agree that the movie is a matter of taste, but its value encapsulated in the grade shouldn't spoil that. For example, I might don't appreciate Van Gogh's paintings but I can't say that his work deserves low grade. Great cast, great movie - everything is real art. Compares to the greatest art films I have ever seen this movie does not deserve the best grade, but compares to shallow art value and narrow oriented stories of the pre-school characters that are cherished with greatest ardour around here - this movie is a masterpiece. Jeffrey Wright is so convincing that after you see the film it stays with you for a pretty long time ...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the artist as a success, a sometimes but not always usual bio-pic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jean Michel Basquiat was a really intriguing creature. He was an artist in the truest proletariat sense of the word. Meaning that he could never be bourgeois, even as he was brought in to that world, dominated by the "15-minutes-of-fame" man himself, Andy Warhol. By the way Julian Schnabel's loving if not too adulatory portrait of Basquiat shows, he was a guy trapped a bit inside of his own mind artistically, but at the same time really responsive to the world around him, commenting on it, sometimes at random, other times with the skill of an artist who just turns the world on a dime without even seeming to try. His art may not appeal to everyone, but it's hard to deny what it is, which is material made to provoke some kind of reaction; only someone like a disconnected bourgeois, like Warhol's lover/manager Bruno (played by Dennis Hopper in this film) would be detached from Basquiat's art. But there poses another question that Schnabel poses to the audience (perhaps a little bluntly, but effective all the same): how does one who is not apart of one world assimilate in another? Basquiat wasn't always the nicest person or easiest to get along with, but he had that quality like Jim Morrison, where he could be turned on to someone so much and so brightly that it was hard to look away, quirks and seething anger (and drug addiction) and all. Schnabel also does not give the audience any firm reason about how or why Jean Michel turned out like this as a kid (we hear at one point from an interviewer he was raised middle class and chose to live in a cardboard box), and it's not always necessary really. He is who he is at the start- a quirky, amused and experimental artist and musician- and then from there his fame is what makes him more (or less) fascinating to us. Basquiat takes the proverbial 'bio-pic' route with some of the expectation one has. For example, Schnabel emphasizes his romantic ties to a waitress and artist, Gina (Forlani), and makes the professional part of his storyline concurrent to that, no more or less important than that strand. But this is not a deterrent to see the usual up-and-down love story between a flawed artist and his love. Perhaps more conventional is seeing the person in the story hooked on drugs, but it was a fact in Basquiat's life and it's dealt with tastefully, or at least realistically. And to counter some of the expectations one has with a 'rise-to-fame' story of an artist, Schnabel makes it very much a film in its time and place: it's late 70's, early 80's, in New York City, where grit and decay seems to counter (or attract) the glitz and glamor, also in its own kind of decay (Warhol was more of a leech by then anyway, in a great scene having someone else drink beer and pee on a canvas since he won't drink beer to do it himself). Sometimes it's just bizarre in a delightful way, like how Basquiat looks up at the sky and sees surfing, and other times it's a fine array of the period in terms of music, or just New York City kind of music in general (Miles Davis to Johnny Rotten to early 80's hip hop to the Rolling Stones). At the center of Schnabel's portrait of an artist as a quasi-question mark, is Jeffrey Wright. He's always 'on' in a scene, even when it looks like Jean Michel is somewhere else, or just not responding to another person in the room (just watch the way Wright, as Basquiat, defuses a very angry Gina after he's painted over her paintings when she wakes up). It's a curious thing, too, to see him contrasted with David Bowie, who almost seems to have gone method in portraying the pop-culture icon as a bit of a quiet creep. It's the kind of performance, by Wright, that says 'watch out for me, I have some good things to offer', and it was a real breakthrough role, leading to the kind of varied work of his career in work ranging from Syriana to Cadillac Records. But as Basquiat, he finds one of his richest real-life characters, an artist of the streets. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Limelight Burns
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JustApt
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basquiat is about the way the fame corrupts the mind or maybe his mind was corrupted right from the start, anyway his brains looked pretty cooked from the very beginning. Basquiat was a product of the hype and not of his talents, he was utilized by the vultures feeding off the art and turned into the merchandise by them. The film starts to the "Fairytale of New York"  a song by Pogues: "It was Christmas Eve in the drunk tank, babe, and I dreamed of you... I can see a better time when all our dreams come true"  the future is always sweet but when it becomes the present it turns into a crap: "You're bum, you're punk, you're an old slut on junk lying there almost dead on the drip in this bed." David Bowie in the role of Andy Warhol is a smasher and the multitude of cameos by the other big stars makes this picture seem like a starry night. This movie also boasts a superb soundtrack.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Weak subject ...... weak film ..................
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cannot believe this was supported by so many good actors, considering the subject was so boorish. Glorifying drug use as contributing to art sounds pretty boring and it is. The artists represented are so pretentious, they would not appeal as even casual acquaintances to most people. So why should anyone looking for entertainment be anything but disappointed with "Basquait"? This film probably should have been locally released in New York to the art house client&egrave;le and then dumped. They say art is in the eye of the beholder, well if this movie is art then it should hang on a wall, and not subject an audience to it's glorified nonsense. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely must see
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trumbull98
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every once in a while you watch a movie that means something to you. This is one. Totally compelling flick that let's you see a glimpse of another's soul. Jeffery Wright is so believable that I would guess he sometimes to this day slips back into character. While most viewers will have no way to judge the accuracy to the real Basquiat, the realism is none the less magical. Watch this movie and for about 90 minutes you will be transported directly into a creative period of American art & life history. There is nothing in this movie that appears out of place and it realistically captures life in NYT. Performances by all the supporting actors are great and Bowie's performance is amazing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Hollywood Attempt To Make A Loser Look Like A Winner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a nutshell: an interesting cast but a lousy movie. Make that a "horrible" movie. Real-life artist Jean Michel Baquiat died at the age of 27 from a heroin overdose, and he's pictured as the hero even though he's barely a step above being a sleazy street person in mentality, morals and beliefs. In other words, he's the kind of guy Hollywood loves. Basquiat (played by Jeffrey Wright) is surrounded by like-minded people in the art world: in other words, a lot of weird people, most of them pretty disgusting. It's the kind of film an agnostic and basically ignorant 18-year-old kid would like: sick. Having said all that, I like Basquiat's art. I've always found it fascinating, which is why I looked at the movie in the first place. I also like a lot of actors and actresses in here. It's just too bad the film wasn't nearly as good as the art and the actors. Another reviewer here, "Synchonic," said it best: "Empty movie full of empty people." I totally agree with that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid bio about one of many overrated "artists" of our idiotic times.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fedor8
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A decent bio about one of pop-art's worthless icons. That whole bogus New York "artiste" scene of the 60s (and onwards) has no value whatsoever. Nevertheless, the movie is quite easy-going and pleasant, and profits also from a large cast of great names (Wincott, Del Toro, Bowie, Posey, Walken, Dafoe, Oldman). There is also no denying that it's interesting to watch the lives within that ridiculous NY scene. Basquiat is shown as a near-tortured artist, though the constant money-for-nothing cash-inflow probably bothered him less. Wright plays him like a semi-retard, which is not an exaggeration  you just have to see Basquiat's retarded pictures with his dumb thoughts scribbled in lettering resembling a 7 year-old mongoloid's hand-writing, and you'll understand. Perhaps they tried to make him seem aloof and mysterious but it came out wrong (i.e. right). Even his walk appears to be suspiciously weird - Basquiat really did talk it like he walk it. Yet this guy lived quite recently so all the nuances of his behaviour should be well-recorded, so maybe he was really this screwed up. There should be a movie made just like this one, entirely about Warhol - that would be fun. If you want to read an extensive satire about modern art (mainly Picasso) contact me by e-mail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Taste This
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    balifox
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one is like a Christmas dinner except your pants won't feel two sizes too small afterwards. Jeffrey Wright is a succulent piece of delectable meat, Gary Oldman is my mashed potatoes, Benicio Del Toro adds his curious level of reason like only your best seasoned vegetable can and my Michael Wincotthe is so delicious, he is easily that forbidden piece of dessert at the end of the table that you swear you won't eat a minute before you are literally gorging yourself on it. The cast is simply pure gold. It is so good and enchanting with a 1980's charm that is simply non-existent in other films. It is the art, music and meaning of that decade at its purest. Effortless, yet clever the dialogue gives you the sincere rise and fall of all artists.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genius or exploitation?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jse126
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Basquiat" is a film with an agenda. Far from being a neutral stage upon which the life and emotion of the artist is played out for us to observe, this film wants to make a point about the art world, casting Basquiat as Oliver Twist. If you are looking to find out what drives an artist you are not going to find it here - unless the answer is money. The filmmakers did not go very far into the head of their subject - either that or he was a very shallow and vapid person. I did not get the feeling from this film that Basquiat was a true artist; rather, he came off as an opportunist who figured out how to capture the mechanics of bad abstract impressionism and pass himself off as one. Then a lucky break, combined with silly art collectors who have way too much money and not enough of their own thought processes, multiplied by a guilt ridden population of white people flush with 1980's cash, combine to equal the phenomenon of Basquiat. I am not saying that this is (or is not) the truth. In the world of art there are no truths anyway. What I am saying is that this is not a neutral biography. It may pay to do a little bit of research into Basquiat before watching the film. As for myself, I admit to watching it only because I was bored and nothing else was on. I knew vaguely the story, and who Basquiat was, but had no opinions of and no real knowledge about him. Since I am not the type of person who forms his opinions on any subject based on information from only one source, I did some research into Basquiat after the film before coming to any sort of conclusions. What those conclusions were are irrelevant as far as this review is concerned - but what does concern me are the many people who undoubtedly had their opinion about Basquiat fed to them by this film and who now consider themselves educated on the subject. As far as the film itself, it is not bad. Not great, but not bad. It had a certain feeling to it. But it is hard to get beyond its portrayal of the subject, as he is the reason for the film. As noted, Basquiat comes off as an empty headed and shallow individual without a lot of talent or original thought who likes to use drugs and drink a lot. The film's Basquiat seemed not to care much about art, that it was an afterthought to him. He was shown as a dabbler - dabbling in music too but not doing much or giving it much effort. Perhaps that is the truth, I don't know, because overall the film is more a study of art and what constitutes it and gives it value than a biography of an artist - and postulates that today's art is more about the name than the actual piece. The same thing that is given away for free by a homeless man who lives in a box can be worth six figures if the right people decide that it should. I also felt that he filmmakers relied on clich&eacute;' a bit too much for my liking. The scene that sticks out in my mind is the one where Basquiat was on a schoolyard basketball court with his buddy, who was trying to get him to play. Basquiat was totally inept at the game and had no desire to play whatsoever. The filmmakers were obviously trying to demonstrate either one or both of two things - that Basquiat was so much of a cerebral artist that he was incapable of physical sport, or that Basquiat was a black man who could not play basketball. Whatever the case, the scene was painful to watch. It was ham-fisted imagery at its worst. A well done scene with some good conversation and emotion could have sent the same message intended in the schoolyard - actually could have done it better because as blockheaded as the schoolyard scene was, it still did not send a clear and defined message. The acting in Basquiat was for the most part serviceable, with David Bowie turning in the most inspired performance as Andy Warhol. Bowie brought a subtle warmth and humanity to a person who is often portrayed as a cold cartoon character. Although Warhol was clearly intended to be an exploiter in the film, Bowie managed to show him as a person who felt that Basquiat was a true friend and not just a paycheck. This is an Andy Warhol who cared about people, and who could have his feelings hurt just like anyone else. This is not the stereotypical movie Warhol, playing with people like the proverbial chess pieces. This Warhol genuinely admired the work of his prot&eacute;g&eacute;s. And David Bowie would know, wouldn't he? He was there. I got the feeling that Bowie took the part to make a statement about Warhol - as if he was annoyed by younger filmmakers using the stereotypical Warhol image in an exploitative way. I felt that he was subversively reading the lines between the lines. Good for him. This film is more a commentary on the art world, on racism, and on exploitation than it is a biography. I would say that it is better to look at it this way, for as a biography it is biased and somewhat mean-spirited. Remember the first line of this review? It seemed to me that the filmmakers were saying that Basquiat was bereft of talent and inspiration - that he was a bum and a drug abuser who got lucky. Perhaps he was, but I'd prefer to make up my own mind. So it would pay to know a bit about the subject before watching - this Basquiat is a light dessert, not the main course.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful! One of my fav movies of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doveniki
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jeffery Wright became Basquiat! He should have won the Oscar for this. If only it was made after Halle Berry's Monsters Ball. Brilliant casting, some of the best Soundtracks ever. I love this movie for so many reasons. It is artistic as the people it portraits. It also manages to put the viewer in the shoes of the characters. Although I don't do drugs I totally got lost as if I was high together in the room with Basquiat when he painted the tires. Every artist knows, that mentally you go to an other place while painting. Somehow each time I see this movie it manages to transfers me into Basquiats strange world. I know its horrible to be an addict, but this flick somehow showed the beauty of it.. I don't know, maybe you have to be an artist, a bit avanguart, in love with new york and music to totally appreciate this #
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just to note
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dusan-22
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am putting my comment on this movie just to emphasize childish level of the voters and visitors of this site. One great film like this deserves much more than attention of semi-infantile audience that is running around IMDb site. I can agree that the movie is a matter of taste, but its value encapsulated in the grade shouldn't spoil that. For example, I might don't appreciate Van Gogh's paintings but I can't say that his work deserves low grade. Great cast, great movie - everything is real art. Compares to the greatest art films I have ever seen this movie does not deserve the best grade, but compares to shallow art value and narrow oriented stories of the pre-school characters that are cherished with greatest ardour around here - this movie is a masterpiece. Jeffrey Wright is so convincing that after you see the film it stays with you for a pretty long time ...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the artist as a success, a sometimes but not always usual bio-pic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jean Michel Basquiat was a really intriguing creature. He was an artist in the truest proletariat sense of the word. Meaning that he could never be bourgeois, even as he was brought in to that world, dominated by the "15-minutes-of-fame" man himself, Andy Warhol. By the way Julian Schnabel's loving if not too adulatory portrait of Basquiat shows, he was a guy trapped a bit inside of his own mind artistically, but at the same time really responsive to the world around him, commenting on it, sometimes at random, other times with the skill of an artist who just turns the world on a dime without even seeming to try. His art may not appeal to everyone, but it's hard to deny what it is, which is material made to provoke some kind of reaction; only someone like a disconnected bourgeois, like Warhol's lover/manager Bruno (played by Dennis Hopper in this film) would be detached from Basquiat's art. But there poses another question that Schnabel poses to the audience (perhaps a little bluntly, but effective all the same): how does one who is not apart of one world assimilate in another? Basquiat wasn't always the nicest person or easiest to get along with, but he had that quality like Jim Morrison, where he could be turned on to someone so much and so brightly that it was hard to look away, quirks and seething anger (and drug addiction) and all. Schnabel also does not give the audience any firm reason about how or why Jean Michel turned out like this as a kid (we hear at one point from an interviewer he was raised middle class and chose to live in a cardboard box), and it's not always necessary really. He is who he is at the start- a quirky, amused and experimental artist and musician- and then from there his fame is what makes him more (or less) fascinating to us. Basquiat takes the proverbial 'bio-pic' route with some of the expectation one has. For example, Schnabel emphasizes his romantic ties to a waitress and artist, Gina (Forlani), and makes the professional part of his storyline concurrent to that, no more or less important than that strand. But this is not a deterrent to see the usual up-and-down love story between a flawed artist and his love. Perhaps more conventional is seeing the person in the story hooked on drugs, but it was a fact in Basquiat's life and it's dealt with tastefully, or at least realistically. And to counter some of the expectations one has with a 'rise-to-fame' story of an artist, Schnabel makes it very much a film in its time and place: it's late 70's, early 80's, in New York City, where grit and decay seems to counter (or attract) the glitz and glamor, also in its own kind of decay (Warhol was more of a leech by then anyway, in a great scene having someone else drink beer and pee on a canvas since he won't drink beer to do it himself). Sometimes it's just bizarre in a delightful way, like how Basquiat looks up at the sky and sees surfing, and other times it's a fine array of the period in terms of music, or just New York City kind of music in general (Miles Davis to Johnny Rotten to early 80's hip hop to the Rolling Stones). At the center of Schnabel's portrait of an artist as a quasi-question mark, is Jeffrey Wright. He's always 'on' in a scene, even when it looks like Jean Michel is somewhere else, or just not responding to another person in the room (just watch the way Wright, as Basquiat, defuses a very angry Gina after he's painted over her paintings when she wakes up). It's a curious thing, too, to see him contrasted with David Bowie, who almost seems to have gone method in portraying the pop-culture icon as a bit of a quiet creep. It's the kind of performance, by Wright, that says 'watch out for me, I have some good things to offer', and it was a real breakthrough role, leading to the kind of varied work of his career in work ranging from Syriana to Cadillac Records. But as Basquiat, he finds one of his richest real-life characters, an artist of the streets. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Limelight Burns
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JustApt
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basquiat is about the way the fame corrupts the mind or maybe his mind was corrupted right from the start, anyway his brains looked pretty cooked from the very beginning. Basquiat was a product of the hype and not of his talents, he was utilized by the vultures feeding off the art and turned into the merchandise by them. The film starts to the "Fairytale of New York"  a song by Pogues: "It was Christmas Eve in the drunk tank, babe, and I dreamed of you... I can see a better time when all our dreams come true"  the future is always sweet but when it becomes the present it turns into a crap: "You're bum, you're punk, you're an old slut on junk lying there almost dead on the drip in this bed." David Bowie in the role of Andy Warhol is a smasher and the multitude of cameos by the other big stars makes this picture seem like a starry night. This movie also boasts a superb soundtrack.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Weak subject ...... weak film ..................
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cannot believe this was supported by so many good actors, considering the subject was so boorish. Glorifying drug use as contributing to art sounds pretty boring and it is. The artists represented are so pretentious, they would not appeal as even casual acquaintances to most people. So why should anyone looking for entertainment be anything but disappointed with "Basquait"? This film probably should have been locally released in New York to the art house client&egrave;le and then dumped. They say art is in the eye of the beholder, well if this movie is art then it should hang on a wall, and not subject an audience to it's glorified nonsense. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely must see
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trumbull98
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every once in a while you watch a movie that means something to you. This is one. Totally compelling flick that let's you see a glimpse of another's soul. Jeffery Wright is so believable that I would guess he sometimes to this day slips back into character. While most viewers will have no way to judge the accuracy to the real Basquiat, the realism is none the less magical. Watch this movie and for about 90 minutes you will be transported directly into a creative period of American art & life history. There is nothing in this movie that appears out of place and it realistically captures life in NYT. Performances by all the supporting actors are great and Bowie's performance is amazing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Hollywood Attempt To Make A Loser Look Like A Winner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a nutshell: an interesting cast but a lousy movie. Make that a "horrible" movie. Real-life artist Jean Michel Baquiat died at the age of 27 from a heroin overdose, and he's pictured as the hero even though he's barely a step above being a sleazy street person in mentality, morals and beliefs. In other words, he's the kind of guy Hollywood loves. Basquiat (played by Jeffrey Wright) is surrounded by like-minded people in the art world: in other words, a lot of weird people, most of them pretty disgusting. It's the kind of film an agnostic and basically ignorant 18-year-old kid would like: sick. Having said all that, I like Basquiat's art. I've always found it fascinating, which is why I looked at the movie in the first place. I also like a lot of actors and actresses in here. It's just too bad the film wasn't nearly as good as the art and the actors. Another reviewer here, "Synchonic," said it best: "Empty movie full of empty people." I totally agree with that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid bio about one of many overrated "artists" of our idiotic times.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fedor8
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A decent bio about one of pop-art's worthless icons. That whole bogus New York "artiste" scene of the 60s (and onwards) has no value whatsoever. Nevertheless, the movie is quite easy-going and pleasant, and profits also from a large cast of great names (Wincott, Del Toro, Bowie, Posey, Walken, Dafoe, Oldman). There is also no denying that it's interesting to watch the lives within that ridiculous NY scene. Basquiat is shown as a near-tortured artist, though the constant money-for-nothing cash-inflow probably bothered him less. Wright plays him like a semi-retard, which is not an exaggeration  you just have to see Basquiat's retarded pictures with his dumb thoughts scribbled in lettering resembling a 7 year-old mongoloid's hand-writing, and you'll understand. Perhaps they tried to make him seem aloof and mysterious but it came out wrong (i.e. right). Even his walk appears to be suspiciously weird - Basquiat really did talk it like he walk it. Yet this guy lived quite recently so all the nuances of his behaviour should be well-recorded, so maybe he was really this screwed up. There should be a movie made just like this one, entirely about Warhol - that would be fun. If you want to read an extensive satire about modern art (mainly Picasso) contact me by e-mail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Taste This
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    balifox
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one is like a Christmas dinner except your pants won't feel two sizes too small afterwards. Jeffrey Wright is a succulent piece of delectable meat, Gary Oldman is my mashed potatoes, Benicio Del Toro adds his curious level of reason like only your best seasoned vegetable can and my Michael Wincotthe is so delicious, he is easily that forbidden piece of dessert at the end of the table that you swear you won't eat a minute before you are literally gorging yourself on it. The cast is simply pure gold. It is so good and enchanting with a 1980's charm that is simply non-existent in other films. It is the art, music and meaning of that decade at its purest. Effortless, yet clever the dialogue gives you the sincere rise and fall of all artists.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genius or exploitation?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jse126
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Basquiat" is a film with an agenda. Far from being a neutral stage upon which the life and emotion of the artist is played out for us to observe, this film wants to make a point about the art world, casting Basquiat as Oliver Twist. If you are looking to find out what drives an artist you are not going to find it here - unless the answer is money. The filmmakers did not go very far into the head of their subject - either that or he was a very shallow and vapid person. I did not get the feeling from this film that Basquiat was a true artist; rather, he came off as an opportunist who figured out how to capture the mechanics of bad abstract impressionism and pass himself off as one. Then a lucky break, combined with silly art collectors who have way too much money and not enough of their own thought processes, multiplied by a guilt ridden population of white people flush with 1980's cash, combine to equal the phenomenon of Basquiat. I am not saying that this is (or is not) the truth. In the world of art there are no truths anyway. What I am saying is that this is not a neutral biography. It may pay to do a little bit of research into Basquiat before watching the film. As for myself, I admit to watching it only because I was bored and nothing else was on. I knew vaguely the story, and who Basquiat was, but had no opinions of and no real knowledge about him. Since I am not the type of person who forms his opinions on any subject based on information from only one source, I did some research into Basquiat after the film before coming to any sort of conclusions. What those conclusions were are irrelevant as far as this review is concerned - but what does concern me are the many people who undoubtedly had their opinion about Basquiat fed to them by this film and who now consider themselves educated on the subject. As far as the film itself, it is not bad. Not great, but not bad. It had a certain feeling to it. But it is hard to get beyond its portrayal of the subject, as he is the reason for the film. As noted, Basquiat comes off as an empty headed and shallow individual without a lot of talent or original thought who likes to use drugs and drink a lot. The film's Basquiat seemed not to care much about art, that it was an afterthought to him. He was shown as a dabbler - dabbling in music too but not doing much or giving it much effort. Perhaps that is the truth, I don't know, because overall the film is more a study of art and what constitutes it and gives it value than a biography of an artist - and postulates that today's art is more about the name than the actual piece. The same thing that is given away for free by a homeless man who lives in a box can be worth six figures if the right people decide that it should. I also felt that he filmmakers relied on clich&eacute;' a bit too much for my liking. The scene that sticks out in my mind is the one where Basquiat was on a schoolyard basketball court with his buddy, who was trying to get him to play. Basquiat was totally inept at the game and had no desire to play whatsoever. The filmmakers were obviously trying to demonstrate either one or both of two things - that Basquiat was so much of a cerebral artist that he was incapable of physical sport, or that Basquiat was a black man who could not play basketball. Whatever the case, the scene was painful to watch. It was ham-fisted imagery at its worst. A well done scene with some good conversation and emotion could have sent the same message intended in the schoolyard - actually could have done it better because as blockheaded as the schoolyard scene was, it still did not send a clear and defined message. The acting in Basquiat was for the most part serviceable, with David Bowie turning in the most inspired performance as Andy Warhol. Bowie brought a subtle warmth and humanity to a person who is often portrayed as a cold cartoon character. Although Warhol was clearly intended to be an exploiter in the film, Bowie managed to show him as a person who felt that Basquiat was a true friend and not just a paycheck. This is an Andy Warhol who cared about people, and who could have his feelings hurt just like anyone else. This is not the stereotypical movie Warhol, playing with people like the proverbial chess pieces. This Warhol genuinely admired the work of his prot&eacute;g&eacute;s. And David Bowie would know, wouldn't he? He was there. I got the feeling that Bowie took the part to make a statement about Warhol - as if he was annoyed by younger filmmakers using the stereotypical Warhol image in an exploitative way. I felt that he was subversively reading the lines between the lines. Good for him. This film is more a commentary on the art world, on racism, and on exploitation than it is a biography. I would say that it is better to look at it this way, for as a biography it is biased and somewhat mean-spirited. Remember the first line of this review? It seemed to me that the filmmakers were saying that Basquiat was bereft of talent and inspiration - that he was a bum and a drug abuser who got lucky. Perhaps he was, but I'd prefer to make up my own mind. So it would pay to know a bit about the subject before watching - this Basquiat is a light dessert, not the main course.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful! One of my fav movies of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doveniki
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jeffery Wright became Basquiat! He should have won the Oscar for this. If only it was made after Halle Berry's Monsters Ball. Brilliant casting, some of the best Soundtracks ever. I love this movie for so many reasons. It is artistic as the people it portraits. It also manages to put the viewer in the shoes of the characters. Although I don't do drugs I totally got lost as if I was high together in the room with Basquiat when he painted the tires. Every artist knows, that mentally you go to an other place while painting. Somehow each time I see this movie it manages to transfers me into Basquiats strange world. I know its horrible to be an addict, but this flick somehow showed the beauty of it.. I don't know, maybe you have to be an artist, a bit avanguart, in love with new york and music to totally appreciate this #
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just to note
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dusan-22
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am putting my comment on this movie just to emphasize childish level of the voters and visitors of this site. One great film like this deserves much more than attention of semi-infantile audience that is running around IMDb site. I can agree that the movie is a matter of taste, but its value encapsulated in the grade shouldn't spoil that. For example, I might don't appreciate Van Gogh's paintings but I can't say that his work deserves low grade. Great cast, great movie - everything is real art. Compares to the greatest art films I have ever seen this movie does not deserve the best grade, but compares to shallow art value and narrow oriented stories of the pre-school characters that are cherished with greatest ardour around here - this movie is a masterpiece. Jeffrey Wright is so convincing that after you see the film it stays with you for a pretty long time ...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the artist as a success, a sometimes but not always usual bio-pic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jean Michel Basquiat was a really intriguing creature. He was an artist in the truest proletariat sense of the word. Meaning that he could never be bourgeois, even as he was brought in to that world, dominated by the "15-minutes-of-fame" man himself, Andy Warhol. By the way Julian Schnabel's loving if not too adulatory portrait of Basquiat shows, he was a guy trapped a bit inside of his own mind artistically, but at the same time really responsive to the world around him, commenting on it, sometimes at random, other times with the skill of an artist who just turns the world on a dime without even seeming to try. His art may not appeal to everyone, but it's hard to deny what it is, which is material made to provoke some kind of reaction; only someone like a disconnected bourgeois, like Warhol's lover/manager Bruno (played by Dennis Hopper in this film) would be detached from Basquiat's art. But there poses another question that Schnabel poses to the audience (perhaps a little bluntly, but effective all the same): how does one who is not apart of one world assimilate in another? Basquiat wasn't always the nicest person or easiest to get along with, but he had that quality like Jim Morrison, where he could be turned on to someone so much and so brightly that it was hard to look away, quirks and seething anger (and drug addiction) and all. Schnabel also does not give the audience any firm reason about how or why Jean Michel turned out like this as a kid (we hear at one point from an interviewer he was raised middle class and chose to live in a cardboard box), and it's not always necessary really. He is who he is at the start- a quirky, amused and experimental artist and musician- and then from there his fame is what makes him more (or less) fascinating to us. Basquiat takes the proverbial 'bio-pic' route with some of the expectation one has. For example, Schnabel emphasizes his romantic ties to a waitress and artist, Gina (Forlani), and makes the professional part of his storyline concurrent to that, no more or less important than that strand. But this is not a deterrent to see the usual up-and-down love story between a flawed artist and his love. Perhaps more conventional is seeing the person in the story hooked on drugs, but it was a fact in Basquiat's life and it's dealt with tastefully, or at least realistically. And to counter some of the expectations one has with a 'rise-to-fame' story of an artist, Schnabel makes it very much a film in its time and place: it's late 70's, early 80's, in New York City, where grit and decay seems to counter (or attract) the glitz and glamor, also in its own kind of decay (Warhol was more of a leech by then anyway, in a great scene having someone else drink beer and pee on a canvas since he won't drink beer to do it himself). Sometimes it's just bizarre in a delightful way, like how Basquiat looks up at the sky and sees surfing, and other times it's a fine array of the period in terms of music, or just New York City kind of music in general (Miles Davis to Johnny Rotten to early 80's hip hop to the Rolling Stones). At the center of Schnabel's portrait of an artist as a quasi-question mark, is Jeffrey Wright. He's always 'on' in a scene, even when it looks like Jean Michel is somewhere else, or just not responding to another person in the room (just watch the way Wright, as Basquiat, defuses a very angry Gina after he's painted over her paintings when she wakes up). It's a curious thing, too, to see him contrasted with David Bowie, who almost seems to have gone method in portraying the pop-culture icon as a bit of a quiet creep. It's the kind of performance, by Wright, that says 'watch out for me, I have some good things to offer', and it was a real breakthrough role, leading to the kind of varied work of his career in work ranging from Syriana to Cadillac Records. But as Basquiat, he finds one of his richest real-life characters, an artist of the streets. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Limelight Burns
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JustApt
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basquiat is about the way the fame corrupts the mind or maybe his mind was corrupted right from the start, anyway his brains looked pretty cooked from the very beginning. Basquiat was a product of the hype and not of his talents, he was utilized by the vultures feeding off the art and turned into the merchandise by them. The film starts to the "Fairytale of New York"  a song by Pogues: "It was Christmas Eve in the drunk tank, babe, and I dreamed of you... I can see a better time when all our dreams come true"  the future is always sweet but when it becomes the present it turns into a crap: "You're bum, you're punk, you're an old slut on junk lying there almost dead on the drip in this bed." David Bowie in the role of Andy Warhol is a smasher and the multitude of cameos by the other big stars makes this picture seem like a starry night. This movie also boasts a superb soundtrack.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Weak subject ...... weak film ..................
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cannot believe this was supported by so many good actors, considering the subject was so boorish. Glorifying drug use as contributing to art sounds pretty boring and it is. The artists represented are so pretentious, they would not appeal as even casual acquaintances to most people. So why should anyone looking for entertainment be anything but disappointed with "Basquait"? This film probably should have been locally released in New York to the art house client&egrave;le and then dumped. They say art is in the eye of the beholder, well if this movie is art then it should hang on a wall, and not subject an audience to it's glorified nonsense. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely must see
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trumbull98
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every once in a while you watch a movie that means something to you. This is one. Totally compelling flick that let's you see a glimpse of another's soul. Jeffery Wright is so believable that I would guess he sometimes to this day slips back into character. While most viewers will have no way to judge the accuracy to the real Basquiat, the realism is none the less magical. Watch this movie and for about 90 minutes you will be transported directly into a creative period of American art & life history. There is nothing in this movie that appears out of place and it realistically captures life in NYT. Performances by all the supporting actors are great and Bowie's performance is amazing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Hollywood Attempt To Make A Loser Look Like A Winner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a nutshell: an interesting cast but a lousy movie. Make that a "horrible" movie. Real-life artist Jean Michel Baquiat died at the age of 27 from a heroin overdose, and he's pictured as the hero even though he's barely a step above being a sleazy street person in mentality, morals and beliefs. In other words, he's the kind of guy Hollywood loves. Basquiat (played by Jeffrey Wright) is surrounded by like-minded people in the art world: in other words, a lot of weird people, most of them pretty disgusting. It's the kind of film an agnostic and basically ignorant 18-year-old kid would like: sick. Having said all that, I like Basquiat's art. I've always found it fascinating, which is why I looked at the movie in the first place. I also like a lot of actors and actresses in here. It's just too bad the film wasn't nearly as good as the art and the actors. Another reviewer here, "Synchonic," said it best: "Empty movie full of empty people." I totally agree with that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid bio about one of many overrated "artists" of our idiotic times.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fedor8
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A decent bio about one of pop-art's worthless icons. That whole bogus New York "artiste" scene of the 60s (and onwards) has no value whatsoever. Nevertheless, the movie is quite easy-going and pleasant, and profits also from a large cast of great names (Wincott, Del Toro, Bowie, Posey, Walken, Dafoe, Oldman). There is also no denying that it's interesting to watch the lives within that ridiculous NY scene. Basquiat is shown as a near-tortured artist, though the constant money-for-nothing cash-inflow probably bothered him less. Wright plays him like a semi-retard, which is not an exaggeration  you just have to see Basquiat's retarded pictures with his dumb thoughts scribbled in lettering resembling a 7 year-old mongoloid's hand-writing, and you'll understand. Perhaps they tried to make him seem aloof and mysterious but it came out wrong (i.e. right). Even his walk appears to be suspiciously weird - Basquiat really did talk it like he walk it. Yet this guy lived quite recently so all the nuances of his behaviour should be well-recorded, so maybe he was really this screwed up. There should be a movie made just like this one, entirely about Warhol - that would be fun. If you want to read an extensive satire about modern art (mainly Picasso) contact me by e-mail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Taste This
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    balifox
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one is like a Christmas dinner except your pants won't feel two sizes too small afterwards. Jeffrey Wright is a succulent piece of delectable meat, Gary Oldman is my mashed potatoes, Benicio Del Toro adds his curious level of reason like only your best seasoned vegetable can and my Michael Wincotthe is so delicious, he is easily that forbidden piece of dessert at the end of the table that you swear you won't eat a minute before you are literally gorging yourself on it. The cast is simply pure gold. It is so good and enchanting with a 1980's charm that is simply non-existent in other films. It is the art, music and meaning of that decade at its purest. Effortless, yet clever the dialogue gives you the sincere rise and fall of all artists.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genius or exploitation?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jse126
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Basquiat" is a film with an agenda. Far from being a neutral stage upon which the life and emotion of the artist is played out for us to observe, this film wants to make a point about the art world, casting Basquiat as Oliver Twist. If you are looking to find out what drives an artist you are not going to find it here - unless the answer is money. The filmmakers did not go very far into the head of their subject - either that or he was a very shallow and vapid person. I did not get the feeling from this film that Basquiat was a true artist; rather, he came off as an opportunist who figured out how to capture the mechanics of bad abstract impressionism and pass himself off as one. Then a lucky break, combined with silly art collectors who have way too much money and not enough of their own thought processes, multiplied by a guilt ridden population of white people flush with 1980's cash, combine to equal the phenomenon of Basquiat. I am not saying that this is (or is not) the truth. In the world of art there are no truths anyway. What I am saying is that this is not a neutral biography. It may pay to do a little bit of research into Basquiat before watching the film. As for myself, I admit to watching it only because I was bored and nothing else was on. I knew vaguely the story, and who Basquiat was, but had no opinions of and no real knowledge about him. Since I am not the type of person who forms his opinions on any subject based on information from only one source, I did some research into Basquiat after the film before coming to any sort of conclusions. What those conclusions were are irrelevant as far as this review is concerned - but what does concern me are the many people who undoubtedly had their opinion about Basquiat fed to them by this film and who now consider themselves educated on the subject. As far as the film itself, it is not bad. Not great, but not bad. It had a certain feeling to it. But it is hard to get beyond its portrayal of the subject, as he is the reason for the film. As noted, Basquiat comes off as an empty headed and shallow individual without a lot of talent or original thought who likes to use drugs and drink a lot. The film's Basquiat seemed not to care much about art, that it was an afterthought to him. He was shown as a dabbler - dabbling in music too but not doing much or giving it much effort. Perhaps that is the truth, I don't know, because overall the film is more a study of art and what constitutes it and gives it value than a biography of an artist - and postulates that today's art is more about the name than the actual piece. The same thing that is given away for free by a homeless man who lives in a box can be worth six figures if the right people decide that it should. I also felt that he filmmakers relied on clich&eacute;' a bit too much for my liking. The scene that sticks out in my mind is the one where Basquiat was on a schoolyard basketball court with his buddy, who was trying to get him to play. Basquiat was totally inept at the game and had no desire to play whatsoever. The filmmakers were obviously trying to demonstrate either one or both of two things - that Basquiat was so much of a cerebral artist that he was incapable of physical sport, or that Basquiat was a black man who could not play basketball. Whatever the case, the scene was painful to watch. It was ham-fisted imagery at its worst. A well done scene with some good conversation and emotion could have sent the same message intended in the schoolyard - actually could have done it better because as blockheaded as the schoolyard scene was, it still did not send a clear and defined message. The acting in Basquiat was for the most part serviceable, with David Bowie turning in the most inspired performance as Andy Warhol. Bowie brought a subtle warmth and humanity to a person who is often portrayed as a cold cartoon character. Although Warhol was clearly intended to be an exploiter in the film, Bowie managed to show him as a person who felt that Basquiat was a true friend and not just a paycheck. This is an Andy Warhol who cared about people, and who could have his feelings hurt just like anyone else. This is not the stereotypical movie Warhol, playing with people like the proverbial chess pieces. This Warhol genuinely admired the work of his prot&eacute;g&eacute;s. And David Bowie would know, wouldn't he? He was there. I got the feeling that Bowie took the part to make a statement about Warhol - as if he was annoyed by younger filmmakers using the stereotypical Warhol image in an exploitative way. I felt that he was subversively reading the lines between the lines. Good for him. This film is more a commentary on the art world, on racism, and on exploitation than it is a biography. I would say that it is better to look at it this way, for as a biography it is biased and somewhat mean-spirited. Remember the first line of this review? It seemed to me that the filmmakers were saying that Basquiat was bereft of talent and inspiration - that he was a bum and a drug abuser who got lucky. Perhaps he was, but I'd prefer to make up my own mind. So it would pay to know a bit about the subject before watching - this Basquiat is a light dessert, not the main course.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful! One of my fav movies of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doveniki
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jeffery Wright became Basquiat! He should have won the Oscar for this. If only it was made after Halle Berry's Monsters Ball. Brilliant casting, some of the best Soundtracks ever. I love this movie for so many reasons. It is artistic as the people it portraits. It also manages to put the viewer in the shoes of the characters. Although I don't do drugs I totally got lost as if I was high together in the room with Basquiat when he painted the tires. Every artist knows, that mentally you go to an other place while painting. Somehow each time I see this movie it manages to transfers me into Basquiats strange world. I know its horrible to be an addict, but this flick somehow showed the beauty of it.. I don't know, maybe you have to be an artist, a bit avanguart, in love with new york and music to totally appreciate this #
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just to note
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dusan-22
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am putting my comment on this movie just to emphasize childish level of the voters and visitors of this site. One great film like this deserves much more than attention of semi-infantile audience that is running around IMDb site. I can agree that the movie is a matter of taste, but its value encapsulated in the grade shouldn't spoil that. For example, I might don't appreciate Van Gogh's paintings but I can't say that his work deserves low grade. Great cast, great movie - everything is real art. Compares to the greatest art films I have ever seen this movie does not deserve the best grade, but compares to shallow art value and narrow oriented stories of the pre-school characters that are cherished with greatest ardour around here - this movie is a masterpiece. Jeffrey Wright is so convincing that after you see the film it stays with you for a pretty long time ...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the artist as a success, a sometimes but not always usual bio-pic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jean Michel Basquiat was a really intriguing creature. He was an artist in the truest proletariat sense of the word. Meaning that he could never be bourgeois, even as he was brought in to that world, dominated by the "15-minutes-of-fame" man himself, Andy Warhol. By the way Julian Schnabel's loving if not too adulatory portrait of Basquiat shows, he was a guy trapped a bit inside of his own mind artistically, but at the same time really responsive to the world around him, commenting on it, sometimes at random, other times with the skill of an artist who just turns the world on a dime without even seeming to try. His art may not appeal to everyone, but it's hard to deny what it is, which is material made to provoke some kind of reaction; only someone like a disconnected bourgeois, like Warhol's lover/manager Bruno (played by Dennis Hopper in this film) would be detached from Basquiat's art. But there poses another question that Schnabel poses to the audience (perhaps a little bluntly, but effective all the same): how does one who is not apart of one world assimilate in another? Basquiat wasn't always the nicest person or easiest to get along with, but he had that quality like Jim Morrison, where he could be turned on to someone so much and so brightly that it was hard to look away, quirks and seething anger (and drug addiction) and all. Schnabel also does not give the audience any firm reason about how or why Jean Michel turned out like this as a kid (we hear at one point from an interviewer he was raised middle class and chose to live in a cardboard box), and it's not always necessary really. He is who he is at the start- a quirky, amused and experimental artist and musician- and then from there his fame is what makes him more (or less) fascinating to us. Basquiat takes the proverbial 'bio-pic' route with some of the expectation one has. For example, Schnabel emphasizes his romantic ties to a waitress and artist, Gina (Forlani), and makes the professional part of his storyline concurrent to that, no more or less important than that strand. But this is not a deterrent to see the usual up-and-down love story between a flawed artist and his love. Perhaps more conventional is seeing the person in the story hooked on drugs, but it was a fact in Basquiat's life and it's dealt with tastefully, or at least realistically. And to counter some of the expectations one has with a 'rise-to-fame' story of an artist, Schnabel makes it very much a film in its time and place: it's late 70's, early 80's, in New York City, where grit and decay seems to counter (or attract) the glitz and glamor, also in its own kind of decay (Warhol was more of a leech by then anyway, in a great scene having someone else drink beer and pee on a canvas since he won't drink beer to do it himself). Sometimes it's just bizarre in a delightful way, like how Basquiat looks up at the sky and sees surfing, and other times it's a fine array of the period in terms of music, or just New York City kind of music in general (Miles Davis to Johnny Rotten to early 80's hip hop to the Rolling Stones). At the center of Schnabel's portrait of an artist as a quasi-question mark, is Jeffrey Wright. He's always 'on' in a scene, even when it looks like Jean Michel is somewhere else, or just not responding to another person in the room (just watch the way Wright, as Basquiat, defuses a very angry Gina after he's painted over her paintings when she wakes up). It's a curious thing, too, to see him contrasted with David Bowie, who almost seems to have gone method in portraying the pop-culture icon as a bit of a quiet creep. It's the kind of performance, by Wright, that says 'watch out for me, I have some good things to offer', and it was a real breakthrough role, leading to the kind of varied work of his career in work ranging from Syriana to Cadillac Records. But as Basquiat, he finds one of his richest real-life characters, an artist of the streets. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Limelight Burns
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JustApt
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basquiat is about the way the fame corrupts the mind or maybe his mind was corrupted right from the start, anyway his brains looked pretty cooked from the very beginning. Basquiat was a product of the hype and not of his talents, he was utilized by the vultures feeding off the art and turned into the merchandise by them. The film starts to the "Fairytale of New York"  a song by Pogues: "It was Christmas Eve in the drunk tank, babe, and I dreamed of you... I can see a better time when all our dreams come true"  the future is always sweet but when it becomes the present it turns into a crap: "You're bum, you're punk, you're an old slut on junk lying there almost dead on the drip in this bed." David Bowie in the role of Andy Warhol is a smasher and the multitude of cameos by the other big stars makes this picture seem like a starry night. This movie also boasts a superb soundtrack.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Weak subject ...... weak film ..................
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cannot believe this was supported by so many good actors, considering the subject was so boorish. Glorifying drug use as contributing to art sounds pretty boring and it is. The artists represented are so pretentious, they would not appeal as even casual acquaintances to most people. So why should anyone looking for entertainment be anything but disappointed with "Basquait"? This film probably should have been locally released in New York to the art house client&egrave;le and then dumped. They say art is in the eye of the beholder, well if this movie is art then it should hang on a wall, and not subject an audience to it's glorified nonsense. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely must see
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trumbull98
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every once in a while you watch a movie that means something to you. This is one. Totally compelling flick that let's you see a glimpse of another's soul. Jeffery Wright is so believable that I would guess he sometimes to this day slips back into character. While most viewers will have no way to judge the accuracy to the real Basquiat, the realism is none the less magical. Watch this movie and for about 90 minutes you will be transported directly into a creative period of American art & life history. There is nothing in this movie that appears out of place and it realistically captures life in NYT. Performances by all the supporting actors are great and Bowie's performance is amazing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Hollywood Attempt To Make A Loser Look Like A Winner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a nutshell: an interesting cast but a lousy movie. Make that a "horrible" movie. Real-life artist Jean Michel Baquiat died at the age of 27 from a heroin overdose, and he's pictured as the hero even though he's barely a step above being a sleazy street person in mentality, morals and beliefs. In other words, he's the kind of guy Hollywood loves. Basquiat (played by Jeffrey Wright) is surrounded by like-minded people in the art world: in other words, a lot of weird people, most of them pretty disgusting. It's the kind of film an agnostic and basically ignorant 18-year-old kid would like: sick. Having said all that, I like Basquiat's art. I've always found it fascinating, which is why I looked at the movie in the first place. I also like a lot of actors and actresses in here. It's just too bad the film wasn't nearly as good as the art and the actors. Another reviewer here, "Synchonic," said it best: "Empty movie full of empty people." I totally agree with that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid bio about one of many overrated "artists" of our idiotic times.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fedor8
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A decent bio about one of pop-art's worthless icons. That whole bogus New York "artiste" scene of the 60s (and onwards) has no value whatsoever. Nevertheless, the movie is quite easy-going and pleasant, and profits also from a large cast of great names (Wincott, Del Toro, Bowie, Posey, Walken, Dafoe, Oldman). There is also no denying that it's interesting to watch the lives within that ridiculous NY scene. Basquiat is shown as a near-tortured artist, though the constant money-for-nothing cash-inflow probably bothered him less. Wright plays him like a semi-retard, which is not an exaggeration  you just have to see Basquiat's retarded pictures with his dumb thoughts scribbled in lettering resembling a 7 year-old mongoloid's hand-writing, and you'll understand. Perhaps they tried to make him seem aloof and mysterious but it came out wrong (i.e. right). Even his walk appears to be suspiciously weird - Basquiat really did talk it like he walk it. Yet this guy lived quite recently so all the nuances of his behaviour should be well-recorded, so maybe he was really this screwed up. There should be a movie made just like this one, entirely about Warhol - that would be fun. If you want to read an extensive satire about modern art (mainly Picasso) contact me by e-mail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Taste This
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    balifox
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one is like a Christmas dinner except your pants won't feel two sizes too small afterwards. Jeffrey Wright is a succulent piece of delectable meat, Gary Oldman is my mashed potatoes, Benicio Del Toro adds his curious level of reason like only your best seasoned vegetable can and my Michael Wincotthe is so delicious, he is easily that forbidden piece of dessert at the end of the table that you swear you won't eat a minute before you are literally gorging yourself on it. The cast is simply pure gold. It is so good and enchanting with a 1980's charm that is simply non-existent in other films. It is the art, music and meaning of that decade at its purest. Effortless, yet clever the dialogue gives you the sincere rise and fall of all artists.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genius or exploitation?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jse126
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Basquiat" is a film with an agenda. Far from being a neutral stage upon which the life and emotion of the artist is played out for us to observe, this film wants to make a point about the art world, casting Basquiat as Oliver Twist. If you are looking to find out what drives an artist you are not going to find it here - unless the answer is money. The filmmakers did not go very far into the head of their subject - either that or he was a very shallow and vapid person. I did not get the feeling from this film that Basquiat was a true artist; rather, he came off as an opportunist who figured out how to capture the mechanics of bad abstract impressionism and pass himself off as one. Then a lucky break, combined with silly art collectors who have way too much money and not enough of their own thought processes, multiplied by a guilt ridden population of white people flush with 1980's cash, combine to equal the phenomenon of Basquiat. I am not saying that this is (or is not) the truth. In the world of art there are no truths anyway. What I am saying is that this is not a neutral biography. It may pay to do a little bit of research into Basquiat before watching the film. As for myself, I admit to watching it only because I was bored and nothing else was on. I knew vaguely the story, and who Basquiat was, but had no opinions of and no real knowledge about him. Since I am not the type of person who forms his opinions on any subject based on information from only one source, I did some research into Basquiat after the film before coming to any sort of conclusions. What those conclusions were are irrelevant as far as this review is concerned - but what does concern me are the many people who undoubtedly had their opinion about Basquiat fed to them by this film and who now consider themselves educated on the subject. As far as the film itself, it is not bad. Not great, but not bad. It had a certain feeling to it. But it is hard to get beyond its portrayal of the subject, as he is the reason for the film. As noted, Basquiat comes off as an empty headed and shallow individual without a lot of talent or original thought who likes to use drugs and drink a lot. The film's Basquiat seemed not to care much about art, that it was an afterthought to him. He was shown as a dabbler - dabbling in music too but not doing much or giving it much effort. Perhaps that is the truth, I don't know, because overall the film is more a study of art and what constitutes it and gives it value than a biography of an artist - and postulates that today's art is more about the name than the actual piece. The same thing that is given away for free by a homeless man who lives in a box can be worth six figures if the right people decide that it should. I also felt that he filmmakers relied on clich&eacute;' a bit too much for my liking. The scene that sticks out in my mind is the one where Basquiat was on a schoolyard basketball court with his buddy, who was trying to get him to play. Basquiat was totally inept at the game and had no desire to play whatsoever. The filmmakers were obviously trying to demonstrate either one or both of two things - that Basquiat was so much of a cerebral artist that he was incapable of physical sport, or that Basquiat was a black man who could not play basketball. Whatever the case, the scene was painful to watch. It was ham-fisted imagery at its worst. A well done scene with some good conversation and emotion could have sent the same message intended in the schoolyard - actually could have done it better because as blockheaded as the schoolyard scene was, it still did not send a clear and defined message. The acting in Basquiat was for the most part serviceable, with David Bowie turning in the most inspired performance as Andy Warhol. Bowie brought a subtle warmth and humanity to a person who is often portrayed as a cold cartoon character. Although Warhol was clearly intended to be an exploiter in the film, Bowie managed to show him as a person who felt that Basquiat was a true friend and not just a paycheck. This is an Andy Warhol who cared about people, and who could have his feelings hurt just like anyone else. This is not the stereotypical movie Warhol, playing with people like the proverbial chess pieces. This Warhol genuinely admired the work of his prot&eacute;g&eacute;s. And David Bowie would know, wouldn't he? He was there. I got the feeling that Bowie took the part to make a statement about Warhol - as if he was annoyed by younger filmmakers using the stereotypical Warhol image in an exploitative way. I felt that he was subversively reading the lines between the lines. Good for him. This film is more a commentary on the art world, on racism, and on exploitation than it is a biography. I would say that it is better to look at it this way, for as a biography it is biased and somewhat mean-spirited. Remember the first line of this review? It seemed to me that the filmmakers were saying that Basquiat was bereft of talent and inspiration - that he was a bum and a drug abuser who got lucky. Perhaps he was, but I'd prefer to make up my own mind. So it would pay to know a bit about the subject before watching - this Basquiat is a light dessert, not the main course.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful! One of my fav movies of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doveniki
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jeffery Wright became Basquiat! He should have won the Oscar for this. If only it was made after Halle Berry's Monsters Ball. Brilliant casting, some of the best Soundtracks ever. I love this movie for so many reasons. It is artistic as the people it portraits. It also manages to put the viewer in the shoes of the characters. Although I don't do drugs I totally got lost as if I was high together in the room with Basquiat when he painted the tires. Every artist knows, that mentally you go to an other place while painting. Somehow each time I see this movie it manages to transfers me into Basquiats strange world. I know its horrible to be an addict, but this flick somehow showed the beauty of it.. I don't know, maybe you have to be an artist, a bit avanguart, in love with new york and music to totally appreciate this #
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just to note
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dusan-22
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am putting my comment on this movie just to emphasize childish level of the voters and visitors of this site. One great film like this deserves much more than attention of semi-infantile audience that is running around IMDb site. I can agree that the movie is a matter of taste, but its value encapsulated in the grade shouldn't spoil that. For example, I might don't appreciate Van Gogh's paintings but I can't say that his work deserves low grade. Great cast, great movie - everything is real art. Compares to the greatest art films I have ever seen this movie does not deserve the best grade, but compares to shallow art value and narrow oriented stories of the pre-school characters that are cherished with greatest ardour around here - this movie is a masterpiece. Jeffrey Wright is so convincing that after you see the film it stays with you for a pretty long time ...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the artist as a success, a sometimes but not always usual bio-pic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jean Michel Basquiat was a really intriguing creature. He was an artist in the truest proletariat sense of the word. Meaning that he could never be bourgeois, even as he was brought in to that world, dominated by the "15-minutes-of-fame" man himself, Andy Warhol. By the way Julian Schnabel's loving if not too adulatory portrait of Basquiat shows, he was a guy trapped a bit inside of his own mind artistically, but at the same time really responsive to the world around him, commenting on it, sometimes at random, other times with the skill of an artist who just turns the world on a dime without even seeming to try. His art may not appeal to everyone, but it's hard to deny what it is, which is material made to provoke some kind of reaction; only someone like a disconnected bourgeois, like Warhol's lover/manager Bruno (played by Dennis Hopper in this film) would be detached from Basquiat's art. But there poses another question that Schnabel poses to the audience (perhaps a little bluntly, but effective all the same): how does one who is not apart of one world assimilate in another? Basquiat wasn't always the nicest person or easiest to get along with, but he had that quality like Jim Morrison, where he could be turned on to someone so much and so brightly that it was hard to look away, quirks and seething anger (and drug addiction) and all. Schnabel also does not give the audience any firm reason about how or why Jean Michel turned out like this as a kid (we hear at one point from an interviewer he was raised middle class and chose to live in a cardboard box), and it's not always necessary really. He is who he is at the start- a quirky, amused and experimental artist and musician- and then from there his fame is what makes him more (or less) fascinating to us. Basquiat takes the proverbial 'bio-pic' route with some of the expectation one has. For example, Schnabel emphasizes his romantic ties to a waitress and artist, Gina (Forlani), and makes the professional part of his storyline concurrent to that, no more or less important than that strand. But this is not a deterrent to see the usual up-and-down love story between a flawed artist and his love. Perhaps more conventional is seeing the person in the story hooked on drugs, but it was a fact in Basquiat's life and it's dealt with tastefully, or at least realistically. And to counter some of the expectations one has with a 'rise-to-fame' story of an artist, Schnabel makes it very much a film in its time and place: it's late 70's, early 80's, in New York City, where grit and decay seems to counter (or attract) the glitz and glamor, also in its own kind of decay (Warhol was more of a leech by then anyway, in a great scene having someone else drink beer and pee on a canvas since he won't drink beer to do it himself). Sometimes it's just bizarre in a delightful way, like how Basquiat looks up at the sky and sees surfing, and other times it's a fine array of the period in terms of music, or just New York City kind of music in general (Miles Davis to Johnny Rotten to early 80's hip hop to the Rolling Stones). At the center of Schnabel's portrait of an artist as a quasi-question mark, is Jeffrey Wright. He's always 'on' in a scene, even when it looks like Jean Michel is somewhere else, or just not responding to another person in the room (just watch the way Wright, as Basquiat, defuses a very angry Gina after he's painted over her paintings when she wakes up). It's a curious thing, too, to see him contrasted with David Bowie, who almost seems to have gone method in portraying the pop-culture icon as a bit of a quiet creep. It's the kind of performance, by Wright, that says 'watch out for me, I have some good things to offer', and it was a real breakthrough role, leading to the kind of varied work of his career in work ranging from Syriana to Cadillac Records. But as Basquiat, he finds one of his richest real-life characters, an artist of the streets. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Limelight Burns
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JustApt
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basquiat is about the way the fame corrupts the mind or maybe his mind was corrupted right from the start, anyway his brains looked pretty cooked from the very beginning. Basquiat was a product of the hype and not of his talents, he was utilized by the vultures feeding off the art and turned into the merchandise by them. The film starts to the "Fairytale of New York"  a song by Pogues: "It was Christmas Eve in the drunk tank, babe, and I dreamed of you... I can see a better time when all our dreams come true"  the future is always sweet but when it becomes the present it turns into a crap: "You're bum, you're punk, you're an old slut on junk lying there almost dead on the drip in this bed." David Bowie in the role of Andy Warhol is a smasher and the multitude of cameos by the other big stars makes this picture seem like a starry night. This movie also boasts a superb soundtrack.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Weak subject ...... weak film ..................
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cannot believe this was supported by so many good actors, considering the subject was so boorish. Glorifying drug use as contributing to art sounds pretty boring and it is. The artists represented are so pretentious, they would not appeal as even casual acquaintances to most people. So why should anyone looking for entertainment be anything but disappointed with "Basquait"? This film probably should have been locally released in New York to the art house client&egrave;le and then dumped. They say art is in the eye of the beholder, well if this movie is art then it should hang on a wall, and not subject an audience to it's glorified nonsense. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely must see
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trumbull98
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every once in a while you watch a movie that means something to you. This is one. Totally compelling flick that let's you see a glimpse of another's soul. Jeffery Wright is so believable that I would guess he sometimes to this day slips back into character. While most viewers will have no way to judge the accuracy to the real Basquiat, the realism is none the less magical. Watch this movie and for about 90 minutes you will be transported directly into a creative period of American art & life history. There is nothing in this movie that appears out of place and it realistically captures life in NYT. Performances by all the supporting actors are great and Bowie's performance is amazing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Hollywood Attempt To Make A Loser Look Like A Winner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a nutshell: an interesting cast but a lousy movie. Make that a "horrible" movie. Real-life artist Jean Michel Baquiat died at the age of 27 from a heroin overdose, and he's pictured as the hero even though he's barely a step above being a sleazy street person in mentality, morals and beliefs. In other words, he's the kind of guy Hollywood loves. Basquiat (played by Jeffrey Wright) is surrounded by like-minded people in the art world: in other words, a lot of weird people, most of them pretty disgusting. It's the kind of film an agnostic and basically ignorant 18-year-old kid would like: sick. Having said all that, I like Basquiat's art. I've always found it fascinating, which is why I looked at the movie in the first place. I also like a lot of actors and actresses in here. It's just too bad the film wasn't nearly as good as the art and the actors. Another reviewer here, "Synchonic," said it best: "Empty movie full of empty people." I totally agree with that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid bio about one of many overrated "artists" of our idiotic times.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fedor8
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A decent bio about one of pop-art's worthless icons. That whole bogus New York "artiste" scene of the 60s (and onwards) has no value whatsoever. Nevertheless, the movie is quite easy-going and pleasant, and profits also from a large cast of great names (Wincott, Del Toro, Bowie, Posey, Walken, Dafoe, Oldman). There is also no denying that it's interesting to watch the lives within that ridiculous NY scene. Basquiat is shown as a near-tortured artist, though the constant money-for-nothing cash-inflow probably bothered him less. Wright plays him like a semi-retard, which is not an exaggeration  you just have to see Basquiat's retarded pictures with his dumb thoughts scribbled in lettering resembling a 7 year-old mongoloid's hand-writing, and you'll understand. Perhaps they tried to make him seem aloof and mysterious but it came out wrong (i.e. right). Even his walk appears to be suspiciously weird - Basquiat really did talk it like he walk it. Yet this guy lived quite recently so all the nuances of his behaviour should be well-recorded, so maybe he was really this screwed up. There should be a movie made just like this one, entirely about Warhol - that would be fun. If you want to read an extensive satire about modern art (mainly Picasso) contact me by e-mail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Taste This
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    balifox
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one is like a Christmas dinner except your pants won't feel two sizes too small afterwards. Jeffrey Wright is a succulent piece of delectable meat, Gary Oldman is my mashed potatoes, Benicio Del Toro adds his curious level of reason like only your best seasoned vegetable can and my Michael Wincotthe is so delicious, he is easily that forbidden piece of dessert at the end of the table that you swear you won't eat a minute before you are literally gorging yourself on it. The cast is simply pure gold. It is so good and enchanting with a 1980's charm that is simply non-existent in other films. It is the art, music and meaning of that decade at its purest. Effortless, yet clever the dialogue gives you the sincere rise and fall of all artists.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genius or exploitation?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jse126
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Basquiat" is a film with an agenda. Far from being a neutral stage upon which the life and emotion of the artist is played out for us to observe, this film wants to make a point about the art world, casting Basquiat as Oliver Twist. If you are looking to find out what drives an artist you are not going to find it here - unless the answer is money. The filmmakers did not go very far into the head of their subject - either that or he was a very shallow and vapid person. I did not get the feeling from this film that Basquiat was a true artist; rather, he came off as an opportunist who figured out how to capture the mechanics of bad abstract impressionism and pass himself off as one. Then a lucky break, combined with silly art collectors who have way too much money and not enough of their own thought processes, multiplied by a guilt ridden population of white people flush with 1980's cash, combine to equal the phenomenon of Basquiat. I am not saying that this is (or is not) the truth. In the world of art there are no truths anyway. What I am saying is that this is not a neutral biography. It may pay to do a little bit of research into Basquiat before watching the film. As for myself, I admit to watching it only because I was bored and nothing else was on. I knew vaguely the story, and who Basquiat was, but had no opinions of and no real knowledge about him. Since I am not the type of person who forms his opinions on any subject based on information from only one source, I did some research into Basquiat after the film before coming to any sort of conclusions. What those conclusions were are irrelevant as far as this review is concerned - but what does concern me are the many people who undoubtedly had their opinion about Basquiat fed to them by this film and who now consider themselves educated on the subject. As far as the film itself, it is not bad. Not great, but not bad. It had a certain feeling to it. But it is hard to get beyond its portrayal of the subject, as he is the reason for the film. As noted, Basquiat comes off as an empty headed and shallow individual without a lot of talent or original thought who likes to use drugs and drink a lot. The film's Basquiat seemed not to care much about art, that it was an afterthought to him. He was shown as a dabbler - dabbling in music too but not doing much or giving it much effort. Perhaps that is the truth, I don't know, because overall the film is more a study of art and what constitutes it and gives it value than a biography of an artist - and postulates that today's art is more about the name than the actual piece. The same thing that is given away for free by a homeless man who lives in a box can be worth six figures if the right people decide that it should. I also felt that he filmmakers relied on clich&eacute;' a bit too much for my liking. The scene that sticks out in my mind is the one where Basquiat was on a schoolyard basketball court with his buddy, who was trying to get him to play. Basquiat was totally inept at the game and had no desire to play whatsoever. The filmmakers were obviously trying to demonstrate either one or both of two things - that Basquiat was so much of a cerebral artist that he was incapable of physical sport, or that Basquiat was a black man who could not play basketball. Whatever the case, the scene was painful to watch. It was ham-fisted imagery at its worst. A well done scene with some good conversation and emotion could have sent the same message intended in the schoolyard - actually could have done it better because as blockheaded as the schoolyard scene was, it still did not send a clear and defined message. The acting in Basquiat was for the most part serviceable, with David Bowie turning in the most inspired performance as Andy Warhol. Bowie brought a subtle warmth and humanity to a person who is often portrayed as a cold cartoon character. Although Warhol was clearly intended to be an exploiter in the film, Bowie managed to show him as a person who felt that Basquiat was a true friend and not just a paycheck. This is an Andy Warhol who cared about people, and who could have his feelings hurt just like anyone else. This is not the stereotypical movie Warhol, playing with people like the proverbial chess pieces. This Warhol genuinely admired the work of his prot&eacute;g&eacute;s. And David Bowie would know, wouldn't he? He was there. I got the feeling that Bowie took the part to make a statement about Warhol - as if he was annoyed by younger filmmakers using the stereotypical Warhol image in an exploitative way. I felt that he was subversively reading the lines between the lines. Good for him. This film is more a commentary on the art world, on racism, and on exploitation than it is a biography. I would say that it is better to look at it this way, for as a biography it is biased and somewhat mean-spirited. Remember the first line of this review? It seemed to me that the filmmakers were saying that Basquiat was bereft of talent and inspiration - that he was a bum and a drug abuser who got lucky. Perhaps he was, but I'd prefer to make up my own mind. So it would pay to know a bit about the subject before watching - this Basquiat is a light dessert, not the main course.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful! One of my fav movies of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doveniki
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jeffery Wright became Basquiat! He should have won the Oscar for this. If only it was made after Halle Berry's Monsters Ball. Brilliant casting, some of the best Soundtracks ever. I love this movie for so many reasons. It is artistic as the people it portraits. It also manages to put the viewer in the shoes of the characters. Although I don't do drugs I totally got lost as if I was high together in the room with Basquiat when he painted the tires. Every artist knows, that mentally you go to an other place while painting. Somehow each time I see this movie it manages to transfers me into Basquiats strange world. I know its horrible to be an addict, but this flick somehow showed the beauty of it.. I don't know, maybe you have to be an artist, a bit avanguart, in love with new york and music to totally appreciate this #
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just to note
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dusan-22
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am putting my comment on this movie just to emphasize childish level of the voters and visitors of this site. One great film like this deserves much more than attention of semi-infantile audience that is running around IMDb site. I can agree that the movie is a matter of taste, but its value encapsulated in the grade shouldn't spoil that. For example, I might don't appreciate Van Gogh's paintings but I can't say that his work deserves low grade. Great cast, great movie - everything is real art. Compares to the greatest art films I have ever seen this movie does not deserve the best grade, but compares to shallow art value and narrow oriented stories of the pre-school characters that are cherished with greatest ardour around here - this movie is a masterpiece. Jeffrey Wright is so convincing that after you see the film it stays with you for a pretty long time ...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the artist as a success, a sometimes but not always usual bio-pic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jean Michel Basquiat was a really intriguing creature. He was an artist in the truest proletariat sense of the word. Meaning that he could never be bourgeois, even as he was brought in to that world, dominated by the "15-minutes-of-fame" man himself, Andy Warhol. By the way Julian Schnabel's loving if not too adulatory portrait of Basquiat shows, he was a guy trapped a bit inside of his own mind artistically, but at the same time really responsive to the world around him, commenting on it, sometimes at random, other times with the skill of an artist who just turns the world on a dime without even seeming to try. His art may not appeal to everyone, but it's hard to deny what it is, which is material made to provoke some kind of reaction; only someone like a disconnected bourgeois, like Warhol's lover/manager Bruno (played by Dennis Hopper in this film) would be detached from Basquiat's art. But there poses another question that Schnabel poses to the audience (perhaps a little bluntly, but effective all the same): how does one who is not apart of one world assimilate in another? Basquiat wasn't always the nicest person or easiest to get along with, but he had that quality like Jim Morrison, where he could be turned on to someone so much and so brightly that it was hard to look away, quirks and seething anger (and drug addiction) and all. Schnabel also does not give the audience any firm reason about how or why Jean Michel turned out like this as a kid (we hear at one point from an interviewer he was raised middle class and chose to live in a cardboard box), and it's not always necessary really. He is who he is at the start- a quirky, amused and experimental artist and musician- and then from there his fame is what makes him more (or less) fascinating to us. Basquiat takes the proverbial 'bio-pic' route with some of the expectation one has. For example, Schnabel emphasizes his romantic ties to a waitress and artist, Gina (Forlani), and makes the professional part of his storyline concurrent to that, no more or less important than that strand. But this is not a deterrent to see the usual up-and-down love story between a flawed artist and his love. Perhaps more conventional is seeing the person in the story hooked on drugs, but it was a fact in Basquiat's life and it's dealt with tastefully, or at least realistically. And to counter some of the expectations one has with a 'rise-to-fame' story of an artist, Schnabel makes it very much a film in its time and place: it's late 70's, early 80's, in New York City, where grit and decay seems to counter (or attract) the glitz and glamor, also in its own kind of decay (Warhol was more of a leech by then anyway, in a great scene having someone else drink beer and pee on a canvas since he won't drink beer to do it himself). Sometimes it's just bizarre in a delightful way, like how Basquiat looks up at the sky and sees surfing, and other times it's a fine array of the period in terms of music, or just New York City kind of music in general (Miles Davis to Johnny Rotten to early 80's hip hop to the Rolling Stones). At the center of Schnabel's portrait of an artist as a quasi-question mark, is Jeffrey Wright. He's always 'on' in a scene, even when it looks like Jean Michel is somewhere else, or just not responding to another person in the room (just watch the way Wright, as Basquiat, defuses a very angry Gina after he's painted over her paintings when she wakes up). It's a curious thing, too, to see him contrasted with David Bowie, who almost seems to have gone method in portraying the pop-culture icon as a bit of a quiet creep. It's the kind of performance, by Wright, that says 'watch out for me, I have some good things to offer', and it was a real breakthrough role, leading to the kind of varied work of his career in work ranging from Syriana to Cadillac Records. But as Basquiat, he finds one of his richest real-life characters, an artist of the streets. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Limelight Burns
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JustApt
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basquiat is about the way the fame corrupts the mind or maybe his mind was corrupted right from the start, anyway his brains looked pretty cooked from the very beginning. Basquiat was a product of the hype and not of his talents, he was utilized by the vultures feeding off the art and turned into the merchandise by them. The film starts to the "Fairytale of New York"  a song by Pogues: "It was Christmas Eve in the drunk tank, babe, and I dreamed of you... I can see a better time when all our dreams come true"  the future is always sweet but when it becomes the present it turns into a crap: "You're bum, you're punk, you're an old slut on junk lying there almost dead on the drip in this bed." David Bowie in the role of Andy Warhol is a smasher and the multitude of cameos by the other big stars makes this picture seem like a starry night. This movie also boasts a superb soundtrack.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Weak subject ...... weak film ..................
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cannot believe this was supported by so many good actors, considering the subject was so boorish. Glorifying drug use as contributing to art sounds pretty boring and it is. The artists represented are so pretentious, they would not appeal as even casual acquaintances to most people. So why should anyone looking for entertainment be anything but disappointed with "Basquait"? This film probably should have been locally released in New York to the art house client&egrave;le and then dumped. They say art is in the eye of the beholder, well if this movie is art then it should hang on a wall, and not subject an audience to it's glorified nonsense. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely must see
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trumbull98
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every once in a while you watch a movie that means something to you. This is one. Totally compelling flick that let's you see a glimpse of another's soul. Jeffery Wright is so believable that I would guess he sometimes to this day slips back into character. While most viewers will have no way to judge the accuracy to the real Basquiat, the realism is none the less magical. Watch this movie and for about 90 minutes you will be transported directly into a creative period of American art & life history. There is nothing in this movie that appears out of place and it realistically captures life in NYT. Performances by all the supporting actors are great and Bowie's performance is amazing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Hollywood Attempt To Make A Loser Look Like A Winner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a nutshell: an interesting cast but a lousy movie. Make that a "horrible" movie. Real-life artist Jean Michel Baquiat died at the age of 27 from a heroin overdose, and he's pictured as the hero even though he's barely a step above being a sleazy street person in mentality, morals and beliefs. In other words, he's the kind of guy Hollywood loves. Basquiat (played by Jeffrey Wright) is surrounded by like-minded people in the art world: in other words, a lot of weird people, most of them pretty disgusting. It's the kind of film an agnostic and basically ignorant 18-year-old kid would like: sick. Having said all that, I like Basquiat's art. I've always found it fascinating, which is why I looked at the movie in the first place. I also like a lot of actors and actresses in here. It's just too bad the film wasn't nearly as good as the art and the actors. Another reviewer here, "Synchonic," said it best: "Empty movie full of empty people." I totally agree with that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid bio about one of many overrated "artists" of our idiotic times.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fedor8
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A decent bio about one of pop-art's worthless icons. That whole bogus New York "artiste" scene of the 60s (and onwards) has no value whatsoever. Nevertheless, the movie is quite easy-going and pleasant, and profits also from a large cast of great names (Wincott, Del Toro, Bowie, Posey, Walken, Dafoe, Oldman). There is also no denying that it's interesting to watch the lives within that ridiculous NY scene. Basquiat is shown as a near-tortured artist, though the constant money-for-nothing cash-inflow probably bothered him less. Wright plays him like a semi-retard, which is not an exaggeration  you just have to see Basquiat's retarded pictures with his dumb thoughts scribbled in lettering resembling a 7 year-old mongoloid's hand-writing, and you'll understand. Perhaps they tried to make him seem aloof and mysterious but it came out wrong (i.e. right). Even his walk appears to be suspiciously weird - Basquiat really did talk it like he walk it. Yet this guy lived quite recently so all the nuances of his behaviour should be well-recorded, so maybe he was really this screwed up. There should be a movie made just like this one, entirely about Warhol - that would be fun. If you want to read an extensive satire about modern art (mainly Picasso) contact me by e-mail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Taste This
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    balifox
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one is like a Christmas dinner except your pants won't feel two sizes too small afterwards. Jeffrey Wright is a succulent piece of delectable meat, Gary Oldman is my mashed potatoes, Benicio Del Toro adds his curious level of reason like only your best seasoned vegetable can and my Michael Wincotthe is so delicious, he is easily that forbidden piece of dessert at the end of the table that you swear you won't eat a minute before you are literally gorging yourself on it. The cast is simply pure gold. It is so good and enchanting with a 1980's charm that is simply non-existent in other films. It is the art, music and meaning of that decade at its purest. Effortless, yet clever the dialogue gives you the sincere rise and fall of all artists.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genius or exploitation?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jse126
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Basquiat" is a film with an agenda. Far from being a neutral stage upon which the life and emotion of the artist is played out for us to observe, this film wants to make a point about the art world, casting Basquiat as Oliver Twist. If you are looking to find out what drives an artist you are not going to find it here - unless the answer is money. The filmmakers did not go very far into the head of their subject - either that or he was a very shallow and vapid person. I did not get the feeling from this film that Basquiat was a true artist; rather, he came off as an opportunist who figured out how to capture the mechanics of bad abstract impressionism and pass himself off as one. Then a lucky break, combined with silly art collectors who have way too much money and not enough of their own thought processes, multiplied by a guilt ridden population of white people flush with 1980's cash, combine to equal the phenomenon of Basquiat. I am not saying that this is (or is not) the truth. In the world of art there are no truths anyway. What I am saying is that this is not a neutral biography. It may pay to do a little bit of research into Basquiat before watching the film. As for myself, I admit to watching it only because I was bored and nothing else was on. I knew vaguely the story, and who Basquiat was, but had no opinions of and no real knowledge about him. Since I am not the type of person who forms his opinions on any subject based on information from only one source, I did some research into Basquiat after the film before coming to any sort of conclusions. What those conclusions were are irrelevant as far as this review is concerned - but what does concern me are the many people who undoubtedly had their opinion about Basquiat fed to them by this film and who now consider themselves educated on the subject. As far as the film itself, it is not bad. Not great, but not bad. It had a certain feeling to it. But it is hard to get beyond its portrayal of the subject, as he is the reason for the film. As noted, Basquiat comes off as an empty headed and shallow individual without a lot of talent or original thought who likes to use drugs and drink a lot. The film's Basquiat seemed not to care much about art, that it was an afterthought to him. He was shown as a dabbler - dabbling in music too but not doing much or giving it much effort. Perhaps that is the truth, I don't know, because overall the film is more a study of art and what constitutes it and gives it value than a biography of an artist - and postulates that today's art is more about the name than the actual piece. The same thing that is given away for free by a homeless man who lives in a box can be worth six figures if the right people decide that it should. I also felt that he filmmakers relied on clich&eacute;' a bit too much for my liking. The scene that sticks out in my mind is the one where Basquiat was on a schoolyard basketball court with his buddy, who was trying to get him to play. Basquiat was totally inept at the game and had no desire to play whatsoever. The filmmakers were obviously trying to demonstrate either one or both of two things - that Basquiat was so much of a cerebral artist that he was incapable of physical sport, or that Basquiat was a black man who could not play basketball. Whatever the case, the scene was painful to watch. It was ham-fisted imagery at its worst. A well done scene with some good conversation and emotion could have sent the same message intended in the schoolyard - actually could have done it better because as blockheaded as the schoolyard scene was, it still did not send a clear and defined message. The acting in Basquiat was for the most part serviceable, with David Bowie turning in the most inspired performance as Andy Warhol. Bowie brought a subtle warmth and humanity to a person who is often portrayed as a cold cartoon character. Although Warhol was clearly intended to be an exploiter in the film, Bowie managed to show him as a person who felt that Basquiat was a true friend and not just a paycheck. This is an Andy Warhol who cared about people, and who could have his feelings hurt just like anyone else. This is not the stereotypical movie Warhol, playing with people like the proverbial chess pieces. This Warhol genuinely admired the work of his prot&eacute;g&eacute;s. And David Bowie would know, wouldn't he? He was there. I got the feeling that Bowie took the part to make a statement about Warhol - as if he was annoyed by younger filmmakers using the stereotypical Warhol image in an exploitative way. I felt that he was subversively reading the lines between the lines. Good for him. This film is more a commentary on the art world, on racism, and on exploitation than it is a biography. I would say that it is better to look at it this way, for as a biography it is biased and somewhat mean-spirited. Remember the first line of this review? It seemed to me that the filmmakers were saying that Basquiat was bereft of talent and inspiration - that he was a bum and a drug abuser who got lucky. Perhaps he was, but I'd prefer to make up my own mind. So it would pay to know a bit about the subject before watching - this Basquiat is a light dessert, not the main course.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful! One of my fav movies of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doveniki
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jeffery Wright became Basquiat! He should have won the Oscar for this. If only it was made after Halle Berry's Monsters Ball. Brilliant casting, some of the best Soundtracks ever. I love this movie for so many reasons. It is artistic as the people it portraits. It also manages to put the viewer in the shoes of the characters. Although I don't do drugs I totally got lost as if I was high together in the room with Basquiat when he painted the tires. Every artist knows, that mentally you go to an other place while painting. Somehow each time I see this movie it manages to transfers me into Basquiats strange world. I know its horrible to be an addict, but this flick somehow showed the beauty of it.. I don't know, maybe you have to be an artist, a bit avanguart, in love with new york and music to totally appreciate this #
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just to note
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dusan-22
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am putting my comment on this movie just to emphasize childish level of the voters and visitors of this site. One great film like this deserves much more than attention of semi-infantile audience that is running around IMDb site. I can agree that the movie is a matter of taste, but its value encapsulated in the grade shouldn't spoil that. For example, I might don't appreciate Van Gogh's paintings but I can't say that his work deserves low grade. Great cast, great movie - everything is real art. Compares to the greatest art films I have ever seen this movie does not deserve the best grade, but compares to shallow art value and narrow oriented stories of the pre-school characters that are cherished with greatest ardour around here - this movie is a masterpiece. Jeffrey Wright is so convincing that after you see the film it stays with you for a pretty long time ...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the artist as a success, a sometimes but not always usual bio-pic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jean Michel Basquiat was a really intriguing creature. He was an artist in the truest proletariat sense of the word. Meaning that he could never be bourgeois, even as he was brought in to that world, dominated by the "15-minutes-of-fame" man himself, Andy Warhol. By the way Julian Schnabel's loving if not too adulatory portrait of Basquiat shows, he was a guy trapped a bit inside of his own mind artistically, but at the same time really responsive to the world around him, commenting on it, sometimes at random, other times with the skill of an artist who just turns the world on a dime without even seeming to try. His art may not appeal to everyone, but it's hard to deny what it is, which is material made to provoke some kind of reaction; only someone like a disconnected bourgeois, like Warhol's lover/manager Bruno (played by Dennis Hopper in this film) would be detached from Basquiat's art. But there poses another question that Schnabel poses to the audience (perhaps a little bluntly, but effective all the same): how does one who is not apart of one world assimilate in another? Basquiat wasn't always the nicest person or easiest to get along with, but he had that quality like Jim Morrison, where he could be turned on to someone so much and so brightly that it was hard to look away, quirks and seething anger (and drug addiction) and all. Schnabel also does not give the audience any firm reason about how or why Jean Michel turned out like this as a kid (we hear at one point from an interviewer he was raised middle class and chose to live in a cardboard box), and it's not always necessary really. He is who he is at the start- a quirky, amused and experimental artist and musician- and then from there his fame is what makes him more (or less) fascinating to us. Basquiat takes the proverbial 'bio-pic' route with some of the expectation one has. For example, Schnabel emphasizes his romantic ties to a waitress and artist, Gina (Forlani), and makes the professional part of his storyline concurrent to that, no more or less important than that strand. But this is not a deterrent to see the usual up-and-down love story between a flawed artist and his love. Perhaps more conventional is seeing the person in the story hooked on drugs, but it was a fact in Basquiat's life and it's dealt with tastefully, or at least realistically. And to counter some of the expectations one has with a 'rise-to-fame' story of an artist, Schnabel makes it very much a film in its time and place: it's late 70's, early 80's, in New York City, where grit and decay seems to counter (or attract) the glitz and glamor, also in its own kind of decay (Warhol was more of a leech by then anyway, in a great scene having someone else drink beer and pee on a canvas since he won't drink beer to do it himself). Sometimes it's just bizarre in a delightful way, like how Basquiat looks up at the sky and sees surfing, and other times it's a fine array of the period in terms of music, or just New York City kind of music in general (Miles Davis to Johnny Rotten to early 80's hip hop to the Rolling Stones). At the center of Schnabel's portrait of an artist as a quasi-question mark, is Jeffrey Wright. He's always 'on' in a scene, even when it looks like Jean Michel is somewhere else, or just not responding to another person in the room (just watch the way Wright, as Basquiat, defuses a very angry Gina after he's painted over her paintings when she wakes up). It's a curious thing, too, to see him contrasted with David Bowie, who almost seems to have gone method in portraying the pop-culture icon as a bit of a quiet creep. It's the kind of performance, by Wright, that says 'watch out for me, I have some good things to offer', and it was a real breakthrough role, leading to the kind of varied work of his career in work ranging from Syriana to Cadillac Records. But as Basquiat, he finds one of his richest real-life characters, an artist of the streets. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Limelight Burns
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JustApt
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basquiat is about the way the fame corrupts the mind or maybe his mind was corrupted right from the start, anyway his brains looked pretty cooked from the very beginning. Basquiat was a product of the hype and not of his talents, he was utilized by the vultures feeding off the art and turned into the merchandise by them. The film starts to the "Fairytale of New York"  a song by Pogues: "It was Christmas Eve in the drunk tank, babe, and I dreamed of you... I can see a better time when all our dreams come true"  the future is always sweet but when it becomes the present it turns into a crap: "You're bum, you're punk, you're an old slut on junk lying there almost dead on the drip in this bed." David Bowie in the role of Andy Warhol is a smasher and the multitude of cameos by the other big stars makes this picture seem like a starry night. This movie also boasts a superb soundtrack.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Weak subject ...... weak film ..................
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cannot believe this was supported by so many good actors, considering the subject was so boorish. Glorifying drug use as contributing to art sounds pretty boring and it is. The artists represented are so pretentious, they would not appeal as even casual acquaintances to most people. So why should anyone looking for entertainment be anything but disappointed with "Basquait"? This film probably should have been locally released in New York to the art house client&egrave;le and then dumped. They say art is in the eye of the beholder, well if this movie is art then it should hang on a wall, and not subject an audience to it's glorified nonsense. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely must see
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trumbull98
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every once in a while you watch a movie that means something to you. This is one. Totally compelling flick that let's you see a glimpse of another's soul. Jeffery Wright is so believable that I would guess he sometimes to this day slips back into character. While most viewers will have no way to judge the accuracy to the real Basquiat, the realism is none the less magical. Watch this movie and for about 90 minutes you will be transported directly into a creative period of American art & life history. There is nothing in this movie that appears out of place and it realistically captures life in NYT. Performances by all the supporting actors are great and Bowie's performance is amazing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Hollywood Attempt To Make A Loser Look Like A Winner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a nutshell: an interesting cast but a lousy movie. Make that a "horrible" movie. Real-life artist Jean Michel Baquiat died at the age of 27 from a heroin overdose, and he's pictured as the hero even though he's barely a step above being a sleazy street person in mentality, morals and beliefs. In other words, he's the kind of guy Hollywood loves. Basquiat (played by Jeffrey Wright) is surrounded by like-minded people in the art world: in other words, a lot of weird people, most of them pretty disgusting. It's the kind of film an agnostic and basically ignorant 18-year-old kid would like: sick. Having said all that, I like Basquiat's art. I've always found it fascinating, which is why I looked at the movie in the first place. I also like a lot of actors and actresses in here. It's just too bad the film wasn't nearly as good as the art and the actors. Another reviewer here, "Synchonic," said it best: "Empty movie full of empty people." I totally agree with that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid bio about one of many overrated "artists" of our idiotic times.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fedor8
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A decent bio about one of pop-art's worthless icons. That whole bogus New York "artiste" scene of the 60s (and onwards) has no value whatsoever. Nevertheless, the movie is quite easy-going and pleasant, and profits also from a large cast of great names (Wincott, Del Toro, Bowie, Posey, Walken, Dafoe, Oldman). There is also no denying that it's interesting to watch the lives within that ridiculous NY scene. Basquiat is shown as a near-tortured artist, though the constant money-for-nothing cash-inflow probably bothered him less. Wright plays him like a semi-retard, which is not an exaggeration  you just have to see Basquiat's retarded pictures with his dumb thoughts scribbled in lettering resembling a 7 year-old mongoloid's hand-writing, and you'll understand. Perhaps they tried to make him seem aloof and mysterious but it came out wrong (i.e. right). Even his walk appears to be suspiciously weird - Basquiat really did talk it like he walk it. Yet this guy lived quite recently so all the nuances of his behaviour should be well-recorded, so maybe he was really this screwed up. There should be a movie made just like this one, entirely about Warhol - that would be fun. If you want to read an extensive satire about modern art (mainly Picasso) contact me by e-mail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Taste This
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    balifox
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one is like a Christmas dinner except your pants won't feel two sizes too small afterwards. Jeffrey Wright is a succulent piece of delectable meat, Gary Oldman is my mashed potatoes, Benicio Del Toro adds his curious level of reason like only your best seasoned vegetable can and my Michael Wincotthe is so delicious, he is easily that forbidden piece of dessert at the end of the table that you swear you won't eat a minute before you are literally gorging yourself on it. The cast is simply pure gold. It is so good and enchanting with a 1980's charm that is simply non-existent in other films. It is the art, music and meaning of that decade at its purest. Effortless, yet clever the dialogue gives you the sincere rise and fall of all artists.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genius or exploitation?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jse126
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Basquiat" is a film with an agenda. Far from being a neutral stage upon which the life and emotion of the artist is played out for us to observe, this film wants to make a point about the art world, casting Basquiat as Oliver Twist. If you are looking to find out what drives an artist you are not going to find it here - unless the answer is money. The filmmakers did not go very far into the head of their subject - either that or he was a very shallow and vapid person. I did not get the feeling from this film that Basquiat was a true artist; rather, he came off as an opportunist who figured out how to capture the mechanics of bad abstract impressionism and pass himself off as one. Then a lucky break, combined with silly art collectors who have way too much money and not enough of their own thought processes, multiplied by a guilt ridden population of white people flush with 1980's cash, combine to equal the phenomenon of Basquiat. I am not saying that this is (or is not) the truth. In the world of art there are no truths anyway. What I am saying is that this is not a neutral biography. It may pay to do a little bit of research into Basquiat before watching the film. As for myself, I admit to watching it only because I was bored and nothing else was on. I knew vaguely the story, and who Basquiat was, but had no opinions of and no real knowledge about him. Since I am not the type of person who forms his opinions on any subject based on information from only one source, I did some research into Basquiat after the film before coming to any sort of conclusions. What those conclusions were are irrelevant as far as this review is concerned - but what does concern me are the many people who undoubtedly had their opinion about Basquiat fed to them by this film and who now consider themselves educated on the subject. As far as the film itself, it is not bad. Not great, but not bad. It had a certain feeling to it. But it is hard to get beyond its portrayal of the subject, as he is the reason for the film. As noted, Basquiat comes off as an empty headed and shallow individual without a lot of talent or original thought who likes to use drugs and drink a lot. The film's Basquiat seemed not to care much about art, that it was an afterthought to him. He was shown as a dabbler - dabbling in music too but not doing much or giving it much effort. Perhaps that is the truth, I don't know, because overall the film is more a study of art and what constitutes it and gives it value than a biography of an artist - and postulates that today's art is more about the name than the actual piece. The same thing that is given away for free by a homeless man who lives in a box can be worth six figures if the right people decide that it should. I also felt that he filmmakers relied on clich&eacute;' a bit too much for my liking. The scene that sticks out in my mind is the one where Basquiat was on a schoolyard basketball court with his buddy, who was trying to get him to play. Basquiat was totally inept at the game and had no desire to play whatsoever. The filmmakers were obviously trying to demonstrate either one or both of two things - that Basquiat was so much of a cerebral artist that he was incapable of physical sport, or that Basquiat was a black man who could not play basketball. Whatever the case, the scene was painful to watch. It was ham-fisted imagery at its worst. A well done scene with some good conversation and emotion could have sent the same message intended in the schoolyard - actually could have done it better because as blockheaded as the schoolyard scene was, it still did not send a clear and defined message. The acting in Basquiat was for the most part serviceable, with David Bowie turning in the most inspired performance as Andy Warhol. Bowie brought a subtle warmth and humanity to a person who is often portrayed as a cold cartoon character. Although Warhol was clearly intended to be an exploiter in the film, Bowie managed to show him as a person who felt that Basquiat was a true friend and not just a paycheck. This is an Andy Warhol who cared about people, and who could have his feelings hurt just like anyone else. This is not the stereotypical movie Warhol, playing with people like the proverbial chess pieces. This Warhol genuinely admired the work of his prot&eacute;g&eacute;s. And David Bowie would know, wouldn't he? He was there. I got the feeling that Bowie took the part to make a statement about Warhol - as if he was annoyed by younger filmmakers using the stereotypical Warhol image in an exploitative way. I felt that he was subversively reading the lines between the lines. Good for him. This film is more a commentary on the art world, on racism, and on exploitation than it is a biography. I would say that it is better to look at it this way, for as a biography it is biased and somewhat mean-spirited. Remember the first line of this review? It seemed to me that the filmmakers were saying that Basquiat was bereft of talent and inspiration - that he was a bum and a drug abuser who got lucky. Perhaps he was, but I'd prefer to make up my own mind. So it would pay to know a bit about the subject before watching - this Basquiat is a light dessert, not the main course.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
