<filme>
 <id>
  1012
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119951
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Rei da Baixaria
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The auto-biographical story of Howard Stern, the radio-rebel who is now also a TV-personality, an author and a movie star.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Having always wanted to be a disc-jockey, Howard Stern works his way painfully from radio at his 1970's college to a Detroit station. It is with a move to Washington that he hits on an outrageous off-the-wall style that catches audience attention. Despite his on-air blue talk, at home he is a loving husband. He needs all the support he can get when he joins NBC in New York and comes up against a very different vision of radio.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Biography
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   radio
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   disc jockey
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   nbc
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   1970s
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   college
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Betty Thomas
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Howard Stern
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Len Blum
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Howard Stern
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Mary McCormack
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Robin Quivers
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stern is good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a long term listener of Howard Stern I was satisfied with the adaptation of the book to the big screen. Betty Thomas was smart enough to allow Howard be himself. It works because Stern is not really acting. Having heard the actual tapes of his father berating him as a kid, seeing Richard Portnow as Ben, was dead on accurate and funny as hell. The other highlight is Paul Giamatti as the program director called pig vomit, who is hired to control Stern's free wheeling and often vulgar on air persona. At one point the self proclaimed king of all media is subjected to a lecture on the proper way of announcing wnbc with a prolonged and exaggerated W "NNNNNNNBC;" it is exactly as it happened because I actually heard the broadcast and the constant battles between Howie and the management at the now defunct radio station. Previous to the WNBC job, we see the struggle from college radio to Briarcliff, NY to Hartford, Ct. to Detroit and the last stop before the Big Apple is Washington, D.C. It is a ride filled with odd ball characters, nude women and people behaving badly, all for the ratings, and it works due to Stern's ability to communicate at the level of a regular guy. The film is well made and should be entertaining even for non listeners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Free speech all the way! Also, I once got to know the woman who played Kenny's wife.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Betty Thomas's "Private Parts" came out, I had only loosely heard of Howard Stern, and usually in a negative context. But the movie really opened my eyes. It turns out that beyond his sometimes shocking radio content, it's all about free speech. Stern may pull some of the grossest stunts on air, but he's just showing what the First Amendment is all about. Like Lenny Bruce, George Carlin, Larry Flynt, John Waters, and the Farrelly Brothers, Stern always goes for the funniest shock value. And the movie does a great job showing that. And yes, it's true, I once got to know Aimee Luzier, who played Pig Vomit's wife. She was the assistant in a history/literature class that I took in high school.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An honest biopic work of art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern is an acquired taste for the diverse and eclectic. Never listening to his radio show, but an avid listener of scattered clips on the internet, I felt Private Parts could give me the proper introduction the man I was looking for. After all, the man has been a radio icon for many years and an FCC bandit for just as long. Like him or not, Stern has changed the face of radio. He has revolutionized the definition of "talk radio." I can't stress enough that I love talk radio. I find it to be not only relaxed but an insightful way to collect information on certain, gray topics. I used to religiously listen to DreX in the Morning, a Chicago-based radio show on WKSC-FM. Once he was gone at the end of 2010 so was I. I couldn't imagine not having him on my radio every morning before I ship myself off for my daily grind. Then in March I quickly turned over to Eddie and Jobo on WJMK-FM. To this day that's my cup of coffee in the morning. Stern has been more controversial than all of three of those men combined. He threatens the very patience of the FCC, and has pretty much thrown caution and restrictions to the wind as he sits in front of the mic and speaks his mind on whatever he wants. Through various warnings and threats made from his station and the FCC, all of which have been dismissed by him, it's pretty clear that as long as there are faithful listeners, Stern isn't concerned with who he offends or what he is faced with. The movie chronicles his life starting at a very young age where we see Stern's father makes an exercise out of verbally abusing his son. This may have contributed to Stern being a very closed book. Not to mention the fact he went to an all black high school, which only made his differences stand out. As years go by, and because of his father's occupation in radio, Stern develops a passion for the airwaves. This is an awkward and unexpected choice from someone who cruised through high school saying almost nothing. The thought of him pioneering a genre of talk radio which focused more on humor than news was not even present at the time because of his very shy nature. After hits and misses at different radio shows, Stern is finally hired by WNBC in New York City where he would wind up in numerous arguments with his station manager nicknamed Pig Vomit (played very well by Paul Giamatti). Stern's run at WNBC in the eighties was where he gained his most popularity and notoriety. After tirelessly working throughout college on their own brand-name radio and at a number of dead end jobs, he finally got the break he deserved. If you can look past his crude, vulgar, shameless persona there lies a sweet, gentle, hilarious side to him. That may have been added since Hollywood is notorious for factoring in little clich&eacute;s into biopics, but since Stern rejected many, many scripts before settling on this one I assume this one got it to almost pin-point accuracy. I forgot to mention that Stern married the beautiful Alison (McCormack) in 1978 after dating her prolifically throughout his run at WRNR. Alison was the first woman who ever gave Stern the time of day. But Stern makes it very clear being married to him is not an easy task. Stern is notorious for releasing private affairs with his wife over the air, which is what lead to their divorce about four years after this film was made. Private Parts is a provocative look at talk radio and where it was and now is because of Howard Stern. Sometimes it appears as if it is glossing over some events and instances that might have happened during Stern's long run. Surely he had to be suspended a few times, and maybe some of the fights with his wife lead to his expulsion from the house for a few days. But the movie doesn't dive into that as much as it looks at Stern's mark on the radio. Which is what it should look at it. It rarely simplifies the story, and comes out to be a very honest biopic work of art. Starring: Howard Stern, Robin Quivers, Fred Norris, Mary McCormack, and Paul Giamatti. Directed by: Betty Thomas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific Comedy with a (Gasp) Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Private Parts (1997) *** 1/2 (out of 4) Taken from Howard Stern's best selling autobiography, this film follows Sterns early years as a loser in high school all the way up to becoming the king of radio in New York City. While the majority of the film deals with his struggle of making it on the radio, we also get the story of his relationship with wife Alison (Mary McCormack). No matter what you think of Stern I think anyone will be able to enjoy this film and in fact I still remember going to see it when it was first released with someone who hated the guy with a passion and even they walked out liking him. I think a large portion of the film and the original book wanted to make people understand Stern and there's no question that the film is a bit one-sided but in the end it accomplishes what it set out to do and that is show people the real person. The film is full of raunchy humor including a great take-off on the Match Game and another terrific sequence with Stern having sex with a woman over the radio and while these comic bits are terrific what really makes the film so memorable is its charm. The film is incredibly charming and one can't help but really fall in love with Stern's character and especially the way he's determined not to stop until he reaches the top. I think the film is rather remarkable in that it can be downright filthy one moment but then sweet the next. It's really hard to mix those two things but the screenplay and director Thomas really make it work and by doing so they've created a rather special movie that keeps getting better with each new viewing. It should come as no shock but Stern makes for a terrific actor even though he's playing himself. I've heard many great actors say that playing themselves would be a very difficult thing to do but Stern handles it with no troubles as does his supporting mates Robin Quivers, Fred Norris and Jackie Martling. McCormack is also extremely good as the wife and her chemistry with Stern comes off as real and they make you feel as if you're watching a real couple. Even better is Paul Giamatti who plays Kenny, aka Pig Vomit, the man who tries to tame Stern when he gets to NBC. The fire and passion that Giamatti brings to the role is rather remarkable to watch and you can't help but laugh at loud when he and Stern are going at it. PRIVATE PARKS is a hilarious movie and a touching one that tells the rise of Stern with loving care and in the end it really delivers everything you'd want it to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Private Parts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw a clip of this featured in one of those Channel 4 countdowns, I didn't acknowledge that the film was based on reality, so I was very keen, from director Betty Thomas (Doctor Dolittle, John Tucker Must Die). Basically, Howard Stern always wanted to be a disc jockey, working for a radio station, playing popular music and speaking his mind, and during the 1970's it was his goal to do it. Howard started out in college with not a lot of zing in his approach and hardly any personality on the Mic, but then he got his big break on a Detroit radio station. It is soon after starting out that Howard has a snap, his glasses and moustache come off, and his more vibrant and opinionated personality is brought out. He is joined on his own show with news anchor Robin Quivers, who shares his unorthodox approach to expressing his opinions, talking whatever he wants to, and doing whatever he can to get high ratings. The radio heads don't share all of Howard's ideas of what the listeners want, but his hilarious off-the-wall antics are getting the listeners, to the point where he is the most famous disc jockey on air. After a little misunderstanding between Howard and wife Alison (Mary McCormack) about her baby miscarriage, where he joked about it, and her forgiving him, Howard gains a bigger opportunity with NBC in New York. Howard also has the good fortune to have Alison pregnant again, but with his new bosses not understanding how he got such high ratings, it is only after taking him on board that they experience it. It is the job of Kenny Rushton (Paul Giamatti) and one or two other crew members to keep Howard in line, or force him to quit with the limitations of what he can do on radio, but this won't stop him. He has many troubles on and off Mic, high demands, including having Robin with him once again, and of course another hit with being the number one disc jockey again, but he also stays true to his family. Also starring Fred Norris, Gary Dell'Abate, Jackie Martling, Carol Alt as Gloria, Richard Portnow as Ben Stern, Allison Janney as Dee Dee, Jenna Jameson as Mandy, Ozzy Osbourne, Mia Farrow, David Letterman, AC-DC (including Brian Johnson, Iggy Pop and Wendy Whoppers as Big-Breasted Woman. Stern completely steals the show with his madcap radio hosting, and the real people playing their own parts keeps the momentum high. The best sequence is Stern using his voice with a stripping woman turning the bass up high on her speakers to have vibration style sex, it was number 28 on The 100 Greatest Funny Moments. A hilarious shock jock, a cast of well-knowns as themselves and in cameos, sexually explicit radio broadcasts, the story is based on facts, this is everything you wants in a biographical comedy. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific and very funny biopic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern has only ever been a vaguely familiar figure here in the UK. When Private Parts first came out I knew who he was and had seen a short segment about him on TV. My opinion of him was not good. From the small amount of information I had, he seemed like a completely unlikeable malicious idiot with an annoying haircut. So I certainly had some preconceptions about the man before seeing this film. After seeing it, I had to admit that, like most things in life, the truth is much more complex. In actual fact I came away from Private Parts liking and respecting Mr Stern quite a bit. Quite a turn-around. Sometimes with a biopic it's good to have very little knowledge of the subject. The trajectory of the story is then more surprising to you. This was true for me with Private Parts, as I had no real clue about Howard Stern's rise to fame. However, what surprised me the most was Stern's character. He was not afraid to paint himself as pathetic, and the honesty of this approach is the key to why it's such a compelling film. Some people have commented that this movie is self-serving and that Stern portrays himself as some kind of misunderstood innocent. While I can't definitively say if this is true or not, my gut feeling is that he depicts himself in a fairly honest way. Many times he shows himself to be seriously uncool and pathetic. And because his whole shtick is about not holding back and saying what he thinks, you can't help but feel that this ethos must apply to the movie too, and this is most probably what he is like. The film is often very funny, and I can't really often say this for most comedies. It mixes standard biopic drama with some inventive comedy moments that recall the style of Woody Allen; although an admittedly lower-brow Woody Allen with a fair smattering of naked women. But still, it's in that general ball-park. Stern is very good as, well, Stern. I think it's quite a reasonable achievement to be fair as it's actually not always that easy playing yourself. Take a look at a few of the cameo appearances in some of the episodes of Extras for proof of this bizarre truth. Anyway, he is a compelling central character, whose underlying personality seems to be very decent. Paul Giamatti is the other actor who stands out. His portrayal of Pig Vomit is hilarious. This is a great comic biopic. You certainly do not need to be familiar with its lead character to enjoy it, as it's a very well delivered and funny story. The humour never feels forced either, it just flows into the narrative. I am surprised I like Private Parts so much. It really changed my view of Howard Stern. Except I still think he has an annoying haircut.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a reminder
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mino
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was watching this one recently with friends and I realized I was the only one being amused. I just realized why. This is Scarface, not a comedy, but a dramatic account of foul taste with balls taking over. It's Tony Montana p***ing everything in his path. It's the logical outcome when ratings decide who stays and who leaves. But why do I find it amusing? Well, I don't, really. I guess it was just the anticipation of Giamatti's performance I had forgotten was so short spanned. I write the comment just in case I get the urge to watch this again in the future.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The King of all media is also the court jester
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nixskits
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern is a polarizing figure in entertainment, probably the most hated and loved figure of the last half century, depending on whether you are an opponent or a fan of his. As the stats are laid out in this film, Stern's enemies are just as, if not more, likely to be found listening to his show. The program he hosts is like millions of people's cup of coffee in the morning. This room rocker of a movie is the first chapter in the big screen project of his life, showing what a crazy thirty plus years it was. Rabid fans want another instalment showing what has developed since the mid 80's when "Private Parts" ends. He's since been divorced, remarried, seen his daughters become young adults, had his head writer Jackie "The Joke Man" Martling walk away and replaced by stand up comic Artie Lange and, last but not least, left terrestrial broadcasting to become the most popular talent now on satellite radio, where millions pay to hear the show that still offends and amuses with it's political satire, prank calls, more candid than anywhere else celebrity interviews and cast of characters who make up a very broad spectrum of voices in society. "Private Parts" is one of the few comedies that's funnier each time I watch it. The showdown Stern has with his nemesis at WnnnnNBC is one of the ten most hilarious scenes in history as far as I'm concerned. Paul Giamatti is so good as Kenny (or "Pig Vomit"), you'll practically throw up with laughter when he's on screen. Not so pleasant moments before Howard found his true voice are recreated, as are classics like "The Match Game" and "Fartman" (with friend of the show John Stamos filling in for Luke Perry at the MTV appearance). Radio has it's share of popular talent, but Stern has really achieved something unique with his approach. His phenomenon doesn't come around once a generation. Just once, period!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost completely made up history. Why?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    headly66
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fact that this was directed by a woman turned what might have been a much raunchier film into a blandish comedy but Howard was probably looking to reach a broader audience at the time. It is a good movie, not great, but mostly a disappointment for Stern fans as it is not a real history of the events that took place. Here's some fake movie history: Luke Perry introduced Howard as Fartman on MTV not John Stamos. Why would Dee Snider make a face at Howard behind stage when they were great friends at the time. Oh by the way, Dee was not even there as Twisted Sister had broke up in 1988, the event was in Sept. of 1992. Neither was Flavor Flav, Ozzy, Blues Traveler, MC Hammer, or Tiny Tim, etc, etc. Also no one treated Howard that way back stage, he was very famous at the time, had a #1 book and many of the same powers to help or hurt peoples careers. There is no song called "Mama Look-A Boo Boo" from the time Howard was driving with his father. The dirty puppet show at the old folks home never happened. They leave out the fact that Howard was doing bits for years before he "discovered himself" and don't show any of the many people he worked with on air over the years in college and up to NBC. Howard was not playing punk music like the Ramones at WRNW, in fact he played mostly disco. Howard did not meet Fred in his first minute on the air at WCCC. Howard was never in a bathtub with Fred and an actress. Howard didn't have long hair until the very end of his time with WNBC. Howard did not quit on the air at WWWW when they went country. Robin did not meet Howard on the air, they had both received tapes of each other prior to meeting and then decided to work together. The on the air orgasm did not happen that way, it was with a small radio and sounded completely different. Technically it could not be done as shown in the movie. Robin was not with Howard at the beginning at NBC as she quit in DC taking a straight news job after not being picked up by WNBC and blamed Howard for abandoning her. So the first night tryout for the Stern crew could never have happened with her. It also did not sound that way, they did not say sperm and gargle with it. Their programmers nickname was pig virus, not pig vomit, why they changed this I have no clue. The prevalence of breast implants is ridiculous in this movie, (girl on phone, girl in studio, girls in lesbian dream) this was not very common in the early 80's especially for women not in the porn or movie industry. In the last scene at the concert (the film says July 27th 1985), Howard looked nothing like this in 1985 nor did Robin. Phil Rudd was not in AC/DC at the time, nor did Stern's wife go into labor. His kids were born in 1983, 1986 and 1993. She wasn't even pregnant at the time, their next child wouldn't be born until May 9, 1986. I really have no problem with movies condensing or changing things a little because of time restraints or creativity but please, when you actually make things up that never happened its a little disconcerting. I mean why don't we just make a movie where Jesus is at the Battle of Waterloo, or John Lennon gets shot on a space ship or George Washington meets Hitler. The sad thing is this happens all the time and people believe its true and take it as history, just look at Braveheart where historical characters are in the same time period even though they lived 200 years apart. Its just sad and stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bonafide comedy classic from the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Superunknovvn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember watching this movie at the cinema when it came out. Originally me and my friend had wanted to go see "Men In Black", but it was sold out. What a shame! So, we decided to see this other flick that I had heard about in a smaller cinema. It was one of the luckiest decisions I've ever made at the movies. "Private Parts" is a funny, politically incorrect tongue-in-cheek biography of the life of Howard Stern, self-proclaimed King Of All Media. Having never heard Stern's show I can only guess that this telling of the events doesn't have too much to do with reality, but that's not really what's important. The movie is entertaining and endlessly quotable. "Private Parts" is the perfect movie for a light hearted evening. Something that cannot be said about "Man In Black".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stern is good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a long term listener of Howard Stern I was satisfied with the adaptation of the book to the big screen. Betty Thomas was smart enough to allow Howard be himself. It works because Stern is not really acting. Having heard the actual tapes of his father berating him as a kid, seeing Richard Portnow as Ben, was dead on accurate and funny as hell. The other highlight is Paul Giamatti as the program director called pig vomit, who is hired to control Stern's free wheeling and often vulgar on air persona. At one point the self proclaimed king of all media is subjected to a lecture on the proper way of announcing wnbc with a prolonged and exaggerated W "NNNNNNNBC;" it is exactly as it happened because I actually heard the broadcast and the constant battles between Howie and the management at the now defunct radio station. Previous to the WNBC job, we see the struggle from college radio to Briarcliff, NY to Hartford, Ct. to Detroit and the last stop before the Big Apple is Washington, D.C. It is a ride filled with odd ball characters, nude women and people behaving badly, all for the ratings, and it works due to Stern's ability to communicate at the level of a regular guy. The film is well made and should be entertaining even for non listeners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Free speech all the way! Also, I once got to know the woman who played Kenny's wife.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Betty Thomas's "Private Parts" came out, I had only loosely heard of Howard Stern, and usually in a negative context. But the movie really opened my eyes. It turns out that beyond his sometimes shocking radio content, it's all about free speech. Stern may pull some of the grossest stunts on air, but he's just showing what the First Amendment is all about. Like Lenny Bruce, George Carlin, Larry Flynt, John Waters, and the Farrelly Brothers, Stern always goes for the funniest shock value. And the movie does a great job showing that. And yes, it's true, I once got to know Aimee Luzier, who played Pig Vomit's wife. She was the assistant in a history/literature class that I took in high school.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An honest biopic work of art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern is an acquired taste for the diverse and eclectic. Never listening to his radio show, but an avid listener of scattered clips on the internet, I felt Private Parts could give me the proper introduction the man I was looking for. After all, the man has been a radio icon for many years and an FCC bandit for just as long. Like him or not, Stern has changed the face of radio. He has revolutionized the definition of "talk radio." I can't stress enough that I love talk radio. I find it to be not only relaxed but an insightful way to collect information on certain, gray topics. I used to religiously listen to DreX in the Morning, a Chicago-based radio show on WKSC-FM. Once he was gone at the end of 2010 so was I. I couldn't imagine not having him on my radio every morning before I ship myself off for my daily grind. Then in March I quickly turned over to Eddie and Jobo on WJMK-FM. To this day that's my cup of coffee in the morning. Stern has been more controversial than all of three of those men combined. He threatens the very patience of the FCC, and has pretty much thrown caution and restrictions to the wind as he sits in front of the mic and speaks his mind on whatever he wants. Through various warnings and threats made from his station and the FCC, all of which have been dismissed by him, it's pretty clear that as long as there are faithful listeners, Stern isn't concerned with who he offends or what he is faced with. The movie chronicles his life starting at a very young age where we see Stern's father makes an exercise out of verbally abusing his son. This may have contributed to Stern being a very closed book. Not to mention the fact he went to an all black high school, which only made his differences stand out. As years go by, and because of his father's occupation in radio, Stern develops a passion for the airwaves. This is an awkward and unexpected choice from someone who cruised through high school saying almost nothing. The thought of him pioneering a genre of talk radio which focused more on humor than news was not even present at the time because of his very shy nature. After hits and misses at different radio shows, Stern is finally hired by WNBC in New York City where he would wind up in numerous arguments with his station manager nicknamed Pig Vomit (played very well by Paul Giamatti). Stern's run at WNBC in the eighties was where he gained his most popularity and notoriety. After tirelessly working throughout college on their own brand-name radio and at a number of dead end jobs, he finally got the break he deserved. If you can look past his crude, vulgar, shameless persona there lies a sweet, gentle, hilarious side to him. That may have been added since Hollywood is notorious for factoring in little clich&eacute;s into biopics, but since Stern rejected many, many scripts before settling on this one I assume this one got it to almost pin-point accuracy. I forgot to mention that Stern married the beautiful Alison (McCormack) in 1978 after dating her prolifically throughout his run at WRNR. Alison was the first woman who ever gave Stern the time of day. But Stern makes it very clear being married to him is not an easy task. Stern is notorious for releasing private affairs with his wife over the air, which is what lead to their divorce about four years after this film was made. Private Parts is a provocative look at talk radio and where it was and now is because of Howard Stern. Sometimes it appears as if it is glossing over some events and instances that might have happened during Stern's long run. Surely he had to be suspended a few times, and maybe some of the fights with his wife lead to his expulsion from the house for a few days. But the movie doesn't dive into that as much as it looks at Stern's mark on the radio. Which is what it should look at it. It rarely simplifies the story, and comes out to be a very honest biopic work of art. Starring: Howard Stern, Robin Quivers, Fred Norris, Mary McCormack, and Paul Giamatti. Directed by: Betty Thomas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific Comedy with a (Gasp) Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Private Parts (1997) *** 1/2 (out of 4) Taken from Howard Stern's best selling autobiography, this film follows Sterns early years as a loser in high school all the way up to becoming the king of radio in New York City. While the majority of the film deals with his struggle of making it on the radio, we also get the story of his relationship with wife Alison (Mary McCormack). No matter what you think of Stern I think anyone will be able to enjoy this film and in fact I still remember going to see it when it was first released with someone who hated the guy with a passion and even they walked out liking him. I think a large portion of the film and the original book wanted to make people understand Stern and there's no question that the film is a bit one-sided but in the end it accomplishes what it set out to do and that is show people the real person. The film is full of raunchy humor including a great take-off on the Match Game and another terrific sequence with Stern having sex with a woman over the radio and while these comic bits are terrific what really makes the film so memorable is its charm. The film is incredibly charming and one can't help but really fall in love with Stern's character and especially the way he's determined not to stop until he reaches the top. I think the film is rather remarkable in that it can be downright filthy one moment but then sweet the next. It's really hard to mix those two things but the screenplay and director Thomas really make it work and by doing so they've created a rather special movie that keeps getting better with each new viewing. It should come as no shock but Stern makes for a terrific actor even though he's playing himself. I've heard many great actors say that playing themselves would be a very difficult thing to do but Stern handles it with no troubles as does his supporting mates Robin Quivers, Fred Norris and Jackie Martling. McCormack is also extremely good as the wife and her chemistry with Stern comes off as real and they make you feel as if you're watching a real couple. Even better is Paul Giamatti who plays Kenny, aka Pig Vomit, the man who tries to tame Stern when he gets to NBC. The fire and passion that Giamatti brings to the role is rather remarkable to watch and you can't help but laugh at loud when he and Stern are going at it. PRIVATE PARKS is a hilarious movie and a touching one that tells the rise of Stern with loving care and in the end it really delivers everything you'd want it to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Private Parts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw a clip of this featured in one of those Channel 4 countdowns, I didn't acknowledge that the film was based on reality, so I was very keen, from director Betty Thomas (Doctor Dolittle, John Tucker Must Die). Basically, Howard Stern always wanted to be a disc jockey, working for a radio station, playing popular music and speaking his mind, and during the 1970's it was his goal to do it. Howard started out in college with not a lot of zing in his approach and hardly any personality on the Mic, but then he got his big break on a Detroit radio station. It is soon after starting out that Howard has a snap, his glasses and moustache come off, and his more vibrant and opinionated personality is brought out. He is joined on his own show with news anchor Robin Quivers, who shares his unorthodox approach to expressing his opinions, talking whatever he wants to, and doing whatever he can to get high ratings. The radio heads don't share all of Howard's ideas of what the listeners want, but his hilarious off-the-wall antics are getting the listeners, to the point where he is the most famous disc jockey on air. After a little misunderstanding between Howard and wife Alison (Mary McCormack) about her baby miscarriage, where he joked about it, and her forgiving him, Howard gains a bigger opportunity with NBC in New York. Howard also has the good fortune to have Alison pregnant again, but with his new bosses not understanding how he got such high ratings, it is only after taking him on board that they experience it. It is the job of Kenny Rushton (Paul Giamatti) and one or two other crew members to keep Howard in line, or force him to quit with the limitations of what he can do on radio, but this won't stop him. He has many troubles on and off Mic, high demands, including having Robin with him once again, and of course another hit with being the number one disc jockey again, but he also stays true to his family. Also starring Fred Norris, Gary Dell'Abate, Jackie Martling, Carol Alt as Gloria, Richard Portnow as Ben Stern, Allison Janney as Dee Dee, Jenna Jameson as Mandy, Ozzy Osbourne, Mia Farrow, David Letterman, AC-DC (including Brian Johnson, Iggy Pop and Wendy Whoppers as Big-Breasted Woman. Stern completely steals the show with his madcap radio hosting, and the real people playing their own parts keeps the momentum high. The best sequence is Stern using his voice with a stripping woman turning the bass up high on her speakers to have vibration style sex, it was number 28 on The 100 Greatest Funny Moments. A hilarious shock jock, a cast of well-knowns as themselves and in cameos, sexually explicit radio broadcasts, the story is based on facts, this is everything you wants in a biographical comedy. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific and very funny biopic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern has only ever been a vaguely familiar figure here in the UK. When Private Parts first came out I knew who he was and had seen a short segment about him on TV. My opinion of him was not good. From the small amount of information I had, he seemed like a completely unlikeable malicious idiot with an annoying haircut. So I certainly had some preconceptions about the man before seeing this film. After seeing it, I had to admit that, like most things in life, the truth is much more complex. In actual fact I came away from Private Parts liking and respecting Mr Stern quite a bit. Quite a turn-around. Sometimes with a biopic it's good to have very little knowledge of the subject. The trajectory of the story is then more surprising to you. This was true for me with Private Parts, as I had no real clue about Howard Stern's rise to fame. However, what surprised me the most was Stern's character. He was not afraid to paint himself as pathetic, and the honesty of this approach is the key to why it's such a compelling film. Some people have commented that this movie is self-serving and that Stern portrays himself as some kind of misunderstood innocent. While I can't definitively say if this is true or not, my gut feeling is that he depicts himself in a fairly honest way. Many times he shows himself to be seriously uncool and pathetic. And because his whole shtick is about not holding back and saying what he thinks, you can't help but feel that this ethos must apply to the movie too, and this is most probably what he is like. The film is often very funny, and I can't really often say this for most comedies. It mixes standard biopic drama with some inventive comedy moments that recall the style of Woody Allen; although an admittedly lower-brow Woody Allen with a fair smattering of naked women. But still, it's in that general ball-park. Stern is very good as, well, Stern. I think it's quite a reasonable achievement to be fair as it's actually not always that easy playing yourself. Take a look at a few of the cameo appearances in some of the episodes of Extras for proof of this bizarre truth. Anyway, he is a compelling central character, whose underlying personality seems to be very decent. Paul Giamatti is the other actor who stands out. His portrayal of Pig Vomit is hilarious. This is a great comic biopic. You certainly do not need to be familiar with its lead character to enjoy it, as it's a very well delivered and funny story. The humour never feels forced either, it just flows into the narrative. I am surprised I like Private Parts so much. It really changed my view of Howard Stern. Except I still think he has an annoying haircut.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a reminder
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mino
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was watching this one recently with friends and I realized I was the only one being amused. I just realized why. This is Scarface, not a comedy, but a dramatic account of foul taste with balls taking over. It's Tony Montana p***ing everything in his path. It's the logical outcome when ratings decide who stays and who leaves. But why do I find it amusing? Well, I don't, really. I guess it was just the anticipation of Giamatti's performance I had forgotten was so short spanned. I write the comment just in case I get the urge to watch this again in the future.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The King of all media is also the court jester
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nixskits
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern is a polarizing figure in entertainment, probably the most hated and loved figure of the last half century, depending on whether you are an opponent or a fan of his. As the stats are laid out in this film, Stern's enemies are just as, if not more, likely to be found listening to his show. The program he hosts is like millions of people's cup of coffee in the morning. This room rocker of a movie is the first chapter in the big screen project of his life, showing what a crazy thirty plus years it was. Rabid fans want another instalment showing what has developed since the mid 80's when "Private Parts" ends. He's since been divorced, remarried, seen his daughters become young adults, had his head writer Jackie "The Joke Man" Martling walk away and replaced by stand up comic Artie Lange and, last but not least, left terrestrial broadcasting to become the most popular talent now on satellite radio, where millions pay to hear the show that still offends and amuses with it's political satire, prank calls, more candid than anywhere else celebrity interviews and cast of characters who make up a very broad spectrum of voices in society. "Private Parts" is one of the few comedies that's funnier each time I watch it. The showdown Stern has with his nemesis at WnnnnNBC is one of the ten most hilarious scenes in history as far as I'm concerned. Paul Giamatti is so good as Kenny (or "Pig Vomit"), you'll practically throw up with laughter when he's on screen. Not so pleasant moments before Howard found his true voice are recreated, as are classics like "The Match Game" and "Fartman" (with friend of the show John Stamos filling in for Luke Perry at the MTV appearance). Radio has it's share of popular talent, but Stern has really achieved something unique with his approach. His phenomenon doesn't come around once a generation. Just once, period!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost completely made up history. Why?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    headly66
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fact that this was directed by a woman turned what might have been a much raunchier film into a blandish comedy but Howard was probably looking to reach a broader audience at the time. It is a good movie, not great, but mostly a disappointment for Stern fans as it is not a real history of the events that took place. Here's some fake movie history: Luke Perry introduced Howard as Fartman on MTV not John Stamos. Why would Dee Snider make a face at Howard behind stage when they were great friends at the time. Oh by the way, Dee was not even there as Twisted Sister had broke up in 1988, the event was in Sept. of 1992. Neither was Flavor Flav, Ozzy, Blues Traveler, MC Hammer, or Tiny Tim, etc, etc. Also no one treated Howard that way back stage, he was very famous at the time, had a #1 book and many of the same powers to help or hurt peoples careers. There is no song called "Mama Look-A Boo Boo" from the time Howard was driving with his father. The dirty puppet show at the old folks home never happened. They leave out the fact that Howard was doing bits for years before he "discovered himself" and don't show any of the many people he worked with on air over the years in college and up to NBC. Howard was not playing punk music like the Ramones at WRNW, in fact he played mostly disco. Howard did not meet Fred in his first minute on the air at WCCC. Howard was never in a bathtub with Fred and an actress. Howard didn't have long hair until the very end of his time with WNBC. Howard did not quit on the air at WWWW when they went country. Robin did not meet Howard on the air, they had both received tapes of each other prior to meeting and then decided to work together. The on the air orgasm did not happen that way, it was with a small radio and sounded completely different. Technically it could not be done as shown in the movie. Robin was not with Howard at the beginning at NBC as she quit in DC taking a straight news job after not being picked up by WNBC and blamed Howard for abandoning her. So the first night tryout for the Stern crew could never have happened with her. It also did not sound that way, they did not say sperm and gargle with it. Their programmers nickname was pig virus, not pig vomit, why they changed this I have no clue. The prevalence of breast implants is ridiculous in this movie, (girl on phone, girl in studio, girls in lesbian dream) this was not very common in the early 80's especially for women not in the porn or movie industry. In the last scene at the concert (the film says July 27th 1985), Howard looked nothing like this in 1985 nor did Robin. Phil Rudd was not in AC/DC at the time, nor did Stern's wife go into labor. His kids were born in 1983, 1986 and 1993. She wasn't even pregnant at the time, their next child wouldn't be born until May 9, 1986. I really have no problem with movies condensing or changing things a little because of time restraints or creativity but please, when you actually make things up that never happened its a little disconcerting. I mean why don't we just make a movie where Jesus is at the Battle of Waterloo, or John Lennon gets shot on a space ship or George Washington meets Hitler. The sad thing is this happens all the time and people believe its true and take it as history, just look at Braveheart where historical characters are in the same time period even though they lived 200 years apart. Its just sad and stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bonafide comedy classic from the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Superunknovvn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember watching this movie at the cinema when it came out. Originally me and my friend had wanted to go see "Men In Black", but it was sold out. What a shame! So, we decided to see this other flick that I had heard about in a smaller cinema. It was one of the luckiest decisions I've ever made at the movies. "Private Parts" is a funny, politically incorrect tongue-in-cheek biography of the life of Howard Stern, self-proclaimed King Of All Media. Having never heard Stern's show I can only guess that this telling of the events doesn't have too much to do with reality, but that's not really what's important. The movie is entertaining and endlessly quotable. "Private Parts" is the perfect movie for a light hearted evening. Something that cannot be said about "Man In Black".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stern is good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a long term listener of Howard Stern I was satisfied with the adaptation of the book to the big screen. Betty Thomas was smart enough to allow Howard be himself. It works because Stern is not really acting. Having heard the actual tapes of his father berating him as a kid, seeing Richard Portnow as Ben, was dead on accurate and funny as hell. The other highlight is Paul Giamatti as the program director called pig vomit, who is hired to control Stern's free wheeling and often vulgar on air persona. At one point the self proclaimed king of all media is subjected to a lecture on the proper way of announcing wnbc with a prolonged and exaggerated W "NNNNNNNBC;" it is exactly as it happened because I actually heard the broadcast and the constant battles between Howie and the management at the now defunct radio station. Previous to the WNBC job, we see the struggle from college radio to Briarcliff, NY to Hartford, Ct. to Detroit and the last stop before the Big Apple is Washington, D.C. It is a ride filled with odd ball characters, nude women and people behaving badly, all for the ratings, and it works due to Stern's ability to communicate at the level of a regular guy. The film is well made and should be entertaining even for non listeners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Free speech all the way! Also, I once got to know the woman who played Kenny's wife.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Betty Thomas's "Private Parts" came out, I had only loosely heard of Howard Stern, and usually in a negative context. But the movie really opened my eyes. It turns out that beyond his sometimes shocking radio content, it's all about free speech. Stern may pull some of the grossest stunts on air, but he's just showing what the First Amendment is all about. Like Lenny Bruce, George Carlin, Larry Flynt, John Waters, and the Farrelly Brothers, Stern always goes for the funniest shock value. And the movie does a great job showing that. And yes, it's true, I once got to know Aimee Luzier, who played Pig Vomit's wife. She was the assistant in a history/literature class that I took in high school.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An honest biopic work of art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern is an acquired taste for the diverse and eclectic. Never listening to his radio show, but an avid listener of scattered clips on the internet, I felt Private Parts could give me the proper introduction the man I was looking for. After all, the man has been a radio icon for many years and an FCC bandit for just as long. Like him or not, Stern has changed the face of radio. He has revolutionized the definition of "talk radio." I can't stress enough that I love talk radio. I find it to be not only relaxed but an insightful way to collect information on certain, gray topics. I used to religiously listen to DreX in the Morning, a Chicago-based radio show on WKSC-FM. Once he was gone at the end of 2010 so was I. I couldn't imagine not having him on my radio every morning before I ship myself off for my daily grind. Then in March I quickly turned over to Eddie and Jobo on WJMK-FM. To this day that's my cup of coffee in the morning. Stern has been more controversial than all of three of those men combined. He threatens the very patience of the FCC, and has pretty much thrown caution and restrictions to the wind as he sits in front of the mic and speaks his mind on whatever he wants. Through various warnings and threats made from his station and the FCC, all of which have been dismissed by him, it's pretty clear that as long as there are faithful listeners, Stern isn't concerned with who he offends or what he is faced with. The movie chronicles his life starting at a very young age where we see Stern's father makes an exercise out of verbally abusing his son. This may have contributed to Stern being a very closed book. Not to mention the fact he went to an all black high school, which only made his differences stand out. As years go by, and because of his father's occupation in radio, Stern develops a passion for the airwaves. This is an awkward and unexpected choice from someone who cruised through high school saying almost nothing. The thought of him pioneering a genre of talk radio which focused more on humor than news was not even present at the time because of his very shy nature. After hits and misses at different radio shows, Stern is finally hired by WNBC in New York City where he would wind up in numerous arguments with his station manager nicknamed Pig Vomit (played very well by Paul Giamatti). Stern's run at WNBC in the eighties was where he gained his most popularity and notoriety. After tirelessly working throughout college on their own brand-name radio and at a number of dead end jobs, he finally got the break he deserved. If you can look past his crude, vulgar, shameless persona there lies a sweet, gentle, hilarious side to him. That may have been added since Hollywood is notorious for factoring in little clich&eacute;s into biopics, but since Stern rejected many, many scripts before settling on this one I assume this one got it to almost pin-point accuracy. I forgot to mention that Stern married the beautiful Alison (McCormack) in 1978 after dating her prolifically throughout his run at WRNR. Alison was the first woman who ever gave Stern the time of day. But Stern makes it very clear being married to him is not an easy task. Stern is notorious for releasing private affairs with his wife over the air, which is what lead to their divorce about four years after this film was made. Private Parts is a provocative look at talk radio and where it was and now is because of Howard Stern. Sometimes it appears as if it is glossing over some events and instances that might have happened during Stern's long run. Surely he had to be suspended a few times, and maybe some of the fights with his wife lead to his expulsion from the house for a few days. But the movie doesn't dive into that as much as it looks at Stern's mark on the radio. Which is what it should look at it. It rarely simplifies the story, and comes out to be a very honest biopic work of art. Starring: Howard Stern, Robin Quivers, Fred Norris, Mary McCormack, and Paul Giamatti. Directed by: Betty Thomas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific Comedy with a (Gasp) Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Private Parts (1997) *** 1/2 (out of 4) Taken from Howard Stern's best selling autobiography, this film follows Sterns early years as a loser in high school all the way up to becoming the king of radio in New York City. While the majority of the film deals with his struggle of making it on the radio, we also get the story of his relationship with wife Alison (Mary McCormack). No matter what you think of Stern I think anyone will be able to enjoy this film and in fact I still remember going to see it when it was first released with someone who hated the guy with a passion and even they walked out liking him. I think a large portion of the film and the original book wanted to make people understand Stern and there's no question that the film is a bit one-sided but in the end it accomplishes what it set out to do and that is show people the real person. The film is full of raunchy humor including a great take-off on the Match Game and another terrific sequence with Stern having sex with a woman over the radio and while these comic bits are terrific what really makes the film so memorable is its charm. The film is incredibly charming and one can't help but really fall in love with Stern's character and especially the way he's determined not to stop until he reaches the top. I think the film is rather remarkable in that it can be downright filthy one moment but then sweet the next. It's really hard to mix those two things but the screenplay and director Thomas really make it work and by doing so they've created a rather special movie that keeps getting better with each new viewing. It should come as no shock but Stern makes for a terrific actor even though he's playing himself. I've heard many great actors say that playing themselves would be a very difficult thing to do but Stern handles it with no troubles as does his supporting mates Robin Quivers, Fred Norris and Jackie Martling. McCormack is also extremely good as the wife and her chemistry with Stern comes off as real and they make you feel as if you're watching a real couple. Even better is Paul Giamatti who plays Kenny, aka Pig Vomit, the man who tries to tame Stern when he gets to NBC. The fire and passion that Giamatti brings to the role is rather remarkable to watch and you can't help but laugh at loud when he and Stern are going at it. PRIVATE PARKS is a hilarious movie and a touching one that tells the rise of Stern with loving care and in the end it really delivers everything you'd want it to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Private Parts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw a clip of this featured in one of those Channel 4 countdowns, I didn't acknowledge that the film was based on reality, so I was very keen, from director Betty Thomas (Doctor Dolittle, John Tucker Must Die). Basically, Howard Stern always wanted to be a disc jockey, working for a radio station, playing popular music and speaking his mind, and during the 1970's it was his goal to do it. Howard started out in college with not a lot of zing in his approach and hardly any personality on the Mic, but then he got his big break on a Detroit radio station. It is soon after starting out that Howard has a snap, his glasses and moustache come off, and his more vibrant and opinionated personality is brought out. He is joined on his own show with news anchor Robin Quivers, who shares his unorthodox approach to expressing his opinions, talking whatever he wants to, and doing whatever he can to get high ratings. The radio heads don't share all of Howard's ideas of what the listeners want, but his hilarious off-the-wall antics are getting the listeners, to the point where he is the most famous disc jockey on air. After a little misunderstanding between Howard and wife Alison (Mary McCormack) about her baby miscarriage, where he joked about it, and her forgiving him, Howard gains a bigger opportunity with NBC in New York. Howard also has the good fortune to have Alison pregnant again, but with his new bosses not understanding how he got such high ratings, it is only after taking him on board that they experience it. It is the job of Kenny Rushton (Paul Giamatti) and one or two other crew members to keep Howard in line, or force him to quit with the limitations of what he can do on radio, but this won't stop him. He has many troubles on and off Mic, high demands, including having Robin with him once again, and of course another hit with being the number one disc jockey again, but he also stays true to his family. Also starring Fred Norris, Gary Dell'Abate, Jackie Martling, Carol Alt as Gloria, Richard Portnow as Ben Stern, Allison Janney as Dee Dee, Jenna Jameson as Mandy, Ozzy Osbourne, Mia Farrow, David Letterman, AC-DC (including Brian Johnson, Iggy Pop and Wendy Whoppers as Big-Breasted Woman. Stern completely steals the show with his madcap radio hosting, and the real people playing their own parts keeps the momentum high. The best sequence is Stern using his voice with a stripping woman turning the bass up high on her speakers to have vibration style sex, it was number 28 on The 100 Greatest Funny Moments. A hilarious shock jock, a cast of well-knowns as themselves and in cameos, sexually explicit radio broadcasts, the story is based on facts, this is everything you wants in a biographical comedy. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific and very funny biopic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern has only ever been a vaguely familiar figure here in the UK. When Private Parts first came out I knew who he was and had seen a short segment about him on TV. My opinion of him was not good. From the small amount of information I had, he seemed like a completely unlikeable malicious idiot with an annoying haircut. So I certainly had some preconceptions about the man before seeing this film. After seeing it, I had to admit that, like most things in life, the truth is much more complex. In actual fact I came away from Private Parts liking and respecting Mr Stern quite a bit. Quite a turn-around. Sometimes with a biopic it's good to have very little knowledge of the subject. The trajectory of the story is then more surprising to you. This was true for me with Private Parts, as I had no real clue about Howard Stern's rise to fame. However, what surprised me the most was Stern's character. He was not afraid to paint himself as pathetic, and the honesty of this approach is the key to why it's such a compelling film. Some people have commented that this movie is self-serving and that Stern portrays himself as some kind of misunderstood innocent. While I can't definitively say if this is true or not, my gut feeling is that he depicts himself in a fairly honest way. Many times he shows himself to be seriously uncool and pathetic. And because his whole shtick is about not holding back and saying what he thinks, you can't help but feel that this ethos must apply to the movie too, and this is most probably what he is like. The film is often very funny, and I can't really often say this for most comedies. It mixes standard biopic drama with some inventive comedy moments that recall the style of Woody Allen; although an admittedly lower-brow Woody Allen with a fair smattering of naked women. But still, it's in that general ball-park. Stern is very good as, well, Stern. I think it's quite a reasonable achievement to be fair as it's actually not always that easy playing yourself. Take a look at a few of the cameo appearances in some of the episodes of Extras for proof of this bizarre truth. Anyway, he is a compelling central character, whose underlying personality seems to be very decent. Paul Giamatti is the other actor who stands out. His portrayal of Pig Vomit is hilarious. This is a great comic biopic. You certainly do not need to be familiar with its lead character to enjoy it, as it's a very well delivered and funny story. The humour never feels forced either, it just flows into the narrative. I am surprised I like Private Parts so much. It really changed my view of Howard Stern. Except I still think he has an annoying haircut.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a reminder
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mino
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was watching this one recently with friends and I realized I was the only one being amused. I just realized why. This is Scarface, not a comedy, but a dramatic account of foul taste with balls taking over. It's Tony Montana p***ing everything in his path. It's the logical outcome when ratings decide who stays and who leaves. But why do I find it amusing? Well, I don't, really. I guess it was just the anticipation of Giamatti's performance I had forgotten was so short spanned. I write the comment just in case I get the urge to watch this again in the future.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The King of all media is also the court jester
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nixskits
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern is a polarizing figure in entertainment, probably the most hated and loved figure of the last half century, depending on whether you are an opponent or a fan of his. As the stats are laid out in this film, Stern's enemies are just as, if not more, likely to be found listening to his show. The program he hosts is like millions of people's cup of coffee in the morning. This room rocker of a movie is the first chapter in the big screen project of his life, showing what a crazy thirty plus years it was. Rabid fans want another instalment showing what has developed since the mid 80's when "Private Parts" ends. He's since been divorced, remarried, seen his daughters become young adults, had his head writer Jackie "The Joke Man" Martling walk away and replaced by stand up comic Artie Lange and, last but not least, left terrestrial broadcasting to become the most popular talent now on satellite radio, where millions pay to hear the show that still offends and amuses with it's political satire, prank calls, more candid than anywhere else celebrity interviews and cast of characters who make up a very broad spectrum of voices in society. "Private Parts" is one of the few comedies that's funnier each time I watch it. The showdown Stern has with his nemesis at WnnnnNBC is one of the ten most hilarious scenes in history as far as I'm concerned. Paul Giamatti is so good as Kenny (or "Pig Vomit"), you'll practically throw up with laughter when he's on screen. Not so pleasant moments before Howard found his true voice are recreated, as are classics like "The Match Game" and "Fartman" (with friend of the show John Stamos filling in for Luke Perry at the MTV appearance). Radio has it's share of popular talent, but Stern has really achieved something unique with his approach. His phenomenon doesn't come around once a generation. Just once, period!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost completely made up history. Why?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    headly66
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fact that this was directed by a woman turned what might have been a much raunchier film into a blandish comedy but Howard was probably looking to reach a broader audience at the time. It is a good movie, not great, but mostly a disappointment for Stern fans as it is not a real history of the events that took place. Here's some fake movie history: Luke Perry introduced Howard as Fartman on MTV not John Stamos. Why would Dee Snider make a face at Howard behind stage when they were great friends at the time. Oh by the way, Dee was not even there as Twisted Sister had broke up in 1988, the event was in Sept. of 1992. Neither was Flavor Flav, Ozzy, Blues Traveler, MC Hammer, or Tiny Tim, etc, etc. Also no one treated Howard that way back stage, he was very famous at the time, had a #1 book and many of the same powers to help or hurt peoples careers. There is no song called "Mama Look-A Boo Boo" from the time Howard was driving with his father. The dirty puppet show at the old folks home never happened. They leave out the fact that Howard was doing bits for years before he "discovered himself" and don't show any of the many people he worked with on air over the years in college and up to NBC. Howard was not playing punk music like the Ramones at WRNW, in fact he played mostly disco. Howard did not meet Fred in his first minute on the air at WCCC. Howard was never in a bathtub with Fred and an actress. Howard didn't have long hair until the very end of his time with WNBC. Howard did not quit on the air at WWWW when they went country. Robin did not meet Howard on the air, they had both received tapes of each other prior to meeting and then decided to work together. The on the air orgasm did not happen that way, it was with a small radio and sounded completely different. Technically it could not be done as shown in the movie. Robin was not with Howard at the beginning at NBC as she quit in DC taking a straight news job after not being picked up by WNBC and blamed Howard for abandoning her. So the first night tryout for the Stern crew could never have happened with her. It also did not sound that way, they did not say sperm and gargle with it. Their programmers nickname was pig virus, not pig vomit, why they changed this I have no clue. The prevalence of breast implants is ridiculous in this movie, (girl on phone, girl in studio, girls in lesbian dream) this was not very common in the early 80's especially for women not in the porn or movie industry. In the last scene at the concert (the film says July 27th 1985), Howard looked nothing like this in 1985 nor did Robin. Phil Rudd was not in AC/DC at the time, nor did Stern's wife go into labor. His kids were born in 1983, 1986 and 1993. She wasn't even pregnant at the time, their next child wouldn't be born until May 9, 1986. I really have no problem with movies condensing or changing things a little because of time restraints or creativity but please, when you actually make things up that never happened its a little disconcerting. I mean why don't we just make a movie where Jesus is at the Battle of Waterloo, or John Lennon gets shot on a space ship or George Washington meets Hitler. The sad thing is this happens all the time and people believe its true and take it as history, just look at Braveheart where historical characters are in the same time period even though they lived 200 years apart. Its just sad and stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bonafide comedy classic from the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Superunknovvn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember watching this movie at the cinema when it came out. Originally me and my friend had wanted to go see "Men In Black", but it was sold out. What a shame! So, we decided to see this other flick that I had heard about in a smaller cinema. It was one of the luckiest decisions I've ever made at the movies. "Private Parts" is a funny, politically incorrect tongue-in-cheek biography of the life of Howard Stern, self-proclaimed King Of All Media. Having never heard Stern's show I can only guess that this telling of the events doesn't have too much to do with reality, but that's not really what's important. The movie is entertaining and endlessly quotable. "Private Parts" is the perfect movie for a light hearted evening. Something that cannot be said about "Man In Black".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stern is good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a long term listener of Howard Stern I was satisfied with the adaptation of the book to the big screen. Betty Thomas was smart enough to allow Howard be himself. It works because Stern is not really acting. Having heard the actual tapes of his father berating him as a kid, seeing Richard Portnow as Ben, was dead on accurate and funny as hell. The other highlight is Paul Giamatti as the program director called pig vomit, who is hired to control Stern's free wheeling and often vulgar on air persona. At one point the self proclaimed king of all media is subjected to a lecture on the proper way of announcing wnbc with a prolonged and exaggerated W "NNNNNNNBC;" it is exactly as it happened because I actually heard the broadcast and the constant battles between Howie and the management at the now defunct radio station. Previous to the WNBC job, we see the struggle from college radio to Briarcliff, NY to Hartford, Ct. to Detroit and the last stop before the Big Apple is Washington, D.C. It is a ride filled with odd ball characters, nude women and people behaving badly, all for the ratings, and it works due to Stern's ability to communicate at the level of a regular guy. The film is well made and should be entertaining even for non listeners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Free speech all the way! Also, I once got to know the woman who played Kenny's wife.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Betty Thomas's "Private Parts" came out, I had only loosely heard of Howard Stern, and usually in a negative context. But the movie really opened my eyes. It turns out that beyond his sometimes shocking radio content, it's all about free speech. Stern may pull some of the grossest stunts on air, but he's just showing what the First Amendment is all about. Like Lenny Bruce, George Carlin, Larry Flynt, John Waters, and the Farrelly Brothers, Stern always goes for the funniest shock value. And the movie does a great job showing that. And yes, it's true, I once got to know Aimee Luzier, who played Pig Vomit's wife. She was the assistant in a history/literature class that I took in high school.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An honest biopic work of art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern is an acquired taste for the diverse and eclectic. Never listening to his radio show, but an avid listener of scattered clips on the internet, I felt Private Parts could give me the proper introduction the man I was looking for. After all, the man has been a radio icon for many years and an FCC bandit for just as long. Like him or not, Stern has changed the face of radio. He has revolutionized the definition of "talk radio." I can't stress enough that I love talk radio. I find it to be not only relaxed but an insightful way to collect information on certain, gray topics. I used to religiously listen to DreX in the Morning, a Chicago-based radio show on WKSC-FM. Once he was gone at the end of 2010 so was I. I couldn't imagine not having him on my radio every morning before I ship myself off for my daily grind. Then in March I quickly turned over to Eddie and Jobo on WJMK-FM. To this day that's my cup of coffee in the morning. Stern has been more controversial than all of three of those men combined. He threatens the very patience of the FCC, and has pretty much thrown caution and restrictions to the wind as he sits in front of the mic and speaks his mind on whatever he wants. Through various warnings and threats made from his station and the FCC, all of which have been dismissed by him, it's pretty clear that as long as there are faithful listeners, Stern isn't concerned with who he offends or what he is faced with. The movie chronicles his life starting at a very young age where we see Stern's father makes an exercise out of verbally abusing his son. This may have contributed to Stern being a very closed book. Not to mention the fact he went to an all black high school, which only made his differences stand out. As years go by, and because of his father's occupation in radio, Stern develops a passion for the airwaves. This is an awkward and unexpected choice from someone who cruised through high school saying almost nothing. The thought of him pioneering a genre of talk radio which focused more on humor than news was not even present at the time because of his very shy nature. After hits and misses at different radio shows, Stern is finally hired by WNBC in New York City where he would wind up in numerous arguments with his station manager nicknamed Pig Vomit (played very well by Paul Giamatti). Stern's run at WNBC in the eighties was where he gained his most popularity and notoriety. After tirelessly working throughout college on their own brand-name radio and at a number of dead end jobs, he finally got the break he deserved. If you can look past his crude, vulgar, shameless persona there lies a sweet, gentle, hilarious side to him. That may have been added since Hollywood is notorious for factoring in little clich&eacute;s into biopics, but since Stern rejected many, many scripts before settling on this one I assume this one got it to almost pin-point accuracy. I forgot to mention that Stern married the beautiful Alison (McCormack) in 1978 after dating her prolifically throughout his run at WRNR. Alison was the first woman who ever gave Stern the time of day. But Stern makes it very clear being married to him is not an easy task. Stern is notorious for releasing private affairs with his wife over the air, which is what lead to their divorce about four years after this film was made. Private Parts is a provocative look at talk radio and where it was and now is because of Howard Stern. Sometimes it appears as if it is glossing over some events and instances that might have happened during Stern's long run. Surely he had to be suspended a few times, and maybe some of the fights with his wife lead to his expulsion from the house for a few days. But the movie doesn't dive into that as much as it looks at Stern's mark on the radio. Which is what it should look at it. It rarely simplifies the story, and comes out to be a very honest biopic work of art. Starring: Howard Stern, Robin Quivers, Fred Norris, Mary McCormack, and Paul Giamatti. Directed by: Betty Thomas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific Comedy with a (Gasp) Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Private Parts (1997) *** 1/2 (out of 4) Taken from Howard Stern's best selling autobiography, this film follows Sterns early years as a loser in high school all the way up to becoming the king of radio in New York City. While the majority of the film deals with his struggle of making it on the radio, we also get the story of his relationship with wife Alison (Mary McCormack). No matter what you think of Stern I think anyone will be able to enjoy this film and in fact I still remember going to see it when it was first released with someone who hated the guy with a passion and even they walked out liking him. I think a large portion of the film and the original book wanted to make people understand Stern and there's no question that the film is a bit one-sided but in the end it accomplishes what it set out to do and that is show people the real person. The film is full of raunchy humor including a great take-off on the Match Game and another terrific sequence with Stern having sex with a woman over the radio and while these comic bits are terrific what really makes the film so memorable is its charm. The film is incredibly charming and one can't help but really fall in love with Stern's character and especially the way he's determined not to stop until he reaches the top. I think the film is rather remarkable in that it can be downright filthy one moment but then sweet the next. It's really hard to mix those two things but the screenplay and director Thomas really make it work and by doing so they've created a rather special movie that keeps getting better with each new viewing. It should come as no shock but Stern makes for a terrific actor even though he's playing himself. I've heard many great actors say that playing themselves would be a very difficult thing to do but Stern handles it with no troubles as does his supporting mates Robin Quivers, Fred Norris and Jackie Martling. McCormack is also extremely good as the wife and her chemistry with Stern comes off as real and they make you feel as if you're watching a real couple. Even better is Paul Giamatti who plays Kenny, aka Pig Vomit, the man who tries to tame Stern when he gets to NBC. The fire and passion that Giamatti brings to the role is rather remarkable to watch and you can't help but laugh at loud when he and Stern are going at it. PRIVATE PARKS is a hilarious movie and a touching one that tells the rise of Stern with loving care and in the end it really delivers everything you'd want it to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Private Parts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw a clip of this featured in one of those Channel 4 countdowns, I didn't acknowledge that the film was based on reality, so I was very keen, from director Betty Thomas (Doctor Dolittle, John Tucker Must Die). Basically, Howard Stern always wanted to be a disc jockey, working for a radio station, playing popular music and speaking his mind, and during the 1970's it was his goal to do it. Howard started out in college with not a lot of zing in his approach and hardly any personality on the Mic, but then he got his big break on a Detroit radio station. It is soon after starting out that Howard has a snap, his glasses and moustache come off, and his more vibrant and opinionated personality is brought out. He is joined on his own show with news anchor Robin Quivers, who shares his unorthodox approach to expressing his opinions, talking whatever he wants to, and doing whatever he can to get high ratings. The radio heads don't share all of Howard's ideas of what the listeners want, but his hilarious off-the-wall antics are getting the listeners, to the point where he is the most famous disc jockey on air. After a little misunderstanding between Howard and wife Alison (Mary McCormack) about her baby miscarriage, where he joked about it, and her forgiving him, Howard gains a bigger opportunity with NBC in New York. Howard also has the good fortune to have Alison pregnant again, but with his new bosses not understanding how he got such high ratings, it is only after taking him on board that they experience it. It is the job of Kenny Rushton (Paul Giamatti) and one or two other crew members to keep Howard in line, or force him to quit with the limitations of what he can do on radio, but this won't stop him. He has many troubles on and off Mic, high demands, including having Robin with him once again, and of course another hit with being the number one disc jockey again, but he also stays true to his family. Also starring Fred Norris, Gary Dell'Abate, Jackie Martling, Carol Alt as Gloria, Richard Portnow as Ben Stern, Allison Janney as Dee Dee, Jenna Jameson as Mandy, Ozzy Osbourne, Mia Farrow, David Letterman, AC-DC (including Brian Johnson, Iggy Pop and Wendy Whoppers as Big-Breasted Woman. Stern completely steals the show with his madcap radio hosting, and the real people playing their own parts keeps the momentum high. The best sequence is Stern using his voice with a stripping woman turning the bass up high on her speakers to have vibration style sex, it was number 28 on The 100 Greatest Funny Moments. A hilarious shock jock, a cast of well-knowns as themselves and in cameos, sexually explicit radio broadcasts, the story is based on facts, this is everything you wants in a biographical comedy. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific and very funny biopic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern has only ever been a vaguely familiar figure here in the UK. When Private Parts first came out I knew who he was and had seen a short segment about him on TV. My opinion of him was not good. From the small amount of information I had, he seemed like a completely unlikeable malicious idiot with an annoying haircut. So I certainly had some preconceptions about the man before seeing this film. After seeing it, I had to admit that, like most things in life, the truth is much more complex. In actual fact I came away from Private Parts liking and respecting Mr Stern quite a bit. Quite a turn-around. Sometimes with a biopic it's good to have very little knowledge of the subject. The trajectory of the story is then more surprising to you. This was true for me with Private Parts, as I had no real clue about Howard Stern's rise to fame. However, what surprised me the most was Stern's character. He was not afraid to paint himself as pathetic, and the honesty of this approach is the key to why it's such a compelling film. Some people have commented that this movie is self-serving and that Stern portrays himself as some kind of misunderstood innocent. While I can't definitively say if this is true or not, my gut feeling is that he depicts himself in a fairly honest way. Many times he shows himself to be seriously uncool and pathetic. And because his whole shtick is about not holding back and saying what he thinks, you can't help but feel that this ethos must apply to the movie too, and this is most probably what he is like. The film is often very funny, and I can't really often say this for most comedies. It mixes standard biopic drama with some inventive comedy moments that recall the style of Woody Allen; although an admittedly lower-brow Woody Allen with a fair smattering of naked women. But still, it's in that general ball-park. Stern is very good as, well, Stern. I think it's quite a reasonable achievement to be fair as it's actually not always that easy playing yourself. Take a look at a few of the cameo appearances in some of the episodes of Extras for proof of this bizarre truth. Anyway, he is a compelling central character, whose underlying personality seems to be very decent. Paul Giamatti is the other actor who stands out. His portrayal of Pig Vomit is hilarious. This is a great comic biopic. You certainly do not need to be familiar with its lead character to enjoy it, as it's a very well delivered and funny story. The humour never feels forced either, it just flows into the narrative. I am surprised I like Private Parts so much. It really changed my view of Howard Stern. Except I still think he has an annoying haircut.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a reminder
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mino
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was watching this one recently with friends and I realized I was the only one being amused. I just realized why. This is Scarface, not a comedy, but a dramatic account of foul taste with balls taking over. It's Tony Montana p***ing everything in his path. It's the logical outcome when ratings decide who stays and who leaves. But why do I find it amusing? Well, I don't, really. I guess it was just the anticipation of Giamatti's performance I had forgotten was so short spanned. I write the comment just in case I get the urge to watch this again in the future.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The King of all media is also the court jester
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nixskits
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern is a polarizing figure in entertainment, probably the most hated and loved figure of the last half century, depending on whether you are an opponent or a fan of his. As the stats are laid out in this film, Stern's enemies are just as, if not more, likely to be found listening to his show. The program he hosts is like millions of people's cup of coffee in the morning. This room rocker of a movie is the first chapter in the big screen project of his life, showing what a crazy thirty plus years it was. Rabid fans want another instalment showing what has developed since the mid 80's when "Private Parts" ends. He's since been divorced, remarried, seen his daughters become young adults, had his head writer Jackie "The Joke Man" Martling walk away and replaced by stand up comic Artie Lange and, last but not least, left terrestrial broadcasting to become the most popular talent now on satellite radio, where millions pay to hear the show that still offends and amuses with it's political satire, prank calls, more candid than anywhere else celebrity interviews and cast of characters who make up a very broad spectrum of voices in society. "Private Parts" is one of the few comedies that's funnier each time I watch it. The showdown Stern has with his nemesis at WnnnnNBC is one of the ten most hilarious scenes in history as far as I'm concerned. Paul Giamatti is so good as Kenny (or "Pig Vomit"), you'll practically throw up with laughter when he's on screen. Not so pleasant moments before Howard found his true voice are recreated, as are classics like "The Match Game" and "Fartman" (with friend of the show John Stamos filling in for Luke Perry at the MTV appearance). Radio has it's share of popular talent, but Stern has really achieved something unique with his approach. His phenomenon doesn't come around once a generation. Just once, period!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost completely made up history. Why?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    headly66
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fact that this was directed by a woman turned what might have been a much raunchier film into a blandish comedy but Howard was probably looking to reach a broader audience at the time. It is a good movie, not great, but mostly a disappointment for Stern fans as it is not a real history of the events that took place. Here's some fake movie history: Luke Perry introduced Howard as Fartman on MTV not John Stamos. Why would Dee Snider make a face at Howard behind stage when they were great friends at the time. Oh by the way, Dee was not even there as Twisted Sister had broke up in 1988, the event was in Sept. of 1992. Neither was Flavor Flav, Ozzy, Blues Traveler, MC Hammer, or Tiny Tim, etc, etc. Also no one treated Howard that way back stage, he was very famous at the time, had a #1 book and many of the same powers to help or hurt peoples careers. There is no song called "Mama Look-A Boo Boo" from the time Howard was driving with his father. The dirty puppet show at the old folks home never happened. They leave out the fact that Howard was doing bits for years before he "discovered himself" and don't show any of the many people he worked with on air over the years in college and up to NBC. Howard was not playing punk music like the Ramones at WRNW, in fact he played mostly disco. Howard did not meet Fred in his first minute on the air at WCCC. Howard was never in a bathtub with Fred and an actress. Howard didn't have long hair until the very end of his time with WNBC. Howard did not quit on the air at WWWW when they went country. Robin did not meet Howard on the air, they had both received tapes of each other prior to meeting and then decided to work together. The on the air orgasm did not happen that way, it was with a small radio and sounded completely different. Technically it could not be done as shown in the movie. Robin was not with Howard at the beginning at NBC as she quit in DC taking a straight news job after not being picked up by WNBC and blamed Howard for abandoning her. So the first night tryout for the Stern crew could never have happened with her. It also did not sound that way, they did not say sperm and gargle with it. Their programmers nickname was pig virus, not pig vomit, why they changed this I have no clue. The prevalence of breast implants is ridiculous in this movie, (girl on phone, girl in studio, girls in lesbian dream) this was not very common in the early 80's especially for women not in the porn or movie industry. In the last scene at the concert (the film says July 27th 1985), Howard looked nothing like this in 1985 nor did Robin. Phil Rudd was not in AC/DC at the time, nor did Stern's wife go into labor. His kids were born in 1983, 1986 and 1993. She wasn't even pregnant at the time, their next child wouldn't be born until May 9, 1986. I really have no problem with movies condensing or changing things a little because of time restraints or creativity but please, when you actually make things up that never happened its a little disconcerting. I mean why don't we just make a movie where Jesus is at the Battle of Waterloo, or John Lennon gets shot on a space ship or George Washington meets Hitler. The sad thing is this happens all the time and people believe its true and take it as history, just look at Braveheart where historical characters are in the same time period even though they lived 200 years apart. Its just sad and stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bonafide comedy classic from the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Superunknovvn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember watching this movie at the cinema when it came out. Originally me and my friend had wanted to go see "Men In Black", but it was sold out. What a shame! So, we decided to see this other flick that I had heard about in a smaller cinema. It was one of the luckiest decisions I've ever made at the movies. "Private Parts" is a funny, politically incorrect tongue-in-cheek biography of the life of Howard Stern, self-proclaimed King Of All Media. Having never heard Stern's show I can only guess that this telling of the events doesn't have too much to do with reality, but that's not really what's important. The movie is entertaining and endlessly quotable. "Private Parts" is the perfect movie for a light hearted evening. Something that cannot be said about "Man In Black".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stern is good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a long term listener of Howard Stern I was satisfied with the adaptation of the book to the big screen. Betty Thomas was smart enough to allow Howard be himself. It works because Stern is not really acting. Having heard the actual tapes of his father berating him as a kid, seeing Richard Portnow as Ben, was dead on accurate and funny as hell. The other highlight is Paul Giamatti as the program director called pig vomit, who is hired to control Stern's free wheeling and often vulgar on air persona. At one point the self proclaimed king of all media is subjected to a lecture on the proper way of announcing wnbc with a prolonged and exaggerated W "NNNNNNNBC;" it is exactly as it happened because I actually heard the broadcast and the constant battles between Howie and the management at the now defunct radio station. Previous to the WNBC job, we see the struggle from college radio to Briarcliff, NY to Hartford, Ct. to Detroit and the last stop before the Big Apple is Washington, D.C. It is a ride filled with odd ball characters, nude women and people behaving badly, all for the ratings, and it works due to Stern's ability to communicate at the level of a regular guy. The film is well made and should be entertaining even for non listeners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Free speech all the way! Also, I once got to know the woman who played Kenny's wife.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Betty Thomas's "Private Parts" came out, I had only loosely heard of Howard Stern, and usually in a negative context. But the movie really opened my eyes. It turns out that beyond his sometimes shocking radio content, it's all about free speech. Stern may pull some of the grossest stunts on air, but he's just showing what the First Amendment is all about. Like Lenny Bruce, George Carlin, Larry Flynt, John Waters, and the Farrelly Brothers, Stern always goes for the funniest shock value. And the movie does a great job showing that. And yes, it's true, I once got to know Aimee Luzier, who played Pig Vomit's wife. She was the assistant in a history/literature class that I took in high school.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An honest biopic work of art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern is an acquired taste for the diverse and eclectic. Never listening to his radio show, but an avid listener of scattered clips on the internet, I felt Private Parts could give me the proper introduction the man I was looking for. After all, the man has been a radio icon for many years and an FCC bandit for just as long. Like him or not, Stern has changed the face of radio. He has revolutionized the definition of "talk radio." I can't stress enough that I love talk radio. I find it to be not only relaxed but an insightful way to collect information on certain, gray topics. I used to religiously listen to DreX in the Morning, a Chicago-based radio show on WKSC-FM. Once he was gone at the end of 2010 so was I. I couldn't imagine not having him on my radio every morning before I ship myself off for my daily grind. Then in March I quickly turned over to Eddie and Jobo on WJMK-FM. To this day that's my cup of coffee in the morning. Stern has been more controversial than all of three of those men combined. He threatens the very patience of the FCC, and has pretty much thrown caution and restrictions to the wind as he sits in front of the mic and speaks his mind on whatever he wants. Through various warnings and threats made from his station and the FCC, all of which have been dismissed by him, it's pretty clear that as long as there are faithful listeners, Stern isn't concerned with who he offends or what he is faced with. The movie chronicles his life starting at a very young age where we see Stern's father makes an exercise out of verbally abusing his son. This may have contributed to Stern being a very closed book. Not to mention the fact he went to an all black high school, which only made his differences stand out. As years go by, and because of his father's occupation in radio, Stern develops a passion for the airwaves. This is an awkward and unexpected choice from someone who cruised through high school saying almost nothing. The thought of him pioneering a genre of talk radio which focused more on humor than news was not even present at the time because of his very shy nature. After hits and misses at different radio shows, Stern is finally hired by WNBC in New York City where he would wind up in numerous arguments with his station manager nicknamed Pig Vomit (played very well by Paul Giamatti). Stern's run at WNBC in the eighties was where he gained his most popularity and notoriety. After tirelessly working throughout college on their own brand-name radio and at a number of dead end jobs, he finally got the break he deserved. If you can look past his crude, vulgar, shameless persona there lies a sweet, gentle, hilarious side to him. That may have been added since Hollywood is notorious for factoring in little clich&eacute;s into biopics, but since Stern rejected many, many scripts before settling on this one I assume this one got it to almost pin-point accuracy. I forgot to mention that Stern married the beautiful Alison (McCormack) in 1978 after dating her prolifically throughout his run at WRNR. Alison was the first woman who ever gave Stern the time of day. But Stern makes it very clear being married to him is not an easy task. Stern is notorious for releasing private affairs with his wife over the air, which is what lead to their divorce about four years after this film was made. Private Parts is a provocative look at talk radio and where it was and now is because of Howard Stern. Sometimes it appears as if it is glossing over some events and instances that might have happened during Stern's long run. Surely he had to be suspended a few times, and maybe some of the fights with his wife lead to his expulsion from the house for a few days. But the movie doesn't dive into that as much as it looks at Stern's mark on the radio. Which is what it should look at it. It rarely simplifies the story, and comes out to be a very honest biopic work of art. Starring: Howard Stern, Robin Quivers, Fred Norris, Mary McCormack, and Paul Giamatti. Directed by: Betty Thomas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific Comedy with a (Gasp) Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Private Parts (1997) *** 1/2 (out of 4) Taken from Howard Stern's best selling autobiography, this film follows Sterns early years as a loser in high school all the way up to becoming the king of radio in New York City. While the majority of the film deals with his struggle of making it on the radio, we also get the story of his relationship with wife Alison (Mary McCormack). No matter what you think of Stern I think anyone will be able to enjoy this film and in fact I still remember going to see it when it was first released with someone who hated the guy with a passion and even they walked out liking him. I think a large portion of the film and the original book wanted to make people understand Stern and there's no question that the film is a bit one-sided but in the end it accomplishes what it set out to do and that is show people the real person. The film is full of raunchy humor including a great take-off on the Match Game and another terrific sequence with Stern having sex with a woman over the radio and while these comic bits are terrific what really makes the film so memorable is its charm. The film is incredibly charming and one can't help but really fall in love with Stern's character and especially the way he's determined not to stop until he reaches the top. I think the film is rather remarkable in that it can be downright filthy one moment but then sweet the next. It's really hard to mix those two things but the screenplay and director Thomas really make it work and by doing so they've created a rather special movie that keeps getting better with each new viewing. It should come as no shock but Stern makes for a terrific actor even though he's playing himself. I've heard many great actors say that playing themselves would be a very difficult thing to do but Stern handles it with no troubles as does his supporting mates Robin Quivers, Fred Norris and Jackie Martling. McCormack is also extremely good as the wife and her chemistry with Stern comes off as real and they make you feel as if you're watching a real couple. Even better is Paul Giamatti who plays Kenny, aka Pig Vomit, the man who tries to tame Stern when he gets to NBC. The fire and passion that Giamatti brings to the role is rather remarkable to watch and you can't help but laugh at loud when he and Stern are going at it. PRIVATE PARKS is a hilarious movie and a touching one that tells the rise of Stern with loving care and in the end it really delivers everything you'd want it to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Private Parts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw a clip of this featured in one of those Channel 4 countdowns, I didn't acknowledge that the film was based on reality, so I was very keen, from director Betty Thomas (Doctor Dolittle, John Tucker Must Die). Basically, Howard Stern always wanted to be a disc jockey, working for a radio station, playing popular music and speaking his mind, and during the 1970's it was his goal to do it. Howard started out in college with not a lot of zing in his approach and hardly any personality on the Mic, but then he got his big break on a Detroit radio station. It is soon after starting out that Howard has a snap, his glasses and moustache come off, and his more vibrant and opinionated personality is brought out. He is joined on his own show with news anchor Robin Quivers, who shares his unorthodox approach to expressing his opinions, talking whatever he wants to, and doing whatever he can to get high ratings. The radio heads don't share all of Howard's ideas of what the listeners want, but his hilarious off-the-wall antics are getting the listeners, to the point where he is the most famous disc jockey on air. After a little misunderstanding between Howard and wife Alison (Mary McCormack) about her baby miscarriage, where he joked about it, and her forgiving him, Howard gains a bigger opportunity with NBC in New York. Howard also has the good fortune to have Alison pregnant again, but with his new bosses not understanding how he got such high ratings, it is only after taking him on board that they experience it. It is the job of Kenny Rushton (Paul Giamatti) and one or two other crew members to keep Howard in line, or force him to quit with the limitations of what he can do on radio, but this won't stop him. He has many troubles on and off Mic, high demands, including having Robin with him once again, and of course another hit with being the number one disc jockey again, but he also stays true to his family. Also starring Fred Norris, Gary Dell'Abate, Jackie Martling, Carol Alt as Gloria, Richard Portnow as Ben Stern, Allison Janney as Dee Dee, Jenna Jameson as Mandy, Ozzy Osbourne, Mia Farrow, David Letterman, AC-DC (including Brian Johnson, Iggy Pop and Wendy Whoppers as Big-Breasted Woman. Stern completely steals the show with his madcap radio hosting, and the real people playing their own parts keeps the momentum high. The best sequence is Stern using his voice with a stripping woman turning the bass up high on her speakers to have vibration style sex, it was number 28 on The 100 Greatest Funny Moments. A hilarious shock jock, a cast of well-knowns as themselves and in cameos, sexually explicit radio broadcasts, the story is based on facts, this is everything you wants in a biographical comedy. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific and very funny biopic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern has only ever been a vaguely familiar figure here in the UK. When Private Parts first came out I knew who he was and had seen a short segment about him on TV. My opinion of him was not good. From the small amount of information I had, he seemed like a completely unlikeable malicious idiot with an annoying haircut. So I certainly had some preconceptions about the man before seeing this film. After seeing it, I had to admit that, like most things in life, the truth is much more complex. In actual fact I came away from Private Parts liking and respecting Mr Stern quite a bit. Quite a turn-around. Sometimes with a biopic it's good to have very little knowledge of the subject. The trajectory of the story is then more surprising to you. This was true for me with Private Parts, as I had no real clue about Howard Stern's rise to fame. However, what surprised me the most was Stern's character. He was not afraid to paint himself as pathetic, and the honesty of this approach is the key to why it's such a compelling film. Some people have commented that this movie is self-serving and that Stern portrays himself as some kind of misunderstood innocent. While I can't definitively say if this is true or not, my gut feeling is that he depicts himself in a fairly honest way. Many times he shows himself to be seriously uncool and pathetic. And because his whole shtick is about not holding back and saying what he thinks, you can't help but feel that this ethos must apply to the movie too, and this is most probably what he is like. The film is often very funny, and I can't really often say this for most comedies. It mixes standard biopic drama with some inventive comedy moments that recall the style of Woody Allen; although an admittedly lower-brow Woody Allen with a fair smattering of naked women. But still, it's in that general ball-park. Stern is very good as, well, Stern. I think it's quite a reasonable achievement to be fair as it's actually not always that easy playing yourself. Take a look at a few of the cameo appearances in some of the episodes of Extras for proof of this bizarre truth. Anyway, he is a compelling central character, whose underlying personality seems to be very decent. Paul Giamatti is the other actor who stands out. His portrayal of Pig Vomit is hilarious. This is a great comic biopic. You certainly do not need to be familiar with its lead character to enjoy it, as it's a very well delivered and funny story. The humour never feels forced either, it just flows into the narrative. I am surprised I like Private Parts so much. It really changed my view of Howard Stern. Except I still think he has an annoying haircut.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a reminder
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mino
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was watching this one recently with friends and I realized I was the only one being amused. I just realized why. This is Scarface, not a comedy, but a dramatic account of foul taste with balls taking over. It's Tony Montana p***ing everything in his path. It's the logical outcome when ratings decide who stays and who leaves. But why do I find it amusing? Well, I don't, really. I guess it was just the anticipation of Giamatti's performance I had forgotten was so short spanned. I write the comment just in case I get the urge to watch this again in the future.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The King of all media is also the court jester
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nixskits
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern is a polarizing figure in entertainment, probably the most hated and loved figure of the last half century, depending on whether you are an opponent or a fan of his. As the stats are laid out in this film, Stern's enemies are just as, if not more, likely to be found listening to his show. The program he hosts is like millions of people's cup of coffee in the morning. This room rocker of a movie is the first chapter in the big screen project of his life, showing what a crazy thirty plus years it was. Rabid fans want another instalment showing what has developed since the mid 80's when "Private Parts" ends. He's since been divorced, remarried, seen his daughters become young adults, had his head writer Jackie "The Joke Man" Martling walk away and replaced by stand up comic Artie Lange and, last but not least, left terrestrial broadcasting to become the most popular talent now on satellite radio, where millions pay to hear the show that still offends and amuses with it's political satire, prank calls, more candid than anywhere else celebrity interviews and cast of characters who make up a very broad spectrum of voices in society. "Private Parts" is one of the few comedies that's funnier each time I watch it. The showdown Stern has with his nemesis at WnnnnNBC is one of the ten most hilarious scenes in history as far as I'm concerned. Paul Giamatti is so good as Kenny (or "Pig Vomit"), you'll practically throw up with laughter when he's on screen. Not so pleasant moments before Howard found his true voice are recreated, as are classics like "The Match Game" and "Fartman" (with friend of the show John Stamos filling in for Luke Perry at the MTV appearance). Radio has it's share of popular talent, but Stern has really achieved something unique with his approach. His phenomenon doesn't come around once a generation. Just once, period!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost completely made up history. Why?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    headly66
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fact that this was directed by a woman turned what might have been a much raunchier film into a blandish comedy but Howard was probably looking to reach a broader audience at the time. It is a good movie, not great, but mostly a disappointment for Stern fans as it is not a real history of the events that took place. Here's some fake movie history: Luke Perry introduced Howard as Fartman on MTV not John Stamos. Why would Dee Snider make a face at Howard behind stage when they were great friends at the time. Oh by the way, Dee was not even there as Twisted Sister had broke up in 1988, the event was in Sept. of 1992. Neither was Flavor Flav, Ozzy, Blues Traveler, MC Hammer, or Tiny Tim, etc, etc. Also no one treated Howard that way back stage, he was very famous at the time, had a #1 book and many of the same powers to help or hurt peoples careers. There is no song called "Mama Look-A Boo Boo" from the time Howard was driving with his father. The dirty puppet show at the old folks home never happened. They leave out the fact that Howard was doing bits for years before he "discovered himself" and don't show any of the many people he worked with on air over the years in college and up to NBC. Howard was not playing punk music like the Ramones at WRNW, in fact he played mostly disco. Howard did not meet Fred in his first minute on the air at WCCC. Howard was never in a bathtub with Fred and an actress. Howard didn't have long hair until the very end of his time with WNBC. Howard did not quit on the air at WWWW when they went country. Robin did not meet Howard on the air, they had both received tapes of each other prior to meeting and then decided to work together. The on the air orgasm did not happen that way, it was with a small radio and sounded completely different. Technically it could not be done as shown in the movie. Robin was not with Howard at the beginning at NBC as she quit in DC taking a straight news job after not being picked up by WNBC and blamed Howard for abandoning her. So the first night tryout for the Stern crew could never have happened with her. It also did not sound that way, they did not say sperm and gargle with it. Their programmers nickname was pig virus, not pig vomit, why they changed this I have no clue. The prevalence of breast implants is ridiculous in this movie, (girl on phone, girl in studio, girls in lesbian dream) this was not very common in the early 80's especially for women not in the porn or movie industry. In the last scene at the concert (the film says July 27th 1985), Howard looked nothing like this in 1985 nor did Robin. Phil Rudd was not in AC/DC at the time, nor did Stern's wife go into labor. His kids were born in 1983, 1986 and 1993. She wasn't even pregnant at the time, their next child wouldn't be born until May 9, 1986. I really have no problem with movies condensing or changing things a little because of time restraints or creativity but please, when you actually make things up that never happened its a little disconcerting. I mean why don't we just make a movie where Jesus is at the Battle of Waterloo, or John Lennon gets shot on a space ship or George Washington meets Hitler. The sad thing is this happens all the time and people believe its true and take it as history, just look at Braveheart where historical characters are in the same time period even though they lived 200 years apart. Its just sad and stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bonafide comedy classic from the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Superunknovvn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember watching this movie at the cinema when it came out. Originally me and my friend had wanted to go see "Men In Black", but it was sold out. What a shame! So, we decided to see this other flick that I had heard about in a smaller cinema. It was one of the luckiest decisions I've ever made at the movies. "Private Parts" is a funny, politically incorrect tongue-in-cheek biography of the life of Howard Stern, self-proclaimed King Of All Media. Having never heard Stern's show I can only guess that this telling of the events doesn't have too much to do with reality, but that's not really what's important. The movie is entertaining and endlessly quotable. "Private Parts" is the perfect movie for a light hearted evening. Something that cannot be said about "Man In Black".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stern is good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a long term listener of Howard Stern I was satisfied with the adaptation of the book to the big screen. Betty Thomas was smart enough to allow Howard be himself. It works because Stern is not really acting. Having heard the actual tapes of his father berating him as a kid, seeing Richard Portnow as Ben, was dead on accurate and funny as hell. The other highlight is Paul Giamatti as the program director called pig vomit, who is hired to control Stern's free wheeling and often vulgar on air persona. At one point the self proclaimed king of all media is subjected to a lecture on the proper way of announcing wnbc with a prolonged and exaggerated W "NNNNNNNBC;" it is exactly as it happened because I actually heard the broadcast and the constant battles between Howie and the management at the now defunct radio station. Previous to the WNBC job, we see the struggle from college radio to Briarcliff, NY to Hartford, Ct. to Detroit and the last stop before the Big Apple is Washington, D.C. It is a ride filled with odd ball characters, nude women and people behaving badly, all for the ratings, and it works due to Stern's ability to communicate at the level of a regular guy. The film is well made and should be entertaining even for non listeners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Free speech all the way! Also, I once got to know the woman who played Kenny's wife.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Betty Thomas's "Private Parts" came out, I had only loosely heard of Howard Stern, and usually in a negative context. But the movie really opened my eyes. It turns out that beyond his sometimes shocking radio content, it's all about free speech. Stern may pull some of the grossest stunts on air, but he's just showing what the First Amendment is all about. Like Lenny Bruce, George Carlin, Larry Flynt, John Waters, and the Farrelly Brothers, Stern always goes for the funniest shock value. And the movie does a great job showing that. And yes, it's true, I once got to know Aimee Luzier, who played Pig Vomit's wife. She was the assistant in a history/literature class that I took in high school.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An honest biopic work of art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern is an acquired taste for the diverse and eclectic. Never listening to his radio show, but an avid listener of scattered clips on the internet, I felt Private Parts could give me the proper introduction the man I was looking for. After all, the man has been a radio icon for many years and an FCC bandit for just as long. Like him or not, Stern has changed the face of radio. He has revolutionized the definition of "talk radio." I can't stress enough that I love talk radio. I find it to be not only relaxed but an insightful way to collect information on certain, gray topics. I used to religiously listen to DreX in the Morning, a Chicago-based radio show on WKSC-FM. Once he was gone at the end of 2010 so was I. I couldn't imagine not having him on my radio every morning before I ship myself off for my daily grind. Then in March I quickly turned over to Eddie and Jobo on WJMK-FM. To this day that's my cup of coffee in the morning. Stern has been more controversial than all of three of those men combined. He threatens the very patience of the FCC, and has pretty much thrown caution and restrictions to the wind as he sits in front of the mic and speaks his mind on whatever he wants. Through various warnings and threats made from his station and the FCC, all of which have been dismissed by him, it's pretty clear that as long as there are faithful listeners, Stern isn't concerned with who he offends or what he is faced with. The movie chronicles his life starting at a very young age where we see Stern's father makes an exercise out of verbally abusing his son. This may have contributed to Stern being a very closed book. Not to mention the fact he went to an all black high school, which only made his differences stand out. As years go by, and because of his father's occupation in radio, Stern develops a passion for the airwaves. This is an awkward and unexpected choice from someone who cruised through high school saying almost nothing. The thought of him pioneering a genre of talk radio which focused more on humor than news was not even present at the time because of his very shy nature. After hits and misses at different radio shows, Stern is finally hired by WNBC in New York City where he would wind up in numerous arguments with his station manager nicknamed Pig Vomit (played very well by Paul Giamatti). Stern's run at WNBC in the eighties was where he gained his most popularity and notoriety. After tirelessly working throughout college on their own brand-name radio and at a number of dead end jobs, he finally got the break he deserved. If you can look past his crude, vulgar, shameless persona there lies a sweet, gentle, hilarious side to him. That may have been added since Hollywood is notorious for factoring in little clich&eacute;s into biopics, but since Stern rejected many, many scripts before settling on this one I assume this one got it to almost pin-point accuracy. I forgot to mention that Stern married the beautiful Alison (McCormack) in 1978 after dating her prolifically throughout his run at WRNR. Alison was the first woman who ever gave Stern the time of day. But Stern makes it very clear being married to him is not an easy task. Stern is notorious for releasing private affairs with his wife over the air, which is what lead to their divorce about four years after this film was made. Private Parts is a provocative look at talk radio and where it was and now is because of Howard Stern. Sometimes it appears as if it is glossing over some events and instances that might have happened during Stern's long run. Surely he had to be suspended a few times, and maybe some of the fights with his wife lead to his expulsion from the house for a few days. But the movie doesn't dive into that as much as it looks at Stern's mark on the radio. Which is what it should look at it. It rarely simplifies the story, and comes out to be a very honest biopic work of art. Starring: Howard Stern, Robin Quivers, Fred Norris, Mary McCormack, and Paul Giamatti. Directed by: Betty Thomas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific Comedy with a (Gasp) Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Private Parts (1997) *** 1/2 (out of 4) Taken from Howard Stern's best selling autobiography, this film follows Sterns early years as a loser in high school all the way up to becoming the king of radio in New York City. While the majority of the film deals with his struggle of making it on the radio, we also get the story of his relationship with wife Alison (Mary McCormack). No matter what you think of Stern I think anyone will be able to enjoy this film and in fact I still remember going to see it when it was first released with someone who hated the guy with a passion and even they walked out liking him. I think a large portion of the film and the original book wanted to make people understand Stern and there's no question that the film is a bit one-sided but in the end it accomplishes what it set out to do and that is show people the real person. The film is full of raunchy humor including a great take-off on the Match Game and another terrific sequence with Stern having sex with a woman over the radio and while these comic bits are terrific what really makes the film so memorable is its charm. The film is incredibly charming and one can't help but really fall in love with Stern's character and especially the way he's determined not to stop until he reaches the top. I think the film is rather remarkable in that it can be downright filthy one moment but then sweet the next. It's really hard to mix those two things but the screenplay and director Thomas really make it work and by doing so they've created a rather special movie that keeps getting better with each new viewing. It should come as no shock but Stern makes for a terrific actor even though he's playing himself. I've heard many great actors say that playing themselves would be a very difficult thing to do but Stern handles it with no troubles as does his supporting mates Robin Quivers, Fred Norris and Jackie Martling. McCormack is also extremely good as the wife and her chemistry with Stern comes off as real and they make you feel as if you're watching a real couple. Even better is Paul Giamatti who plays Kenny, aka Pig Vomit, the man who tries to tame Stern when he gets to NBC. The fire and passion that Giamatti brings to the role is rather remarkable to watch and you can't help but laugh at loud when he and Stern are going at it. PRIVATE PARKS is a hilarious movie and a touching one that tells the rise of Stern with loving care and in the end it really delivers everything you'd want it to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Private Parts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw a clip of this featured in one of those Channel 4 countdowns, I didn't acknowledge that the film was based on reality, so I was very keen, from director Betty Thomas (Doctor Dolittle, John Tucker Must Die). Basically, Howard Stern always wanted to be a disc jockey, working for a radio station, playing popular music and speaking his mind, and during the 1970's it was his goal to do it. Howard started out in college with not a lot of zing in his approach and hardly any personality on the Mic, but then he got his big break on a Detroit radio station. It is soon after starting out that Howard has a snap, his glasses and moustache come off, and his more vibrant and opinionated personality is brought out. He is joined on his own show with news anchor Robin Quivers, who shares his unorthodox approach to expressing his opinions, talking whatever he wants to, and doing whatever he can to get high ratings. The radio heads don't share all of Howard's ideas of what the listeners want, but his hilarious off-the-wall antics are getting the listeners, to the point where he is the most famous disc jockey on air. After a little misunderstanding between Howard and wife Alison (Mary McCormack) about her baby miscarriage, where he joked about it, and her forgiving him, Howard gains a bigger opportunity with NBC in New York. Howard also has the good fortune to have Alison pregnant again, but with his new bosses not understanding how he got such high ratings, it is only after taking him on board that they experience it. It is the job of Kenny Rushton (Paul Giamatti) and one or two other crew members to keep Howard in line, or force him to quit with the limitations of what he can do on radio, but this won't stop him. He has many troubles on and off Mic, high demands, including having Robin with him once again, and of course another hit with being the number one disc jockey again, but he also stays true to his family. Also starring Fred Norris, Gary Dell'Abate, Jackie Martling, Carol Alt as Gloria, Richard Portnow as Ben Stern, Allison Janney as Dee Dee, Jenna Jameson as Mandy, Ozzy Osbourne, Mia Farrow, David Letterman, AC-DC (including Brian Johnson, Iggy Pop and Wendy Whoppers as Big-Breasted Woman. Stern completely steals the show with his madcap radio hosting, and the real people playing their own parts keeps the momentum high. The best sequence is Stern using his voice with a stripping woman turning the bass up high on her speakers to have vibration style sex, it was number 28 on The 100 Greatest Funny Moments. A hilarious shock jock, a cast of well-knowns as themselves and in cameos, sexually explicit radio broadcasts, the story is based on facts, this is everything you wants in a biographical comedy. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific and very funny biopic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern has only ever been a vaguely familiar figure here in the UK. When Private Parts first came out I knew who he was and had seen a short segment about him on TV. My opinion of him was not good. From the small amount of information I had, he seemed like a completely unlikeable malicious idiot with an annoying haircut. So I certainly had some preconceptions about the man before seeing this film. After seeing it, I had to admit that, like most things in life, the truth is much more complex. In actual fact I came away from Private Parts liking and respecting Mr Stern quite a bit. Quite a turn-around. Sometimes with a biopic it's good to have very little knowledge of the subject. The trajectory of the story is then more surprising to you. This was true for me with Private Parts, as I had no real clue about Howard Stern's rise to fame. However, what surprised me the most was Stern's character. He was not afraid to paint himself as pathetic, and the honesty of this approach is the key to why it's such a compelling film. Some people have commented that this movie is self-serving and that Stern portrays himself as some kind of misunderstood innocent. While I can't definitively say if this is true or not, my gut feeling is that he depicts himself in a fairly honest way. Many times he shows himself to be seriously uncool and pathetic. And because his whole shtick is about not holding back and saying what he thinks, you can't help but feel that this ethos must apply to the movie too, and this is most probably what he is like. The film is often very funny, and I can't really often say this for most comedies. It mixes standard biopic drama with some inventive comedy moments that recall the style of Woody Allen; although an admittedly lower-brow Woody Allen with a fair smattering of naked women. But still, it's in that general ball-park. Stern is very good as, well, Stern. I think it's quite a reasonable achievement to be fair as it's actually not always that easy playing yourself. Take a look at a few of the cameo appearances in some of the episodes of Extras for proof of this bizarre truth. Anyway, he is a compelling central character, whose underlying personality seems to be very decent. Paul Giamatti is the other actor who stands out. His portrayal of Pig Vomit is hilarious. This is a great comic biopic. You certainly do not need to be familiar with its lead character to enjoy it, as it's a very well delivered and funny story. The humour never feels forced either, it just flows into the narrative. I am surprised I like Private Parts so much. It really changed my view of Howard Stern. Except I still think he has an annoying haircut.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a reminder
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mino
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was watching this one recently with friends and I realized I was the only one being amused. I just realized why. This is Scarface, not a comedy, but a dramatic account of foul taste with balls taking over. It's Tony Montana p***ing everything in his path. It's the logical outcome when ratings decide who stays and who leaves. But why do I find it amusing? Well, I don't, really. I guess it was just the anticipation of Giamatti's performance I had forgotten was so short spanned. I write the comment just in case I get the urge to watch this again in the future.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The King of all media is also the court jester
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nixskits
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern is a polarizing figure in entertainment, probably the most hated and loved figure of the last half century, depending on whether you are an opponent or a fan of his. As the stats are laid out in this film, Stern's enemies are just as, if not more, likely to be found listening to his show. The program he hosts is like millions of people's cup of coffee in the morning. This room rocker of a movie is the first chapter in the big screen project of his life, showing what a crazy thirty plus years it was. Rabid fans want another instalment showing what has developed since the mid 80's when "Private Parts" ends. He's since been divorced, remarried, seen his daughters become young adults, had his head writer Jackie "The Joke Man" Martling walk away and replaced by stand up comic Artie Lange and, last but not least, left terrestrial broadcasting to become the most popular talent now on satellite radio, where millions pay to hear the show that still offends and amuses with it's political satire, prank calls, more candid than anywhere else celebrity interviews and cast of characters who make up a very broad spectrum of voices in society. "Private Parts" is one of the few comedies that's funnier each time I watch it. The showdown Stern has with his nemesis at WnnnnNBC is one of the ten most hilarious scenes in history as far as I'm concerned. Paul Giamatti is so good as Kenny (or "Pig Vomit"), you'll practically throw up with laughter when he's on screen. Not so pleasant moments before Howard found his true voice are recreated, as are classics like "The Match Game" and "Fartman" (with friend of the show John Stamos filling in for Luke Perry at the MTV appearance). Radio has it's share of popular talent, but Stern has really achieved something unique with his approach. His phenomenon doesn't come around once a generation. Just once, period!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost completely made up history. Why?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    headly66
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fact that this was directed by a woman turned what might have been a much raunchier film into a blandish comedy but Howard was probably looking to reach a broader audience at the time. It is a good movie, not great, but mostly a disappointment for Stern fans as it is not a real history of the events that took place. Here's some fake movie history: Luke Perry introduced Howard as Fartman on MTV not John Stamos. Why would Dee Snider make a face at Howard behind stage when they were great friends at the time. Oh by the way, Dee was not even there as Twisted Sister had broke up in 1988, the event was in Sept. of 1992. Neither was Flavor Flav, Ozzy, Blues Traveler, MC Hammer, or Tiny Tim, etc, etc. Also no one treated Howard that way back stage, he was very famous at the time, had a #1 book and many of the same powers to help or hurt peoples careers. There is no song called "Mama Look-A Boo Boo" from the time Howard was driving with his father. The dirty puppet show at the old folks home never happened. They leave out the fact that Howard was doing bits for years before he "discovered himself" and don't show any of the many people he worked with on air over the years in college and up to NBC. Howard was not playing punk music like the Ramones at WRNW, in fact he played mostly disco. Howard did not meet Fred in his first minute on the air at WCCC. Howard was never in a bathtub with Fred and an actress. Howard didn't have long hair until the very end of his time with WNBC. Howard did not quit on the air at WWWW when they went country. Robin did not meet Howard on the air, they had both received tapes of each other prior to meeting and then decided to work together. The on the air orgasm did not happen that way, it was with a small radio and sounded completely different. Technically it could not be done as shown in the movie. Robin was not with Howard at the beginning at NBC as she quit in DC taking a straight news job after not being picked up by WNBC and blamed Howard for abandoning her. So the first night tryout for the Stern crew could never have happened with her. It also did not sound that way, they did not say sperm and gargle with it. Their programmers nickname was pig virus, not pig vomit, why they changed this I have no clue. The prevalence of breast implants is ridiculous in this movie, (girl on phone, girl in studio, girls in lesbian dream) this was not very common in the early 80's especially for women not in the porn or movie industry. In the last scene at the concert (the film says July 27th 1985), Howard looked nothing like this in 1985 nor did Robin. Phil Rudd was not in AC/DC at the time, nor did Stern's wife go into labor. His kids were born in 1983, 1986 and 1993. She wasn't even pregnant at the time, their next child wouldn't be born until May 9, 1986. I really have no problem with movies condensing or changing things a little because of time restraints or creativity but please, when you actually make things up that never happened its a little disconcerting. I mean why don't we just make a movie where Jesus is at the Battle of Waterloo, or John Lennon gets shot on a space ship or George Washington meets Hitler. The sad thing is this happens all the time and people believe its true and take it as history, just look at Braveheart where historical characters are in the same time period even though they lived 200 years apart. Its just sad and stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bonafide comedy classic from the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Superunknovvn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember watching this movie at the cinema when it came out. Originally me and my friend had wanted to go see "Men In Black", but it was sold out. What a shame! So, we decided to see this other flick that I had heard about in a smaller cinema. It was one of the luckiest decisions I've ever made at the movies. "Private Parts" is a funny, politically incorrect tongue-in-cheek biography of the life of Howard Stern, self-proclaimed King Of All Media. Having never heard Stern's show I can only guess that this telling of the events doesn't have too much to do with reality, but that's not really what's important. The movie is entertaining and endlessly quotable. "Private Parts" is the perfect movie for a light hearted evening. Something that cannot be said about "Man In Black".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stern is good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a long term listener of Howard Stern I was satisfied with the adaptation of the book to the big screen. Betty Thomas was smart enough to allow Howard be himself. It works because Stern is not really acting. Having heard the actual tapes of his father berating him as a kid, seeing Richard Portnow as Ben, was dead on accurate and funny as hell. The other highlight is Paul Giamatti as the program director called pig vomit, who is hired to control Stern's free wheeling and often vulgar on air persona. At one point the self proclaimed king of all media is subjected to a lecture on the proper way of announcing wnbc with a prolonged and exaggerated W "NNNNNNNBC;" it is exactly as it happened because I actually heard the broadcast and the constant battles between Howie and the management at the now defunct radio station. Previous to the WNBC job, we see the struggle from college radio to Briarcliff, NY to Hartford, Ct. to Detroit and the last stop before the Big Apple is Washington, D.C. It is a ride filled with odd ball characters, nude women and people behaving badly, all for the ratings, and it works due to Stern's ability to communicate at the level of a regular guy. The film is well made and should be entertaining even for non listeners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Free speech all the way! Also, I once got to know the woman who played Kenny's wife.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Betty Thomas's "Private Parts" came out, I had only loosely heard of Howard Stern, and usually in a negative context. But the movie really opened my eyes. It turns out that beyond his sometimes shocking radio content, it's all about free speech. Stern may pull some of the grossest stunts on air, but he's just showing what the First Amendment is all about. Like Lenny Bruce, George Carlin, Larry Flynt, John Waters, and the Farrelly Brothers, Stern always goes for the funniest shock value. And the movie does a great job showing that. And yes, it's true, I once got to know Aimee Luzier, who played Pig Vomit's wife. She was the assistant in a history/literature class that I took in high school.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An honest biopic work of art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern is an acquired taste for the diverse and eclectic. Never listening to his radio show, but an avid listener of scattered clips on the internet, I felt Private Parts could give me the proper introduction the man I was looking for. After all, the man has been a radio icon for many years and an FCC bandit for just as long. Like him or not, Stern has changed the face of radio. He has revolutionized the definition of "talk radio." I can't stress enough that I love talk radio. I find it to be not only relaxed but an insightful way to collect information on certain, gray topics. I used to religiously listen to DreX in the Morning, a Chicago-based radio show on WKSC-FM. Once he was gone at the end of 2010 so was I. I couldn't imagine not having him on my radio every morning before I ship myself off for my daily grind. Then in March I quickly turned over to Eddie and Jobo on WJMK-FM. To this day that's my cup of coffee in the morning. Stern has been more controversial than all of three of those men combined. He threatens the very patience of the FCC, and has pretty much thrown caution and restrictions to the wind as he sits in front of the mic and speaks his mind on whatever he wants. Through various warnings and threats made from his station and the FCC, all of which have been dismissed by him, it's pretty clear that as long as there are faithful listeners, Stern isn't concerned with who he offends or what he is faced with. The movie chronicles his life starting at a very young age where we see Stern's father makes an exercise out of verbally abusing his son. This may have contributed to Stern being a very closed book. Not to mention the fact he went to an all black high school, which only made his differences stand out. As years go by, and because of his father's occupation in radio, Stern develops a passion for the airwaves. This is an awkward and unexpected choice from someone who cruised through high school saying almost nothing. The thought of him pioneering a genre of talk radio which focused more on humor than news was not even present at the time because of his very shy nature. After hits and misses at different radio shows, Stern is finally hired by WNBC in New York City where he would wind up in numerous arguments with his station manager nicknamed Pig Vomit (played very well by Paul Giamatti). Stern's run at WNBC in the eighties was where he gained his most popularity and notoriety. After tirelessly working throughout college on their own brand-name radio and at a number of dead end jobs, he finally got the break he deserved. If you can look past his crude, vulgar, shameless persona there lies a sweet, gentle, hilarious side to him. That may have been added since Hollywood is notorious for factoring in little clich&eacute;s into biopics, but since Stern rejected many, many scripts before settling on this one I assume this one got it to almost pin-point accuracy. I forgot to mention that Stern married the beautiful Alison (McCormack) in 1978 after dating her prolifically throughout his run at WRNR. Alison was the first woman who ever gave Stern the time of day. But Stern makes it very clear being married to him is not an easy task. Stern is notorious for releasing private affairs with his wife over the air, which is what lead to their divorce about four years after this film was made. Private Parts is a provocative look at talk radio and where it was and now is because of Howard Stern. Sometimes it appears as if it is glossing over some events and instances that might have happened during Stern's long run. Surely he had to be suspended a few times, and maybe some of the fights with his wife lead to his expulsion from the house for a few days. But the movie doesn't dive into that as much as it looks at Stern's mark on the radio. Which is what it should look at it. It rarely simplifies the story, and comes out to be a very honest biopic work of art. Starring: Howard Stern, Robin Quivers, Fred Norris, Mary McCormack, and Paul Giamatti. Directed by: Betty Thomas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific Comedy with a (Gasp) Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Private Parts (1997) *** 1/2 (out of 4) Taken from Howard Stern's best selling autobiography, this film follows Sterns early years as a loser in high school all the way up to becoming the king of radio in New York City. While the majority of the film deals with his struggle of making it on the radio, we also get the story of his relationship with wife Alison (Mary McCormack). No matter what you think of Stern I think anyone will be able to enjoy this film and in fact I still remember going to see it when it was first released with someone who hated the guy with a passion and even they walked out liking him. I think a large portion of the film and the original book wanted to make people understand Stern and there's no question that the film is a bit one-sided but in the end it accomplishes what it set out to do and that is show people the real person. The film is full of raunchy humor including a great take-off on the Match Game and another terrific sequence with Stern having sex with a woman over the radio and while these comic bits are terrific what really makes the film so memorable is its charm. The film is incredibly charming and one can't help but really fall in love with Stern's character and especially the way he's determined not to stop until he reaches the top. I think the film is rather remarkable in that it can be downright filthy one moment but then sweet the next. It's really hard to mix those two things but the screenplay and director Thomas really make it work and by doing so they've created a rather special movie that keeps getting better with each new viewing. It should come as no shock but Stern makes for a terrific actor even though he's playing himself. I've heard many great actors say that playing themselves would be a very difficult thing to do but Stern handles it with no troubles as does his supporting mates Robin Quivers, Fred Norris and Jackie Martling. McCormack is also extremely good as the wife and her chemistry with Stern comes off as real and they make you feel as if you're watching a real couple. Even better is Paul Giamatti who plays Kenny, aka Pig Vomit, the man who tries to tame Stern when he gets to NBC. The fire and passion that Giamatti brings to the role is rather remarkable to watch and you can't help but laugh at loud when he and Stern are going at it. PRIVATE PARKS is a hilarious movie and a touching one that tells the rise of Stern with loving care and in the end it really delivers everything you'd want it to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Private Parts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw a clip of this featured in one of those Channel 4 countdowns, I didn't acknowledge that the film was based on reality, so I was very keen, from director Betty Thomas (Doctor Dolittle, John Tucker Must Die). Basically, Howard Stern always wanted to be a disc jockey, working for a radio station, playing popular music and speaking his mind, and during the 1970's it was his goal to do it. Howard started out in college with not a lot of zing in his approach and hardly any personality on the Mic, but then he got his big break on a Detroit radio station. It is soon after starting out that Howard has a snap, his glasses and moustache come off, and his more vibrant and opinionated personality is brought out. He is joined on his own show with news anchor Robin Quivers, who shares his unorthodox approach to expressing his opinions, talking whatever he wants to, and doing whatever he can to get high ratings. The radio heads don't share all of Howard's ideas of what the listeners want, but his hilarious off-the-wall antics are getting the listeners, to the point where he is the most famous disc jockey on air. After a little misunderstanding between Howard and wife Alison (Mary McCormack) about her baby miscarriage, where he joked about it, and her forgiving him, Howard gains a bigger opportunity with NBC in New York. Howard also has the good fortune to have Alison pregnant again, but with his new bosses not understanding how he got such high ratings, it is only after taking him on board that they experience it. It is the job of Kenny Rushton (Paul Giamatti) and one or two other crew members to keep Howard in line, or force him to quit with the limitations of what he can do on radio, but this won't stop him. He has many troubles on and off Mic, high demands, including having Robin with him once again, and of course another hit with being the number one disc jockey again, but he also stays true to his family. Also starring Fred Norris, Gary Dell'Abate, Jackie Martling, Carol Alt as Gloria, Richard Portnow as Ben Stern, Allison Janney as Dee Dee, Jenna Jameson as Mandy, Ozzy Osbourne, Mia Farrow, David Letterman, AC-DC (including Brian Johnson, Iggy Pop and Wendy Whoppers as Big-Breasted Woman. Stern completely steals the show with his madcap radio hosting, and the real people playing their own parts keeps the momentum high. The best sequence is Stern using his voice with a stripping woman turning the bass up high on her speakers to have vibration style sex, it was number 28 on The 100 Greatest Funny Moments. A hilarious shock jock, a cast of well-knowns as themselves and in cameos, sexually explicit radio broadcasts, the story is based on facts, this is everything you wants in a biographical comedy. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific and very funny biopic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern has only ever been a vaguely familiar figure here in the UK. When Private Parts first came out I knew who he was and had seen a short segment about him on TV. My opinion of him was not good. From the small amount of information I had, he seemed like a completely unlikeable malicious idiot with an annoying haircut. So I certainly had some preconceptions about the man before seeing this film. After seeing it, I had to admit that, like most things in life, the truth is much more complex. In actual fact I came away from Private Parts liking and respecting Mr Stern quite a bit. Quite a turn-around. Sometimes with a biopic it's good to have very little knowledge of the subject. The trajectory of the story is then more surprising to you. This was true for me with Private Parts, as I had no real clue about Howard Stern's rise to fame. However, what surprised me the most was Stern's character. He was not afraid to paint himself as pathetic, and the honesty of this approach is the key to why it's such a compelling film. Some people have commented that this movie is self-serving and that Stern portrays himself as some kind of misunderstood innocent. While I can't definitively say if this is true or not, my gut feeling is that he depicts himself in a fairly honest way. Many times he shows himself to be seriously uncool and pathetic. And because his whole shtick is about not holding back and saying what he thinks, you can't help but feel that this ethos must apply to the movie too, and this is most probably what he is like. The film is often very funny, and I can't really often say this for most comedies. It mixes standard biopic drama with some inventive comedy moments that recall the style of Woody Allen; although an admittedly lower-brow Woody Allen with a fair smattering of naked women. But still, it's in that general ball-park. Stern is very good as, well, Stern. I think it's quite a reasonable achievement to be fair as it's actually not always that easy playing yourself. Take a look at a few of the cameo appearances in some of the episodes of Extras for proof of this bizarre truth. Anyway, he is a compelling central character, whose underlying personality seems to be very decent. Paul Giamatti is the other actor who stands out. His portrayal of Pig Vomit is hilarious. This is a great comic biopic. You certainly do not need to be familiar with its lead character to enjoy it, as it's a very well delivered and funny story. The humour never feels forced either, it just flows into the narrative. I am surprised I like Private Parts so much. It really changed my view of Howard Stern. Except I still think he has an annoying haircut.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a reminder
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mino
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was watching this one recently with friends and I realized I was the only one being amused. I just realized why. This is Scarface, not a comedy, but a dramatic account of foul taste with balls taking over. It's Tony Montana p***ing everything in his path. It's the logical outcome when ratings decide who stays and who leaves. But why do I find it amusing? Well, I don't, really. I guess it was just the anticipation of Giamatti's performance I had forgotten was so short spanned. I write the comment just in case I get the urge to watch this again in the future.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The King of all media is also the court jester
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nixskits
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern is a polarizing figure in entertainment, probably the most hated and loved figure of the last half century, depending on whether you are an opponent or a fan of his. As the stats are laid out in this film, Stern's enemies are just as, if not more, likely to be found listening to his show. The program he hosts is like millions of people's cup of coffee in the morning. This room rocker of a movie is the first chapter in the big screen project of his life, showing what a crazy thirty plus years it was. Rabid fans want another instalment showing what has developed since the mid 80's when "Private Parts" ends. He's since been divorced, remarried, seen his daughters become young adults, had his head writer Jackie "The Joke Man" Martling walk away and replaced by stand up comic Artie Lange and, last but not least, left terrestrial broadcasting to become the most popular talent now on satellite radio, where millions pay to hear the show that still offends and amuses with it's political satire, prank calls, more candid than anywhere else celebrity interviews and cast of characters who make up a very broad spectrum of voices in society. "Private Parts" is one of the few comedies that's funnier each time I watch it. The showdown Stern has with his nemesis at WnnnnNBC is one of the ten most hilarious scenes in history as far as I'm concerned. Paul Giamatti is so good as Kenny (or "Pig Vomit"), you'll practically throw up with laughter when he's on screen. Not so pleasant moments before Howard found his true voice are recreated, as are classics like "The Match Game" and "Fartman" (with friend of the show John Stamos filling in for Luke Perry at the MTV appearance). Radio has it's share of popular talent, but Stern has really achieved something unique with his approach. His phenomenon doesn't come around once a generation. Just once, period!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost completely made up history. Why?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    headly66
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fact that this was directed by a woman turned what might have been a much raunchier film into a blandish comedy but Howard was probably looking to reach a broader audience at the time. It is a good movie, not great, but mostly a disappointment for Stern fans as it is not a real history of the events that took place. Here's some fake movie history: Luke Perry introduced Howard as Fartman on MTV not John Stamos. Why would Dee Snider make a face at Howard behind stage when they were great friends at the time. Oh by the way, Dee was not even there as Twisted Sister had broke up in 1988, the event was in Sept. of 1992. Neither was Flavor Flav, Ozzy, Blues Traveler, MC Hammer, or Tiny Tim, etc, etc. Also no one treated Howard that way back stage, he was very famous at the time, had a #1 book and many of the same powers to help or hurt peoples careers. There is no song called "Mama Look-A Boo Boo" from the time Howard was driving with his father. The dirty puppet show at the old folks home never happened. They leave out the fact that Howard was doing bits for years before he "discovered himself" and don't show any of the many people he worked with on air over the years in college and up to NBC. Howard was not playing punk music like the Ramones at WRNW, in fact he played mostly disco. Howard did not meet Fred in his first minute on the air at WCCC. Howard was never in a bathtub with Fred and an actress. Howard didn't have long hair until the very end of his time with WNBC. Howard did not quit on the air at WWWW when they went country. Robin did not meet Howard on the air, they had both received tapes of each other prior to meeting and then decided to work together. The on the air orgasm did not happen that way, it was with a small radio and sounded completely different. Technically it could not be done as shown in the movie. Robin was not with Howard at the beginning at NBC as she quit in DC taking a straight news job after not being picked up by WNBC and blamed Howard for abandoning her. So the first night tryout for the Stern crew could never have happened with her. It also did not sound that way, they did not say sperm and gargle with it. Their programmers nickname was pig virus, not pig vomit, why they changed this I have no clue. The prevalence of breast implants is ridiculous in this movie, (girl on phone, girl in studio, girls in lesbian dream) this was not very common in the early 80's especially for women not in the porn or movie industry. In the last scene at the concert (the film says July 27th 1985), Howard looked nothing like this in 1985 nor did Robin. Phil Rudd was not in AC/DC at the time, nor did Stern's wife go into labor. His kids were born in 1983, 1986 and 1993. She wasn't even pregnant at the time, their next child wouldn't be born until May 9, 1986. I really have no problem with movies condensing or changing things a little because of time restraints or creativity but please, when you actually make things up that never happened its a little disconcerting. I mean why don't we just make a movie where Jesus is at the Battle of Waterloo, or John Lennon gets shot on a space ship or George Washington meets Hitler. The sad thing is this happens all the time and people believe its true and take it as history, just look at Braveheart where historical characters are in the same time period even though they lived 200 years apart. Its just sad and stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bonafide comedy classic from the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Superunknovvn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember watching this movie at the cinema when it came out. Originally me and my friend had wanted to go see "Men In Black", but it was sold out. What a shame! So, we decided to see this other flick that I had heard about in a smaller cinema. It was one of the luckiest decisions I've ever made at the movies. "Private Parts" is a funny, politically incorrect tongue-in-cheek biography of the life of Howard Stern, self-proclaimed King Of All Media. Having never heard Stern's show I can only guess that this telling of the events doesn't have too much to do with reality, but that's not really what's important. The movie is entertaining and endlessly quotable. "Private Parts" is the perfect movie for a light hearted evening. Something that cannot be said about "Man In Black".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stern is good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a long term listener of Howard Stern I was satisfied with the adaptation of the book to the big screen. Betty Thomas was smart enough to allow Howard be himself. It works because Stern is not really acting. Having heard the actual tapes of his father berating him as a kid, seeing Richard Portnow as Ben, was dead on accurate and funny as hell. The other highlight is Paul Giamatti as the program director called pig vomit, who is hired to control Stern's free wheeling and often vulgar on air persona. At one point the self proclaimed king of all media is subjected to a lecture on the proper way of announcing wnbc with a prolonged and exaggerated W "NNNNNNNBC;" it is exactly as it happened because I actually heard the broadcast and the constant battles between Howie and the management at the now defunct radio station. Previous to the WNBC job, we see the struggle from college radio to Briarcliff, NY to Hartford, Ct. to Detroit and the last stop before the Big Apple is Washington, D.C. It is a ride filled with odd ball characters, nude women and people behaving badly, all for the ratings, and it works due to Stern's ability to communicate at the level of a regular guy. The film is well made and should be entertaining even for non listeners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Free speech all the way! Also, I once got to know the woman who played Kenny's wife.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Betty Thomas's "Private Parts" came out, I had only loosely heard of Howard Stern, and usually in a negative context. But the movie really opened my eyes. It turns out that beyond his sometimes shocking radio content, it's all about free speech. Stern may pull some of the grossest stunts on air, but he's just showing what the First Amendment is all about. Like Lenny Bruce, George Carlin, Larry Flynt, John Waters, and the Farrelly Brothers, Stern always goes for the funniest shock value. And the movie does a great job showing that. And yes, it's true, I once got to know Aimee Luzier, who played Pig Vomit's wife. She was the assistant in a history/literature class that I took in high school.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An honest biopic work of art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern is an acquired taste for the diverse and eclectic. Never listening to his radio show, but an avid listener of scattered clips on the internet, I felt Private Parts could give me the proper introduction the man I was looking for. After all, the man has been a radio icon for many years and an FCC bandit for just as long. Like him or not, Stern has changed the face of radio. He has revolutionized the definition of "talk radio." I can't stress enough that I love talk radio. I find it to be not only relaxed but an insightful way to collect information on certain, gray topics. I used to religiously listen to DreX in the Morning, a Chicago-based radio show on WKSC-FM. Once he was gone at the end of 2010 so was I. I couldn't imagine not having him on my radio every morning before I ship myself off for my daily grind. Then in March I quickly turned over to Eddie and Jobo on WJMK-FM. To this day that's my cup of coffee in the morning. Stern has been more controversial than all of three of those men combined. He threatens the very patience of the FCC, and has pretty much thrown caution and restrictions to the wind as he sits in front of the mic and speaks his mind on whatever he wants. Through various warnings and threats made from his station and the FCC, all of which have been dismissed by him, it's pretty clear that as long as there are faithful listeners, Stern isn't concerned with who he offends or what he is faced with. The movie chronicles his life starting at a very young age where we see Stern's father makes an exercise out of verbally abusing his son. This may have contributed to Stern being a very closed book. Not to mention the fact he went to an all black high school, which only made his differences stand out. As years go by, and because of his father's occupation in radio, Stern develops a passion for the airwaves. This is an awkward and unexpected choice from someone who cruised through high school saying almost nothing. The thought of him pioneering a genre of talk radio which focused more on humor than news was not even present at the time because of his very shy nature. After hits and misses at different radio shows, Stern is finally hired by WNBC in New York City where he would wind up in numerous arguments with his station manager nicknamed Pig Vomit (played very well by Paul Giamatti). Stern's run at WNBC in the eighties was where he gained his most popularity and notoriety. After tirelessly working throughout college on their own brand-name radio and at a number of dead end jobs, he finally got the break he deserved. If you can look past his crude, vulgar, shameless persona there lies a sweet, gentle, hilarious side to him. That may have been added since Hollywood is notorious for factoring in little clich&eacute;s into biopics, but since Stern rejected many, many scripts before settling on this one I assume this one got it to almost pin-point accuracy. I forgot to mention that Stern married the beautiful Alison (McCormack) in 1978 after dating her prolifically throughout his run at WRNR. Alison was the first woman who ever gave Stern the time of day. But Stern makes it very clear being married to him is not an easy task. Stern is notorious for releasing private affairs with his wife over the air, which is what lead to their divorce about four years after this film was made. Private Parts is a provocative look at talk radio and where it was and now is because of Howard Stern. Sometimes it appears as if it is glossing over some events and instances that might have happened during Stern's long run. Surely he had to be suspended a few times, and maybe some of the fights with his wife lead to his expulsion from the house for a few days. But the movie doesn't dive into that as much as it looks at Stern's mark on the radio. Which is what it should look at it. It rarely simplifies the story, and comes out to be a very honest biopic work of art. Starring: Howard Stern, Robin Quivers, Fred Norris, Mary McCormack, and Paul Giamatti. Directed by: Betty Thomas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific Comedy with a (Gasp) Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Private Parts (1997) *** 1/2 (out of 4) Taken from Howard Stern's best selling autobiography, this film follows Sterns early years as a loser in high school all the way up to becoming the king of radio in New York City. While the majority of the film deals with his struggle of making it on the radio, we also get the story of his relationship with wife Alison (Mary McCormack). No matter what you think of Stern I think anyone will be able to enjoy this film and in fact I still remember going to see it when it was first released with someone who hated the guy with a passion and even they walked out liking him. I think a large portion of the film and the original book wanted to make people understand Stern and there's no question that the film is a bit one-sided but in the end it accomplishes what it set out to do and that is show people the real person. The film is full of raunchy humor including a great take-off on the Match Game and another terrific sequence with Stern having sex with a woman over the radio and while these comic bits are terrific what really makes the film so memorable is its charm. The film is incredibly charming and one can't help but really fall in love with Stern's character and especially the way he's determined not to stop until he reaches the top. I think the film is rather remarkable in that it can be downright filthy one moment but then sweet the next. It's really hard to mix those two things but the screenplay and director Thomas really make it work and by doing so they've created a rather special movie that keeps getting better with each new viewing. It should come as no shock but Stern makes for a terrific actor even though he's playing himself. I've heard many great actors say that playing themselves would be a very difficult thing to do but Stern handles it with no troubles as does his supporting mates Robin Quivers, Fred Norris and Jackie Martling. McCormack is also extremely good as the wife and her chemistry with Stern comes off as real and they make you feel as if you're watching a real couple. Even better is Paul Giamatti who plays Kenny, aka Pig Vomit, the man who tries to tame Stern when he gets to NBC. The fire and passion that Giamatti brings to the role is rather remarkable to watch and you can't help but laugh at loud when he and Stern are going at it. PRIVATE PARKS is a hilarious movie and a touching one that tells the rise of Stern with loving care and in the end it really delivers everything you'd want it to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Private Parts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw a clip of this featured in one of those Channel 4 countdowns, I didn't acknowledge that the film was based on reality, so I was very keen, from director Betty Thomas (Doctor Dolittle, John Tucker Must Die). Basically, Howard Stern always wanted to be a disc jockey, working for a radio station, playing popular music and speaking his mind, and during the 1970's it was his goal to do it. Howard started out in college with not a lot of zing in his approach and hardly any personality on the Mic, but then he got his big break on a Detroit radio station. It is soon after starting out that Howard has a snap, his glasses and moustache come off, and his more vibrant and opinionated personality is brought out. He is joined on his own show with news anchor Robin Quivers, who shares his unorthodox approach to expressing his opinions, talking whatever he wants to, and doing whatever he can to get high ratings. The radio heads don't share all of Howard's ideas of what the listeners want, but his hilarious off-the-wall antics are getting the listeners, to the point where he is the most famous disc jockey on air. After a little misunderstanding between Howard and wife Alison (Mary McCormack) about her baby miscarriage, where he joked about it, and her forgiving him, Howard gains a bigger opportunity with NBC in New York. Howard also has the good fortune to have Alison pregnant again, but with his new bosses not understanding how he got such high ratings, it is only after taking him on board that they experience it. It is the job of Kenny Rushton (Paul Giamatti) and one or two other crew members to keep Howard in line, or force him to quit with the limitations of what he can do on radio, but this won't stop him. He has many troubles on and off Mic, high demands, including having Robin with him once again, and of course another hit with being the number one disc jockey again, but he also stays true to his family. Also starring Fred Norris, Gary Dell'Abate, Jackie Martling, Carol Alt as Gloria, Richard Portnow as Ben Stern, Allison Janney as Dee Dee, Jenna Jameson as Mandy, Ozzy Osbourne, Mia Farrow, David Letterman, AC-DC (including Brian Johnson, Iggy Pop and Wendy Whoppers as Big-Breasted Woman. Stern completely steals the show with his madcap radio hosting, and the real people playing their own parts keeps the momentum high. The best sequence is Stern using his voice with a stripping woman turning the bass up high on her speakers to have vibration style sex, it was number 28 on The 100 Greatest Funny Moments. A hilarious shock jock, a cast of well-knowns as themselves and in cameos, sexually explicit radio broadcasts, the story is based on facts, this is everything you wants in a biographical comedy. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific and very funny biopic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern has only ever been a vaguely familiar figure here in the UK. When Private Parts first came out I knew who he was and had seen a short segment about him on TV. My opinion of him was not good. From the small amount of information I had, he seemed like a completely unlikeable malicious idiot with an annoying haircut. So I certainly had some preconceptions about the man before seeing this film. After seeing it, I had to admit that, like most things in life, the truth is much more complex. In actual fact I came away from Private Parts liking and respecting Mr Stern quite a bit. Quite a turn-around. Sometimes with a biopic it's good to have very little knowledge of the subject. The trajectory of the story is then more surprising to you. This was true for me with Private Parts, as I had no real clue about Howard Stern's rise to fame. However, what surprised me the most was Stern's character. He was not afraid to paint himself as pathetic, and the honesty of this approach is the key to why it's such a compelling film. Some people have commented that this movie is self-serving and that Stern portrays himself as some kind of misunderstood innocent. While I can't definitively say if this is true or not, my gut feeling is that he depicts himself in a fairly honest way. Many times he shows himself to be seriously uncool and pathetic. And because his whole shtick is about not holding back and saying what he thinks, you can't help but feel that this ethos must apply to the movie too, and this is most probably what he is like. The film is often very funny, and I can't really often say this for most comedies. It mixes standard biopic drama with some inventive comedy moments that recall the style of Woody Allen; although an admittedly lower-brow Woody Allen with a fair smattering of naked women. But still, it's in that general ball-park. Stern is very good as, well, Stern. I think it's quite a reasonable achievement to be fair as it's actually not always that easy playing yourself. Take a look at a few of the cameo appearances in some of the episodes of Extras for proof of this bizarre truth. Anyway, he is a compelling central character, whose underlying personality seems to be very decent. Paul Giamatti is the other actor who stands out. His portrayal of Pig Vomit is hilarious. This is a great comic biopic. You certainly do not need to be familiar with its lead character to enjoy it, as it's a very well delivered and funny story. The humour never feels forced either, it just flows into the narrative. I am surprised I like Private Parts so much. It really changed my view of Howard Stern. Except I still think he has an annoying haircut.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a reminder
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mino
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was watching this one recently with friends and I realized I was the only one being amused. I just realized why. This is Scarface, not a comedy, but a dramatic account of foul taste with balls taking over. It's Tony Montana p***ing everything in his path. It's the logical outcome when ratings decide who stays and who leaves. But why do I find it amusing? Well, I don't, really. I guess it was just the anticipation of Giamatti's performance I had forgotten was so short spanned. I write the comment just in case I get the urge to watch this again in the future.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The King of all media is also the court jester
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nixskits
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern is a polarizing figure in entertainment, probably the most hated and loved figure of the last half century, depending on whether you are an opponent or a fan of his. As the stats are laid out in this film, Stern's enemies are just as, if not more, likely to be found listening to his show. The program he hosts is like millions of people's cup of coffee in the morning. This room rocker of a movie is the first chapter in the big screen project of his life, showing what a crazy thirty plus years it was. Rabid fans want another instalment showing what has developed since the mid 80's when "Private Parts" ends. He's since been divorced, remarried, seen his daughters become young adults, had his head writer Jackie "The Joke Man" Martling walk away and replaced by stand up comic Artie Lange and, last but not least, left terrestrial broadcasting to become the most popular talent now on satellite radio, where millions pay to hear the show that still offends and amuses with it's political satire, prank calls, more candid than anywhere else celebrity interviews and cast of characters who make up a very broad spectrum of voices in society. "Private Parts" is one of the few comedies that's funnier each time I watch it. The showdown Stern has with his nemesis at WnnnnNBC is one of the ten most hilarious scenes in history as far as I'm concerned. Paul Giamatti is so good as Kenny (or "Pig Vomit"), you'll practically throw up with laughter when he's on screen. Not so pleasant moments before Howard found his true voice are recreated, as are classics like "The Match Game" and "Fartman" (with friend of the show John Stamos filling in for Luke Perry at the MTV appearance). Radio has it's share of popular talent, but Stern has really achieved something unique with his approach. His phenomenon doesn't come around once a generation. Just once, period!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost completely made up history. Why?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    headly66
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fact that this was directed by a woman turned what might have been a much raunchier film into a blandish comedy but Howard was probably looking to reach a broader audience at the time. It is a good movie, not great, but mostly a disappointment for Stern fans as it is not a real history of the events that took place. Here's some fake movie history: Luke Perry introduced Howard as Fartman on MTV not John Stamos. Why would Dee Snider make a face at Howard behind stage when they were great friends at the time. Oh by the way, Dee was not even there as Twisted Sister had broke up in 1988, the event was in Sept. of 1992. Neither was Flavor Flav, Ozzy, Blues Traveler, MC Hammer, or Tiny Tim, etc, etc. Also no one treated Howard that way back stage, he was very famous at the time, had a #1 book and many of the same powers to help or hurt peoples careers. There is no song called "Mama Look-A Boo Boo" from the time Howard was driving with his father. The dirty puppet show at the old folks home never happened. They leave out the fact that Howard was doing bits for years before he "discovered himself" and don't show any of the many people he worked with on air over the years in college and up to NBC. Howard was not playing punk music like the Ramones at WRNW, in fact he played mostly disco. Howard did not meet Fred in his first minute on the air at WCCC. Howard was never in a bathtub with Fred and an actress. Howard didn't have long hair until the very end of his time with WNBC. Howard did not quit on the air at WWWW when they went country. Robin did not meet Howard on the air, they had both received tapes of each other prior to meeting and then decided to work together. The on the air orgasm did not happen that way, it was with a small radio and sounded completely different. Technically it could not be done as shown in the movie. Robin was not with Howard at the beginning at NBC as she quit in DC taking a straight news job after not being picked up by WNBC and blamed Howard for abandoning her. So the first night tryout for the Stern crew could never have happened with her. It also did not sound that way, they did not say sperm and gargle with it. Their programmers nickname was pig virus, not pig vomit, why they changed this I have no clue. The prevalence of breast implants is ridiculous in this movie, (girl on phone, girl in studio, girls in lesbian dream) this was not very common in the early 80's especially for women not in the porn or movie industry. In the last scene at the concert (the film says July 27th 1985), Howard looked nothing like this in 1985 nor did Robin. Phil Rudd was not in AC/DC at the time, nor did Stern's wife go into labor. His kids were born in 1983, 1986 and 1993. She wasn't even pregnant at the time, their next child wouldn't be born until May 9, 1986. I really have no problem with movies condensing or changing things a little because of time restraints or creativity but please, when you actually make things up that never happened its a little disconcerting. I mean why don't we just make a movie where Jesus is at the Battle of Waterloo, or John Lennon gets shot on a space ship or George Washington meets Hitler. The sad thing is this happens all the time and people believe its true and take it as history, just look at Braveheart where historical characters are in the same time period even though they lived 200 years apart. Its just sad and stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bonafide comedy classic from the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Superunknovvn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember watching this movie at the cinema when it came out. Originally me and my friend had wanted to go see "Men In Black", but it was sold out. What a shame! So, we decided to see this other flick that I had heard about in a smaller cinema. It was one of the luckiest decisions I've ever made at the movies. "Private Parts" is a funny, politically incorrect tongue-in-cheek biography of the life of Howard Stern, self-proclaimed King Of All Media. Having never heard Stern's show I can only guess that this telling of the events doesn't have too much to do with reality, but that's not really what's important. The movie is entertaining and endlessly quotable. "Private Parts" is the perfect movie for a light hearted evening. Something that cannot be said about "Man In Black".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stern is good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a long term listener of Howard Stern I was satisfied with the adaptation of the book to the big screen. Betty Thomas was smart enough to allow Howard be himself. It works because Stern is not really acting. Having heard the actual tapes of his father berating him as a kid, seeing Richard Portnow as Ben, was dead on accurate and funny as hell. The other highlight is Paul Giamatti as the program director called pig vomit, who is hired to control Stern's free wheeling and often vulgar on air persona. At one point the self proclaimed king of all media is subjected to a lecture on the proper way of announcing wnbc with a prolonged and exaggerated W "NNNNNNNBC;" it is exactly as it happened because I actually heard the broadcast and the constant battles between Howie and the management at the now defunct radio station. Previous to the WNBC job, we see the struggle from college radio to Briarcliff, NY to Hartford, Ct. to Detroit and the last stop before the Big Apple is Washington, D.C. It is a ride filled with odd ball characters, nude women and people behaving badly, all for the ratings, and it works due to Stern's ability to communicate at the level of a regular guy. The film is well made and should be entertaining even for non listeners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Free speech all the way! Also, I once got to know the woman who played Kenny's wife.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Betty Thomas's "Private Parts" came out, I had only loosely heard of Howard Stern, and usually in a negative context. But the movie really opened my eyes. It turns out that beyond his sometimes shocking radio content, it's all about free speech. Stern may pull some of the grossest stunts on air, but he's just showing what the First Amendment is all about. Like Lenny Bruce, George Carlin, Larry Flynt, John Waters, and the Farrelly Brothers, Stern always goes for the funniest shock value. And the movie does a great job showing that. And yes, it's true, I once got to know Aimee Luzier, who played Pig Vomit's wife. She was the assistant in a history/literature class that I took in high school.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An honest biopic work of art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern is an acquired taste for the diverse and eclectic. Never listening to his radio show, but an avid listener of scattered clips on the internet, I felt Private Parts could give me the proper introduction the man I was looking for. After all, the man has been a radio icon for many years and an FCC bandit for just as long. Like him or not, Stern has changed the face of radio. He has revolutionized the definition of "talk radio." I can't stress enough that I love talk radio. I find it to be not only relaxed but an insightful way to collect information on certain, gray topics. I used to religiously listen to DreX in the Morning, a Chicago-based radio show on WKSC-FM. Once he was gone at the end of 2010 so was I. I couldn't imagine not having him on my radio every morning before I ship myself off for my daily grind. Then in March I quickly turned over to Eddie and Jobo on WJMK-FM. To this day that's my cup of coffee in the morning. Stern has been more controversial than all of three of those men combined. He threatens the very patience of the FCC, and has pretty much thrown caution and restrictions to the wind as he sits in front of the mic and speaks his mind on whatever he wants. Through various warnings and threats made from his station and the FCC, all of which have been dismissed by him, it's pretty clear that as long as there are faithful listeners, Stern isn't concerned with who he offends or what he is faced with. The movie chronicles his life starting at a very young age where we see Stern's father makes an exercise out of verbally abusing his son. This may have contributed to Stern being a very closed book. Not to mention the fact he went to an all black high school, which only made his differences stand out. As years go by, and because of his father's occupation in radio, Stern develops a passion for the airwaves. This is an awkward and unexpected choice from someone who cruised through high school saying almost nothing. The thought of him pioneering a genre of talk radio which focused more on humor than news was not even present at the time because of his very shy nature. After hits and misses at different radio shows, Stern is finally hired by WNBC in New York City where he would wind up in numerous arguments with his station manager nicknamed Pig Vomit (played very well by Paul Giamatti). Stern's run at WNBC in the eighties was where he gained his most popularity and notoriety. After tirelessly working throughout college on their own brand-name radio and at a number of dead end jobs, he finally got the break he deserved. If you can look past his crude, vulgar, shameless persona there lies a sweet, gentle, hilarious side to him. That may have been added since Hollywood is notorious for factoring in little clich&eacute;s into biopics, but since Stern rejected many, many scripts before settling on this one I assume this one got it to almost pin-point accuracy. I forgot to mention that Stern married the beautiful Alison (McCormack) in 1978 after dating her prolifically throughout his run at WRNR. Alison was the first woman who ever gave Stern the time of day. But Stern makes it very clear being married to him is not an easy task. Stern is notorious for releasing private affairs with his wife over the air, which is what lead to their divorce about four years after this film was made. Private Parts is a provocative look at talk radio and where it was and now is because of Howard Stern. Sometimes it appears as if it is glossing over some events and instances that might have happened during Stern's long run. Surely he had to be suspended a few times, and maybe some of the fights with his wife lead to his expulsion from the house for a few days. But the movie doesn't dive into that as much as it looks at Stern's mark on the radio. Which is what it should look at it. It rarely simplifies the story, and comes out to be a very honest biopic work of art. Starring: Howard Stern, Robin Quivers, Fred Norris, Mary McCormack, and Paul Giamatti. Directed by: Betty Thomas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific Comedy with a (Gasp) Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Private Parts (1997) *** 1/2 (out of 4) Taken from Howard Stern's best selling autobiography, this film follows Sterns early years as a loser in high school all the way up to becoming the king of radio in New York City. While the majority of the film deals with his struggle of making it on the radio, we also get the story of his relationship with wife Alison (Mary McCormack). No matter what you think of Stern I think anyone will be able to enjoy this film and in fact I still remember going to see it when it was first released with someone who hated the guy with a passion and even they walked out liking him. I think a large portion of the film and the original book wanted to make people understand Stern and there's no question that the film is a bit one-sided but in the end it accomplishes what it set out to do and that is show people the real person. The film is full of raunchy humor including a great take-off on the Match Game and another terrific sequence with Stern having sex with a woman over the radio and while these comic bits are terrific what really makes the film so memorable is its charm. The film is incredibly charming and one can't help but really fall in love with Stern's character and especially the way he's determined not to stop until he reaches the top. I think the film is rather remarkable in that it can be downright filthy one moment but then sweet the next. It's really hard to mix those two things but the screenplay and director Thomas really make it work and by doing so they've created a rather special movie that keeps getting better with each new viewing. It should come as no shock but Stern makes for a terrific actor even though he's playing himself. I've heard many great actors say that playing themselves would be a very difficult thing to do but Stern handles it with no troubles as does his supporting mates Robin Quivers, Fred Norris and Jackie Martling. McCormack is also extremely good as the wife and her chemistry with Stern comes off as real and they make you feel as if you're watching a real couple. Even better is Paul Giamatti who plays Kenny, aka Pig Vomit, the man who tries to tame Stern when he gets to NBC. The fire and passion that Giamatti brings to the role is rather remarkable to watch and you can't help but laugh at loud when he and Stern are going at it. PRIVATE PARKS is a hilarious movie and a touching one that tells the rise of Stern with loving care and in the end it really delivers everything you'd want it to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Private Parts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw a clip of this featured in one of those Channel 4 countdowns, I didn't acknowledge that the film was based on reality, so I was very keen, from director Betty Thomas (Doctor Dolittle, John Tucker Must Die). Basically, Howard Stern always wanted to be a disc jockey, working for a radio station, playing popular music and speaking his mind, and during the 1970's it was his goal to do it. Howard started out in college with not a lot of zing in his approach and hardly any personality on the Mic, but then he got his big break on a Detroit radio station. It is soon after starting out that Howard has a snap, his glasses and moustache come off, and his more vibrant and opinionated personality is brought out. He is joined on his own show with news anchor Robin Quivers, who shares his unorthodox approach to expressing his opinions, talking whatever he wants to, and doing whatever he can to get high ratings. The radio heads don't share all of Howard's ideas of what the listeners want, but his hilarious off-the-wall antics are getting the listeners, to the point where he is the most famous disc jockey on air. After a little misunderstanding between Howard and wife Alison (Mary McCormack) about her baby miscarriage, where he joked about it, and her forgiving him, Howard gains a bigger opportunity with NBC in New York. Howard also has the good fortune to have Alison pregnant again, but with his new bosses not understanding how he got such high ratings, it is only after taking him on board that they experience it. It is the job of Kenny Rushton (Paul Giamatti) and one or two other crew members to keep Howard in line, or force him to quit with the limitations of what he can do on radio, but this won't stop him. He has many troubles on and off Mic, high demands, including having Robin with him once again, and of course another hit with being the number one disc jockey again, but he also stays true to his family. Also starring Fred Norris, Gary Dell'Abate, Jackie Martling, Carol Alt as Gloria, Richard Portnow as Ben Stern, Allison Janney as Dee Dee, Jenna Jameson as Mandy, Ozzy Osbourne, Mia Farrow, David Letterman, AC-DC (including Brian Johnson, Iggy Pop and Wendy Whoppers as Big-Breasted Woman. Stern completely steals the show with his madcap radio hosting, and the real people playing their own parts keeps the momentum high. The best sequence is Stern using his voice with a stripping woman turning the bass up high on her speakers to have vibration style sex, it was number 28 on The 100 Greatest Funny Moments. A hilarious shock jock, a cast of well-knowns as themselves and in cameos, sexually explicit radio broadcasts, the story is based on facts, this is everything you wants in a biographical comedy. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific and very funny biopic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern has only ever been a vaguely familiar figure here in the UK. When Private Parts first came out I knew who he was and had seen a short segment about him on TV. My opinion of him was not good. From the small amount of information I had, he seemed like a completely unlikeable malicious idiot with an annoying haircut. So I certainly had some preconceptions about the man before seeing this film. After seeing it, I had to admit that, like most things in life, the truth is much more complex. In actual fact I came away from Private Parts liking and respecting Mr Stern quite a bit. Quite a turn-around. Sometimes with a biopic it's good to have very little knowledge of the subject. The trajectory of the story is then more surprising to you. This was true for me with Private Parts, as I had no real clue about Howard Stern's rise to fame. However, what surprised me the most was Stern's character. He was not afraid to paint himself as pathetic, and the honesty of this approach is the key to why it's such a compelling film. Some people have commented that this movie is self-serving and that Stern portrays himself as some kind of misunderstood innocent. While I can't definitively say if this is true or not, my gut feeling is that he depicts himself in a fairly honest way. Many times he shows himself to be seriously uncool and pathetic. And because his whole shtick is about not holding back and saying what he thinks, you can't help but feel that this ethos must apply to the movie too, and this is most probably what he is like. The film is often very funny, and I can't really often say this for most comedies. It mixes standard biopic drama with some inventive comedy moments that recall the style of Woody Allen; although an admittedly lower-brow Woody Allen with a fair smattering of naked women. But still, it's in that general ball-park. Stern is very good as, well, Stern. I think it's quite a reasonable achievement to be fair as it's actually not always that easy playing yourself. Take a look at a few of the cameo appearances in some of the episodes of Extras for proof of this bizarre truth. Anyway, he is a compelling central character, whose underlying personality seems to be very decent. Paul Giamatti is the other actor who stands out. His portrayal of Pig Vomit is hilarious. This is a great comic biopic. You certainly do not need to be familiar with its lead character to enjoy it, as it's a very well delivered and funny story. The humour never feels forced either, it just flows into the narrative. I am surprised I like Private Parts so much. It really changed my view of Howard Stern. Except I still think he has an annoying haircut.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a reminder
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mino
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was watching this one recently with friends and I realized I was the only one being amused. I just realized why. This is Scarface, not a comedy, but a dramatic account of foul taste with balls taking over. It's Tony Montana p***ing everything in his path. It's the logical outcome when ratings decide who stays and who leaves. But why do I find it amusing? Well, I don't, really. I guess it was just the anticipation of Giamatti's performance I had forgotten was so short spanned. I write the comment just in case I get the urge to watch this again in the future.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The King of all media is also the court jester
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nixskits
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern is a polarizing figure in entertainment, probably the most hated and loved figure of the last half century, depending on whether you are an opponent or a fan of his. As the stats are laid out in this film, Stern's enemies are just as, if not more, likely to be found listening to his show. The program he hosts is like millions of people's cup of coffee in the morning. This room rocker of a movie is the first chapter in the big screen project of his life, showing what a crazy thirty plus years it was. Rabid fans want another instalment showing what has developed since the mid 80's when "Private Parts" ends. He's since been divorced, remarried, seen his daughters become young adults, had his head writer Jackie "The Joke Man" Martling walk away and replaced by stand up comic Artie Lange and, last but not least, left terrestrial broadcasting to become the most popular talent now on satellite radio, where millions pay to hear the show that still offends and amuses with it's political satire, prank calls, more candid than anywhere else celebrity interviews and cast of characters who make up a very broad spectrum of voices in society. "Private Parts" is one of the few comedies that's funnier each time I watch it. The showdown Stern has with his nemesis at WnnnnNBC is one of the ten most hilarious scenes in history as far as I'm concerned. Paul Giamatti is so good as Kenny (or "Pig Vomit"), you'll practically throw up with laughter when he's on screen. Not so pleasant moments before Howard found his true voice are recreated, as are classics like "The Match Game" and "Fartman" (with friend of the show John Stamos filling in for Luke Perry at the MTV appearance). Radio has it's share of popular talent, but Stern has really achieved something unique with his approach. His phenomenon doesn't come around once a generation. Just once, period!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost completely made up history. Why?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    headly66
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fact that this was directed by a woman turned what might have been a much raunchier film into a blandish comedy but Howard was probably looking to reach a broader audience at the time. It is a good movie, not great, but mostly a disappointment for Stern fans as it is not a real history of the events that took place. Here's some fake movie history: Luke Perry introduced Howard as Fartman on MTV not John Stamos. Why would Dee Snider make a face at Howard behind stage when they were great friends at the time. Oh by the way, Dee was not even there as Twisted Sister had broke up in 1988, the event was in Sept. of 1992. Neither was Flavor Flav, Ozzy, Blues Traveler, MC Hammer, or Tiny Tim, etc, etc. Also no one treated Howard that way back stage, he was very famous at the time, had a #1 book and many of the same powers to help or hurt peoples careers. There is no song called "Mama Look-A Boo Boo" from the time Howard was driving with his father. The dirty puppet show at the old folks home never happened. They leave out the fact that Howard was doing bits for years before he "discovered himself" and don't show any of the many people he worked with on air over the years in college and up to NBC. Howard was not playing punk music like the Ramones at WRNW, in fact he played mostly disco. Howard did not meet Fred in his first minute on the air at WCCC. Howard was never in a bathtub with Fred and an actress. Howard didn't have long hair until the very end of his time with WNBC. Howard did not quit on the air at WWWW when they went country. Robin did not meet Howard on the air, they had both received tapes of each other prior to meeting and then decided to work together. The on the air orgasm did not happen that way, it was with a small radio and sounded completely different. Technically it could not be done as shown in the movie. Robin was not with Howard at the beginning at NBC as she quit in DC taking a straight news job after not being picked up by WNBC and blamed Howard for abandoning her. So the first night tryout for the Stern crew could never have happened with her. It also did not sound that way, they did not say sperm and gargle with it. Their programmers nickname was pig virus, not pig vomit, why they changed this I have no clue. The prevalence of breast implants is ridiculous in this movie, (girl on phone, girl in studio, girls in lesbian dream) this was not very common in the early 80's especially for women not in the porn or movie industry. In the last scene at the concert (the film says July 27th 1985), Howard looked nothing like this in 1985 nor did Robin. Phil Rudd was not in AC/DC at the time, nor did Stern's wife go into labor. His kids were born in 1983, 1986 and 1993. She wasn't even pregnant at the time, their next child wouldn't be born until May 9, 1986. I really have no problem with movies condensing or changing things a little because of time restraints or creativity but please, when you actually make things up that never happened its a little disconcerting. I mean why don't we just make a movie where Jesus is at the Battle of Waterloo, or John Lennon gets shot on a space ship or George Washington meets Hitler. The sad thing is this happens all the time and people believe its true and take it as history, just look at Braveheart where historical characters are in the same time period even though they lived 200 years apart. Its just sad and stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bonafide comedy classic from the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Superunknovvn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember watching this movie at the cinema when it came out. Originally me and my friend had wanted to go see "Men In Black", but it was sold out. What a shame! So, we decided to see this other flick that I had heard about in a smaller cinema. It was one of the luckiest decisions I've ever made at the movies. "Private Parts" is a funny, politically incorrect tongue-in-cheek biography of the life of Howard Stern, self-proclaimed King Of All Media. Having never heard Stern's show I can only guess that this telling of the events doesn't have too much to do with reality, but that's not really what's important. The movie is entertaining and endlessly quotable. "Private Parts" is the perfect movie for a light hearted evening. Something that cannot be said about "Man In Black".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stern is good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a long term listener of Howard Stern I was satisfied with the adaptation of the book to the big screen. Betty Thomas was smart enough to allow Howard be himself. It works because Stern is not really acting. Having heard the actual tapes of his father berating him as a kid, seeing Richard Portnow as Ben, was dead on accurate and funny as hell. The other highlight is Paul Giamatti as the program director called pig vomit, who is hired to control Stern's free wheeling and often vulgar on air persona. At one point the self proclaimed king of all media is subjected to a lecture on the proper way of announcing wnbc with a prolonged and exaggerated W "NNNNNNNBC;" it is exactly as it happened because I actually heard the broadcast and the constant battles between Howie and the management at the now defunct radio station. Previous to the WNBC job, we see the struggle from college radio to Briarcliff, NY to Hartford, Ct. to Detroit and the last stop before the Big Apple is Washington, D.C. It is a ride filled with odd ball characters, nude women and people behaving badly, all for the ratings, and it works due to Stern's ability to communicate at the level of a regular guy. The film is well made and should be entertaining even for non listeners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Free speech all the way! Also, I once got to know the woman who played Kenny's wife.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Betty Thomas's "Private Parts" came out, I had only loosely heard of Howard Stern, and usually in a negative context. But the movie really opened my eyes. It turns out that beyond his sometimes shocking radio content, it's all about free speech. Stern may pull some of the grossest stunts on air, but he's just showing what the First Amendment is all about. Like Lenny Bruce, George Carlin, Larry Flynt, John Waters, and the Farrelly Brothers, Stern always goes for the funniest shock value. And the movie does a great job showing that. And yes, it's true, I once got to know Aimee Luzier, who played Pig Vomit's wife. She was the assistant in a history/literature class that I took in high school.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An honest biopic work of art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern is an acquired taste for the diverse and eclectic. Never listening to his radio show, but an avid listener of scattered clips on the internet, I felt Private Parts could give me the proper introduction the man I was looking for. After all, the man has been a radio icon for many years and an FCC bandit for just as long. Like him or not, Stern has changed the face of radio. He has revolutionized the definition of "talk radio." I can't stress enough that I love talk radio. I find it to be not only relaxed but an insightful way to collect information on certain, gray topics. I used to religiously listen to DreX in the Morning, a Chicago-based radio show on WKSC-FM. Once he was gone at the end of 2010 so was I. I couldn't imagine not having him on my radio every morning before I ship myself off for my daily grind. Then in March I quickly turned over to Eddie and Jobo on WJMK-FM. To this day that's my cup of coffee in the morning. Stern has been more controversial than all of three of those men combined. He threatens the very patience of the FCC, and has pretty much thrown caution and restrictions to the wind as he sits in front of the mic and speaks his mind on whatever he wants. Through various warnings and threats made from his station and the FCC, all of which have been dismissed by him, it's pretty clear that as long as there are faithful listeners, Stern isn't concerned with who he offends or what he is faced with. The movie chronicles his life starting at a very young age where we see Stern's father makes an exercise out of verbally abusing his son. This may have contributed to Stern being a very closed book. Not to mention the fact he went to an all black high school, which only made his differences stand out. As years go by, and because of his father's occupation in radio, Stern develops a passion for the airwaves. This is an awkward and unexpected choice from someone who cruised through high school saying almost nothing. The thought of him pioneering a genre of talk radio which focused more on humor than news was not even present at the time because of his very shy nature. After hits and misses at different radio shows, Stern is finally hired by WNBC in New York City where he would wind up in numerous arguments with his station manager nicknamed Pig Vomit (played very well by Paul Giamatti). Stern's run at WNBC in the eighties was where he gained his most popularity and notoriety. After tirelessly working throughout college on their own brand-name radio and at a number of dead end jobs, he finally got the break he deserved. If you can look past his crude, vulgar, shameless persona there lies a sweet, gentle, hilarious side to him. That may have been added since Hollywood is notorious for factoring in little clich&eacute;s into biopics, but since Stern rejected many, many scripts before settling on this one I assume this one got it to almost pin-point accuracy. I forgot to mention that Stern married the beautiful Alison (McCormack) in 1978 after dating her prolifically throughout his run at WRNR. Alison was the first woman who ever gave Stern the time of day. But Stern makes it very clear being married to him is not an easy task. Stern is notorious for releasing private affairs with his wife over the air, which is what lead to their divorce about four years after this film was made. Private Parts is a provocative look at talk radio and where it was and now is because of Howard Stern. Sometimes it appears as if it is glossing over some events and instances that might have happened during Stern's long run. Surely he had to be suspended a few times, and maybe some of the fights with his wife lead to his expulsion from the house for a few days. But the movie doesn't dive into that as much as it looks at Stern's mark on the radio. Which is what it should look at it. It rarely simplifies the story, and comes out to be a very honest biopic work of art. Starring: Howard Stern, Robin Quivers, Fred Norris, Mary McCormack, and Paul Giamatti. Directed by: Betty Thomas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific Comedy with a (Gasp) Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Private Parts (1997) *** 1/2 (out of 4) Taken from Howard Stern's best selling autobiography, this film follows Sterns early years as a loser in high school all the way up to becoming the king of radio in New York City. While the majority of the film deals with his struggle of making it on the radio, we also get the story of his relationship with wife Alison (Mary McCormack). No matter what you think of Stern I think anyone will be able to enjoy this film and in fact I still remember going to see it when it was first released with someone who hated the guy with a passion and even they walked out liking him. I think a large portion of the film and the original book wanted to make people understand Stern and there's no question that the film is a bit one-sided but in the end it accomplishes what it set out to do and that is show people the real person. The film is full of raunchy humor including a great take-off on the Match Game and another terrific sequence with Stern having sex with a woman over the radio and while these comic bits are terrific what really makes the film so memorable is its charm. The film is incredibly charming and one can't help but really fall in love with Stern's character and especially the way he's determined not to stop until he reaches the top. I think the film is rather remarkable in that it can be downright filthy one moment but then sweet the next. It's really hard to mix those two things but the screenplay and director Thomas really make it work and by doing so they've created a rather special movie that keeps getting better with each new viewing. It should come as no shock but Stern makes for a terrific actor even though he's playing himself. I've heard many great actors say that playing themselves would be a very difficult thing to do but Stern handles it with no troubles as does his supporting mates Robin Quivers, Fred Norris and Jackie Martling. McCormack is also extremely good as the wife and her chemistry with Stern comes off as real and they make you feel as if you're watching a real couple. Even better is Paul Giamatti who plays Kenny, aka Pig Vomit, the man who tries to tame Stern when he gets to NBC. The fire and passion that Giamatti brings to the role is rather remarkable to watch and you can't help but laugh at loud when he and Stern are going at it. PRIVATE PARKS is a hilarious movie and a touching one that tells the rise of Stern with loving care and in the end it really delivers everything you'd want it to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Private Parts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw a clip of this featured in one of those Channel 4 countdowns, I didn't acknowledge that the film was based on reality, so I was very keen, from director Betty Thomas (Doctor Dolittle, John Tucker Must Die). Basically, Howard Stern always wanted to be a disc jockey, working for a radio station, playing popular music and speaking his mind, and during the 1970's it was his goal to do it. Howard started out in college with not a lot of zing in his approach and hardly any personality on the Mic, but then he got his big break on a Detroit radio station. It is soon after starting out that Howard has a snap, his glasses and moustache come off, and his more vibrant and opinionated personality is brought out. He is joined on his own show with news anchor Robin Quivers, who shares his unorthodox approach to expressing his opinions, talking whatever he wants to, and doing whatever he can to get high ratings. The radio heads don't share all of Howard's ideas of what the listeners want, but his hilarious off-the-wall antics are getting the listeners, to the point where he is the most famous disc jockey on air. After a little misunderstanding between Howard and wife Alison (Mary McCormack) about her baby miscarriage, where he joked about it, and her forgiving him, Howard gains a bigger opportunity with NBC in New York. Howard also has the good fortune to have Alison pregnant again, but with his new bosses not understanding how he got such high ratings, it is only after taking him on board that they experience it. It is the job of Kenny Rushton (Paul Giamatti) and one or two other crew members to keep Howard in line, or force him to quit with the limitations of what he can do on radio, but this won't stop him. He has many troubles on and off Mic, high demands, including having Robin with him once again, and of course another hit with being the number one disc jockey again, but he also stays true to his family. Also starring Fred Norris, Gary Dell'Abate, Jackie Martling, Carol Alt as Gloria, Richard Portnow as Ben Stern, Allison Janney as Dee Dee, Jenna Jameson as Mandy, Ozzy Osbourne, Mia Farrow, David Letterman, AC-DC (including Brian Johnson, Iggy Pop and Wendy Whoppers as Big-Breasted Woman. Stern completely steals the show with his madcap radio hosting, and the real people playing their own parts keeps the momentum high. The best sequence is Stern using his voice with a stripping woman turning the bass up high on her speakers to have vibration style sex, it was number 28 on The 100 Greatest Funny Moments. A hilarious shock jock, a cast of well-knowns as themselves and in cameos, sexually explicit radio broadcasts, the story is based on facts, this is everything you wants in a biographical comedy. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific and very funny biopic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern has only ever been a vaguely familiar figure here in the UK. When Private Parts first came out I knew who he was and had seen a short segment about him on TV. My opinion of him was not good. From the small amount of information I had, he seemed like a completely unlikeable malicious idiot with an annoying haircut. So I certainly had some preconceptions about the man before seeing this film. After seeing it, I had to admit that, like most things in life, the truth is much more complex. In actual fact I came away from Private Parts liking and respecting Mr Stern quite a bit. Quite a turn-around. Sometimes with a biopic it's good to have very little knowledge of the subject. The trajectory of the story is then more surprising to you. This was true for me with Private Parts, as I had no real clue about Howard Stern's rise to fame. However, what surprised me the most was Stern's character. He was not afraid to paint himself as pathetic, and the honesty of this approach is the key to why it's such a compelling film. Some people have commented that this movie is self-serving and that Stern portrays himself as some kind of misunderstood innocent. While I can't definitively say if this is true or not, my gut feeling is that he depicts himself in a fairly honest way. Many times he shows himself to be seriously uncool and pathetic. And because his whole shtick is about not holding back and saying what he thinks, you can't help but feel that this ethos must apply to the movie too, and this is most probably what he is like. The film is often very funny, and I can't really often say this for most comedies. It mixes standard biopic drama with some inventive comedy moments that recall the style of Woody Allen; although an admittedly lower-brow Woody Allen with a fair smattering of naked women. But still, it's in that general ball-park. Stern is very good as, well, Stern. I think it's quite a reasonable achievement to be fair as it's actually not always that easy playing yourself. Take a look at a few of the cameo appearances in some of the episodes of Extras for proof of this bizarre truth. Anyway, he is a compelling central character, whose underlying personality seems to be very decent. Paul Giamatti is the other actor who stands out. His portrayal of Pig Vomit is hilarious. This is a great comic biopic. You certainly do not need to be familiar with its lead character to enjoy it, as it's a very well delivered and funny story. The humour never feels forced either, it just flows into the narrative. I am surprised I like Private Parts so much. It really changed my view of Howard Stern. Except I still think he has an annoying haircut.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a reminder
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mino
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was watching this one recently with friends and I realized I was the only one being amused. I just realized why. This is Scarface, not a comedy, but a dramatic account of foul taste with balls taking over. It's Tony Montana p***ing everything in his path. It's the logical outcome when ratings decide who stays and who leaves. But why do I find it amusing? Well, I don't, really. I guess it was just the anticipation of Giamatti's performance I had forgotten was so short spanned. I write the comment just in case I get the urge to watch this again in the future.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The King of all media is also the court jester
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nixskits
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Howard Stern is a polarizing figure in entertainment, probably the most hated and loved figure of the last half century, depending on whether you are an opponent or a fan of his. As the stats are laid out in this film, Stern's enemies are just as, if not more, likely to be found listening to his show. The program he hosts is like millions of people's cup of coffee in the morning. This room rocker of a movie is the first chapter in the big screen project of his life, showing what a crazy thirty plus years it was. Rabid fans want another instalment showing what has developed since the mid 80's when "Private Parts" ends. He's since been divorced, remarried, seen his daughters become young adults, had his head writer Jackie "The Joke Man" Martling walk away and replaced by stand up comic Artie Lange and, last but not least, left terrestrial broadcasting to become the most popular talent now on satellite radio, where millions pay to hear the show that still offends and amuses with it's political satire, prank calls, more candid than anywhere else celebrity interviews and cast of characters who make up a very broad spectrum of voices in society. "Private Parts" is one of the few comedies that's funnier each time I watch it. The showdown Stern has with his nemesis at WnnnnNBC is one of the ten most hilarious scenes in history as far as I'm concerned. Paul Giamatti is so good as Kenny (or "Pig Vomit"), you'll practically throw up with laughter when he's on screen. Not so pleasant moments before Howard found his true voice are recreated, as are classics like "The Match Game" and "Fartman" (with friend of the show John Stamos filling in for Luke Perry at the MTV appearance). Radio has it's share of popular talent, but Stern has really achieved something unique with his approach. His phenomenon doesn't come around once a generation. Just once, period!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost completely made up history. Why?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    headly66
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fact that this was directed by a woman turned what might have been a much raunchier film into a blandish comedy but Howard was probably looking to reach a broader audience at the time. It is a good movie, not great, but mostly a disappointment for Stern fans as it is not a real history of the events that took place. Here's some fake movie history: Luke Perry introduced Howard as Fartman on MTV not John Stamos. Why would Dee Snider make a face at Howard behind stage when they were great friends at the time. Oh by the way, Dee was not even there as Twisted Sister had broke up in 1988, the event was in Sept. of 1992. Neither was Flavor Flav, Ozzy, Blues Traveler, MC Hammer, or Tiny Tim, etc, etc. Also no one treated Howard that way back stage, he was very famous at the time, had a #1 book and many of the same powers to help or hurt peoples careers. There is no song called "Mama Look-A Boo Boo" from the time Howard was driving with his father. The dirty puppet show at the old folks home never happened. They leave out the fact that Howard was doing bits for years before he "discovered himself" and don't show any of the many people he worked with on air over the years in college and up to NBC. Howard was not playing punk music like the Ramones at WRNW, in fact he played mostly disco. Howard did not meet Fred in his first minute on the air at WCCC. Howard was never in a bathtub with Fred and an actress. Howard didn't have long hair until the very end of his time with WNBC. Howard did not quit on the air at WWWW when they went country. Robin did not meet Howard on the air, they had both received tapes of each other prior to meeting and then decided to work together. The on the air orgasm did not happen that way, it was with a small radio and sounded completely different. Technically it could not be done as shown in the movie. Robin was not with Howard at the beginning at NBC as she quit in DC taking a straight news job after not being picked up by WNBC and blamed Howard for abandoning her. So the first night tryout for the Stern crew could never have happened with her. It also did not sound that way, they did not say sperm and gargle with it. Their programmers nickname was pig virus, not pig vomit, why they changed this I have no clue. The prevalence of breast implants is ridiculous in this movie, (girl on phone, girl in studio, girls in lesbian dream) this was not very common in the early 80's especially for women not in the porn or movie industry. In the last scene at the concert (the film says July 27th 1985), Howard looked nothing like this in 1985 nor did Robin. Phil Rudd was not in AC/DC at the time, nor did Stern's wife go into labor. His kids were born in 1983, 1986 and 1993. She wasn't even pregnant at the time, their next child wouldn't be born until May 9, 1986. I really have no problem with movies condensing or changing things a little because of time restraints or creativity but please, when you actually make things up that never happened its a little disconcerting. I mean why don't we just make a movie where Jesus is at the Battle of Waterloo, or John Lennon gets shot on a space ship or George Washington meets Hitler. The sad thing is this happens all the time and people believe its true and take it as history, just look at Braveheart where historical characters are in the same time period even though they lived 200 years apart. Its just sad and stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bonafide comedy classic from the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Superunknovvn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember watching this movie at the cinema when it came out. Originally me and my friend had wanted to go see "Men In Black", but it was sold out. What a shame! So, we decided to see this other flick that I had heard about in a smaller cinema. It was one of the luckiest decisions I've ever made at the movies. "Private Parts" is a funny, politically incorrect tongue-in-cheek biography of the life of Howard Stern, self-proclaimed King Of All Media. Having never heard Stern's show I can only guess that this telling of the events doesn't have too much to do with reality, but that's not really what's important. The movie is entertaining and endlessly quotable. "Private Parts" is the perfect movie for a light hearted evening. Something that cannot be said about "Man In Black".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
