<filme>
 <id>
  1013
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118615
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Anaconda
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  4.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A "National Geographic" film crew is taken hostage by an insane hunter, who takes them along on his quest to capture the world's largest - and deadliest - snake.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  When a documentary crew traveling through the Amazon jungle, picks up a stranded man, they are unaware of the trouble that will occur. This stranger's hobby is to capture the giant Anaconda snake, and plans to continue targeting it on their boat, by any means necessary.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   snake
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   boat
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   anaconda
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   jungle
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   amazon
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Luis Llosa
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Hans Bauer
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Jim Cash
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jon Voight
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jennifer Lopez
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Eric Stoltz
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This river can kill you in a thousand ways.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A National Geographic crew head down the Amazon in a boat to make a documentary on a long-lost tribe of natives. On the way, they rescue a hunter from his sinking boat and take him on board. After the ship's captain is attacked by a poisonous insect and goes comatose, the hunter commandeers the boat. taking the crew hostage, he makes them go along on his insane quest to capture a giant anaconda..... First things first, the film is awful, its all over the shop and there has to be some of the most over the top acting I've ever seen in a movie. Saying that, I had a blast from beginning to end. Any film that can dub Trejos voice and kill him off in literally the first two minutes, has to be seen. The rest of the film is owned by Voight and a really dodgy looking reptile. Considering this is four years after Jurassic Park, and they spent a hundred grand every second that beast was on screen, its pretty laughable. The rest of the cast are there for filler. Lopez is good, Ice Cube is just a happier Doughboy, Wilson getting into Hollywood big time, and Jonathan Hyde as the token British snob, which is xenophobia if I've ever seen it. But there is so much fun to be had, guessing who will die first, the amount of times Voights accent changes thought the film, and obviously how much better Lopezs' nose looks today. But it is a bad film, and although I had lots of fun watching it, I cannot justify giving it a high rating. But its the best movie ever made where Eric Stoltz is asleep for 80% of the running time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Snake of the Century!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching "Anaconda is like plastering the palm of your hand against a clear glass jar that contains a rattlesnake and then gambling that you won't flinch when the snake strikes at the glass from within the container. More than half of the audience with whom I sat lost this wager every time that the eponymous snake struck. The ghoulish, B-movie plot of "Anaconda" resembles a blueprint for a theme park cruise. Scenarists Hans Bauer, Jim Cash, and Jack Epps, Jr., have borrowed surefire elements and incidents from better movies, such as "Moby Dick" (1956), "Creature from the Black Lagoon" (1954), and "Jaws" (1975). Sadly, although it is entertaining in an idiotic kind of way, "Anaconda" never seems to enthrall its audience because its campy sense of unreality undercuts its chills. The premise has something to do with journalists on an expedition heading down the Amazon in search of a lost South American tribe of Indians. Expedition leader Dr. Steven Cale (Eric Stoltz of "Killing Zoe") picks up a shipwrecked survivor, Paul Sarone (Jon Voight of "Midnight Cowboy"), along the way, but nothing good comes from this act of kindness. Voight turns in a heavily accented performance as an incredibly slimy villain. He is cast as a sinister ex-priest who resembles the feisty Quint (Robert Shaw) in "Jaws." Sarone is as obsessed with bagging giant killer snake as Ahab (Gregory Peck) was with catching a great white whale in "Moby Dick." Sarone is perfectly willing to use his new friends as bait if necessary to trap his 40-foot snake. A freak underwater accident early on puts Dr. Cale out of commission. It seems that when he dove in to fix a stuck propeller, a poisonous fish swam into his mouth and stung him. Sarone convinces the expedition film director, Terri Flores (Jennifer Lopez of "Selena") that he knows a short-cut down a blocked tributary that will cut 50 miles off their trip and save Cale's life. Foolishly, Terri believes Sarone and off they steam literally into the jaws of death. Director Louis Llosa and his scribes really heat up the suspense when Sarone commandeers the boat. Our heroes are cut off now in the untamed jungles of South America, and their radio has crapped out on them. They are without help and completely at the Sarone's mercy. Furthermore, during a big snake attack, the reptile knocks most of their fuel overboard so they have to prowl deeper into snake country to find more fuel. Standing out among the trendy-looking cast for his resilience is rapper Ice Cube from "Boyz N the Hood." He plays a tough, resourceful, film photographer who joins forces with Terri to thwart Sarone. The rest of the expedition crew are largely victims biding their time until they are eaten. If you don't know an animatronic snake from the real McCoy, or if you think this super anaconda could outrun the Road Runner, you're in for a nightmare experience. Every time this fake anaconda struck, most of the audience with which I sat went berserk. This big mother of a snake slings its coils like so many lariats around its prey. No matter if they're scrambling for a ladder or jogging through the jungle, this lethal anaconda hits them like a twister, wraps around them, and then chomps down on their heads. A pretty sight it is not. Meanwhile, the audiences sheds its collective skin. Maybe it wasn't as terrifying as "Alien," but then my audience wouldn't have known the difference. What really matters in "Anaconda" is who will the big, bad snake devour next? And how will our heroes destroy it? Director Louis Llosa, whose helmed better movies such as "The Specialist" and "Sniper," exploits the colorful Amazonian flora and fauna as does the snake. Sure, there are the inevitable anaconda cam shots and for the artistically inclined, Llosa provides a grotesque point of view shot. We get to see what it looks like staring down inside of the python's gullet as it digest another victim. Llosa paces "Anaconda" like a jack-in-the-box. He cranks up the tension between attacks. Just before his audiences has recovered, he unleashes another attack. And be warned, nothing can stop this anaconda. It can smash through windows, shatter boat hulls, and has special sensing ability that attracts it to its prey. This anaconda also shrieks like a cat when it gets hooked. As horror movies go, "Anaconda" is a straightforward, gut and churn classic. Not classic in the sense that it represents superior entertainment. Instead, classic in the sense that it egregious. The only moment in the entire film when the movie makers reach too far is Voight's tacky winking scene. This scene is so hideous that you either howl or hurl. Llosa succeeds in frightening the frijoles out of his audiences with unsavory material. Nothing wrong with that. Any movie that provokes a response is worth watching at least once. The closet that the filmmakers come to sexual encounters is a quickie on the bank that the snake hisses at, and Lopez's wet T-shirt. Despite its glossy, big-budgeted production values, "Anaconda" ends up as such a flaky carnival of outlandish special effects and unrealistic antics that you want to snicker when you should scream and scream when you should snicker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant - The snake reminds me of my first wife.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pog53
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a hoot! A brilliant B movie to watch with a large Gin & Tonic to cheer on the snake. Regrettably I was laughing so much I missed the bit where the amazingly annoying Kari Wuhrer gets the chop. The snake is actually rather good - it looks a bit like my first wife. I didn't know they can scream as well. Jon Voight is as brilliant as ever but the cast dialogue coach was clearly deranged - accents are all over the place and the music is totally out of sync with the scenes. The first snake attack on the boat is a classic - screaming girls, deranged Voight and Owen Wilson ending up as a snake stocking filler. Brilliant. Ice Cube sums it up nicely when he announces: "That's it - I'm off back to LA". Very sensible, mate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Pure Dissapoitment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thewillt08
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a movie with John Voight, Jennifer Lopez, Ice Cube, Owen Wilson, and a giant anaconda, oh dear god. As a kid I loved watching Anaconda, but after seeing it again I must have been crazy as a kid. I think I liked the fact that a giant snake was eating people. The basic premise is that Lopez and her boyfriend I guess are leading an expedition into the Amazon and tend to make a documentary or something. They run into John Voight, a strange man with a terrible accent. Chaos soon ensues when a giant snake terrorizes the passengers and it is up to them to survive or get eaten. Let's start with the cast, the cast in this movie has very little talent. Jennifer Lopez is only in the movie because she is smoking hot. Ice Cube can't act for his life. I can't stand Owen Wilson, but that's a rant for another time. John Voight is an obvious miscast because he is supposed to be the villain and every time he opens his mouth you want to block your ears. The snake looks terrible and I guess there was two of them so the title "Anaconda" is a lie. The only person I can say I actually liked was the British guy. His character actually fit well in the story and he had some development as he eventually turns into a hero of some sort. One character, I don't remember his name, started out important and the movie built him up as a hero and he is sidelined for over half of the movie. He just lays in a bed in a coma like state and it annoyed me to my core. I was counting down the scenes until he came back because he was a likable and relatable character. Instead the movie decided to focus on John Voight and his stupid character and Owen Wilson and his stupidity, then his whiney girlfriend and her stupidity. This movie was frustrating above all else. The special effects in this movie are just plain embarrassing. The snake looks terrible, the makeup and prosthetics look miserable. There is a scene where the anaconda eats a black panther and the panther looked way too fake. Even the nose it made sounded fake. Obviously they wouldn't use a real panther or snake but it was poor and lazy filmmaking. This movie was not a complete fail it did have some entertaining parts, specifically the end. Despite being very predictable and knowing which characters would die when, I don't want to vilify this movie because it isn't the worst movie I've ever seen. My favorite scene is the one when they kill the first anaconda. Voight is tied up but he being the way he is turns the scene around and then there's the whole thing with the waterfall. It had the vibe and feel of a climax but it wasn't. Even though the last scene was incredibly ridiculous it was still entertaining. Watching the snake and seeing how huge it was was cool and unexpected. As a kid I loved this movie and I still don't know why. The acting was terrible but I loved Ice Cube. He was terrible but I liked that he was in the movie. For the time he was a big pop culture figure and it made sense that he was in there. I feel like I'm rambling so I'm going to wrap this up. Overall, Anaconda will be a childhood favorite but childhood opinions mean virtually nothing. I want this movie to be rebooted and made properly. There have been sequels that were OK but still unacceptable. A giant snake terrorizing people is interesting and can be exciting. However, John Vogiht's awful accent, Ice Cube, Jennifer Lopez, either of the Wilsons, awful special effects, and poor direction is not the way to do it. I am really disappointed in the movie and it has to get the WillyT Seal of DISapproval.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It will take your breath away!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    irrelevantlife
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some movies seem to be destined to be viewed as bad, even though they contain no bad elements at all, and are only loathed because of their premise; Anaconda (1997) falls into that category of movies. What we have here is the best snake horror movie/creature feature ever created with an actual budget, good actors (great actors, Jon Voight!) and an interesting plot and setting which is used very skilfully by director Luis Llosa. No doubt one of the most impressive and deadly reptiles on this planet, the giant green anaconda is the heavies and some might even argue the longest of all constrictors, and the snake has a mythical status as a ultimate predator in the Amazon, you simply can't argue that a 33 foot snake weighing more than 400 pounds isn't one of THE ultimate aquatic and terrestrial predators. The plot is very straight forward, a team of film makers and scientists travel the Amazon River to document a illusive tribe and their ways of life, on their journey they stumble across a hunter (Jon Voight) who's boat is malfunctioning, they take him in, but soon find out that he has other plans, and is on the hunt for the giant anaconda. The special effects are truly astounding for this type of movie, considering it was made in 1996. The animatronics snake is terrific, and is modelled very accurately to its real life counterpart, something that is imperative in a movie such as this; you want as much authenticity as possible. The CGI effects are very solid, and the score is catchy, yet suspenseful at the same time. People seem to forget that many revered critics at the time of release praised the movie for being well constructed and acted, so the hate for it is completely unfound. Of course we can't review this movie without mentioning the awful sequels that did made all the mistakes the first movie avoided, such as skipping out on authenticity making the snakes look like rubber bands more than actual anacondas. Overall Anaconda, is a great snake horror movie worth watching, it has all the right ingredients of suspense, horror and humour with likable and believable characters and fantastic performance from Voight who steals the show. I strongly recommend this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hello!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    apregnantlesbian
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hello! This is my review for the popular horrible movie called "Anaconda". Anaconda is a popular horrible movie that concerns very angry snake. Maybe it will remind of Steven Spielberg's popular feature presentation "JAWS", although that was shark rather than serpent ha-ha. In this motion picture you will have many shocks and suspense. It is very surprising when snake pops out!!! Be sure not to watch this with your dog, maybe it is a dumb dog and will want to chasing the snake ha-ha. Some interesting trivia about snake, for your enjoyment: - Snake is not a rope. However, it is like an angry rope. - Snake does not have legs.!! So how does it walk??? Snake is full of mysteries...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to take it serious when the snake looks like a giant puppet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JSwallowX1
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's suffice to say that when Jennifer Lopez, Ice Cube and Owen Wilson are amongst the lead cast in a film about a giant snake in the Amazon that it is not going to be much good. And indeed IT isn't; and despite Jon Voight and Eric Stoltz also being amongst the cast in this $45,000,000 production it is a very embarrassing project to be part of. The film has been followed by three sequels to date. A National Geographic crew travel into the heart of the Amazon to shoot a documentary on the long-lost tribe reported to be somewhere along the banks of the immense river. "Cannibal Holocaust" it is not, I'm afraid. Director Terri Flores (Jennifer Lopez) and her anthropologist boyfriend (Eric Stoltz) lead the team. Not long into their voyage they rescue a stranded Paraguayan snake hunter named Paul (Jon Voight). In return, he offers to help them find the lost tribe they are looking for, claiming to have met them. But his true plans unfold when he takes over the boat and forces the crew to aid him in his manic quest to track down a record-breaking Giant Anaconda. And it descends into a typical hunters-become-the-hunted scenario henceforth. For the first half an hour at least, "Anaconda" is somewhat enjoyable. But after that it quickly descends into mediocrity. One must ask the question as to where exactly the $45 million went, because it was certainly not invested in to the special effects department, that's for sure. The Anaconda looks ridiculous. I've seen monsters on the ludicrous Syfy channel films from the last ten years with lower budgets than this managing to turn out better looking monsters. Albeit, just slightly. And I know it was the year 1997, but come on now people, it wasn't that long ago and there was some superb CGI around that time and even before it. "Anaconda" is just a very poorly made film. The acting is diabolical... horrendous (Although in saying that Voight's performance was somewhat interesting). The script resembles something written on a rainy afternoon in after-school study by two bored kids. With dialogue as ingenious as this: "Is it just me or does the jungle make you really, really horny?" that one was courtesy of our man Owen Wilson. And Ice Cube has to get his two cents worth in there too - "That's it, man, I'm getting' the hell back to LA". But Owen Wilson delivers yet again and takes the cake - "You don't know sh*t about the sh*t we're in out here!" Genius. As an adventure film it's oh-so-typical but I suppose it does deliver the trills required for the genre. As a horror movie, it's just too cheap and flamboyant to be anything scary or unsettling. Indeed, the snake may devour someone whole in the film but its more comical than it is disturbing. The snake resembles a giant puppet, and in some scenes I could have sworn I could make-out the wires or whatever they were bobbing it up and down in the water or springing it out of the water like a jack-in-the-box.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anaconda (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfnmbessert-224-279128
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'Anaconda' now, fifteen years after it's release, it's clear to see that this was really just a spiffed up B-movie, cashing in on the success to other monster flicks of the time which were hugely popular like 'Jurassic Park' and 'The Lost World: Jurassic Park' both of which I lump in along with the likes of 'Anaconda'. I have fond memories of wearing out my VHS copies of these films when I was younger, and while 'Anaconda' doesn't stand up to the likes of 'Jurassic Park' in any way, it had its fair share of influencing countless other films which would try to imitate the huge snake killing and eating everyone, none of which had a premise as good as that of 'Anaconda'. Factual errors all aside, the cast is good, and it's notable especially because of the direction they would later take in the following decade, Owen Wilson going more in the direction of comedy rather than action. Jon Voight is the perfect bad guy here, Ice Cube retains his gangster street cred, alongside Jennifer Lopez, and the absolutely beautiful Kari Wuhrer. It's nice that Eric Stoltz's pretentious character is comatose for a good portion of the film, as he's one of the least likable, although I'd say all of the characters here are pretty well written. Danny Trejo's small role in the beginning was something I had forgotten about, being that I haven't seen this in a long time. I know it's probably really only 6 material but since I hold this film in higher regard because of nostalgia, I'm going to give it a 7. ANACONDA ----7/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whether you're laughing at it or with it, at least you're laughing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a worrying sign that the first 60 seconds of a 90 minute film feels the need to 'serious up' the tone by running a lengthy blurb that effectively says 'big snakes are big and dangerous'. Ummmmm. Duh. Now bring on the killer legless lizards! Featuring a cast that is not so much 'good' as 'recognisable' Anaconda thankfully then gets down to the business of being an enjoyably inane flick with B actors wrestling fake snakes and being thrown around by big CGI effects. The threadbare plot has a doco crew traveling the largely unexplored tributaries of the Amazon searching for a long lost tribe of primitive South Americans who legend has it are protected by giant snakes. And how. After a few hiccups in the mission they pick up supposedly 'Paraguayan' snake hunter played by Jon Voight in a hammy performance to rival that of Tim Curry in Congo. He leads the boat on a snaky ahem 'sneaky' shortcut that should save all involved time. Now the fun starts. From this point on there is little for the cast to do but look alternately scared and suspicious in between running around like white mice. The talentless J Lo looks suitably lost and confused  no surprises there  and Eric Stoltz is laid up injured for half the film while Owen Wilson hones his shaggy locked surfer boy thing that has since made him a wealthy man. Ice Cube gets the worst wardrobe and the best lines, and I dare you not to chuckle when they show introduce 'snake stomach' cam near the end of the film. While you might be laughing or gasping about &frac12; the time with and the other &frac12; in spite of the goings on, I guess one way or the other at least you're laughing. Final Rating  5 / 10. Anaconda was released during a spate of creepy crawly based movies in the 90s, it won't blow you away but it was by no means the worst of the bunch and it spawned the usual sucky sequels.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anaconda (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a stupid B-Movie with enough quality to fly by, and enough camp charm to get away with such cinematic crimes. The cast play it straight, apart from Voight. I'm pretty sure he was drunk during the shooting, coming out with an inexplicable accent and a look reminiscent of Hannibal Lecter. It's ridiculous fun, with hokey CGI and animatronics. The animatronics are great and make me miss the 90s. It's a big snake shaped tube and goes from slow robotic motions, to super fast CGI. Cube and Hyde manage some, at times, adorable dialogue. Voight's presence also unites the rest of the cast, and each character gets their own heroic captain moment. Fun filled and just plain bad. I loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This river can kill you in a thousand ways.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A National Geographic crew head down the Amazon in a boat to make a documentary on a long-lost tribe of natives. On the way, they rescue a hunter from his sinking boat and take him on board. After the ship's captain is attacked by a poisonous insect and goes comatose, the hunter commandeers the boat. taking the crew hostage, he makes them go along on his insane quest to capture a giant anaconda..... First things first, the film is awful, its all over the shop and there has to be some of the most over the top acting I've ever seen in a movie. Saying that, I had a blast from beginning to end. Any film that can dub Trejos voice and kill him off in literally the first two minutes, has to be seen. The rest of the film is owned by Voight and a really dodgy looking reptile. Considering this is four years after Jurassic Park, and they spent a hundred grand every second that beast was on screen, its pretty laughable. The rest of the cast are there for filler. Lopez is good, Ice Cube is just a happier Doughboy, Wilson getting into Hollywood big time, and Jonathan Hyde as the token British snob, which is xenophobia if I've ever seen it. But there is so much fun to be had, guessing who will die first, the amount of times Voights accent changes thought the film, and obviously how much better Lopezs' nose looks today. But it is a bad film, and although I had lots of fun watching it, I cannot justify giving it a high rating. But its the best movie ever made where Eric Stoltz is asleep for 80% of the running time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Snake of the Century!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching "Anaconda is like plastering the palm of your hand against a clear glass jar that contains a rattlesnake and then gambling that you won't flinch when the snake strikes at the glass from within the container. More than half of the audience with whom I sat lost this wager every time that the eponymous snake struck. The ghoulish, B-movie plot of "Anaconda" resembles a blueprint for a theme park cruise. Scenarists Hans Bauer, Jim Cash, and Jack Epps, Jr., have borrowed surefire elements and incidents from better movies, such as "Moby Dick" (1956), "Creature from the Black Lagoon" (1954), and "Jaws" (1975). Sadly, although it is entertaining in an idiotic kind of way, "Anaconda" never seems to enthrall its audience because its campy sense of unreality undercuts its chills. The premise has something to do with journalists on an expedition heading down the Amazon in search of a lost South American tribe of Indians. Expedition leader Dr. Steven Cale (Eric Stoltz of "Killing Zoe") picks up a shipwrecked survivor, Paul Sarone (Jon Voight of "Midnight Cowboy"), along the way, but nothing good comes from this act of kindness. Voight turns in a heavily accented performance as an incredibly slimy villain. He is cast as a sinister ex-priest who resembles the feisty Quint (Robert Shaw) in "Jaws." Sarone is as obsessed with bagging giant killer snake as Ahab (Gregory Peck) was with catching a great white whale in "Moby Dick." Sarone is perfectly willing to use his new friends as bait if necessary to trap his 40-foot snake. A freak underwater accident early on puts Dr. Cale out of commission. It seems that when he dove in to fix a stuck propeller, a poisonous fish swam into his mouth and stung him. Sarone convinces the expedition film director, Terri Flores (Jennifer Lopez of "Selena") that he knows a short-cut down a blocked tributary that will cut 50 miles off their trip and save Cale's life. Foolishly, Terri believes Sarone and off they steam literally into the jaws of death. Director Louis Llosa and his scribes really heat up the suspense when Sarone commandeers the boat. Our heroes are cut off now in the untamed jungles of South America, and their radio has crapped out on them. They are without help and completely at the Sarone's mercy. Furthermore, during a big snake attack, the reptile knocks most of their fuel overboard so they have to prowl deeper into snake country to find more fuel. Standing out among the trendy-looking cast for his resilience is rapper Ice Cube from "Boyz N the Hood." He plays a tough, resourceful, film photographer who joins forces with Terri to thwart Sarone. The rest of the expedition crew are largely victims biding their time until they are eaten. If you don't know an animatronic snake from the real McCoy, or if you think this super anaconda could outrun the Road Runner, you're in for a nightmare experience. Every time this fake anaconda struck, most of the audience with which I sat went berserk. This big mother of a snake slings its coils like so many lariats around its prey. No matter if they're scrambling for a ladder or jogging through the jungle, this lethal anaconda hits them like a twister, wraps around them, and then chomps down on their heads. A pretty sight it is not. Meanwhile, the audiences sheds its collective skin. Maybe it wasn't as terrifying as "Alien," but then my audience wouldn't have known the difference. What really matters in "Anaconda" is who will the big, bad snake devour next? And how will our heroes destroy it? Director Louis Llosa, whose helmed better movies such as "The Specialist" and "Sniper," exploits the colorful Amazonian flora and fauna as does the snake. Sure, there are the inevitable anaconda cam shots and for the artistically inclined, Llosa provides a grotesque point of view shot. We get to see what it looks like staring down inside of the python's gullet as it digest another victim. Llosa paces "Anaconda" like a jack-in-the-box. He cranks up the tension between attacks. Just before his audiences has recovered, he unleashes another attack. And be warned, nothing can stop this anaconda. It can smash through windows, shatter boat hulls, and has special sensing ability that attracts it to its prey. This anaconda also shrieks like a cat when it gets hooked. As horror movies go, "Anaconda" is a straightforward, gut and churn classic. Not classic in the sense that it represents superior entertainment. Instead, classic in the sense that it egregious. The only moment in the entire film when the movie makers reach too far is Voight's tacky winking scene. This scene is so hideous that you either howl or hurl. Llosa succeeds in frightening the frijoles out of his audiences with unsavory material. Nothing wrong with that. Any movie that provokes a response is worth watching at least once. The closet that the filmmakers come to sexual encounters is a quickie on the bank that the snake hisses at, and Lopez's wet T-shirt. Despite its glossy, big-budgeted production values, "Anaconda" ends up as such a flaky carnival of outlandish special effects and unrealistic antics that you want to snicker when you should scream and scream when you should snicker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant - The snake reminds me of my first wife.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pog53
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a hoot! A brilliant B movie to watch with a large Gin & Tonic to cheer on the snake. Regrettably I was laughing so much I missed the bit where the amazingly annoying Kari Wuhrer gets the chop. The snake is actually rather good - it looks a bit like my first wife. I didn't know they can scream as well. Jon Voight is as brilliant as ever but the cast dialogue coach was clearly deranged - accents are all over the place and the music is totally out of sync with the scenes. The first snake attack on the boat is a classic - screaming girls, deranged Voight and Owen Wilson ending up as a snake stocking filler. Brilliant. Ice Cube sums it up nicely when he announces: "That's it - I'm off back to LA". Very sensible, mate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Pure Dissapoitment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thewillt08
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a movie with John Voight, Jennifer Lopez, Ice Cube, Owen Wilson, and a giant anaconda, oh dear god. As a kid I loved watching Anaconda, but after seeing it again I must have been crazy as a kid. I think I liked the fact that a giant snake was eating people. The basic premise is that Lopez and her boyfriend I guess are leading an expedition into the Amazon and tend to make a documentary or something. They run into John Voight, a strange man with a terrible accent. Chaos soon ensues when a giant snake terrorizes the passengers and it is up to them to survive or get eaten. Let's start with the cast, the cast in this movie has very little talent. Jennifer Lopez is only in the movie because she is smoking hot. Ice Cube can't act for his life. I can't stand Owen Wilson, but that's a rant for another time. John Voight is an obvious miscast because he is supposed to be the villain and every time he opens his mouth you want to block your ears. The snake looks terrible and I guess there was two of them so the title "Anaconda" is a lie. The only person I can say I actually liked was the British guy. His character actually fit well in the story and he had some development as he eventually turns into a hero of some sort. One character, I don't remember his name, started out important and the movie built him up as a hero and he is sidelined for over half of the movie. He just lays in a bed in a coma like state and it annoyed me to my core. I was counting down the scenes until he came back because he was a likable and relatable character. Instead the movie decided to focus on John Voight and his stupid character and Owen Wilson and his stupidity, then his whiney girlfriend and her stupidity. This movie was frustrating above all else. The special effects in this movie are just plain embarrassing. The snake looks terrible, the makeup and prosthetics look miserable. There is a scene where the anaconda eats a black panther and the panther looked way too fake. Even the nose it made sounded fake. Obviously they wouldn't use a real panther or snake but it was poor and lazy filmmaking. This movie was not a complete fail it did have some entertaining parts, specifically the end. Despite being very predictable and knowing which characters would die when, I don't want to vilify this movie because it isn't the worst movie I've ever seen. My favorite scene is the one when they kill the first anaconda. Voight is tied up but he being the way he is turns the scene around and then there's the whole thing with the waterfall. It had the vibe and feel of a climax but it wasn't. Even though the last scene was incredibly ridiculous it was still entertaining. Watching the snake and seeing how huge it was was cool and unexpected. As a kid I loved this movie and I still don't know why. The acting was terrible but I loved Ice Cube. He was terrible but I liked that he was in the movie. For the time he was a big pop culture figure and it made sense that he was in there. I feel like I'm rambling so I'm going to wrap this up. Overall, Anaconda will be a childhood favorite but childhood opinions mean virtually nothing. I want this movie to be rebooted and made properly. There have been sequels that were OK but still unacceptable. A giant snake terrorizing people is interesting and can be exciting. However, John Vogiht's awful accent, Ice Cube, Jennifer Lopez, either of the Wilsons, awful special effects, and poor direction is not the way to do it. I am really disappointed in the movie and it has to get the WillyT Seal of DISapproval.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It will take your breath away!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    irrelevantlife
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some movies seem to be destined to be viewed as bad, even though they contain no bad elements at all, and are only loathed because of their premise; Anaconda (1997) falls into that category of movies. What we have here is the best snake horror movie/creature feature ever created with an actual budget, good actors (great actors, Jon Voight!) and an interesting plot and setting which is used very skilfully by director Luis Llosa. No doubt one of the most impressive and deadly reptiles on this planet, the giant green anaconda is the heavies and some might even argue the longest of all constrictors, and the snake has a mythical status as a ultimate predator in the Amazon, you simply can't argue that a 33 foot snake weighing more than 400 pounds isn't one of THE ultimate aquatic and terrestrial predators. The plot is very straight forward, a team of film makers and scientists travel the Amazon River to document a illusive tribe and their ways of life, on their journey they stumble across a hunter (Jon Voight) who's boat is malfunctioning, they take him in, but soon find out that he has other plans, and is on the hunt for the giant anaconda. The special effects are truly astounding for this type of movie, considering it was made in 1996. The animatronics snake is terrific, and is modelled very accurately to its real life counterpart, something that is imperative in a movie such as this; you want as much authenticity as possible. The CGI effects are very solid, and the score is catchy, yet suspenseful at the same time. People seem to forget that many revered critics at the time of release praised the movie for being well constructed and acted, so the hate for it is completely unfound. Of course we can't review this movie without mentioning the awful sequels that did made all the mistakes the first movie avoided, such as skipping out on authenticity making the snakes look like rubber bands more than actual anacondas. Overall Anaconda, is a great snake horror movie worth watching, it has all the right ingredients of suspense, horror and humour with likable and believable characters and fantastic performance from Voight who steals the show. I strongly recommend this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hello!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    apregnantlesbian
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hello! This is my review for the popular horrible movie called "Anaconda". Anaconda is a popular horrible movie that concerns very angry snake. Maybe it will remind of Steven Spielberg's popular feature presentation "JAWS", although that was shark rather than serpent ha-ha. In this motion picture you will have many shocks and suspense. It is very surprising when snake pops out!!! Be sure not to watch this with your dog, maybe it is a dumb dog and will want to chasing the snake ha-ha. Some interesting trivia about snake, for your enjoyment: - Snake is not a rope. However, it is like an angry rope. - Snake does not have legs.!! So how does it walk??? Snake is full of mysteries...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to take it serious when the snake looks like a giant puppet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JSwallowX1
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's suffice to say that when Jennifer Lopez, Ice Cube and Owen Wilson are amongst the lead cast in a film about a giant snake in the Amazon that it is not going to be much good. And indeed IT isn't; and despite Jon Voight and Eric Stoltz also being amongst the cast in this $45,000,000 production it is a very embarrassing project to be part of. The film has been followed by three sequels to date. A National Geographic crew travel into the heart of the Amazon to shoot a documentary on the long-lost tribe reported to be somewhere along the banks of the immense river. "Cannibal Holocaust" it is not, I'm afraid. Director Terri Flores (Jennifer Lopez) and her anthropologist boyfriend (Eric Stoltz) lead the team. Not long into their voyage they rescue a stranded Paraguayan snake hunter named Paul (Jon Voight). In return, he offers to help them find the lost tribe they are looking for, claiming to have met them. But his true plans unfold when he takes over the boat and forces the crew to aid him in his manic quest to track down a record-breaking Giant Anaconda. And it descends into a typical hunters-become-the-hunted scenario henceforth. For the first half an hour at least, "Anaconda" is somewhat enjoyable. But after that it quickly descends into mediocrity. One must ask the question as to where exactly the $45 million went, because it was certainly not invested in to the special effects department, that's for sure. The Anaconda looks ridiculous. I've seen monsters on the ludicrous Syfy channel films from the last ten years with lower budgets than this managing to turn out better looking monsters. Albeit, just slightly. And I know it was the year 1997, but come on now people, it wasn't that long ago and there was some superb CGI around that time and even before it. "Anaconda" is just a very poorly made film. The acting is diabolical... horrendous (Although in saying that Voight's performance was somewhat interesting). The script resembles something written on a rainy afternoon in after-school study by two bored kids. With dialogue as ingenious as this: "Is it just me or does the jungle make you really, really horny?" that one was courtesy of our man Owen Wilson. And Ice Cube has to get his two cents worth in there too - "That's it, man, I'm getting' the hell back to LA". But Owen Wilson delivers yet again and takes the cake - "You don't know sh*t about the sh*t we're in out here!" Genius. As an adventure film it's oh-so-typical but I suppose it does deliver the trills required for the genre. As a horror movie, it's just too cheap and flamboyant to be anything scary or unsettling. Indeed, the snake may devour someone whole in the film but its more comical than it is disturbing. The snake resembles a giant puppet, and in some scenes I could have sworn I could make-out the wires or whatever they were bobbing it up and down in the water or springing it out of the water like a jack-in-the-box.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anaconda (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfnmbessert-224-279128
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'Anaconda' now, fifteen years after it's release, it's clear to see that this was really just a spiffed up B-movie, cashing in on the success to other monster flicks of the time which were hugely popular like 'Jurassic Park' and 'The Lost World: Jurassic Park' both of which I lump in along with the likes of 'Anaconda'. I have fond memories of wearing out my VHS copies of these films when I was younger, and while 'Anaconda' doesn't stand up to the likes of 'Jurassic Park' in any way, it had its fair share of influencing countless other films which would try to imitate the huge snake killing and eating everyone, none of which had a premise as good as that of 'Anaconda'. Factual errors all aside, the cast is good, and it's notable especially because of the direction they would later take in the following decade, Owen Wilson going more in the direction of comedy rather than action. Jon Voight is the perfect bad guy here, Ice Cube retains his gangster street cred, alongside Jennifer Lopez, and the absolutely beautiful Kari Wuhrer. It's nice that Eric Stoltz's pretentious character is comatose for a good portion of the film, as he's one of the least likable, although I'd say all of the characters here are pretty well written. Danny Trejo's small role in the beginning was something I had forgotten about, being that I haven't seen this in a long time. I know it's probably really only 6 material but since I hold this film in higher regard because of nostalgia, I'm going to give it a 7. ANACONDA ----7/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whether you're laughing at it or with it, at least you're laughing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a worrying sign that the first 60 seconds of a 90 minute film feels the need to 'serious up' the tone by running a lengthy blurb that effectively says 'big snakes are big and dangerous'. Ummmmm. Duh. Now bring on the killer legless lizards! Featuring a cast that is not so much 'good' as 'recognisable' Anaconda thankfully then gets down to the business of being an enjoyably inane flick with B actors wrestling fake snakes and being thrown around by big CGI effects. The threadbare plot has a doco crew traveling the largely unexplored tributaries of the Amazon searching for a long lost tribe of primitive South Americans who legend has it are protected by giant snakes. And how. After a few hiccups in the mission they pick up supposedly 'Paraguayan' snake hunter played by Jon Voight in a hammy performance to rival that of Tim Curry in Congo. He leads the boat on a snaky ahem 'sneaky' shortcut that should save all involved time. Now the fun starts. From this point on there is little for the cast to do but look alternately scared and suspicious in between running around like white mice. The talentless J Lo looks suitably lost and confused  no surprises there  and Eric Stoltz is laid up injured for half the film while Owen Wilson hones his shaggy locked surfer boy thing that has since made him a wealthy man. Ice Cube gets the worst wardrobe and the best lines, and I dare you not to chuckle when they show introduce 'snake stomach' cam near the end of the film. While you might be laughing or gasping about &frac12; the time with and the other &frac12; in spite of the goings on, I guess one way or the other at least you're laughing. Final Rating  5 / 10. Anaconda was released during a spate of creepy crawly based movies in the 90s, it won't blow you away but it was by no means the worst of the bunch and it spawned the usual sucky sequels.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anaconda (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a stupid B-Movie with enough quality to fly by, and enough camp charm to get away with such cinematic crimes. The cast play it straight, apart from Voight. I'm pretty sure he was drunk during the shooting, coming out with an inexplicable accent and a look reminiscent of Hannibal Lecter. It's ridiculous fun, with hokey CGI and animatronics. The animatronics are great and make me miss the 90s. It's a big snake shaped tube and goes from slow robotic motions, to super fast CGI. Cube and Hyde manage some, at times, adorable dialogue. Voight's presence also unites the rest of the cast, and each character gets their own heroic captain moment. Fun filled and just plain bad. I loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This river can kill you in a thousand ways.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A National Geographic crew head down the Amazon in a boat to make a documentary on a long-lost tribe of natives. On the way, they rescue a hunter from his sinking boat and take him on board. After the ship's captain is attacked by a poisonous insect and goes comatose, the hunter commandeers the boat. taking the crew hostage, he makes them go along on his insane quest to capture a giant anaconda..... First things first, the film is awful, its all over the shop and there has to be some of the most over the top acting I've ever seen in a movie. Saying that, I had a blast from beginning to end. Any film that can dub Trejos voice and kill him off in literally the first two minutes, has to be seen. The rest of the film is owned by Voight and a really dodgy looking reptile. Considering this is four years after Jurassic Park, and they spent a hundred grand every second that beast was on screen, its pretty laughable. The rest of the cast are there for filler. Lopez is good, Ice Cube is just a happier Doughboy, Wilson getting into Hollywood big time, and Jonathan Hyde as the token British snob, which is xenophobia if I've ever seen it. But there is so much fun to be had, guessing who will die first, the amount of times Voights accent changes thought the film, and obviously how much better Lopezs' nose looks today. But it is a bad film, and although I had lots of fun watching it, I cannot justify giving it a high rating. But its the best movie ever made where Eric Stoltz is asleep for 80% of the running time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Snake of the Century!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching "Anaconda is like plastering the palm of your hand against a clear glass jar that contains a rattlesnake and then gambling that you won't flinch when the snake strikes at the glass from within the container. More than half of the audience with whom I sat lost this wager every time that the eponymous snake struck. The ghoulish, B-movie plot of "Anaconda" resembles a blueprint for a theme park cruise. Scenarists Hans Bauer, Jim Cash, and Jack Epps, Jr., have borrowed surefire elements and incidents from better movies, such as "Moby Dick" (1956), "Creature from the Black Lagoon" (1954), and "Jaws" (1975). Sadly, although it is entertaining in an idiotic kind of way, "Anaconda" never seems to enthrall its audience because its campy sense of unreality undercuts its chills. The premise has something to do with journalists on an expedition heading down the Amazon in search of a lost South American tribe of Indians. Expedition leader Dr. Steven Cale (Eric Stoltz of "Killing Zoe") picks up a shipwrecked survivor, Paul Sarone (Jon Voight of "Midnight Cowboy"), along the way, but nothing good comes from this act of kindness. Voight turns in a heavily accented performance as an incredibly slimy villain. He is cast as a sinister ex-priest who resembles the feisty Quint (Robert Shaw) in "Jaws." Sarone is as obsessed with bagging giant killer snake as Ahab (Gregory Peck) was with catching a great white whale in "Moby Dick." Sarone is perfectly willing to use his new friends as bait if necessary to trap his 40-foot snake. A freak underwater accident early on puts Dr. Cale out of commission. It seems that when he dove in to fix a stuck propeller, a poisonous fish swam into his mouth and stung him. Sarone convinces the expedition film director, Terri Flores (Jennifer Lopez of "Selena") that he knows a short-cut down a blocked tributary that will cut 50 miles off their trip and save Cale's life. Foolishly, Terri believes Sarone and off they steam literally into the jaws of death. Director Louis Llosa and his scribes really heat up the suspense when Sarone commandeers the boat. Our heroes are cut off now in the untamed jungles of South America, and their radio has crapped out on them. They are without help and completely at the Sarone's mercy. Furthermore, during a big snake attack, the reptile knocks most of their fuel overboard so they have to prowl deeper into snake country to find more fuel. Standing out among the trendy-looking cast for his resilience is rapper Ice Cube from "Boyz N the Hood." He plays a tough, resourceful, film photographer who joins forces with Terri to thwart Sarone. The rest of the expedition crew are largely victims biding their time until they are eaten. If you don't know an animatronic snake from the real McCoy, or if you think this super anaconda could outrun the Road Runner, you're in for a nightmare experience. Every time this fake anaconda struck, most of the audience with which I sat went berserk. This big mother of a snake slings its coils like so many lariats around its prey. No matter if they're scrambling for a ladder or jogging through the jungle, this lethal anaconda hits them like a twister, wraps around them, and then chomps down on their heads. A pretty sight it is not. Meanwhile, the audiences sheds its collective skin. Maybe it wasn't as terrifying as "Alien," but then my audience wouldn't have known the difference. What really matters in "Anaconda" is who will the big, bad snake devour next? And how will our heroes destroy it? Director Louis Llosa, whose helmed better movies such as "The Specialist" and "Sniper," exploits the colorful Amazonian flora and fauna as does the snake. Sure, there are the inevitable anaconda cam shots and for the artistically inclined, Llosa provides a grotesque point of view shot. We get to see what it looks like staring down inside of the python's gullet as it digest another victim. Llosa paces "Anaconda" like a jack-in-the-box. He cranks up the tension between attacks. Just before his audiences has recovered, he unleashes another attack. And be warned, nothing can stop this anaconda. It can smash through windows, shatter boat hulls, and has special sensing ability that attracts it to its prey. This anaconda also shrieks like a cat when it gets hooked. As horror movies go, "Anaconda" is a straightforward, gut and churn classic. Not classic in the sense that it represents superior entertainment. Instead, classic in the sense that it egregious. The only moment in the entire film when the movie makers reach too far is Voight's tacky winking scene. This scene is so hideous that you either howl or hurl. Llosa succeeds in frightening the frijoles out of his audiences with unsavory material. Nothing wrong with that. Any movie that provokes a response is worth watching at least once. The closet that the filmmakers come to sexual encounters is a quickie on the bank that the snake hisses at, and Lopez's wet T-shirt. Despite its glossy, big-budgeted production values, "Anaconda" ends up as such a flaky carnival of outlandish special effects and unrealistic antics that you want to snicker when you should scream and scream when you should snicker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant - The snake reminds me of my first wife.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pog53
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a hoot! A brilliant B movie to watch with a large Gin & Tonic to cheer on the snake. Regrettably I was laughing so much I missed the bit where the amazingly annoying Kari Wuhrer gets the chop. The snake is actually rather good - it looks a bit like my first wife. I didn't know they can scream as well. Jon Voight is as brilliant as ever but the cast dialogue coach was clearly deranged - accents are all over the place and the music is totally out of sync with the scenes. The first snake attack on the boat is a classic - screaming girls, deranged Voight and Owen Wilson ending up as a snake stocking filler. Brilliant. Ice Cube sums it up nicely when he announces: "That's it - I'm off back to LA". Very sensible, mate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Pure Dissapoitment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thewillt08
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a movie with John Voight, Jennifer Lopez, Ice Cube, Owen Wilson, and a giant anaconda, oh dear god. As a kid I loved watching Anaconda, but after seeing it again I must have been crazy as a kid. I think I liked the fact that a giant snake was eating people. The basic premise is that Lopez and her boyfriend I guess are leading an expedition into the Amazon and tend to make a documentary or something. They run into John Voight, a strange man with a terrible accent. Chaos soon ensues when a giant snake terrorizes the passengers and it is up to them to survive or get eaten. Let's start with the cast, the cast in this movie has very little talent. Jennifer Lopez is only in the movie because she is smoking hot. Ice Cube can't act for his life. I can't stand Owen Wilson, but that's a rant for another time. John Voight is an obvious miscast because he is supposed to be the villain and every time he opens his mouth you want to block your ears. The snake looks terrible and I guess there was two of them so the title "Anaconda" is a lie. The only person I can say I actually liked was the British guy. His character actually fit well in the story and he had some development as he eventually turns into a hero of some sort. One character, I don't remember his name, started out important and the movie built him up as a hero and he is sidelined for over half of the movie. He just lays in a bed in a coma like state and it annoyed me to my core. I was counting down the scenes until he came back because he was a likable and relatable character. Instead the movie decided to focus on John Voight and his stupid character and Owen Wilson and his stupidity, then his whiney girlfriend and her stupidity. This movie was frustrating above all else. The special effects in this movie are just plain embarrassing. The snake looks terrible, the makeup and prosthetics look miserable. There is a scene where the anaconda eats a black panther and the panther looked way too fake. Even the nose it made sounded fake. Obviously they wouldn't use a real panther or snake but it was poor and lazy filmmaking. This movie was not a complete fail it did have some entertaining parts, specifically the end. Despite being very predictable and knowing which characters would die when, I don't want to vilify this movie because it isn't the worst movie I've ever seen. My favorite scene is the one when they kill the first anaconda. Voight is tied up but he being the way he is turns the scene around and then there's the whole thing with the waterfall. It had the vibe and feel of a climax but it wasn't. Even though the last scene was incredibly ridiculous it was still entertaining. Watching the snake and seeing how huge it was was cool and unexpected. As a kid I loved this movie and I still don't know why. The acting was terrible but I loved Ice Cube. He was terrible but I liked that he was in the movie. For the time he was a big pop culture figure and it made sense that he was in there. I feel like I'm rambling so I'm going to wrap this up. Overall, Anaconda will be a childhood favorite but childhood opinions mean virtually nothing. I want this movie to be rebooted and made properly. There have been sequels that were OK but still unacceptable. A giant snake terrorizing people is interesting and can be exciting. However, John Vogiht's awful accent, Ice Cube, Jennifer Lopez, either of the Wilsons, awful special effects, and poor direction is not the way to do it. I am really disappointed in the movie and it has to get the WillyT Seal of DISapproval.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It will take your breath away!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    irrelevantlife
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some movies seem to be destined to be viewed as bad, even though they contain no bad elements at all, and are only loathed because of their premise; Anaconda (1997) falls into that category of movies. What we have here is the best snake horror movie/creature feature ever created with an actual budget, good actors (great actors, Jon Voight!) and an interesting plot and setting which is used very skilfully by director Luis Llosa. No doubt one of the most impressive and deadly reptiles on this planet, the giant green anaconda is the heavies and some might even argue the longest of all constrictors, and the snake has a mythical status as a ultimate predator in the Amazon, you simply can't argue that a 33 foot snake weighing more than 400 pounds isn't one of THE ultimate aquatic and terrestrial predators. The plot is very straight forward, a team of film makers and scientists travel the Amazon River to document a illusive tribe and their ways of life, on their journey they stumble across a hunter (Jon Voight) who's boat is malfunctioning, they take him in, but soon find out that he has other plans, and is on the hunt for the giant anaconda. The special effects are truly astounding for this type of movie, considering it was made in 1996. The animatronics snake is terrific, and is modelled very accurately to its real life counterpart, something that is imperative in a movie such as this; you want as much authenticity as possible. The CGI effects are very solid, and the score is catchy, yet suspenseful at the same time. People seem to forget that many revered critics at the time of release praised the movie for being well constructed and acted, so the hate for it is completely unfound. Of course we can't review this movie without mentioning the awful sequels that did made all the mistakes the first movie avoided, such as skipping out on authenticity making the snakes look like rubber bands more than actual anacondas. Overall Anaconda, is a great snake horror movie worth watching, it has all the right ingredients of suspense, horror and humour with likable and believable characters and fantastic performance from Voight who steals the show. I strongly recommend this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hello!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    apregnantlesbian
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hello! This is my review for the popular horrible movie called "Anaconda". Anaconda is a popular horrible movie that concerns very angry snake. Maybe it will remind of Steven Spielberg's popular feature presentation "JAWS", although that was shark rather than serpent ha-ha. In this motion picture you will have many shocks and suspense. It is very surprising when snake pops out!!! Be sure not to watch this with your dog, maybe it is a dumb dog and will want to chasing the snake ha-ha. Some interesting trivia about snake, for your enjoyment: - Snake is not a rope. However, it is like an angry rope. - Snake does not have legs.!! So how does it walk??? Snake is full of mysteries...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to take it serious when the snake looks like a giant puppet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JSwallowX1
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's suffice to say that when Jennifer Lopez, Ice Cube and Owen Wilson are amongst the lead cast in a film about a giant snake in the Amazon that it is not going to be much good. And indeed IT isn't; and despite Jon Voight and Eric Stoltz also being amongst the cast in this $45,000,000 production it is a very embarrassing project to be part of. The film has been followed by three sequels to date. A National Geographic crew travel into the heart of the Amazon to shoot a documentary on the long-lost tribe reported to be somewhere along the banks of the immense river. "Cannibal Holocaust" it is not, I'm afraid. Director Terri Flores (Jennifer Lopez) and her anthropologist boyfriend (Eric Stoltz) lead the team. Not long into their voyage they rescue a stranded Paraguayan snake hunter named Paul (Jon Voight). In return, he offers to help them find the lost tribe they are looking for, claiming to have met them. But his true plans unfold when he takes over the boat and forces the crew to aid him in his manic quest to track down a record-breaking Giant Anaconda. And it descends into a typical hunters-become-the-hunted scenario henceforth. For the first half an hour at least, "Anaconda" is somewhat enjoyable. But after that it quickly descends into mediocrity. One must ask the question as to where exactly the $45 million went, because it was certainly not invested in to the special effects department, that's for sure. The Anaconda looks ridiculous. I've seen monsters on the ludicrous Syfy channel films from the last ten years with lower budgets than this managing to turn out better looking monsters. Albeit, just slightly. And I know it was the year 1997, but come on now people, it wasn't that long ago and there was some superb CGI around that time and even before it. "Anaconda" is just a very poorly made film. The acting is diabolical... horrendous (Although in saying that Voight's performance was somewhat interesting). The script resembles something written on a rainy afternoon in after-school study by two bored kids. With dialogue as ingenious as this: "Is it just me or does the jungle make you really, really horny?" that one was courtesy of our man Owen Wilson. And Ice Cube has to get his two cents worth in there too - "That's it, man, I'm getting' the hell back to LA". But Owen Wilson delivers yet again and takes the cake - "You don't know sh*t about the sh*t we're in out here!" Genius. As an adventure film it's oh-so-typical but I suppose it does deliver the trills required for the genre. As a horror movie, it's just too cheap and flamboyant to be anything scary or unsettling. Indeed, the snake may devour someone whole in the film but its more comical than it is disturbing. The snake resembles a giant puppet, and in some scenes I could have sworn I could make-out the wires or whatever they were bobbing it up and down in the water or springing it out of the water like a jack-in-the-box.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anaconda (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfnmbessert-224-279128
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'Anaconda' now, fifteen years after it's release, it's clear to see that this was really just a spiffed up B-movie, cashing in on the success to other monster flicks of the time which were hugely popular like 'Jurassic Park' and 'The Lost World: Jurassic Park' both of which I lump in along with the likes of 'Anaconda'. I have fond memories of wearing out my VHS copies of these films when I was younger, and while 'Anaconda' doesn't stand up to the likes of 'Jurassic Park' in any way, it had its fair share of influencing countless other films which would try to imitate the huge snake killing and eating everyone, none of which had a premise as good as that of 'Anaconda'. Factual errors all aside, the cast is good, and it's notable especially because of the direction they would later take in the following decade, Owen Wilson going more in the direction of comedy rather than action. Jon Voight is the perfect bad guy here, Ice Cube retains his gangster street cred, alongside Jennifer Lopez, and the absolutely beautiful Kari Wuhrer. It's nice that Eric Stoltz's pretentious character is comatose for a good portion of the film, as he's one of the least likable, although I'd say all of the characters here are pretty well written. Danny Trejo's small role in the beginning was something I had forgotten about, being that I haven't seen this in a long time. I know it's probably really only 6 material but since I hold this film in higher regard because of nostalgia, I'm going to give it a 7. ANACONDA ----7/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whether you're laughing at it or with it, at least you're laughing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a worrying sign that the first 60 seconds of a 90 minute film feels the need to 'serious up' the tone by running a lengthy blurb that effectively says 'big snakes are big and dangerous'. Ummmmm. Duh. Now bring on the killer legless lizards! Featuring a cast that is not so much 'good' as 'recognisable' Anaconda thankfully then gets down to the business of being an enjoyably inane flick with B actors wrestling fake snakes and being thrown around by big CGI effects. The threadbare plot has a doco crew traveling the largely unexplored tributaries of the Amazon searching for a long lost tribe of primitive South Americans who legend has it are protected by giant snakes. And how. After a few hiccups in the mission they pick up supposedly 'Paraguayan' snake hunter played by Jon Voight in a hammy performance to rival that of Tim Curry in Congo. He leads the boat on a snaky ahem 'sneaky' shortcut that should save all involved time. Now the fun starts. From this point on there is little for the cast to do but look alternately scared and suspicious in between running around like white mice. The talentless J Lo looks suitably lost and confused  no surprises there  and Eric Stoltz is laid up injured for half the film while Owen Wilson hones his shaggy locked surfer boy thing that has since made him a wealthy man. Ice Cube gets the worst wardrobe and the best lines, and I dare you not to chuckle when they show introduce 'snake stomach' cam near the end of the film. While you might be laughing or gasping about &frac12; the time with and the other &frac12; in spite of the goings on, I guess one way or the other at least you're laughing. Final Rating  5 / 10. Anaconda was released during a spate of creepy crawly based movies in the 90s, it won't blow you away but it was by no means the worst of the bunch and it spawned the usual sucky sequels.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anaconda (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a stupid B-Movie with enough quality to fly by, and enough camp charm to get away with such cinematic crimes. The cast play it straight, apart from Voight. I'm pretty sure he was drunk during the shooting, coming out with an inexplicable accent and a look reminiscent of Hannibal Lecter. It's ridiculous fun, with hokey CGI and animatronics. The animatronics are great and make me miss the 90s. It's a big snake shaped tube and goes from slow robotic motions, to super fast CGI. Cube and Hyde manage some, at times, adorable dialogue. Voight's presence also unites the rest of the cast, and each character gets their own heroic captain moment. Fun filled and just plain bad. I loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This river can kill you in a thousand ways.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A National Geographic crew head down the Amazon in a boat to make a documentary on a long-lost tribe of natives. On the way, they rescue a hunter from his sinking boat and take him on board. After the ship's captain is attacked by a poisonous insect and goes comatose, the hunter commandeers the boat. taking the crew hostage, he makes them go along on his insane quest to capture a giant anaconda..... First things first, the film is awful, its all over the shop and there has to be some of the most over the top acting I've ever seen in a movie. Saying that, I had a blast from beginning to end. Any film that can dub Trejos voice and kill him off in literally the first two minutes, has to be seen. The rest of the film is owned by Voight and a really dodgy looking reptile. Considering this is four years after Jurassic Park, and they spent a hundred grand every second that beast was on screen, its pretty laughable. The rest of the cast are there for filler. Lopez is good, Ice Cube is just a happier Doughboy, Wilson getting into Hollywood big time, and Jonathan Hyde as the token British snob, which is xenophobia if I've ever seen it. But there is so much fun to be had, guessing who will die first, the amount of times Voights accent changes thought the film, and obviously how much better Lopezs' nose looks today. But it is a bad film, and although I had lots of fun watching it, I cannot justify giving it a high rating. But its the best movie ever made where Eric Stoltz is asleep for 80% of the running time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Snake of the Century!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching "Anaconda is like plastering the palm of your hand against a clear glass jar that contains a rattlesnake and then gambling that you won't flinch when the snake strikes at the glass from within the container. More than half of the audience with whom I sat lost this wager every time that the eponymous snake struck. The ghoulish, B-movie plot of "Anaconda" resembles a blueprint for a theme park cruise. Scenarists Hans Bauer, Jim Cash, and Jack Epps, Jr., have borrowed surefire elements and incidents from better movies, such as "Moby Dick" (1956), "Creature from the Black Lagoon" (1954), and "Jaws" (1975). Sadly, although it is entertaining in an idiotic kind of way, "Anaconda" never seems to enthrall its audience because its campy sense of unreality undercuts its chills. The premise has something to do with journalists on an expedition heading down the Amazon in search of a lost South American tribe of Indians. Expedition leader Dr. Steven Cale (Eric Stoltz of "Killing Zoe") picks up a shipwrecked survivor, Paul Sarone (Jon Voight of "Midnight Cowboy"), along the way, but nothing good comes from this act of kindness. Voight turns in a heavily accented performance as an incredibly slimy villain. He is cast as a sinister ex-priest who resembles the feisty Quint (Robert Shaw) in "Jaws." Sarone is as obsessed with bagging giant killer snake as Ahab (Gregory Peck) was with catching a great white whale in "Moby Dick." Sarone is perfectly willing to use his new friends as bait if necessary to trap his 40-foot snake. A freak underwater accident early on puts Dr. Cale out of commission. It seems that when he dove in to fix a stuck propeller, a poisonous fish swam into his mouth and stung him. Sarone convinces the expedition film director, Terri Flores (Jennifer Lopez of "Selena") that he knows a short-cut down a blocked tributary that will cut 50 miles off their trip and save Cale's life. Foolishly, Terri believes Sarone and off they steam literally into the jaws of death. Director Louis Llosa and his scribes really heat up the suspense when Sarone commandeers the boat. Our heroes are cut off now in the untamed jungles of South America, and their radio has crapped out on them. They are without help and completely at the Sarone's mercy. Furthermore, during a big snake attack, the reptile knocks most of their fuel overboard so they have to prowl deeper into snake country to find more fuel. Standing out among the trendy-looking cast for his resilience is rapper Ice Cube from "Boyz N the Hood." He plays a tough, resourceful, film photographer who joins forces with Terri to thwart Sarone. The rest of the expedition crew are largely victims biding their time until they are eaten. If you don't know an animatronic snake from the real McCoy, or if you think this super anaconda could outrun the Road Runner, you're in for a nightmare experience. Every time this fake anaconda struck, most of the audience with which I sat went berserk. This big mother of a snake slings its coils like so many lariats around its prey. No matter if they're scrambling for a ladder or jogging through the jungle, this lethal anaconda hits them like a twister, wraps around them, and then chomps down on their heads. A pretty sight it is not. Meanwhile, the audiences sheds its collective skin. Maybe it wasn't as terrifying as "Alien," but then my audience wouldn't have known the difference. What really matters in "Anaconda" is who will the big, bad snake devour next? And how will our heroes destroy it? Director Louis Llosa, whose helmed better movies such as "The Specialist" and "Sniper," exploits the colorful Amazonian flora and fauna as does the snake. Sure, there are the inevitable anaconda cam shots and for the artistically inclined, Llosa provides a grotesque point of view shot. We get to see what it looks like staring down inside of the python's gullet as it digest another victim. Llosa paces "Anaconda" like a jack-in-the-box. He cranks up the tension between attacks. Just before his audiences has recovered, he unleashes another attack. And be warned, nothing can stop this anaconda. It can smash through windows, shatter boat hulls, and has special sensing ability that attracts it to its prey. This anaconda also shrieks like a cat when it gets hooked. As horror movies go, "Anaconda" is a straightforward, gut and churn classic. Not classic in the sense that it represents superior entertainment. Instead, classic in the sense that it egregious. The only moment in the entire film when the movie makers reach too far is Voight's tacky winking scene. This scene is so hideous that you either howl or hurl. Llosa succeeds in frightening the frijoles out of his audiences with unsavory material. Nothing wrong with that. Any movie that provokes a response is worth watching at least once. The closet that the filmmakers come to sexual encounters is a quickie on the bank that the snake hisses at, and Lopez's wet T-shirt. Despite its glossy, big-budgeted production values, "Anaconda" ends up as such a flaky carnival of outlandish special effects and unrealistic antics that you want to snicker when you should scream and scream when you should snicker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant - The snake reminds me of my first wife.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pog53
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a hoot! A brilliant B movie to watch with a large Gin & Tonic to cheer on the snake. Regrettably I was laughing so much I missed the bit where the amazingly annoying Kari Wuhrer gets the chop. The snake is actually rather good - it looks a bit like my first wife. I didn't know they can scream as well. Jon Voight is as brilliant as ever but the cast dialogue coach was clearly deranged - accents are all over the place and the music is totally out of sync with the scenes. The first snake attack on the boat is a classic - screaming girls, deranged Voight and Owen Wilson ending up as a snake stocking filler. Brilliant. Ice Cube sums it up nicely when he announces: "That's it - I'm off back to LA". Very sensible, mate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Pure Dissapoitment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thewillt08
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a movie with John Voight, Jennifer Lopez, Ice Cube, Owen Wilson, and a giant anaconda, oh dear god. As a kid I loved watching Anaconda, but after seeing it again I must have been crazy as a kid. I think I liked the fact that a giant snake was eating people. The basic premise is that Lopez and her boyfriend I guess are leading an expedition into the Amazon and tend to make a documentary or something. They run into John Voight, a strange man with a terrible accent. Chaos soon ensues when a giant snake terrorizes the passengers and it is up to them to survive or get eaten. Let's start with the cast, the cast in this movie has very little talent. Jennifer Lopez is only in the movie because she is smoking hot. Ice Cube can't act for his life. I can't stand Owen Wilson, but that's a rant for another time. John Voight is an obvious miscast because he is supposed to be the villain and every time he opens his mouth you want to block your ears. The snake looks terrible and I guess there was two of them so the title "Anaconda" is a lie. The only person I can say I actually liked was the British guy. His character actually fit well in the story and he had some development as he eventually turns into a hero of some sort. One character, I don't remember his name, started out important and the movie built him up as a hero and he is sidelined for over half of the movie. He just lays in a bed in a coma like state and it annoyed me to my core. I was counting down the scenes until he came back because he was a likable and relatable character. Instead the movie decided to focus on John Voight and his stupid character and Owen Wilson and his stupidity, then his whiney girlfriend and her stupidity. This movie was frustrating above all else. The special effects in this movie are just plain embarrassing. The snake looks terrible, the makeup and prosthetics look miserable. There is a scene where the anaconda eats a black panther and the panther looked way too fake. Even the nose it made sounded fake. Obviously they wouldn't use a real panther or snake but it was poor and lazy filmmaking. This movie was not a complete fail it did have some entertaining parts, specifically the end. Despite being very predictable and knowing which characters would die when, I don't want to vilify this movie because it isn't the worst movie I've ever seen. My favorite scene is the one when they kill the first anaconda. Voight is tied up but he being the way he is turns the scene around and then there's the whole thing with the waterfall. It had the vibe and feel of a climax but it wasn't. Even though the last scene was incredibly ridiculous it was still entertaining. Watching the snake and seeing how huge it was was cool and unexpected. As a kid I loved this movie and I still don't know why. The acting was terrible but I loved Ice Cube. He was terrible but I liked that he was in the movie. For the time he was a big pop culture figure and it made sense that he was in there. I feel like I'm rambling so I'm going to wrap this up. Overall, Anaconda will be a childhood favorite but childhood opinions mean virtually nothing. I want this movie to be rebooted and made properly. There have been sequels that were OK but still unacceptable. A giant snake terrorizing people is interesting and can be exciting. However, John Vogiht's awful accent, Ice Cube, Jennifer Lopez, either of the Wilsons, awful special effects, and poor direction is not the way to do it. I am really disappointed in the movie and it has to get the WillyT Seal of DISapproval.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It will take your breath away!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    irrelevantlife
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some movies seem to be destined to be viewed as bad, even though they contain no bad elements at all, and are only loathed because of their premise; Anaconda (1997) falls into that category of movies. What we have here is the best snake horror movie/creature feature ever created with an actual budget, good actors (great actors, Jon Voight!) and an interesting plot and setting which is used very skilfully by director Luis Llosa. No doubt one of the most impressive and deadly reptiles on this planet, the giant green anaconda is the heavies and some might even argue the longest of all constrictors, and the snake has a mythical status as a ultimate predator in the Amazon, you simply can't argue that a 33 foot snake weighing more than 400 pounds isn't one of THE ultimate aquatic and terrestrial predators. The plot is very straight forward, a team of film makers and scientists travel the Amazon River to document a illusive tribe and their ways of life, on their journey they stumble across a hunter (Jon Voight) who's boat is malfunctioning, they take him in, but soon find out that he has other plans, and is on the hunt for the giant anaconda. The special effects are truly astounding for this type of movie, considering it was made in 1996. The animatronics snake is terrific, and is modelled very accurately to its real life counterpart, something that is imperative in a movie such as this; you want as much authenticity as possible. The CGI effects are very solid, and the score is catchy, yet suspenseful at the same time. People seem to forget that many revered critics at the time of release praised the movie for being well constructed and acted, so the hate for it is completely unfound. Of course we can't review this movie without mentioning the awful sequels that did made all the mistakes the first movie avoided, such as skipping out on authenticity making the snakes look like rubber bands more than actual anacondas. Overall Anaconda, is a great snake horror movie worth watching, it has all the right ingredients of suspense, horror and humour with likable and believable characters and fantastic performance from Voight who steals the show. I strongly recommend this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hello!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    apregnantlesbian
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hello! This is my review for the popular horrible movie called "Anaconda". Anaconda is a popular horrible movie that concerns very angry snake. Maybe it will remind of Steven Spielberg's popular feature presentation "JAWS", although that was shark rather than serpent ha-ha. In this motion picture you will have many shocks and suspense. It is very surprising when snake pops out!!! Be sure not to watch this with your dog, maybe it is a dumb dog and will want to chasing the snake ha-ha. Some interesting trivia about snake, for your enjoyment: - Snake is not a rope. However, it is like an angry rope. - Snake does not have legs.!! So how does it walk??? Snake is full of mysteries...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to take it serious when the snake looks like a giant puppet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JSwallowX1
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's suffice to say that when Jennifer Lopez, Ice Cube and Owen Wilson are amongst the lead cast in a film about a giant snake in the Amazon that it is not going to be much good. And indeed IT isn't; and despite Jon Voight and Eric Stoltz also being amongst the cast in this $45,000,000 production it is a very embarrassing project to be part of. The film has been followed by three sequels to date. A National Geographic crew travel into the heart of the Amazon to shoot a documentary on the long-lost tribe reported to be somewhere along the banks of the immense river. "Cannibal Holocaust" it is not, I'm afraid. Director Terri Flores (Jennifer Lopez) and her anthropologist boyfriend (Eric Stoltz) lead the team. Not long into their voyage they rescue a stranded Paraguayan snake hunter named Paul (Jon Voight). In return, he offers to help them find the lost tribe they are looking for, claiming to have met them. But his true plans unfold when he takes over the boat and forces the crew to aid him in his manic quest to track down a record-breaking Giant Anaconda. And it descends into a typical hunters-become-the-hunted scenario henceforth. For the first half an hour at least, "Anaconda" is somewhat enjoyable. But after that it quickly descends into mediocrity. One must ask the question as to where exactly the $45 million went, because it was certainly not invested in to the special effects department, that's for sure. The Anaconda looks ridiculous. I've seen monsters on the ludicrous Syfy channel films from the last ten years with lower budgets than this managing to turn out better looking monsters. Albeit, just slightly. And I know it was the year 1997, but come on now people, it wasn't that long ago and there was some superb CGI around that time and even before it. "Anaconda" is just a very poorly made film. The acting is diabolical... horrendous (Although in saying that Voight's performance was somewhat interesting). The script resembles something written on a rainy afternoon in after-school study by two bored kids. With dialogue as ingenious as this: "Is it just me or does the jungle make you really, really horny?" that one was courtesy of our man Owen Wilson. And Ice Cube has to get his two cents worth in there too - "That's it, man, I'm getting' the hell back to LA". But Owen Wilson delivers yet again and takes the cake - "You don't know sh*t about the sh*t we're in out here!" Genius. As an adventure film it's oh-so-typical but I suppose it does deliver the trills required for the genre. As a horror movie, it's just too cheap and flamboyant to be anything scary or unsettling. Indeed, the snake may devour someone whole in the film but its more comical than it is disturbing. The snake resembles a giant puppet, and in some scenes I could have sworn I could make-out the wires or whatever they were bobbing it up and down in the water or springing it out of the water like a jack-in-the-box.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anaconda (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfnmbessert-224-279128
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'Anaconda' now, fifteen years after it's release, it's clear to see that this was really just a spiffed up B-movie, cashing in on the success to other monster flicks of the time which were hugely popular like 'Jurassic Park' and 'The Lost World: Jurassic Park' both of which I lump in along with the likes of 'Anaconda'. I have fond memories of wearing out my VHS copies of these films when I was younger, and while 'Anaconda' doesn't stand up to the likes of 'Jurassic Park' in any way, it had its fair share of influencing countless other films which would try to imitate the huge snake killing and eating everyone, none of which had a premise as good as that of 'Anaconda'. Factual errors all aside, the cast is good, and it's notable especially because of the direction they would later take in the following decade, Owen Wilson going more in the direction of comedy rather than action. Jon Voight is the perfect bad guy here, Ice Cube retains his gangster street cred, alongside Jennifer Lopez, and the absolutely beautiful Kari Wuhrer. It's nice that Eric Stoltz's pretentious character is comatose for a good portion of the film, as he's one of the least likable, although I'd say all of the characters here are pretty well written. Danny Trejo's small role in the beginning was something I had forgotten about, being that I haven't seen this in a long time. I know it's probably really only 6 material but since I hold this film in higher regard because of nostalgia, I'm going to give it a 7. ANACONDA ----7/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whether you're laughing at it or with it, at least you're laughing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a worrying sign that the first 60 seconds of a 90 minute film feels the need to 'serious up' the tone by running a lengthy blurb that effectively says 'big snakes are big and dangerous'. Ummmmm. Duh. Now bring on the killer legless lizards! Featuring a cast that is not so much 'good' as 'recognisable' Anaconda thankfully then gets down to the business of being an enjoyably inane flick with B actors wrestling fake snakes and being thrown around by big CGI effects. The threadbare plot has a doco crew traveling the largely unexplored tributaries of the Amazon searching for a long lost tribe of primitive South Americans who legend has it are protected by giant snakes. And how. After a few hiccups in the mission they pick up supposedly 'Paraguayan' snake hunter played by Jon Voight in a hammy performance to rival that of Tim Curry in Congo. He leads the boat on a snaky ahem 'sneaky' shortcut that should save all involved time. Now the fun starts. From this point on there is little for the cast to do but look alternately scared and suspicious in between running around like white mice. The talentless J Lo looks suitably lost and confused  no surprises there  and Eric Stoltz is laid up injured for half the film while Owen Wilson hones his shaggy locked surfer boy thing that has since made him a wealthy man. Ice Cube gets the worst wardrobe and the best lines, and I dare you not to chuckle when they show introduce 'snake stomach' cam near the end of the film. While you might be laughing or gasping about &frac12; the time with and the other &frac12; in spite of the goings on, I guess one way or the other at least you're laughing. Final Rating  5 / 10. Anaconda was released during a spate of creepy crawly based movies in the 90s, it won't blow you away but it was by no means the worst of the bunch and it spawned the usual sucky sequels.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anaconda (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a stupid B-Movie with enough quality to fly by, and enough camp charm to get away with such cinematic crimes. The cast play it straight, apart from Voight. I'm pretty sure he was drunk during the shooting, coming out with an inexplicable accent and a look reminiscent of Hannibal Lecter. It's ridiculous fun, with hokey CGI and animatronics. The animatronics are great and make me miss the 90s. It's a big snake shaped tube and goes from slow robotic motions, to super fast CGI. Cube and Hyde manage some, at times, adorable dialogue. Voight's presence also unites the rest of the cast, and each character gets their own heroic captain moment. Fun filled and just plain bad. I loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This river can kill you in a thousand ways.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A National Geographic crew head down the Amazon in a boat to make a documentary on a long-lost tribe of natives. On the way, they rescue a hunter from his sinking boat and take him on board. After the ship's captain is attacked by a poisonous insect and goes comatose, the hunter commandeers the boat. taking the crew hostage, he makes them go along on his insane quest to capture a giant anaconda..... First things first, the film is awful, its all over the shop and there has to be some of the most over the top acting I've ever seen in a movie. Saying that, I had a blast from beginning to end. Any film that can dub Trejos voice and kill him off in literally the first two minutes, has to be seen. The rest of the film is owned by Voight and a really dodgy looking reptile. Considering this is four years after Jurassic Park, and they spent a hundred grand every second that beast was on screen, its pretty laughable. The rest of the cast are there for filler. Lopez is good, Ice Cube is just a happier Doughboy, Wilson getting into Hollywood big time, and Jonathan Hyde as the token British snob, which is xenophobia if I've ever seen it. But there is so much fun to be had, guessing who will die first, the amount of times Voights accent changes thought the film, and obviously how much better Lopezs' nose looks today. But it is a bad film, and although I had lots of fun watching it, I cannot justify giving it a high rating. But its the best movie ever made where Eric Stoltz is asleep for 80% of the running time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Snake of the Century!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching "Anaconda is like plastering the palm of your hand against a clear glass jar that contains a rattlesnake and then gambling that you won't flinch when the snake strikes at the glass from within the container. More than half of the audience with whom I sat lost this wager every time that the eponymous snake struck. The ghoulish, B-movie plot of "Anaconda" resembles a blueprint for a theme park cruise. Scenarists Hans Bauer, Jim Cash, and Jack Epps, Jr., have borrowed surefire elements and incidents from better movies, such as "Moby Dick" (1956), "Creature from the Black Lagoon" (1954), and "Jaws" (1975). Sadly, although it is entertaining in an idiotic kind of way, "Anaconda" never seems to enthrall its audience because its campy sense of unreality undercuts its chills. The premise has something to do with journalists on an expedition heading down the Amazon in search of a lost South American tribe of Indians. Expedition leader Dr. Steven Cale (Eric Stoltz of "Killing Zoe") picks up a shipwrecked survivor, Paul Sarone (Jon Voight of "Midnight Cowboy"), along the way, but nothing good comes from this act of kindness. Voight turns in a heavily accented performance as an incredibly slimy villain. He is cast as a sinister ex-priest who resembles the feisty Quint (Robert Shaw) in "Jaws." Sarone is as obsessed with bagging giant killer snake as Ahab (Gregory Peck) was with catching a great white whale in "Moby Dick." Sarone is perfectly willing to use his new friends as bait if necessary to trap his 40-foot snake. A freak underwater accident early on puts Dr. Cale out of commission. It seems that when he dove in to fix a stuck propeller, a poisonous fish swam into his mouth and stung him. Sarone convinces the expedition film director, Terri Flores (Jennifer Lopez of "Selena") that he knows a short-cut down a blocked tributary that will cut 50 miles off their trip and save Cale's life. Foolishly, Terri believes Sarone and off they steam literally into the jaws of death. Director Louis Llosa and his scribes really heat up the suspense when Sarone commandeers the boat. Our heroes are cut off now in the untamed jungles of South America, and their radio has crapped out on them. They are without help and completely at the Sarone's mercy. Furthermore, during a big snake attack, the reptile knocks most of their fuel overboard so they have to prowl deeper into snake country to find more fuel. Standing out among the trendy-looking cast for his resilience is rapper Ice Cube from "Boyz N the Hood." He plays a tough, resourceful, film photographer who joins forces with Terri to thwart Sarone. The rest of the expedition crew are largely victims biding their time until they are eaten. If you don't know an animatronic snake from the real McCoy, or if you think this super anaconda could outrun the Road Runner, you're in for a nightmare experience. Every time this fake anaconda struck, most of the audience with which I sat went berserk. This big mother of a snake slings its coils like so many lariats around its prey. No matter if they're scrambling for a ladder or jogging through the jungle, this lethal anaconda hits them like a twister, wraps around them, and then chomps down on their heads. A pretty sight it is not. Meanwhile, the audiences sheds its collective skin. Maybe it wasn't as terrifying as "Alien," but then my audience wouldn't have known the difference. What really matters in "Anaconda" is who will the big, bad snake devour next? And how will our heroes destroy it? Director Louis Llosa, whose helmed better movies such as "The Specialist" and "Sniper," exploits the colorful Amazonian flora and fauna as does the snake. Sure, there are the inevitable anaconda cam shots and for the artistically inclined, Llosa provides a grotesque point of view shot. We get to see what it looks like staring down inside of the python's gullet as it digest another victim. Llosa paces "Anaconda" like a jack-in-the-box. He cranks up the tension between attacks. Just before his audiences has recovered, he unleashes another attack. And be warned, nothing can stop this anaconda. It can smash through windows, shatter boat hulls, and has special sensing ability that attracts it to its prey. This anaconda also shrieks like a cat when it gets hooked. As horror movies go, "Anaconda" is a straightforward, gut and churn classic. Not classic in the sense that it represents superior entertainment. Instead, classic in the sense that it egregious. The only moment in the entire film when the movie makers reach too far is Voight's tacky winking scene. This scene is so hideous that you either howl or hurl. Llosa succeeds in frightening the frijoles out of his audiences with unsavory material. Nothing wrong with that. Any movie that provokes a response is worth watching at least once. The closet that the filmmakers come to sexual encounters is a quickie on the bank that the snake hisses at, and Lopez's wet T-shirt. Despite its glossy, big-budgeted production values, "Anaconda" ends up as such a flaky carnival of outlandish special effects and unrealistic antics that you want to snicker when you should scream and scream when you should snicker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant - The snake reminds me of my first wife.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pog53
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a hoot! A brilliant B movie to watch with a large Gin & Tonic to cheer on the snake. Regrettably I was laughing so much I missed the bit where the amazingly annoying Kari Wuhrer gets the chop. The snake is actually rather good - it looks a bit like my first wife. I didn't know they can scream as well. Jon Voight is as brilliant as ever but the cast dialogue coach was clearly deranged - accents are all over the place and the music is totally out of sync with the scenes. The first snake attack on the boat is a classic - screaming girls, deranged Voight and Owen Wilson ending up as a snake stocking filler. Brilliant. Ice Cube sums it up nicely when he announces: "That's it - I'm off back to LA". Very sensible, mate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Pure Dissapoitment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thewillt08
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a movie with John Voight, Jennifer Lopez, Ice Cube, Owen Wilson, and a giant anaconda, oh dear god. As a kid I loved watching Anaconda, but after seeing it again I must have been crazy as a kid. I think I liked the fact that a giant snake was eating people. The basic premise is that Lopez and her boyfriend I guess are leading an expedition into the Amazon and tend to make a documentary or something. They run into John Voight, a strange man with a terrible accent. Chaos soon ensues when a giant snake terrorizes the passengers and it is up to them to survive or get eaten. Let's start with the cast, the cast in this movie has very little talent. Jennifer Lopez is only in the movie because she is smoking hot. Ice Cube can't act for his life. I can't stand Owen Wilson, but that's a rant for another time. John Voight is an obvious miscast because he is supposed to be the villain and every time he opens his mouth you want to block your ears. The snake looks terrible and I guess there was two of them so the title "Anaconda" is a lie. The only person I can say I actually liked was the British guy. His character actually fit well in the story and he had some development as he eventually turns into a hero of some sort. One character, I don't remember his name, started out important and the movie built him up as a hero and he is sidelined for over half of the movie. He just lays in a bed in a coma like state and it annoyed me to my core. I was counting down the scenes until he came back because he was a likable and relatable character. Instead the movie decided to focus on John Voight and his stupid character and Owen Wilson and his stupidity, then his whiney girlfriend and her stupidity. This movie was frustrating above all else. The special effects in this movie are just plain embarrassing. The snake looks terrible, the makeup and prosthetics look miserable. There is a scene where the anaconda eats a black panther and the panther looked way too fake. Even the nose it made sounded fake. Obviously they wouldn't use a real panther or snake but it was poor and lazy filmmaking. This movie was not a complete fail it did have some entertaining parts, specifically the end. Despite being very predictable and knowing which characters would die when, I don't want to vilify this movie because it isn't the worst movie I've ever seen. My favorite scene is the one when they kill the first anaconda. Voight is tied up but he being the way he is turns the scene around and then there's the whole thing with the waterfall. It had the vibe and feel of a climax but it wasn't. Even though the last scene was incredibly ridiculous it was still entertaining. Watching the snake and seeing how huge it was was cool and unexpected. As a kid I loved this movie and I still don't know why. The acting was terrible but I loved Ice Cube. He was terrible but I liked that he was in the movie. For the time he was a big pop culture figure and it made sense that he was in there. I feel like I'm rambling so I'm going to wrap this up. Overall, Anaconda will be a childhood favorite but childhood opinions mean virtually nothing. I want this movie to be rebooted and made properly. There have been sequels that were OK but still unacceptable. A giant snake terrorizing people is interesting and can be exciting. However, John Vogiht's awful accent, Ice Cube, Jennifer Lopez, either of the Wilsons, awful special effects, and poor direction is not the way to do it. I am really disappointed in the movie and it has to get the WillyT Seal of DISapproval.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It will take your breath away!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    irrelevantlife
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some movies seem to be destined to be viewed as bad, even though they contain no bad elements at all, and are only loathed because of their premise; Anaconda (1997) falls into that category of movies. What we have here is the best snake horror movie/creature feature ever created with an actual budget, good actors (great actors, Jon Voight!) and an interesting plot and setting which is used very skilfully by director Luis Llosa. No doubt one of the most impressive and deadly reptiles on this planet, the giant green anaconda is the heavies and some might even argue the longest of all constrictors, and the snake has a mythical status as a ultimate predator in the Amazon, you simply can't argue that a 33 foot snake weighing more than 400 pounds isn't one of THE ultimate aquatic and terrestrial predators. The plot is very straight forward, a team of film makers and scientists travel the Amazon River to document a illusive tribe and their ways of life, on their journey they stumble across a hunter (Jon Voight) who's boat is malfunctioning, they take him in, but soon find out that he has other plans, and is on the hunt for the giant anaconda. The special effects are truly astounding for this type of movie, considering it was made in 1996. The animatronics snake is terrific, and is modelled very accurately to its real life counterpart, something that is imperative in a movie such as this; you want as much authenticity as possible. The CGI effects are very solid, and the score is catchy, yet suspenseful at the same time. People seem to forget that many revered critics at the time of release praised the movie for being well constructed and acted, so the hate for it is completely unfound. Of course we can't review this movie without mentioning the awful sequels that did made all the mistakes the first movie avoided, such as skipping out on authenticity making the snakes look like rubber bands more than actual anacondas. Overall Anaconda, is a great snake horror movie worth watching, it has all the right ingredients of suspense, horror and humour with likable and believable characters and fantastic performance from Voight who steals the show. I strongly recommend this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hello!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    apregnantlesbian
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hello! This is my review for the popular horrible movie called "Anaconda". Anaconda is a popular horrible movie that concerns very angry snake. Maybe it will remind of Steven Spielberg's popular feature presentation "JAWS", although that was shark rather than serpent ha-ha. In this motion picture you will have many shocks and suspense. It is very surprising when snake pops out!!! Be sure not to watch this with your dog, maybe it is a dumb dog and will want to chasing the snake ha-ha. Some interesting trivia about snake, for your enjoyment: - Snake is not a rope. However, it is like an angry rope. - Snake does not have legs.!! So how does it walk??? Snake is full of mysteries...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to take it serious when the snake looks like a giant puppet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JSwallowX1
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's suffice to say that when Jennifer Lopez, Ice Cube and Owen Wilson are amongst the lead cast in a film about a giant snake in the Amazon that it is not going to be much good. And indeed IT isn't; and despite Jon Voight and Eric Stoltz also being amongst the cast in this $45,000,000 production it is a very embarrassing project to be part of. The film has been followed by three sequels to date. A National Geographic crew travel into the heart of the Amazon to shoot a documentary on the long-lost tribe reported to be somewhere along the banks of the immense river. "Cannibal Holocaust" it is not, I'm afraid. Director Terri Flores (Jennifer Lopez) and her anthropologist boyfriend (Eric Stoltz) lead the team. Not long into their voyage they rescue a stranded Paraguayan snake hunter named Paul (Jon Voight). In return, he offers to help them find the lost tribe they are looking for, claiming to have met them. But his true plans unfold when he takes over the boat and forces the crew to aid him in his manic quest to track down a record-breaking Giant Anaconda. And it descends into a typical hunters-become-the-hunted scenario henceforth. For the first half an hour at least, "Anaconda" is somewhat enjoyable. But after that it quickly descends into mediocrity. One must ask the question as to where exactly the $45 million went, because it was certainly not invested in to the special effects department, that's for sure. The Anaconda looks ridiculous. I've seen monsters on the ludicrous Syfy channel films from the last ten years with lower budgets than this managing to turn out better looking monsters. Albeit, just slightly. And I know it was the year 1997, but come on now people, it wasn't that long ago and there was some superb CGI around that time and even before it. "Anaconda" is just a very poorly made film. The acting is diabolical... horrendous (Although in saying that Voight's performance was somewhat interesting). The script resembles something written on a rainy afternoon in after-school study by two bored kids. With dialogue as ingenious as this: "Is it just me or does the jungle make you really, really horny?" that one was courtesy of our man Owen Wilson. And Ice Cube has to get his two cents worth in there too - "That's it, man, I'm getting' the hell back to LA". But Owen Wilson delivers yet again and takes the cake - "You don't know sh*t about the sh*t we're in out here!" Genius. As an adventure film it's oh-so-typical but I suppose it does deliver the trills required for the genre. As a horror movie, it's just too cheap and flamboyant to be anything scary or unsettling. Indeed, the snake may devour someone whole in the film but its more comical than it is disturbing. The snake resembles a giant puppet, and in some scenes I could have sworn I could make-out the wires or whatever they were bobbing it up and down in the water or springing it out of the water like a jack-in-the-box.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anaconda (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfnmbessert-224-279128
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'Anaconda' now, fifteen years after it's release, it's clear to see that this was really just a spiffed up B-movie, cashing in on the success to other monster flicks of the time which were hugely popular like 'Jurassic Park' and 'The Lost World: Jurassic Park' both of which I lump in along with the likes of 'Anaconda'. I have fond memories of wearing out my VHS copies of these films when I was younger, and while 'Anaconda' doesn't stand up to the likes of 'Jurassic Park' in any way, it had its fair share of influencing countless other films which would try to imitate the huge snake killing and eating everyone, none of which had a premise as good as that of 'Anaconda'. Factual errors all aside, the cast is good, and it's notable especially because of the direction they would later take in the following decade, Owen Wilson going more in the direction of comedy rather than action. Jon Voight is the perfect bad guy here, Ice Cube retains his gangster street cred, alongside Jennifer Lopez, and the absolutely beautiful Kari Wuhrer. It's nice that Eric Stoltz's pretentious character is comatose for a good portion of the film, as he's one of the least likable, although I'd say all of the characters here are pretty well written. Danny Trejo's small role in the beginning was something I had forgotten about, being that I haven't seen this in a long time. I know it's probably really only 6 material but since I hold this film in higher regard because of nostalgia, I'm going to give it a 7. ANACONDA ----7/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whether you're laughing at it or with it, at least you're laughing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a worrying sign that the first 60 seconds of a 90 minute film feels the need to 'serious up' the tone by running a lengthy blurb that effectively says 'big snakes are big and dangerous'. Ummmmm. Duh. Now bring on the killer legless lizards! Featuring a cast that is not so much 'good' as 'recognisable' Anaconda thankfully then gets down to the business of being an enjoyably inane flick with B actors wrestling fake snakes and being thrown around by big CGI effects. The threadbare plot has a doco crew traveling the largely unexplored tributaries of the Amazon searching for a long lost tribe of primitive South Americans who legend has it are protected by giant snakes. And how. After a few hiccups in the mission they pick up supposedly 'Paraguayan' snake hunter played by Jon Voight in a hammy performance to rival that of Tim Curry in Congo. He leads the boat on a snaky ahem 'sneaky' shortcut that should save all involved time. Now the fun starts. From this point on there is little for the cast to do but look alternately scared and suspicious in between running around like white mice. The talentless J Lo looks suitably lost and confused  no surprises there  and Eric Stoltz is laid up injured for half the film while Owen Wilson hones his shaggy locked surfer boy thing that has since made him a wealthy man. Ice Cube gets the worst wardrobe and the best lines, and I dare you not to chuckle when they show introduce 'snake stomach' cam near the end of the film. While you might be laughing or gasping about &frac12; the time with and the other &frac12; in spite of the goings on, I guess one way or the other at least you're laughing. Final Rating  5 / 10. Anaconda was released during a spate of creepy crawly based movies in the 90s, it won't blow you away but it was by no means the worst of the bunch and it spawned the usual sucky sequels.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anaconda (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a stupid B-Movie with enough quality to fly by, and enough camp charm to get away with such cinematic crimes. The cast play it straight, apart from Voight. I'm pretty sure he was drunk during the shooting, coming out with an inexplicable accent and a look reminiscent of Hannibal Lecter. It's ridiculous fun, with hokey CGI and animatronics. The animatronics are great and make me miss the 90s. It's a big snake shaped tube and goes from slow robotic motions, to super fast CGI. Cube and Hyde manage some, at times, adorable dialogue. Voight's presence also unites the rest of the cast, and each character gets their own heroic captain moment. Fun filled and just plain bad. I loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This river can kill you in a thousand ways.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A National Geographic crew head down the Amazon in a boat to make a documentary on a long-lost tribe of natives. On the way, they rescue a hunter from his sinking boat and take him on board. After the ship's captain is attacked by a poisonous insect and goes comatose, the hunter commandeers the boat. taking the crew hostage, he makes them go along on his insane quest to capture a giant anaconda..... First things first, the film is awful, its all over the shop and there has to be some of the most over the top acting I've ever seen in a movie. Saying that, I had a blast from beginning to end. Any film that can dub Trejos voice and kill him off in literally the first two minutes, has to be seen. The rest of the film is owned by Voight and a really dodgy looking reptile. Considering this is four years after Jurassic Park, and they spent a hundred grand every second that beast was on screen, its pretty laughable. The rest of the cast are there for filler. Lopez is good, Ice Cube is just a happier Doughboy, Wilson getting into Hollywood big time, and Jonathan Hyde as the token British snob, which is xenophobia if I've ever seen it. But there is so much fun to be had, guessing who will die first, the amount of times Voights accent changes thought the film, and obviously how much better Lopezs' nose looks today. But it is a bad film, and although I had lots of fun watching it, I cannot justify giving it a high rating. But its the best movie ever made where Eric Stoltz is asleep for 80% of the running time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Snake of the Century!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching "Anaconda is like plastering the palm of your hand against a clear glass jar that contains a rattlesnake and then gambling that you won't flinch when the snake strikes at the glass from within the container. More than half of the audience with whom I sat lost this wager every time that the eponymous snake struck. The ghoulish, B-movie plot of "Anaconda" resembles a blueprint for a theme park cruise. Scenarists Hans Bauer, Jim Cash, and Jack Epps, Jr., have borrowed surefire elements and incidents from better movies, such as "Moby Dick" (1956), "Creature from the Black Lagoon" (1954), and "Jaws" (1975). Sadly, although it is entertaining in an idiotic kind of way, "Anaconda" never seems to enthrall its audience because its campy sense of unreality undercuts its chills. The premise has something to do with journalists on an expedition heading down the Amazon in search of a lost South American tribe of Indians. Expedition leader Dr. Steven Cale (Eric Stoltz of "Killing Zoe") picks up a shipwrecked survivor, Paul Sarone (Jon Voight of "Midnight Cowboy"), along the way, but nothing good comes from this act of kindness. Voight turns in a heavily accented performance as an incredibly slimy villain. He is cast as a sinister ex-priest who resembles the feisty Quint (Robert Shaw) in "Jaws." Sarone is as obsessed with bagging giant killer snake as Ahab (Gregory Peck) was with catching a great white whale in "Moby Dick." Sarone is perfectly willing to use his new friends as bait if necessary to trap his 40-foot snake. A freak underwater accident early on puts Dr. Cale out of commission. It seems that when he dove in to fix a stuck propeller, a poisonous fish swam into his mouth and stung him. Sarone convinces the expedition film director, Terri Flores (Jennifer Lopez of "Selena") that he knows a short-cut down a blocked tributary that will cut 50 miles off their trip and save Cale's life. Foolishly, Terri believes Sarone and off they steam literally into the jaws of death. Director Louis Llosa and his scribes really heat up the suspense when Sarone commandeers the boat. Our heroes are cut off now in the untamed jungles of South America, and their radio has crapped out on them. They are without help and completely at the Sarone's mercy. Furthermore, during a big snake attack, the reptile knocks most of their fuel overboard so they have to prowl deeper into snake country to find more fuel. Standing out among the trendy-looking cast for his resilience is rapper Ice Cube from "Boyz N the Hood." He plays a tough, resourceful, film photographer who joins forces with Terri to thwart Sarone. The rest of the expedition crew are largely victims biding their time until they are eaten. If you don't know an animatronic snake from the real McCoy, or if you think this super anaconda could outrun the Road Runner, you're in for a nightmare experience. Every time this fake anaconda struck, most of the audience with which I sat went berserk. This big mother of a snake slings its coils like so many lariats around its prey. No matter if they're scrambling for a ladder or jogging through the jungle, this lethal anaconda hits them like a twister, wraps around them, and then chomps down on their heads. A pretty sight it is not. Meanwhile, the audiences sheds its collective skin. Maybe it wasn't as terrifying as "Alien," but then my audience wouldn't have known the difference. What really matters in "Anaconda" is who will the big, bad snake devour next? And how will our heroes destroy it? Director Louis Llosa, whose helmed better movies such as "The Specialist" and "Sniper," exploits the colorful Amazonian flora and fauna as does the snake. Sure, there are the inevitable anaconda cam shots and for the artistically inclined, Llosa provides a grotesque point of view shot. We get to see what it looks like staring down inside of the python's gullet as it digest another victim. Llosa paces "Anaconda" like a jack-in-the-box. He cranks up the tension between attacks. Just before his audiences has recovered, he unleashes another attack. And be warned, nothing can stop this anaconda. It can smash through windows, shatter boat hulls, and has special sensing ability that attracts it to its prey. This anaconda also shrieks like a cat when it gets hooked. As horror movies go, "Anaconda" is a straightforward, gut and churn classic. Not classic in the sense that it represents superior entertainment. Instead, classic in the sense that it egregious. The only moment in the entire film when the movie makers reach too far is Voight's tacky winking scene. This scene is so hideous that you either howl or hurl. Llosa succeeds in frightening the frijoles out of his audiences with unsavory material. Nothing wrong with that. Any movie that provokes a response is worth watching at least once. The closet that the filmmakers come to sexual encounters is a quickie on the bank that the snake hisses at, and Lopez's wet T-shirt. Despite its glossy, big-budgeted production values, "Anaconda" ends up as such a flaky carnival of outlandish special effects and unrealistic antics that you want to snicker when you should scream and scream when you should snicker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant - The snake reminds me of my first wife.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pog53
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a hoot! A brilliant B movie to watch with a large Gin & Tonic to cheer on the snake. Regrettably I was laughing so much I missed the bit where the amazingly annoying Kari Wuhrer gets the chop. The snake is actually rather good - it looks a bit like my first wife. I didn't know they can scream as well. Jon Voight is as brilliant as ever but the cast dialogue coach was clearly deranged - accents are all over the place and the music is totally out of sync with the scenes. The first snake attack on the boat is a classic - screaming girls, deranged Voight and Owen Wilson ending up as a snake stocking filler. Brilliant. Ice Cube sums it up nicely when he announces: "That's it - I'm off back to LA". Very sensible, mate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Pure Dissapoitment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thewillt08
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a movie with John Voight, Jennifer Lopez, Ice Cube, Owen Wilson, and a giant anaconda, oh dear god. As a kid I loved watching Anaconda, but after seeing it again I must have been crazy as a kid. I think I liked the fact that a giant snake was eating people. The basic premise is that Lopez and her boyfriend I guess are leading an expedition into the Amazon and tend to make a documentary or something. They run into John Voight, a strange man with a terrible accent. Chaos soon ensues when a giant snake terrorizes the passengers and it is up to them to survive or get eaten. Let's start with the cast, the cast in this movie has very little talent. Jennifer Lopez is only in the movie because she is smoking hot. Ice Cube can't act for his life. I can't stand Owen Wilson, but that's a rant for another time. John Voight is an obvious miscast because he is supposed to be the villain and every time he opens his mouth you want to block your ears. The snake looks terrible and I guess there was two of them so the title "Anaconda" is a lie. The only person I can say I actually liked was the British guy. His character actually fit well in the story and he had some development as he eventually turns into a hero of some sort. One character, I don't remember his name, started out important and the movie built him up as a hero and he is sidelined for over half of the movie. He just lays in a bed in a coma like state and it annoyed me to my core. I was counting down the scenes until he came back because he was a likable and relatable character. Instead the movie decided to focus on John Voight and his stupid character and Owen Wilson and his stupidity, then his whiney girlfriend and her stupidity. This movie was frustrating above all else. The special effects in this movie are just plain embarrassing. The snake looks terrible, the makeup and prosthetics look miserable. There is a scene where the anaconda eats a black panther and the panther looked way too fake. Even the nose it made sounded fake. Obviously they wouldn't use a real panther or snake but it was poor and lazy filmmaking. This movie was not a complete fail it did have some entertaining parts, specifically the end. Despite being very predictable and knowing which characters would die when, I don't want to vilify this movie because it isn't the worst movie I've ever seen. My favorite scene is the one when they kill the first anaconda. Voight is tied up but he being the way he is turns the scene around and then there's the whole thing with the waterfall. It had the vibe and feel of a climax but it wasn't. Even though the last scene was incredibly ridiculous it was still entertaining. Watching the snake and seeing how huge it was was cool and unexpected. As a kid I loved this movie and I still don't know why. The acting was terrible but I loved Ice Cube. He was terrible but I liked that he was in the movie. For the time he was a big pop culture figure and it made sense that he was in there. I feel like I'm rambling so I'm going to wrap this up. Overall, Anaconda will be a childhood favorite but childhood opinions mean virtually nothing. I want this movie to be rebooted and made properly. There have been sequels that were OK but still unacceptable. A giant snake terrorizing people is interesting and can be exciting. However, John Vogiht's awful accent, Ice Cube, Jennifer Lopez, either of the Wilsons, awful special effects, and poor direction is not the way to do it. I am really disappointed in the movie and it has to get the WillyT Seal of DISapproval.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It will take your breath away!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    irrelevantlife
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some movies seem to be destined to be viewed as bad, even though they contain no bad elements at all, and are only loathed because of their premise; Anaconda (1997) falls into that category of movies. What we have here is the best snake horror movie/creature feature ever created with an actual budget, good actors (great actors, Jon Voight!) and an interesting plot and setting which is used very skilfully by director Luis Llosa. No doubt one of the most impressive and deadly reptiles on this planet, the giant green anaconda is the heavies and some might even argue the longest of all constrictors, and the snake has a mythical status as a ultimate predator in the Amazon, you simply can't argue that a 33 foot snake weighing more than 400 pounds isn't one of THE ultimate aquatic and terrestrial predators. The plot is very straight forward, a team of film makers and scientists travel the Amazon River to document a illusive tribe and their ways of life, on their journey they stumble across a hunter (Jon Voight) who's boat is malfunctioning, they take him in, but soon find out that he has other plans, and is on the hunt for the giant anaconda. The special effects are truly astounding for this type of movie, considering it was made in 1996. The animatronics snake is terrific, and is modelled very accurately to its real life counterpart, something that is imperative in a movie such as this; you want as much authenticity as possible. The CGI effects are very solid, and the score is catchy, yet suspenseful at the same time. People seem to forget that many revered critics at the time of release praised the movie for being well constructed and acted, so the hate for it is completely unfound. Of course we can't review this movie without mentioning the awful sequels that did made all the mistakes the first movie avoided, such as skipping out on authenticity making the snakes look like rubber bands more than actual anacondas. Overall Anaconda, is a great snake horror movie worth watching, it has all the right ingredients of suspense, horror and humour with likable and believable characters and fantastic performance from Voight who steals the show. I strongly recommend this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hello!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    apregnantlesbian
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hello! This is my review for the popular horrible movie called "Anaconda". Anaconda is a popular horrible movie that concerns very angry snake. Maybe it will remind of Steven Spielberg's popular feature presentation "JAWS", although that was shark rather than serpent ha-ha. In this motion picture you will have many shocks and suspense. It is very surprising when snake pops out!!! Be sure not to watch this with your dog, maybe it is a dumb dog and will want to chasing the snake ha-ha. Some interesting trivia about snake, for your enjoyment: - Snake is not a rope. However, it is like an angry rope. - Snake does not have legs.!! So how does it walk??? Snake is full of mysteries...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to take it serious when the snake looks like a giant puppet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JSwallowX1
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's suffice to say that when Jennifer Lopez, Ice Cube and Owen Wilson are amongst the lead cast in a film about a giant snake in the Amazon that it is not going to be much good. And indeed IT isn't; and despite Jon Voight and Eric Stoltz also being amongst the cast in this $45,000,000 production it is a very embarrassing project to be part of. The film has been followed by three sequels to date. A National Geographic crew travel into the heart of the Amazon to shoot a documentary on the long-lost tribe reported to be somewhere along the banks of the immense river. "Cannibal Holocaust" it is not, I'm afraid. Director Terri Flores (Jennifer Lopez) and her anthropologist boyfriend (Eric Stoltz) lead the team. Not long into their voyage they rescue a stranded Paraguayan snake hunter named Paul (Jon Voight). In return, he offers to help them find the lost tribe they are looking for, claiming to have met them. But his true plans unfold when he takes over the boat and forces the crew to aid him in his manic quest to track down a record-breaking Giant Anaconda. And it descends into a typical hunters-become-the-hunted scenario henceforth. For the first half an hour at least, "Anaconda" is somewhat enjoyable. But after that it quickly descends into mediocrity. One must ask the question as to where exactly the $45 million went, because it was certainly not invested in to the special effects department, that's for sure. The Anaconda looks ridiculous. I've seen monsters on the ludicrous Syfy channel films from the last ten years with lower budgets than this managing to turn out better looking monsters. Albeit, just slightly. And I know it was the year 1997, but come on now people, it wasn't that long ago and there was some superb CGI around that time and even before it. "Anaconda" is just a very poorly made film. The acting is diabolical... horrendous (Although in saying that Voight's performance was somewhat interesting). The script resembles something written on a rainy afternoon in after-school study by two bored kids. With dialogue as ingenious as this: "Is it just me or does the jungle make you really, really horny?" that one was courtesy of our man Owen Wilson. And Ice Cube has to get his two cents worth in there too - "That's it, man, I'm getting' the hell back to LA". But Owen Wilson delivers yet again and takes the cake - "You don't know sh*t about the sh*t we're in out here!" Genius. As an adventure film it's oh-so-typical but I suppose it does deliver the trills required for the genre. As a horror movie, it's just too cheap and flamboyant to be anything scary or unsettling. Indeed, the snake may devour someone whole in the film but its more comical than it is disturbing. The snake resembles a giant puppet, and in some scenes I could have sworn I could make-out the wires or whatever they were bobbing it up and down in the water or springing it out of the water like a jack-in-the-box.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anaconda (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfnmbessert-224-279128
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'Anaconda' now, fifteen years after it's release, it's clear to see that this was really just a spiffed up B-movie, cashing in on the success to other monster flicks of the time which were hugely popular like 'Jurassic Park' and 'The Lost World: Jurassic Park' both of which I lump in along with the likes of 'Anaconda'. I have fond memories of wearing out my VHS copies of these films when I was younger, and while 'Anaconda' doesn't stand up to the likes of 'Jurassic Park' in any way, it had its fair share of influencing countless other films which would try to imitate the huge snake killing and eating everyone, none of which had a premise as good as that of 'Anaconda'. Factual errors all aside, the cast is good, and it's notable especially because of the direction they would later take in the following decade, Owen Wilson going more in the direction of comedy rather than action. Jon Voight is the perfect bad guy here, Ice Cube retains his gangster street cred, alongside Jennifer Lopez, and the absolutely beautiful Kari Wuhrer. It's nice that Eric Stoltz's pretentious character is comatose for a good portion of the film, as he's one of the least likable, although I'd say all of the characters here are pretty well written. Danny Trejo's small role in the beginning was something I had forgotten about, being that I haven't seen this in a long time. I know it's probably really only 6 material but since I hold this film in higher regard because of nostalgia, I'm going to give it a 7. ANACONDA ----7/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whether you're laughing at it or with it, at least you're laughing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a worrying sign that the first 60 seconds of a 90 minute film feels the need to 'serious up' the tone by running a lengthy blurb that effectively says 'big snakes are big and dangerous'. Ummmmm. Duh. Now bring on the killer legless lizards! Featuring a cast that is not so much 'good' as 'recognisable' Anaconda thankfully then gets down to the business of being an enjoyably inane flick with B actors wrestling fake snakes and being thrown around by big CGI effects. The threadbare plot has a doco crew traveling the largely unexplored tributaries of the Amazon searching for a long lost tribe of primitive South Americans who legend has it are protected by giant snakes. And how. After a few hiccups in the mission they pick up supposedly 'Paraguayan' snake hunter played by Jon Voight in a hammy performance to rival that of Tim Curry in Congo. He leads the boat on a snaky ahem 'sneaky' shortcut that should save all involved time. Now the fun starts. From this point on there is little for the cast to do but look alternately scared and suspicious in between running around like white mice. The talentless J Lo looks suitably lost and confused  no surprises there  and Eric Stoltz is laid up injured for half the film while Owen Wilson hones his shaggy locked surfer boy thing that has since made him a wealthy man. Ice Cube gets the worst wardrobe and the best lines, and I dare you not to chuckle when they show introduce 'snake stomach' cam near the end of the film. While you might be laughing or gasping about &frac12; the time with and the other &frac12; in spite of the goings on, I guess one way or the other at least you're laughing. Final Rating  5 / 10. Anaconda was released during a spate of creepy crawly based movies in the 90s, it won't blow you away but it was by no means the worst of the bunch and it spawned the usual sucky sequels.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anaconda (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a stupid B-Movie with enough quality to fly by, and enough camp charm to get away with such cinematic crimes. The cast play it straight, apart from Voight. I'm pretty sure he was drunk during the shooting, coming out with an inexplicable accent and a look reminiscent of Hannibal Lecter. It's ridiculous fun, with hokey CGI and animatronics. The animatronics are great and make me miss the 90s. It's a big snake shaped tube and goes from slow robotic motions, to super fast CGI. Cube and Hyde manage some, at times, adorable dialogue. Voight's presence also unites the rest of the cast, and each character gets their own heroic captain moment. Fun filled and just plain bad. I loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This river can kill you in a thousand ways.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A National Geographic crew head down the Amazon in a boat to make a documentary on a long-lost tribe of natives. On the way, they rescue a hunter from his sinking boat and take him on board. After the ship's captain is attacked by a poisonous insect and goes comatose, the hunter commandeers the boat. taking the crew hostage, he makes them go along on his insane quest to capture a giant anaconda..... First things first, the film is awful, its all over the shop and there has to be some of the most over the top acting I've ever seen in a movie. Saying that, I had a blast from beginning to end. Any film that can dub Trejos voice and kill him off in literally the first two minutes, has to be seen. The rest of the film is owned by Voight and a really dodgy looking reptile. Considering this is four years after Jurassic Park, and they spent a hundred grand every second that beast was on screen, its pretty laughable. The rest of the cast are there for filler. Lopez is good, Ice Cube is just a happier Doughboy, Wilson getting into Hollywood big time, and Jonathan Hyde as the token British snob, which is xenophobia if I've ever seen it. But there is so much fun to be had, guessing who will die first, the amount of times Voights accent changes thought the film, and obviously how much better Lopezs' nose looks today. But it is a bad film, and although I had lots of fun watching it, I cannot justify giving it a high rating. But its the best movie ever made where Eric Stoltz is asleep for 80% of the running time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Snake of the Century!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching "Anaconda is like plastering the palm of your hand against a clear glass jar that contains a rattlesnake and then gambling that you won't flinch when the snake strikes at the glass from within the container. More than half of the audience with whom I sat lost this wager every time that the eponymous snake struck. The ghoulish, B-movie plot of "Anaconda" resembles a blueprint for a theme park cruise. Scenarists Hans Bauer, Jim Cash, and Jack Epps, Jr., have borrowed surefire elements and incidents from better movies, such as "Moby Dick" (1956), "Creature from the Black Lagoon" (1954), and "Jaws" (1975). Sadly, although it is entertaining in an idiotic kind of way, "Anaconda" never seems to enthrall its audience because its campy sense of unreality undercuts its chills. The premise has something to do with journalists on an expedition heading down the Amazon in search of a lost South American tribe of Indians. Expedition leader Dr. Steven Cale (Eric Stoltz of "Killing Zoe") picks up a shipwrecked survivor, Paul Sarone (Jon Voight of "Midnight Cowboy"), along the way, but nothing good comes from this act of kindness. Voight turns in a heavily accented performance as an incredibly slimy villain. He is cast as a sinister ex-priest who resembles the feisty Quint (Robert Shaw) in "Jaws." Sarone is as obsessed with bagging giant killer snake as Ahab (Gregory Peck) was with catching a great white whale in "Moby Dick." Sarone is perfectly willing to use his new friends as bait if necessary to trap his 40-foot snake. A freak underwater accident early on puts Dr. Cale out of commission. It seems that when he dove in to fix a stuck propeller, a poisonous fish swam into his mouth and stung him. Sarone convinces the expedition film director, Terri Flores (Jennifer Lopez of "Selena") that he knows a short-cut down a blocked tributary that will cut 50 miles off their trip and save Cale's life. Foolishly, Terri believes Sarone and off they steam literally into the jaws of death. Director Louis Llosa and his scribes really heat up the suspense when Sarone commandeers the boat. Our heroes are cut off now in the untamed jungles of South America, and their radio has crapped out on them. They are without help and completely at the Sarone's mercy. Furthermore, during a big snake attack, the reptile knocks most of their fuel overboard so they have to prowl deeper into snake country to find more fuel. Standing out among the trendy-looking cast for his resilience is rapper Ice Cube from "Boyz N the Hood." He plays a tough, resourceful, film photographer who joins forces with Terri to thwart Sarone. The rest of the expedition crew are largely victims biding their time until they are eaten. If you don't know an animatronic snake from the real McCoy, or if you think this super anaconda could outrun the Road Runner, you're in for a nightmare experience. Every time this fake anaconda struck, most of the audience with which I sat went berserk. This big mother of a snake slings its coils like so many lariats around its prey. No matter if they're scrambling for a ladder or jogging through the jungle, this lethal anaconda hits them like a twister, wraps around them, and then chomps down on their heads. A pretty sight it is not. Meanwhile, the audiences sheds its collective skin. Maybe it wasn't as terrifying as "Alien," but then my audience wouldn't have known the difference. What really matters in "Anaconda" is who will the big, bad snake devour next? And how will our heroes destroy it? Director Louis Llosa, whose helmed better movies such as "The Specialist" and "Sniper," exploits the colorful Amazonian flora and fauna as does the snake. Sure, there are the inevitable anaconda cam shots and for the artistically inclined, Llosa provides a grotesque point of view shot. We get to see what it looks like staring down inside of the python's gullet as it digest another victim. Llosa paces "Anaconda" like a jack-in-the-box. He cranks up the tension between attacks. Just before his audiences has recovered, he unleashes another attack. And be warned, nothing can stop this anaconda. It can smash through windows, shatter boat hulls, and has special sensing ability that attracts it to its prey. This anaconda also shrieks like a cat when it gets hooked. As horror movies go, "Anaconda" is a straightforward, gut and churn classic. Not classic in the sense that it represents superior entertainment. Instead, classic in the sense that it egregious. The only moment in the entire film when the movie makers reach too far is Voight's tacky winking scene. This scene is so hideous that you either howl or hurl. Llosa succeeds in frightening the frijoles out of his audiences with unsavory material. Nothing wrong with that. Any movie that provokes a response is worth watching at least once. The closet that the filmmakers come to sexual encounters is a quickie on the bank that the snake hisses at, and Lopez's wet T-shirt. Despite its glossy, big-budgeted production values, "Anaconda" ends up as such a flaky carnival of outlandish special effects and unrealistic antics that you want to snicker when you should scream and scream when you should snicker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant - The snake reminds me of my first wife.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pog53
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a hoot! A brilliant B movie to watch with a large Gin & Tonic to cheer on the snake. Regrettably I was laughing so much I missed the bit where the amazingly annoying Kari Wuhrer gets the chop. The snake is actually rather good - it looks a bit like my first wife. I didn't know they can scream as well. Jon Voight is as brilliant as ever but the cast dialogue coach was clearly deranged - accents are all over the place and the music is totally out of sync with the scenes. The first snake attack on the boat is a classic - screaming girls, deranged Voight and Owen Wilson ending up as a snake stocking filler. Brilliant. Ice Cube sums it up nicely when he announces: "That's it - I'm off back to LA". Very sensible, mate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Pure Dissapoitment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thewillt08
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a movie with John Voight, Jennifer Lopez, Ice Cube, Owen Wilson, and a giant anaconda, oh dear god. As a kid I loved watching Anaconda, but after seeing it again I must have been crazy as a kid. I think I liked the fact that a giant snake was eating people. The basic premise is that Lopez and her boyfriend I guess are leading an expedition into the Amazon and tend to make a documentary or something. They run into John Voight, a strange man with a terrible accent. Chaos soon ensues when a giant snake terrorizes the passengers and it is up to them to survive or get eaten. Let's start with the cast, the cast in this movie has very little talent. Jennifer Lopez is only in the movie because she is smoking hot. Ice Cube can't act for his life. I can't stand Owen Wilson, but that's a rant for another time. John Voight is an obvious miscast because he is supposed to be the villain and every time he opens his mouth you want to block your ears. The snake looks terrible and I guess there was two of them so the title "Anaconda" is a lie. The only person I can say I actually liked was the British guy. His character actually fit well in the story and he had some development as he eventually turns into a hero of some sort. One character, I don't remember his name, started out important and the movie built him up as a hero and he is sidelined for over half of the movie. He just lays in a bed in a coma like state and it annoyed me to my core. I was counting down the scenes until he came back because he was a likable and relatable character. Instead the movie decided to focus on John Voight and his stupid character and Owen Wilson and his stupidity, then his whiney girlfriend and her stupidity. This movie was frustrating above all else. The special effects in this movie are just plain embarrassing. The snake looks terrible, the makeup and prosthetics look miserable. There is a scene where the anaconda eats a black panther and the panther looked way too fake. Even the nose it made sounded fake. Obviously they wouldn't use a real panther or snake but it was poor and lazy filmmaking. This movie was not a complete fail it did have some entertaining parts, specifically the end. Despite being very predictable and knowing which characters would die when, I don't want to vilify this movie because it isn't the worst movie I've ever seen. My favorite scene is the one when they kill the first anaconda. Voight is tied up but he being the way he is turns the scene around and then there's the whole thing with the waterfall. It had the vibe and feel of a climax but it wasn't. Even though the last scene was incredibly ridiculous it was still entertaining. Watching the snake and seeing how huge it was was cool and unexpected. As a kid I loved this movie and I still don't know why. The acting was terrible but I loved Ice Cube. He was terrible but I liked that he was in the movie. For the time he was a big pop culture figure and it made sense that he was in there. I feel like I'm rambling so I'm going to wrap this up. Overall, Anaconda will be a childhood favorite but childhood opinions mean virtually nothing. I want this movie to be rebooted and made properly. There have been sequels that were OK but still unacceptable. A giant snake terrorizing people is interesting and can be exciting. However, John Vogiht's awful accent, Ice Cube, Jennifer Lopez, either of the Wilsons, awful special effects, and poor direction is not the way to do it. I am really disappointed in the movie and it has to get the WillyT Seal of DISapproval.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It will take your breath away!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    irrelevantlife
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some movies seem to be destined to be viewed as bad, even though they contain no bad elements at all, and are only loathed because of their premise; Anaconda (1997) falls into that category of movies. What we have here is the best snake horror movie/creature feature ever created with an actual budget, good actors (great actors, Jon Voight!) and an interesting plot and setting which is used very skilfully by director Luis Llosa. No doubt one of the most impressive and deadly reptiles on this planet, the giant green anaconda is the heavies and some might even argue the longest of all constrictors, and the snake has a mythical status as a ultimate predator in the Amazon, you simply can't argue that a 33 foot snake weighing more than 400 pounds isn't one of THE ultimate aquatic and terrestrial predators. The plot is very straight forward, a team of film makers and scientists travel the Amazon River to document a illusive tribe and their ways of life, on their journey they stumble across a hunter (Jon Voight) who's boat is malfunctioning, they take him in, but soon find out that he has other plans, and is on the hunt for the giant anaconda. The special effects are truly astounding for this type of movie, considering it was made in 1996. The animatronics snake is terrific, and is modelled very accurately to its real life counterpart, something that is imperative in a movie such as this; you want as much authenticity as possible. The CGI effects are very solid, and the score is catchy, yet suspenseful at the same time. People seem to forget that many revered critics at the time of release praised the movie for being well constructed and acted, so the hate for it is completely unfound. Of course we can't review this movie without mentioning the awful sequels that did made all the mistakes the first movie avoided, such as skipping out on authenticity making the snakes look like rubber bands more than actual anacondas. Overall Anaconda, is a great snake horror movie worth watching, it has all the right ingredients of suspense, horror and humour with likable and believable characters and fantastic performance from Voight who steals the show. I strongly recommend this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hello!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    apregnantlesbian
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hello! This is my review for the popular horrible movie called "Anaconda". Anaconda is a popular horrible movie that concerns very angry snake. Maybe it will remind of Steven Spielberg's popular feature presentation "JAWS", although that was shark rather than serpent ha-ha. In this motion picture you will have many shocks and suspense. It is very surprising when snake pops out!!! Be sure not to watch this with your dog, maybe it is a dumb dog and will want to chasing the snake ha-ha. Some interesting trivia about snake, for your enjoyment: - Snake is not a rope. However, it is like an angry rope. - Snake does not have legs.!! So how does it walk??? Snake is full of mysteries...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to take it serious when the snake looks like a giant puppet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JSwallowX1
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's suffice to say that when Jennifer Lopez, Ice Cube and Owen Wilson are amongst the lead cast in a film about a giant snake in the Amazon that it is not going to be much good. And indeed IT isn't; and despite Jon Voight and Eric Stoltz also being amongst the cast in this $45,000,000 production it is a very embarrassing project to be part of. The film has been followed by three sequels to date. A National Geographic crew travel into the heart of the Amazon to shoot a documentary on the long-lost tribe reported to be somewhere along the banks of the immense river. "Cannibal Holocaust" it is not, I'm afraid. Director Terri Flores (Jennifer Lopez) and her anthropologist boyfriend (Eric Stoltz) lead the team. Not long into their voyage they rescue a stranded Paraguayan snake hunter named Paul (Jon Voight). In return, he offers to help them find the lost tribe they are looking for, claiming to have met them. But his true plans unfold when he takes over the boat and forces the crew to aid him in his manic quest to track down a record-breaking Giant Anaconda. And it descends into a typical hunters-become-the-hunted scenario henceforth. For the first half an hour at least, "Anaconda" is somewhat enjoyable. But after that it quickly descends into mediocrity. One must ask the question as to where exactly the $45 million went, because it was certainly not invested in to the special effects department, that's for sure. The Anaconda looks ridiculous. I've seen monsters on the ludicrous Syfy channel films from the last ten years with lower budgets than this managing to turn out better looking monsters. Albeit, just slightly. And I know it was the year 1997, but come on now people, it wasn't that long ago and there was some superb CGI around that time and even before it. "Anaconda" is just a very poorly made film. The acting is diabolical... horrendous (Although in saying that Voight's performance was somewhat interesting). The script resembles something written on a rainy afternoon in after-school study by two bored kids. With dialogue as ingenious as this: "Is it just me or does the jungle make you really, really horny?" that one was courtesy of our man Owen Wilson. And Ice Cube has to get his two cents worth in there too - "That's it, man, I'm getting' the hell back to LA". But Owen Wilson delivers yet again and takes the cake - "You don't know sh*t about the sh*t we're in out here!" Genius. As an adventure film it's oh-so-typical but I suppose it does deliver the trills required for the genre. As a horror movie, it's just too cheap and flamboyant to be anything scary or unsettling. Indeed, the snake may devour someone whole in the film but its more comical than it is disturbing. The snake resembles a giant puppet, and in some scenes I could have sworn I could make-out the wires or whatever they were bobbing it up and down in the water or springing it out of the water like a jack-in-the-box.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anaconda (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfnmbessert-224-279128
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'Anaconda' now, fifteen years after it's release, it's clear to see that this was really just a spiffed up B-movie, cashing in on the success to other monster flicks of the time which were hugely popular like 'Jurassic Park' and 'The Lost World: Jurassic Park' both of which I lump in along with the likes of 'Anaconda'. I have fond memories of wearing out my VHS copies of these films when I was younger, and while 'Anaconda' doesn't stand up to the likes of 'Jurassic Park' in any way, it had its fair share of influencing countless other films which would try to imitate the huge snake killing and eating everyone, none of which had a premise as good as that of 'Anaconda'. Factual errors all aside, the cast is good, and it's notable especially because of the direction they would later take in the following decade, Owen Wilson going more in the direction of comedy rather than action. Jon Voight is the perfect bad guy here, Ice Cube retains his gangster street cred, alongside Jennifer Lopez, and the absolutely beautiful Kari Wuhrer. It's nice that Eric Stoltz's pretentious character is comatose for a good portion of the film, as he's one of the least likable, although I'd say all of the characters here are pretty well written. Danny Trejo's small role in the beginning was something I had forgotten about, being that I haven't seen this in a long time. I know it's probably really only 6 material but since I hold this film in higher regard because of nostalgia, I'm going to give it a 7. ANACONDA ----7/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whether you're laughing at it or with it, at least you're laughing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a worrying sign that the first 60 seconds of a 90 minute film feels the need to 'serious up' the tone by running a lengthy blurb that effectively says 'big snakes are big and dangerous'. Ummmmm. Duh. Now bring on the killer legless lizards! Featuring a cast that is not so much 'good' as 'recognisable' Anaconda thankfully then gets down to the business of being an enjoyably inane flick with B actors wrestling fake snakes and being thrown around by big CGI effects. The threadbare plot has a doco crew traveling the largely unexplored tributaries of the Amazon searching for a long lost tribe of primitive South Americans who legend has it are protected by giant snakes. And how. After a few hiccups in the mission they pick up supposedly 'Paraguayan' snake hunter played by Jon Voight in a hammy performance to rival that of Tim Curry in Congo. He leads the boat on a snaky ahem 'sneaky' shortcut that should save all involved time. Now the fun starts. From this point on there is little for the cast to do but look alternately scared and suspicious in between running around like white mice. The talentless J Lo looks suitably lost and confused  no surprises there  and Eric Stoltz is laid up injured for half the film while Owen Wilson hones his shaggy locked surfer boy thing that has since made him a wealthy man. Ice Cube gets the worst wardrobe and the best lines, and I dare you not to chuckle when they show introduce 'snake stomach' cam near the end of the film. While you might be laughing or gasping about &frac12; the time with and the other &frac12; in spite of the goings on, I guess one way or the other at least you're laughing. Final Rating  5 / 10. Anaconda was released during a spate of creepy crawly based movies in the 90s, it won't blow you away but it was by no means the worst of the bunch and it spawned the usual sucky sequels.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anaconda (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a stupid B-Movie with enough quality to fly by, and enough camp charm to get away with such cinematic crimes. The cast play it straight, apart from Voight. I'm pretty sure he was drunk during the shooting, coming out with an inexplicable accent and a look reminiscent of Hannibal Lecter. It's ridiculous fun, with hokey CGI and animatronics. The animatronics are great and make me miss the 90s. It's a big snake shaped tube and goes from slow robotic motions, to super fast CGI. Cube and Hyde manage some, at times, adorable dialogue. Voight's presence also unites the rest of the cast, and each character gets their own heroic captain moment. Fun filled and just plain bad. I loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This river can kill you in a thousand ways.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A National Geographic crew head down the Amazon in a boat to make a documentary on a long-lost tribe of natives. On the way, they rescue a hunter from his sinking boat and take him on board. After the ship's captain is attacked by a poisonous insect and goes comatose, the hunter commandeers the boat. taking the crew hostage, he makes them go along on his insane quest to capture a giant anaconda..... First things first, the film is awful, its all over the shop and there has to be some of the most over the top acting I've ever seen in a movie. Saying that, I had a blast from beginning to end. Any film that can dub Trejos voice and kill him off in literally the first two minutes, has to be seen. The rest of the film is owned by Voight and a really dodgy looking reptile. Considering this is four years after Jurassic Park, and they spent a hundred grand every second that beast was on screen, its pretty laughable. The rest of the cast are there for filler. Lopez is good, Ice Cube is just a happier Doughboy, Wilson getting into Hollywood big time, and Jonathan Hyde as the token British snob, which is xenophobia if I've ever seen it. But there is so much fun to be had, guessing who will die first, the amount of times Voights accent changes thought the film, and obviously how much better Lopezs' nose looks today. But it is a bad film, and although I had lots of fun watching it, I cannot justify giving it a high rating. But its the best movie ever made where Eric Stoltz is asleep for 80% of the running time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Snake of the Century!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching "Anaconda is like plastering the palm of your hand against a clear glass jar that contains a rattlesnake and then gambling that you won't flinch when the snake strikes at the glass from within the container. More than half of the audience with whom I sat lost this wager every time that the eponymous snake struck. The ghoulish, B-movie plot of "Anaconda" resembles a blueprint for a theme park cruise. Scenarists Hans Bauer, Jim Cash, and Jack Epps, Jr., have borrowed surefire elements and incidents from better movies, such as "Moby Dick" (1956), "Creature from the Black Lagoon" (1954), and "Jaws" (1975). Sadly, although it is entertaining in an idiotic kind of way, "Anaconda" never seems to enthrall its audience because its campy sense of unreality undercuts its chills. The premise has something to do with journalists on an expedition heading down the Amazon in search of a lost South American tribe of Indians. Expedition leader Dr. Steven Cale (Eric Stoltz of "Killing Zoe") picks up a shipwrecked survivor, Paul Sarone (Jon Voight of "Midnight Cowboy"), along the way, but nothing good comes from this act of kindness. Voight turns in a heavily accented performance as an incredibly slimy villain. He is cast as a sinister ex-priest who resembles the feisty Quint (Robert Shaw) in "Jaws." Sarone is as obsessed with bagging giant killer snake as Ahab (Gregory Peck) was with catching a great white whale in "Moby Dick." Sarone is perfectly willing to use his new friends as bait if necessary to trap his 40-foot snake. A freak underwater accident early on puts Dr. Cale out of commission. It seems that when he dove in to fix a stuck propeller, a poisonous fish swam into his mouth and stung him. Sarone convinces the expedition film director, Terri Flores (Jennifer Lopez of "Selena") that he knows a short-cut down a blocked tributary that will cut 50 miles off their trip and save Cale's life. Foolishly, Terri believes Sarone and off they steam literally into the jaws of death. Director Louis Llosa and his scribes really heat up the suspense when Sarone commandeers the boat. Our heroes are cut off now in the untamed jungles of South America, and their radio has crapped out on them. They are without help and completely at the Sarone's mercy. Furthermore, during a big snake attack, the reptile knocks most of their fuel overboard so they have to prowl deeper into snake country to find more fuel. Standing out among the trendy-looking cast for his resilience is rapper Ice Cube from "Boyz N the Hood." He plays a tough, resourceful, film photographer who joins forces with Terri to thwart Sarone. The rest of the expedition crew are largely victims biding their time until they are eaten. If you don't know an animatronic snake from the real McCoy, or if you think this super anaconda could outrun the Road Runner, you're in for a nightmare experience. Every time this fake anaconda struck, most of the audience with which I sat went berserk. This big mother of a snake slings its coils like so many lariats around its prey. No matter if they're scrambling for a ladder or jogging through the jungle, this lethal anaconda hits them like a twister, wraps around them, and then chomps down on their heads. A pretty sight it is not. Meanwhile, the audiences sheds its collective skin. Maybe it wasn't as terrifying as "Alien," but then my audience wouldn't have known the difference. What really matters in "Anaconda" is who will the big, bad snake devour next? And how will our heroes destroy it? Director Louis Llosa, whose helmed better movies such as "The Specialist" and "Sniper," exploits the colorful Amazonian flora and fauna as does the snake. Sure, there are the inevitable anaconda cam shots and for the artistically inclined, Llosa provides a grotesque point of view shot. We get to see what it looks like staring down inside of the python's gullet as it digest another victim. Llosa paces "Anaconda" like a jack-in-the-box. He cranks up the tension between attacks. Just before his audiences has recovered, he unleashes another attack. And be warned, nothing can stop this anaconda. It can smash through windows, shatter boat hulls, and has special sensing ability that attracts it to its prey. This anaconda also shrieks like a cat when it gets hooked. As horror movies go, "Anaconda" is a straightforward, gut and churn classic. Not classic in the sense that it represents superior entertainment. Instead, classic in the sense that it egregious. The only moment in the entire film when the movie makers reach too far is Voight's tacky winking scene. This scene is so hideous that you either howl or hurl. Llosa succeeds in frightening the frijoles out of his audiences with unsavory material. Nothing wrong with that. Any movie that provokes a response is worth watching at least once. The closet that the filmmakers come to sexual encounters is a quickie on the bank that the snake hisses at, and Lopez's wet T-shirt. Despite its glossy, big-budgeted production values, "Anaconda" ends up as such a flaky carnival of outlandish special effects and unrealistic antics that you want to snicker when you should scream and scream when you should snicker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant - The snake reminds me of my first wife.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pog53
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a hoot! A brilliant B movie to watch with a large Gin & Tonic to cheer on the snake. Regrettably I was laughing so much I missed the bit where the amazingly annoying Kari Wuhrer gets the chop. The snake is actually rather good - it looks a bit like my first wife. I didn't know they can scream as well. Jon Voight is as brilliant as ever but the cast dialogue coach was clearly deranged - accents are all over the place and the music is totally out of sync with the scenes. The first snake attack on the boat is a classic - screaming girls, deranged Voight and Owen Wilson ending up as a snake stocking filler. Brilliant. Ice Cube sums it up nicely when he announces: "That's it - I'm off back to LA". Very sensible, mate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Pure Dissapoitment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thewillt08
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a movie with John Voight, Jennifer Lopez, Ice Cube, Owen Wilson, and a giant anaconda, oh dear god. As a kid I loved watching Anaconda, but after seeing it again I must have been crazy as a kid. I think I liked the fact that a giant snake was eating people. The basic premise is that Lopez and her boyfriend I guess are leading an expedition into the Amazon and tend to make a documentary or something. They run into John Voight, a strange man with a terrible accent. Chaos soon ensues when a giant snake terrorizes the passengers and it is up to them to survive or get eaten. Let's start with the cast, the cast in this movie has very little talent. Jennifer Lopez is only in the movie because she is smoking hot. Ice Cube can't act for his life. I can't stand Owen Wilson, but that's a rant for another time. John Voight is an obvious miscast because he is supposed to be the villain and every time he opens his mouth you want to block your ears. The snake looks terrible and I guess there was two of them so the title "Anaconda" is a lie. The only person I can say I actually liked was the British guy. His character actually fit well in the story and he had some development as he eventually turns into a hero of some sort. One character, I don't remember his name, started out important and the movie built him up as a hero and he is sidelined for over half of the movie. He just lays in a bed in a coma like state and it annoyed me to my core. I was counting down the scenes until he came back because he was a likable and relatable character. Instead the movie decided to focus on John Voight and his stupid character and Owen Wilson and his stupidity, then his whiney girlfriend and her stupidity. This movie was frustrating above all else. The special effects in this movie are just plain embarrassing. The snake looks terrible, the makeup and prosthetics look miserable. There is a scene where the anaconda eats a black panther and the panther looked way too fake. Even the nose it made sounded fake. Obviously they wouldn't use a real panther or snake but it was poor and lazy filmmaking. This movie was not a complete fail it did have some entertaining parts, specifically the end. Despite being very predictable and knowing which characters would die when, I don't want to vilify this movie because it isn't the worst movie I've ever seen. My favorite scene is the one when they kill the first anaconda. Voight is tied up but he being the way he is turns the scene around and then there's the whole thing with the waterfall. It had the vibe and feel of a climax but it wasn't. Even though the last scene was incredibly ridiculous it was still entertaining. Watching the snake and seeing how huge it was was cool and unexpected. As a kid I loved this movie and I still don't know why. The acting was terrible but I loved Ice Cube. He was terrible but I liked that he was in the movie. For the time he was a big pop culture figure and it made sense that he was in there. I feel like I'm rambling so I'm going to wrap this up. Overall, Anaconda will be a childhood favorite but childhood opinions mean virtually nothing. I want this movie to be rebooted and made properly. There have been sequels that were OK but still unacceptable. A giant snake terrorizing people is interesting and can be exciting. However, John Vogiht's awful accent, Ice Cube, Jennifer Lopez, either of the Wilsons, awful special effects, and poor direction is not the way to do it. I am really disappointed in the movie and it has to get the WillyT Seal of DISapproval.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It will take your breath away!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    irrelevantlife
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some movies seem to be destined to be viewed as bad, even though they contain no bad elements at all, and are only loathed because of their premise; Anaconda (1997) falls into that category of movies. What we have here is the best snake horror movie/creature feature ever created with an actual budget, good actors (great actors, Jon Voight!) and an interesting plot and setting which is used very skilfully by director Luis Llosa. No doubt one of the most impressive and deadly reptiles on this planet, the giant green anaconda is the heavies and some might even argue the longest of all constrictors, and the snake has a mythical status as a ultimate predator in the Amazon, you simply can't argue that a 33 foot snake weighing more than 400 pounds isn't one of THE ultimate aquatic and terrestrial predators. The plot is very straight forward, a team of film makers and scientists travel the Amazon River to document a illusive tribe and their ways of life, on their journey they stumble across a hunter (Jon Voight) who's boat is malfunctioning, they take him in, but soon find out that he has other plans, and is on the hunt for the giant anaconda. The special effects are truly astounding for this type of movie, considering it was made in 1996. The animatronics snake is terrific, and is modelled very accurately to its real life counterpart, something that is imperative in a movie such as this; you want as much authenticity as possible. The CGI effects are very solid, and the score is catchy, yet suspenseful at the same time. People seem to forget that many revered critics at the time of release praised the movie for being well constructed and acted, so the hate for it is completely unfound. Of course we can't review this movie without mentioning the awful sequels that did made all the mistakes the first movie avoided, such as skipping out on authenticity making the snakes look like rubber bands more than actual anacondas. Overall Anaconda, is a great snake horror movie worth watching, it has all the right ingredients of suspense, horror and humour with likable and believable characters and fantastic performance from Voight who steals the show. I strongly recommend this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hello!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    apregnantlesbian
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hello! This is my review for the popular horrible movie called "Anaconda". Anaconda is a popular horrible movie that concerns very angry snake. Maybe it will remind of Steven Spielberg's popular feature presentation "JAWS", although that was shark rather than serpent ha-ha. In this motion picture you will have many shocks and suspense. It is very surprising when snake pops out!!! Be sure not to watch this with your dog, maybe it is a dumb dog and will want to chasing the snake ha-ha. Some interesting trivia about snake, for your enjoyment: - Snake is not a rope. However, it is like an angry rope. - Snake does not have legs.!! So how does it walk??? Snake is full of mysteries...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to take it serious when the snake looks like a giant puppet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JSwallowX1
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's suffice to say that when Jennifer Lopez, Ice Cube and Owen Wilson are amongst the lead cast in a film about a giant snake in the Amazon that it is not going to be much good. And indeed IT isn't; and despite Jon Voight and Eric Stoltz also being amongst the cast in this $45,000,000 production it is a very embarrassing project to be part of. The film has been followed by three sequels to date. A National Geographic crew travel into the heart of the Amazon to shoot a documentary on the long-lost tribe reported to be somewhere along the banks of the immense river. "Cannibal Holocaust" it is not, I'm afraid. Director Terri Flores (Jennifer Lopez) and her anthropologist boyfriend (Eric Stoltz) lead the team. Not long into their voyage they rescue a stranded Paraguayan snake hunter named Paul (Jon Voight). In return, he offers to help them find the lost tribe they are looking for, claiming to have met them. But his true plans unfold when he takes over the boat and forces the crew to aid him in his manic quest to track down a record-breaking Giant Anaconda. And it descends into a typical hunters-become-the-hunted scenario henceforth. For the first half an hour at least, "Anaconda" is somewhat enjoyable. But after that it quickly descends into mediocrity. One must ask the question as to where exactly the $45 million went, because it was certainly not invested in to the special effects department, that's for sure. The Anaconda looks ridiculous. I've seen monsters on the ludicrous Syfy channel films from the last ten years with lower budgets than this managing to turn out better looking monsters. Albeit, just slightly. And I know it was the year 1997, but come on now people, it wasn't that long ago and there was some superb CGI around that time and even before it. "Anaconda" is just a very poorly made film. The acting is diabolical... horrendous (Although in saying that Voight's performance was somewhat interesting). The script resembles something written on a rainy afternoon in after-school study by two bored kids. With dialogue as ingenious as this: "Is it just me or does the jungle make you really, really horny?" that one was courtesy of our man Owen Wilson. And Ice Cube has to get his two cents worth in there too - "That's it, man, I'm getting' the hell back to LA". But Owen Wilson delivers yet again and takes the cake - "You don't know sh*t about the sh*t we're in out here!" Genius. As an adventure film it's oh-so-typical but I suppose it does deliver the trills required for the genre. As a horror movie, it's just too cheap and flamboyant to be anything scary or unsettling. Indeed, the snake may devour someone whole in the film but its more comical than it is disturbing. The snake resembles a giant puppet, and in some scenes I could have sworn I could make-out the wires or whatever they were bobbing it up and down in the water or springing it out of the water like a jack-in-the-box.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anaconda (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfnmbessert-224-279128
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'Anaconda' now, fifteen years after it's release, it's clear to see that this was really just a spiffed up B-movie, cashing in on the success to other monster flicks of the time which were hugely popular like 'Jurassic Park' and 'The Lost World: Jurassic Park' both of which I lump in along with the likes of 'Anaconda'. I have fond memories of wearing out my VHS copies of these films when I was younger, and while 'Anaconda' doesn't stand up to the likes of 'Jurassic Park' in any way, it had its fair share of influencing countless other films which would try to imitate the huge snake killing and eating everyone, none of which had a premise as good as that of 'Anaconda'. Factual errors all aside, the cast is good, and it's notable especially because of the direction they would later take in the following decade, Owen Wilson going more in the direction of comedy rather than action. Jon Voight is the perfect bad guy here, Ice Cube retains his gangster street cred, alongside Jennifer Lopez, and the absolutely beautiful Kari Wuhrer. It's nice that Eric Stoltz's pretentious character is comatose for a good portion of the film, as he's one of the least likable, although I'd say all of the characters here are pretty well written. Danny Trejo's small role in the beginning was something I had forgotten about, being that I haven't seen this in a long time. I know it's probably really only 6 material but since I hold this film in higher regard because of nostalgia, I'm going to give it a 7. ANACONDA ----7/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whether you're laughing at it or with it, at least you're laughing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a worrying sign that the first 60 seconds of a 90 minute film feels the need to 'serious up' the tone by running a lengthy blurb that effectively says 'big snakes are big and dangerous'. Ummmmm. Duh. Now bring on the killer legless lizards! Featuring a cast that is not so much 'good' as 'recognisable' Anaconda thankfully then gets down to the business of being an enjoyably inane flick with B actors wrestling fake snakes and being thrown around by big CGI effects. The threadbare plot has a doco crew traveling the largely unexplored tributaries of the Amazon searching for a long lost tribe of primitive South Americans who legend has it are protected by giant snakes. And how. After a few hiccups in the mission they pick up supposedly 'Paraguayan' snake hunter played by Jon Voight in a hammy performance to rival that of Tim Curry in Congo. He leads the boat on a snaky ahem 'sneaky' shortcut that should save all involved time. Now the fun starts. From this point on there is little for the cast to do but look alternately scared and suspicious in between running around like white mice. The talentless J Lo looks suitably lost and confused  no surprises there  and Eric Stoltz is laid up injured for half the film while Owen Wilson hones his shaggy locked surfer boy thing that has since made him a wealthy man. Ice Cube gets the worst wardrobe and the best lines, and I dare you not to chuckle when they show introduce 'snake stomach' cam near the end of the film. While you might be laughing or gasping about &frac12; the time with and the other &frac12; in spite of the goings on, I guess one way or the other at least you're laughing. Final Rating  5 / 10. Anaconda was released during a spate of creepy crawly based movies in the 90s, it won't blow you away but it was by no means the worst of the bunch and it spawned the usual sucky sequels.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anaconda (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a stupid B-Movie with enough quality to fly by, and enough camp charm to get away with such cinematic crimes. The cast play it straight, apart from Voight. I'm pretty sure he was drunk during the shooting, coming out with an inexplicable accent and a look reminiscent of Hannibal Lecter. It's ridiculous fun, with hokey CGI and animatronics. The animatronics are great and make me miss the 90s. It's a big snake shaped tube and goes from slow robotic motions, to super fast CGI. Cube and Hyde manage some, at times, adorable dialogue. Voight's presence also unites the rest of the cast, and each character gets their own heroic captain moment. Fun filled and just plain bad. I loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This river can kill you in a thousand ways.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A National Geographic crew head down the Amazon in a boat to make a documentary on a long-lost tribe of natives. On the way, they rescue a hunter from his sinking boat and take him on board. After the ship's captain is attacked by a poisonous insect and goes comatose, the hunter commandeers the boat. taking the crew hostage, he makes them go along on his insane quest to capture a giant anaconda..... First things first, the film is awful, its all over the shop and there has to be some of the most over the top acting I've ever seen in a movie. Saying that, I had a blast from beginning to end. Any film that can dub Trejos voice and kill him off in literally the first two minutes, has to be seen. The rest of the film is owned by Voight and a really dodgy looking reptile. Considering this is four years after Jurassic Park, and they spent a hundred grand every second that beast was on screen, its pretty laughable. The rest of the cast are there for filler. Lopez is good, Ice Cube is just a happier Doughboy, Wilson getting into Hollywood big time, and Jonathan Hyde as the token British snob, which is xenophobia if I've ever seen it. But there is so much fun to be had, guessing who will die first, the amount of times Voights accent changes thought the film, and obviously how much better Lopezs' nose looks today. But it is a bad film, and although I had lots of fun watching it, I cannot justify giving it a high rating. But its the best movie ever made where Eric Stoltz is asleep for 80% of the running time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Snake of the Century!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching "Anaconda is like plastering the palm of your hand against a clear glass jar that contains a rattlesnake and then gambling that you won't flinch when the snake strikes at the glass from within the container. More than half of the audience with whom I sat lost this wager every time that the eponymous snake struck. The ghoulish, B-movie plot of "Anaconda" resembles a blueprint for a theme park cruise. Scenarists Hans Bauer, Jim Cash, and Jack Epps, Jr., have borrowed surefire elements and incidents from better movies, such as "Moby Dick" (1956), "Creature from the Black Lagoon" (1954), and "Jaws" (1975). Sadly, although it is entertaining in an idiotic kind of way, "Anaconda" never seems to enthrall its audience because its campy sense of unreality undercuts its chills. The premise has something to do with journalists on an expedition heading down the Amazon in search of a lost South American tribe of Indians. Expedition leader Dr. Steven Cale (Eric Stoltz of "Killing Zoe") picks up a shipwrecked survivor, Paul Sarone (Jon Voight of "Midnight Cowboy"), along the way, but nothing good comes from this act of kindness. Voight turns in a heavily accented performance as an incredibly slimy villain. He is cast as a sinister ex-priest who resembles the feisty Quint (Robert Shaw) in "Jaws." Sarone is as obsessed with bagging giant killer snake as Ahab (Gregory Peck) was with catching a great white whale in "Moby Dick." Sarone is perfectly willing to use his new friends as bait if necessary to trap his 40-foot snake. A freak underwater accident early on puts Dr. Cale out of commission. It seems that when he dove in to fix a stuck propeller, a poisonous fish swam into his mouth and stung him. Sarone convinces the expedition film director, Terri Flores (Jennifer Lopez of "Selena") that he knows a short-cut down a blocked tributary that will cut 50 miles off their trip and save Cale's life. Foolishly, Terri believes Sarone and off they steam literally into the jaws of death. Director Louis Llosa and his scribes really heat up the suspense when Sarone commandeers the boat. Our heroes are cut off now in the untamed jungles of South America, and their radio has crapped out on them. They are without help and completely at the Sarone's mercy. Furthermore, during a big snake attack, the reptile knocks most of their fuel overboard so they have to prowl deeper into snake country to find more fuel. Standing out among the trendy-looking cast for his resilience is rapper Ice Cube from "Boyz N the Hood." He plays a tough, resourceful, film photographer who joins forces with Terri to thwart Sarone. The rest of the expedition crew are largely victims biding their time until they are eaten. If you don't know an animatronic snake from the real McCoy, or if you think this super anaconda could outrun the Road Runner, you're in for a nightmare experience. Every time this fake anaconda struck, most of the audience with which I sat went berserk. This big mother of a snake slings its coils like so many lariats around its prey. No matter if they're scrambling for a ladder or jogging through the jungle, this lethal anaconda hits them like a twister, wraps around them, and then chomps down on their heads. A pretty sight it is not. Meanwhile, the audiences sheds its collective skin. Maybe it wasn't as terrifying as "Alien," but then my audience wouldn't have known the difference. What really matters in "Anaconda" is who will the big, bad snake devour next? And how will our heroes destroy it? Director Louis Llosa, whose helmed better movies such as "The Specialist" and "Sniper," exploits the colorful Amazonian flora and fauna as does the snake. Sure, there are the inevitable anaconda cam shots and for the artistically inclined, Llosa provides a grotesque point of view shot. We get to see what it looks like staring down inside of the python's gullet as it digest another victim. Llosa paces "Anaconda" like a jack-in-the-box. He cranks up the tension between attacks. Just before his audiences has recovered, he unleashes another attack. And be warned, nothing can stop this anaconda. It can smash through windows, shatter boat hulls, and has special sensing ability that attracts it to its prey. This anaconda also shrieks like a cat when it gets hooked. As horror movies go, "Anaconda" is a straightforward, gut and churn classic. Not classic in the sense that it represents superior entertainment. Instead, classic in the sense that it egregious. The only moment in the entire film when the movie makers reach too far is Voight's tacky winking scene. This scene is so hideous that you either howl or hurl. Llosa succeeds in frightening the frijoles out of his audiences with unsavory material. Nothing wrong with that. Any movie that provokes a response is worth watching at least once. The closet that the filmmakers come to sexual encounters is a quickie on the bank that the snake hisses at, and Lopez's wet T-shirt. Despite its glossy, big-budgeted production values, "Anaconda" ends up as such a flaky carnival of outlandish special effects and unrealistic antics that you want to snicker when you should scream and scream when you should snicker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant - The snake reminds me of my first wife.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pog53
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a hoot! A brilliant B movie to watch with a large Gin & Tonic to cheer on the snake. Regrettably I was laughing so much I missed the bit where the amazingly annoying Kari Wuhrer gets the chop. The snake is actually rather good - it looks a bit like my first wife. I didn't know they can scream as well. Jon Voight is as brilliant as ever but the cast dialogue coach was clearly deranged - accents are all over the place and the music is totally out of sync with the scenes. The first snake attack on the boat is a classic - screaming girls, deranged Voight and Owen Wilson ending up as a snake stocking filler. Brilliant. Ice Cube sums it up nicely when he announces: "That's it - I'm off back to LA". Very sensible, mate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Pure Dissapoitment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thewillt08
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a movie with John Voight, Jennifer Lopez, Ice Cube, Owen Wilson, and a giant anaconda, oh dear god. As a kid I loved watching Anaconda, but after seeing it again I must have been crazy as a kid. I think I liked the fact that a giant snake was eating people. The basic premise is that Lopez and her boyfriend I guess are leading an expedition into the Amazon and tend to make a documentary or something. They run into John Voight, a strange man with a terrible accent. Chaos soon ensues when a giant snake terrorizes the passengers and it is up to them to survive or get eaten. Let's start with the cast, the cast in this movie has very little talent. Jennifer Lopez is only in the movie because she is smoking hot. Ice Cube can't act for his life. I can't stand Owen Wilson, but that's a rant for another time. John Voight is an obvious miscast because he is supposed to be the villain and every time he opens his mouth you want to block your ears. The snake looks terrible and I guess there was two of them so the title "Anaconda" is a lie. The only person I can say I actually liked was the British guy. His character actually fit well in the story and he had some development as he eventually turns into a hero of some sort. One character, I don't remember his name, started out important and the movie built him up as a hero and he is sidelined for over half of the movie. He just lays in a bed in a coma like state and it annoyed me to my core. I was counting down the scenes until he came back because he was a likable and relatable character. Instead the movie decided to focus on John Voight and his stupid character and Owen Wilson and his stupidity, then his whiney girlfriend and her stupidity. This movie was frustrating above all else. The special effects in this movie are just plain embarrassing. The snake looks terrible, the makeup and prosthetics look miserable. There is a scene where the anaconda eats a black panther and the panther looked way too fake. Even the nose it made sounded fake. Obviously they wouldn't use a real panther or snake but it was poor and lazy filmmaking. This movie was not a complete fail it did have some entertaining parts, specifically the end. Despite being very predictable and knowing which characters would die when, I don't want to vilify this movie because it isn't the worst movie I've ever seen. My favorite scene is the one when they kill the first anaconda. Voight is tied up but he being the way he is turns the scene around and then there's the whole thing with the waterfall. It had the vibe and feel of a climax but it wasn't. Even though the last scene was incredibly ridiculous it was still entertaining. Watching the snake and seeing how huge it was was cool and unexpected. As a kid I loved this movie and I still don't know why. The acting was terrible but I loved Ice Cube. He was terrible but I liked that he was in the movie. For the time he was a big pop culture figure and it made sense that he was in there. I feel like I'm rambling so I'm going to wrap this up. Overall, Anaconda will be a childhood favorite but childhood opinions mean virtually nothing. I want this movie to be rebooted and made properly. There have been sequels that were OK but still unacceptable. A giant snake terrorizing people is interesting and can be exciting. However, John Vogiht's awful accent, Ice Cube, Jennifer Lopez, either of the Wilsons, awful special effects, and poor direction is not the way to do it. I am really disappointed in the movie and it has to get the WillyT Seal of DISapproval.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It will take your breath away!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    irrelevantlife
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some movies seem to be destined to be viewed as bad, even though they contain no bad elements at all, and are only loathed because of their premise; Anaconda (1997) falls into that category of movies. What we have here is the best snake horror movie/creature feature ever created with an actual budget, good actors (great actors, Jon Voight!) and an interesting plot and setting which is used very skilfully by director Luis Llosa. No doubt one of the most impressive and deadly reptiles on this planet, the giant green anaconda is the heavies and some might even argue the longest of all constrictors, and the snake has a mythical status as a ultimate predator in the Amazon, you simply can't argue that a 33 foot snake weighing more than 400 pounds isn't one of THE ultimate aquatic and terrestrial predators. The plot is very straight forward, a team of film makers and scientists travel the Amazon River to document a illusive tribe and their ways of life, on their journey they stumble across a hunter (Jon Voight) who's boat is malfunctioning, they take him in, but soon find out that he has other plans, and is on the hunt for the giant anaconda. The special effects are truly astounding for this type of movie, considering it was made in 1996. The animatronics snake is terrific, and is modelled very accurately to its real life counterpart, something that is imperative in a movie such as this; you want as much authenticity as possible. The CGI effects are very solid, and the score is catchy, yet suspenseful at the same time. People seem to forget that many revered critics at the time of release praised the movie for being well constructed and acted, so the hate for it is completely unfound. Of course we can't review this movie without mentioning the awful sequels that did made all the mistakes the first movie avoided, such as skipping out on authenticity making the snakes look like rubber bands more than actual anacondas. Overall Anaconda, is a great snake horror movie worth watching, it has all the right ingredients of suspense, horror and humour with likable and believable characters and fantastic performance from Voight who steals the show. I strongly recommend this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hello!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    apregnantlesbian
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hello! This is my review for the popular horrible movie called "Anaconda". Anaconda is a popular horrible movie that concerns very angry snake. Maybe it will remind of Steven Spielberg's popular feature presentation "JAWS", although that was shark rather than serpent ha-ha. In this motion picture you will have many shocks and suspense. It is very surprising when snake pops out!!! Be sure not to watch this with your dog, maybe it is a dumb dog and will want to chasing the snake ha-ha. Some interesting trivia about snake, for your enjoyment: - Snake is not a rope. However, it is like an angry rope. - Snake does not have legs.!! So how does it walk??? Snake is full of mysteries...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to take it serious when the snake looks like a giant puppet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JSwallowX1
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's suffice to say that when Jennifer Lopez, Ice Cube and Owen Wilson are amongst the lead cast in a film about a giant snake in the Amazon that it is not going to be much good. And indeed IT isn't; and despite Jon Voight and Eric Stoltz also being amongst the cast in this $45,000,000 production it is a very embarrassing project to be part of. The film has been followed by three sequels to date. A National Geographic crew travel into the heart of the Amazon to shoot a documentary on the long-lost tribe reported to be somewhere along the banks of the immense river. "Cannibal Holocaust" it is not, I'm afraid. Director Terri Flores (Jennifer Lopez) and her anthropologist boyfriend (Eric Stoltz) lead the team. Not long into their voyage they rescue a stranded Paraguayan snake hunter named Paul (Jon Voight). In return, he offers to help them find the lost tribe they are looking for, claiming to have met them. But his true plans unfold when he takes over the boat and forces the crew to aid him in his manic quest to track down a record-breaking Giant Anaconda. And it descends into a typical hunters-become-the-hunted scenario henceforth. For the first half an hour at least, "Anaconda" is somewhat enjoyable. But after that it quickly descends into mediocrity. One must ask the question as to where exactly the $45 million went, because it was certainly not invested in to the special effects department, that's for sure. The Anaconda looks ridiculous. I've seen monsters on the ludicrous Syfy channel films from the last ten years with lower budgets than this managing to turn out better looking monsters. Albeit, just slightly. And I know it was the year 1997, but come on now people, it wasn't that long ago and there was some superb CGI around that time and even before it. "Anaconda" is just a very poorly made film. The acting is diabolical... horrendous (Although in saying that Voight's performance was somewhat interesting). The script resembles something written on a rainy afternoon in after-school study by two bored kids. With dialogue as ingenious as this: "Is it just me or does the jungle make you really, really horny?" that one was courtesy of our man Owen Wilson. And Ice Cube has to get his two cents worth in there too - "That's it, man, I'm getting' the hell back to LA". But Owen Wilson delivers yet again and takes the cake - "You don't know sh*t about the sh*t we're in out here!" Genius. As an adventure film it's oh-so-typical but I suppose it does deliver the trills required for the genre. As a horror movie, it's just too cheap and flamboyant to be anything scary or unsettling. Indeed, the snake may devour someone whole in the film but its more comical than it is disturbing. The snake resembles a giant puppet, and in some scenes I could have sworn I could make-out the wires or whatever they were bobbing it up and down in the water or springing it out of the water like a jack-in-the-box.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anaconda (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfnmbessert-224-279128
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'Anaconda' now, fifteen years after it's release, it's clear to see that this was really just a spiffed up B-movie, cashing in on the success to other monster flicks of the time which were hugely popular like 'Jurassic Park' and 'The Lost World: Jurassic Park' both of which I lump in along with the likes of 'Anaconda'. I have fond memories of wearing out my VHS copies of these films when I was younger, and while 'Anaconda' doesn't stand up to the likes of 'Jurassic Park' in any way, it had its fair share of influencing countless other films which would try to imitate the huge snake killing and eating everyone, none of which had a premise as good as that of 'Anaconda'. Factual errors all aside, the cast is good, and it's notable especially because of the direction they would later take in the following decade, Owen Wilson going more in the direction of comedy rather than action. Jon Voight is the perfect bad guy here, Ice Cube retains his gangster street cred, alongside Jennifer Lopez, and the absolutely beautiful Kari Wuhrer. It's nice that Eric Stoltz's pretentious character is comatose for a good portion of the film, as he's one of the least likable, although I'd say all of the characters here are pretty well written. Danny Trejo's small role in the beginning was something I had forgotten about, being that I haven't seen this in a long time. I know it's probably really only 6 material but since I hold this film in higher regard because of nostalgia, I'm going to give it a 7. ANACONDA ----7/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whether you're laughing at it or with it, at least you're laughing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a worrying sign that the first 60 seconds of a 90 minute film feels the need to 'serious up' the tone by running a lengthy blurb that effectively says 'big snakes are big and dangerous'. Ummmmm. Duh. Now bring on the killer legless lizards! Featuring a cast that is not so much 'good' as 'recognisable' Anaconda thankfully then gets down to the business of being an enjoyably inane flick with B actors wrestling fake snakes and being thrown around by big CGI effects. The threadbare plot has a doco crew traveling the largely unexplored tributaries of the Amazon searching for a long lost tribe of primitive South Americans who legend has it are protected by giant snakes. And how. After a few hiccups in the mission they pick up supposedly 'Paraguayan' snake hunter played by Jon Voight in a hammy performance to rival that of Tim Curry in Congo. He leads the boat on a snaky ahem 'sneaky' shortcut that should save all involved time. Now the fun starts. From this point on there is little for the cast to do but look alternately scared and suspicious in between running around like white mice. The talentless J Lo looks suitably lost and confused  no surprises there  and Eric Stoltz is laid up injured for half the film while Owen Wilson hones his shaggy locked surfer boy thing that has since made him a wealthy man. Ice Cube gets the worst wardrobe and the best lines, and I dare you not to chuckle when they show introduce 'snake stomach' cam near the end of the film. While you might be laughing or gasping about &frac12; the time with and the other &frac12; in spite of the goings on, I guess one way or the other at least you're laughing. Final Rating  5 / 10. Anaconda was released during a spate of creepy crawly based movies in the 90s, it won't blow you away but it was by no means the worst of the bunch and it spawned the usual sucky sequels.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anaconda (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a stupid B-Movie with enough quality to fly by, and enough camp charm to get away with such cinematic crimes. The cast play it straight, apart from Voight. I'm pretty sure he was drunk during the shooting, coming out with an inexplicable accent and a look reminiscent of Hannibal Lecter. It's ridiculous fun, with hokey CGI and animatronics. The animatronics are great and make me miss the 90s. It's a big snake shaped tube and goes from slow robotic motions, to super fast CGI. Cube and Hyde manage some, at times, adorable dialogue. Voight's presence also unites the rest of the cast, and each character gets their own heroic captain moment. Fun filled and just plain bad. I loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This river can kill you in a thousand ways.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A National Geographic crew head down the Amazon in a boat to make a documentary on a long-lost tribe of natives. On the way, they rescue a hunter from his sinking boat and take him on board. After the ship's captain is attacked by a poisonous insect and goes comatose, the hunter commandeers the boat. taking the crew hostage, he makes them go along on his insane quest to capture a giant anaconda..... First things first, the film is awful, its all over the shop and there has to be some of the most over the top acting I've ever seen in a movie. Saying that, I had a blast from beginning to end. Any film that can dub Trejos voice and kill him off in literally the first two minutes, has to be seen. The rest of the film is owned by Voight and a really dodgy looking reptile. Considering this is four years after Jurassic Park, and they spent a hundred grand every second that beast was on screen, its pretty laughable. The rest of the cast are there for filler. Lopez is good, Ice Cube is just a happier Doughboy, Wilson getting into Hollywood big time, and Jonathan Hyde as the token British snob, which is xenophobia if I've ever seen it. But there is so much fun to be had, guessing who will die first, the amount of times Voights accent changes thought the film, and obviously how much better Lopezs' nose looks today. But it is a bad film, and although I had lots of fun watching it, I cannot justify giving it a high rating. But its the best movie ever made where Eric Stoltz is asleep for 80% of the running time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Snake of the Century!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching "Anaconda is like plastering the palm of your hand against a clear glass jar that contains a rattlesnake and then gambling that you won't flinch when the snake strikes at the glass from within the container. More than half of the audience with whom I sat lost this wager every time that the eponymous snake struck. The ghoulish, B-movie plot of "Anaconda" resembles a blueprint for a theme park cruise. Scenarists Hans Bauer, Jim Cash, and Jack Epps, Jr., have borrowed surefire elements and incidents from better movies, such as "Moby Dick" (1956), "Creature from the Black Lagoon" (1954), and "Jaws" (1975). Sadly, although it is entertaining in an idiotic kind of way, "Anaconda" never seems to enthrall its audience because its campy sense of unreality undercuts its chills. The premise has something to do with journalists on an expedition heading down the Amazon in search of a lost South American tribe of Indians. Expedition leader Dr. Steven Cale (Eric Stoltz of "Killing Zoe") picks up a shipwrecked survivor, Paul Sarone (Jon Voight of "Midnight Cowboy"), along the way, but nothing good comes from this act of kindness. Voight turns in a heavily accented performance as an incredibly slimy villain. He is cast as a sinister ex-priest who resembles the feisty Quint (Robert Shaw) in "Jaws." Sarone is as obsessed with bagging giant killer snake as Ahab (Gregory Peck) was with catching a great white whale in "Moby Dick." Sarone is perfectly willing to use his new friends as bait if necessary to trap his 40-foot snake. A freak underwater accident early on puts Dr. Cale out of commission. It seems that when he dove in to fix a stuck propeller, a poisonous fish swam into his mouth and stung him. Sarone convinces the expedition film director, Terri Flores (Jennifer Lopez of "Selena") that he knows a short-cut down a blocked tributary that will cut 50 miles off their trip and save Cale's life. Foolishly, Terri believes Sarone and off they steam literally into the jaws of death. Director Louis Llosa and his scribes really heat up the suspense when Sarone commandeers the boat. Our heroes are cut off now in the untamed jungles of South America, and their radio has crapped out on them. They are without help and completely at the Sarone's mercy. Furthermore, during a big snake attack, the reptile knocks most of their fuel overboard so they have to prowl deeper into snake country to find more fuel. Standing out among the trendy-looking cast for his resilience is rapper Ice Cube from "Boyz N the Hood." He plays a tough, resourceful, film photographer who joins forces with Terri to thwart Sarone. The rest of the expedition crew are largely victims biding their time until they are eaten. If you don't know an animatronic snake from the real McCoy, or if you think this super anaconda could outrun the Road Runner, you're in for a nightmare experience. Every time this fake anaconda struck, most of the audience with which I sat went berserk. This big mother of a snake slings its coils like so many lariats around its prey. No matter if they're scrambling for a ladder or jogging through the jungle, this lethal anaconda hits them like a twister, wraps around them, and then chomps down on their heads. A pretty sight it is not. Meanwhile, the audiences sheds its collective skin. Maybe it wasn't as terrifying as "Alien," but then my audience wouldn't have known the difference. What really matters in "Anaconda" is who will the big, bad snake devour next? And how will our heroes destroy it? Director Louis Llosa, whose helmed better movies such as "The Specialist" and "Sniper," exploits the colorful Amazonian flora and fauna as does the snake. Sure, there are the inevitable anaconda cam shots and for the artistically inclined, Llosa provides a grotesque point of view shot. We get to see what it looks like staring down inside of the python's gullet as it digest another victim. Llosa paces "Anaconda" like a jack-in-the-box. He cranks up the tension between attacks. Just before his audiences has recovered, he unleashes another attack. And be warned, nothing can stop this anaconda. It can smash through windows, shatter boat hulls, and has special sensing ability that attracts it to its prey. This anaconda also shrieks like a cat when it gets hooked. As horror movies go, "Anaconda" is a straightforward, gut and churn classic. Not classic in the sense that it represents superior entertainment. Instead, classic in the sense that it egregious. The only moment in the entire film when the movie makers reach too far is Voight's tacky winking scene. This scene is so hideous that you either howl or hurl. Llosa succeeds in frightening the frijoles out of his audiences with unsavory material. Nothing wrong with that. Any movie that provokes a response is worth watching at least once. The closet that the filmmakers come to sexual encounters is a quickie on the bank that the snake hisses at, and Lopez's wet T-shirt. Despite its glossy, big-budgeted production values, "Anaconda" ends up as such a flaky carnival of outlandish special effects and unrealistic antics that you want to snicker when you should scream and scream when you should snicker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant - The snake reminds me of my first wife.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pog53
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a hoot! A brilliant B movie to watch with a large Gin & Tonic to cheer on the snake. Regrettably I was laughing so much I missed the bit where the amazingly annoying Kari Wuhrer gets the chop. The snake is actually rather good - it looks a bit like my first wife. I didn't know they can scream as well. Jon Voight is as brilliant as ever but the cast dialogue coach was clearly deranged - accents are all over the place and the music is totally out of sync with the scenes. The first snake attack on the boat is a classic - screaming girls, deranged Voight and Owen Wilson ending up as a snake stocking filler. Brilliant. Ice Cube sums it up nicely when he announces: "That's it - I'm off back to LA". Very sensible, mate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Pure Dissapoitment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thewillt08
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a movie with John Voight, Jennifer Lopez, Ice Cube, Owen Wilson, and a giant anaconda, oh dear god. As a kid I loved watching Anaconda, but after seeing it again I must have been crazy as a kid. I think I liked the fact that a giant snake was eating people. The basic premise is that Lopez and her boyfriend I guess are leading an expedition into the Amazon and tend to make a documentary or something. They run into John Voight, a strange man with a terrible accent. Chaos soon ensues when a giant snake terrorizes the passengers and it is up to them to survive or get eaten. Let's start with the cast, the cast in this movie has very little talent. Jennifer Lopez is only in the movie because she is smoking hot. Ice Cube can't act for his life. I can't stand Owen Wilson, but that's a rant for another time. John Voight is an obvious miscast because he is supposed to be the villain and every time he opens his mouth you want to block your ears. The snake looks terrible and I guess there was two of them so the title "Anaconda" is a lie. The only person I can say I actually liked was the British guy. His character actually fit well in the story and he had some development as he eventually turns into a hero of some sort. One character, I don't remember his name, started out important and the movie built him up as a hero and he is sidelined for over half of the movie. He just lays in a bed in a coma like state and it annoyed me to my core. I was counting down the scenes until he came back because he was a likable and relatable character. Instead the movie decided to focus on John Voight and his stupid character and Owen Wilson and his stupidity, then his whiney girlfriend and her stupidity. This movie was frustrating above all else. The special effects in this movie are just plain embarrassing. The snake looks terrible, the makeup and prosthetics look miserable. There is a scene where the anaconda eats a black panther and the panther looked way too fake. Even the nose it made sounded fake. Obviously they wouldn't use a real panther or snake but it was poor and lazy filmmaking. This movie was not a complete fail it did have some entertaining parts, specifically the end. Despite being very predictable and knowing which characters would die when, I don't want to vilify this movie because it isn't the worst movie I've ever seen. My favorite scene is the one when they kill the first anaconda. Voight is tied up but he being the way he is turns the scene around and then there's the whole thing with the waterfall. It had the vibe and feel of a climax but it wasn't. Even though the last scene was incredibly ridiculous it was still entertaining. Watching the snake and seeing how huge it was was cool and unexpected. As a kid I loved this movie and I still don't know why. The acting was terrible but I loved Ice Cube. He was terrible but I liked that he was in the movie. For the time he was a big pop culture figure and it made sense that he was in there. I feel like I'm rambling so I'm going to wrap this up. Overall, Anaconda will be a childhood favorite but childhood opinions mean virtually nothing. I want this movie to be rebooted and made properly. There have been sequels that were OK but still unacceptable. A giant snake terrorizing people is interesting and can be exciting. However, John Vogiht's awful accent, Ice Cube, Jennifer Lopez, either of the Wilsons, awful special effects, and poor direction is not the way to do it. I am really disappointed in the movie and it has to get the WillyT Seal of DISapproval.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It will take your breath away!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    irrelevantlife
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some movies seem to be destined to be viewed as bad, even though they contain no bad elements at all, and are only loathed because of their premise; Anaconda (1997) falls into that category of movies. What we have here is the best snake horror movie/creature feature ever created with an actual budget, good actors (great actors, Jon Voight!) and an interesting plot and setting which is used very skilfully by director Luis Llosa. No doubt one of the most impressive and deadly reptiles on this planet, the giant green anaconda is the heavies and some might even argue the longest of all constrictors, and the snake has a mythical status as a ultimate predator in the Amazon, you simply can't argue that a 33 foot snake weighing more than 400 pounds isn't one of THE ultimate aquatic and terrestrial predators. The plot is very straight forward, a team of film makers and scientists travel the Amazon River to document a illusive tribe and their ways of life, on their journey they stumble across a hunter (Jon Voight) who's boat is malfunctioning, they take him in, but soon find out that he has other plans, and is on the hunt for the giant anaconda. The special effects are truly astounding for this type of movie, considering it was made in 1996. The animatronics snake is terrific, and is modelled very accurately to its real life counterpart, something that is imperative in a movie such as this; you want as much authenticity as possible. The CGI effects are very solid, and the score is catchy, yet suspenseful at the same time. People seem to forget that many revered critics at the time of release praised the movie for being well constructed and acted, so the hate for it is completely unfound. Of course we can't review this movie without mentioning the awful sequels that did made all the mistakes the first movie avoided, such as skipping out on authenticity making the snakes look like rubber bands more than actual anacondas. Overall Anaconda, is a great snake horror movie worth watching, it has all the right ingredients of suspense, horror and humour with likable and believable characters and fantastic performance from Voight who steals the show. I strongly recommend this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hello!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    apregnantlesbian
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hello! This is my review for the popular horrible movie called "Anaconda". Anaconda is a popular horrible movie that concerns very angry snake. Maybe it will remind of Steven Spielberg's popular feature presentation "JAWS", although that was shark rather than serpent ha-ha. In this motion picture you will have many shocks and suspense. It is very surprising when snake pops out!!! Be sure not to watch this with your dog, maybe it is a dumb dog and will want to chasing the snake ha-ha. Some interesting trivia about snake, for your enjoyment: - Snake is not a rope. However, it is like an angry rope. - Snake does not have legs.!! So how does it walk??? Snake is full of mysteries...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to take it serious when the snake looks like a giant puppet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JSwallowX1
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's suffice to say that when Jennifer Lopez, Ice Cube and Owen Wilson are amongst the lead cast in a film about a giant snake in the Amazon that it is not going to be much good. And indeed IT isn't; and despite Jon Voight and Eric Stoltz also being amongst the cast in this $45,000,000 production it is a very embarrassing project to be part of. The film has been followed by three sequels to date. A National Geographic crew travel into the heart of the Amazon to shoot a documentary on the long-lost tribe reported to be somewhere along the banks of the immense river. "Cannibal Holocaust" it is not, I'm afraid. Director Terri Flores (Jennifer Lopez) and her anthropologist boyfriend (Eric Stoltz) lead the team. Not long into their voyage they rescue a stranded Paraguayan snake hunter named Paul (Jon Voight). In return, he offers to help them find the lost tribe they are looking for, claiming to have met them. But his true plans unfold when he takes over the boat and forces the crew to aid him in his manic quest to track down a record-breaking Giant Anaconda. And it descends into a typical hunters-become-the-hunted scenario henceforth. For the first half an hour at least, "Anaconda" is somewhat enjoyable. But after that it quickly descends into mediocrity. One must ask the question as to where exactly the $45 million went, because it was certainly not invested in to the special effects department, that's for sure. The Anaconda looks ridiculous. I've seen monsters on the ludicrous Syfy channel films from the last ten years with lower budgets than this managing to turn out better looking monsters. Albeit, just slightly. And I know it was the year 1997, but come on now people, it wasn't that long ago and there was some superb CGI around that time and even before it. "Anaconda" is just a very poorly made film. The acting is diabolical... horrendous (Although in saying that Voight's performance was somewhat interesting). The script resembles something written on a rainy afternoon in after-school study by two bored kids. With dialogue as ingenious as this: "Is it just me or does the jungle make you really, really horny?" that one was courtesy of our man Owen Wilson. And Ice Cube has to get his two cents worth in there too - "That's it, man, I'm getting' the hell back to LA". But Owen Wilson delivers yet again and takes the cake - "You don't know sh*t about the sh*t we're in out here!" Genius. As an adventure film it's oh-so-typical but I suppose it does deliver the trills required for the genre. As a horror movie, it's just too cheap and flamboyant to be anything scary or unsettling. Indeed, the snake may devour someone whole in the film but its more comical than it is disturbing. The snake resembles a giant puppet, and in some scenes I could have sworn I could make-out the wires or whatever they were bobbing it up and down in the water or springing it out of the water like a jack-in-the-box.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anaconda (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfnmbessert-224-279128
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'Anaconda' now, fifteen years after it's release, it's clear to see that this was really just a spiffed up B-movie, cashing in on the success to other monster flicks of the time which were hugely popular like 'Jurassic Park' and 'The Lost World: Jurassic Park' both of which I lump in along with the likes of 'Anaconda'. I have fond memories of wearing out my VHS copies of these films when I was younger, and while 'Anaconda' doesn't stand up to the likes of 'Jurassic Park' in any way, it had its fair share of influencing countless other films which would try to imitate the huge snake killing and eating everyone, none of which had a premise as good as that of 'Anaconda'. Factual errors all aside, the cast is good, and it's notable especially because of the direction they would later take in the following decade, Owen Wilson going more in the direction of comedy rather than action. Jon Voight is the perfect bad guy here, Ice Cube retains his gangster street cred, alongside Jennifer Lopez, and the absolutely beautiful Kari Wuhrer. It's nice that Eric Stoltz's pretentious character is comatose for a good portion of the film, as he's one of the least likable, although I'd say all of the characters here are pretty well written. Danny Trejo's small role in the beginning was something I had forgotten about, being that I haven't seen this in a long time. I know it's probably really only 6 material but since I hold this film in higher regard because of nostalgia, I'm going to give it a 7. ANACONDA ----7/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whether you're laughing at it or with it, at least you're laughing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a worrying sign that the first 60 seconds of a 90 minute film feels the need to 'serious up' the tone by running a lengthy blurb that effectively says 'big snakes are big and dangerous'. Ummmmm. Duh. Now bring on the killer legless lizards! Featuring a cast that is not so much 'good' as 'recognisable' Anaconda thankfully then gets down to the business of being an enjoyably inane flick with B actors wrestling fake snakes and being thrown around by big CGI effects. The threadbare plot has a doco crew traveling the largely unexplored tributaries of the Amazon searching for a long lost tribe of primitive South Americans who legend has it are protected by giant snakes. And how. After a few hiccups in the mission they pick up supposedly 'Paraguayan' snake hunter played by Jon Voight in a hammy performance to rival that of Tim Curry in Congo. He leads the boat on a snaky ahem 'sneaky' shortcut that should save all involved time. Now the fun starts. From this point on there is little for the cast to do but look alternately scared and suspicious in between running around like white mice. The talentless J Lo looks suitably lost and confused  no surprises there  and Eric Stoltz is laid up injured for half the film while Owen Wilson hones his shaggy locked surfer boy thing that has since made him a wealthy man. Ice Cube gets the worst wardrobe and the best lines, and I dare you not to chuckle when they show introduce 'snake stomach' cam near the end of the film. While you might be laughing or gasping about &frac12; the time with and the other &frac12; in spite of the goings on, I guess one way or the other at least you're laughing. Final Rating  5 / 10. Anaconda was released during a spate of creepy crawly based movies in the 90s, it won't blow you away but it was by no means the worst of the bunch and it spawned the usual sucky sequels.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anaconda (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a stupid B-Movie with enough quality to fly by, and enough camp charm to get away with such cinematic crimes. The cast play it straight, apart from Voight. I'm pretty sure he was drunk during the shooting, coming out with an inexplicable accent and a look reminiscent of Hannibal Lecter. It's ridiculous fun, with hokey CGI and animatronics. The animatronics are great and make me miss the 90s. It's a big snake shaped tube and goes from slow robotic motions, to super fast CGI. Cube and Hyde manage some, at times, adorable dialogue. Voight's presence also unites the rest of the cast, and each character gets their own heroic captain moment. Fun filled and just plain bad. I loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
