<filme>
 <id>
  1027
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0114432
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  The Shooter
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  4.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A CIA agent gets caught up in political intrigue after he gets brought in to solve the murder of a Cuban ambassador.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  The Ambassador of Cuba was killed in New York. To prevent another attack of the terrorists at the US-Cuba-summit in Prague the CIA sends one of their best federal agents, Michael Dane (Dolph Lundgren). The suspected killer Nikita is a lesbian club owner, Simone Rosset. But as usual everything is much more complicated than it seemed at first; and therefore Dane has to work much more with his brain than with his muscles to survive.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   ambassador
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   agent
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   murder
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   lesbian
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   shootout
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Ted Kotcheff
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Yves Andr&eacute; Martin
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Meg Thayer
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Dolph Lundgren
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Maruschka Detmers
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Assumpta Serna
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hidden Assassin is one of the better 90's Dolph flicks.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Comeuppance Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When the Cuban ambassador to the U.N. is assassinated by a sniper, U.S. Marshal Michael Dane (Dolph) travels to Prague to apprehend the suspect. As it turns out, the suspect is Simone Rosset (Detmers), and the relationship between Dane and Rosset becomes complicated. Naturally, there is a conspiracy that goes all the way to the top - and Dane must fight hard to get to the truth. Being a stranger in a strange land, will he succeed? Hidden Assassin - not to be confused with Silent Trigger (1996), or Hidden Agenda (2001) for that matter (although Silent Trigger has a similar plot that involves male and female snipers who are conflicted about their actions) - was made during the period in Dolph's career where he was trying to be more serious, and was appearing in films with a darker and more somber tone. Whether intentionally or not on his part when he was choosing his roles, these 90's Dolphs are different from his 80's heyday. What follows is more intrigue than out-and-out action, and that's not necessarily a bad thing, it's just a different animal from, say, The Punisher (1989). Here Dolph is put into some interesting scenarios - from a smooth, wine-tasting gentleman, to an action hero not afraid to get hurt and be covered in blood (interestingly, his white T-shirt with the bloodstain will remind you of Andrew W.K.). He even wears an interesting Franz Kafka shirt at one point. The Prague locations are a highlight of the movie. The cinematography is top-notch, and thanks to the interesting setting and good production values, as well as the big-sounding score, Hidden Assassin seems to be going for a classier vibe. Detmers recalls a more-sane Sean Young in her prime, and as far as casting goes, in lesser (?) hands, Dolph's role could have been played - should the dire need arise - by Frank Zagarino (similar hair). His sidekick could have been played by Dennis Franz. What's going on with Dennis Franz? We haven't heard too much from him lately. Hidden Assassin is probably one of the better 90's Dolphs, thanks to the quality of the technical aspects of the film, but had this movie been made in the 80's, it would have been a more full-throttle action film, and that would have been nice to see. For more insanity, please visit: comeuppancereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The haunting of Michael Dane
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oOgiandujaOo
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I quite like watching Dolph Lundgren movies that are high on atmosphere. One of my favourite movies is Silent Trigger, which is just gorgeously shot. So I read reviews of this one as being also beautiful, and there's sniping in the movie too, so I went with it. I'm not going to make a huge fuss and tell you that the movie is Barry Lyndon, but it really is purty. I'll get to that after a brief round up of the plot. So the Dolphage here is US Marshal Michael Dane, who has been sent abroad to kidnap Simone Rosset (Maruschka Detmers), a sniper who is accused of assassinating a Cuban official in New York, and bring her to trial. I don't quite know how controversial such an extra-jurisdictional kidnapping is, there are documented cases of the US doing it, but I wouldn't have thought the US Marshal service would have been employed. It's morally wrong, as Rosset says in the movie, if the Czechs abducted a US citizen from Pittsburgh for trial in the Czech Republic, that would be a huge international incident. Thing is she may not even have done it, and Dane (like Waxman in Silent Trigger) has a troubled conscience. Rosset has been in retirement for at least a decade and is now running a restaurant in Prague with her lover Marta (Assumpta Serna), their world is not just a little intoxicating to Dane. You get a sense, when he sees Simone's expressive dancing in a lesbian night club, that it's an image that will be engraved into his mind for the rest of his days. Assumpta Serna's presence is welcome, she's an unbelievable sauce who actually appears to have more sexual power 10 years later in the Quay Brothers' superb movie PianoTuner of Earthquakes at the age of nearly 50. Purty places include the fabulous Czech restaurant, which I suspect is probably a little more touristy than the movie suggests (you can see Alphonse Mucha designs on the backs of the menus - famous artist of Prague). There's also a lovely wine cellar, and Marta's flat is quite beautiful. Something I harp on about a lot is the transformative quality of interior design in movies, it really does help if you have good diegetic lighting and plush dream apartments in movies. Marta has candles a plenty, cushions on the floor to lounge on, and lovely greenery everywhere, cheese plants, mimosa, and the like. Marta and Simone, one gets the impression, are experts at living. Although others have said that the special effects are not all that, I think there's a couple of pretty cool ones, take the leap to the metro car for example. It's true that the movie is a cheapie compared with modern stuff, but I don't think a few cases of movie explosives were going to make this one better. The plot is fairly much all over the place, and the Cuban officials in the movie a big annoyance, the fact that Dolph is basically the adopted son of one of the spooks comes off as pretty silly, as does the major plot twist. Despite what is also a fairly ludicrous ending, there are very cool parts to the script, such as the observation by Alex (the adoptive father), that the only time self-doubt is useful is when you're playing Hamlet on stage. There's also a kind of strange beauty to the fights between Dolph and Simone, in that he's more than twice her size, and yet she has enough nouse to make them last out. The lasting value is in the film's aesthetics, and the haunting of Dane, as well as the occasional fairly cool special effect. It joins my list of flawed but very purty and lovable movies that were made during my childhood, alongside the likes of Albert Pyun's Cyborg, and Wes Craven's Shocker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not terrible... but awfully flat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wizard-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's really hard to believe that this movie was directed by the same person who directed FIRST BLOOD. I was expecting top-grade action, especially since Lundgren was the star, but the movie is a real bore. Oh, there are shootings, hand-to-hand combat, and chases, but all of this is presented to come across as just as unexciting as the rest of the movie. The script is (mostly) unsurprising, containing a major plot twist that you'll see coming from the first few minutes of the movie. (Though I admit the eventual plot turn concerning the female lead did give me a surprise.) Movie is also badly photographed, with muddy colors throughout. Lundgren tries, but is pretty overwhelmed, and the best performance turns out to be by John Ashton, playing Lundgren's buddy. Recommended only to die-hard (and very forgiving) Lundgren fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favourite Dolph movies...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    theduke_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Though this film would be classed as mediocre by most, I rate this movie fairly high. The scenery is fantastic, the soundtrack is interesting with its combination of suspense and smooth jazz, and with Dolph Lundgren side-kicked with John Ashton you get a smooth, even dose of action, adventure and comedy. Though the movie does seem slow at times, and you tend to forget the characters names or the reason why Dolph is actually there in the first place, the movie does provide decent suspense and action throughout. I didn't like the fact that Dolph's main wound (his arm) was self-inflicted and rather, well... pointless. However, the rooftop-gunfight scene (end) and the part where Dolph takes out a sniper with a handgun are simply a must see! (Believable? It is within Dolph's power, ha-ha!) The ending is simply awesome. Enough said. This movie is fantastic, you'll either rate it as a masterpiece or just a decent, action flick; but nothing lower.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Name is Michael Dane
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dolph Lundgren in a murkily-lit modestly-budgeted Co-European production, I have to say, is not a prospect to get the average moviegoer's pulse racing; Dolph is the poor man's Arnie  not, as it turns out, because of acting ability or screen presence, but simply because Arnie came first. Nevertheless, that's the way it is for poor old Dolph, so throughout the 90s all he seemed to get were the scraps that fell from Arnie's table. This one isn't as bad as you might expect. It isn't good either, but it's serviceable. It certainly improves on a weak first ten minutes that are hampered by some lousy lighting and even lousier acting from the likes of Gavan O'Herlihy who chews scenery like a man with indigestion who doesn't wish to appear impolite. Dolph is Michael Dane, a US Marshal on the hunt for Simone Rosset (Maruschka Detmers) a shapely assassin suspected of doing a Frank Sinatra and coming out of retirement to off a Cuban ambassador. Rosset, however, pleads her innocence, and Dane uncovers doings of the murky variety when he investigates a little further. Detmers is an actress new to me, but she adds a touch of class to an otherwise pedestrian action movie. Her character is obviously modelled on Nikita, but Simone is a part-time lesbian with a taste for good wine and a knack for jumping off high places. Detmers gives the impression she is slumming  that's how classy she is. Lundgren gives a decent enough performance too, but the story lets them both down in crucial areas. Dane is just a little too dim, even for a Marshal. He uses a tactic of self-mutilation instead of surveillance, stages a car chase which nearly ends up with him and his passenger being squashed between two tram cars simply because he wants to drive rather than be driven, and shoots indiscriminately into a moving train. On the plus side, the story does at least try to be a little different from the countless other mid-budget efforts out there, adding an unexpected twist that is well-timed and effective, and making use of some terrific Prague location work. This one is for those times when you really don't want to think about what you are watching; it's for when you want the film to do all the work and lay everything out for you without inserting any sly subtexts, etc. The action set-pieces are a little workmanlike  the budgets restricts them to a couple of car chases and a lot of gunfights  but one, carried out on the rooftops of Prague, is pretty cool. No-one sitting down to watch a film like this should be doing so with high expectations, so it follows then that no-one should be disappointed
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dolph saves the day and single-handedly restores US-Cuban relations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ****SPOILERS**** After the Cuban Ambassador to the UN is assassinated in New York City the CIA, with the help of Cuban government officials, trace the killer to be the daughter of an exiled anti-Castro Cuban living in the Czech Republic who's a professional assassin named Simone Rosset and using the name of Yanna Natova, Maruschka Detmers. With a major meeting by the Cuban and US government set in Prague to re-establish diplomatic relations between those two countries it's expected that Simone will disrupt the meeting by trying to kill both the Cuban and US officials expected to sign that agreement. Sending US Marshall Michael Dane, Dolph Lundgren, to arrest Simone and bring her back to the US to stand trial for the Cuban Ambassador's murder Michael is met by his long time friend and US government agent Alex Reed, John Aston, to help him in finding and arresting Simone. After tracking her down during a number of car and train chases as well as a dangerous jump, from a high bridge into the Danube River, that almost killed both Michael and Simone, Michael finally captures her. Later as Michael is about to take Simone to the Prague airport to fly with her back to the US, to be tried for murder, Simone tells him that she never was in New York the day of the Ambassador's killing and never left the Czech Republic in five years; Simone also tells Michael that she'll never live to stand trial. Simone's prediction comes sadly true when she's assassinated in a Prague hotel room after Michael saved her life from a number of assassin attempts that he foiled. One of Dolph's better efforts showing that he could act as well as haul and kick butt that he's so well known for. Realizing, too late to save Simone's life, that it's evident that there are those in higher ups in both the US and Cuban governments who don't want that signing to take place Michael goes to the signing ceremony in Prague to prevent it from being disrupted by the real assassins of the Cuban UN Ambassador. Great action scenes that leave you black and blue just from watching them with Dolph Lundgren at his best as the reluctant hero who breaks with his superiors, to stop the very assassination that he was assigned by them to prevent, who think that the real killer is already dead. Maruschka Detmers is the biggest surprise in the movie by being every bit as good as Dolph in the action scenes but also touches the heart-strings with her both sensitive as well as tragic performance as the doomed Simone. Tremendous final under the streets and on top of the buildings of picturesque Prague with Dolph Lundgren, bloody T-shirt and all, saving the day by putting the bad guys on ice as well as single-handedly restoring US-Cuban relations for the first time in some forty years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Average, if not entertaining........
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rmadesp (rmadesp@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like to carve Dolph Lundgren's career into 3 different slices. The 1st being his glory days from Rocky IV to Army Of One......the 3rd being his recent releases which have been all pretty disappointing, and the 2nd are made up of films like this one which fall in the period between the other two. Here we have a film which is not bad nor mediocre, yet doesnt quite reach the level of greatness that Dolph has achieved in previous releases. In other words, the action sequences are quite dull & unimaginative, yet there is a believable story line here which keeps the viewer watching. Another high point is the Prague setting.......some nice visuals here. Dont expect I Come In Peace or Punisher standards, but still worth checking out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Dolph's better flicks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bd119-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hidden Assassin (its proper name is The Shooter) is not just another mindless Dolph Lundgren actioner. It's a fairly well-plotted and exciting political thriller with some fine acting and great action sequences. But the real best thing about this movie is the setting. Filmed on location in Prague, the film looks beautiful and often stunning. Dolph plays a US Marshall (surprise, surprise) who is sent to Prague to find the assassin who killed the Cuban ambassador. Detmers is a beautiful bisexual assassin who Dolph gets caught up with, and before long the two of them are walking on dangerous ground while trying to stay alive the whole time. The suspense is always growing, as we never know who the killer is, wondering if it's Dolph's boss or even Detmers herself... I really like this movie. It's entertaining to watch and full of twists and surprises. Overall, I would probably recommend this one over some of Dolph's most well-known movies (Red Scorpion, Universal Soldier). Though without it's share of plot-holes, this remains a fun and very enjoyable romp.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An above average crime thriller.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Jolliffe (supertom-3)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a Dolph Lundgren fan this film goes down as one of my prefered viewings. I do like a good thriller, with some plot twists and tension. This film has those but to a mild degree, your not going to get really excited at this compared to something like Mission Impoosble with its high production and A-list cast but for a B-movie this is a good film that is surprising in places and reasonably well written. Dolph plays Michael Dane, who is working with the FBI to try to capture a known assasin played by the sexy Maruschka Detmers. Dane does not beleive she killed the Cuban Ambassador, but he still has to bring her into custody in the build up to a summit between the US and Cuba to try to get the two country's to shake and make up if you like. The plot at times raises questions that many action thrillers do, for instance why are they doing that? one particular example is the inclusion of Dolphs character, he is flown in from New York to Prague simply to arrest this Woman, why on Earth she wasn't brought in before is beyond me, especially considering that her whereabouts were known. A lot doesn't make sense but those minor quibbles aside, the film is nicely paced and is enjoyable. The acting is good, Dolph is assured and puts in one of his better performances, he has great chemistry with the excellent Maruschka who in turn also shows great chemistry with Assumpta Serna who plays Marta the possible lover of Simone. That is another mystery of the film, the sexual preference of Simone (Detmers) this does kind of undermine the development of a relationship between Dolph and Maruschkas characters. Also good is John Ashton as a bit of comic support as Danes Foster father and aid in the hunt for Simone. Furthermore, the action scenes. They are not overly stylish but are exciting, Dolph is in prime condition to dish out a battering and there is some good gun play included as well. Particular standout scenes are the capturing of Simone, and her subsequant escape. Also later in the film when Dolph rescues Simones character and just after when they both escape. The end is good to with the music helping to really build everything to a climactic crescendo. Overall this is a fairly decent thriller, with some nice lighting in the dark shots, and some nice and suitably dank locations. Dolph and Maruschka have a great chemistry, and the twists in the film are good. I would give this a 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A positive review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles (ang1150)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I got it because I'm a Maruschka Detmers fan, and I wasn't disappointed in her part, however limited it was in showcasing her talents. I didn't take this movie seriously, and I'll bet the actors had fun making this movie. The scenery and location were very impressive, the interaction between the main characters was good, with a touch of (unintended?) comedy throughout. Some of the scenes were unbelievable, but that just added to the feeling that you couldn't take this seriously as an action-adventure movie. For example, how could Michael pass by all the security points, evil bad guys pursuing him unscathed? If it isn't taken seriously, well that's the fun of it. I had never seen Dolph Lundgren act before, and was comparing him to Arnold... both are hard workers. The story line is this movie's weakest point, along with a few minor characters who obviously were put in the movie for appearance but no acting ability whatsoever. Overall, I liked it and after repeated viewings, I still enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hidden Assassin is one of the better 90's Dolph flicks.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Comeuppance Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When the Cuban ambassador to the U.N. is assassinated by a sniper, U.S. Marshal Michael Dane (Dolph) travels to Prague to apprehend the suspect. As it turns out, the suspect is Simone Rosset (Detmers), and the relationship between Dane and Rosset becomes complicated. Naturally, there is a conspiracy that goes all the way to the top - and Dane must fight hard to get to the truth. Being a stranger in a strange land, will he succeed? Hidden Assassin - not to be confused with Silent Trigger (1996), or Hidden Agenda (2001) for that matter (although Silent Trigger has a similar plot that involves male and female snipers who are conflicted about their actions) - was made during the period in Dolph's career where he was trying to be more serious, and was appearing in films with a darker and more somber tone. Whether intentionally or not on his part when he was choosing his roles, these 90's Dolphs are different from his 80's heyday. What follows is more intrigue than out-and-out action, and that's not necessarily a bad thing, it's just a different animal from, say, The Punisher (1989). Here Dolph is put into some interesting scenarios - from a smooth, wine-tasting gentleman, to an action hero not afraid to get hurt and be covered in blood (interestingly, his white T-shirt with the bloodstain will remind you of Andrew W.K.). He even wears an interesting Franz Kafka shirt at one point. The Prague locations are a highlight of the movie. The cinematography is top-notch, and thanks to the interesting setting and good production values, as well as the big-sounding score, Hidden Assassin seems to be going for a classier vibe. Detmers recalls a more-sane Sean Young in her prime, and as far as casting goes, in lesser (?) hands, Dolph's role could have been played - should the dire need arise - by Frank Zagarino (similar hair). His sidekick could have been played by Dennis Franz. What's going on with Dennis Franz? We haven't heard too much from him lately. Hidden Assassin is probably one of the better 90's Dolphs, thanks to the quality of the technical aspects of the film, but had this movie been made in the 80's, it would have been a more full-throttle action film, and that would have been nice to see. For more insanity, please visit: comeuppancereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The haunting of Michael Dane
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oOgiandujaOo
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I quite like watching Dolph Lundgren movies that are high on atmosphere. One of my favourite movies is Silent Trigger, which is just gorgeously shot. So I read reviews of this one as being also beautiful, and there's sniping in the movie too, so I went with it. I'm not going to make a huge fuss and tell you that the movie is Barry Lyndon, but it really is purty. I'll get to that after a brief round up of the plot. So the Dolphage here is US Marshal Michael Dane, who has been sent abroad to kidnap Simone Rosset (Maruschka Detmers), a sniper who is accused of assassinating a Cuban official in New York, and bring her to trial. I don't quite know how controversial such an extra-jurisdictional kidnapping is, there are documented cases of the US doing it, but I wouldn't have thought the US Marshal service would have been employed. It's morally wrong, as Rosset says in the movie, if the Czechs abducted a US citizen from Pittsburgh for trial in the Czech Republic, that would be a huge international incident. Thing is she may not even have done it, and Dane (like Waxman in Silent Trigger) has a troubled conscience. Rosset has been in retirement for at least a decade and is now running a restaurant in Prague with her lover Marta (Assumpta Serna), their world is not just a little intoxicating to Dane. You get a sense, when he sees Simone's expressive dancing in a lesbian night club, that it's an image that will be engraved into his mind for the rest of his days. Assumpta Serna's presence is welcome, she's an unbelievable sauce who actually appears to have more sexual power 10 years later in the Quay Brothers' superb movie PianoTuner of Earthquakes at the age of nearly 50. Purty places include the fabulous Czech restaurant, which I suspect is probably a little more touristy than the movie suggests (you can see Alphonse Mucha designs on the backs of the menus - famous artist of Prague). There's also a lovely wine cellar, and Marta's flat is quite beautiful. Something I harp on about a lot is the transformative quality of interior design in movies, it really does help if you have good diegetic lighting and plush dream apartments in movies. Marta has candles a plenty, cushions on the floor to lounge on, and lovely greenery everywhere, cheese plants, mimosa, and the like. Marta and Simone, one gets the impression, are experts at living. Although others have said that the special effects are not all that, I think there's a couple of pretty cool ones, take the leap to the metro car for example. It's true that the movie is a cheapie compared with modern stuff, but I don't think a few cases of movie explosives were going to make this one better. The plot is fairly much all over the place, and the Cuban officials in the movie a big annoyance, the fact that Dolph is basically the adopted son of one of the spooks comes off as pretty silly, as does the major plot twist. Despite what is also a fairly ludicrous ending, there are very cool parts to the script, such as the observation by Alex (the adoptive father), that the only time self-doubt is useful is when you're playing Hamlet on stage. There's also a kind of strange beauty to the fights between Dolph and Simone, in that he's more than twice her size, and yet she has enough nouse to make them last out. The lasting value is in the film's aesthetics, and the haunting of Dane, as well as the occasional fairly cool special effect. It joins my list of flawed but very purty and lovable movies that were made during my childhood, alongside the likes of Albert Pyun's Cyborg, and Wes Craven's Shocker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not terrible... but awfully flat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wizard-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's really hard to believe that this movie was directed by the same person who directed FIRST BLOOD. I was expecting top-grade action, especially since Lundgren was the star, but the movie is a real bore. Oh, there are shootings, hand-to-hand combat, and chases, but all of this is presented to come across as just as unexciting as the rest of the movie. The script is (mostly) unsurprising, containing a major plot twist that you'll see coming from the first few minutes of the movie. (Though I admit the eventual plot turn concerning the female lead did give me a surprise.) Movie is also badly photographed, with muddy colors throughout. Lundgren tries, but is pretty overwhelmed, and the best performance turns out to be by John Ashton, playing Lundgren's buddy. Recommended only to die-hard (and very forgiving) Lundgren fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favourite Dolph movies...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    theduke_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Though this film would be classed as mediocre by most, I rate this movie fairly high. The scenery is fantastic, the soundtrack is interesting with its combination of suspense and smooth jazz, and with Dolph Lundgren side-kicked with John Ashton you get a smooth, even dose of action, adventure and comedy. Though the movie does seem slow at times, and you tend to forget the characters names or the reason why Dolph is actually there in the first place, the movie does provide decent suspense and action throughout. I didn't like the fact that Dolph's main wound (his arm) was self-inflicted and rather, well... pointless. However, the rooftop-gunfight scene (end) and the part where Dolph takes out a sniper with a handgun are simply a must see! (Believable? It is within Dolph's power, ha-ha!) The ending is simply awesome. Enough said. This movie is fantastic, you'll either rate it as a masterpiece or just a decent, action flick; but nothing lower.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Name is Michael Dane
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dolph Lundgren in a murkily-lit modestly-budgeted Co-European production, I have to say, is not a prospect to get the average moviegoer's pulse racing; Dolph is the poor man's Arnie  not, as it turns out, because of acting ability or screen presence, but simply because Arnie came first. Nevertheless, that's the way it is for poor old Dolph, so throughout the 90s all he seemed to get were the scraps that fell from Arnie's table. This one isn't as bad as you might expect. It isn't good either, but it's serviceable. It certainly improves on a weak first ten minutes that are hampered by some lousy lighting and even lousier acting from the likes of Gavan O'Herlihy who chews scenery like a man with indigestion who doesn't wish to appear impolite. Dolph is Michael Dane, a US Marshal on the hunt for Simone Rosset (Maruschka Detmers) a shapely assassin suspected of doing a Frank Sinatra and coming out of retirement to off a Cuban ambassador. Rosset, however, pleads her innocence, and Dane uncovers doings of the murky variety when he investigates a little further. Detmers is an actress new to me, but she adds a touch of class to an otherwise pedestrian action movie. Her character is obviously modelled on Nikita, but Simone is a part-time lesbian with a taste for good wine and a knack for jumping off high places. Detmers gives the impression she is slumming  that's how classy she is. Lundgren gives a decent enough performance too, but the story lets them both down in crucial areas. Dane is just a little too dim, even for a Marshal. He uses a tactic of self-mutilation instead of surveillance, stages a car chase which nearly ends up with him and his passenger being squashed between two tram cars simply because he wants to drive rather than be driven, and shoots indiscriminately into a moving train. On the plus side, the story does at least try to be a little different from the countless other mid-budget efforts out there, adding an unexpected twist that is well-timed and effective, and making use of some terrific Prague location work. This one is for those times when you really don't want to think about what you are watching; it's for when you want the film to do all the work and lay everything out for you without inserting any sly subtexts, etc. The action set-pieces are a little workmanlike  the budgets restricts them to a couple of car chases and a lot of gunfights  but one, carried out on the rooftops of Prague, is pretty cool. No-one sitting down to watch a film like this should be doing so with high expectations, so it follows then that no-one should be disappointed
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dolph saves the day and single-handedly restores US-Cuban relations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ****SPOILERS**** After the Cuban Ambassador to the UN is assassinated in New York City the CIA, with the help of Cuban government officials, trace the killer to be the daughter of an exiled anti-Castro Cuban living in the Czech Republic who's a professional assassin named Simone Rosset and using the name of Yanna Natova, Maruschka Detmers. With a major meeting by the Cuban and US government set in Prague to re-establish diplomatic relations between those two countries it's expected that Simone will disrupt the meeting by trying to kill both the Cuban and US officials expected to sign that agreement. Sending US Marshall Michael Dane, Dolph Lundgren, to arrest Simone and bring her back to the US to stand trial for the Cuban Ambassador's murder Michael is met by his long time friend and US government agent Alex Reed, John Aston, to help him in finding and arresting Simone. After tracking her down during a number of car and train chases as well as a dangerous jump, from a high bridge into the Danube River, that almost killed both Michael and Simone, Michael finally captures her. Later as Michael is about to take Simone to the Prague airport to fly with her back to the US, to be tried for murder, Simone tells him that she never was in New York the day of the Ambassador's killing and never left the Czech Republic in five years; Simone also tells Michael that she'll never live to stand trial. Simone's prediction comes sadly true when she's assassinated in a Prague hotel room after Michael saved her life from a number of assassin attempts that he foiled. One of Dolph's better efforts showing that he could act as well as haul and kick butt that he's so well known for. Realizing, too late to save Simone's life, that it's evident that there are those in higher ups in both the US and Cuban governments who don't want that signing to take place Michael goes to the signing ceremony in Prague to prevent it from being disrupted by the real assassins of the Cuban UN Ambassador. Great action scenes that leave you black and blue just from watching them with Dolph Lundgren at his best as the reluctant hero who breaks with his superiors, to stop the very assassination that he was assigned by them to prevent, who think that the real killer is already dead. Maruschka Detmers is the biggest surprise in the movie by being every bit as good as Dolph in the action scenes but also touches the heart-strings with her both sensitive as well as tragic performance as the doomed Simone. Tremendous final under the streets and on top of the buildings of picturesque Prague with Dolph Lundgren, bloody T-shirt and all, saving the day by putting the bad guys on ice as well as single-handedly restoring US-Cuban relations for the first time in some forty years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Average, if not entertaining........
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rmadesp (rmadesp@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like to carve Dolph Lundgren's career into 3 different slices. The 1st being his glory days from Rocky IV to Army Of One......the 3rd being his recent releases which have been all pretty disappointing, and the 2nd are made up of films like this one which fall in the period between the other two. Here we have a film which is not bad nor mediocre, yet doesnt quite reach the level of greatness that Dolph has achieved in previous releases. In other words, the action sequences are quite dull & unimaginative, yet there is a believable story line here which keeps the viewer watching. Another high point is the Prague setting.......some nice visuals here. Dont expect I Come In Peace or Punisher standards, but still worth checking out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Dolph's better flicks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bd119-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hidden Assassin (its proper name is The Shooter) is not just another mindless Dolph Lundgren actioner. It's a fairly well-plotted and exciting political thriller with some fine acting and great action sequences. But the real best thing about this movie is the setting. Filmed on location in Prague, the film looks beautiful and often stunning. Dolph plays a US Marshall (surprise, surprise) who is sent to Prague to find the assassin who killed the Cuban ambassador. Detmers is a beautiful bisexual assassin who Dolph gets caught up with, and before long the two of them are walking on dangerous ground while trying to stay alive the whole time. The suspense is always growing, as we never know who the killer is, wondering if it's Dolph's boss or even Detmers herself... I really like this movie. It's entertaining to watch and full of twists and surprises. Overall, I would probably recommend this one over some of Dolph's most well-known movies (Red Scorpion, Universal Soldier). Though without it's share of plot-holes, this remains a fun and very enjoyable romp.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An above average crime thriller.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Jolliffe (supertom-3)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a Dolph Lundgren fan this film goes down as one of my prefered viewings. I do like a good thriller, with some plot twists and tension. This film has those but to a mild degree, your not going to get really excited at this compared to something like Mission Impoosble with its high production and A-list cast but for a B-movie this is a good film that is surprising in places and reasonably well written. Dolph plays Michael Dane, who is working with the FBI to try to capture a known assasin played by the sexy Maruschka Detmers. Dane does not beleive she killed the Cuban Ambassador, but he still has to bring her into custody in the build up to a summit between the US and Cuba to try to get the two country's to shake and make up if you like. The plot at times raises questions that many action thrillers do, for instance why are they doing that? one particular example is the inclusion of Dolphs character, he is flown in from New York to Prague simply to arrest this Woman, why on Earth she wasn't brought in before is beyond me, especially considering that her whereabouts were known. A lot doesn't make sense but those minor quibbles aside, the film is nicely paced and is enjoyable. The acting is good, Dolph is assured and puts in one of his better performances, he has great chemistry with the excellent Maruschka who in turn also shows great chemistry with Assumpta Serna who plays Marta the possible lover of Simone. That is another mystery of the film, the sexual preference of Simone (Detmers) this does kind of undermine the development of a relationship between Dolph and Maruschkas characters. Also good is John Ashton as a bit of comic support as Danes Foster father and aid in the hunt for Simone. Furthermore, the action scenes. They are not overly stylish but are exciting, Dolph is in prime condition to dish out a battering and there is some good gun play included as well. Particular standout scenes are the capturing of Simone, and her subsequant escape. Also later in the film when Dolph rescues Simones character and just after when they both escape. The end is good to with the music helping to really build everything to a climactic crescendo. Overall this is a fairly decent thriller, with some nice lighting in the dark shots, and some nice and suitably dank locations. Dolph and Maruschka have a great chemistry, and the twists in the film are good. I would give this a 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A positive review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles (ang1150)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I got it because I'm a Maruschka Detmers fan, and I wasn't disappointed in her part, however limited it was in showcasing her talents. I didn't take this movie seriously, and I'll bet the actors had fun making this movie. The scenery and location were very impressive, the interaction between the main characters was good, with a touch of (unintended?) comedy throughout. Some of the scenes were unbelievable, but that just added to the feeling that you couldn't take this seriously as an action-adventure movie. For example, how could Michael pass by all the security points, evil bad guys pursuing him unscathed? If it isn't taken seriously, well that's the fun of it. I had never seen Dolph Lundgren act before, and was comparing him to Arnold... both are hard workers. The story line is this movie's weakest point, along with a few minor characters who obviously were put in the movie for appearance but no acting ability whatsoever. Overall, I liked it and after repeated viewings, I still enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
