<filme>
 <id>
  1034
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0117420
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Desafio Mortal
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Chris embarks on an odyssey of self-discovery that spans the globe. Kidnapped and enslaved by gun smugglers, sold by pirates and thrust into the murky underworld of gambling and kickboxing,... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Chris embarks on an odyssey of self-discovery that spans the globe. Kidnapped and enslaved by gun smugglers, sold by pirates and thrust into the murky underworld of gambling and kickboxing, Chris' journey takes him to forbidding Muay Thai Island where deadly martial arts are taught, the colonial splendor of British East Asia, the dank back alleys of Bangkok, desolate deserts once trod by the warriors of Genghis Khan and finally, the ancient Lost City. There he must face the ultimate test of his manhood in the fabled Ghang-gheng, the ancient winner-take-all competition in which the deadliest fighters from around the world employ the most spectacular feats of martial arts skills ever displayed in order to win the prized Golden Dragon. But fighting prowess alone will not be enough for Chris to triumph over such daunting foes. He must reach deep inside and access all of the determination, strength of character and sense of selfless honor within in order to triumph over this final obstacle...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   martial arts
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   island
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   kickboxing
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   muay thai
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   punched in the face
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Jean-Claude Van Damme
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Frank Dux
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Jean-Claude Van Damme
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jean-Claude Van Damme
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Roger Moore
  </ator>
  <ator>
   James Remar
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where does Bloodsport end and The Quest begin...?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For a Jean Claude Van Damme movie, then "The Quest" is a fairly standard one. And if you have seen the 1988 "Bloodsport" movie, then you have essentially also seen "The Quest". And I don't think that it is a mere coincidence, especially since the story was written by Frank Dux and Jean Claude Van Damme. The story is about Christopher Dubois (played by Jean-Claude Van Damme) who is living on the streets, when he is forced to run for his life and ending up as a stowaway on a ship. When he comes to his senses, he is put into slavery, working on the ship. By sheer luck he is rescued by Lord Edgar Dobbs (played by Roger Moore) and Harry Smythe (played by Jack McGee), two thieves and con artists. Setting out to steal a massive golden dragon in a reclusive and secret fighting tournament, Christoper Dubois finds himself fighting on behalf of the boxer Maxie Devine (played by James Remar). Storywise, then "The Quest" focused more on the fights and action. And as in "Bloodsport", then there is lots of it, and the fight sequences are nicely executed and brought to the screen. The movie itself is as predictable as they come - but then again, aren't most of Jean Claude Van Damme's movies? There are so many similarities between "Bloodsport" and "The Quest", that you just sit there wondering why "The Quest" was actually ever put on film. Wasn't it enough with this story being told in 1988 back when "Bloodsport" came out? But as with virtually all of Jean Claude Van Damme's movies, the main focus is the action and fighting, and whatever story or resemblance of a story there is becomes secondary. Obviously you have the fighting tournament held in an exotic location, there was the bested friend of whom Van Damme takes a headband, there was a woman reporter, there was a massive and seemingly invincible opponent, and of course there is Jean Claude Van Damme as the underdog who swoops in and wins it all against all odds. That being said, then "The Quest" is good entertainment where you don't have to use your brain at all. Funny, how I remembered this movie being much better back in the late 90's, when I remember my brother getting it on VHS. And after having obtained the DVD in 2013 and watched it again, it wasn't as cool as I remembered it to be. But still, fun and action-packed, a fairly standard Jean Claude Van Damme movie to be honest.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bloodsport's Second Best Remake !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before watching it, I have heard that it didn't do well in the box office, but I haven't known why. After watching it, that "why" wasn't hard to answer. It's so close to Bloodsport (1988), which was another movie starring Jean-Claude Van Damme, another movie inspired by martial artist Frank Dux's life and experiences, and another movie centers around a secret martial arts tournament. In fact, the similar points between the 2 movies are many; whereas a beautiful American she-journalist is on the lead's side, an earlier enmity happens between one of the contestants and the lead, a friend for the lead is cruelly beaten, let alone that the lead wins at last. True, they added an older time period, a character of a pirate who wants to steal gold, a situation where the lead proves his nobleness, but I felt I was watching the same movie again. At times, I thought that all of these differences was originally put just to mislead you that this is a remake of a movie done 8 years before ! The first half's writing is fine. It is thrilling, swiftly paced, and takes place in numerous lands. The lead gets from a trouble to another fascinatingly. And he's a human action hero, who has lost and poor child inside of him, and wants to save other lost and poor children, by doing the right thing. Though, in the second half, things weren't as fine. The American journalist didn't do anything (or say anything !). Aside from presenting such a totally extra character, this took a lot from the emotional side of the movie; making it badly concrete. The basis of the enmity between the Mongolian fighter and the lead was trivial (a conflict around a restaurant table !). When the Asian guy's son is killed, we don't get enthusiastic over the idea of how the lead must avenge him, because we weren't introduced to that character appropriately, and the script didn't make them, the lead and him, friends or even close from the start. And I didn't find any use out of the first and last scenes, where the lead was narrating his story as a very old man, sure they ended up as naive. Plus, it's hard to believe that 90 something guy can hit 2 punks that easily ! Van Damme's direction had its share of mistakes too. He overused the TV-ish close-ups, not doing much to hide the poor budget; in a movie that supposedly depends on impressive backgrounds, sets and costumes. Hence it has a medium TV pilot feel written all over it, especially with borrowed shots from richer movies ! I hated how Van Damme filmed the guy who announces the competitors before every match, by the same cadre and from the same angle, creating something between boring and funny. However, the bigger mistake can be felt in the fighting scenes. OH MY GOD, the action star did the action scenes wrongly. He suffered a hysteria which got to those scenes then to us, with too many various angles, stupidly fast cutting, and the most unnecessary slow-motion ever; which was being used every 10 seconds (as if Van Damme thought he was giving an illustrative lesson for martial arts students !). So the final result was annoying time, with nothing to concentrate on or watch. And by the way, Randy Edelman's music score seemed inane, and its fervent charge wasn't that fervent. The good points kind of compensate. The performance was so right. James Remar mastered that gallant fighter, having most of the lights for himself. Roger Moore was more than perfect as Lord futile swindler, being the best star to handle such a role, and the best relief this movie had. I loved discovering that he's a military captain-turned- pirate, which added much to his character beside his huge presence and genuine wit. I don't know why he considers The Quest his least favorite movie, since he has done worse (believe me, he has done a far far worse !). Van Damme looked tired, maybe due to his being behind and in front the camera in the same time. But he was more like Jackie Chan in some moments, managing to be a clueless child on a mission, and by that I mean a good thing. Casting all of those diverse martial arts champions was smart and interesting. The choreography of the climactic fight satisfied me the most. And the direction of Van Damme's fights outclassed all the rest's. The Quest is a B-grade B-movie. As a director, I didn't wait for more than that from Van Damme's side. And as an action hero, he provided his usual. Undoubtedly it has some entertainment value. But clearly it needed more to win the box office, or my A-grade rank, like less copied story and more good directing. This way it would have been anything better than Bloodsport's second best remake !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the epic Van Damme was aiming for. This is sadly, routine with uninspired fight scenes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Van Damme & Frank Dux collaborated together for this so called once in a lifetime project, hoping to make a classic Martial Arts film like of Bloodsport. Not only do they fail, but they created something that falls completely flat. I don't like criticizing Van Damme, as Van Damme is one of my all time favorite action heroes, but he has left me with no choice here. The movie tries to build up a deep relationship with Van Damme being trained in the art of Muay Thai. That ends as quickly as it begins, and it has no emotion what so ever. Van Damme clearly forgets this, and tries to recreate a key emotional scene in Bloodsport with Phang & Chris, but it has nowhere near the merit it had in Bloodsport, simply because The Quest failed to make me care like it should have. The fight choreography is a colossal disappointment. Van Damme who knows a thing or two about fighting, should know how to create an exciting fight, right? Wrong. The fights couldn't be more mundane if they tried. The fighters themselves have the repertoire to make an exciting fight, but they were often squashes with flashes of brilliance that never lasted as long as I would have liked. The end fight is typical Van Damage. Which means he gets his ass kicked for most of it and makes the "impossible" comeback; it works in most Van Damme movies, but not here. It's over the top and ho-hum The cinematography is actually excellent. It's a sight to behold at times, and I felt they got the time period they were doing down pat. Van Damme doesn't display any of that natural charm that he is well known for, and gives a one-note performance here for the most part. Maybe it was because of his directing responsibilities, but he was shockingly dull a lot of the time. His acrobatics are good as usual, but that's it. Roger Moore shamefully mugs his way through the film, and looks a bit embarrassed to be here. I have read he considers this to be his worst film. While I felt this movie was very much average, and not that great, it's far from his worst. He's made a couple of James Bond films that are worse than this movie. It's a rather annoying performance that quickly made me intolerant. James Remar is amusing as Maxie Devine, but his role is poorly written. Janet Gunn doesn't have much of a part except to be easy on the eyes. Abdel Qissi makes for a formidable presence as the imposing baddie. I was also disappointed by the lack of Chris's background on his childhood. We see snippets of it, but not nearly enough. A more thought out movie would have been really nice, but this is not the case. This is stuff I consider to be rather fruitful Final Thoughts: It's watchable, but nothing more. Considering the epic he was going for in his directional debut, I highly doubt he had such a watered down retread of The Bloodsport in mind. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's a reason why JCVD and James Bond haven't worked together again - 43%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Scrolling through the TV schedules as I often do, it's a rare film indeed that makes me stop and think about recording it. But how can anyone not be intrigued by "a period action adventure with Jean-Claude Van Damme and Roger Moore" - sure, it wouldn't be likely to change the world but what a line-up! My masochistic side pricking my conscious, I duly recording this and settled down today to watch what must be the strangest piece of casting I think I've ever seen. The Muscles From Brussels plays Chris Dubois, a ragamuffin street thief operating a child gang on the streets of New York in 1925. But after one daring escape from the police too many, Dubois inadvertently stows away and finds himself far from home and at the mercy of vicious pirates. Eventually, he is rescued by dashing British adventurer Lord Dobbs (Moore) and his partner-in-crime Smythe (Jack McGee) and they agree to help Dubois return to America. But Dobbs betrays Dubois and leaves him stranded in the Muay Thai Islands where his adventures really begin. He soon finds himself thrown into a global fighting tournament against the best in the world but as his paths cross with fellow Americans Maxie Devine (James Remar) and journalist Carrie Newton (Janet Gunn), Dubois realises he must win the tournament or risk all their futures... I can't comment on this film's similarity with the earlier "Bloodsport" because that film has somehow passed me by. What I will comment on is the alarming similarity to another Van Damme flick, the frankly forgettable "AWOL: Absent Without Leave". I can't help but feel that for his directorial debut, Van Damme should have stretched himself a bit more beyond the tired "fighting tournament" plot. He probably was too busy dominating proceedings - once the film's second half begins, the fighting takes over completely and dialogue fades into the odd shout and macho grunt. Yes, there are odd bits and pieces of plot to get through such as the moment when an opponent makes an enemy of Dubois and we then know who's gonna get beaten up last. It's as though JCVD felt that the cast weren't trying and decided to run the rest of the film himself. And to be honest, he may have a point - other than Moore, the rest of the cast disappear into the background like early morning fog. As does the plot - can anyone tell me why Devine hung around for so long or what exactly was the story Newton felt she had to chase? I couldn't find one to last the 95 minutes of this movie, let alone a Pulitzer prize. I could go on but you get the picture. "The Quest" is an unremarkable and deeply formulaic martial arts movie that reminds us why JCVD now spends his days selling Coors. It's poorly directed with lots of needless slow motion, incoherent and offers little surprises other than the bizarre combination of its two lead stars. It also feels very dated and that's nothing to do with its period setting - this film comes five years after the likes of "Terminator 2: Judgement Day" which is a quantum leap ahead in terms of story-telling, set pieces, special effects and performances. Van Damme has made decent enough movies in the past - I recommend the likes of "Universal Soldier" or "Sudden Death" - but this really isn't one of them. A Damme shame, then. And just what was the point of the whole thing being a flash-back?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speculation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cam Cloutier
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoy Van Damme's films occasionally, especially "Time Cop". Of his films, I consider this one of his worst, but that rating is purely from a technical vantage. A genuine martial artist is like anyone else when they go to the movies. They expect to see only fiction. The same is true even of martial arts action flics. Even if the choreographer and stars know their business, it's goosed up for entertainment purposes. Nevertheless, the discerning eye seeks a few gems, to see if the martial artists involved in the film's production at least cast a brief nod of respect to the art. In "The Quest", that nod is within the first 15 minutes of the movie: when an aging hero defends himself with his cane. The cane techniques are marvelous and entertaining and, suffice to say, a rarity in Hollywood kung fu cinema. Afterwards, it's typical dreck. Worse, as a long-time practitioner of Okinawan karate, I was mildly insulted by the portrayal of the "champion of karate" in the final segment of the film. One can only speculate why the producers (which included Van Damme) would show such a buffoon. We can go positive or negative in our speculation. Positively, we can say that Van Damme nodded in respect to the real masters of karate who, in the film's period time, were among the deadliest men who have EVER LIVED (Choki Motobu, Kanryo Higashionna, Itoman Bunkichi, Miyagi Chojun, to list but a few). Such men, though competitive, would have either not heard of the tournament or snubbed it. Negatively, we might say that Van Damme's Shotokan upbringing had rendered him oblivious to karate that was not watered down for schoolchildren (and a system that didn't even exist in the film's period; Funakoshi was only getting started teaching in Japan at that time). That would also be in line with many others' contemporary views of karate, common nowadays in the MMA, ever since the Gracies issued their silly challenge and no -real- karateka deigned to answer them. The sight of a karateka trying to side kick a sumo wrestler in the belly should make anyone twitch, unless they already nurse a profound (or ignorant) bias against real karate. I found the film otherwise tolerable if typical of Van Damme's work and of cinema of the 80s/90s generally.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoy Christmas in the lost city.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Duboir is Kidnapped and enslaved by gun smugglers, sold by pirates and thrust into the murky underworld of gambling and kick-boxing. His journey takes him to Muay Thai Island where martial arts are taught, and finally, the ancient Lost City. There he must face the ultimate test of his manhood in the ancient winner-take-all competition in which the deadliest fighters from around the world employ the most spectacular feats of martial arts skills ever displayed in order to win the prized Golden Dragon. But fighting prowess alone will not be enough for him to triumph over such daunting foes. He must reach deep inside and access all of the determination, strength of character and sense of selfless honour within in order to triumph over this final obstacle..... When Van Damme met Bond is a really strange movie to watch and probably not the best Van Damme film to start with. It's basically a retread of Bloodsport, set in a different time and location, with added Roger Moore. And while it's nowhere near as good as that movie, it's pretty darn good, and beautiful to look at. Van Damme is competent behind the camera, and even thought the main action of the film is your typical video game style beat em' up, the characters are rich and a little bit different. Van Damme is good, and Moore looks uncomfortable, but it's Van Dammes Baby, and he really tries hard with this. Plus, he gets to fight the bloke from Hot Chocolate at the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the James Bond 007 series celebrating its 50th anniversary because of Dr. No, and the third actor to play the famous spy role getting about a lot at the time, it made sense to me to see some of his films before and after Bond, so I found this one, the directorial debut from Jean-Claude Van Damme. Basically an old man is telling a story to a bartender after getting into a fight, and we flashback to this man younger, Christopher Dubois (Van Damme), a pickpocket living in 1925 New York who was orphaned as a child and runs a gang of orphan children pickpockets who also con and steal to get by. They get found by gangsters but Dubois manages to get away, but he does get the attention of the police as well, but he promises to return to the children before stowing away on a boat, but he is found by the crew and forced to be a slave by the pirates aboard. He is saved a few years later by mercenary Englishman Lord Edgar Dobbs (Sir Roger Moore) who agrees to help him get home to America, but in fact he sells him off as a slave on the island of Siam where he gets trained in Muay Thai fighting for a scheme that is coming up. Six months pass and Dobbs with his partner Harry Smythe (Jack McGee) are shocked to see Dubois fighting in the Muay Thai fighting ring, but they see he has become a skilled fighter, so they buy his freedom so that he will represent the USA in the Ghang-Gheng worldwide fighting tournament held in the Lost City of Tibet. Other countries competing in the global event include China, Japan, Germany, Brazil, France, Turkey, Greece, Spain, Africa, Korea, Soviet Union (Russia) and Scotland, all are eliminated round by round, and at the end of the tournament the winning country will receive the prestigious and valuable statue the Golden Dragon. As the contest goes on Dubois gets to know American reporter Carrie Newton (Janet Gunn) and heavyweight boxing champion Maxie Devine (James Remar) who give him advice and tips, and after winning against apposing countries the biggest challenge comes in the final round when he faces Khan the Mongolian Fighter (Abdel Qissi) who is savage. At the end Dubois ultimately wins the tournament, and refusing the Golden Dragon he wins the freedom of his friends Dobbs and Smythe who were sentenced to death after they tried to steal the golden statue, he returned to New York and got the children off the streets, Devine trained great fighters in his future, Dobbs and Smythe went deep into the Amazon to open a trading post, and Carrie wrote the story of everything called The Quest. Also starring Aki Aleong as Khao, Louis Mandylor as Riggi, Chang Ching Peng Chaplin as Master Tchi, Ryan Cutrona as Officer O'Keefe, Peter Wong as Chinese Fighter, Kitao Koji as Sumo Wrestler, Habby Heske as German Fighter, C&eacute;sar Carneiro as Brazilian Fighter, Takis Triggelis as French Fighter, Azdine Nouri as Turkish Fighter, Stefanos Miltsakakis as Greek Fighter, Peter Malota as Spanish Fighter, Winston Ellis as African Fighter, Ong Soo Han as Korean Fighter, Brick Bronsky as Russian Fighter, Ip Choi Nam as Korean Fighter and Mike Lambert as Scottish Fighter. Van Damme is relatively interesting as the pickpocket turned strong fighter, I will be honest and say that I was paying more attention to Moore though with his charming mannerisms and overall English good nature, I have only seen a few of Van Damme's films, many of them are meant to be involving fighting, so as one of them this is I suppose a good enough one, the story is simple enough and the fight sequences are certainly gripping, it is an alright martial arts action adventure. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Predictable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jennifer Fode
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say! Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say! Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jonathanruano
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Quest" does not know what kind of movie it wants to be - a version of "Oliver Twist," a pirate movie, a film about Muay Thai training, or another "Bloodsport" - and so it covers all these elements at once and does so badly, rather than focusing on one element and doing it well. When I saw "The Quest," I was impressed by the cinematography which seems reminiscent in a way of those great epic films of the 1950s and 1960s. Yet at the same time, I was bored with the film because the vast majority of its ideas seemed to be half-baked. If you want to do a film with multiple plots, like the "Crying Game" did, then what you need is an brilliant film director and excellent screen writers who know what they are doing. Yet Jean Claude Van Damme seems way over his head in his directorial debut. He knows how to film gorgeous looking scenes, but he cannot bring the various elements of film-making together into one coherent narrative. "The Quest" looks like an array of elements thrown together haphazardly in the hope that they would amount to something, but they do not. In the opening scenes, Jean Claude Van Damme plays a clown with stilts against a richly layered backdrop of a 1920s city coupled with a hideaway with thieving boys which is reminiscent of Fagin's lair from the film "Oliver Twist." Then we have scenes that appear, at least on the surface, to come straight out of the movie "Treasure Island"(1954) which includes its pirate ship. This is followed by another epic scene with Muay Thai fighters training on the beach while large waves are crashing against the shore. Then we see Jean Claude Van Damme and company travelling through Asia on elephants and then horses en route to a temple in the snowy mountains of Tibet. But do all these scenes amount to anything? Actually no, because none of these ideas are fully developed and imbued with meaning. The other problem is with the acting. A film that tries to cover as much ground as "The Quest" does needs capable (probably even gifted) actors to convey its material well. But Jean Claude Van Damme, with his poor acting abilities, seems like an uncomfortable fit as the film's protagonist. Van Damme is much more suited for laid-back, easy going, macho films, like Bloodsport and Kickboxer, where you can excuse the bad acting (and laugh at it) and have a good time. But in "The Quest," the sets upstage Van Damme, making him look small and insignificant. You really need someone with Eroll Flynn or Peter O'Toole's stature (when they were young) to carry a quasi-swashbuckling film, like "The Quest," forward in a convincing way. Roger Moore is a more experienced actor, but he merely reprises his dull cornball James Bond role as the pirate captain and (like his James Bond character) his performance just doesn't work. Although Robert Newton's Captain Silver character has become a clich&eacute;, I would have preferred that type of pirate captain rather than the one depicted by Roger Moore. Towards the end, Van Damme switches gears and creates another version of "Bloodsport" with its Hollywood formulae. He seems to be more comfortable with this material (especially since it requires him to do the martial arts that he knows so well), which explains why the martial arts sequences in the last 30-40 minutes of this film are reasonably entertaining. Those martial arts sequences are not, unfortunately, as good as the ones in Bloodsport which had better choreography and a great music soundtrack by composer Paul Hertzog. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only Van Damme or perhaps Roger Moore completists need apply.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Comeuppance Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set in the 1920's, Chris Dubois (Van Damme) is a street performer who wears clown makeup, a funny hat, and walks on stilts for a living. Adventure finds him when he ends up a stowaway on a boat heading to mysterious Muay Thai Island. There he learns martial arts, and, later in Tibet, meets the charming Lord Dobbs (Moore) and his assistant Smythe (McGee). It is around this time that Chris seeks to be involved in Ghan Geng, a secret underground fighting tournament. The winner gets a huge golden dragon, so Dobbs has a stake in Chris winning, as he wants the Dragon. Fighters are invited from all over the world , and America is represented by boxer Maxie Devine (Remar). Chris must take his place in the tournament and defeat the sinister Khan (Quissi) to win it all. Also, there's some mild romance with the prerequisite female reporter Carrie Newton (Gunn). Van Damme does a solid , professional job with his directional debut. Having co-written the film with Bloodsport (1988) dude Frank Dux, you pretty much know what to expect- but this movie is rated PG-13, so it was clearly trying to bring the Punchfighting genre some mainstream acceptance. With its slick Hollywood look and booming, sweeping score by Randy Edelman, the final product is perfect for 13-year olds, presumably its target demographic. Interestingly, the movie is a period piece, and plays like a prequel to Bloodsport. Instead of The Kumite, It's Ghan Geng. Van Damme tries on a number of personas from "Old Man Van Damme" to "Van Damme The Clown" and many things in between. The presence of Roger Moore adds class and respectability to the proceedings, and James Remar of Quiet Cool (1986) fame stands out as Devine. He's always worth seeing. Janet Gunn from Night Of The Running Man (1995) and The Sweeper (1996) is the eye candy but not much else. It's important to remember this was when video games like Mortal Kombat and Street Fighter were at the peak of their popularity. So when the Ghan Geng section of the movie begins (pretty much the last half)- the plot just STOPS. It's just one fighter from one country facing off against another fighter from another country. It gets repetitive and pretty numbing after awhile. Other Punchfighters don't do this. They vary the Punchfighting scenes with other plot-based stuff. Not so here. Plus the fact the movie is kind of on the long side doesn't help matters. What The Quest should have been is an 80 minute R-rated Punchfighter. Simply cutting the length but adding more violence would have helped immensely. But they weren't going for that audience, unfortunately. The Quest is more of a big "adventure" film where characters are seeking a "lost city" and many countries and time periods are represented. This might be a good way to start younger viewers on a career of watching Van Damme movies\action movies\Punchfighters but for adults. Only Van Damme or perhaps Roger Moore completists need apply. For more insanity, please visit: comeuppancereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where does Bloodsport end and The Quest begin...?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For a Jean Claude Van Damme movie, then "The Quest" is a fairly standard one. And if you have seen the 1988 "Bloodsport" movie, then you have essentially also seen "The Quest". And I don't think that it is a mere coincidence, especially since the story was written by Frank Dux and Jean Claude Van Damme. The story is about Christopher Dubois (played by Jean-Claude Van Damme) who is living on the streets, when he is forced to run for his life and ending up as a stowaway on a ship. When he comes to his senses, he is put into slavery, working on the ship. By sheer luck he is rescued by Lord Edgar Dobbs (played by Roger Moore) and Harry Smythe (played by Jack McGee), two thieves and con artists. Setting out to steal a massive golden dragon in a reclusive and secret fighting tournament, Christoper Dubois finds himself fighting on behalf of the boxer Maxie Devine (played by James Remar). Storywise, then "The Quest" focused more on the fights and action. And as in "Bloodsport", then there is lots of it, and the fight sequences are nicely executed and brought to the screen. The movie itself is as predictable as they come - but then again, aren't most of Jean Claude Van Damme's movies? There are so many similarities between "Bloodsport" and "The Quest", that you just sit there wondering why "The Quest" was actually ever put on film. Wasn't it enough with this story being told in 1988 back when "Bloodsport" came out? But as with virtually all of Jean Claude Van Damme's movies, the main focus is the action and fighting, and whatever story or resemblance of a story there is becomes secondary. Obviously you have the fighting tournament held in an exotic location, there was the bested friend of whom Van Damme takes a headband, there was a woman reporter, there was a massive and seemingly invincible opponent, and of course there is Jean Claude Van Damme as the underdog who swoops in and wins it all against all odds. That being said, then "The Quest" is good entertainment where you don't have to use your brain at all. Funny, how I remembered this movie being much better back in the late 90's, when I remember my brother getting it on VHS. And after having obtained the DVD in 2013 and watched it again, it wasn't as cool as I remembered it to be. But still, fun and action-packed, a fairly standard Jean Claude Van Damme movie to be honest.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bloodsport's Second Best Remake !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before watching it, I have heard that it didn't do well in the box office, but I haven't known why. After watching it, that "why" wasn't hard to answer. It's so close to Bloodsport (1988), which was another movie starring Jean-Claude Van Damme, another movie inspired by martial artist Frank Dux's life and experiences, and another movie centers around a secret martial arts tournament. In fact, the similar points between the 2 movies are many; whereas a beautiful American she-journalist is on the lead's side, an earlier enmity happens between one of the contestants and the lead, a friend for the lead is cruelly beaten, let alone that the lead wins at last. True, they added an older time period, a character of a pirate who wants to steal gold, a situation where the lead proves his nobleness, but I felt I was watching the same movie again. At times, I thought that all of these differences was originally put just to mislead you that this is a remake of a movie done 8 years before ! The first half's writing is fine. It is thrilling, swiftly paced, and takes place in numerous lands. The lead gets from a trouble to another fascinatingly. And he's a human action hero, who has lost and poor child inside of him, and wants to save other lost and poor children, by doing the right thing. Though, in the second half, things weren't as fine. The American journalist didn't do anything (or say anything !). Aside from presenting such a totally extra character, this took a lot from the emotional side of the movie; making it badly concrete. The basis of the enmity between the Mongolian fighter and the lead was trivial (a conflict around a restaurant table !). When the Asian guy's son is killed, we don't get enthusiastic over the idea of how the lead must avenge him, because we weren't introduced to that character appropriately, and the script didn't make them, the lead and him, friends or even close from the start. And I didn't find any use out of the first and last scenes, where the lead was narrating his story as a very old man, sure they ended up as naive. Plus, it's hard to believe that 90 something guy can hit 2 punks that easily ! Van Damme's direction had its share of mistakes too. He overused the TV-ish close-ups, not doing much to hide the poor budget; in a movie that supposedly depends on impressive backgrounds, sets and costumes. Hence it has a medium TV pilot feel written all over it, especially with borrowed shots from richer movies ! I hated how Van Damme filmed the guy who announces the competitors before every match, by the same cadre and from the same angle, creating something between boring and funny. However, the bigger mistake can be felt in the fighting scenes. OH MY GOD, the action star did the action scenes wrongly. He suffered a hysteria which got to those scenes then to us, with too many various angles, stupidly fast cutting, and the most unnecessary slow-motion ever; which was being used every 10 seconds (as if Van Damme thought he was giving an illustrative lesson for martial arts students !). So the final result was annoying time, with nothing to concentrate on or watch. And by the way, Randy Edelman's music score seemed inane, and its fervent charge wasn't that fervent. The good points kind of compensate. The performance was so right. James Remar mastered that gallant fighter, having most of the lights for himself. Roger Moore was more than perfect as Lord futile swindler, being the best star to handle such a role, and the best relief this movie had. I loved discovering that he's a military captain-turned- pirate, which added much to his character beside his huge presence and genuine wit. I don't know why he considers The Quest his least favorite movie, since he has done worse (believe me, he has done a far far worse !). Van Damme looked tired, maybe due to his being behind and in front the camera in the same time. But he was more like Jackie Chan in some moments, managing to be a clueless child on a mission, and by that I mean a good thing. Casting all of those diverse martial arts champions was smart and interesting. The choreography of the climactic fight satisfied me the most. And the direction of Van Damme's fights outclassed all the rest's. The Quest is a B-grade B-movie. As a director, I didn't wait for more than that from Van Damme's side. And as an action hero, he provided his usual. Undoubtedly it has some entertainment value. But clearly it needed more to win the box office, or my A-grade rank, like less copied story and more good directing. This way it would have been anything better than Bloodsport's second best remake !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the epic Van Damme was aiming for. This is sadly, routine with uninspired fight scenes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Van Damme & Frank Dux collaborated together for this so called once in a lifetime project, hoping to make a classic Martial Arts film like of Bloodsport. Not only do they fail, but they created something that falls completely flat. I don't like criticizing Van Damme, as Van Damme is one of my all time favorite action heroes, but he has left me with no choice here. The movie tries to build up a deep relationship with Van Damme being trained in the art of Muay Thai. That ends as quickly as it begins, and it has no emotion what so ever. Van Damme clearly forgets this, and tries to recreate a key emotional scene in Bloodsport with Phang & Chris, but it has nowhere near the merit it had in Bloodsport, simply because The Quest failed to make me care like it should have. The fight choreography is a colossal disappointment. Van Damme who knows a thing or two about fighting, should know how to create an exciting fight, right? Wrong. The fights couldn't be more mundane if they tried. The fighters themselves have the repertoire to make an exciting fight, but they were often squashes with flashes of brilliance that never lasted as long as I would have liked. The end fight is typical Van Damage. Which means he gets his ass kicked for most of it and makes the "impossible" comeback; it works in most Van Damme movies, but not here. It's over the top and ho-hum The cinematography is actually excellent. It's a sight to behold at times, and I felt they got the time period they were doing down pat. Van Damme doesn't display any of that natural charm that he is well known for, and gives a one-note performance here for the most part. Maybe it was because of his directing responsibilities, but he was shockingly dull a lot of the time. His acrobatics are good as usual, but that's it. Roger Moore shamefully mugs his way through the film, and looks a bit embarrassed to be here. I have read he considers this to be his worst film. While I felt this movie was very much average, and not that great, it's far from his worst. He's made a couple of James Bond films that are worse than this movie. It's a rather annoying performance that quickly made me intolerant. James Remar is amusing as Maxie Devine, but his role is poorly written. Janet Gunn doesn't have much of a part except to be easy on the eyes. Abdel Qissi makes for a formidable presence as the imposing baddie. I was also disappointed by the lack of Chris's background on his childhood. We see snippets of it, but not nearly enough. A more thought out movie would have been really nice, but this is not the case. This is stuff I consider to be rather fruitful Final Thoughts: It's watchable, but nothing more. Considering the epic he was going for in his directional debut, I highly doubt he had such a watered down retread of The Bloodsport in mind. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's a reason why JCVD and James Bond haven't worked together again - 43%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Scrolling through the TV schedules as I often do, it's a rare film indeed that makes me stop and think about recording it. But how can anyone not be intrigued by "a period action adventure with Jean-Claude Van Damme and Roger Moore" - sure, it wouldn't be likely to change the world but what a line-up! My masochistic side pricking my conscious, I duly recording this and settled down today to watch what must be the strangest piece of casting I think I've ever seen. The Muscles From Brussels plays Chris Dubois, a ragamuffin street thief operating a child gang on the streets of New York in 1925. But after one daring escape from the police too many, Dubois inadvertently stows away and finds himself far from home and at the mercy of vicious pirates. Eventually, he is rescued by dashing British adventurer Lord Dobbs (Moore) and his partner-in-crime Smythe (Jack McGee) and they agree to help Dubois return to America. But Dobbs betrays Dubois and leaves him stranded in the Muay Thai Islands where his adventures really begin. He soon finds himself thrown into a global fighting tournament against the best in the world but as his paths cross with fellow Americans Maxie Devine (James Remar) and journalist Carrie Newton (Janet Gunn), Dubois realises he must win the tournament or risk all their futures... I can't comment on this film's similarity with the earlier "Bloodsport" because that film has somehow passed me by. What I will comment on is the alarming similarity to another Van Damme flick, the frankly forgettable "AWOL: Absent Without Leave". I can't help but feel that for his directorial debut, Van Damme should have stretched himself a bit more beyond the tired "fighting tournament" plot. He probably was too busy dominating proceedings - once the film's second half begins, the fighting takes over completely and dialogue fades into the odd shout and macho grunt. Yes, there are odd bits and pieces of plot to get through such as the moment when an opponent makes an enemy of Dubois and we then know who's gonna get beaten up last. It's as though JCVD felt that the cast weren't trying and decided to run the rest of the film himself. And to be honest, he may have a point - other than Moore, the rest of the cast disappear into the background like early morning fog. As does the plot - can anyone tell me why Devine hung around for so long or what exactly was the story Newton felt she had to chase? I couldn't find one to last the 95 minutes of this movie, let alone a Pulitzer prize. I could go on but you get the picture. "The Quest" is an unremarkable and deeply formulaic martial arts movie that reminds us why JCVD now spends his days selling Coors. It's poorly directed with lots of needless slow motion, incoherent and offers little surprises other than the bizarre combination of its two lead stars. It also feels very dated and that's nothing to do with its period setting - this film comes five years after the likes of "Terminator 2: Judgement Day" which is a quantum leap ahead in terms of story-telling, set pieces, special effects and performances. Van Damme has made decent enough movies in the past - I recommend the likes of "Universal Soldier" or "Sudden Death" - but this really isn't one of them. A Damme shame, then. And just what was the point of the whole thing being a flash-back?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speculation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cam Cloutier
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoy Van Damme's films occasionally, especially "Time Cop". Of his films, I consider this one of his worst, but that rating is purely from a technical vantage. A genuine martial artist is like anyone else when they go to the movies. They expect to see only fiction. The same is true even of martial arts action flics. Even if the choreographer and stars know their business, it's goosed up for entertainment purposes. Nevertheless, the discerning eye seeks a few gems, to see if the martial artists involved in the film's production at least cast a brief nod of respect to the art. In "The Quest", that nod is within the first 15 minutes of the movie: when an aging hero defends himself with his cane. The cane techniques are marvelous and entertaining and, suffice to say, a rarity in Hollywood kung fu cinema. Afterwards, it's typical dreck. Worse, as a long-time practitioner of Okinawan karate, I was mildly insulted by the portrayal of the "champion of karate" in the final segment of the film. One can only speculate why the producers (which included Van Damme) would show such a buffoon. We can go positive or negative in our speculation. Positively, we can say that Van Damme nodded in respect to the real masters of karate who, in the film's period time, were among the deadliest men who have EVER LIVED (Choki Motobu, Kanryo Higashionna, Itoman Bunkichi, Miyagi Chojun, to list but a few). Such men, though competitive, would have either not heard of the tournament or snubbed it. Negatively, we might say that Van Damme's Shotokan upbringing had rendered him oblivious to karate that was not watered down for schoolchildren (and a system that didn't even exist in the film's period; Funakoshi was only getting started teaching in Japan at that time). That would also be in line with many others' contemporary views of karate, common nowadays in the MMA, ever since the Gracies issued their silly challenge and no -real- karateka deigned to answer them. The sight of a karateka trying to side kick a sumo wrestler in the belly should make anyone twitch, unless they already nurse a profound (or ignorant) bias against real karate. I found the film otherwise tolerable if typical of Van Damme's work and of cinema of the 80s/90s generally.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoy Christmas in the lost city.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Duboir is Kidnapped and enslaved by gun smugglers, sold by pirates and thrust into the murky underworld of gambling and kick-boxing. His journey takes him to Muay Thai Island where martial arts are taught, and finally, the ancient Lost City. There he must face the ultimate test of his manhood in the ancient winner-take-all competition in which the deadliest fighters from around the world employ the most spectacular feats of martial arts skills ever displayed in order to win the prized Golden Dragon. But fighting prowess alone will not be enough for him to triumph over such daunting foes. He must reach deep inside and access all of the determination, strength of character and sense of selfless honour within in order to triumph over this final obstacle..... When Van Damme met Bond is a really strange movie to watch and probably not the best Van Damme film to start with. It's basically a retread of Bloodsport, set in a different time and location, with added Roger Moore. And while it's nowhere near as good as that movie, it's pretty darn good, and beautiful to look at. Van Damme is competent behind the camera, and even thought the main action of the film is your typical video game style beat em' up, the characters are rich and a little bit different. Van Damme is good, and Moore looks uncomfortable, but it's Van Dammes Baby, and he really tries hard with this. Plus, he gets to fight the bloke from Hot Chocolate at the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the James Bond 007 series celebrating its 50th anniversary because of Dr. No, and the third actor to play the famous spy role getting about a lot at the time, it made sense to me to see some of his films before and after Bond, so I found this one, the directorial debut from Jean-Claude Van Damme. Basically an old man is telling a story to a bartender after getting into a fight, and we flashback to this man younger, Christopher Dubois (Van Damme), a pickpocket living in 1925 New York who was orphaned as a child and runs a gang of orphan children pickpockets who also con and steal to get by. They get found by gangsters but Dubois manages to get away, but he does get the attention of the police as well, but he promises to return to the children before stowing away on a boat, but he is found by the crew and forced to be a slave by the pirates aboard. He is saved a few years later by mercenary Englishman Lord Edgar Dobbs (Sir Roger Moore) who agrees to help him get home to America, but in fact he sells him off as a slave on the island of Siam where he gets trained in Muay Thai fighting for a scheme that is coming up. Six months pass and Dobbs with his partner Harry Smythe (Jack McGee) are shocked to see Dubois fighting in the Muay Thai fighting ring, but they see he has become a skilled fighter, so they buy his freedom so that he will represent the USA in the Ghang-Gheng worldwide fighting tournament held in the Lost City of Tibet. Other countries competing in the global event include China, Japan, Germany, Brazil, France, Turkey, Greece, Spain, Africa, Korea, Soviet Union (Russia) and Scotland, all are eliminated round by round, and at the end of the tournament the winning country will receive the prestigious and valuable statue the Golden Dragon. As the contest goes on Dubois gets to know American reporter Carrie Newton (Janet Gunn) and heavyweight boxing champion Maxie Devine (James Remar) who give him advice and tips, and after winning against apposing countries the biggest challenge comes in the final round when he faces Khan the Mongolian Fighter (Abdel Qissi) who is savage. At the end Dubois ultimately wins the tournament, and refusing the Golden Dragon he wins the freedom of his friends Dobbs and Smythe who were sentenced to death after they tried to steal the golden statue, he returned to New York and got the children off the streets, Devine trained great fighters in his future, Dobbs and Smythe went deep into the Amazon to open a trading post, and Carrie wrote the story of everything called The Quest. Also starring Aki Aleong as Khao, Louis Mandylor as Riggi, Chang Ching Peng Chaplin as Master Tchi, Ryan Cutrona as Officer O'Keefe, Peter Wong as Chinese Fighter, Kitao Koji as Sumo Wrestler, Habby Heske as German Fighter, C&eacute;sar Carneiro as Brazilian Fighter, Takis Triggelis as French Fighter, Azdine Nouri as Turkish Fighter, Stefanos Miltsakakis as Greek Fighter, Peter Malota as Spanish Fighter, Winston Ellis as African Fighter, Ong Soo Han as Korean Fighter, Brick Bronsky as Russian Fighter, Ip Choi Nam as Korean Fighter and Mike Lambert as Scottish Fighter. Van Damme is relatively interesting as the pickpocket turned strong fighter, I will be honest and say that I was paying more attention to Moore though with his charming mannerisms and overall English good nature, I have only seen a few of Van Damme's films, many of them are meant to be involving fighting, so as one of them this is I suppose a good enough one, the story is simple enough and the fight sequences are certainly gripping, it is an alright martial arts action adventure. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Predictable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jennifer Fode
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say! Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say! Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jonathanruano
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Quest" does not know what kind of movie it wants to be - a version of "Oliver Twist," a pirate movie, a film about Muay Thai training, or another "Bloodsport" - and so it covers all these elements at once and does so badly, rather than focusing on one element and doing it well. When I saw "The Quest," I was impressed by the cinematography which seems reminiscent in a way of those great epic films of the 1950s and 1960s. Yet at the same time, I was bored with the film because the vast majority of its ideas seemed to be half-baked. If you want to do a film with multiple plots, like the "Crying Game" did, then what you need is an brilliant film director and excellent screen writers who know what they are doing. Yet Jean Claude Van Damme seems way over his head in his directorial debut. He knows how to film gorgeous looking scenes, but he cannot bring the various elements of film-making together into one coherent narrative. "The Quest" looks like an array of elements thrown together haphazardly in the hope that they would amount to something, but they do not. In the opening scenes, Jean Claude Van Damme plays a clown with stilts against a richly layered backdrop of a 1920s city coupled with a hideaway with thieving boys which is reminiscent of Fagin's lair from the film "Oliver Twist." Then we have scenes that appear, at least on the surface, to come straight out of the movie "Treasure Island"(1954) which includes its pirate ship. This is followed by another epic scene with Muay Thai fighters training on the beach while large waves are crashing against the shore. Then we see Jean Claude Van Damme and company travelling through Asia on elephants and then horses en route to a temple in the snowy mountains of Tibet. But do all these scenes amount to anything? Actually no, because none of these ideas are fully developed and imbued with meaning. The other problem is with the acting. A film that tries to cover as much ground as "The Quest" does needs capable (probably even gifted) actors to convey its material well. But Jean Claude Van Damme, with his poor acting abilities, seems like an uncomfortable fit as the film's protagonist. Van Damme is much more suited for laid-back, easy going, macho films, like Bloodsport and Kickboxer, where you can excuse the bad acting (and laugh at it) and have a good time. But in "The Quest," the sets upstage Van Damme, making him look small and insignificant. You really need someone with Eroll Flynn or Peter O'Toole's stature (when they were young) to carry a quasi-swashbuckling film, like "The Quest," forward in a convincing way. Roger Moore is a more experienced actor, but he merely reprises his dull cornball James Bond role as the pirate captain and (like his James Bond character) his performance just doesn't work. Although Robert Newton's Captain Silver character has become a clich&eacute;, I would have preferred that type of pirate captain rather than the one depicted by Roger Moore. Towards the end, Van Damme switches gears and creates another version of "Bloodsport" with its Hollywood formulae. He seems to be more comfortable with this material (especially since it requires him to do the martial arts that he knows so well), which explains why the martial arts sequences in the last 30-40 minutes of this film are reasonably entertaining. Those martial arts sequences are not, unfortunately, as good as the ones in Bloodsport which had better choreography and a great music soundtrack by composer Paul Hertzog. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only Van Damme or perhaps Roger Moore completists need apply.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Comeuppance Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set in the 1920's, Chris Dubois (Van Damme) is a street performer who wears clown makeup, a funny hat, and walks on stilts for a living. Adventure finds him when he ends up a stowaway on a boat heading to mysterious Muay Thai Island. There he learns martial arts, and, later in Tibet, meets the charming Lord Dobbs (Moore) and his assistant Smythe (McGee). It is around this time that Chris seeks to be involved in Ghan Geng, a secret underground fighting tournament. The winner gets a huge golden dragon, so Dobbs has a stake in Chris winning, as he wants the Dragon. Fighters are invited from all over the world , and America is represented by boxer Maxie Devine (Remar). Chris must take his place in the tournament and defeat the sinister Khan (Quissi) to win it all. Also, there's some mild romance with the prerequisite female reporter Carrie Newton (Gunn). Van Damme does a solid , professional job with his directional debut. Having co-written the film with Bloodsport (1988) dude Frank Dux, you pretty much know what to expect- but this movie is rated PG-13, so it was clearly trying to bring the Punchfighting genre some mainstream acceptance. With its slick Hollywood look and booming, sweeping score by Randy Edelman, the final product is perfect for 13-year olds, presumably its target demographic. Interestingly, the movie is a period piece, and plays like a prequel to Bloodsport. Instead of The Kumite, It's Ghan Geng. Van Damme tries on a number of personas from "Old Man Van Damme" to "Van Damme The Clown" and many things in between. The presence of Roger Moore adds class and respectability to the proceedings, and James Remar of Quiet Cool (1986) fame stands out as Devine. He's always worth seeing. Janet Gunn from Night Of The Running Man (1995) and The Sweeper (1996) is the eye candy but not much else. It's important to remember this was when video games like Mortal Kombat and Street Fighter were at the peak of their popularity. So when the Ghan Geng section of the movie begins (pretty much the last half)- the plot just STOPS. It's just one fighter from one country facing off against another fighter from another country. It gets repetitive and pretty numbing after awhile. Other Punchfighters don't do this. They vary the Punchfighting scenes with other plot-based stuff. Not so here. Plus the fact the movie is kind of on the long side doesn't help matters. What The Quest should have been is an 80 minute R-rated Punchfighter. Simply cutting the length but adding more violence would have helped immensely. But they weren't going for that audience, unfortunately. The Quest is more of a big "adventure" film where characters are seeking a "lost city" and many countries and time periods are represented. This might be a good way to start younger viewers on a career of watching Van Damme movies\action movies\Punchfighters but for adults. Only Van Damme or perhaps Roger Moore completists need apply. For more insanity, please visit: comeuppancereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where does Bloodsport end and The Quest begin...?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For a Jean Claude Van Damme movie, then "The Quest" is a fairly standard one. And if you have seen the 1988 "Bloodsport" movie, then you have essentially also seen "The Quest". And I don't think that it is a mere coincidence, especially since the story was written by Frank Dux and Jean Claude Van Damme. The story is about Christopher Dubois (played by Jean-Claude Van Damme) who is living on the streets, when he is forced to run for his life and ending up as a stowaway on a ship. When he comes to his senses, he is put into slavery, working on the ship. By sheer luck he is rescued by Lord Edgar Dobbs (played by Roger Moore) and Harry Smythe (played by Jack McGee), two thieves and con artists. Setting out to steal a massive golden dragon in a reclusive and secret fighting tournament, Christoper Dubois finds himself fighting on behalf of the boxer Maxie Devine (played by James Remar). Storywise, then "The Quest" focused more on the fights and action. And as in "Bloodsport", then there is lots of it, and the fight sequences are nicely executed and brought to the screen. The movie itself is as predictable as they come - but then again, aren't most of Jean Claude Van Damme's movies? There are so many similarities between "Bloodsport" and "The Quest", that you just sit there wondering why "The Quest" was actually ever put on film. Wasn't it enough with this story being told in 1988 back when "Bloodsport" came out? But as with virtually all of Jean Claude Van Damme's movies, the main focus is the action and fighting, and whatever story or resemblance of a story there is becomes secondary. Obviously you have the fighting tournament held in an exotic location, there was the bested friend of whom Van Damme takes a headband, there was a woman reporter, there was a massive and seemingly invincible opponent, and of course there is Jean Claude Van Damme as the underdog who swoops in and wins it all against all odds. That being said, then "The Quest" is good entertainment where you don't have to use your brain at all. Funny, how I remembered this movie being much better back in the late 90's, when I remember my brother getting it on VHS. And after having obtained the DVD in 2013 and watched it again, it wasn't as cool as I remembered it to be. But still, fun and action-packed, a fairly standard Jean Claude Van Damme movie to be honest.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bloodsport's Second Best Remake !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before watching it, I have heard that it didn't do well in the box office, but I haven't known why. After watching it, that "why" wasn't hard to answer. It's so close to Bloodsport (1988), which was another movie starring Jean-Claude Van Damme, another movie inspired by martial artist Frank Dux's life and experiences, and another movie centers around a secret martial arts tournament. In fact, the similar points between the 2 movies are many; whereas a beautiful American she-journalist is on the lead's side, an earlier enmity happens between one of the contestants and the lead, a friend for the lead is cruelly beaten, let alone that the lead wins at last. True, they added an older time period, a character of a pirate who wants to steal gold, a situation where the lead proves his nobleness, but I felt I was watching the same movie again. At times, I thought that all of these differences was originally put just to mislead you that this is a remake of a movie done 8 years before ! The first half's writing is fine. It is thrilling, swiftly paced, and takes place in numerous lands. The lead gets from a trouble to another fascinatingly. And he's a human action hero, who has lost and poor child inside of him, and wants to save other lost and poor children, by doing the right thing. Though, in the second half, things weren't as fine. The American journalist didn't do anything (or say anything !). Aside from presenting such a totally extra character, this took a lot from the emotional side of the movie; making it badly concrete. The basis of the enmity between the Mongolian fighter and the lead was trivial (a conflict around a restaurant table !). When the Asian guy's son is killed, we don't get enthusiastic over the idea of how the lead must avenge him, because we weren't introduced to that character appropriately, and the script didn't make them, the lead and him, friends or even close from the start. And I didn't find any use out of the first and last scenes, where the lead was narrating his story as a very old man, sure they ended up as naive. Plus, it's hard to believe that 90 something guy can hit 2 punks that easily ! Van Damme's direction had its share of mistakes too. He overused the TV-ish close-ups, not doing much to hide the poor budget; in a movie that supposedly depends on impressive backgrounds, sets and costumes. Hence it has a medium TV pilot feel written all over it, especially with borrowed shots from richer movies ! I hated how Van Damme filmed the guy who announces the competitors before every match, by the same cadre and from the same angle, creating something between boring and funny. However, the bigger mistake can be felt in the fighting scenes. OH MY GOD, the action star did the action scenes wrongly. He suffered a hysteria which got to those scenes then to us, with too many various angles, stupidly fast cutting, and the most unnecessary slow-motion ever; which was being used every 10 seconds (as if Van Damme thought he was giving an illustrative lesson for martial arts students !). So the final result was annoying time, with nothing to concentrate on or watch. And by the way, Randy Edelman's music score seemed inane, and its fervent charge wasn't that fervent. The good points kind of compensate. The performance was so right. James Remar mastered that gallant fighter, having most of the lights for himself. Roger Moore was more than perfect as Lord futile swindler, being the best star to handle such a role, and the best relief this movie had. I loved discovering that he's a military captain-turned- pirate, which added much to his character beside his huge presence and genuine wit. I don't know why he considers The Quest his least favorite movie, since he has done worse (believe me, he has done a far far worse !). Van Damme looked tired, maybe due to his being behind and in front the camera in the same time. But he was more like Jackie Chan in some moments, managing to be a clueless child on a mission, and by that I mean a good thing. Casting all of those diverse martial arts champions was smart and interesting. The choreography of the climactic fight satisfied me the most. And the direction of Van Damme's fights outclassed all the rest's. The Quest is a B-grade B-movie. As a director, I didn't wait for more than that from Van Damme's side. And as an action hero, he provided his usual. Undoubtedly it has some entertainment value. But clearly it needed more to win the box office, or my A-grade rank, like less copied story and more good directing. This way it would have been anything better than Bloodsport's second best remake !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the epic Van Damme was aiming for. This is sadly, routine with uninspired fight scenes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Van Damme & Frank Dux collaborated together for this so called once in a lifetime project, hoping to make a classic Martial Arts film like of Bloodsport. Not only do they fail, but they created something that falls completely flat. I don't like criticizing Van Damme, as Van Damme is one of my all time favorite action heroes, but he has left me with no choice here. The movie tries to build up a deep relationship with Van Damme being trained in the art of Muay Thai. That ends as quickly as it begins, and it has no emotion what so ever. Van Damme clearly forgets this, and tries to recreate a key emotional scene in Bloodsport with Phang & Chris, but it has nowhere near the merit it had in Bloodsport, simply because The Quest failed to make me care like it should have. The fight choreography is a colossal disappointment. Van Damme who knows a thing or two about fighting, should know how to create an exciting fight, right? Wrong. The fights couldn't be more mundane if they tried. The fighters themselves have the repertoire to make an exciting fight, but they were often squashes with flashes of brilliance that never lasted as long as I would have liked. The end fight is typical Van Damage. Which means he gets his ass kicked for most of it and makes the "impossible" comeback; it works in most Van Damme movies, but not here. It's over the top and ho-hum The cinematography is actually excellent. It's a sight to behold at times, and I felt they got the time period they were doing down pat. Van Damme doesn't display any of that natural charm that he is well known for, and gives a one-note performance here for the most part. Maybe it was because of his directing responsibilities, but he was shockingly dull a lot of the time. His acrobatics are good as usual, but that's it. Roger Moore shamefully mugs his way through the film, and looks a bit embarrassed to be here. I have read he considers this to be his worst film. While I felt this movie was very much average, and not that great, it's far from his worst. He's made a couple of James Bond films that are worse than this movie. It's a rather annoying performance that quickly made me intolerant. James Remar is amusing as Maxie Devine, but his role is poorly written. Janet Gunn doesn't have much of a part except to be easy on the eyes. Abdel Qissi makes for a formidable presence as the imposing baddie. I was also disappointed by the lack of Chris's background on his childhood. We see snippets of it, but not nearly enough. A more thought out movie would have been really nice, but this is not the case. This is stuff I consider to be rather fruitful Final Thoughts: It's watchable, but nothing more. Considering the epic he was going for in his directional debut, I highly doubt he had such a watered down retread of The Bloodsport in mind. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's a reason why JCVD and James Bond haven't worked together again - 43%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Scrolling through the TV schedules as I often do, it's a rare film indeed that makes me stop and think about recording it. But how can anyone not be intrigued by "a period action adventure with Jean-Claude Van Damme and Roger Moore" - sure, it wouldn't be likely to change the world but what a line-up! My masochistic side pricking my conscious, I duly recording this and settled down today to watch what must be the strangest piece of casting I think I've ever seen. The Muscles From Brussels plays Chris Dubois, a ragamuffin street thief operating a child gang on the streets of New York in 1925. But after one daring escape from the police too many, Dubois inadvertently stows away and finds himself far from home and at the mercy of vicious pirates. Eventually, he is rescued by dashing British adventurer Lord Dobbs (Moore) and his partner-in-crime Smythe (Jack McGee) and they agree to help Dubois return to America. But Dobbs betrays Dubois and leaves him stranded in the Muay Thai Islands where his adventures really begin. He soon finds himself thrown into a global fighting tournament against the best in the world but as his paths cross with fellow Americans Maxie Devine (James Remar) and journalist Carrie Newton (Janet Gunn), Dubois realises he must win the tournament or risk all their futures... I can't comment on this film's similarity with the earlier "Bloodsport" because that film has somehow passed me by. What I will comment on is the alarming similarity to another Van Damme flick, the frankly forgettable "AWOL: Absent Without Leave". I can't help but feel that for his directorial debut, Van Damme should have stretched himself a bit more beyond the tired "fighting tournament" plot. He probably was too busy dominating proceedings - once the film's second half begins, the fighting takes over completely and dialogue fades into the odd shout and macho grunt. Yes, there are odd bits and pieces of plot to get through such as the moment when an opponent makes an enemy of Dubois and we then know who's gonna get beaten up last. It's as though JCVD felt that the cast weren't trying and decided to run the rest of the film himself. And to be honest, he may have a point - other than Moore, the rest of the cast disappear into the background like early morning fog. As does the plot - can anyone tell me why Devine hung around for so long or what exactly was the story Newton felt she had to chase? I couldn't find one to last the 95 minutes of this movie, let alone a Pulitzer prize. I could go on but you get the picture. "The Quest" is an unremarkable and deeply formulaic martial arts movie that reminds us why JCVD now spends his days selling Coors. It's poorly directed with lots of needless slow motion, incoherent and offers little surprises other than the bizarre combination of its two lead stars. It also feels very dated and that's nothing to do with its period setting - this film comes five years after the likes of "Terminator 2: Judgement Day" which is a quantum leap ahead in terms of story-telling, set pieces, special effects and performances. Van Damme has made decent enough movies in the past - I recommend the likes of "Universal Soldier" or "Sudden Death" - but this really isn't one of them. A Damme shame, then. And just what was the point of the whole thing being a flash-back?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speculation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cam Cloutier
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoy Van Damme's films occasionally, especially "Time Cop". Of his films, I consider this one of his worst, but that rating is purely from a technical vantage. A genuine martial artist is like anyone else when they go to the movies. They expect to see only fiction. The same is true even of martial arts action flics. Even if the choreographer and stars know their business, it's goosed up for entertainment purposes. Nevertheless, the discerning eye seeks a few gems, to see if the martial artists involved in the film's production at least cast a brief nod of respect to the art. In "The Quest", that nod is within the first 15 minutes of the movie: when an aging hero defends himself with his cane. The cane techniques are marvelous and entertaining and, suffice to say, a rarity in Hollywood kung fu cinema. Afterwards, it's typical dreck. Worse, as a long-time practitioner of Okinawan karate, I was mildly insulted by the portrayal of the "champion of karate" in the final segment of the film. One can only speculate why the producers (which included Van Damme) would show such a buffoon. We can go positive or negative in our speculation. Positively, we can say that Van Damme nodded in respect to the real masters of karate who, in the film's period time, were among the deadliest men who have EVER LIVED (Choki Motobu, Kanryo Higashionna, Itoman Bunkichi, Miyagi Chojun, to list but a few). Such men, though competitive, would have either not heard of the tournament or snubbed it. Negatively, we might say that Van Damme's Shotokan upbringing had rendered him oblivious to karate that was not watered down for schoolchildren (and a system that didn't even exist in the film's period; Funakoshi was only getting started teaching in Japan at that time). That would also be in line with many others' contemporary views of karate, common nowadays in the MMA, ever since the Gracies issued their silly challenge and no -real- karateka deigned to answer them. The sight of a karateka trying to side kick a sumo wrestler in the belly should make anyone twitch, unless they already nurse a profound (or ignorant) bias against real karate. I found the film otherwise tolerable if typical of Van Damme's work and of cinema of the 80s/90s generally.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoy Christmas in the lost city.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Duboir is Kidnapped and enslaved by gun smugglers, sold by pirates and thrust into the murky underworld of gambling and kick-boxing. His journey takes him to Muay Thai Island where martial arts are taught, and finally, the ancient Lost City. There he must face the ultimate test of his manhood in the ancient winner-take-all competition in which the deadliest fighters from around the world employ the most spectacular feats of martial arts skills ever displayed in order to win the prized Golden Dragon. But fighting prowess alone will not be enough for him to triumph over such daunting foes. He must reach deep inside and access all of the determination, strength of character and sense of selfless honour within in order to triumph over this final obstacle..... When Van Damme met Bond is a really strange movie to watch and probably not the best Van Damme film to start with. It's basically a retread of Bloodsport, set in a different time and location, with added Roger Moore. And while it's nowhere near as good as that movie, it's pretty darn good, and beautiful to look at. Van Damme is competent behind the camera, and even thought the main action of the film is your typical video game style beat em' up, the characters are rich and a little bit different. Van Damme is good, and Moore looks uncomfortable, but it's Van Dammes Baby, and he really tries hard with this. Plus, he gets to fight the bloke from Hot Chocolate at the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the James Bond 007 series celebrating its 50th anniversary because of Dr. No, and the third actor to play the famous spy role getting about a lot at the time, it made sense to me to see some of his films before and after Bond, so I found this one, the directorial debut from Jean-Claude Van Damme. Basically an old man is telling a story to a bartender after getting into a fight, and we flashback to this man younger, Christopher Dubois (Van Damme), a pickpocket living in 1925 New York who was orphaned as a child and runs a gang of orphan children pickpockets who also con and steal to get by. They get found by gangsters but Dubois manages to get away, but he does get the attention of the police as well, but he promises to return to the children before stowing away on a boat, but he is found by the crew and forced to be a slave by the pirates aboard. He is saved a few years later by mercenary Englishman Lord Edgar Dobbs (Sir Roger Moore) who agrees to help him get home to America, but in fact he sells him off as a slave on the island of Siam where he gets trained in Muay Thai fighting for a scheme that is coming up. Six months pass and Dobbs with his partner Harry Smythe (Jack McGee) are shocked to see Dubois fighting in the Muay Thai fighting ring, but they see he has become a skilled fighter, so they buy his freedom so that he will represent the USA in the Ghang-Gheng worldwide fighting tournament held in the Lost City of Tibet. Other countries competing in the global event include China, Japan, Germany, Brazil, France, Turkey, Greece, Spain, Africa, Korea, Soviet Union (Russia) and Scotland, all are eliminated round by round, and at the end of the tournament the winning country will receive the prestigious and valuable statue the Golden Dragon. As the contest goes on Dubois gets to know American reporter Carrie Newton (Janet Gunn) and heavyweight boxing champion Maxie Devine (James Remar) who give him advice and tips, and after winning against apposing countries the biggest challenge comes in the final round when he faces Khan the Mongolian Fighter (Abdel Qissi) who is savage. At the end Dubois ultimately wins the tournament, and refusing the Golden Dragon he wins the freedom of his friends Dobbs and Smythe who were sentenced to death after they tried to steal the golden statue, he returned to New York and got the children off the streets, Devine trained great fighters in his future, Dobbs and Smythe went deep into the Amazon to open a trading post, and Carrie wrote the story of everything called The Quest. Also starring Aki Aleong as Khao, Louis Mandylor as Riggi, Chang Ching Peng Chaplin as Master Tchi, Ryan Cutrona as Officer O'Keefe, Peter Wong as Chinese Fighter, Kitao Koji as Sumo Wrestler, Habby Heske as German Fighter, C&eacute;sar Carneiro as Brazilian Fighter, Takis Triggelis as French Fighter, Azdine Nouri as Turkish Fighter, Stefanos Miltsakakis as Greek Fighter, Peter Malota as Spanish Fighter, Winston Ellis as African Fighter, Ong Soo Han as Korean Fighter, Brick Bronsky as Russian Fighter, Ip Choi Nam as Korean Fighter and Mike Lambert as Scottish Fighter. Van Damme is relatively interesting as the pickpocket turned strong fighter, I will be honest and say that I was paying more attention to Moore though with his charming mannerisms and overall English good nature, I have only seen a few of Van Damme's films, many of them are meant to be involving fighting, so as one of them this is I suppose a good enough one, the story is simple enough and the fight sequences are certainly gripping, it is an alright martial arts action adventure. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Predictable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jennifer Fode
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say! Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say! Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jonathanruano
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Quest" does not know what kind of movie it wants to be - a version of "Oliver Twist," a pirate movie, a film about Muay Thai training, or another "Bloodsport" - and so it covers all these elements at once and does so badly, rather than focusing on one element and doing it well. When I saw "The Quest," I was impressed by the cinematography which seems reminiscent in a way of those great epic films of the 1950s and 1960s. Yet at the same time, I was bored with the film because the vast majority of its ideas seemed to be half-baked. If you want to do a film with multiple plots, like the "Crying Game" did, then what you need is an brilliant film director and excellent screen writers who know what they are doing. Yet Jean Claude Van Damme seems way over his head in his directorial debut. He knows how to film gorgeous looking scenes, but he cannot bring the various elements of film-making together into one coherent narrative. "The Quest" looks like an array of elements thrown together haphazardly in the hope that they would amount to something, but they do not. In the opening scenes, Jean Claude Van Damme plays a clown with stilts against a richly layered backdrop of a 1920s city coupled with a hideaway with thieving boys which is reminiscent of Fagin's lair from the film "Oliver Twist." Then we have scenes that appear, at least on the surface, to come straight out of the movie "Treasure Island"(1954) which includes its pirate ship. This is followed by another epic scene with Muay Thai fighters training on the beach while large waves are crashing against the shore. Then we see Jean Claude Van Damme and company travelling through Asia on elephants and then horses en route to a temple in the snowy mountains of Tibet. But do all these scenes amount to anything? Actually no, because none of these ideas are fully developed and imbued with meaning. The other problem is with the acting. A film that tries to cover as much ground as "The Quest" does needs capable (probably even gifted) actors to convey its material well. But Jean Claude Van Damme, with his poor acting abilities, seems like an uncomfortable fit as the film's protagonist. Van Damme is much more suited for laid-back, easy going, macho films, like Bloodsport and Kickboxer, where you can excuse the bad acting (and laugh at it) and have a good time. But in "The Quest," the sets upstage Van Damme, making him look small and insignificant. You really need someone with Eroll Flynn or Peter O'Toole's stature (when they were young) to carry a quasi-swashbuckling film, like "The Quest," forward in a convincing way. Roger Moore is a more experienced actor, but he merely reprises his dull cornball James Bond role as the pirate captain and (like his James Bond character) his performance just doesn't work. Although Robert Newton's Captain Silver character has become a clich&eacute;, I would have preferred that type of pirate captain rather than the one depicted by Roger Moore. Towards the end, Van Damme switches gears and creates another version of "Bloodsport" with its Hollywood formulae. He seems to be more comfortable with this material (especially since it requires him to do the martial arts that he knows so well), which explains why the martial arts sequences in the last 30-40 minutes of this film are reasonably entertaining. Those martial arts sequences are not, unfortunately, as good as the ones in Bloodsport which had better choreography and a great music soundtrack by composer Paul Hertzog. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only Van Damme or perhaps Roger Moore completists need apply.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Comeuppance Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set in the 1920's, Chris Dubois (Van Damme) is a street performer who wears clown makeup, a funny hat, and walks on stilts for a living. Adventure finds him when he ends up a stowaway on a boat heading to mysterious Muay Thai Island. There he learns martial arts, and, later in Tibet, meets the charming Lord Dobbs (Moore) and his assistant Smythe (McGee). It is around this time that Chris seeks to be involved in Ghan Geng, a secret underground fighting tournament. The winner gets a huge golden dragon, so Dobbs has a stake in Chris winning, as he wants the Dragon. Fighters are invited from all over the world , and America is represented by boxer Maxie Devine (Remar). Chris must take his place in the tournament and defeat the sinister Khan (Quissi) to win it all. Also, there's some mild romance with the prerequisite female reporter Carrie Newton (Gunn). Van Damme does a solid , professional job with his directional debut. Having co-written the film with Bloodsport (1988) dude Frank Dux, you pretty much know what to expect- but this movie is rated PG-13, so it was clearly trying to bring the Punchfighting genre some mainstream acceptance. With its slick Hollywood look and booming, sweeping score by Randy Edelman, the final product is perfect for 13-year olds, presumably its target demographic. Interestingly, the movie is a period piece, and plays like a prequel to Bloodsport. Instead of The Kumite, It's Ghan Geng. Van Damme tries on a number of personas from "Old Man Van Damme" to "Van Damme The Clown" and many things in between. The presence of Roger Moore adds class and respectability to the proceedings, and James Remar of Quiet Cool (1986) fame stands out as Devine. He's always worth seeing. Janet Gunn from Night Of The Running Man (1995) and The Sweeper (1996) is the eye candy but not much else. It's important to remember this was when video games like Mortal Kombat and Street Fighter were at the peak of their popularity. So when the Ghan Geng section of the movie begins (pretty much the last half)- the plot just STOPS. It's just one fighter from one country facing off against another fighter from another country. It gets repetitive and pretty numbing after awhile. Other Punchfighters don't do this. They vary the Punchfighting scenes with other plot-based stuff. Not so here. Plus the fact the movie is kind of on the long side doesn't help matters. What The Quest should have been is an 80 minute R-rated Punchfighter. Simply cutting the length but adding more violence would have helped immensely. But they weren't going for that audience, unfortunately. The Quest is more of a big "adventure" film where characters are seeking a "lost city" and many countries and time periods are represented. This might be a good way to start younger viewers on a career of watching Van Damme movies\action movies\Punchfighters but for adults. Only Van Damme or perhaps Roger Moore completists need apply. For more insanity, please visit: comeuppancereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where does Bloodsport end and The Quest begin...?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For a Jean Claude Van Damme movie, then "The Quest" is a fairly standard one. And if you have seen the 1988 "Bloodsport" movie, then you have essentially also seen "The Quest". And I don't think that it is a mere coincidence, especially since the story was written by Frank Dux and Jean Claude Van Damme. The story is about Christopher Dubois (played by Jean-Claude Van Damme) who is living on the streets, when he is forced to run for his life and ending up as a stowaway on a ship. When he comes to his senses, he is put into slavery, working on the ship. By sheer luck he is rescued by Lord Edgar Dobbs (played by Roger Moore) and Harry Smythe (played by Jack McGee), two thieves and con artists. Setting out to steal a massive golden dragon in a reclusive and secret fighting tournament, Christoper Dubois finds himself fighting on behalf of the boxer Maxie Devine (played by James Remar). Storywise, then "The Quest" focused more on the fights and action. And as in "Bloodsport", then there is lots of it, and the fight sequences are nicely executed and brought to the screen. The movie itself is as predictable as they come - but then again, aren't most of Jean Claude Van Damme's movies? There are so many similarities between "Bloodsport" and "The Quest", that you just sit there wondering why "The Quest" was actually ever put on film. Wasn't it enough with this story being told in 1988 back when "Bloodsport" came out? But as with virtually all of Jean Claude Van Damme's movies, the main focus is the action and fighting, and whatever story or resemblance of a story there is becomes secondary. Obviously you have the fighting tournament held in an exotic location, there was the bested friend of whom Van Damme takes a headband, there was a woman reporter, there was a massive and seemingly invincible opponent, and of course there is Jean Claude Van Damme as the underdog who swoops in and wins it all against all odds. That being said, then "The Quest" is good entertainment where you don't have to use your brain at all. Funny, how I remembered this movie being much better back in the late 90's, when I remember my brother getting it on VHS. And after having obtained the DVD in 2013 and watched it again, it wasn't as cool as I remembered it to be. But still, fun and action-packed, a fairly standard Jean Claude Van Damme movie to be honest.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bloodsport's Second Best Remake !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before watching it, I have heard that it didn't do well in the box office, but I haven't known why. After watching it, that "why" wasn't hard to answer. It's so close to Bloodsport (1988), which was another movie starring Jean-Claude Van Damme, another movie inspired by martial artist Frank Dux's life and experiences, and another movie centers around a secret martial arts tournament. In fact, the similar points between the 2 movies are many; whereas a beautiful American she-journalist is on the lead's side, an earlier enmity happens between one of the contestants and the lead, a friend for the lead is cruelly beaten, let alone that the lead wins at last. True, they added an older time period, a character of a pirate who wants to steal gold, a situation where the lead proves his nobleness, but I felt I was watching the same movie again. At times, I thought that all of these differences was originally put just to mislead you that this is a remake of a movie done 8 years before ! The first half's writing is fine. It is thrilling, swiftly paced, and takes place in numerous lands. The lead gets from a trouble to another fascinatingly. And he's a human action hero, who has lost and poor child inside of him, and wants to save other lost and poor children, by doing the right thing. Though, in the second half, things weren't as fine. The American journalist didn't do anything (or say anything !). Aside from presenting such a totally extra character, this took a lot from the emotional side of the movie; making it badly concrete. The basis of the enmity between the Mongolian fighter and the lead was trivial (a conflict around a restaurant table !). When the Asian guy's son is killed, we don't get enthusiastic over the idea of how the lead must avenge him, because we weren't introduced to that character appropriately, and the script didn't make them, the lead and him, friends or even close from the start. And I didn't find any use out of the first and last scenes, where the lead was narrating his story as a very old man, sure they ended up as naive. Plus, it's hard to believe that 90 something guy can hit 2 punks that easily ! Van Damme's direction had its share of mistakes too. He overused the TV-ish close-ups, not doing much to hide the poor budget; in a movie that supposedly depends on impressive backgrounds, sets and costumes. Hence it has a medium TV pilot feel written all over it, especially with borrowed shots from richer movies ! I hated how Van Damme filmed the guy who announces the competitors before every match, by the same cadre and from the same angle, creating something between boring and funny. However, the bigger mistake can be felt in the fighting scenes. OH MY GOD, the action star did the action scenes wrongly. He suffered a hysteria which got to those scenes then to us, with too many various angles, stupidly fast cutting, and the most unnecessary slow-motion ever; which was being used every 10 seconds (as if Van Damme thought he was giving an illustrative lesson for martial arts students !). So the final result was annoying time, with nothing to concentrate on or watch. And by the way, Randy Edelman's music score seemed inane, and its fervent charge wasn't that fervent. The good points kind of compensate. The performance was so right. James Remar mastered that gallant fighter, having most of the lights for himself. Roger Moore was more than perfect as Lord futile swindler, being the best star to handle such a role, and the best relief this movie had. I loved discovering that he's a military captain-turned- pirate, which added much to his character beside his huge presence and genuine wit. I don't know why he considers The Quest his least favorite movie, since he has done worse (believe me, he has done a far far worse !). Van Damme looked tired, maybe due to his being behind and in front the camera in the same time. But he was more like Jackie Chan in some moments, managing to be a clueless child on a mission, and by that I mean a good thing. Casting all of those diverse martial arts champions was smart and interesting. The choreography of the climactic fight satisfied me the most. And the direction of Van Damme's fights outclassed all the rest's. The Quest is a B-grade B-movie. As a director, I didn't wait for more than that from Van Damme's side. And as an action hero, he provided his usual. Undoubtedly it has some entertainment value. But clearly it needed more to win the box office, or my A-grade rank, like less copied story and more good directing. This way it would have been anything better than Bloodsport's second best remake !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the epic Van Damme was aiming for. This is sadly, routine with uninspired fight scenes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Van Damme & Frank Dux collaborated together for this so called once in a lifetime project, hoping to make a classic Martial Arts film like of Bloodsport. Not only do they fail, but they created something that falls completely flat. I don't like criticizing Van Damme, as Van Damme is one of my all time favorite action heroes, but he has left me with no choice here. The movie tries to build up a deep relationship with Van Damme being trained in the art of Muay Thai. That ends as quickly as it begins, and it has no emotion what so ever. Van Damme clearly forgets this, and tries to recreate a key emotional scene in Bloodsport with Phang & Chris, but it has nowhere near the merit it had in Bloodsport, simply because The Quest failed to make me care like it should have. The fight choreography is a colossal disappointment. Van Damme who knows a thing or two about fighting, should know how to create an exciting fight, right? Wrong. The fights couldn't be more mundane if they tried. The fighters themselves have the repertoire to make an exciting fight, but they were often squashes with flashes of brilliance that never lasted as long as I would have liked. The end fight is typical Van Damage. Which means he gets his ass kicked for most of it and makes the "impossible" comeback; it works in most Van Damme movies, but not here. It's over the top and ho-hum The cinematography is actually excellent. It's a sight to behold at times, and I felt they got the time period they were doing down pat. Van Damme doesn't display any of that natural charm that he is well known for, and gives a one-note performance here for the most part. Maybe it was because of his directing responsibilities, but he was shockingly dull a lot of the time. His acrobatics are good as usual, but that's it. Roger Moore shamefully mugs his way through the film, and looks a bit embarrassed to be here. I have read he considers this to be his worst film. While I felt this movie was very much average, and not that great, it's far from his worst. He's made a couple of James Bond films that are worse than this movie. It's a rather annoying performance that quickly made me intolerant. James Remar is amusing as Maxie Devine, but his role is poorly written. Janet Gunn doesn't have much of a part except to be easy on the eyes. Abdel Qissi makes for a formidable presence as the imposing baddie. I was also disappointed by the lack of Chris's background on his childhood. We see snippets of it, but not nearly enough. A more thought out movie would have been really nice, but this is not the case. This is stuff I consider to be rather fruitful Final Thoughts: It's watchable, but nothing more. Considering the epic he was going for in his directional debut, I highly doubt he had such a watered down retread of The Bloodsport in mind. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's a reason why JCVD and James Bond haven't worked together again - 43%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Scrolling through the TV schedules as I often do, it's a rare film indeed that makes me stop and think about recording it. But how can anyone not be intrigued by "a period action adventure with Jean-Claude Van Damme and Roger Moore" - sure, it wouldn't be likely to change the world but what a line-up! My masochistic side pricking my conscious, I duly recording this and settled down today to watch what must be the strangest piece of casting I think I've ever seen. The Muscles From Brussels plays Chris Dubois, a ragamuffin street thief operating a child gang on the streets of New York in 1925. But after one daring escape from the police too many, Dubois inadvertently stows away and finds himself far from home and at the mercy of vicious pirates. Eventually, he is rescued by dashing British adventurer Lord Dobbs (Moore) and his partner-in-crime Smythe (Jack McGee) and they agree to help Dubois return to America. But Dobbs betrays Dubois and leaves him stranded in the Muay Thai Islands where his adventures really begin. He soon finds himself thrown into a global fighting tournament against the best in the world but as his paths cross with fellow Americans Maxie Devine (James Remar) and journalist Carrie Newton (Janet Gunn), Dubois realises he must win the tournament or risk all their futures... I can't comment on this film's similarity with the earlier "Bloodsport" because that film has somehow passed me by. What I will comment on is the alarming similarity to another Van Damme flick, the frankly forgettable "AWOL: Absent Without Leave". I can't help but feel that for his directorial debut, Van Damme should have stretched himself a bit more beyond the tired "fighting tournament" plot. He probably was too busy dominating proceedings - once the film's second half begins, the fighting takes over completely and dialogue fades into the odd shout and macho grunt. Yes, there are odd bits and pieces of plot to get through such as the moment when an opponent makes an enemy of Dubois and we then know who's gonna get beaten up last. It's as though JCVD felt that the cast weren't trying and decided to run the rest of the film himself. And to be honest, he may have a point - other than Moore, the rest of the cast disappear into the background like early morning fog. As does the plot - can anyone tell me why Devine hung around for so long or what exactly was the story Newton felt she had to chase? I couldn't find one to last the 95 minutes of this movie, let alone a Pulitzer prize. I could go on but you get the picture. "The Quest" is an unremarkable and deeply formulaic martial arts movie that reminds us why JCVD now spends his days selling Coors. It's poorly directed with lots of needless slow motion, incoherent and offers little surprises other than the bizarre combination of its two lead stars. It also feels very dated and that's nothing to do with its period setting - this film comes five years after the likes of "Terminator 2: Judgement Day" which is a quantum leap ahead in terms of story-telling, set pieces, special effects and performances. Van Damme has made decent enough movies in the past - I recommend the likes of "Universal Soldier" or "Sudden Death" - but this really isn't one of them. A Damme shame, then. And just what was the point of the whole thing being a flash-back?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speculation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cam Cloutier
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoy Van Damme's films occasionally, especially "Time Cop". Of his films, I consider this one of his worst, but that rating is purely from a technical vantage. A genuine martial artist is like anyone else when they go to the movies. They expect to see only fiction. The same is true even of martial arts action flics. Even if the choreographer and stars know their business, it's goosed up for entertainment purposes. Nevertheless, the discerning eye seeks a few gems, to see if the martial artists involved in the film's production at least cast a brief nod of respect to the art. In "The Quest", that nod is within the first 15 minutes of the movie: when an aging hero defends himself with his cane. The cane techniques are marvelous and entertaining and, suffice to say, a rarity in Hollywood kung fu cinema. Afterwards, it's typical dreck. Worse, as a long-time practitioner of Okinawan karate, I was mildly insulted by the portrayal of the "champion of karate" in the final segment of the film. One can only speculate why the producers (which included Van Damme) would show such a buffoon. We can go positive or negative in our speculation. Positively, we can say that Van Damme nodded in respect to the real masters of karate who, in the film's period time, were among the deadliest men who have EVER LIVED (Choki Motobu, Kanryo Higashionna, Itoman Bunkichi, Miyagi Chojun, to list but a few). Such men, though competitive, would have either not heard of the tournament or snubbed it. Negatively, we might say that Van Damme's Shotokan upbringing had rendered him oblivious to karate that was not watered down for schoolchildren (and a system that didn't even exist in the film's period; Funakoshi was only getting started teaching in Japan at that time). That would also be in line with many others' contemporary views of karate, common nowadays in the MMA, ever since the Gracies issued their silly challenge and no -real- karateka deigned to answer them. The sight of a karateka trying to side kick a sumo wrestler in the belly should make anyone twitch, unless they already nurse a profound (or ignorant) bias against real karate. I found the film otherwise tolerable if typical of Van Damme's work and of cinema of the 80s/90s generally.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoy Christmas in the lost city.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Duboir is Kidnapped and enslaved by gun smugglers, sold by pirates and thrust into the murky underworld of gambling and kick-boxing. His journey takes him to Muay Thai Island where martial arts are taught, and finally, the ancient Lost City. There he must face the ultimate test of his manhood in the ancient winner-take-all competition in which the deadliest fighters from around the world employ the most spectacular feats of martial arts skills ever displayed in order to win the prized Golden Dragon. But fighting prowess alone will not be enough for him to triumph over such daunting foes. He must reach deep inside and access all of the determination, strength of character and sense of selfless honour within in order to triumph over this final obstacle..... When Van Damme met Bond is a really strange movie to watch and probably not the best Van Damme film to start with. It's basically a retread of Bloodsport, set in a different time and location, with added Roger Moore. And while it's nowhere near as good as that movie, it's pretty darn good, and beautiful to look at. Van Damme is competent behind the camera, and even thought the main action of the film is your typical video game style beat em' up, the characters are rich and a little bit different. Van Damme is good, and Moore looks uncomfortable, but it's Van Dammes Baby, and he really tries hard with this. Plus, he gets to fight the bloke from Hot Chocolate at the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the James Bond 007 series celebrating its 50th anniversary because of Dr. No, and the third actor to play the famous spy role getting about a lot at the time, it made sense to me to see some of his films before and after Bond, so I found this one, the directorial debut from Jean-Claude Van Damme. Basically an old man is telling a story to a bartender after getting into a fight, and we flashback to this man younger, Christopher Dubois (Van Damme), a pickpocket living in 1925 New York who was orphaned as a child and runs a gang of orphan children pickpockets who also con and steal to get by. They get found by gangsters but Dubois manages to get away, but he does get the attention of the police as well, but he promises to return to the children before stowing away on a boat, but he is found by the crew and forced to be a slave by the pirates aboard. He is saved a few years later by mercenary Englishman Lord Edgar Dobbs (Sir Roger Moore) who agrees to help him get home to America, but in fact he sells him off as a slave on the island of Siam where he gets trained in Muay Thai fighting for a scheme that is coming up. Six months pass and Dobbs with his partner Harry Smythe (Jack McGee) are shocked to see Dubois fighting in the Muay Thai fighting ring, but they see he has become a skilled fighter, so they buy his freedom so that he will represent the USA in the Ghang-Gheng worldwide fighting tournament held in the Lost City of Tibet. Other countries competing in the global event include China, Japan, Germany, Brazil, France, Turkey, Greece, Spain, Africa, Korea, Soviet Union (Russia) and Scotland, all are eliminated round by round, and at the end of the tournament the winning country will receive the prestigious and valuable statue the Golden Dragon. As the contest goes on Dubois gets to know American reporter Carrie Newton (Janet Gunn) and heavyweight boxing champion Maxie Devine (James Remar) who give him advice and tips, and after winning against apposing countries the biggest challenge comes in the final round when he faces Khan the Mongolian Fighter (Abdel Qissi) who is savage. At the end Dubois ultimately wins the tournament, and refusing the Golden Dragon he wins the freedom of his friends Dobbs and Smythe who were sentenced to death after they tried to steal the golden statue, he returned to New York and got the children off the streets, Devine trained great fighters in his future, Dobbs and Smythe went deep into the Amazon to open a trading post, and Carrie wrote the story of everything called The Quest. Also starring Aki Aleong as Khao, Louis Mandylor as Riggi, Chang Ching Peng Chaplin as Master Tchi, Ryan Cutrona as Officer O'Keefe, Peter Wong as Chinese Fighter, Kitao Koji as Sumo Wrestler, Habby Heske as German Fighter, C&eacute;sar Carneiro as Brazilian Fighter, Takis Triggelis as French Fighter, Azdine Nouri as Turkish Fighter, Stefanos Miltsakakis as Greek Fighter, Peter Malota as Spanish Fighter, Winston Ellis as African Fighter, Ong Soo Han as Korean Fighter, Brick Bronsky as Russian Fighter, Ip Choi Nam as Korean Fighter and Mike Lambert as Scottish Fighter. Van Damme is relatively interesting as the pickpocket turned strong fighter, I will be honest and say that I was paying more attention to Moore though with his charming mannerisms and overall English good nature, I have only seen a few of Van Damme's films, many of them are meant to be involving fighting, so as one of them this is I suppose a good enough one, the story is simple enough and the fight sequences are certainly gripping, it is an alright martial arts action adventure. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Predictable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jennifer Fode
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say! Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say! Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jonathanruano
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Quest" does not know what kind of movie it wants to be - a version of "Oliver Twist," a pirate movie, a film about Muay Thai training, or another "Bloodsport" - and so it covers all these elements at once and does so badly, rather than focusing on one element and doing it well. When I saw "The Quest," I was impressed by the cinematography which seems reminiscent in a way of those great epic films of the 1950s and 1960s. Yet at the same time, I was bored with the film because the vast majority of its ideas seemed to be half-baked. If you want to do a film with multiple plots, like the "Crying Game" did, then what you need is an brilliant film director and excellent screen writers who know what they are doing. Yet Jean Claude Van Damme seems way over his head in his directorial debut. He knows how to film gorgeous looking scenes, but he cannot bring the various elements of film-making together into one coherent narrative. "The Quest" looks like an array of elements thrown together haphazardly in the hope that they would amount to something, but they do not. In the opening scenes, Jean Claude Van Damme plays a clown with stilts against a richly layered backdrop of a 1920s city coupled with a hideaway with thieving boys which is reminiscent of Fagin's lair from the film "Oliver Twist." Then we have scenes that appear, at least on the surface, to come straight out of the movie "Treasure Island"(1954) which includes its pirate ship. This is followed by another epic scene with Muay Thai fighters training on the beach while large waves are crashing against the shore. Then we see Jean Claude Van Damme and company travelling through Asia on elephants and then horses en route to a temple in the snowy mountains of Tibet. But do all these scenes amount to anything? Actually no, because none of these ideas are fully developed and imbued with meaning. The other problem is with the acting. A film that tries to cover as much ground as "The Quest" does needs capable (probably even gifted) actors to convey its material well. But Jean Claude Van Damme, with his poor acting abilities, seems like an uncomfortable fit as the film's protagonist. Van Damme is much more suited for laid-back, easy going, macho films, like Bloodsport and Kickboxer, where you can excuse the bad acting (and laugh at it) and have a good time. But in "The Quest," the sets upstage Van Damme, making him look small and insignificant. You really need someone with Eroll Flynn or Peter O'Toole's stature (when they were young) to carry a quasi-swashbuckling film, like "The Quest," forward in a convincing way. Roger Moore is a more experienced actor, but he merely reprises his dull cornball James Bond role as the pirate captain and (like his James Bond character) his performance just doesn't work. Although Robert Newton's Captain Silver character has become a clich&eacute;, I would have preferred that type of pirate captain rather than the one depicted by Roger Moore. Towards the end, Van Damme switches gears and creates another version of "Bloodsport" with its Hollywood formulae. He seems to be more comfortable with this material (especially since it requires him to do the martial arts that he knows so well), which explains why the martial arts sequences in the last 30-40 minutes of this film are reasonably entertaining. Those martial arts sequences are not, unfortunately, as good as the ones in Bloodsport which had better choreography and a great music soundtrack by composer Paul Hertzog. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only Van Damme or perhaps Roger Moore completists need apply.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Comeuppance Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set in the 1920's, Chris Dubois (Van Damme) is a street performer who wears clown makeup, a funny hat, and walks on stilts for a living. Adventure finds him when he ends up a stowaway on a boat heading to mysterious Muay Thai Island. There he learns martial arts, and, later in Tibet, meets the charming Lord Dobbs (Moore) and his assistant Smythe (McGee). It is around this time that Chris seeks to be involved in Ghan Geng, a secret underground fighting tournament. The winner gets a huge golden dragon, so Dobbs has a stake in Chris winning, as he wants the Dragon. Fighters are invited from all over the world , and America is represented by boxer Maxie Devine (Remar). Chris must take his place in the tournament and defeat the sinister Khan (Quissi) to win it all. Also, there's some mild romance with the prerequisite female reporter Carrie Newton (Gunn). Van Damme does a solid , professional job with his directional debut. Having co-written the film with Bloodsport (1988) dude Frank Dux, you pretty much know what to expect- but this movie is rated PG-13, so it was clearly trying to bring the Punchfighting genre some mainstream acceptance. With its slick Hollywood look and booming, sweeping score by Randy Edelman, the final product is perfect for 13-year olds, presumably its target demographic. Interestingly, the movie is a period piece, and plays like a prequel to Bloodsport. Instead of The Kumite, It's Ghan Geng. Van Damme tries on a number of personas from "Old Man Van Damme" to "Van Damme The Clown" and many things in between. The presence of Roger Moore adds class and respectability to the proceedings, and James Remar of Quiet Cool (1986) fame stands out as Devine. He's always worth seeing. Janet Gunn from Night Of The Running Man (1995) and The Sweeper (1996) is the eye candy but not much else. It's important to remember this was when video games like Mortal Kombat and Street Fighter were at the peak of their popularity. So when the Ghan Geng section of the movie begins (pretty much the last half)- the plot just STOPS. It's just one fighter from one country facing off against another fighter from another country. It gets repetitive and pretty numbing after awhile. Other Punchfighters don't do this. They vary the Punchfighting scenes with other plot-based stuff. Not so here. Plus the fact the movie is kind of on the long side doesn't help matters. What The Quest should have been is an 80 minute R-rated Punchfighter. Simply cutting the length but adding more violence would have helped immensely. But they weren't going for that audience, unfortunately. The Quest is more of a big "adventure" film where characters are seeking a "lost city" and many countries and time periods are represented. This might be a good way to start younger viewers on a career of watching Van Damme movies\action movies\Punchfighters but for adults. Only Van Damme or perhaps Roger Moore completists need apply. For more insanity, please visit: comeuppancereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where does Bloodsport end and The Quest begin...?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For a Jean Claude Van Damme movie, then "The Quest" is a fairly standard one. And if you have seen the 1988 "Bloodsport" movie, then you have essentially also seen "The Quest". And I don't think that it is a mere coincidence, especially since the story was written by Frank Dux and Jean Claude Van Damme. The story is about Christopher Dubois (played by Jean-Claude Van Damme) who is living on the streets, when he is forced to run for his life and ending up as a stowaway on a ship. When he comes to his senses, he is put into slavery, working on the ship. By sheer luck he is rescued by Lord Edgar Dobbs (played by Roger Moore) and Harry Smythe (played by Jack McGee), two thieves and con artists. Setting out to steal a massive golden dragon in a reclusive and secret fighting tournament, Christoper Dubois finds himself fighting on behalf of the boxer Maxie Devine (played by James Remar). Storywise, then "The Quest" focused more on the fights and action. And as in "Bloodsport", then there is lots of it, and the fight sequences are nicely executed and brought to the screen. The movie itself is as predictable as they come - but then again, aren't most of Jean Claude Van Damme's movies? There are so many similarities between "Bloodsport" and "The Quest", that you just sit there wondering why "The Quest" was actually ever put on film. Wasn't it enough with this story being told in 1988 back when "Bloodsport" came out? But as with virtually all of Jean Claude Van Damme's movies, the main focus is the action and fighting, and whatever story or resemblance of a story there is becomes secondary. Obviously you have the fighting tournament held in an exotic location, there was the bested friend of whom Van Damme takes a headband, there was a woman reporter, there was a massive and seemingly invincible opponent, and of course there is Jean Claude Van Damme as the underdog who swoops in and wins it all against all odds. That being said, then "The Quest" is good entertainment where you don't have to use your brain at all. Funny, how I remembered this movie being much better back in the late 90's, when I remember my brother getting it on VHS. And after having obtained the DVD in 2013 and watched it again, it wasn't as cool as I remembered it to be. But still, fun and action-packed, a fairly standard Jean Claude Van Damme movie to be honest.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bloodsport's Second Best Remake !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before watching it, I have heard that it didn't do well in the box office, but I haven't known why. After watching it, that "why" wasn't hard to answer. It's so close to Bloodsport (1988), which was another movie starring Jean-Claude Van Damme, another movie inspired by martial artist Frank Dux's life and experiences, and another movie centers around a secret martial arts tournament. In fact, the similar points between the 2 movies are many; whereas a beautiful American she-journalist is on the lead's side, an earlier enmity happens between one of the contestants and the lead, a friend for the lead is cruelly beaten, let alone that the lead wins at last. True, they added an older time period, a character of a pirate who wants to steal gold, a situation where the lead proves his nobleness, but I felt I was watching the same movie again. At times, I thought that all of these differences was originally put just to mislead you that this is a remake of a movie done 8 years before ! The first half's writing is fine. It is thrilling, swiftly paced, and takes place in numerous lands. The lead gets from a trouble to another fascinatingly. And he's a human action hero, who has lost and poor child inside of him, and wants to save other lost and poor children, by doing the right thing. Though, in the second half, things weren't as fine. The American journalist didn't do anything (or say anything !). Aside from presenting such a totally extra character, this took a lot from the emotional side of the movie; making it badly concrete. The basis of the enmity between the Mongolian fighter and the lead was trivial (a conflict around a restaurant table !). When the Asian guy's son is killed, we don't get enthusiastic over the idea of how the lead must avenge him, because we weren't introduced to that character appropriately, and the script didn't make them, the lead and him, friends or even close from the start. And I didn't find any use out of the first and last scenes, where the lead was narrating his story as a very old man, sure they ended up as naive. Plus, it's hard to believe that 90 something guy can hit 2 punks that easily ! Van Damme's direction had its share of mistakes too. He overused the TV-ish close-ups, not doing much to hide the poor budget; in a movie that supposedly depends on impressive backgrounds, sets and costumes. Hence it has a medium TV pilot feel written all over it, especially with borrowed shots from richer movies ! I hated how Van Damme filmed the guy who announces the competitors before every match, by the same cadre and from the same angle, creating something between boring and funny. However, the bigger mistake can be felt in the fighting scenes. OH MY GOD, the action star did the action scenes wrongly. He suffered a hysteria which got to those scenes then to us, with too many various angles, stupidly fast cutting, and the most unnecessary slow-motion ever; which was being used every 10 seconds (as if Van Damme thought he was giving an illustrative lesson for martial arts students !). So the final result was annoying time, with nothing to concentrate on or watch. And by the way, Randy Edelman's music score seemed inane, and its fervent charge wasn't that fervent. The good points kind of compensate. The performance was so right. James Remar mastered that gallant fighter, having most of the lights for himself. Roger Moore was more than perfect as Lord futile swindler, being the best star to handle such a role, and the best relief this movie had. I loved discovering that he's a military captain-turned- pirate, which added much to his character beside his huge presence and genuine wit. I don't know why he considers The Quest his least favorite movie, since he has done worse (believe me, he has done a far far worse !). Van Damme looked tired, maybe due to his being behind and in front the camera in the same time. But he was more like Jackie Chan in some moments, managing to be a clueless child on a mission, and by that I mean a good thing. Casting all of those diverse martial arts champions was smart and interesting. The choreography of the climactic fight satisfied me the most. And the direction of Van Damme's fights outclassed all the rest's. The Quest is a B-grade B-movie. As a director, I didn't wait for more than that from Van Damme's side. And as an action hero, he provided his usual. Undoubtedly it has some entertainment value. But clearly it needed more to win the box office, or my A-grade rank, like less copied story and more good directing. This way it would have been anything better than Bloodsport's second best remake !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the epic Van Damme was aiming for. This is sadly, routine with uninspired fight scenes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Van Damme & Frank Dux collaborated together for this so called once in a lifetime project, hoping to make a classic Martial Arts film like of Bloodsport. Not only do they fail, but they created something that falls completely flat. I don't like criticizing Van Damme, as Van Damme is one of my all time favorite action heroes, but he has left me with no choice here. The movie tries to build up a deep relationship with Van Damme being trained in the art of Muay Thai. That ends as quickly as it begins, and it has no emotion what so ever. Van Damme clearly forgets this, and tries to recreate a key emotional scene in Bloodsport with Phang & Chris, but it has nowhere near the merit it had in Bloodsport, simply because The Quest failed to make me care like it should have. The fight choreography is a colossal disappointment. Van Damme who knows a thing or two about fighting, should know how to create an exciting fight, right? Wrong. The fights couldn't be more mundane if they tried. The fighters themselves have the repertoire to make an exciting fight, but they were often squashes with flashes of brilliance that never lasted as long as I would have liked. The end fight is typical Van Damage. Which means he gets his ass kicked for most of it and makes the "impossible" comeback; it works in most Van Damme movies, but not here. It's over the top and ho-hum The cinematography is actually excellent. It's a sight to behold at times, and I felt they got the time period they were doing down pat. Van Damme doesn't display any of that natural charm that he is well known for, and gives a one-note performance here for the most part. Maybe it was because of his directing responsibilities, but he was shockingly dull a lot of the time. His acrobatics are good as usual, but that's it. Roger Moore shamefully mugs his way through the film, and looks a bit embarrassed to be here. I have read he considers this to be his worst film. While I felt this movie was very much average, and not that great, it's far from his worst. He's made a couple of James Bond films that are worse than this movie. It's a rather annoying performance that quickly made me intolerant. James Remar is amusing as Maxie Devine, but his role is poorly written. Janet Gunn doesn't have much of a part except to be easy on the eyes. Abdel Qissi makes for a formidable presence as the imposing baddie. I was also disappointed by the lack of Chris's background on his childhood. We see snippets of it, but not nearly enough. A more thought out movie would have been really nice, but this is not the case. This is stuff I consider to be rather fruitful Final Thoughts: It's watchable, but nothing more. Considering the epic he was going for in his directional debut, I highly doubt he had such a watered down retread of The Bloodsport in mind. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's a reason why JCVD and James Bond haven't worked together again - 43%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Scrolling through the TV schedules as I often do, it's a rare film indeed that makes me stop and think about recording it. But how can anyone not be intrigued by "a period action adventure with Jean-Claude Van Damme and Roger Moore" - sure, it wouldn't be likely to change the world but what a line-up! My masochistic side pricking my conscious, I duly recording this and settled down today to watch what must be the strangest piece of casting I think I've ever seen. The Muscles From Brussels plays Chris Dubois, a ragamuffin street thief operating a child gang on the streets of New York in 1925. But after one daring escape from the police too many, Dubois inadvertently stows away and finds himself far from home and at the mercy of vicious pirates. Eventually, he is rescued by dashing British adventurer Lord Dobbs (Moore) and his partner-in-crime Smythe (Jack McGee) and they agree to help Dubois return to America. But Dobbs betrays Dubois and leaves him stranded in the Muay Thai Islands where his adventures really begin. He soon finds himself thrown into a global fighting tournament against the best in the world but as his paths cross with fellow Americans Maxie Devine (James Remar) and journalist Carrie Newton (Janet Gunn), Dubois realises he must win the tournament or risk all their futures... I can't comment on this film's similarity with the earlier "Bloodsport" because that film has somehow passed me by. What I will comment on is the alarming similarity to another Van Damme flick, the frankly forgettable "AWOL: Absent Without Leave". I can't help but feel that for his directorial debut, Van Damme should have stretched himself a bit more beyond the tired "fighting tournament" plot. He probably was too busy dominating proceedings - once the film's second half begins, the fighting takes over completely and dialogue fades into the odd shout and macho grunt. Yes, there are odd bits and pieces of plot to get through such as the moment when an opponent makes an enemy of Dubois and we then know who's gonna get beaten up last. It's as though JCVD felt that the cast weren't trying and decided to run the rest of the film himself. And to be honest, he may have a point - other than Moore, the rest of the cast disappear into the background like early morning fog. As does the plot - can anyone tell me why Devine hung around for so long or what exactly was the story Newton felt she had to chase? I couldn't find one to last the 95 minutes of this movie, let alone a Pulitzer prize. I could go on but you get the picture. "The Quest" is an unremarkable and deeply formulaic martial arts movie that reminds us why JCVD now spends his days selling Coors. It's poorly directed with lots of needless slow motion, incoherent and offers little surprises other than the bizarre combination of its two lead stars. It also feels very dated and that's nothing to do with its period setting - this film comes five years after the likes of "Terminator 2: Judgement Day" which is a quantum leap ahead in terms of story-telling, set pieces, special effects and performances. Van Damme has made decent enough movies in the past - I recommend the likes of "Universal Soldier" or "Sudden Death" - but this really isn't one of them. A Damme shame, then. And just what was the point of the whole thing being a flash-back?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speculation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cam Cloutier
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoy Van Damme's films occasionally, especially "Time Cop". Of his films, I consider this one of his worst, but that rating is purely from a technical vantage. A genuine martial artist is like anyone else when they go to the movies. They expect to see only fiction. The same is true even of martial arts action flics. Even if the choreographer and stars know their business, it's goosed up for entertainment purposes. Nevertheless, the discerning eye seeks a few gems, to see if the martial artists involved in the film's production at least cast a brief nod of respect to the art. In "The Quest", that nod is within the first 15 minutes of the movie: when an aging hero defends himself with his cane. The cane techniques are marvelous and entertaining and, suffice to say, a rarity in Hollywood kung fu cinema. Afterwards, it's typical dreck. Worse, as a long-time practitioner of Okinawan karate, I was mildly insulted by the portrayal of the "champion of karate" in the final segment of the film. One can only speculate why the producers (which included Van Damme) would show such a buffoon. We can go positive or negative in our speculation. Positively, we can say that Van Damme nodded in respect to the real masters of karate who, in the film's period time, were among the deadliest men who have EVER LIVED (Choki Motobu, Kanryo Higashionna, Itoman Bunkichi, Miyagi Chojun, to list but a few). Such men, though competitive, would have either not heard of the tournament or snubbed it. Negatively, we might say that Van Damme's Shotokan upbringing had rendered him oblivious to karate that was not watered down for schoolchildren (and a system that didn't even exist in the film's period; Funakoshi was only getting started teaching in Japan at that time). That would also be in line with many others' contemporary views of karate, common nowadays in the MMA, ever since the Gracies issued their silly challenge and no -real- karateka deigned to answer them. The sight of a karateka trying to side kick a sumo wrestler in the belly should make anyone twitch, unless they already nurse a profound (or ignorant) bias against real karate. I found the film otherwise tolerable if typical of Van Damme's work and of cinema of the 80s/90s generally.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoy Christmas in the lost city.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Duboir is Kidnapped and enslaved by gun smugglers, sold by pirates and thrust into the murky underworld of gambling and kick-boxing. His journey takes him to Muay Thai Island where martial arts are taught, and finally, the ancient Lost City. There he must face the ultimate test of his manhood in the ancient winner-take-all competition in which the deadliest fighters from around the world employ the most spectacular feats of martial arts skills ever displayed in order to win the prized Golden Dragon. But fighting prowess alone will not be enough for him to triumph over such daunting foes. He must reach deep inside and access all of the determination, strength of character and sense of selfless honour within in order to triumph over this final obstacle..... When Van Damme met Bond is a really strange movie to watch and probably not the best Van Damme film to start with. It's basically a retread of Bloodsport, set in a different time and location, with added Roger Moore. And while it's nowhere near as good as that movie, it's pretty darn good, and beautiful to look at. Van Damme is competent behind the camera, and even thought the main action of the film is your typical video game style beat em' up, the characters are rich and a little bit different. Van Damme is good, and Moore looks uncomfortable, but it's Van Dammes Baby, and he really tries hard with this. Plus, he gets to fight the bloke from Hot Chocolate at the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the James Bond 007 series celebrating its 50th anniversary because of Dr. No, and the third actor to play the famous spy role getting about a lot at the time, it made sense to me to see some of his films before and after Bond, so I found this one, the directorial debut from Jean-Claude Van Damme. Basically an old man is telling a story to a bartender after getting into a fight, and we flashback to this man younger, Christopher Dubois (Van Damme), a pickpocket living in 1925 New York who was orphaned as a child and runs a gang of orphan children pickpockets who also con and steal to get by. They get found by gangsters but Dubois manages to get away, but he does get the attention of the police as well, but he promises to return to the children before stowing away on a boat, but he is found by the crew and forced to be a slave by the pirates aboard. He is saved a few years later by mercenary Englishman Lord Edgar Dobbs (Sir Roger Moore) who agrees to help him get home to America, but in fact he sells him off as a slave on the island of Siam where he gets trained in Muay Thai fighting for a scheme that is coming up. Six months pass and Dobbs with his partner Harry Smythe (Jack McGee) are shocked to see Dubois fighting in the Muay Thai fighting ring, but they see he has become a skilled fighter, so they buy his freedom so that he will represent the USA in the Ghang-Gheng worldwide fighting tournament held in the Lost City of Tibet. Other countries competing in the global event include China, Japan, Germany, Brazil, France, Turkey, Greece, Spain, Africa, Korea, Soviet Union (Russia) and Scotland, all are eliminated round by round, and at the end of the tournament the winning country will receive the prestigious and valuable statue the Golden Dragon. As the contest goes on Dubois gets to know American reporter Carrie Newton (Janet Gunn) and heavyweight boxing champion Maxie Devine (James Remar) who give him advice and tips, and after winning against apposing countries the biggest challenge comes in the final round when he faces Khan the Mongolian Fighter (Abdel Qissi) who is savage. At the end Dubois ultimately wins the tournament, and refusing the Golden Dragon he wins the freedom of his friends Dobbs and Smythe who were sentenced to death after they tried to steal the golden statue, he returned to New York and got the children off the streets, Devine trained great fighters in his future, Dobbs and Smythe went deep into the Amazon to open a trading post, and Carrie wrote the story of everything called The Quest. Also starring Aki Aleong as Khao, Louis Mandylor as Riggi, Chang Ching Peng Chaplin as Master Tchi, Ryan Cutrona as Officer O'Keefe, Peter Wong as Chinese Fighter, Kitao Koji as Sumo Wrestler, Habby Heske as German Fighter, C&eacute;sar Carneiro as Brazilian Fighter, Takis Triggelis as French Fighter, Azdine Nouri as Turkish Fighter, Stefanos Miltsakakis as Greek Fighter, Peter Malota as Spanish Fighter, Winston Ellis as African Fighter, Ong Soo Han as Korean Fighter, Brick Bronsky as Russian Fighter, Ip Choi Nam as Korean Fighter and Mike Lambert as Scottish Fighter. Van Damme is relatively interesting as the pickpocket turned strong fighter, I will be honest and say that I was paying more attention to Moore though with his charming mannerisms and overall English good nature, I have only seen a few of Van Damme's films, many of them are meant to be involving fighting, so as one of them this is I suppose a good enough one, the story is simple enough and the fight sequences are certainly gripping, it is an alright martial arts action adventure. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Predictable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jennifer Fode
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say! Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say! Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jonathanruano
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Quest" does not know what kind of movie it wants to be - a version of "Oliver Twist," a pirate movie, a film about Muay Thai training, or another "Bloodsport" - and so it covers all these elements at once and does so badly, rather than focusing on one element and doing it well. When I saw "The Quest," I was impressed by the cinematography which seems reminiscent in a way of those great epic films of the 1950s and 1960s. Yet at the same time, I was bored with the film because the vast majority of its ideas seemed to be half-baked. If you want to do a film with multiple plots, like the "Crying Game" did, then what you need is an brilliant film director and excellent screen writers who know what they are doing. Yet Jean Claude Van Damme seems way over his head in his directorial debut. He knows how to film gorgeous looking scenes, but he cannot bring the various elements of film-making together into one coherent narrative. "The Quest" looks like an array of elements thrown together haphazardly in the hope that they would amount to something, but they do not. In the opening scenes, Jean Claude Van Damme plays a clown with stilts against a richly layered backdrop of a 1920s city coupled with a hideaway with thieving boys which is reminiscent of Fagin's lair from the film "Oliver Twist." Then we have scenes that appear, at least on the surface, to come straight out of the movie "Treasure Island"(1954) which includes its pirate ship. This is followed by another epic scene with Muay Thai fighters training on the beach while large waves are crashing against the shore. Then we see Jean Claude Van Damme and company travelling through Asia on elephants and then horses en route to a temple in the snowy mountains of Tibet. But do all these scenes amount to anything? Actually no, because none of these ideas are fully developed and imbued with meaning. The other problem is with the acting. A film that tries to cover as much ground as "The Quest" does needs capable (probably even gifted) actors to convey its material well. But Jean Claude Van Damme, with his poor acting abilities, seems like an uncomfortable fit as the film's protagonist. Van Damme is much more suited for laid-back, easy going, macho films, like Bloodsport and Kickboxer, where you can excuse the bad acting (and laugh at it) and have a good time. But in "The Quest," the sets upstage Van Damme, making him look small and insignificant. You really need someone with Eroll Flynn or Peter O'Toole's stature (when they were young) to carry a quasi-swashbuckling film, like "The Quest," forward in a convincing way. Roger Moore is a more experienced actor, but he merely reprises his dull cornball James Bond role as the pirate captain and (like his James Bond character) his performance just doesn't work. Although Robert Newton's Captain Silver character has become a clich&eacute;, I would have preferred that type of pirate captain rather than the one depicted by Roger Moore. Towards the end, Van Damme switches gears and creates another version of "Bloodsport" with its Hollywood formulae. He seems to be more comfortable with this material (especially since it requires him to do the martial arts that he knows so well), which explains why the martial arts sequences in the last 30-40 minutes of this film are reasonably entertaining. Those martial arts sequences are not, unfortunately, as good as the ones in Bloodsport which had better choreography and a great music soundtrack by composer Paul Hertzog. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only Van Damme or perhaps Roger Moore completists need apply.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Comeuppance Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set in the 1920's, Chris Dubois (Van Damme) is a street performer who wears clown makeup, a funny hat, and walks on stilts for a living. Adventure finds him when he ends up a stowaway on a boat heading to mysterious Muay Thai Island. There he learns martial arts, and, later in Tibet, meets the charming Lord Dobbs (Moore) and his assistant Smythe (McGee). It is around this time that Chris seeks to be involved in Ghan Geng, a secret underground fighting tournament. The winner gets a huge golden dragon, so Dobbs has a stake in Chris winning, as he wants the Dragon. Fighters are invited from all over the world , and America is represented by boxer Maxie Devine (Remar). Chris must take his place in the tournament and defeat the sinister Khan (Quissi) to win it all. Also, there's some mild romance with the prerequisite female reporter Carrie Newton (Gunn). Van Damme does a solid , professional job with his directional debut. Having co-written the film with Bloodsport (1988) dude Frank Dux, you pretty much know what to expect- but this movie is rated PG-13, so it was clearly trying to bring the Punchfighting genre some mainstream acceptance. With its slick Hollywood look and booming, sweeping score by Randy Edelman, the final product is perfect for 13-year olds, presumably its target demographic. Interestingly, the movie is a period piece, and plays like a prequel to Bloodsport. Instead of The Kumite, It's Ghan Geng. Van Damme tries on a number of personas from "Old Man Van Damme" to "Van Damme The Clown" and many things in between. The presence of Roger Moore adds class and respectability to the proceedings, and James Remar of Quiet Cool (1986) fame stands out as Devine. He's always worth seeing. Janet Gunn from Night Of The Running Man (1995) and The Sweeper (1996) is the eye candy but not much else. It's important to remember this was when video games like Mortal Kombat and Street Fighter were at the peak of their popularity. So when the Ghan Geng section of the movie begins (pretty much the last half)- the plot just STOPS. It's just one fighter from one country facing off against another fighter from another country. It gets repetitive and pretty numbing after awhile. Other Punchfighters don't do this. They vary the Punchfighting scenes with other plot-based stuff. Not so here. Plus the fact the movie is kind of on the long side doesn't help matters. What The Quest should have been is an 80 minute R-rated Punchfighter. Simply cutting the length but adding more violence would have helped immensely. But they weren't going for that audience, unfortunately. The Quest is more of a big "adventure" film where characters are seeking a "lost city" and many countries and time periods are represented. This might be a good way to start younger viewers on a career of watching Van Damme movies\action movies\Punchfighters but for adults. Only Van Damme or perhaps Roger Moore completists need apply. For more insanity, please visit: comeuppancereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where does Bloodsport end and The Quest begin...?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For a Jean Claude Van Damme movie, then "The Quest" is a fairly standard one. And if you have seen the 1988 "Bloodsport" movie, then you have essentially also seen "The Quest". And I don't think that it is a mere coincidence, especially since the story was written by Frank Dux and Jean Claude Van Damme. The story is about Christopher Dubois (played by Jean-Claude Van Damme) who is living on the streets, when he is forced to run for his life and ending up as a stowaway on a ship. When he comes to his senses, he is put into slavery, working on the ship. By sheer luck he is rescued by Lord Edgar Dobbs (played by Roger Moore) and Harry Smythe (played by Jack McGee), two thieves and con artists. Setting out to steal a massive golden dragon in a reclusive and secret fighting tournament, Christoper Dubois finds himself fighting on behalf of the boxer Maxie Devine (played by James Remar). Storywise, then "The Quest" focused more on the fights and action. And as in "Bloodsport", then there is lots of it, and the fight sequences are nicely executed and brought to the screen. The movie itself is as predictable as they come - but then again, aren't most of Jean Claude Van Damme's movies? There are so many similarities between "Bloodsport" and "The Quest", that you just sit there wondering why "The Quest" was actually ever put on film. Wasn't it enough with this story being told in 1988 back when "Bloodsport" came out? But as with virtually all of Jean Claude Van Damme's movies, the main focus is the action and fighting, and whatever story or resemblance of a story there is becomes secondary. Obviously you have the fighting tournament held in an exotic location, there was the bested friend of whom Van Damme takes a headband, there was a woman reporter, there was a massive and seemingly invincible opponent, and of course there is Jean Claude Van Damme as the underdog who swoops in and wins it all against all odds. That being said, then "The Quest" is good entertainment where you don't have to use your brain at all. Funny, how I remembered this movie being much better back in the late 90's, when I remember my brother getting it on VHS. And after having obtained the DVD in 2013 and watched it again, it wasn't as cool as I remembered it to be. But still, fun and action-packed, a fairly standard Jean Claude Van Damme movie to be honest.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bloodsport's Second Best Remake !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before watching it, I have heard that it didn't do well in the box office, but I haven't known why. After watching it, that "why" wasn't hard to answer. It's so close to Bloodsport (1988), which was another movie starring Jean-Claude Van Damme, another movie inspired by martial artist Frank Dux's life and experiences, and another movie centers around a secret martial arts tournament. In fact, the similar points between the 2 movies are many; whereas a beautiful American she-journalist is on the lead's side, an earlier enmity happens between one of the contestants and the lead, a friend for the lead is cruelly beaten, let alone that the lead wins at last. True, they added an older time period, a character of a pirate who wants to steal gold, a situation where the lead proves his nobleness, but I felt I was watching the same movie again. At times, I thought that all of these differences was originally put just to mislead you that this is a remake of a movie done 8 years before ! The first half's writing is fine. It is thrilling, swiftly paced, and takes place in numerous lands. The lead gets from a trouble to another fascinatingly. And he's a human action hero, who has lost and poor child inside of him, and wants to save other lost and poor children, by doing the right thing. Though, in the second half, things weren't as fine. The American journalist didn't do anything (or say anything !). Aside from presenting such a totally extra character, this took a lot from the emotional side of the movie; making it badly concrete. The basis of the enmity between the Mongolian fighter and the lead was trivial (a conflict around a restaurant table !). When the Asian guy's son is killed, we don't get enthusiastic over the idea of how the lead must avenge him, because we weren't introduced to that character appropriately, and the script didn't make them, the lead and him, friends or even close from the start. And I didn't find any use out of the first and last scenes, where the lead was narrating his story as a very old man, sure they ended up as naive. Plus, it's hard to believe that 90 something guy can hit 2 punks that easily ! Van Damme's direction had its share of mistakes too. He overused the TV-ish close-ups, not doing much to hide the poor budget; in a movie that supposedly depends on impressive backgrounds, sets and costumes. Hence it has a medium TV pilot feel written all over it, especially with borrowed shots from richer movies ! I hated how Van Damme filmed the guy who announces the competitors before every match, by the same cadre and from the same angle, creating something between boring and funny. However, the bigger mistake can be felt in the fighting scenes. OH MY GOD, the action star did the action scenes wrongly. He suffered a hysteria which got to those scenes then to us, with too many various angles, stupidly fast cutting, and the most unnecessary slow-motion ever; which was being used every 10 seconds (as if Van Damme thought he was giving an illustrative lesson for martial arts students !). So the final result was annoying time, with nothing to concentrate on or watch. And by the way, Randy Edelman's music score seemed inane, and its fervent charge wasn't that fervent. The good points kind of compensate. The performance was so right. James Remar mastered that gallant fighter, having most of the lights for himself. Roger Moore was more than perfect as Lord futile swindler, being the best star to handle such a role, and the best relief this movie had. I loved discovering that he's a military captain-turned- pirate, which added much to his character beside his huge presence and genuine wit. I don't know why he considers The Quest his least favorite movie, since he has done worse (believe me, he has done a far far worse !). Van Damme looked tired, maybe due to his being behind and in front the camera in the same time. But he was more like Jackie Chan in some moments, managing to be a clueless child on a mission, and by that I mean a good thing. Casting all of those diverse martial arts champions was smart and interesting. The choreography of the climactic fight satisfied me the most. And the direction of Van Damme's fights outclassed all the rest's. The Quest is a B-grade B-movie. As a director, I didn't wait for more than that from Van Damme's side. And as an action hero, he provided his usual. Undoubtedly it has some entertainment value. But clearly it needed more to win the box office, or my A-grade rank, like less copied story and more good directing. This way it would have been anything better than Bloodsport's second best remake !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the epic Van Damme was aiming for. This is sadly, routine with uninspired fight scenes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Van Damme & Frank Dux collaborated together for this so called once in a lifetime project, hoping to make a classic Martial Arts film like of Bloodsport. Not only do they fail, but they created something that falls completely flat. I don't like criticizing Van Damme, as Van Damme is one of my all time favorite action heroes, but he has left me with no choice here. The movie tries to build up a deep relationship with Van Damme being trained in the art of Muay Thai. That ends as quickly as it begins, and it has no emotion what so ever. Van Damme clearly forgets this, and tries to recreate a key emotional scene in Bloodsport with Phang & Chris, but it has nowhere near the merit it had in Bloodsport, simply because The Quest failed to make me care like it should have. The fight choreography is a colossal disappointment. Van Damme who knows a thing or two about fighting, should know how to create an exciting fight, right? Wrong. The fights couldn't be more mundane if they tried. The fighters themselves have the repertoire to make an exciting fight, but they were often squashes with flashes of brilliance that never lasted as long as I would have liked. The end fight is typical Van Damage. Which means he gets his ass kicked for most of it and makes the "impossible" comeback; it works in most Van Damme movies, but not here. It's over the top and ho-hum The cinematography is actually excellent. It's a sight to behold at times, and I felt they got the time period they were doing down pat. Van Damme doesn't display any of that natural charm that he is well known for, and gives a one-note performance here for the most part. Maybe it was because of his directing responsibilities, but he was shockingly dull a lot of the time. His acrobatics are good as usual, but that's it. Roger Moore shamefully mugs his way through the film, and looks a bit embarrassed to be here. I have read he considers this to be his worst film. While I felt this movie was very much average, and not that great, it's far from his worst. He's made a couple of James Bond films that are worse than this movie. It's a rather annoying performance that quickly made me intolerant. James Remar is amusing as Maxie Devine, but his role is poorly written. Janet Gunn doesn't have much of a part except to be easy on the eyes. Abdel Qissi makes for a formidable presence as the imposing baddie. I was also disappointed by the lack of Chris's background on his childhood. We see snippets of it, but not nearly enough. A more thought out movie would have been really nice, but this is not the case. This is stuff I consider to be rather fruitful Final Thoughts: It's watchable, but nothing more. Considering the epic he was going for in his directional debut, I highly doubt he had such a watered down retread of The Bloodsport in mind. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's a reason why JCVD and James Bond haven't worked together again - 43%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Scrolling through the TV schedules as I often do, it's a rare film indeed that makes me stop and think about recording it. But how can anyone not be intrigued by "a period action adventure with Jean-Claude Van Damme and Roger Moore" - sure, it wouldn't be likely to change the world but what a line-up! My masochistic side pricking my conscious, I duly recording this and settled down today to watch what must be the strangest piece of casting I think I've ever seen. The Muscles From Brussels plays Chris Dubois, a ragamuffin street thief operating a child gang on the streets of New York in 1925. But after one daring escape from the police too many, Dubois inadvertently stows away and finds himself far from home and at the mercy of vicious pirates. Eventually, he is rescued by dashing British adventurer Lord Dobbs (Moore) and his partner-in-crime Smythe (Jack McGee) and they agree to help Dubois return to America. But Dobbs betrays Dubois and leaves him stranded in the Muay Thai Islands where his adventures really begin. He soon finds himself thrown into a global fighting tournament against the best in the world but as his paths cross with fellow Americans Maxie Devine (James Remar) and journalist Carrie Newton (Janet Gunn), Dubois realises he must win the tournament or risk all their futures... I can't comment on this film's similarity with the earlier "Bloodsport" because that film has somehow passed me by. What I will comment on is the alarming similarity to another Van Damme flick, the frankly forgettable "AWOL: Absent Without Leave". I can't help but feel that for his directorial debut, Van Damme should have stretched himself a bit more beyond the tired "fighting tournament" plot. He probably was too busy dominating proceedings - once the film's second half begins, the fighting takes over completely and dialogue fades into the odd shout and macho grunt. Yes, there are odd bits and pieces of plot to get through such as the moment when an opponent makes an enemy of Dubois and we then know who's gonna get beaten up last. It's as though JCVD felt that the cast weren't trying and decided to run the rest of the film himself. And to be honest, he may have a point - other than Moore, the rest of the cast disappear into the background like early morning fog. As does the plot - can anyone tell me why Devine hung around for so long or what exactly was the story Newton felt she had to chase? I couldn't find one to last the 95 minutes of this movie, let alone a Pulitzer prize. I could go on but you get the picture. "The Quest" is an unremarkable and deeply formulaic martial arts movie that reminds us why JCVD now spends his days selling Coors. It's poorly directed with lots of needless slow motion, incoherent and offers little surprises other than the bizarre combination of its two lead stars. It also feels very dated and that's nothing to do with its period setting - this film comes five years after the likes of "Terminator 2: Judgement Day" which is a quantum leap ahead in terms of story-telling, set pieces, special effects and performances. Van Damme has made decent enough movies in the past - I recommend the likes of "Universal Soldier" or "Sudden Death" - but this really isn't one of them. A Damme shame, then. And just what was the point of the whole thing being a flash-back?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speculation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cam Cloutier
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoy Van Damme's films occasionally, especially "Time Cop". Of his films, I consider this one of his worst, but that rating is purely from a technical vantage. A genuine martial artist is like anyone else when they go to the movies. They expect to see only fiction. The same is true even of martial arts action flics. Even if the choreographer and stars know their business, it's goosed up for entertainment purposes. Nevertheless, the discerning eye seeks a few gems, to see if the martial artists involved in the film's production at least cast a brief nod of respect to the art. In "The Quest", that nod is within the first 15 minutes of the movie: when an aging hero defends himself with his cane. The cane techniques are marvelous and entertaining and, suffice to say, a rarity in Hollywood kung fu cinema. Afterwards, it's typical dreck. Worse, as a long-time practitioner of Okinawan karate, I was mildly insulted by the portrayal of the "champion of karate" in the final segment of the film. One can only speculate why the producers (which included Van Damme) would show such a buffoon. We can go positive or negative in our speculation. Positively, we can say that Van Damme nodded in respect to the real masters of karate who, in the film's period time, were among the deadliest men who have EVER LIVED (Choki Motobu, Kanryo Higashionna, Itoman Bunkichi, Miyagi Chojun, to list but a few). Such men, though competitive, would have either not heard of the tournament or snubbed it. Negatively, we might say that Van Damme's Shotokan upbringing had rendered him oblivious to karate that was not watered down for schoolchildren (and a system that didn't even exist in the film's period; Funakoshi was only getting started teaching in Japan at that time). That would also be in line with many others' contemporary views of karate, common nowadays in the MMA, ever since the Gracies issued their silly challenge and no -real- karateka deigned to answer them. The sight of a karateka trying to side kick a sumo wrestler in the belly should make anyone twitch, unless they already nurse a profound (or ignorant) bias against real karate. I found the film otherwise tolerable if typical of Van Damme's work and of cinema of the 80s/90s generally.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoy Christmas in the lost city.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Duboir is Kidnapped and enslaved by gun smugglers, sold by pirates and thrust into the murky underworld of gambling and kick-boxing. His journey takes him to Muay Thai Island where martial arts are taught, and finally, the ancient Lost City. There he must face the ultimate test of his manhood in the ancient winner-take-all competition in which the deadliest fighters from around the world employ the most spectacular feats of martial arts skills ever displayed in order to win the prized Golden Dragon. But fighting prowess alone will not be enough for him to triumph over such daunting foes. He must reach deep inside and access all of the determination, strength of character and sense of selfless honour within in order to triumph over this final obstacle..... When Van Damme met Bond is a really strange movie to watch and probably not the best Van Damme film to start with. It's basically a retread of Bloodsport, set in a different time and location, with added Roger Moore. And while it's nowhere near as good as that movie, it's pretty darn good, and beautiful to look at. Van Damme is competent behind the camera, and even thought the main action of the film is your typical video game style beat em' up, the characters are rich and a little bit different. Van Damme is good, and Moore looks uncomfortable, but it's Van Dammes Baby, and he really tries hard with this. Plus, he gets to fight the bloke from Hot Chocolate at the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the James Bond 007 series celebrating its 50th anniversary because of Dr. No, and the third actor to play the famous spy role getting about a lot at the time, it made sense to me to see some of his films before and after Bond, so I found this one, the directorial debut from Jean-Claude Van Damme. Basically an old man is telling a story to a bartender after getting into a fight, and we flashback to this man younger, Christopher Dubois (Van Damme), a pickpocket living in 1925 New York who was orphaned as a child and runs a gang of orphan children pickpockets who also con and steal to get by. They get found by gangsters but Dubois manages to get away, but he does get the attention of the police as well, but he promises to return to the children before stowing away on a boat, but he is found by the crew and forced to be a slave by the pirates aboard. He is saved a few years later by mercenary Englishman Lord Edgar Dobbs (Sir Roger Moore) who agrees to help him get home to America, but in fact he sells him off as a slave on the island of Siam where he gets trained in Muay Thai fighting for a scheme that is coming up. Six months pass and Dobbs with his partner Harry Smythe (Jack McGee) are shocked to see Dubois fighting in the Muay Thai fighting ring, but they see he has become a skilled fighter, so they buy his freedom so that he will represent the USA in the Ghang-Gheng worldwide fighting tournament held in the Lost City of Tibet. Other countries competing in the global event include China, Japan, Germany, Brazil, France, Turkey, Greece, Spain, Africa, Korea, Soviet Union (Russia) and Scotland, all are eliminated round by round, and at the end of the tournament the winning country will receive the prestigious and valuable statue the Golden Dragon. As the contest goes on Dubois gets to know American reporter Carrie Newton (Janet Gunn) and heavyweight boxing champion Maxie Devine (James Remar) who give him advice and tips, and after winning against apposing countries the biggest challenge comes in the final round when he faces Khan the Mongolian Fighter (Abdel Qissi) who is savage. At the end Dubois ultimately wins the tournament, and refusing the Golden Dragon he wins the freedom of his friends Dobbs and Smythe who were sentenced to death after they tried to steal the golden statue, he returned to New York and got the children off the streets, Devine trained great fighters in his future, Dobbs and Smythe went deep into the Amazon to open a trading post, and Carrie wrote the story of everything called The Quest. Also starring Aki Aleong as Khao, Louis Mandylor as Riggi, Chang Ching Peng Chaplin as Master Tchi, Ryan Cutrona as Officer O'Keefe, Peter Wong as Chinese Fighter, Kitao Koji as Sumo Wrestler, Habby Heske as German Fighter, C&eacute;sar Carneiro as Brazilian Fighter, Takis Triggelis as French Fighter, Azdine Nouri as Turkish Fighter, Stefanos Miltsakakis as Greek Fighter, Peter Malota as Spanish Fighter, Winston Ellis as African Fighter, Ong Soo Han as Korean Fighter, Brick Bronsky as Russian Fighter, Ip Choi Nam as Korean Fighter and Mike Lambert as Scottish Fighter. Van Damme is relatively interesting as the pickpocket turned strong fighter, I will be honest and say that I was paying more attention to Moore though with his charming mannerisms and overall English good nature, I have only seen a few of Van Damme's films, many of them are meant to be involving fighting, so as one of them this is I suppose a good enough one, the story is simple enough and the fight sequences are certainly gripping, it is an alright martial arts action adventure. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Predictable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jennifer Fode
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say! Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say! Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jonathanruano
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Quest" does not know what kind of movie it wants to be - a version of "Oliver Twist," a pirate movie, a film about Muay Thai training, or another "Bloodsport" - and so it covers all these elements at once and does so badly, rather than focusing on one element and doing it well. When I saw "The Quest," I was impressed by the cinematography which seems reminiscent in a way of those great epic films of the 1950s and 1960s. Yet at the same time, I was bored with the film because the vast majority of its ideas seemed to be half-baked. If you want to do a film with multiple plots, like the "Crying Game" did, then what you need is an brilliant film director and excellent screen writers who know what they are doing. Yet Jean Claude Van Damme seems way over his head in his directorial debut. He knows how to film gorgeous looking scenes, but he cannot bring the various elements of film-making together into one coherent narrative. "The Quest" looks like an array of elements thrown together haphazardly in the hope that they would amount to something, but they do not. In the opening scenes, Jean Claude Van Damme plays a clown with stilts against a richly layered backdrop of a 1920s city coupled with a hideaway with thieving boys which is reminiscent of Fagin's lair from the film "Oliver Twist." Then we have scenes that appear, at least on the surface, to come straight out of the movie "Treasure Island"(1954) which includes its pirate ship. This is followed by another epic scene with Muay Thai fighters training on the beach while large waves are crashing against the shore. Then we see Jean Claude Van Damme and company travelling through Asia on elephants and then horses en route to a temple in the snowy mountains of Tibet. But do all these scenes amount to anything? Actually no, because none of these ideas are fully developed and imbued with meaning. The other problem is with the acting. A film that tries to cover as much ground as "The Quest" does needs capable (probably even gifted) actors to convey its material well. But Jean Claude Van Damme, with his poor acting abilities, seems like an uncomfortable fit as the film's protagonist. Van Damme is much more suited for laid-back, easy going, macho films, like Bloodsport and Kickboxer, where you can excuse the bad acting (and laugh at it) and have a good time. But in "The Quest," the sets upstage Van Damme, making him look small and insignificant. You really need someone with Eroll Flynn or Peter O'Toole's stature (when they were young) to carry a quasi-swashbuckling film, like "The Quest," forward in a convincing way. Roger Moore is a more experienced actor, but he merely reprises his dull cornball James Bond role as the pirate captain and (like his James Bond character) his performance just doesn't work. Although Robert Newton's Captain Silver character has become a clich&eacute;, I would have preferred that type of pirate captain rather than the one depicted by Roger Moore. Towards the end, Van Damme switches gears and creates another version of "Bloodsport" with its Hollywood formulae. He seems to be more comfortable with this material (especially since it requires him to do the martial arts that he knows so well), which explains why the martial arts sequences in the last 30-40 minutes of this film are reasonably entertaining. Those martial arts sequences are not, unfortunately, as good as the ones in Bloodsport which had better choreography and a great music soundtrack by composer Paul Hertzog. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only Van Damme or perhaps Roger Moore completists need apply.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Comeuppance Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set in the 1920's, Chris Dubois (Van Damme) is a street performer who wears clown makeup, a funny hat, and walks on stilts for a living. Adventure finds him when he ends up a stowaway on a boat heading to mysterious Muay Thai Island. There he learns martial arts, and, later in Tibet, meets the charming Lord Dobbs (Moore) and his assistant Smythe (McGee). It is around this time that Chris seeks to be involved in Ghan Geng, a secret underground fighting tournament. The winner gets a huge golden dragon, so Dobbs has a stake in Chris winning, as he wants the Dragon. Fighters are invited from all over the world , and America is represented by boxer Maxie Devine (Remar). Chris must take his place in the tournament and defeat the sinister Khan (Quissi) to win it all. Also, there's some mild romance with the prerequisite female reporter Carrie Newton (Gunn). Van Damme does a solid , professional job with his directional debut. Having co-written the film with Bloodsport (1988) dude Frank Dux, you pretty much know what to expect- but this movie is rated PG-13, so it was clearly trying to bring the Punchfighting genre some mainstream acceptance. With its slick Hollywood look and booming, sweeping score by Randy Edelman, the final product is perfect for 13-year olds, presumably its target demographic. Interestingly, the movie is a period piece, and plays like a prequel to Bloodsport. Instead of The Kumite, It's Ghan Geng. Van Damme tries on a number of personas from "Old Man Van Damme" to "Van Damme The Clown" and many things in between. The presence of Roger Moore adds class and respectability to the proceedings, and James Remar of Quiet Cool (1986) fame stands out as Devine. He's always worth seeing. Janet Gunn from Night Of The Running Man (1995) and The Sweeper (1996) is the eye candy but not much else. It's important to remember this was when video games like Mortal Kombat and Street Fighter were at the peak of their popularity. So when the Ghan Geng section of the movie begins (pretty much the last half)- the plot just STOPS. It's just one fighter from one country facing off against another fighter from another country. It gets repetitive and pretty numbing after awhile. Other Punchfighters don't do this. They vary the Punchfighting scenes with other plot-based stuff. Not so here. Plus the fact the movie is kind of on the long side doesn't help matters. What The Quest should have been is an 80 minute R-rated Punchfighter. Simply cutting the length but adding more violence would have helped immensely. But they weren't going for that audience, unfortunately. The Quest is more of a big "adventure" film where characters are seeking a "lost city" and many countries and time periods are represented. This might be a good way to start younger viewers on a career of watching Van Damme movies\action movies\Punchfighters but for adults. Only Van Damme or perhaps Roger Moore completists need apply. For more insanity, please visit: comeuppancereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where does Bloodsport end and The Quest begin...?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For a Jean Claude Van Damme movie, then "The Quest" is a fairly standard one. And if you have seen the 1988 "Bloodsport" movie, then you have essentially also seen "The Quest". And I don't think that it is a mere coincidence, especially since the story was written by Frank Dux and Jean Claude Van Damme. The story is about Christopher Dubois (played by Jean-Claude Van Damme) who is living on the streets, when he is forced to run for his life and ending up as a stowaway on a ship. When he comes to his senses, he is put into slavery, working on the ship. By sheer luck he is rescued by Lord Edgar Dobbs (played by Roger Moore) and Harry Smythe (played by Jack McGee), two thieves and con artists. Setting out to steal a massive golden dragon in a reclusive and secret fighting tournament, Christoper Dubois finds himself fighting on behalf of the boxer Maxie Devine (played by James Remar). Storywise, then "The Quest" focused more on the fights and action. And as in "Bloodsport", then there is lots of it, and the fight sequences are nicely executed and brought to the screen. The movie itself is as predictable as they come - but then again, aren't most of Jean Claude Van Damme's movies? There are so many similarities between "Bloodsport" and "The Quest", that you just sit there wondering why "The Quest" was actually ever put on film. Wasn't it enough with this story being told in 1988 back when "Bloodsport" came out? But as with virtually all of Jean Claude Van Damme's movies, the main focus is the action and fighting, and whatever story or resemblance of a story there is becomes secondary. Obviously you have the fighting tournament held in an exotic location, there was the bested friend of whom Van Damme takes a headband, there was a woman reporter, there was a massive and seemingly invincible opponent, and of course there is Jean Claude Van Damme as the underdog who swoops in and wins it all against all odds. That being said, then "The Quest" is good entertainment where you don't have to use your brain at all. Funny, how I remembered this movie being much better back in the late 90's, when I remember my brother getting it on VHS. And after having obtained the DVD in 2013 and watched it again, it wasn't as cool as I remembered it to be. But still, fun and action-packed, a fairly standard Jean Claude Van Damme movie to be honest.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bloodsport's Second Best Remake !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before watching it, I have heard that it didn't do well in the box office, but I haven't known why. After watching it, that "why" wasn't hard to answer. It's so close to Bloodsport (1988), which was another movie starring Jean-Claude Van Damme, another movie inspired by martial artist Frank Dux's life and experiences, and another movie centers around a secret martial arts tournament. In fact, the similar points between the 2 movies are many; whereas a beautiful American she-journalist is on the lead's side, an earlier enmity happens between one of the contestants and the lead, a friend for the lead is cruelly beaten, let alone that the lead wins at last. True, they added an older time period, a character of a pirate who wants to steal gold, a situation where the lead proves his nobleness, but I felt I was watching the same movie again. At times, I thought that all of these differences was originally put just to mislead you that this is a remake of a movie done 8 years before ! The first half's writing is fine. It is thrilling, swiftly paced, and takes place in numerous lands. The lead gets from a trouble to another fascinatingly. And he's a human action hero, who has lost and poor child inside of him, and wants to save other lost and poor children, by doing the right thing. Though, in the second half, things weren't as fine. The American journalist didn't do anything (or say anything !). Aside from presenting such a totally extra character, this took a lot from the emotional side of the movie; making it badly concrete. The basis of the enmity between the Mongolian fighter and the lead was trivial (a conflict around a restaurant table !). When the Asian guy's son is killed, we don't get enthusiastic over the idea of how the lead must avenge him, because we weren't introduced to that character appropriately, and the script didn't make them, the lead and him, friends or even close from the start. And I didn't find any use out of the first and last scenes, where the lead was narrating his story as a very old man, sure they ended up as naive. Plus, it's hard to believe that 90 something guy can hit 2 punks that easily ! Van Damme's direction had its share of mistakes too. He overused the TV-ish close-ups, not doing much to hide the poor budget; in a movie that supposedly depends on impressive backgrounds, sets and costumes. Hence it has a medium TV pilot feel written all over it, especially with borrowed shots from richer movies ! I hated how Van Damme filmed the guy who announces the competitors before every match, by the same cadre and from the same angle, creating something between boring and funny. However, the bigger mistake can be felt in the fighting scenes. OH MY GOD, the action star did the action scenes wrongly. He suffered a hysteria which got to those scenes then to us, with too many various angles, stupidly fast cutting, and the most unnecessary slow-motion ever; which was being used every 10 seconds (as if Van Damme thought he was giving an illustrative lesson for martial arts students !). So the final result was annoying time, with nothing to concentrate on or watch. And by the way, Randy Edelman's music score seemed inane, and its fervent charge wasn't that fervent. The good points kind of compensate. The performance was so right. James Remar mastered that gallant fighter, having most of the lights for himself. Roger Moore was more than perfect as Lord futile swindler, being the best star to handle such a role, and the best relief this movie had. I loved discovering that he's a military captain-turned- pirate, which added much to his character beside his huge presence and genuine wit. I don't know why he considers The Quest his least favorite movie, since he has done worse (believe me, he has done a far far worse !). Van Damme looked tired, maybe due to his being behind and in front the camera in the same time. But he was more like Jackie Chan in some moments, managing to be a clueless child on a mission, and by that I mean a good thing. Casting all of those diverse martial arts champions was smart and interesting. The choreography of the climactic fight satisfied me the most. And the direction of Van Damme's fights outclassed all the rest's. The Quest is a B-grade B-movie. As a director, I didn't wait for more than that from Van Damme's side. And as an action hero, he provided his usual. Undoubtedly it has some entertainment value. But clearly it needed more to win the box office, or my A-grade rank, like less copied story and more good directing. This way it would have been anything better than Bloodsport's second best remake !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the epic Van Damme was aiming for. This is sadly, routine with uninspired fight scenes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Van Damme & Frank Dux collaborated together for this so called once in a lifetime project, hoping to make a classic Martial Arts film like of Bloodsport. Not only do they fail, but they created something that falls completely flat. I don't like criticizing Van Damme, as Van Damme is one of my all time favorite action heroes, but he has left me with no choice here. The movie tries to build up a deep relationship with Van Damme being trained in the art of Muay Thai. That ends as quickly as it begins, and it has no emotion what so ever. Van Damme clearly forgets this, and tries to recreate a key emotional scene in Bloodsport with Phang & Chris, but it has nowhere near the merit it had in Bloodsport, simply because The Quest failed to make me care like it should have. The fight choreography is a colossal disappointment. Van Damme who knows a thing or two about fighting, should know how to create an exciting fight, right? Wrong. The fights couldn't be more mundane if they tried. The fighters themselves have the repertoire to make an exciting fight, but they were often squashes with flashes of brilliance that never lasted as long as I would have liked. The end fight is typical Van Damage. Which means he gets his ass kicked for most of it and makes the "impossible" comeback; it works in most Van Damme movies, but not here. It's over the top and ho-hum The cinematography is actually excellent. It's a sight to behold at times, and I felt they got the time period they were doing down pat. Van Damme doesn't display any of that natural charm that he is well known for, and gives a one-note performance here for the most part. Maybe it was because of his directing responsibilities, but he was shockingly dull a lot of the time. His acrobatics are good as usual, but that's it. Roger Moore shamefully mugs his way through the film, and looks a bit embarrassed to be here. I have read he considers this to be his worst film. While I felt this movie was very much average, and not that great, it's far from his worst. He's made a couple of James Bond films that are worse than this movie. It's a rather annoying performance that quickly made me intolerant. James Remar is amusing as Maxie Devine, but his role is poorly written. Janet Gunn doesn't have much of a part except to be easy on the eyes. Abdel Qissi makes for a formidable presence as the imposing baddie. I was also disappointed by the lack of Chris's background on his childhood. We see snippets of it, but not nearly enough. A more thought out movie would have been really nice, but this is not the case. This is stuff I consider to be rather fruitful Final Thoughts: It's watchable, but nothing more. Considering the epic he was going for in his directional debut, I highly doubt he had such a watered down retread of The Bloodsport in mind. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's a reason why JCVD and James Bond haven't worked together again - 43%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Scrolling through the TV schedules as I often do, it's a rare film indeed that makes me stop and think about recording it. But how can anyone not be intrigued by "a period action adventure with Jean-Claude Van Damme and Roger Moore" - sure, it wouldn't be likely to change the world but what a line-up! My masochistic side pricking my conscious, I duly recording this and settled down today to watch what must be the strangest piece of casting I think I've ever seen. The Muscles From Brussels plays Chris Dubois, a ragamuffin street thief operating a child gang on the streets of New York in 1925. But after one daring escape from the police too many, Dubois inadvertently stows away and finds himself far from home and at the mercy of vicious pirates. Eventually, he is rescued by dashing British adventurer Lord Dobbs (Moore) and his partner-in-crime Smythe (Jack McGee) and they agree to help Dubois return to America. But Dobbs betrays Dubois and leaves him stranded in the Muay Thai Islands where his adventures really begin. He soon finds himself thrown into a global fighting tournament against the best in the world but as his paths cross with fellow Americans Maxie Devine (James Remar) and journalist Carrie Newton (Janet Gunn), Dubois realises he must win the tournament or risk all their futures... I can't comment on this film's similarity with the earlier "Bloodsport" because that film has somehow passed me by. What I will comment on is the alarming similarity to another Van Damme flick, the frankly forgettable "AWOL: Absent Without Leave". I can't help but feel that for his directorial debut, Van Damme should have stretched himself a bit more beyond the tired "fighting tournament" plot. He probably was too busy dominating proceedings - once the film's second half begins, the fighting takes over completely and dialogue fades into the odd shout and macho grunt. Yes, there are odd bits and pieces of plot to get through such as the moment when an opponent makes an enemy of Dubois and we then know who's gonna get beaten up last. It's as though JCVD felt that the cast weren't trying and decided to run the rest of the film himself. And to be honest, he may have a point - other than Moore, the rest of the cast disappear into the background like early morning fog. As does the plot - can anyone tell me why Devine hung around for so long or what exactly was the story Newton felt she had to chase? I couldn't find one to last the 95 minutes of this movie, let alone a Pulitzer prize. I could go on but you get the picture. "The Quest" is an unremarkable and deeply formulaic martial arts movie that reminds us why JCVD now spends his days selling Coors. It's poorly directed with lots of needless slow motion, incoherent and offers little surprises other than the bizarre combination of its two lead stars. It also feels very dated and that's nothing to do with its period setting - this film comes five years after the likes of "Terminator 2: Judgement Day" which is a quantum leap ahead in terms of story-telling, set pieces, special effects and performances. Van Damme has made decent enough movies in the past - I recommend the likes of "Universal Soldier" or "Sudden Death" - but this really isn't one of them. A Damme shame, then. And just what was the point of the whole thing being a flash-back?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speculation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cam Cloutier
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoy Van Damme's films occasionally, especially "Time Cop". Of his films, I consider this one of his worst, but that rating is purely from a technical vantage. A genuine martial artist is like anyone else when they go to the movies. They expect to see only fiction. The same is true even of martial arts action flics. Even if the choreographer and stars know their business, it's goosed up for entertainment purposes. Nevertheless, the discerning eye seeks a few gems, to see if the martial artists involved in the film's production at least cast a brief nod of respect to the art. In "The Quest", that nod is within the first 15 minutes of the movie: when an aging hero defends himself with his cane. The cane techniques are marvelous and entertaining and, suffice to say, a rarity in Hollywood kung fu cinema. Afterwards, it's typical dreck. Worse, as a long-time practitioner of Okinawan karate, I was mildly insulted by the portrayal of the "champion of karate" in the final segment of the film. One can only speculate why the producers (which included Van Damme) would show such a buffoon. We can go positive or negative in our speculation. Positively, we can say that Van Damme nodded in respect to the real masters of karate who, in the film's period time, were among the deadliest men who have EVER LIVED (Choki Motobu, Kanryo Higashionna, Itoman Bunkichi, Miyagi Chojun, to list but a few). Such men, though competitive, would have either not heard of the tournament or snubbed it. Negatively, we might say that Van Damme's Shotokan upbringing had rendered him oblivious to karate that was not watered down for schoolchildren (and a system that didn't even exist in the film's period; Funakoshi was only getting started teaching in Japan at that time). That would also be in line with many others' contemporary views of karate, common nowadays in the MMA, ever since the Gracies issued their silly challenge and no -real- karateka deigned to answer them. The sight of a karateka trying to side kick a sumo wrestler in the belly should make anyone twitch, unless they already nurse a profound (or ignorant) bias against real karate. I found the film otherwise tolerable if typical of Van Damme's work and of cinema of the 80s/90s generally.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoy Christmas in the lost city.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Duboir is Kidnapped and enslaved by gun smugglers, sold by pirates and thrust into the murky underworld of gambling and kick-boxing. His journey takes him to Muay Thai Island where martial arts are taught, and finally, the ancient Lost City. There he must face the ultimate test of his manhood in the ancient winner-take-all competition in which the deadliest fighters from around the world employ the most spectacular feats of martial arts skills ever displayed in order to win the prized Golden Dragon. But fighting prowess alone will not be enough for him to triumph over such daunting foes. He must reach deep inside and access all of the determination, strength of character and sense of selfless honour within in order to triumph over this final obstacle..... When Van Damme met Bond is a really strange movie to watch and probably not the best Van Damme film to start with. It's basically a retread of Bloodsport, set in a different time and location, with added Roger Moore. And while it's nowhere near as good as that movie, it's pretty darn good, and beautiful to look at. Van Damme is competent behind the camera, and even thought the main action of the film is your typical video game style beat em' up, the characters are rich and a little bit different. Van Damme is good, and Moore looks uncomfortable, but it's Van Dammes Baby, and he really tries hard with this. Plus, he gets to fight the bloke from Hot Chocolate at the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the James Bond 007 series celebrating its 50th anniversary because of Dr. No, and the third actor to play the famous spy role getting about a lot at the time, it made sense to me to see some of his films before and after Bond, so I found this one, the directorial debut from Jean-Claude Van Damme. Basically an old man is telling a story to a bartender after getting into a fight, and we flashback to this man younger, Christopher Dubois (Van Damme), a pickpocket living in 1925 New York who was orphaned as a child and runs a gang of orphan children pickpockets who also con and steal to get by. They get found by gangsters but Dubois manages to get away, but he does get the attention of the police as well, but he promises to return to the children before stowing away on a boat, but he is found by the crew and forced to be a slave by the pirates aboard. He is saved a few years later by mercenary Englishman Lord Edgar Dobbs (Sir Roger Moore) who agrees to help him get home to America, but in fact he sells him off as a slave on the island of Siam where he gets trained in Muay Thai fighting for a scheme that is coming up. Six months pass and Dobbs with his partner Harry Smythe (Jack McGee) are shocked to see Dubois fighting in the Muay Thai fighting ring, but they see he has become a skilled fighter, so they buy his freedom so that he will represent the USA in the Ghang-Gheng worldwide fighting tournament held in the Lost City of Tibet. Other countries competing in the global event include China, Japan, Germany, Brazil, France, Turkey, Greece, Spain, Africa, Korea, Soviet Union (Russia) and Scotland, all are eliminated round by round, and at the end of the tournament the winning country will receive the prestigious and valuable statue the Golden Dragon. As the contest goes on Dubois gets to know American reporter Carrie Newton (Janet Gunn) and heavyweight boxing champion Maxie Devine (James Remar) who give him advice and tips, and after winning against apposing countries the biggest challenge comes in the final round when he faces Khan the Mongolian Fighter (Abdel Qissi) who is savage. At the end Dubois ultimately wins the tournament, and refusing the Golden Dragon he wins the freedom of his friends Dobbs and Smythe who were sentenced to death after they tried to steal the golden statue, he returned to New York and got the children off the streets, Devine trained great fighters in his future, Dobbs and Smythe went deep into the Amazon to open a trading post, and Carrie wrote the story of everything called The Quest. Also starring Aki Aleong as Khao, Louis Mandylor as Riggi, Chang Ching Peng Chaplin as Master Tchi, Ryan Cutrona as Officer O'Keefe, Peter Wong as Chinese Fighter, Kitao Koji as Sumo Wrestler, Habby Heske as German Fighter, C&eacute;sar Carneiro as Brazilian Fighter, Takis Triggelis as French Fighter, Azdine Nouri as Turkish Fighter, Stefanos Miltsakakis as Greek Fighter, Peter Malota as Spanish Fighter, Winston Ellis as African Fighter, Ong Soo Han as Korean Fighter, Brick Bronsky as Russian Fighter, Ip Choi Nam as Korean Fighter and Mike Lambert as Scottish Fighter. Van Damme is relatively interesting as the pickpocket turned strong fighter, I will be honest and say that I was paying more attention to Moore though with his charming mannerisms and overall English good nature, I have only seen a few of Van Damme's films, many of them are meant to be involving fighting, so as one of them this is I suppose a good enough one, the story is simple enough and the fight sequences are certainly gripping, it is an alright martial arts action adventure. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Predictable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jennifer Fode
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say! Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say! Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jonathanruano
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Quest" does not know what kind of movie it wants to be - a version of "Oliver Twist," a pirate movie, a film about Muay Thai training, or another "Bloodsport" - and so it covers all these elements at once and does so badly, rather than focusing on one element and doing it well. When I saw "The Quest," I was impressed by the cinematography which seems reminiscent in a way of those great epic films of the 1950s and 1960s. Yet at the same time, I was bored with the film because the vast majority of its ideas seemed to be half-baked. If you want to do a film with multiple plots, like the "Crying Game" did, then what you need is an brilliant film director and excellent screen writers who know what they are doing. Yet Jean Claude Van Damme seems way over his head in his directorial debut. He knows how to film gorgeous looking scenes, but he cannot bring the various elements of film-making together into one coherent narrative. "The Quest" looks like an array of elements thrown together haphazardly in the hope that they would amount to something, but they do not. In the opening scenes, Jean Claude Van Damme plays a clown with stilts against a richly layered backdrop of a 1920s city coupled with a hideaway with thieving boys which is reminiscent of Fagin's lair from the film "Oliver Twist." Then we have scenes that appear, at least on the surface, to come straight out of the movie "Treasure Island"(1954) which includes its pirate ship. This is followed by another epic scene with Muay Thai fighters training on the beach while large waves are crashing against the shore. Then we see Jean Claude Van Damme and company travelling through Asia on elephants and then horses en route to a temple in the snowy mountains of Tibet. But do all these scenes amount to anything? Actually no, because none of these ideas are fully developed and imbued with meaning. The other problem is with the acting. A film that tries to cover as much ground as "The Quest" does needs capable (probably even gifted) actors to convey its material well. But Jean Claude Van Damme, with his poor acting abilities, seems like an uncomfortable fit as the film's protagonist. Van Damme is much more suited for laid-back, easy going, macho films, like Bloodsport and Kickboxer, where you can excuse the bad acting (and laugh at it) and have a good time. But in "The Quest," the sets upstage Van Damme, making him look small and insignificant. You really need someone with Eroll Flynn or Peter O'Toole's stature (when they were young) to carry a quasi-swashbuckling film, like "The Quest," forward in a convincing way. Roger Moore is a more experienced actor, but he merely reprises his dull cornball James Bond role as the pirate captain and (like his James Bond character) his performance just doesn't work. Although Robert Newton's Captain Silver character has become a clich&eacute;, I would have preferred that type of pirate captain rather than the one depicted by Roger Moore. Towards the end, Van Damme switches gears and creates another version of "Bloodsport" with its Hollywood formulae. He seems to be more comfortable with this material (especially since it requires him to do the martial arts that he knows so well), which explains why the martial arts sequences in the last 30-40 minutes of this film are reasonably entertaining. Those martial arts sequences are not, unfortunately, as good as the ones in Bloodsport which had better choreography and a great music soundtrack by composer Paul Hertzog. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only Van Damme or perhaps Roger Moore completists need apply.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Comeuppance Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set in the 1920's, Chris Dubois (Van Damme) is a street performer who wears clown makeup, a funny hat, and walks on stilts for a living. Adventure finds him when he ends up a stowaway on a boat heading to mysterious Muay Thai Island. There he learns martial arts, and, later in Tibet, meets the charming Lord Dobbs (Moore) and his assistant Smythe (McGee). It is around this time that Chris seeks to be involved in Ghan Geng, a secret underground fighting tournament. The winner gets a huge golden dragon, so Dobbs has a stake in Chris winning, as he wants the Dragon. Fighters are invited from all over the world , and America is represented by boxer Maxie Devine (Remar). Chris must take his place in the tournament and defeat the sinister Khan (Quissi) to win it all. Also, there's some mild romance with the prerequisite female reporter Carrie Newton (Gunn). Van Damme does a solid , professional job with his directional debut. Having co-written the film with Bloodsport (1988) dude Frank Dux, you pretty much know what to expect- but this movie is rated PG-13, so it was clearly trying to bring the Punchfighting genre some mainstream acceptance. With its slick Hollywood look and booming, sweeping score by Randy Edelman, the final product is perfect for 13-year olds, presumably its target demographic. Interestingly, the movie is a period piece, and plays like a prequel to Bloodsport. Instead of The Kumite, It's Ghan Geng. Van Damme tries on a number of personas from "Old Man Van Damme" to "Van Damme The Clown" and many things in between. The presence of Roger Moore adds class and respectability to the proceedings, and James Remar of Quiet Cool (1986) fame stands out as Devine. He's always worth seeing. Janet Gunn from Night Of The Running Man (1995) and The Sweeper (1996) is the eye candy but not much else. It's important to remember this was when video games like Mortal Kombat and Street Fighter were at the peak of their popularity. So when the Ghan Geng section of the movie begins (pretty much the last half)- the plot just STOPS. It's just one fighter from one country facing off against another fighter from another country. It gets repetitive and pretty numbing after awhile. Other Punchfighters don't do this. They vary the Punchfighting scenes with other plot-based stuff. Not so here. Plus the fact the movie is kind of on the long side doesn't help matters. What The Quest should have been is an 80 minute R-rated Punchfighter. Simply cutting the length but adding more violence would have helped immensely. But they weren't going for that audience, unfortunately. The Quest is more of a big "adventure" film where characters are seeking a "lost city" and many countries and time periods are represented. This might be a good way to start younger viewers on a career of watching Van Damme movies\action movies\Punchfighters but for adults. Only Van Damme or perhaps Roger Moore completists need apply. For more insanity, please visit: comeuppancereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where does Bloodsport end and The Quest begin...?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For a Jean Claude Van Damme movie, then "The Quest" is a fairly standard one. And if you have seen the 1988 "Bloodsport" movie, then you have essentially also seen "The Quest". And I don't think that it is a mere coincidence, especially since the story was written by Frank Dux and Jean Claude Van Damme. The story is about Christopher Dubois (played by Jean-Claude Van Damme) who is living on the streets, when he is forced to run for his life and ending up as a stowaway on a ship. When he comes to his senses, he is put into slavery, working on the ship. By sheer luck he is rescued by Lord Edgar Dobbs (played by Roger Moore) and Harry Smythe (played by Jack McGee), two thieves and con artists. Setting out to steal a massive golden dragon in a reclusive and secret fighting tournament, Christoper Dubois finds himself fighting on behalf of the boxer Maxie Devine (played by James Remar). Storywise, then "The Quest" focused more on the fights and action. And as in "Bloodsport", then there is lots of it, and the fight sequences are nicely executed and brought to the screen. The movie itself is as predictable as they come - but then again, aren't most of Jean Claude Van Damme's movies? There are so many similarities between "Bloodsport" and "The Quest", that you just sit there wondering why "The Quest" was actually ever put on film. Wasn't it enough with this story being told in 1988 back when "Bloodsport" came out? But as with virtually all of Jean Claude Van Damme's movies, the main focus is the action and fighting, and whatever story or resemblance of a story there is becomes secondary. Obviously you have the fighting tournament held in an exotic location, there was the bested friend of whom Van Damme takes a headband, there was a woman reporter, there was a massive and seemingly invincible opponent, and of course there is Jean Claude Van Damme as the underdog who swoops in and wins it all against all odds. That being said, then "The Quest" is good entertainment where you don't have to use your brain at all. Funny, how I remembered this movie being much better back in the late 90's, when I remember my brother getting it on VHS. And after having obtained the DVD in 2013 and watched it again, it wasn't as cool as I remembered it to be. But still, fun and action-packed, a fairly standard Jean Claude Van Damme movie to be honest.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bloodsport's Second Best Remake !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before watching it, I have heard that it didn't do well in the box office, but I haven't known why. After watching it, that "why" wasn't hard to answer. It's so close to Bloodsport (1988), which was another movie starring Jean-Claude Van Damme, another movie inspired by martial artist Frank Dux's life and experiences, and another movie centers around a secret martial arts tournament. In fact, the similar points between the 2 movies are many; whereas a beautiful American she-journalist is on the lead's side, an earlier enmity happens between one of the contestants and the lead, a friend for the lead is cruelly beaten, let alone that the lead wins at last. True, they added an older time period, a character of a pirate who wants to steal gold, a situation where the lead proves his nobleness, but I felt I was watching the same movie again. At times, I thought that all of these differences was originally put just to mislead you that this is a remake of a movie done 8 years before ! The first half's writing is fine. It is thrilling, swiftly paced, and takes place in numerous lands. The lead gets from a trouble to another fascinatingly. And he's a human action hero, who has lost and poor child inside of him, and wants to save other lost and poor children, by doing the right thing. Though, in the second half, things weren't as fine. The American journalist didn't do anything (or say anything !). Aside from presenting such a totally extra character, this took a lot from the emotional side of the movie; making it badly concrete. The basis of the enmity between the Mongolian fighter and the lead was trivial (a conflict around a restaurant table !). When the Asian guy's son is killed, we don't get enthusiastic over the idea of how the lead must avenge him, because we weren't introduced to that character appropriately, and the script didn't make them, the lead and him, friends or even close from the start. And I didn't find any use out of the first and last scenes, where the lead was narrating his story as a very old man, sure they ended up as naive. Plus, it's hard to believe that 90 something guy can hit 2 punks that easily ! Van Damme's direction had its share of mistakes too. He overused the TV-ish close-ups, not doing much to hide the poor budget; in a movie that supposedly depends on impressive backgrounds, sets and costumes. Hence it has a medium TV pilot feel written all over it, especially with borrowed shots from richer movies ! I hated how Van Damme filmed the guy who announces the competitors before every match, by the same cadre and from the same angle, creating something between boring and funny. However, the bigger mistake can be felt in the fighting scenes. OH MY GOD, the action star did the action scenes wrongly. He suffered a hysteria which got to those scenes then to us, with too many various angles, stupidly fast cutting, and the most unnecessary slow-motion ever; which was being used every 10 seconds (as if Van Damme thought he was giving an illustrative lesson for martial arts students !). So the final result was annoying time, with nothing to concentrate on or watch. And by the way, Randy Edelman's music score seemed inane, and its fervent charge wasn't that fervent. The good points kind of compensate. The performance was so right. James Remar mastered that gallant fighter, having most of the lights for himself. Roger Moore was more than perfect as Lord futile swindler, being the best star to handle such a role, and the best relief this movie had. I loved discovering that he's a military captain-turned- pirate, which added much to his character beside his huge presence and genuine wit. I don't know why he considers The Quest his least favorite movie, since he has done worse (believe me, he has done a far far worse !). Van Damme looked tired, maybe due to his being behind and in front the camera in the same time. But he was more like Jackie Chan in some moments, managing to be a clueless child on a mission, and by that I mean a good thing. Casting all of those diverse martial arts champions was smart and interesting. The choreography of the climactic fight satisfied me the most. And the direction of Van Damme's fights outclassed all the rest's. The Quest is a B-grade B-movie. As a director, I didn't wait for more than that from Van Damme's side. And as an action hero, he provided his usual. Undoubtedly it has some entertainment value. But clearly it needed more to win the box office, or my A-grade rank, like less copied story and more good directing. This way it would have been anything better than Bloodsport's second best remake !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the epic Van Damme was aiming for. This is sadly, routine with uninspired fight scenes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Van Damme & Frank Dux collaborated together for this so called once in a lifetime project, hoping to make a classic Martial Arts film like of Bloodsport. Not only do they fail, but they created something that falls completely flat. I don't like criticizing Van Damme, as Van Damme is one of my all time favorite action heroes, but he has left me with no choice here. The movie tries to build up a deep relationship with Van Damme being trained in the art of Muay Thai. That ends as quickly as it begins, and it has no emotion what so ever. Van Damme clearly forgets this, and tries to recreate a key emotional scene in Bloodsport with Phang & Chris, but it has nowhere near the merit it had in Bloodsport, simply because The Quest failed to make me care like it should have. The fight choreography is a colossal disappointment. Van Damme who knows a thing or two about fighting, should know how to create an exciting fight, right? Wrong. The fights couldn't be more mundane if they tried. The fighters themselves have the repertoire to make an exciting fight, but they were often squashes with flashes of brilliance that never lasted as long as I would have liked. The end fight is typical Van Damage. Which means he gets his ass kicked for most of it and makes the "impossible" comeback; it works in most Van Damme movies, but not here. It's over the top and ho-hum The cinematography is actually excellent. It's a sight to behold at times, and I felt they got the time period they were doing down pat. Van Damme doesn't display any of that natural charm that he is well known for, and gives a one-note performance here for the most part. Maybe it was because of his directing responsibilities, but he was shockingly dull a lot of the time. His acrobatics are good as usual, but that's it. Roger Moore shamefully mugs his way through the film, and looks a bit embarrassed to be here. I have read he considers this to be his worst film. While I felt this movie was very much average, and not that great, it's far from his worst. He's made a couple of James Bond films that are worse than this movie. It's a rather annoying performance that quickly made me intolerant. James Remar is amusing as Maxie Devine, but his role is poorly written. Janet Gunn doesn't have much of a part except to be easy on the eyes. Abdel Qissi makes for a formidable presence as the imposing baddie. I was also disappointed by the lack of Chris's background on his childhood. We see snippets of it, but not nearly enough. A more thought out movie would have been really nice, but this is not the case. This is stuff I consider to be rather fruitful Final Thoughts: It's watchable, but nothing more. Considering the epic he was going for in his directional debut, I highly doubt he had such a watered down retread of The Bloodsport in mind. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's a reason why JCVD and James Bond haven't worked together again - 43%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Scrolling through the TV schedules as I often do, it's a rare film indeed that makes me stop and think about recording it. But how can anyone not be intrigued by "a period action adventure with Jean-Claude Van Damme and Roger Moore" - sure, it wouldn't be likely to change the world but what a line-up! My masochistic side pricking my conscious, I duly recording this and settled down today to watch what must be the strangest piece of casting I think I've ever seen. The Muscles From Brussels plays Chris Dubois, a ragamuffin street thief operating a child gang on the streets of New York in 1925. But after one daring escape from the police too many, Dubois inadvertently stows away and finds himself far from home and at the mercy of vicious pirates. Eventually, he is rescued by dashing British adventurer Lord Dobbs (Moore) and his partner-in-crime Smythe (Jack McGee) and they agree to help Dubois return to America. But Dobbs betrays Dubois and leaves him stranded in the Muay Thai Islands where his adventures really begin. He soon finds himself thrown into a global fighting tournament against the best in the world but as his paths cross with fellow Americans Maxie Devine (James Remar) and journalist Carrie Newton (Janet Gunn), Dubois realises he must win the tournament or risk all their futures... I can't comment on this film's similarity with the earlier "Bloodsport" because that film has somehow passed me by. What I will comment on is the alarming similarity to another Van Damme flick, the frankly forgettable "AWOL: Absent Without Leave". I can't help but feel that for his directorial debut, Van Damme should have stretched himself a bit more beyond the tired "fighting tournament" plot. He probably was too busy dominating proceedings - once the film's second half begins, the fighting takes over completely and dialogue fades into the odd shout and macho grunt. Yes, there are odd bits and pieces of plot to get through such as the moment when an opponent makes an enemy of Dubois and we then know who's gonna get beaten up last. It's as though JCVD felt that the cast weren't trying and decided to run the rest of the film himself. And to be honest, he may have a point - other than Moore, the rest of the cast disappear into the background like early morning fog. As does the plot - can anyone tell me why Devine hung around for so long or what exactly was the story Newton felt she had to chase? I couldn't find one to last the 95 minutes of this movie, let alone a Pulitzer prize. I could go on but you get the picture. "The Quest" is an unremarkable and deeply formulaic martial arts movie that reminds us why JCVD now spends his days selling Coors. It's poorly directed with lots of needless slow motion, incoherent and offers little surprises other than the bizarre combination of its two lead stars. It also feels very dated and that's nothing to do with its period setting - this film comes five years after the likes of "Terminator 2: Judgement Day" which is a quantum leap ahead in terms of story-telling, set pieces, special effects and performances. Van Damme has made decent enough movies in the past - I recommend the likes of "Universal Soldier" or "Sudden Death" - but this really isn't one of them. A Damme shame, then. And just what was the point of the whole thing being a flash-back?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speculation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cam Cloutier
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoy Van Damme's films occasionally, especially "Time Cop". Of his films, I consider this one of his worst, but that rating is purely from a technical vantage. A genuine martial artist is like anyone else when they go to the movies. They expect to see only fiction. The same is true even of martial arts action flics. Even if the choreographer and stars know their business, it's goosed up for entertainment purposes. Nevertheless, the discerning eye seeks a few gems, to see if the martial artists involved in the film's production at least cast a brief nod of respect to the art. In "The Quest", that nod is within the first 15 minutes of the movie: when an aging hero defends himself with his cane. The cane techniques are marvelous and entertaining and, suffice to say, a rarity in Hollywood kung fu cinema. Afterwards, it's typical dreck. Worse, as a long-time practitioner of Okinawan karate, I was mildly insulted by the portrayal of the "champion of karate" in the final segment of the film. One can only speculate why the producers (which included Van Damme) would show such a buffoon. We can go positive or negative in our speculation. Positively, we can say that Van Damme nodded in respect to the real masters of karate who, in the film's period time, were among the deadliest men who have EVER LIVED (Choki Motobu, Kanryo Higashionna, Itoman Bunkichi, Miyagi Chojun, to list but a few). Such men, though competitive, would have either not heard of the tournament or snubbed it. Negatively, we might say that Van Damme's Shotokan upbringing had rendered him oblivious to karate that was not watered down for schoolchildren (and a system that didn't even exist in the film's period; Funakoshi was only getting started teaching in Japan at that time). That would also be in line with many others' contemporary views of karate, common nowadays in the MMA, ever since the Gracies issued their silly challenge and no -real- karateka deigned to answer them. The sight of a karateka trying to side kick a sumo wrestler in the belly should make anyone twitch, unless they already nurse a profound (or ignorant) bias against real karate. I found the film otherwise tolerable if typical of Van Damme's work and of cinema of the 80s/90s generally.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoy Christmas in the lost city.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Duboir is Kidnapped and enslaved by gun smugglers, sold by pirates and thrust into the murky underworld of gambling and kick-boxing. His journey takes him to Muay Thai Island where martial arts are taught, and finally, the ancient Lost City. There he must face the ultimate test of his manhood in the ancient winner-take-all competition in which the deadliest fighters from around the world employ the most spectacular feats of martial arts skills ever displayed in order to win the prized Golden Dragon. But fighting prowess alone will not be enough for him to triumph over such daunting foes. He must reach deep inside and access all of the determination, strength of character and sense of selfless honour within in order to triumph over this final obstacle..... When Van Damme met Bond is a really strange movie to watch and probably not the best Van Damme film to start with. It's basically a retread of Bloodsport, set in a different time and location, with added Roger Moore. And while it's nowhere near as good as that movie, it's pretty darn good, and beautiful to look at. Van Damme is competent behind the camera, and even thought the main action of the film is your typical video game style beat em' up, the characters are rich and a little bit different. Van Damme is good, and Moore looks uncomfortable, but it's Van Dammes Baby, and he really tries hard with this. Plus, he gets to fight the bloke from Hot Chocolate at the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the James Bond 007 series celebrating its 50th anniversary because of Dr. No, and the third actor to play the famous spy role getting about a lot at the time, it made sense to me to see some of his films before and after Bond, so I found this one, the directorial debut from Jean-Claude Van Damme. Basically an old man is telling a story to a bartender after getting into a fight, and we flashback to this man younger, Christopher Dubois (Van Damme), a pickpocket living in 1925 New York who was orphaned as a child and runs a gang of orphan children pickpockets who also con and steal to get by. They get found by gangsters but Dubois manages to get away, but he does get the attention of the police as well, but he promises to return to the children before stowing away on a boat, but he is found by the crew and forced to be a slave by the pirates aboard. He is saved a few years later by mercenary Englishman Lord Edgar Dobbs (Sir Roger Moore) who agrees to help him get home to America, but in fact he sells him off as a slave on the island of Siam where he gets trained in Muay Thai fighting for a scheme that is coming up. Six months pass and Dobbs with his partner Harry Smythe (Jack McGee) are shocked to see Dubois fighting in the Muay Thai fighting ring, but they see he has become a skilled fighter, so they buy his freedom so that he will represent the USA in the Ghang-Gheng worldwide fighting tournament held in the Lost City of Tibet. Other countries competing in the global event include China, Japan, Germany, Brazil, France, Turkey, Greece, Spain, Africa, Korea, Soviet Union (Russia) and Scotland, all are eliminated round by round, and at the end of the tournament the winning country will receive the prestigious and valuable statue the Golden Dragon. As the contest goes on Dubois gets to know American reporter Carrie Newton (Janet Gunn) and heavyweight boxing champion Maxie Devine (James Remar) who give him advice and tips, and after winning against apposing countries the biggest challenge comes in the final round when he faces Khan the Mongolian Fighter (Abdel Qissi) who is savage. At the end Dubois ultimately wins the tournament, and refusing the Golden Dragon he wins the freedom of his friends Dobbs and Smythe who were sentenced to death after they tried to steal the golden statue, he returned to New York and got the children off the streets, Devine trained great fighters in his future, Dobbs and Smythe went deep into the Amazon to open a trading post, and Carrie wrote the story of everything called The Quest. Also starring Aki Aleong as Khao, Louis Mandylor as Riggi, Chang Ching Peng Chaplin as Master Tchi, Ryan Cutrona as Officer O'Keefe, Peter Wong as Chinese Fighter, Kitao Koji as Sumo Wrestler, Habby Heske as German Fighter, C&eacute;sar Carneiro as Brazilian Fighter, Takis Triggelis as French Fighter, Azdine Nouri as Turkish Fighter, Stefanos Miltsakakis as Greek Fighter, Peter Malota as Spanish Fighter, Winston Ellis as African Fighter, Ong Soo Han as Korean Fighter, Brick Bronsky as Russian Fighter, Ip Choi Nam as Korean Fighter and Mike Lambert as Scottish Fighter. Van Damme is relatively interesting as the pickpocket turned strong fighter, I will be honest and say that I was paying more attention to Moore though with his charming mannerisms and overall English good nature, I have only seen a few of Van Damme's films, many of them are meant to be involving fighting, so as one of them this is I suppose a good enough one, the story is simple enough and the fight sequences are certainly gripping, it is an alright martial arts action adventure. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Predictable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jennifer Fode
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say! Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say! Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jonathanruano
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Quest" does not know what kind of movie it wants to be - a version of "Oliver Twist," a pirate movie, a film about Muay Thai training, or another "Bloodsport" - and so it covers all these elements at once and does so badly, rather than focusing on one element and doing it well. When I saw "The Quest," I was impressed by the cinematography which seems reminiscent in a way of those great epic films of the 1950s and 1960s. Yet at the same time, I was bored with the film because the vast majority of its ideas seemed to be half-baked. If you want to do a film with multiple plots, like the "Crying Game" did, then what you need is an brilliant film director and excellent screen writers who know what they are doing. Yet Jean Claude Van Damme seems way over his head in his directorial debut. He knows how to film gorgeous looking scenes, but he cannot bring the various elements of film-making together into one coherent narrative. "The Quest" looks like an array of elements thrown together haphazardly in the hope that they would amount to something, but they do not. In the opening scenes, Jean Claude Van Damme plays a clown with stilts against a richly layered backdrop of a 1920s city coupled with a hideaway with thieving boys which is reminiscent of Fagin's lair from the film "Oliver Twist." Then we have scenes that appear, at least on the surface, to come straight out of the movie "Treasure Island"(1954) which includes its pirate ship. This is followed by another epic scene with Muay Thai fighters training on the beach while large waves are crashing against the shore. Then we see Jean Claude Van Damme and company travelling through Asia on elephants and then horses en route to a temple in the snowy mountains of Tibet. But do all these scenes amount to anything? Actually no, because none of these ideas are fully developed and imbued with meaning. The other problem is with the acting. A film that tries to cover as much ground as "The Quest" does needs capable (probably even gifted) actors to convey its material well. But Jean Claude Van Damme, with his poor acting abilities, seems like an uncomfortable fit as the film's protagonist. Van Damme is much more suited for laid-back, easy going, macho films, like Bloodsport and Kickboxer, where you can excuse the bad acting (and laugh at it) and have a good time. But in "The Quest," the sets upstage Van Damme, making him look small and insignificant. You really need someone with Eroll Flynn or Peter O'Toole's stature (when they were young) to carry a quasi-swashbuckling film, like "The Quest," forward in a convincing way. Roger Moore is a more experienced actor, but he merely reprises his dull cornball James Bond role as the pirate captain and (like his James Bond character) his performance just doesn't work. Although Robert Newton's Captain Silver character has become a clich&eacute;, I would have preferred that type of pirate captain rather than the one depicted by Roger Moore. Towards the end, Van Damme switches gears and creates another version of "Bloodsport" with its Hollywood formulae. He seems to be more comfortable with this material (especially since it requires him to do the martial arts that he knows so well), which explains why the martial arts sequences in the last 30-40 minutes of this film are reasonably entertaining. Those martial arts sequences are not, unfortunately, as good as the ones in Bloodsport which had better choreography and a great music soundtrack by composer Paul Hertzog. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only Van Damme or perhaps Roger Moore completists need apply.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Comeuppance Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set in the 1920's, Chris Dubois (Van Damme) is a street performer who wears clown makeup, a funny hat, and walks on stilts for a living. Adventure finds him when he ends up a stowaway on a boat heading to mysterious Muay Thai Island. There he learns martial arts, and, later in Tibet, meets the charming Lord Dobbs (Moore) and his assistant Smythe (McGee). It is around this time that Chris seeks to be involved in Ghan Geng, a secret underground fighting tournament. The winner gets a huge golden dragon, so Dobbs has a stake in Chris winning, as he wants the Dragon. Fighters are invited from all over the world , and America is represented by boxer Maxie Devine (Remar). Chris must take his place in the tournament and defeat the sinister Khan (Quissi) to win it all. Also, there's some mild romance with the prerequisite female reporter Carrie Newton (Gunn). Van Damme does a solid , professional job with his directional debut. Having co-written the film with Bloodsport (1988) dude Frank Dux, you pretty much know what to expect- but this movie is rated PG-13, so it was clearly trying to bring the Punchfighting genre some mainstream acceptance. With its slick Hollywood look and booming, sweeping score by Randy Edelman, the final product is perfect for 13-year olds, presumably its target demographic. Interestingly, the movie is a period piece, and plays like a prequel to Bloodsport. Instead of The Kumite, It's Ghan Geng. Van Damme tries on a number of personas from "Old Man Van Damme" to "Van Damme The Clown" and many things in between. The presence of Roger Moore adds class and respectability to the proceedings, and James Remar of Quiet Cool (1986) fame stands out as Devine. He's always worth seeing. Janet Gunn from Night Of The Running Man (1995) and The Sweeper (1996) is the eye candy but not much else. It's important to remember this was when video games like Mortal Kombat and Street Fighter were at the peak of their popularity. So when the Ghan Geng section of the movie begins (pretty much the last half)- the plot just STOPS. It's just one fighter from one country facing off against another fighter from another country. It gets repetitive and pretty numbing after awhile. Other Punchfighters don't do this. They vary the Punchfighting scenes with other plot-based stuff. Not so here. Plus the fact the movie is kind of on the long side doesn't help matters. What The Quest should have been is an 80 minute R-rated Punchfighter. Simply cutting the length but adding more violence would have helped immensely. But they weren't going for that audience, unfortunately. The Quest is more of a big "adventure" film where characters are seeking a "lost city" and many countries and time periods are represented. This might be a good way to start younger viewers on a career of watching Van Damme movies\action movies\Punchfighters but for adults. Only Van Damme or perhaps Roger Moore completists need apply. For more insanity, please visit: comeuppancereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where does Bloodsport end and The Quest begin...?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For a Jean Claude Van Damme movie, then "The Quest" is a fairly standard one. And if you have seen the 1988 "Bloodsport" movie, then you have essentially also seen "The Quest". And I don't think that it is a mere coincidence, especially since the story was written by Frank Dux and Jean Claude Van Damme. The story is about Christopher Dubois (played by Jean-Claude Van Damme) who is living on the streets, when he is forced to run for his life and ending up as a stowaway on a ship. When he comes to his senses, he is put into slavery, working on the ship. By sheer luck he is rescued by Lord Edgar Dobbs (played by Roger Moore) and Harry Smythe (played by Jack McGee), two thieves and con artists. Setting out to steal a massive golden dragon in a reclusive and secret fighting tournament, Christoper Dubois finds himself fighting on behalf of the boxer Maxie Devine (played by James Remar). Storywise, then "The Quest" focused more on the fights and action. And as in "Bloodsport", then there is lots of it, and the fight sequences are nicely executed and brought to the screen. The movie itself is as predictable as they come - but then again, aren't most of Jean Claude Van Damme's movies? There are so many similarities between "Bloodsport" and "The Quest", that you just sit there wondering why "The Quest" was actually ever put on film. Wasn't it enough with this story being told in 1988 back when "Bloodsport" came out? But as with virtually all of Jean Claude Van Damme's movies, the main focus is the action and fighting, and whatever story or resemblance of a story there is becomes secondary. Obviously you have the fighting tournament held in an exotic location, there was the bested friend of whom Van Damme takes a headband, there was a woman reporter, there was a massive and seemingly invincible opponent, and of course there is Jean Claude Van Damme as the underdog who swoops in and wins it all against all odds. That being said, then "The Quest" is good entertainment where you don't have to use your brain at all. Funny, how I remembered this movie being much better back in the late 90's, when I remember my brother getting it on VHS. And after having obtained the DVD in 2013 and watched it again, it wasn't as cool as I remembered it to be. But still, fun and action-packed, a fairly standard Jean Claude Van Damme movie to be honest.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bloodsport's Second Best Remake !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before watching it, I have heard that it didn't do well in the box office, but I haven't known why. After watching it, that "why" wasn't hard to answer. It's so close to Bloodsport (1988), which was another movie starring Jean-Claude Van Damme, another movie inspired by martial artist Frank Dux's life and experiences, and another movie centers around a secret martial arts tournament. In fact, the similar points between the 2 movies are many; whereas a beautiful American she-journalist is on the lead's side, an earlier enmity happens between one of the contestants and the lead, a friend for the lead is cruelly beaten, let alone that the lead wins at last. True, they added an older time period, a character of a pirate who wants to steal gold, a situation where the lead proves his nobleness, but I felt I was watching the same movie again. At times, I thought that all of these differences was originally put just to mislead you that this is a remake of a movie done 8 years before ! The first half's writing is fine. It is thrilling, swiftly paced, and takes place in numerous lands. The lead gets from a trouble to another fascinatingly. And he's a human action hero, who has lost and poor child inside of him, and wants to save other lost and poor children, by doing the right thing. Though, in the second half, things weren't as fine. The American journalist didn't do anything (or say anything !). Aside from presenting such a totally extra character, this took a lot from the emotional side of the movie; making it badly concrete. The basis of the enmity between the Mongolian fighter and the lead was trivial (a conflict around a restaurant table !). When the Asian guy's son is killed, we don't get enthusiastic over the idea of how the lead must avenge him, because we weren't introduced to that character appropriately, and the script didn't make them, the lead and him, friends or even close from the start. And I didn't find any use out of the first and last scenes, where the lead was narrating his story as a very old man, sure they ended up as naive. Plus, it's hard to believe that 90 something guy can hit 2 punks that easily ! Van Damme's direction had its share of mistakes too. He overused the TV-ish close-ups, not doing much to hide the poor budget; in a movie that supposedly depends on impressive backgrounds, sets and costumes. Hence it has a medium TV pilot feel written all over it, especially with borrowed shots from richer movies ! I hated how Van Damme filmed the guy who announces the competitors before every match, by the same cadre and from the same angle, creating something between boring and funny. However, the bigger mistake can be felt in the fighting scenes. OH MY GOD, the action star did the action scenes wrongly. He suffered a hysteria which got to those scenes then to us, with too many various angles, stupidly fast cutting, and the most unnecessary slow-motion ever; which was being used every 10 seconds (as if Van Damme thought he was giving an illustrative lesson for martial arts students !). So the final result was annoying time, with nothing to concentrate on or watch. And by the way, Randy Edelman's music score seemed inane, and its fervent charge wasn't that fervent. The good points kind of compensate. The performance was so right. James Remar mastered that gallant fighter, having most of the lights for himself. Roger Moore was more than perfect as Lord futile swindler, being the best star to handle such a role, and the best relief this movie had. I loved discovering that he's a military captain-turned- pirate, which added much to his character beside his huge presence and genuine wit. I don't know why he considers The Quest his least favorite movie, since he has done worse (believe me, he has done a far far worse !). Van Damme looked tired, maybe due to his being behind and in front the camera in the same time. But he was more like Jackie Chan in some moments, managing to be a clueless child on a mission, and by that I mean a good thing. Casting all of those diverse martial arts champions was smart and interesting. The choreography of the climactic fight satisfied me the most. And the direction of Van Damme's fights outclassed all the rest's. The Quest is a B-grade B-movie. As a director, I didn't wait for more than that from Van Damme's side. And as an action hero, he provided his usual. Undoubtedly it has some entertainment value. But clearly it needed more to win the box office, or my A-grade rank, like less copied story and more good directing. This way it would have been anything better than Bloodsport's second best remake !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the epic Van Damme was aiming for. This is sadly, routine with uninspired fight scenes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Van Damme & Frank Dux collaborated together for this so called once in a lifetime project, hoping to make a classic Martial Arts film like of Bloodsport. Not only do they fail, but they created something that falls completely flat. I don't like criticizing Van Damme, as Van Damme is one of my all time favorite action heroes, but he has left me with no choice here. The movie tries to build up a deep relationship with Van Damme being trained in the art of Muay Thai. That ends as quickly as it begins, and it has no emotion what so ever. Van Damme clearly forgets this, and tries to recreate a key emotional scene in Bloodsport with Phang & Chris, but it has nowhere near the merit it had in Bloodsport, simply because The Quest failed to make me care like it should have. The fight choreography is a colossal disappointment. Van Damme who knows a thing or two about fighting, should know how to create an exciting fight, right? Wrong. The fights couldn't be more mundane if they tried. The fighters themselves have the repertoire to make an exciting fight, but they were often squashes with flashes of brilliance that never lasted as long as I would have liked. The end fight is typical Van Damage. Which means he gets his ass kicked for most of it and makes the "impossible" comeback; it works in most Van Damme movies, but not here. It's over the top and ho-hum The cinematography is actually excellent. It's a sight to behold at times, and I felt they got the time period they were doing down pat. Van Damme doesn't display any of that natural charm that he is well known for, and gives a one-note performance here for the most part. Maybe it was because of his directing responsibilities, but he was shockingly dull a lot of the time. His acrobatics are good as usual, but that's it. Roger Moore shamefully mugs his way through the film, and looks a bit embarrassed to be here. I have read he considers this to be his worst film. While I felt this movie was very much average, and not that great, it's far from his worst. He's made a couple of James Bond films that are worse than this movie. It's a rather annoying performance that quickly made me intolerant. James Remar is amusing as Maxie Devine, but his role is poorly written. Janet Gunn doesn't have much of a part except to be easy on the eyes. Abdel Qissi makes for a formidable presence as the imposing baddie. I was also disappointed by the lack of Chris's background on his childhood. We see snippets of it, but not nearly enough. A more thought out movie would have been really nice, but this is not the case. This is stuff I consider to be rather fruitful Final Thoughts: It's watchable, but nothing more. Considering the epic he was going for in his directional debut, I highly doubt he had such a watered down retread of The Bloodsport in mind. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's a reason why JCVD and James Bond haven't worked together again - 43%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Scrolling through the TV schedules as I often do, it's a rare film indeed that makes me stop and think about recording it. But how can anyone not be intrigued by "a period action adventure with Jean-Claude Van Damme and Roger Moore" - sure, it wouldn't be likely to change the world but what a line-up! My masochistic side pricking my conscious, I duly recording this and settled down today to watch what must be the strangest piece of casting I think I've ever seen. The Muscles From Brussels plays Chris Dubois, a ragamuffin street thief operating a child gang on the streets of New York in 1925. But after one daring escape from the police too many, Dubois inadvertently stows away and finds himself far from home and at the mercy of vicious pirates. Eventually, he is rescued by dashing British adventurer Lord Dobbs (Moore) and his partner-in-crime Smythe (Jack McGee) and they agree to help Dubois return to America. But Dobbs betrays Dubois and leaves him stranded in the Muay Thai Islands where his adventures really begin. He soon finds himself thrown into a global fighting tournament against the best in the world but as his paths cross with fellow Americans Maxie Devine (James Remar) and journalist Carrie Newton (Janet Gunn), Dubois realises he must win the tournament or risk all their futures... I can't comment on this film's similarity with the earlier "Bloodsport" because that film has somehow passed me by. What I will comment on is the alarming similarity to another Van Damme flick, the frankly forgettable "AWOL: Absent Without Leave". I can't help but feel that for his directorial debut, Van Damme should have stretched himself a bit more beyond the tired "fighting tournament" plot. He probably was too busy dominating proceedings - once the film's second half begins, the fighting takes over completely and dialogue fades into the odd shout and macho grunt. Yes, there are odd bits and pieces of plot to get through such as the moment when an opponent makes an enemy of Dubois and we then know who's gonna get beaten up last. It's as though JCVD felt that the cast weren't trying and decided to run the rest of the film himself. And to be honest, he may have a point - other than Moore, the rest of the cast disappear into the background like early morning fog. As does the plot - can anyone tell me why Devine hung around for so long or what exactly was the story Newton felt she had to chase? I couldn't find one to last the 95 minutes of this movie, let alone a Pulitzer prize. I could go on but you get the picture. "The Quest" is an unremarkable and deeply formulaic martial arts movie that reminds us why JCVD now spends his days selling Coors. It's poorly directed with lots of needless slow motion, incoherent and offers little surprises other than the bizarre combination of its two lead stars. It also feels very dated and that's nothing to do with its period setting - this film comes five years after the likes of "Terminator 2: Judgement Day" which is a quantum leap ahead in terms of story-telling, set pieces, special effects and performances. Van Damme has made decent enough movies in the past - I recommend the likes of "Universal Soldier" or "Sudden Death" - but this really isn't one of them. A Damme shame, then. And just what was the point of the whole thing being a flash-back?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speculation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cam Cloutier
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoy Van Damme's films occasionally, especially "Time Cop". Of his films, I consider this one of his worst, but that rating is purely from a technical vantage. A genuine martial artist is like anyone else when they go to the movies. They expect to see only fiction. The same is true even of martial arts action flics. Even if the choreographer and stars know their business, it's goosed up for entertainment purposes. Nevertheless, the discerning eye seeks a few gems, to see if the martial artists involved in the film's production at least cast a brief nod of respect to the art. In "The Quest", that nod is within the first 15 minutes of the movie: when an aging hero defends himself with his cane. The cane techniques are marvelous and entertaining and, suffice to say, a rarity in Hollywood kung fu cinema. Afterwards, it's typical dreck. Worse, as a long-time practitioner of Okinawan karate, I was mildly insulted by the portrayal of the "champion of karate" in the final segment of the film. One can only speculate why the producers (which included Van Damme) would show such a buffoon. We can go positive or negative in our speculation. Positively, we can say that Van Damme nodded in respect to the real masters of karate who, in the film's period time, were among the deadliest men who have EVER LIVED (Choki Motobu, Kanryo Higashionna, Itoman Bunkichi, Miyagi Chojun, to list but a few). Such men, though competitive, would have either not heard of the tournament or snubbed it. Negatively, we might say that Van Damme's Shotokan upbringing had rendered him oblivious to karate that was not watered down for schoolchildren (and a system that didn't even exist in the film's period; Funakoshi was only getting started teaching in Japan at that time). That would also be in line with many others' contemporary views of karate, common nowadays in the MMA, ever since the Gracies issued their silly challenge and no -real- karateka deigned to answer them. The sight of a karateka trying to side kick a sumo wrestler in the belly should make anyone twitch, unless they already nurse a profound (or ignorant) bias against real karate. I found the film otherwise tolerable if typical of Van Damme's work and of cinema of the 80s/90s generally.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoy Christmas in the lost city.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Duboir is Kidnapped and enslaved by gun smugglers, sold by pirates and thrust into the murky underworld of gambling and kick-boxing. His journey takes him to Muay Thai Island where martial arts are taught, and finally, the ancient Lost City. There he must face the ultimate test of his manhood in the ancient winner-take-all competition in which the deadliest fighters from around the world employ the most spectacular feats of martial arts skills ever displayed in order to win the prized Golden Dragon. But fighting prowess alone will not be enough for him to triumph over such daunting foes. He must reach deep inside and access all of the determination, strength of character and sense of selfless honour within in order to triumph over this final obstacle..... When Van Damme met Bond is a really strange movie to watch and probably not the best Van Damme film to start with. It's basically a retread of Bloodsport, set in a different time and location, with added Roger Moore. And while it's nowhere near as good as that movie, it's pretty darn good, and beautiful to look at. Van Damme is competent behind the camera, and even thought the main action of the film is your typical video game style beat em' up, the characters are rich and a little bit different. Van Damme is good, and Moore looks uncomfortable, but it's Van Dammes Baby, and he really tries hard with this. Plus, he gets to fight the bloke from Hot Chocolate at the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the James Bond 007 series celebrating its 50th anniversary because of Dr. No, and the third actor to play the famous spy role getting about a lot at the time, it made sense to me to see some of his films before and after Bond, so I found this one, the directorial debut from Jean-Claude Van Damme. Basically an old man is telling a story to a bartender after getting into a fight, and we flashback to this man younger, Christopher Dubois (Van Damme), a pickpocket living in 1925 New York who was orphaned as a child and runs a gang of orphan children pickpockets who also con and steal to get by. They get found by gangsters but Dubois manages to get away, but he does get the attention of the police as well, but he promises to return to the children before stowing away on a boat, but he is found by the crew and forced to be a slave by the pirates aboard. He is saved a few years later by mercenary Englishman Lord Edgar Dobbs (Sir Roger Moore) who agrees to help him get home to America, but in fact he sells him off as a slave on the island of Siam where he gets trained in Muay Thai fighting for a scheme that is coming up. Six months pass and Dobbs with his partner Harry Smythe (Jack McGee) are shocked to see Dubois fighting in the Muay Thai fighting ring, but they see he has become a skilled fighter, so they buy his freedom so that he will represent the USA in the Ghang-Gheng worldwide fighting tournament held in the Lost City of Tibet. Other countries competing in the global event include China, Japan, Germany, Brazil, France, Turkey, Greece, Spain, Africa, Korea, Soviet Union (Russia) and Scotland, all are eliminated round by round, and at the end of the tournament the winning country will receive the prestigious and valuable statue the Golden Dragon. As the contest goes on Dubois gets to know American reporter Carrie Newton (Janet Gunn) and heavyweight boxing champion Maxie Devine (James Remar) who give him advice and tips, and after winning against apposing countries the biggest challenge comes in the final round when he faces Khan the Mongolian Fighter (Abdel Qissi) who is savage. At the end Dubois ultimately wins the tournament, and refusing the Golden Dragon he wins the freedom of his friends Dobbs and Smythe who were sentenced to death after they tried to steal the golden statue, he returned to New York and got the children off the streets, Devine trained great fighters in his future, Dobbs and Smythe went deep into the Amazon to open a trading post, and Carrie wrote the story of everything called The Quest. Also starring Aki Aleong as Khao, Louis Mandylor as Riggi, Chang Ching Peng Chaplin as Master Tchi, Ryan Cutrona as Officer O'Keefe, Peter Wong as Chinese Fighter, Kitao Koji as Sumo Wrestler, Habby Heske as German Fighter, C&eacute;sar Carneiro as Brazilian Fighter, Takis Triggelis as French Fighter, Azdine Nouri as Turkish Fighter, Stefanos Miltsakakis as Greek Fighter, Peter Malota as Spanish Fighter, Winston Ellis as African Fighter, Ong Soo Han as Korean Fighter, Brick Bronsky as Russian Fighter, Ip Choi Nam as Korean Fighter and Mike Lambert as Scottish Fighter. Van Damme is relatively interesting as the pickpocket turned strong fighter, I will be honest and say that I was paying more attention to Moore though with his charming mannerisms and overall English good nature, I have only seen a few of Van Damme's films, many of them are meant to be involving fighting, so as one of them this is I suppose a good enough one, the story is simple enough and the fight sequences are certainly gripping, it is an alright martial arts action adventure. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Predictable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jennifer Fode
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say! Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say! Slapstick and predictable to an extend where it becomes funny. Not a very well-considered movie. The plot awful planning of the plot is simply disquised by the amount of action figthing that is incorporated into the movie. Don't expect anything, but a relaxed, easy-to-follow, simple and adventurous watch. That's really all there is to say!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jonathanruano
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Quest" does not know what kind of movie it wants to be - a version of "Oliver Twist," a pirate movie, a film about Muay Thai training, or another "Bloodsport" - and so it covers all these elements at once and does so badly, rather than focusing on one element and doing it well. When I saw "The Quest," I was impressed by the cinematography which seems reminiscent in a way of those great epic films of the 1950s and 1960s. Yet at the same time, I was bored with the film because the vast majority of its ideas seemed to be half-baked. If you want to do a film with multiple plots, like the "Crying Game" did, then what you need is an brilliant film director and excellent screen writers who know what they are doing. Yet Jean Claude Van Damme seems way over his head in his directorial debut. He knows how to film gorgeous looking scenes, but he cannot bring the various elements of film-making together into one coherent narrative. "The Quest" looks like an array of elements thrown together haphazardly in the hope that they would amount to something, but they do not. In the opening scenes, Jean Claude Van Damme plays a clown with stilts against a richly layered backdrop of a 1920s city coupled with a hideaway with thieving boys which is reminiscent of Fagin's lair from the film "Oliver Twist." Then we have scenes that appear, at least on the surface, to come straight out of the movie "Treasure Island"(1954) which includes its pirate ship. This is followed by another epic scene with Muay Thai fighters training on the beach while large waves are crashing against the shore. Then we see Jean Claude Van Damme and company travelling through Asia on elephants and then horses en route to a temple in the snowy mountains of Tibet. But do all these scenes amount to anything? Actually no, because none of these ideas are fully developed and imbued with meaning. The other problem is with the acting. A film that tries to cover as much ground as "The Quest" does needs capable (probably even gifted) actors to convey its material well. But Jean Claude Van Damme, with his poor acting abilities, seems like an uncomfortable fit as the film's protagonist. Van Damme is much more suited for laid-back, easy going, macho films, like Bloodsport and Kickboxer, where you can excuse the bad acting (and laugh at it) and have a good time. But in "The Quest," the sets upstage Van Damme, making him look small and insignificant. You really need someone with Eroll Flynn or Peter O'Toole's stature (when they were young) to carry a quasi-swashbuckling film, like "The Quest," forward in a convincing way. Roger Moore is a more experienced actor, but he merely reprises his dull cornball James Bond role as the pirate captain and (like his James Bond character) his performance just doesn't work. Although Robert Newton's Captain Silver character has become a clich&eacute;, I would have preferred that type of pirate captain rather than the one depicted by Roger Moore. Towards the end, Van Damme switches gears and creates another version of "Bloodsport" with its Hollywood formulae. He seems to be more comfortable with this material (especially since it requires him to do the martial arts that he knows so well), which explains why the martial arts sequences in the last 30-40 minutes of this film are reasonably entertaining. Those martial arts sequences are not, unfortunately, as good as the ones in Bloodsport which had better choreography and a great music soundtrack by composer Paul Hertzog. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only Van Damme or perhaps Roger Moore completists need apply.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Comeuppance Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set in the 1920's, Chris Dubois (Van Damme) is a street performer who wears clown makeup, a funny hat, and walks on stilts for a living. Adventure finds him when he ends up a stowaway on a boat heading to mysterious Muay Thai Island. There he learns martial arts, and, later in Tibet, meets the charming Lord Dobbs (Moore) and his assistant Smythe (McGee). It is around this time that Chris seeks to be involved in Ghan Geng, a secret underground fighting tournament. The winner gets a huge golden dragon, so Dobbs has a stake in Chris winning, as he wants the Dragon. Fighters are invited from all over the world , and America is represented by boxer Maxie Devine (Remar). Chris must take his place in the tournament and defeat the sinister Khan (Quissi) to win it all. Also, there's some mild romance with the prerequisite female reporter Carrie Newton (Gunn). Van Damme does a solid , professional job with his directional debut. Having co-written the film with Bloodsport (1988) dude Frank Dux, you pretty much know what to expect- but this movie is rated PG-13, so it was clearly trying to bring the Punchfighting genre some mainstream acceptance. With its slick Hollywood look and booming, sweeping score by Randy Edelman, the final product is perfect for 13-year olds, presumably its target demographic. Interestingly, the movie is a period piece, and plays like a prequel to Bloodsport. Instead of The Kumite, It's Ghan Geng. Van Damme tries on a number of personas from "Old Man Van Damme" to "Van Damme The Clown" and many things in between. The presence of Roger Moore adds class and respectability to the proceedings, and James Remar of Quiet Cool (1986) fame stands out as Devine. He's always worth seeing. Janet Gunn from Night Of The Running Man (1995) and The Sweeper (1996) is the eye candy but not much else. It's important to remember this was when video games like Mortal Kombat and Street Fighter were at the peak of their popularity. So when the Ghan Geng section of the movie begins (pretty much the last half)- the plot just STOPS. It's just one fighter from one country facing off against another fighter from another country. It gets repetitive and pretty numbing after awhile. Other Punchfighters don't do this. They vary the Punchfighting scenes with other plot-based stuff. Not so here. Plus the fact the movie is kind of on the long side doesn't help matters. What The Quest should have been is an 80 minute R-rated Punchfighter. Simply cutting the length but adding more violence would have helped immensely. But they weren't going for that audience, unfortunately. The Quest is more of a big "adventure" film where characters are seeking a "lost city" and many countries and time periods are represented. This might be a good way to start younger viewers on a career of watching Van Damme movies\action movies\Punchfighters but for adults. Only Van Damme or perhaps Roger Moore completists need apply. For more insanity, please visit: comeuppancereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
