<filme>
 <id>
  1037
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0084021
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1982
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Grease 2 - Os Tempos da Brilhantina Voltaram
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  3.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  An English student at a 1960's American high school has to prove himself to the leader of a girls' gang whose members can only date greasers.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Return to rockin' Rydell High for a whole new term! It's 1961, two years after the original Grease gang graduated, and there's a new crop of seniors - and new members of the coolest cliques on campus, the Pink Ladies and T-Birds. Michael Carrington is the new kid in school - but he's been branded a brainiac. Can he fix up an old motorcycle, don a leather jacket, avoid a rumble with the leader of the T-Birds, and win the heart of Pink Lady Stephanie Zinone? He's surely going to try!
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Musical
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   school
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   pink ladies
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   1960s
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   greaser
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   high school
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Patricia Birch
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Ken Finkleman
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Michelle Pfeiffer
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Maxwell Caulfield
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Lorna Luft
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's all pretend there was no 'Grease 2'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worse than 'Grease' in every department, this cash-in tries to recapture the bouncy atmosphere of its predecessor but fails spectacularly. In a rather desperate attempt to link the two films, Maxwell Caulfield is Sandy's cousin, who turns up at Rydell High and falls for Michelle Pfeiffer. He's bookish but she wants a biker, so Caulfield disguises himself as a mysterious goggled rider who defeats the bad guys and wins her heart, yeah! To be fair, this is likable enough and there are a couple of decent songs (with little connection to the story), but that just doesn't cut it when the tunes in 'Grease' were so memorable. It's a painless watch if you're in an iron lung and the nurse has left the TV on, but I think we all know it shouldn't exist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease 2 - (the sequel to) THE BEST MUSICAL EVER!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Grease 2! Going in to watching Grease 2 and expecting to see a musical sequel live up to the strong likes of Grease will certainly cause you to breakdown sobbing uncontrollably calling for your mommy all within a first few minutes of the film, but it's really NOT, all that bad well ya it is but still, it's a forgivable bad. Grease 2 is very ingratiating, just like Grease, but in a different vibe. The sequel just never has any chance at being as good as Grease, but still Grease 2 is such a guilty pleasure of mine. It's really not that bad. It's playful, very decent mild-mannered merriment. The songs are...so worse than the songs of Grease...let's not say that, let's say they're catchy good. I love the songs of Grease 2 even though they're not all that good, or on second thought, maybe they are good, I dunno, I do love them, I mean.....no...no they're definitely, definitely not that good. My favorite Grease 2 tunes are "Back To School Again", "Score Tonight", and "Cool Rider". I love, love, love Michelle Pfeiffer starring and singing and performing in Grease 2. Without the worthwhile Michelle Pfeiffer there's really no telling how bad it might have got. Grease 2 is enjoyable at times though it is consistently bad, but it isn't too unsavory and it tries so good. It earns a good 5 rating wholly on its fun, lighthearted goodness, and for the presence of Pfeiffer. If I love Grease 2 this much, please understand just how much it is that I love Grease......sooooooooo, so very much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as bad as some say!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rcurton29906
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has some campy moments,but overall it is entertainment at it's finest.Do not compare it to the original as it stands on it's own merit.It is a return to the days when movies were fun.Just watch this movie with an open mind and have fun.It is an hour and half vacation.The music is awesome.I really like this movie,it's just fun to watch with the whole family.Michelle does a great job of being the bad girl in high school that every guy wants.Maxwell is awesome at being the "nerdy" English student who transform's himself into the cool dude.The T-Birds are supposed to be the "tuff" guys who are just a bunch of parrots that just repeat what there told,but do it great.Again,watch this movie with an open mind.You will enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease 2 stands on its own.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    simonkie
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease 2 is not a sequel. It has new characters and new story lines. People who criticize this film only because of the tittle of the movie. If they had named this movie Glee back in 1982 it would have been a big hit but many are biased toward this movie because they expected John Travolta or Olivia Newton John to be in it. This movie is very entertaining with catchy songs and an interesting story. What's even more impressive are the performances from the Maxwell Caulfield and Michelle Pfeiffer who were making their first feature film of their careers. Disregard the enormous expectations this movie had to live up to which was impossible and judge this movie on it's own merits and you will find much to enjoy from it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than Grease 1..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paypalscam9002
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no idea what is wrong with people bashing on this movie. Grease 2 is really really a great movie. I have watched it more than 10 times in my life and each time i'm having great fun watching it. I am very picky when it comes to movies. Most movies that i enjoy usually end up with an Oscar for best movie picture or something. Grease 2 is one of the few rare movies that i enjoy watching but didn't get any award. The way i see this is that Grease 2 is meant for a different type of audience. Back when i was in college, we (guys) had to impress girls in order to get them. We had to be cool, we had to be unreal (almost fake), we were creating an image to impress the girls. Of course, i don't do that anymore, (not as much. I'm married, got kids, and still got my motorcycle etc. But one thing that has changed since my college days is that i am more connected to reality now than i was in college. Grease 2 is about a nerds (maxwell) that wants THE Chix (pfeiffer ) but to do that he can't stay natural, he can't be himself so he has to impersonate an image. You see, this is exactly the daily reality for many teenagers. Observe how our teenagers behave today. No different than in Grease 2 (minus the music). I must admit, i was also a Geek guy trying to be cool, dreaming about some (impossible to get girl), when i was in college...and there was. Girls that (20 years later) i wish i had got even if my current wife is a very cute and sexy slim woman... Watching Grease 2 reminds me how i was in college. (like maxwell actually). To be more exact, i wished i was like maxwell. Because in Grease 2 he made it, he succeed getting pfeiffer. But in really it is much more complicated almost impossible for a Geek guy to get the most beautiful girl because the most beautiful girl usually can pick any guy she want. Being an educator in a high school, i can tell you that sex is probably to most spoken subject in our teenagers conversation and concern. To summarize: Grease 2 (from a guy point of view) is a movie for anyone who felt at one point in their college year in love with an (impossible to get girl). A guy who likes to dream and do crazy things just to impress someone, a good guy in nature. Grease 2 is a masterpiece (atleast) for some audience... I give it a 10/10 to re-balance that thrash reviews this movie has got but the real score should be around 8/10 objectively.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poor casting doomed this one from the start.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TOMASBBloodhound
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease 2 is one of the most ridiculed sequels of all time, and though it pales to the original, its certainly better than the rating would imply. The film is just more musical numbers and hijinks from the kids at Rydell High. Only this time, the new kid on the block is a guy trying to impress a cool chick. As opposed to a goody-two-shoes girl trying to win over a cool guy like we saw in the original. There are some cute songs and funny moments, but the two leads (Caulfield and Pfeiffer) just cannot live up to Olivia Newton-John or John Travolta. Not even close. First of all, neither can sing terribly well, and generally you'd like your leads in a musical to be able to sing. It really helps. Caulfield is somewhat more likable in the underdog role, but Pfeiffer's acting is really poor. She was a pretty face and little more at that point of her career. Her song "Cool Rider" is one of the film's worst. While singing it, she does look kind of sexy while climbing up to the top of a ladder and then straddling it. But then when she gets down she starts doing something resembling the Elaine dance from Seinfeld. Thumbs in the air and all! Weird. Director/choreographer Pat Birch should have fixed that. There are some good performances from some of the folks playing the T-Birds and Pink Ladies. Adrian Zmed provides some chuckles with his false bravado in many scenes. Chris McDonald who plays the Goose has been a solid performer in movies and TV for years. And you're telling me Lorna Luft is a daughter of Judy Garland? Who new? Its good to see some of the faculty members are back from the original, but Didi Conn doesn't seem to belong. It seems like the producers agreed and just kind of wrote her out of the movie by the third act. It's really kind of odd how this movie has been aired seemingly more than the popular original over the years. It didn't hurt Pfeiffer's career (nor did marrying producer David E. Kelly), but this movie destroyed Caulfield's before it even began. He has kept somewhat busy, and was even considered at one point for the James Bond role. But he's never been the star he perhaps could have been. Grease 2 isn't all bad. It's worth about 5 of 10 stars. The Hound.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not very well made.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hailee-rebecca
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you watched the original "Grease" then this will most likely be a disappointment. I liked the idea - the tough chick falling for the sweet guy, but I think it could have been produced much better. The music wasn't all that great, neither with the dance sequences. I knew before I turned it on that it would not be able to the exact standards "Grease" did but I didn't expect to be this much of a disappointment. Stick to watching the classic. Though, I'll admit, the movie wasn't totally bogus. I really enjoyed Micheal's character and I liked seeing Frenchy again - she was my favourite character from the original. I thought it was weird that the 'Pink Ladies' were now owned by the T-Birds; they couldn't date outside the group because they were the T-Birds girls. That just didn't match up to me. The 'Reproduction' scene was kind of cool, I suppose.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit N Miss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nfmorse
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is a sad attempt to capitalize on the original's success. almost EVERY scene with Michelle Pfeiffer is not era appropriate clothing or hair n make-up for the times. You could 'plunk' her, (and her character) out of this movie and insert her into St Elmo's Fire or The Breakfast Club and have everything current with the fashion of the time. did she insist on only doing this movie if she could appear in a manner as she wouldn't be embarrassed? i was Born in the 60's and she does NOT represent the 60's by a LONG shot. i did not ONCE see era appropriate hair one her.. where was the structure curl of 'roller setting' on her? and the Sad portrayal of every one of the main characters as IDIOTS. the making of this movie should NEVER have been associated with the first Grease and should have been made as more of a parody for the times, but not be linked with the first Grease. the characters of the first were NOT so shallow and stupid as these people were who were supposed to be following in the footsteps of COOL people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than it's given credit for
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    urthmothr
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We saw this movie before the original "Grease," and have always preferred "2." We identify more with the characters, the humor, the whole "superhero shtick," and fell in love with Michelle Pfeiffer long before we saw her in anything else! Lorna Luft as Paulette was a hoot, and we enjoyed the rest of the cast, including the "returning faculty" from "Grease," some of whom we remember from their old TV shows. The bomb shelter scene was especially meaningful to "baby boomer's" who grew up in the 50's and 60's. Our favorite song is "Cool Rider," and the ending chorus to "A Girl for All Seasons" was especially poignant. This was our generation, we are class of '63 in NJ and '64 in Georgia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sloppy Cash-in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one's got cash-in written all over it. The original Grease was no work of art, but at least it was entertaining and fun. Its sequel has all the hallmarks of studio greed, with a minimal amount of money spent in the hope of the greatest possible return. So we have mostly unfamiliar characters in familiar surroundings, and the only link to the original film  other than a few minor characters  is the fact that it's the same story with the roles reversed. This time it's bland pretty-boy Maxwell Caulfield (once touted as the next big thing, he was last seen in the equally bland English soap Emmerdale) as the straight one and a young and impossibly gorgeous Michelle Pfeiffer as the bad girl member of the T-Birds. Pfeiffer isn't really bad. She doesn't even misbehave, which is perhaps an indicator of how much the makers of this movie have watered down the contents of the original. The songs are dull and unmemorable, the humour is lame  and nobody realises Maxwell's the enigmatic biker because he's wearing goggles. To top it all, the damn thing goes on forever, clocking in at around the two hour mark.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's all pretend there was no 'Grease 2'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worse than 'Grease' in every department, this cash-in tries to recapture the bouncy atmosphere of its predecessor but fails spectacularly. In a rather desperate attempt to link the two films, Maxwell Caulfield is Sandy's cousin, who turns up at Rydell High and falls for Michelle Pfeiffer. He's bookish but she wants a biker, so Caulfield disguises himself as a mysterious goggled rider who defeats the bad guys and wins her heart, yeah! To be fair, this is likable enough and there are a couple of decent songs (with little connection to the story), but that just doesn't cut it when the tunes in 'Grease' were so memorable. It's a painless watch if you're in an iron lung and the nurse has left the TV on, but I think we all know it shouldn't exist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease 2 - (the sequel to) THE BEST MUSICAL EVER!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Grease 2! Going in to watching Grease 2 and expecting to see a musical sequel live up to the strong likes of Grease will certainly cause you to breakdown sobbing uncontrollably calling for your mommy all within a first few minutes of the film, but it's really NOT, all that bad well ya it is but still, it's a forgivable bad. Grease 2 is very ingratiating, just like Grease, but in a different vibe. The sequel just never has any chance at being as good as Grease, but still Grease 2 is such a guilty pleasure of mine. It's really not that bad. It's playful, very decent mild-mannered merriment. The songs are...so worse than the songs of Grease...let's not say that, let's say they're catchy good. I love the songs of Grease 2 even though they're not all that good, or on second thought, maybe they are good, I dunno, I do love them, I mean.....no...no they're definitely, definitely not that good. My favorite Grease 2 tunes are "Back To School Again", "Score Tonight", and "Cool Rider". I love, love, love Michelle Pfeiffer starring and singing and performing in Grease 2. Without the worthwhile Michelle Pfeiffer there's really no telling how bad it might have got. Grease 2 is enjoyable at times though it is consistently bad, but it isn't too unsavory and it tries so good. It earns a good 5 rating wholly on its fun, lighthearted goodness, and for the presence of Pfeiffer. If I love Grease 2 this much, please understand just how much it is that I love Grease......sooooooooo, so very much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as bad as some say!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rcurton29906
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has some campy moments,but overall it is entertainment at it's finest.Do not compare it to the original as it stands on it's own merit.It is a return to the days when movies were fun.Just watch this movie with an open mind and have fun.It is an hour and half vacation.The music is awesome.I really like this movie,it's just fun to watch with the whole family.Michelle does a great job of being the bad girl in high school that every guy wants.Maxwell is awesome at being the "nerdy" English student who transform's himself into the cool dude.The T-Birds are supposed to be the "tuff" guys who are just a bunch of parrots that just repeat what there told,but do it great.Again,watch this movie with an open mind.You will enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease 2 stands on its own.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    simonkie
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease 2 is not a sequel. It has new characters and new story lines. People who criticize this film only because of the tittle of the movie. If they had named this movie Glee back in 1982 it would have been a big hit but many are biased toward this movie because they expected John Travolta or Olivia Newton John to be in it. This movie is very entertaining with catchy songs and an interesting story. What's even more impressive are the performances from the Maxwell Caulfield and Michelle Pfeiffer who were making their first feature film of their careers. Disregard the enormous expectations this movie had to live up to which was impossible and judge this movie on it's own merits and you will find much to enjoy from it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than Grease 1..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paypalscam9002
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no idea what is wrong with people bashing on this movie. Grease 2 is really really a great movie. I have watched it more than 10 times in my life and each time i'm having great fun watching it. I am very picky when it comes to movies. Most movies that i enjoy usually end up with an Oscar for best movie picture or something. Grease 2 is one of the few rare movies that i enjoy watching but didn't get any award. The way i see this is that Grease 2 is meant for a different type of audience. Back when i was in college, we (guys) had to impress girls in order to get them. We had to be cool, we had to be unreal (almost fake), we were creating an image to impress the girls. Of course, i don't do that anymore, (not as much. I'm married, got kids, and still got my motorcycle etc. But one thing that has changed since my college days is that i am more connected to reality now than i was in college. Grease 2 is about a nerds (maxwell) that wants THE Chix (pfeiffer ) but to do that he can't stay natural, he can't be himself so he has to impersonate an image. You see, this is exactly the daily reality for many teenagers. Observe how our teenagers behave today. No different than in Grease 2 (minus the music). I must admit, i was also a Geek guy trying to be cool, dreaming about some (impossible to get girl), when i was in college...and there was. Girls that (20 years later) i wish i had got even if my current wife is a very cute and sexy slim woman... Watching Grease 2 reminds me how i was in college. (like maxwell actually). To be more exact, i wished i was like maxwell. Because in Grease 2 he made it, he succeed getting pfeiffer. But in really it is much more complicated almost impossible for a Geek guy to get the most beautiful girl because the most beautiful girl usually can pick any guy she want. Being an educator in a high school, i can tell you that sex is probably to most spoken subject in our teenagers conversation and concern. To summarize: Grease 2 (from a guy point of view) is a movie for anyone who felt at one point in their college year in love with an (impossible to get girl). A guy who likes to dream and do crazy things just to impress someone, a good guy in nature. Grease 2 is a masterpiece (atleast) for some audience... I give it a 10/10 to re-balance that thrash reviews this movie has got but the real score should be around 8/10 objectively.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poor casting doomed this one from the start.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TOMASBBloodhound
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease 2 is one of the most ridiculed sequels of all time, and though it pales to the original, its certainly better than the rating would imply. The film is just more musical numbers and hijinks from the kids at Rydell High. Only this time, the new kid on the block is a guy trying to impress a cool chick. As opposed to a goody-two-shoes girl trying to win over a cool guy like we saw in the original. There are some cute songs and funny moments, but the two leads (Caulfield and Pfeiffer) just cannot live up to Olivia Newton-John or John Travolta. Not even close. First of all, neither can sing terribly well, and generally you'd like your leads in a musical to be able to sing. It really helps. Caulfield is somewhat more likable in the underdog role, but Pfeiffer's acting is really poor. She was a pretty face and little more at that point of her career. Her song "Cool Rider" is one of the film's worst. While singing it, she does look kind of sexy while climbing up to the top of a ladder and then straddling it. But then when she gets down she starts doing something resembling the Elaine dance from Seinfeld. Thumbs in the air and all! Weird. Director/choreographer Pat Birch should have fixed that. There are some good performances from some of the folks playing the T-Birds and Pink Ladies. Adrian Zmed provides some chuckles with his false bravado in many scenes. Chris McDonald who plays the Goose has been a solid performer in movies and TV for years. And you're telling me Lorna Luft is a daughter of Judy Garland? Who new? Its good to see some of the faculty members are back from the original, but Didi Conn doesn't seem to belong. It seems like the producers agreed and just kind of wrote her out of the movie by the third act. It's really kind of odd how this movie has been aired seemingly more than the popular original over the years. It didn't hurt Pfeiffer's career (nor did marrying producer David E. Kelly), but this movie destroyed Caulfield's before it even began. He has kept somewhat busy, and was even considered at one point for the James Bond role. But he's never been the star he perhaps could have been. Grease 2 isn't all bad. It's worth about 5 of 10 stars. The Hound.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not very well made.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hailee-rebecca
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you watched the original "Grease" then this will most likely be a disappointment. I liked the idea - the tough chick falling for the sweet guy, but I think it could have been produced much better. The music wasn't all that great, neither with the dance sequences. I knew before I turned it on that it would not be able to the exact standards "Grease" did but I didn't expect to be this much of a disappointment. Stick to watching the classic. Though, I'll admit, the movie wasn't totally bogus. I really enjoyed Micheal's character and I liked seeing Frenchy again - she was my favourite character from the original. I thought it was weird that the 'Pink Ladies' were now owned by the T-Birds; they couldn't date outside the group because they were the T-Birds girls. That just didn't match up to me. The 'Reproduction' scene was kind of cool, I suppose.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit N Miss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nfmorse
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is a sad attempt to capitalize on the original's success. almost EVERY scene with Michelle Pfeiffer is not era appropriate clothing or hair n make-up for the times. You could 'plunk' her, (and her character) out of this movie and insert her into St Elmo's Fire or The Breakfast Club and have everything current with the fashion of the time. did she insist on only doing this movie if she could appear in a manner as she wouldn't be embarrassed? i was Born in the 60's and she does NOT represent the 60's by a LONG shot. i did not ONCE see era appropriate hair one her.. where was the structure curl of 'roller setting' on her? and the Sad portrayal of every one of the main characters as IDIOTS. the making of this movie should NEVER have been associated with the first Grease and should have been made as more of a parody for the times, but not be linked with the first Grease. the characters of the first were NOT so shallow and stupid as these people were who were supposed to be following in the footsteps of COOL people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than it's given credit for
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    urthmothr
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We saw this movie before the original "Grease," and have always preferred "2." We identify more with the characters, the humor, the whole "superhero shtick," and fell in love with Michelle Pfeiffer long before we saw her in anything else! Lorna Luft as Paulette was a hoot, and we enjoyed the rest of the cast, including the "returning faculty" from "Grease," some of whom we remember from their old TV shows. The bomb shelter scene was especially meaningful to "baby boomer's" who grew up in the 50's and 60's. Our favorite song is "Cool Rider," and the ending chorus to "A Girl for All Seasons" was especially poignant. This was our generation, we are class of '63 in NJ and '64 in Georgia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sloppy Cash-in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one's got cash-in written all over it. The original Grease was no work of art, but at least it was entertaining and fun. Its sequel has all the hallmarks of studio greed, with a minimal amount of money spent in the hope of the greatest possible return. So we have mostly unfamiliar characters in familiar surroundings, and the only link to the original film  other than a few minor characters  is the fact that it's the same story with the roles reversed. This time it's bland pretty-boy Maxwell Caulfield (once touted as the next big thing, he was last seen in the equally bland English soap Emmerdale) as the straight one and a young and impossibly gorgeous Michelle Pfeiffer as the bad girl member of the T-Birds. Pfeiffer isn't really bad. She doesn't even misbehave, which is perhaps an indicator of how much the makers of this movie have watered down the contents of the original. The songs are dull and unmemorable, the humour is lame  and nobody realises Maxwell's the enigmatic biker because he's wearing goggles. To top it all, the damn thing goes on forever, clocking in at around the two hour mark.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's all pretend there was no 'Grease 2'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worse than 'Grease' in every department, this cash-in tries to recapture the bouncy atmosphere of its predecessor but fails spectacularly. In a rather desperate attempt to link the two films, Maxwell Caulfield is Sandy's cousin, who turns up at Rydell High and falls for Michelle Pfeiffer. He's bookish but she wants a biker, so Caulfield disguises himself as a mysterious goggled rider who defeats the bad guys and wins her heart, yeah! To be fair, this is likable enough and there are a couple of decent songs (with little connection to the story), but that just doesn't cut it when the tunes in 'Grease' were so memorable. It's a painless watch if you're in an iron lung and the nurse has left the TV on, but I think we all know it shouldn't exist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease 2 - (the sequel to) THE BEST MUSICAL EVER!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Grease 2! Going in to watching Grease 2 and expecting to see a musical sequel live up to the strong likes of Grease will certainly cause you to breakdown sobbing uncontrollably calling for your mommy all within a first few minutes of the film, but it's really NOT, all that bad well ya it is but still, it's a forgivable bad. Grease 2 is very ingratiating, just like Grease, but in a different vibe. The sequel just never has any chance at being as good as Grease, but still Grease 2 is such a guilty pleasure of mine. It's really not that bad. It's playful, very decent mild-mannered merriment. The songs are...so worse than the songs of Grease...let's not say that, let's say they're catchy good. I love the songs of Grease 2 even though they're not all that good, or on second thought, maybe they are good, I dunno, I do love them, I mean.....no...no they're definitely, definitely not that good. My favorite Grease 2 tunes are "Back To School Again", "Score Tonight", and "Cool Rider". I love, love, love Michelle Pfeiffer starring and singing and performing in Grease 2. Without the worthwhile Michelle Pfeiffer there's really no telling how bad it might have got. Grease 2 is enjoyable at times though it is consistently bad, but it isn't too unsavory and it tries so good. It earns a good 5 rating wholly on its fun, lighthearted goodness, and for the presence of Pfeiffer. If I love Grease 2 this much, please understand just how much it is that I love Grease......sooooooooo, so very much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as bad as some say!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rcurton29906
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has some campy moments,but overall it is entertainment at it's finest.Do not compare it to the original as it stands on it's own merit.It is a return to the days when movies were fun.Just watch this movie with an open mind and have fun.It is an hour and half vacation.The music is awesome.I really like this movie,it's just fun to watch with the whole family.Michelle does a great job of being the bad girl in high school that every guy wants.Maxwell is awesome at being the "nerdy" English student who transform's himself into the cool dude.The T-Birds are supposed to be the "tuff" guys who are just a bunch of parrots that just repeat what there told,but do it great.Again,watch this movie with an open mind.You will enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease 2 stands on its own.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    simonkie
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease 2 is not a sequel. It has new characters and new story lines. People who criticize this film only because of the tittle of the movie. If they had named this movie Glee back in 1982 it would have been a big hit but many are biased toward this movie because they expected John Travolta or Olivia Newton John to be in it. This movie is very entertaining with catchy songs and an interesting story. What's even more impressive are the performances from the Maxwell Caulfield and Michelle Pfeiffer who were making their first feature film of their careers. Disregard the enormous expectations this movie had to live up to which was impossible and judge this movie on it's own merits and you will find much to enjoy from it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than Grease 1..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paypalscam9002
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no idea what is wrong with people bashing on this movie. Grease 2 is really really a great movie. I have watched it more than 10 times in my life and each time i'm having great fun watching it. I am very picky when it comes to movies. Most movies that i enjoy usually end up with an Oscar for best movie picture or something. Grease 2 is one of the few rare movies that i enjoy watching but didn't get any award. The way i see this is that Grease 2 is meant for a different type of audience. Back when i was in college, we (guys) had to impress girls in order to get them. We had to be cool, we had to be unreal (almost fake), we were creating an image to impress the girls. Of course, i don't do that anymore, (not as much. I'm married, got kids, and still got my motorcycle etc. But one thing that has changed since my college days is that i am more connected to reality now than i was in college. Grease 2 is about a nerds (maxwell) that wants THE Chix (pfeiffer ) but to do that he can't stay natural, he can't be himself so he has to impersonate an image. You see, this is exactly the daily reality for many teenagers. Observe how our teenagers behave today. No different than in Grease 2 (minus the music). I must admit, i was also a Geek guy trying to be cool, dreaming about some (impossible to get girl), when i was in college...and there was. Girls that (20 years later) i wish i had got even if my current wife is a very cute and sexy slim woman... Watching Grease 2 reminds me how i was in college. (like maxwell actually). To be more exact, i wished i was like maxwell. Because in Grease 2 he made it, he succeed getting pfeiffer. But in really it is much more complicated almost impossible for a Geek guy to get the most beautiful girl because the most beautiful girl usually can pick any guy she want. Being an educator in a high school, i can tell you that sex is probably to most spoken subject in our teenagers conversation and concern. To summarize: Grease 2 (from a guy point of view) is a movie for anyone who felt at one point in their college year in love with an (impossible to get girl). A guy who likes to dream and do crazy things just to impress someone, a good guy in nature. Grease 2 is a masterpiece (atleast) for some audience... I give it a 10/10 to re-balance that thrash reviews this movie has got but the real score should be around 8/10 objectively.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poor casting doomed this one from the start.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TOMASBBloodhound
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease 2 is one of the most ridiculed sequels of all time, and though it pales to the original, its certainly better than the rating would imply. The film is just more musical numbers and hijinks from the kids at Rydell High. Only this time, the new kid on the block is a guy trying to impress a cool chick. As opposed to a goody-two-shoes girl trying to win over a cool guy like we saw in the original. There are some cute songs and funny moments, but the two leads (Caulfield and Pfeiffer) just cannot live up to Olivia Newton-John or John Travolta. Not even close. First of all, neither can sing terribly well, and generally you'd like your leads in a musical to be able to sing. It really helps. Caulfield is somewhat more likable in the underdog role, but Pfeiffer's acting is really poor. She was a pretty face and little more at that point of her career. Her song "Cool Rider" is one of the film's worst. While singing it, she does look kind of sexy while climbing up to the top of a ladder and then straddling it. But then when she gets down she starts doing something resembling the Elaine dance from Seinfeld. Thumbs in the air and all! Weird. Director/choreographer Pat Birch should have fixed that. There are some good performances from some of the folks playing the T-Birds and Pink Ladies. Adrian Zmed provides some chuckles with his false bravado in many scenes. Chris McDonald who plays the Goose has been a solid performer in movies and TV for years. And you're telling me Lorna Luft is a daughter of Judy Garland? Who new? Its good to see some of the faculty members are back from the original, but Didi Conn doesn't seem to belong. It seems like the producers agreed and just kind of wrote her out of the movie by the third act. It's really kind of odd how this movie has been aired seemingly more than the popular original over the years. It didn't hurt Pfeiffer's career (nor did marrying producer David E. Kelly), but this movie destroyed Caulfield's before it even began. He has kept somewhat busy, and was even considered at one point for the James Bond role. But he's never been the star he perhaps could have been. Grease 2 isn't all bad. It's worth about 5 of 10 stars. The Hound.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not very well made.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hailee-rebecca
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you watched the original "Grease" then this will most likely be a disappointment. I liked the idea - the tough chick falling for the sweet guy, but I think it could have been produced much better. The music wasn't all that great, neither with the dance sequences. I knew before I turned it on that it would not be able to the exact standards "Grease" did but I didn't expect to be this much of a disappointment. Stick to watching the classic. Though, I'll admit, the movie wasn't totally bogus. I really enjoyed Micheal's character and I liked seeing Frenchy again - she was my favourite character from the original. I thought it was weird that the 'Pink Ladies' were now owned by the T-Birds; they couldn't date outside the group because they were the T-Birds girls. That just didn't match up to me. The 'Reproduction' scene was kind of cool, I suppose.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit N Miss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nfmorse
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is a sad attempt to capitalize on the original's success. almost EVERY scene with Michelle Pfeiffer is not era appropriate clothing or hair n make-up for the times. You could 'plunk' her, (and her character) out of this movie and insert her into St Elmo's Fire or The Breakfast Club and have everything current with the fashion of the time. did she insist on only doing this movie if she could appear in a manner as she wouldn't be embarrassed? i was Born in the 60's and she does NOT represent the 60's by a LONG shot. i did not ONCE see era appropriate hair one her.. where was the structure curl of 'roller setting' on her? and the Sad portrayal of every one of the main characters as IDIOTS. the making of this movie should NEVER have been associated with the first Grease and should have been made as more of a parody for the times, but not be linked with the first Grease. the characters of the first were NOT so shallow and stupid as these people were who were supposed to be following in the footsteps of COOL people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than it's given credit for
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    urthmothr
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We saw this movie before the original "Grease," and have always preferred "2." We identify more with the characters, the humor, the whole "superhero shtick," and fell in love with Michelle Pfeiffer long before we saw her in anything else! Lorna Luft as Paulette was a hoot, and we enjoyed the rest of the cast, including the "returning faculty" from "Grease," some of whom we remember from their old TV shows. The bomb shelter scene was especially meaningful to "baby boomer's" who grew up in the 50's and 60's. Our favorite song is "Cool Rider," and the ending chorus to "A Girl for All Seasons" was especially poignant. This was our generation, we are class of '63 in NJ and '64 in Georgia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sloppy Cash-in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one's got cash-in written all over it. The original Grease was no work of art, but at least it was entertaining and fun. Its sequel has all the hallmarks of studio greed, with a minimal amount of money spent in the hope of the greatest possible return. So we have mostly unfamiliar characters in familiar surroundings, and the only link to the original film  other than a few minor characters  is the fact that it's the same story with the roles reversed. This time it's bland pretty-boy Maxwell Caulfield (once touted as the next big thing, he was last seen in the equally bland English soap Emmerdale) as the straight one and a young and impossibly gorgeous Michelle Pfeiffer as the bad girl member of the T-Birds. Pfeiffer isn't really bad. She doesn't even misbehave, which is perhaps an indicator of how much the makers of this movie have watered down the contents of the original. The songs are dull and unmemorable, the humour is lame  and nobody realises Maxwell's the enigmatic biker because he's wearing goggles. To top it all, the damn thing goes on forever, clocking in at around the two hour mark.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's all pretend there was no 'Grease 2'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worse than 'Grease' in every department, this cash-in tries to recapture the bouncy atmosphere of its predecessor but fails spectacularly. In a rather desperate attempt to link the two films, Maxwell Caulfield is Sandy's cousin, who turns up at Rydell High and falls for Michelle Pfeiffer. He's bookish but she wants a biker, so Caulfield disguises himself as a mysterious goggled rider who defeats the bad guys and wins her heart, yeah! To be fair, this is likable enough and there are a couple of decent songs (with little connection to the story), but that just doesn't cut it when the tunes in 'Grease' were so memorable. It's a painless watch if you're in an iron lung and the nurse has left the TV on, but I think we all know it shouldn't exist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease 2 - (the sequel to) THE BEST MUSICAL EVER!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Grease 2! Going in to watching Grease 2 and expecting to see a musical sequel live up to the strong likes of Grease will certainly cause you to breakdown sobbing uncontrollably calling for your mommy all within a first few minutes of the film, but it's really NOT, all that bad well ya it is but still, it's a forgivable bad. Grease 2 is very ingratiating, just like Grease, but in a different vibe. The sequel just never has any chance at being as good as Grease, but still Grease 2 is such a guilty pleasure of mine. It's really not that bad. It's playful, very decent mild-mannered merriment. The songs are...so worse than the songs of Grease...let's not say that, let's say they're catchy good. I love the songs of Grease 2 even though they're not all that good, or on second thought, maybe they are good, I dunno, I do love them, I mean.....no...no they're definitely, definitely not that good. My favorite Grease 2 tunes are "Back To School Again", "Score Tonight", and "Cool Rider". I love, love, love Michelle Pfeiffer starring and singing and performing in Grease 2. Without the worthwhile Michelle Pfeiffer there's really no telling how bad it might have got. Grease 2 is enjoyable at times though it is consistently bad, but it isn't too unsavory and it tries so good. It earns a good 5 rating wholly on its fun, lighthearted goodness, and for the presence of Pfeiffer. If I love Grease 2 this much, please understand just how much it is that I love Grease......sooooooooo, so very much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as bad as some say!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rcurton29906
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has some campy moments,but overall it is entertainment at it's finest.Do not compare it to the original as it stands on it's own merit.It is a return to the days when movies were fun.Just watch this movie with an open mind and have fun.It is an hour and half vacation.The music is awesome.I really like this movie,it's just fun to watch with the whole family.Michelle does a great job of being the bad girl in high school that every guy wants.Maxwell is awesome at being the "nerdy" English student who transform's himself into the cool dude.The T-Birds are supposed to be the "tuff" guys who are just a bunch of parrots that just repeat what there told,but do it great.Again,watch this movie with an open mind.You will enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease 2 stands on its own.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    simonkie
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease 2 is not a sequel. It has new characters and new story lines. People who criticize this film only because of the tittle of the movie. If they had named this movie Glee back in 1982 it would have been a big hit but many are biased toward this movie because they expected John Travolta or Olivia Newton John to be in it. This movie is very entertaining with catchy songs and an interesting story. What's even more impressive are the performances from the Maxwell Caulfield and Michelle Pfeiffer who were making their first feature film of their careers. Disregard the enormous expectations this movie had to live up to which was impossible and judge this movie on it's own merits and you will find much to enjoy from it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than Grease 1..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paypalscam9002
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no idea what is wrong with people bashing on this movie. Grease 2 is really really a great movie. I have watched it more than 10 times in my life and each time i'm having great fun watching it. I am very picky when it comes to movies. Most movies that i enjoy usually end up with an Oscar for best movie picture or something. Grease 2 is one of the few rare movies that i enjoy watching but didn't get any award. The way i see this is that Grease 2 is meant for a different type of audience. Back when i was in college, we (guys) had to impress girls in order to get them. We had to be cool, we had to be unreal (almost fake), we were creating an image to impress the girls. Of course, i don't do that anymore, (not as much. I'm married, got kids, and still got my motorcycle etc. But one thing that has changed since my college days is that i am more connected to reality now than i was in college. Grease 2 is about a nerds (maxwell) that wants THE Chix (pfeiffer ) but to do that he can't stay natural, he can't be himself so he has to impersonate an image. You see, this is exactly the daily reality for many teenagers. Observe how our teenagers behave today. No different than in Grease 2 (minus the music). I must admit, i was also a Geek guy trying to be cool, dreaming about some (impossible to get girl), when i was in college...and there was. Girls that (20 years later) i wish i had got even if my current wife is a very cute and sexy slim woman... Watching Grease 2 reminds me how i was in college. (like maxwell actually). To be more exact, i wished i was like maxwell. Because in Grease 2 he made it, he succeed getting pfeiffer. But in really it is much more complicated almost impossible for a Geek guy to get the most beautiful girl because the most beautiful girl usually can pick any guy she want. Being an educator in a high school, i can tell you that sex is probably to most spoken subject in our teenagers conversation and concern. To summarize: Grease 2 (from a guy point of view) is a movie for anyone who felt at one point in their college year in love with an (impossible to get girl). A guy who likes to dream and do crazy things just to impress someone, a good guy in nature. Grease 2 is a masterpiece (atleast) for some audience... I give it a 10/10 to re-balance that thrash reviews this movie has got but the real score should be around 8/10 objectively.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poor casting doomed this one from the start.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TOMASBBloodhound
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease 2 is one of the most ridiculed sequels of all time, and though it pales to the original, its certainly better than the rating would imply. The film is just more musical numbers and hijinks from the kids at Rydell High. Only this time, the new kid on the block is a guy trying to impress a cool chick. As opposed to a goody-two-shoes girl trying to win over a cool guy like we saw in the original. There are some cute songs and funny moments, but the two leads (Caulfield and Pfeiffer) just cannot live up to Olivia Newton-John or John Travolta. Not even close. First of all, neither can sing terribly well, and generally you'd like your leads in a musical to be able to sing. It really helps. Caulfield is somewhat more likable in the underdog role, but Pfeiffer's acting is really poor. She was a pretty face and little more at that point of her career. Her song "Cool Rider" is one of the film's worst. While singing it, she does look kind of sexy while climbing up to the top of a ladder and then straddling it. But then when she gets down she starts doing something resembling the Elaine dance from Seinfeld. Thumbs in the air and all! Weird. Director/choreographer Pat Birch should have fixed that. There are some good performances from some of the folks playing the T-Birds and Pink Ladies. Adrian Zmed provides some chuckles with his false bravado in many scenes. Chris McDonald who plays the Goose has been a solid performer in movies and TV for years. And you're telling me Lorna Luft is a daughter of Judy Garland? Who new? Its good to see some of the faculty members are back from the original, but Didi Conn doesn't seem to belong. It seems like the producers agreed and just kind of wrote her out of the movie by the third act. It's really kind of odd how this movie has been aired seemingly more than the popular original over the years. It didn't hurt Pfeiffer's career (nor did marrying producer David E. Kelly), but this movie destroyed Caulfield's before it even began. He has kept somewhat busy, and was even considered at one point for the James Bond role. But he's never been the star he perhaps could have been. Grease 2 isn't all bad. It's worth about 5 of 10 stars. The Hound.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not very well made.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hailee-rebecca
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you watched the original "Grease" then this will most likely be a disappointment. I liked the idea - the tough chick falling for the sweet guy, but I think it could have been produced much better. The music wasn't all that great, neither with the dance sequences. I knew before I turned it on that it would not be able to the exact standards "Grease" did but I didn't expect to be this much of a disappointment. Stick to watching the classic. Though, I'll admit, the movie wasn't totally bogus. I really enjoyed Micheal's character and I liked seeing Frenchy again - she was my favourite character from the original. I thought it was weird that the 'Pink Ladies' were now owned by the T-Birds; they couldn't date outside the group because they were the T-Birds girls. That just didn't match up to me. The 'Reproduction' scene was kind of cool, I suppose.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit N Miss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nfmorse
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is a sad attempt to capitalize on the original's success. almost EVERY scene with Michelle Pfeiffer is not era appropriate clothing or hair n make-up for the times. You could 'plunk' her, (and her character) out of this movie and insert her into St Elmo's Fire or The Breakfast Club and have everything current with the fashion of the time. did she insist on only doing this movie if she could appear in a manner as she wouldn't be embarrassed? i was Born in the 60's and she does NOT represent the 60's by a LONG shot. i did not ONCE see era appropriate hair one her.. where was the structure curl of 'roller setting' on her? and the Sad portrayal of every one of the main characters as IDIOTS. the making of this movie should NEVER have been associated with the first Grease and should have been made as more of a parody for the times, but not be linked with the first Grease. the characters of the first were NOT so shallow and stupid as these people were who were supposed to be following in the footsteps of COOL people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than it's given credit for
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    urthmothr
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We saw this movie before the original "Grease," and have always preferred "2." We identify more with the characters, the humor, the whole "superhero shtick," and fell in love with Michelle Pfeiffer long before we saw her in anything else! Lorna Luft as Paulette was a hoot, and we enjoyed the rest of the cast, including the "returning faculty" from "Grease," some of whom we remember from their old TV shows. The bomb shelter scene was especially meaningful to "baby boomer's" who grew up in the 50's and 60's. Our favorite song is "Cool Rider," and the ending chorus to "A Girl for All Seasons" was especially poignant. This was our generation, we are class of '63 in NJ and '64 in Georgia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sloppy Cash-in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one's got cash-in written all over it. The original Grease was no work of art, but at least it was entertaining and fun. Its sequel has all the hallmarks of studio greed, with a minimal amount of money spent in the hope of the greatest possible return. So we have mostly unfamiliar characters in familiar surroundings, and the only link to the original film  other than a few minor characters  is the fact that it's the same story with the roles reversed. This time it's bland pretty-boy Maxwell Caulfield (once touted as the next big thing, he was last seen in the equally bland English soap Emmerdale) as the straight one and a young and impossibly gorgeous Michelle Pfeiffer as the bad girl member of the T-Birds. Pfeiffer isn't really bad. She doesn't even misbehave, which is perhaps an indicator of how much the makers of this movie have watered down the contents of the original. The songs are dull and unmemorable, the humour is lame  and nobody realises Maxwell's the enigmatic biker because he's wearing goggles. To top it all, the damn thing goes on forever, clocking in at around the two hour mark.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's all pretend there was no 'Grease 2'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worse than 'Grease' in every department, this cash-in tries to recapture the bouncy atmosphere of its predecessor but fails spectacularly. In a rather desperate attempt to link the two films, Maxwell Caulfield is Sandy's cousin, who turns up at Rydell High and falls for Michelle Pfeiffer. He's bookish but she wants a biker, so Caulfield disguises himself as a mysterious goggled rider who defeats the bad guys and wins her heart, yeah! To be fair, this is likable enough and there are a couple of decent songs (with little connection to the story), but that just doesn't cut it when the tunes in 'Grease' were so memorable. It's a painless watch if you're in an iron lung and the nurse has left the TV on, but I think we all know it shouldn't exist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease 2 - (the sequel to) THE BEST MUSICAL EVER!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Grease 2! Going in to watching Grease 2 and expecting to see a musical sequel live up to the strong likes of Grease will certainly cause you to breakdown sobbing uncontrollably calling for your mommy all within a first few minutes of the film, but it's really NOT, all that bad well ya it is but still, it's a forgivable bad. Grease 2 is very ingratiating, just like Grease, but in a different vibe. The sequel just never has any chance at being as good as Grease, but still Grease 2 is such a guilty pleasure of mine. It's really not that bad. It's playful, very decent mild-mannered merriment. The songs are...so worse than the songs of Grease...let's not say that, let's say they're catchy good. I love the songs of Grease 2 even though they're not all that good, or on second thought, maybe they are good, I dunno, I do love them, I mean.....no...no they're definitely, definitely not that good. My favorite Grease 2 tunes are "Back To School Again", "Score Tonight", and "Cool Rider". I love, love, love Michelle Pfeiffer starring and singing and performing in Grease 2. Without the worthwhile Michelle Pfeiffer there's really no telling how bad it might have got. Grease 2 is enjoyable at times though it is consistently bad, but it isn't too unsavory and it tries so good. It earns a good 5 rating wholly on its fun, lighthearted goodness, and for the presence of Pfeiffer. If I love Grease 2 this much, please understand just how much it is that I love Grease......sooooooooo, so very much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as bad as some say!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rcurton29906
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has some campy moments,but overall it is entertainment at it's finest.Do not compare it to the original as it stands on it's own merit.It is a return to the days when movies were fun.Just watch this movie with an open mind and have fun.It is an hour and half vacation.The music is awesome.I really like this movie,it's just fun to watch with the whole family.Michelle does a great job of being the bad girl in high school that every guy wants.Maxwell is awesome at being the "nerdy" English student who transform's himself into the cool dude.The T-Birds are supposed to be the "tuff" guys who are just a bunch of parrots that just repeat what there told,but do it great.Again,watch this movie with an open mind.You will enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease 2 stands on its own.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    simonkie
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease 2 is not a sequel. It has new characters and new story lines. People who criticize this film only because of the tittle of the movie. If they had named this movie Glee back in 1982 it would have been a big hit but many are biased toward this movie because they expected John Travolta or Olivia Newton John to be in it. This movie is very entertaining with catchy songs and an interesting story. What's even more impressive are the performances from the Maxwell Caulfield and Michelle Pfeiffer who were making their first feature film of their careers. Disregard the enormous expectations this movie had to live up to which was impossible and judge this movie on it's own merits and you will find much to enjoy from it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than Grease 1..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paypalscam9002
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no idea what is wrong with people bashing on this movie. Grease 2 is really really a great movie. I have watched it more than 10 times in my life and each time i'm having great fun watching it. I am very picky when it comes to movies. Most movies that i enjoy usually end up with an Oscar for best movie picture or something. Grease 2 is one of the few rare movies that i enjoy watching but didn't get any award. The way i see this is that Grease 2 is meant for a different type of audience. Back when i was in college, we (guys) had to impress girls in order to get them. We had to be cool, we had to be unreal (almost fake), we were creating an image to impress the girls. Of course, i don't do that anymore, (not as much. I'm married, got kids, and still got my motorcycle etc. But one thing that has changed since my college days is that i am more connected to reality now than i was in college. Grease 2 is about a nerds (maxwell) that wants THE Chix (pfeiffer ) but to do that he can't stay natural, he can't be himself so he has to impersonate an image. You see, this is exactly the daily reality for many teenagers. Observe how our teenagers behave today. No different than in Grease 2 (minus the music). I must admit, i was also a Geek guy trying to be cool, dreaming about some (impossible to get girl), when i was in college...and there was. Girls that (20 years later) i wish i had got even if my current wife is a very cute and sexy slim woman... Watching Grease 2 reminds me how i was in college. (like maxwell actually). To be more exact, i wished i was like maxwell. Because in Grease 2 he made it, he succeed getting pfeiffer. But in really it is much more complicated almost impossible for a Geek guy to get the most beautiful girl because the most beautiful girl usually can pick any guy she want. Being an educator in a high school, i can tell you that sex is probably to most spoken subject in our teenagers conversation and concern. To summarize: Grease 2 (from a guy point of view) is a movie for anyone who felt at one point in their college year in love with an (impossible to get girl). A guy who likes to dream and do crazy things just to impress someone, a good guy in nature. Grease 2 is a masterpiece (atleast) for some audience... I give it a 10/10 to re-balance that thrash reviews this movie has got but the real score should be around 8/10 objectively.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poor casting doomed this one from the start.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TOMASBBloodhound
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease 2 is one of the most ridiculed sequels of all time, and though it pales to the original, its certainly better than the rating would imply. The film is just more musical numbers and hijinks from the kids at Rydell High. Only this time, the new kid on the block is a guy trying to impress a cool chick. As opposed to a goody-two-shoes girl trying to win over a cool guy like we saw in the original. There are some cute songs and funny moments, but the two leads (Caulfield and Pfeiffer) just cannot live up to Olivia Newton-John or John Travolta. Not even close. First of all, neither can sing terribly well, and generally you'd like your leads in a musical to be able to sing. It really helps. Caulfield is somewhat more likable in the underdog role, but Pfeiffer's acting is really poor. She was a pretty face and little more at that point of her career. Her song "Cool Rider" is one of the film's worst. While singing it, she does look kind of sexy while climbing up to the top of a ladder and then straddling it. But then when she gets down she starts doing something resembling the Elaine dance from Seinfeld. Thumbs in the air and all! Weird. Director/choreographer Pat Birch should have fixed that. There are some good performances from some of the folks playing the T-Birds and Pink Ladies. Adrian Zmed provides some chuckles with his false bravado in many scenes. Chris McDonald who plays the Goose has been a solid performer in movies and TV for years. And you're telling me Lorna Luft is a daughter of Judy Garland? Who new? Its good to see some of the faculty members are back from the original, but Didi Conn doesn't seem to belong. It seems like the producers agreed and just kind of wrote her out of the movie by the third act. It's really kind of odd how this movie has been aired seemingly more than the popular original over the years. It didn't hurt Pfeiffer's career (nor did marrying producer David E. Kelly), but this movie destroyed Caulfield's before it even began. He has kept somewhat busy, and was even considered at one point for the James Bond role. But he's never been the star he perhaps could have been. Grease 2 isn't all bad. It's worth about 5 of 10 stars. The Hound.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not very well made.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hailee-rebecca
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you watched the original "Grease" then this will most likely be a disappointment. I liked the idea - the tough chick falling for the sweet guy, but I think it could have been produced much better. The music wasn't all that great, neither with the dance sequences. I knew before I turned it on that it would not be able to the exact standards "Grease" did but I didn't expect to be this much of a disappointment. Stick to watching the classic. Though, I'll admit, the movie wasn't totally bogus. I really enjoyed Micheal's character and I liked seeing Frenchy again - she was my favourite character from the original. I thought it was weird that the 'Pink Ladies' were now owned by the T-Birds; they couldn't date outside the group because they were the T-Birds girls. That just didn't match up to me. The 'Reproduction' scene was kind of cool, I suppose.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit N Miss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nfmorse
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is a sad attempt to capitalize on the original's success. almost EVERY scene with Michelle Pfeiffer is not era appropriate clothing or hair n make-up for the times. You could 'plunk' her, (and her character) out of this movie and insert her into St Elmo's Fire or The Breakfast Club and have everything current with the fashion of the time. did she insist on only doing this movie if she could appear in a manner as she wouldn't be embarrassed? i was Born in the 60's and she does NOT represent the 60's by a LONG shot. i did not ONCE see era appropriate hair one her.. where was the structure curl of 'roller setting' on her? and the Sad portrayal of every one of the main characters as IDIOTS. the making of this movie should NEVER have been associated with the first Grease and should have been made as more of a parody for the times, but not be linked with the first Grease. the characters of the first were NOT so shallow and stupid as these people were who were supposed to be following in the footsteps of COOL people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than it's given credit for
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    urthmothr
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We saw this movie before the original "Grease," and have always preferred "2." We identify more with the characters, the humor, the whole "superhero shtick," and fell in love with Michelle Pfeiffer long before we saw her in anything else! Lorna Luft as Paulette was a hoot, and we enjoyed the rest of the cast, including the "returning faculty" from "Grease," some of whom we remember from their old TV shows. The bomb shelter scene was especially meaningful to "baby boomer's" who grew up in the 50's and 60's. Our favorite song is "Cool Rider," and the ending chorus to "A Girl for All Seasons" was especially poignant. This was our generation, we are class of '63 in NJ and '64 in Georgia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sloppy Cash-in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one's got cash-in written all over it. The original Grease was no work of art, but at least it was entertaining and fun. Its sequel has all the hallmarks of studio greed, with a minimal amount of money spent in the hope of the greatest possible return. So we have mostly unfamiliar characters in familiar surroundings, and the only link to the original film  other than a few minor characters  is the fact that it's the same story with the roles reversed. This time it's bland pretty-boy Maxwell Caulfield (once touted as the next big thing, he was last seen in the equally bland English soap Emmerdale) as the straight one and a young and impossibly gorgeous Michelle Pfeiffer as the bad girl member of the T-Birds. Pfeiffer isn't really bad. She doesn't even misbehave, which is perhaps an indicator of how much the makers of this movie have watered down the contents of the original. The songs are dull and unmemorable, the humour is lame  and nobody realises Maxwell's the enigmatic biker because he's wearing goggles. To top it all, the damn thing goes on forever, clocking in at around the two hour mark.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's all pretend there was no 'Grease 2'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worse than 'Grease' in every department, this cash-in tries to recapture the bouncy atmosphere of its predecessor but fails spectacularly. In a rather desperate attempt to link the two films, Maxwell Caulfield is Sandy's cousin, who turns up at Rydell High and falls for Michelle Pfeiffer. He's bookish but she wants a biker, so Caulfield disguises himself as a mysterious goggled rider who defeats the bad guys and wins her heart, yeah! To be fair, this is likable enough and there are a couple of decent songs (with little connection to the story), but that just doesn't cut it when the tunes in 'Grease' were so memorable. It's a painless watch if you're in an iron lung and the nurse has left the TV on, but I think we all know it shouldn't exist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease 2 - (the sequel to) THE BEST MUSICAL EVER!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Grease 2! Going in to watching Grease 2 and expecting to see a musical sequel live up to the strong likes of Grease will certainly cause you to breakdown sobbing uncontrollably calling for your mommy all within a first few minutes of the film, but it's really NOT, all that bad well ya it is but still, it's a forgivable bad. Grease 2 is very ingratiating, just like Grease, but in a different vibe. The sequel just never has any chance at being as good as Grease, but still Grease 2 is such a guilty pleasure of mine. It's really not that bad. It's playful, very decent mild-mannered merriment. The songs are...so worse than the songs of Grease...let's not say that, let's say they're catchy good. I love the songs of Grease 2 even though they're not all that good, or on second thought, maybe they are good, I dunno, I do love them, I mean.....no...no they're definitely, definitely not that good. My favorite Grease 2 tunes are "Back To School Again", "Score Tonight", and "Cool Rider". I love, love, love Michelle Pfeiffer starring and singing and performing in Grease 2. Without the worthwhile Michelle Pfeiffer there's really no telling how bad it might have got. Grease 2 is enjoyable at times though it is consistently bad, but it isn't too unsavory and it tries so good. It earns a good 5 rating wholly on its fun, lighthearted goodness, and for the presence of Pfeiffer. If I love Grease 2 this much, please understand just how much it is that I love Grease......sooooooooo, so very much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as bad as some say!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rcurton29906
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has some campy moments,but overall it is entertainment at it's finest.Do not compare it to the original as it stands on it's own merit.It is a return to the days when movies were fun.Just watch this movie with an open mind and have fun.It is an hour and half vacation.The music is awesome.I really like this movie,it's just fun to watch with the whole family.Michelle does a great job of being the bad girl in high school that every guy wants.Maxwell is awesome at being the "nerdy" English student who transform's himself into the cool dude.The T-Birds are supposed to be the "tuff" guys who are just a bunch of parrots that just repeat what there told,but do it great.Again,watch this movie with an open mind.You will enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease 2 stands on its own.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    simonkie
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease 2 is not a sequel. It has new characters and new story lines. People who criticize this film only because of the tittle of the movie. If they had named this movie Glee back in 1982 it would have been a big hit but many are biased toward this movie because they expected John Travolta or Olivia Newton John to be in it. This movie is very entertaining with catchy songs and an interesting story. What's even more impressive are the performances from the Maxwell Caulfield and Michelle Pfeiffer who were making their first feature film of their careers. Disregard the enormous expectations this movie had to live up to which was impossible and judge this movie on it's own merits and you will find much to enjoy from it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than Grease 1..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paypalscam9002
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no idea what is wrong with people bashing on this movie. Grease 2 is really really a great movie. I have watched it more than 10 times in my life and each time i'm having great fun watching it. I am very picky when it comes to movies. Most movies that i enjoy usually end up with an Oscar for best movie picture or something. Grease 2 is one of the few rare movies that i enjoy watching but didn't get any award. The way i see this is that Grease 2 is meant for a different type of audience. Back when i was in college, we (guys) had to impress girls in order to get them. We had to be cool, we had to be unreal (almost fake), we were creating an image to impress the girls. Of course, i don't do that anymore, (not as much. I'm married, got kids, and still got my motorcycle etc. But one thing that has changed since my college days is that i am more connected to reality now than i was in college. Grease 2 is about a nerds (maxwell) that wants THE Chix (pfeiffer ) but to do that he can't stay natural, he can't be himself so he has to impersonate an image. You see, this is exactly the daily reality for many teenagers. Observe how our teenagers behave today. No different than in Grease 2 (minus the music). I must admit, i was also a Geek guy trying to be cool, dreaming about some (impossible to get girl), when i was in college...and there was. Girls that (20 years later) i wish i had got even if my current wife is a very cute and sexy slim woman... Watching Grease 2 reminds me how i was in college. (like maxwell actually). To be more exact, i wished i was like maxwell. Because in Grease 2 he made it, he succeed getting pfeiffer. But in really it is much more complicated almost impossible for a Geek guy to get the most beautiful girl because the most beautiful girl usually can pick any guy she want. Being an educator in a high school, i can tell you that sex is probably to most spoken subject in our teenagers conversation and concern. To summarize: Grease 2 (from a guy point of view) is a movie for anyone who felt at one point in their college year in love with an (impossible to get girl). A guy who likes to dream and do crazy things just to impress someone, a good guy in nature. Grease 2 is a masterpiece (atleast) for some audience... I give it a 10/10 to re-balance that thrash reviews this movie has got but the real score should be around 8/10 objectively.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poor casting doomed this one from the start.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TOMASBBloodhound
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease 2 is one of the most ridiculed sequels of all time, and though it pales to the original, its certainly better than the rating would imply. The film is just more musical numbers and hijinks from the kids at Rydell High. Only this time, the new kid on the block is a guy trying to impress a cool chick. As opposed to a goody-two-shoes girl trying to win over a cool guy like we saw in the original. There are some cute songs and funny moments, but the two leads (Caulfield and Pfeiffer) just cannot live up to Olivia Newton-John or John Travolta. Not even close. First of all, neither can sing terribly well, and generally you'd like your leads in a musical to be able to sing. It really helps. Caulfield is somewhat more likable in the underdog role, but Pfeiffer's acting is really poor. She was a pretty face and little more at that point of her career. Her song "Cool Rider" is one of the film's worst. While singing it, she does look kind of sexy while climbing up to the top of a ladder and then straddling it. But then when she gets down she starts doing something resembling the Elaine dance from Seinfeld. Thumbs in the air and all! Weird. Director/choreographer Pat Birch should have fixed that. There are some good performances from some of the folks playing the T-Birds and Pink Ladies. Adrian Zmed provides some chuckles with his false bravado in many scenes. Chris McDonald who plays the Goose has been a solid performer in movies and TV for years. And you're telling me Lorna Luft is a daughter of Judy Garland? Who new? Its good to see some of the faculty members are back from the original, but Didi Conn doesn't seem to belong. It seems like the producers agreed and just kind of wrote her out of the movie by the third act. It's really kind of odd how this movie has been aired seemingly more than the popular original over the years. It didn't hurt Pfeiffer's career (nor did marrying producer David E. Kelly), but this movie destroyed Caulfield's before it even began. He has kept somewhat busy, and was even considered at one point for the James Bond role. But he's never been the star he perhaps could have been. Grease 2 isn't all bad. It's worth about 5 of 10 stars. The Hound.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not very well made.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hailee-rebecca
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you watched the original "Grease" then this will most likely be a disappointment. I liked the idea - the tough chick falling for the sweet guy, but I think it could have been produced much better. The music wasn't all that great, neither with the dance sequences. I knew before I turned it on that it would not be able to the exact standards "Grease" did but I didn't expect to be this much of a disappointment. Stick to watching the classic. Though, I'll admit, the movie wasn't totally bogus. I really enjoyed Micheal's character and I liked seeing Frenchy again - she was my favourite character from the original. I thought it was weird that the 'Pink Ladies' were now owned by the T-Birds; they couldn't date outside the group because they were the T-Birds girls. That just didn't match up to me. The 'Reproduction' scene was kind of cool, I suppose.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit N Miss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nfmorse
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is a sad attempt to capitalize on the original's success. almost EVERY scene with Michelle Pfeiffer is not era appropriate clothing or hair n make-up for the times. You could 'plunk' her, (and her character) out of this movie and insert her into St Elmo's Fire or The Breakfast Club and have everything current with the fashion of the time. did she insist on only doing this movie if she could appear in a manner as she wouldn't be embarrassed? i was Born in the 60's and she does NOT represent the 60's by a LONG shot. i did not ONCE see era appropriate hair one her.. where was the structure curl of 'roller setting' on her? and the Sad portrayal of every one of the main characters as IDIOTS. the making of this movie should NEVER have been associated with the first Grease and should have been made as more of a parody for the times, but not be linked with the first Grease. the characters of the first were NOT so shallow and stupid as these people were who were supposed to be following in the footsteps of COOL people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than it's given credit for
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    urthmothr
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We saw this movie before the original "Grease," and have always preferred "2." We identify more with the characters, the humor, the whole "superhero shtick," and fell in love with Michelle Pfeiffer long before we saw her in anything else! Lorna Luft as Paulette was a hoot, and we enjoyed the rest of the cast, including the "returning faculty" from "Grease," some of whom we remember from their old TV shows. The bomb shelter scene was especially meaningful to "baby boomer's" who grew up in the 50's and 60's. Our favorite song is "Cool Rider," and the ending chorus to "A Girl for All Seasons" was especially poignant. This was our generation, we are class of '63 in NJ and '64 in Georgia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sloppy Cash-in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one's got cash-in written all over it. The original Grease was no work of art, but at least it was entertaining and fun. Its sequel has all the hallmarks of studio greed, with a minimal amount of money spent in the hope of the greatest possible return. So we have mostly unfamiliar characters in familiar surroundings, and the only link to the original film  other than a few minor characters  is the fact that it's the same story with the roles reversed. This time it's bland pretty-boy Maxwell Caulfield (once touted as the next big thing, he was last seen in the equally bland English soap Emmerdale) as the straight one and a young and impossibly gorgeous Michelle Pfeiffer as the bad girl member of the T-Birds. Pfeiffer isn't really bad. She doesn't even misbehave, which is perhaps an indicator of how much the makers of this movie have watered down the contents of the original. The songs are dull and unmemorable, the humour is lame  and nobody realises Maxwell's the enigmatic biker because he's wearing goggles. To top it all, the damn thing goes on forever, clocking in at around the two hour mark.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's all pretend there was no 'Grease 2'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worse than 'Grease' in every department, this cash-in tries to recapture the bouncy atmosphere of its predecessor but fails spectacularly. In a rather desperate attempt to link the two films, Maxwell Caulfield is Sandy's cousin, who turns up at Rydell High and falls for Michelle Pfeiffer. He's bookish but she wants a biker, so Caulfield disguises himself as a mysterious goggled rider who defeats the bad guys and wins her heart, yeah! To be fair, this is likable enough and there are a couple of decent songs (with little connection to the story), but that just doesn't cut it when the tunes in 'Grease' were so memorable. It's a painless watch if you're in an iron lung and the nurse has left the TV on, but I think we all know it shouldn't exist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease 2 - (the sequel to) THE BEST MUSICAL EVER!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Grease 2! Going in to watching Grease 2 and expecting to see a musical sequel live up to the strong likes of Grease will certainly cause you to breakdown sobbing uncontrollably calling for your mommy all within a first few minutes of the film, but it's really NOT, all that bad well ya it is but still, it's a forgivable bad. Grease 2 is very ingratiating, just like Grease, but in a different vibe. The sequel just never has any chance at being as good as Grease, but still Grease 2 is such a guilty pleasure of mine. It's really not that bad. It's playful, very decent mild-mannered merriment. The songs are...so worse than the songs of Grease...let's not say that, let's say they're catchy good. I love the songs of Grease 2 even though they're not all that good, or on second thought, maybe they are good, I dunno, I do love them, I mean.....no...no they're definitely, definitely not that good. My favorite Grease 2 tunes are "Back To School Again", "Score Tonight", and "Cool Rider". I love, love, love Michelle Pfeiffer starring and singing and performing in Grease 2. Without the worthwhile Michelle Pfeiffer there's really no telling how bad it might have got. Grease 2 is enjoyable at times though it is consistently bad, but it isn't too unsavory and it tries so good. It earns a good 5 rating wholly on its fun, lighthearted goodness, and for the presence of Pfeiffer. If I love Grease 2 this much, please understand just how much it is that I love Grease......sooooooooo, so very much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as bad as some say!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rcurton29906
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has some campy moments,but overall it is entertainment at it's finest.Do not compare it to the original as it stands on it's own merit.It is a return to the days when movies were fun.Just watch this movie with an open mind and have fun.It is an hour and half vacation.The music is awesome.I really like this movie,it's just fun to watch with the whole family.Michelle does a great job of being the bad girl in high school that every guy wants.Maxwell is awesome at being the "nerdy" English student who transform's himself into the cool dude.The T-Birds are supposed to be the "tuff" guys who are just a bunch of parrots that just repeat what there told,but do it great.Again,watch this movie with an open mind.You will enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease 2 stands on its own.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    simonkie
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease 2 is not a sequel. It has new characters and new story lines. People who criticize this film only because of the tittle of the movie. If they had named this movie Glee back in 1982 it would have been a big hit but many are biased toward this movie because they expected John Travolta or Olivia Newton John to be in it. This movie is very entertaining with catchy songs and an interesting story. What's even more impressive are the performances from the Maxwell Caulfield and Michelle Pfeiffer who were making their first feature film of their careers. Disregard the enormous expectations this movie had to live up to which was impossible and judge this movie on it's own merits and you will find much to enjoy from it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than Grease 1..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paypalscam9002
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no idea what is wrong with people bashing on this movie. Grease 2 is really really a great movie. I have watched it more than 10 times in my life and each time i'm having great fun watching it. I am very picky when it comes to movies. Most movies that i enjoy usually end up with an Oscar for best movie picture or something. Grease 2 is one of the few rare movies that i enjoy watching but didn't get any award. The way i see this is that Grease 2 is meant for a different type of audience. Back when i was in college, we (guys) had to impress girls in order to get them. We had to be cool, we had to be unreal (almost fake), we were creating an image to impress the girls. Of course, i don't do that anymore, (not as much. I'm married, got kids, and still got my motorcycle etc. But one thing that has changed since my college days is that i am more connected to reality now than i was in college. Grease 2 is about a nerds (maxwell) that wants THE Chix (pfeiffer ) but to do that he can't stay natural, he can't be himself so he has to impersonate an image. You see, this is exactly the daily reality for many teenagers. Observe how our teenagers behave today. No different than in Grease 2 (minus the music). I must admit, i was also a Geek guy trying to be cool, dreaming about some (impossible to get girl), when i was in college...and there was. Girls that (20 years later) i wish i had got even if my current wife is a very cute and sexy slim woman... Watching Grease 2 reminds me how i was in college. (like maxwell actually). To be more exact, i wished i was like maxwell. Because in Grease 2 he made it, he succeed getting pfeiffer. But in really it is much more complicated almost impossible for a Geek guy to get the most beautiful girl because the most beautiful girl usually can pick any guy she want. Being an educator in a high school, i can tell you that sex is probably to most spoken subject in our teenagers conversation and concern. To summarize: Grease 2 (from a guy point of view) is a movie for anyone who felt at one point in their college year in love with an (impossible to get girl). A guy who likes to dream and do crazy things just to impress someone, a good guy in nature. Grease 2 is a masterpiece (atleast) for some audience... I give it a 10/10 to re-balance that thrash reviews this movie has got but the real score should be around 8/10 objectively.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poor casting doomed this one from the start.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TOMASBBloodhound
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease 2 is one of the most ridiculed sequels of all time, and though it pales to the original, its certainly better than the rating would imply. The film is just more musical numbers and hijinks from the kids at Rydell High. Only this time, the new kid on the block is a guy trying to impress a cool chick. As opposed to a goody-two-shoes girl trying to win over a cool guy like we saw in the original. There are some cute songs and funny moments, but the two leads (Caulfield and Pfeiffer) just cannot live up to Olivia Newton-John or John Travolta. Not even close. First of all, neither can sing terribly well, and generally you'd like your leads in a musical to be able to sing. It really helps. Caulfield is somewhat more likable in the underdog role, but Pfeiffer's acting is really poor. She was a pretty face and little more at that point of her career. Her song "Cool Rider" is one of the film's worst. While singing it, she does look kind of sexy while climbing up to the top of a ladder and then straddling it. But then when she gets down she starts doing something resembling the Elaine dance from Seinfeld. Thumbs in the air and all! Weird. Director/choreographer Pat Birch should have fixed that. There are some good performances from some of the folks playing the T-Birds and Pink Ladies. Adrian Zmed provides some chuckles with his false bravado in many scenes. Chris McDonald who plays the Goose has been a solid performer in movies and TV for years. And you're telling me Lorna Luft is a daughter of Judy Garland? Who new? Its good to see some of the faculty members are back from the original, but Didi Conn doesn't seem to belong. It seems like the producers agreed and just kind of wrote her out of the movie by the third act. It's really kind of odd how this movie has been aired seemingly more than the popular original over the years. It didn't hurt Pfeiffer's career (nor did marrying producer David E. Kelly), but this movie destroyed Caulfield's before it even began. He has kept somewhat busy, and was even considered at one point for the James Bond role. But he's never been the star he perhaps could have been. Grease 2 isn't all bad. It's worth about 5 of 10 stars. The Hound.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not very well made.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hailee-rebecca
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you watched the original "Grease" then this will most likely be a disappointment. I liked the idea - the tough chick falling for the sweet guy, but I think it could have been produced much better. The music wasn't all that great, neither with the dance sequences. I knew before I turned it on that it would not be able to the exact standards "Grease" did but I didn't expect to be this much of a disappointment. Stick to watching the classic. Though, I'll admit, the movie wasn't totally bogus. I really enjoyed Micheal's character and I liked seeing Frenchy again - she was my favourite character from the original. I thought it was weird that the 'Pink Ladies' were now owned by the T-Birds; they couldn't date outside the group because they were the T-Birds girls. That just didn't match up to me. The 'Reproduction' scene was kind of cool, I suppose.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit N Miss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nfmorse
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is a sad attempt to capitalize on the original's success. almost EVERY scene with Michelle Pfeiffer is not era appropriate clothing or hair n make-up for the times. You could 'plunk' her, (and her character) out of this movie and insert her into St Elmo's Fire or The Breakfast Club and have everything current with the fashion of the time. did she insist on only doing this movie if she could appear in a manner as she wouldn't be embarrassed? i was Born in the 60's and she does NOT represent the 60's by a LONG shot. i did not ONCE see era appropriate hair one her.. where was the structure curl of 'roller setting' on her? and the Sad portrayal of every one of the main characters as IDIOTS. the making of this movie should NEVER have been associated with the first Grease and should have been made as more of a parody for the times, but not be linked with the first Grease. the characters of the first were NOT so shallow and stupid as these people were who were supposed to be following in the footsteps of COOL people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than it's given credit for
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    urthmothr
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We saw this movie before the original "Grease," and have always preferred "2." We identify more with the characters, the humor, the whole "superhero shtick," and fell in love with Michelle Pfeiffer long before we saw her in anything else! Lorna Luft as Paulette was a hoot, and we enjoyed the rest of the cast, including the "returning faculty" from "Grease," some of whom we remember from their old TV shows. The bomb shelter scene was especially meaningful to "baby boomer's" who grew up in the 50's and 60's. Our favorite song is "Cool Rider," and the ending chorus to "A Girl for All Seasons" was especially poignant. This was our generation, we are class of '63 in NJ and '64 in Georgia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sloppy Cash-in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one's got cash-in written all over it. The original Grease was no work of art, but at least it was entertaining and fun. Its sequel has all the hallmarks of studio greed, with a minimal amount of money spent in the hope of the greatest possible return. So we have mostly unfamiliar characters in familiar surroundings, and the only link to the original film  other than a few minor characters  is the fact that it's the same story with the roles reversed. This time it's bland pretty-boy Maxwell Caulfield (once touted as the next big thing, he was last seen in the equally bland English soap Emmerdale) as the straight one and a young and impossibly gorgeous Michelle Pfeiffer as the bad girl member of the T-Birds. Pfeiffer isn't really bad. She doesn't even misbehave, which is perhaps an indicator of how much the makers of this movie have watered down the contents of the original. The songs are dull and unmemorable, the humour is lame  and nobody realises Maxwell's the enigmatic biker because he's wearing goggles. To top it all, the damn thing goes on forever, clocking in at around the two hour mark.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's all pretend there was no 'Grease 2'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worse than 'Grease' in every department, this cash-in tries to recapture the bouncy atmosphere of its predecessor but fails spectacularly. In a rather desperate attempt to link the two films, Maxwell Caulfield is Sandy's cousin, who turns up at Rydell High and falls for Michelle Pfeiffer. He's bookish but she wants a biker, so Caulfield disguises himself as a mysterious goggled rider who defeats the bad guys and wins her heart, yeah! To be fair, this is likable enough and there are a couple of decent songs (with little connection to the story), but that just doesn't cut it when the tunes in 'Grease' were so memorable. It's a painless watch if you're in an iron lung and the nurse has left the TV on, but I think we all know it shouldn't exist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease 2 - (the sequel to) THE BEST MUSICAL EVER!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Grease 2! Going in to watching Grease 2 and expecting to see a musical sequel live up to the strong likes of Grease will certainly cause you to breakdown sobbing uncontrollably calling for your mommy all within a first few minutes of the film, but it's really NOT, all that bad well ya it is but still, it's a forgivable bad. Grease 2 is very ingratiating, just like Grease, but in a different vibe. The sequel just never has any chance at being as good as Grease, but still Grease 2 is such a guilty pleasure of mine. It's really not that bad. It's playful, very decent mild-mannered merriment. The songs are...so worse than the songs of Grease...let's not say that, let's say they're catchy good. I love the songs of Grease 2 even though they're not all that good, or on second thought, maybe they are good, I dunno, I do love them, I mean.....no...no they're definitely, definitely not that good. My favorite Grease 2 tunes are "Back To School Again", "Score Tonight", and "Cool Rider". I love, love, love Michelle Pfeiffer starring and singing and performing in Grease 2. Without the worthwhile Michelle Pfeiffer there's really no telling how bad it might have got. Grease 2 is enjoyable at times though it is consistently bad, but it isn't too unsavory and it tries so good. It earns a good 5 rating wholly on its fun, lighthearted goodness, and for the presence of Pfeiffer. If I love Grease 2 this much, please understand just how much it is that I love Grease......sooooooooo, so very much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as bad as some say!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rcurton29906
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has some campy moments,but overall it is entertainment at it's finest.Do not compare it to the original as it stands on it's own merit.It is a return to the days when movies were fun.Just watch this movie with an open mind and have fun.It is an hour and half vacation.The music is awesome.I really like this movie,it's just fun to watch with the whole family.Michelle does a great job of being the bad girl in high school that every guy wants.Maxwell is awesome at being the "nerdy" English student who transform's himself into the cool dude.The T-Birds are supposed to be the "tuff" guys who are just a bunch of parrots that just repeat what there told,but do it great.Again,watch this movie with an open mind.You will enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease 2 stands on its own.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    simonkie
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease 2 is not a sequel. It has new characters and new story lines. People who criticize this film only because of the tittle of the movie. If they had named this movie Glee back in 1982 it would have been a big hit but many are biased toward this movie because they expected John Travolta or Olivia Newton John to be in it. This movie is very entertaining with catchy songs and an interesting story. What's even more impressive are the performances from the Maxwell Caulfield and Michelle Pfeiffer who were making their first feature film of their careers. Disregard the enormous expectations this movie had to live up to which was impossible and judge this movie on it's own merits and you will find much to enjoy from it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than Grease 1..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paypalscam9002
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no idea what is wrong with people bashing on this movie. Grease 2 is really really a great movie. I have watched it more than 10 times in my life and each time i'm having great fun watching it. I am very picky when it comes to movies. Most movies that i enjoy usually end up with an Oscar for best movie picture or something. Grease 2 is one of the few rare movies that i enjoy watching but didn't get any award. The way i see this is that Grease 2 is meant for a different type of audience. Back when i was in college, we (guys) had to impress girls in order to get them. We had to be cool, we had to be unreal (almost fake), we were creating an image to impress the girls. Of course, i don't do that anymore, (not as much. I'm married, got kids, and still got my motorcycle etc. But one thing that has changed since my college days is that i am more connected to reality now than i was in college. Grease 2 is about a nerds (maxwell) that wants THE Chix (pfeiffer ) but to do that he can't stay natural, he can't be himself so he has to impersonate an image. You see, this is exactly the daily reality for many teenagers. Observe how our teenagers behave today. No different than in Grease 2 (minus the music). I must admit, i was also a Geek guy trying to be cool, dreaming about some (impossible to get girl), when i was in college...and there was. Girls that (20 years later) i wish i had got even if my current wife is a very cute and sexy slim woman... Watching Grease 2 reminds me how i was in college. (like maxwell actually). To be more exact, i wished i was like maxwell. Because in Grease 2 he made it, he succeed getting pfeiffer. But in really it is much more complicated almost impossible for a Geek guy to get the most beautiful girl because the most beautiful girl usually can pick any guy she want. Being an educator in a high school, i can tell you that sex is probably to most spoken subject in our teenagers conversation and concern. To summarize: Grease 2 (from a guy point of view) is a movie for anyone who felt at one point in their college year in love with an (impossible to get girl). A guy who likes to dream and do crazy things just to impress someone, a good guy in nature. Grease 2 is a masterpiece (atleast) for some audience... I give it a 10/10 to re-balance that thrash reviews this movie has got but the real score should be around 8/10 objectively.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poor casting doomed this one from the start.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TOMASBBloodhound
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease 2 is one of the most ridiculed sequels of all time, and though it pales to the original, its certainly better than the rating would imply. The film is just more musical numbers and hijinks from the kids at Rydell High. Only this time, the new kid on the block is a guy trying to impress a cool chick. As opposed to a goody-two-shoes girl trying to win over a cool guy like we saw in the original. There are some cute songs and funny moments, but the two leads (Caulfield and Pfeiffer) just cannot live up to Olivia Newton-John or John Travolta. Not even close. First of all, neither can sing terribly well, and generally you'd like your leads in a musical to be able to sing. It really helps. Caulfield is somewhat more likable in the underdog role, but Pfeiffer's acting is really poor. She was a pretty face and little more at that point of her career. Her song "Cool Rider" is one of the film's worst. While singing it, she does look kind of sexy while climbing up to the top of a ladder and then straddling it. But then when she gets down she starts doing something resembling the Elaine dance from Seinfeld. Thumbs in the air and all! Weird. Director/choreographer Pat Birch should have fixed that. There are some good performances from some of the folks playing the T-Birds and Pink Ladies. Adrian Zmed provides some chuckles with his false bravado in many scenes. Chris McDonald who plays the Goose has been a solid performer in movies and TV for years. And you're telling me Lorna Luft is a daughter of Judy Garland? Who new? Its good to see some of the faculty members are back from the original, but Didi Conn doesn't seem to belong. It seems like the producers agreed and just kind of wrote her out of the movie by the third act. It's really kind of odd how this movie has been aired seemingly more than the popular original over the years. It didn't hurt Pfeiffer's career (nor did marrying producer David E. Kelly), but this movie destroyed Caulfield's before it even began. He has kept somewhat busy, and was even considered at one point for the James Bond role. But he's never been the star he perhaps could have been. Grease 2 isn't all bad. It's worth about 5 of 10 stars. The Hound.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not very well made.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hailee-rebecca
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you watched the original "Grease" then this will most likely be a disappointment. I liked the idea - the tough chick falling for the sweet guy, but I think it could have been produced much better. The music wasn't all that great, neither with the dance sequences. I knew before I turned it on that it would not be able to the exact standards "Grease" did but I didn't expect to be this much of a disappointment. Stick to watching the classic. Though, I'll admit, the movie wasn't totally bogus. I really enjoyed Micheal's character and I liked seeing Frenchy again - she was my favourite character from the original. I thought it was weird that the 'Pink Ladies' were now owned by the T-Birds; they couldn't date outside the group because they were the T-Birds girls. That just didn't match up to me. The 'Reproduction' scene was kind of cool, I suppose.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit N Miss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nfmorse
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is a sad attempt to capitalize on the original's success. almost EVERY scene with Michelle Pfeiffer is not era appropriate clothing or hair n make-up for the times. You could 'plunk' her, (and her character) out of this movie and insert her into St Elmo's Fire or The Breakfast Club and have everything current with the fashion of the time. did she insist on only doing this movie if she could appear in a manner as she wouldn't be embarrassed? i was Born in the 60's and she does NOT represent the 60's by a LONG shot. i did not ONCE see era appropriate hair one her.. where was the structure curl of 'roller setting' on her? and the Sad portrayal of every one of the main characters as IDIOTS. the making of this movie should NEVER have been associated with the first Grease and should have been made as more of a parody for the times, but not be linked with the first Grease. the characters of the first were NOT so shallow and stupid as these people were who were supposed to be following in the footsteps of COOL people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than it's given credit for
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    urthmothr
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We saw this movie before the original "Grease," and have always preferred "2." We identify more with the characters, the humor, the whole "superhero shtick," and fell in love with Michelle Pfeiffer long before we saw her in anything else! Lorna Luft as Paulette was a hoot, and we enjoyed the rest of the cast, including the "returning faculty" from "Grease," some of whom we remember from their old TV shows. The bomb shelter scene was especially meaningful to "baby boomer's" who grew up in the 50's and 60's. Our favorite song is "Cool Rider," and the ending chorus to "A Girl for All Seasons" was especially poignant. This was our generation, we are class of '63 in NJ and '64 in Georgia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sloppy Cash-in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one's got cash-in written all over it. The original Grease was no work of art, but at least it was entertaining and fun. Its sequel has all the hallmarks of studio greed, with a minimal amount of money spent in the hope of the greatest possible return. So we have mostly unfamiliar characters in familiar surroundings, and the only link to the original film  other than a few minor characters  is the fact that it's the same story with the roles reversed. This time it's bland pretty-boy Maxwell Caulfield (once touted as the next big thing, he was last seen in the equally bland English soap Emmerdale) as the straight one and a young and impossibly gorgeous Michelle Pfeiffer as the bad girl member of the T-Birds. Pfeiffer isn't really bad. She doesn't even misbehave, which is perhaps an indicator of how much the makers of this movie have watered down the contents of the original. The songs are dull and unmemorable, the humour is lame  and nobody realises Maxwell's the enigmatic biker because he's wearing goggles. To top it all, the damn thing goes on forever, clocking in at around the two hour mark.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's all pretend there was no 'Grease 2'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worse than 'Grease' in every department, this cash-in tries to recapture the bouncy atmosphere of its predecessor but fails spectacularly. In a rather desperate attempt to link the two films, Maxwell Caulfield is Sandy's cousin, who turns up at Rydell High and falls for Michelle Pfeiffer. He's bookish but she wants a biker, so Caulfield disguises himself as a mysterious goggled rider who defeats the bad guys and wins her heart, yeah! To be fair, this is likable enough and there are a couple of decent songs (with little connection to the story), but that just doesn't cut it when the tunes in 'Grease' were so memorable. It's a painless watch if you're in an iron lung and the nurse has left the TV on, but I think we all know it shouldn't exist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease 2 - (the sequel to) THE BEST MUSICAL EVER!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Grease 2! Going in to watching Grease 2 and expecting to see a musical sequel live up to the strong likes of Grease will certainly cause you to breakdown sobbing uncontrollably calling for your mommy all within a first few minutes of the film, but it's really NOT, all that bad well ya it is but still, it's a forgivable bad. Grease 2 is very ingratiating, just like Grease, but in a different vibe. The sequel just never has any chance at being as good as Grease, but still Grease 2 is such a guilty pleasure of mine. It's really not that bad. It's playful, very decent mild-mannered merriment. The songs are...so worse than the songs of Grease...let's not say that, let's say they're catchy good. I love the songs of Grease 2 even though they're not all that good, or on second thought, maybe they are good, I dunno, I do love them, I mean.....no...no they're definitely, definitely not that good. My favorite Grease 2 tunes are "Back To School Again", "Score Tonight", and "Cool Rider". I love, love, love Michelle Pfeiffer starring and singing and performing in Grease 2. Without the worthwhile Michelle Pfeiffer there's really no telling how bad it might have got. Grease 2 is enjoyable at times though it is consistently bad, but it isn't too unsavory and it tries so good. It earns a good 5 rating wholly on its fun, lighthearted goodness, and for the presence of Pfeiffer. If I love Grease 2 this much, please understand just how much it is that I love Grease......sooooooooo, so very much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as bad as some say!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rcurton29906
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has some campy moments,but overall it is entertainment at it's finest.Do not compare it to the original as it stands on it's own merit.It is a return to the days when movies were fun.Just watch this movie with an open mind and have fun.It is an hour and half vacation.The music is awesome.I really like this movie,it's just fun to watch with the whole family.Michelle does a great job of being the bad girl in high school that every guy wants.Maxwell is awesome at being the "nerdy" English student who transform's himself into the cool dude.The T-Birds are supposed to be the "tuff" guys who are just a bunch of parrots that just repeat what there told,but do it great.Again,watch this movie with an open mind.You will enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease 2 stands on its own.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    simonkie
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease 2 is not a sequel. It has new characters and new story lines. People who criticize this film only because of the tittle of the movie. If they had named this movie Glee back in 1982 it would have been a big hit but many are biased toward this movie because they expected John Travolta or Olivia Newton John to be in it. This movie is very entertaining with catchy songs and an interesting story. What's even more impressive are the performances from the Maxwell Caulfield and Michelle Pfeiffer who were making their first feature film of their careers. Disregard the enormous expectations this movie had to live up to which was impossible and judge this movie on it's own merits and you will find much to enjoy from it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than Grease 1..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paypalscam9002
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no idea what is wrong with people bashing on this movie. Grease 2 is really really a great movie. I have watched it more than 10 times in my life and each time i'm having great fun watching it. I am very picky when it comes to movies. Most movies that i enjoy usually end up with an Oscar for best movie picture or something. Grease 2 is one of the few rare movies that i enjoy watching but didn't get any award. The way i see this is that Grease 2 is meant for a different type of audience. Back when i was in college, we (guys) had to impress girls in order to get them. We had to be cool, we had to be unreal (almost fake), we were creating an image to impress the girls. Of course, i don't do that anymore, (not as much. I'm married, got kids, and still got my motorcycle etc. But one thing that has changed since my college days is that i am more connected to reality now than i was in college. Grease 2 is about a nerds (maxwell) that wants THE Chix (pfeiffer ) but to do that he can't stay natural, he can't be himself so he has to impersonate an image. You see, this is exactly the daily reality for many teenagers. Observe how our teenagers behave today. No different than in Grease 2 (minus the music). I must admit, i was also a Geek guy trying to be cool, dreaming about some (impossible to get girl), when i was in college...and there was. Girls that (20 years later) i wish i had got even if my current wife is a very cute and sexy slim woman... Watching Grease 2 reminds me how i was in college. (like maxwell actually). To be more exact, i wished i was like maxwell. Because in Grease 2 he made it, he succeed getting pfeiffer. But in really it is much more complicated almost impossible for a Geek guy to get the most beautiful girl because the most beautiful girl usually can pick any guy she want. Being an educator in a high school, i can tell you that sex is probably to most spoken subject in our teenagers conversation and concern. To summarize: Grease 2 (from a guy point of view) is a movie for anyone who felt at one point in their college year in love with an (impossible to get girl). A guy who likes to dream and do crazy things just to impress someone, a good guy in nature. Grease 2 is a masterpiece (atleast) for some audience... I give it a 10/10 to re-balance that thrash reviews this movie has got but the real score should be around 8/10 objectively.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poor casting doomed this one from the start.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TOMASBBloodhound
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease 2 is one of the most ridiculed sequels of all time, and though it pales to the original, its certainly better than the rating would imply. The film is just more musical numbers and hijinks from the kids at Rydell High. Only this time, the new kid on the block is a guy trying to impress a cool chick. As opposed to a goody-two-shoes girl trying to win over a cool guy like we saw in the original. There are some cute songs and funny moments, but the two leads (Caulfield and Pfeiffer) just cannot live up to Olivia Newton-John or John Travolta. Not even close. First of all, neither can sing terribly well, and generally you'd like your leads in a musical to be able to sing. It really helps. Caulfield is somewhat more likable in the underdog role, but Pfeiffer's acting is really poor. She was a pretty face and little more at that point of her career. Her song "Cool Rider" is one of the film's worst. While singing it, she does look kind of sexy while climbing up to the top of a ladder and then straddling it. But then when she gets down she starts doing something resembling the Elaine dance from Seinfeld. Thumbs in the air and all! Weird. Director/choreographer Pat Birch should have fixed that. There are some good performances from some of the folks playing the T-Birds and Pink Ladies. Adrian Zmed provides some chuckles with his false bravado in many scenes. Chris McDonald who plays the Goose has been a solid performer in movies and TV for years. And you're telling me Lorna Luft is a daughter of Judy Garland? Who new? Its good to see some of the faculty members are back from the original, but Didi Conn doesn't seem to belong. It seems like the producers agreed and just kind of wrote her out of the movie by the third act. It's really kind of odd how this movie has been aired seemingly more than the popular original over the years. It didn't hurt Pfeiffer's career (nor did marrying producer David E. Kelly), but this movie destroyed Caulfield's before it even began. He has kept somewhat busy, and was even considered at one point for the James Bond role. But he's never been the star he perhaps could have been. Grease 2 isn't all bad. It's worth about 5 of 10 stars. The Hound.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not very well made.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hailee-rebecca
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you watched the original "Grease" then this will most likely be a disappointment. I liked the idea - the tough chick falling for the sweet guy, but I think it could have been produced much better. The music wasn't all that great, neither with the dance sequences. I knew before I turned it on that it would not be able to the exact standards "Grease" did but I didn't expect to be this much of a disappointment. Stick to watching the classic. Though, I'll admit, the movie wasn't totally bogus. I really enjoyed Micheal's character and I liked seeing Frenchy again - she was my favourite character from the original. I thought it was weird that the 'Pink Ladies' were now owned by the T-Birds; they couldn't date outside the group because they were the T-Birds girls. That just didn't match up to me. The 'Reproduction' scene was kind of cool, I suppose.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit N Miss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nfmorse
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is a sad attempt to capitalize on the original's success. almost EVERY scene with Michelle Pfeiffer is not era appropriate clothing or hair n make-up for the times. You could 'plunk' her, (and her character) out of this movie and insert her into St Elmo's Fire or The Breakfast Club and have everything current with the fashion of the time. did she insist on only doing this movie if she could appear in a manner as she wouldn't be embarrassed? i was Born in the 60's and she does NOT represent the 60's by a LONG shot. i did not ONCE see era appropriate hair one her.. where was the structure curl of 'roller setting' on her? and the Sad portrayal of every one of the main characters as IDIOTS. the making of this movie should NEVER have been associated with the first Grease and should have been made as more of a parody for the times, but not be linked with the first Grease. the characters of the first were NOT so shallow and stupid as these people were who were supposed to be following in the footsteps of COOL people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than it's given credit for
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    urthmothr
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We saw this movie before the original "Grease," and have always preferred "2." We identify more with the characters, the humor, the whole "superhero shtick," and fell in love with Michelle Pfeiffer long before we saw her in anything else! Lorna Luft as Paulette was a hoot, and we enjoyed the rest of the cast, including the "returning faculty" from "Grease," some of whom we remember from their old TV shows. The bomb shelter scene was especially meaningful to "baby boomer's" who grew up in the 50's and 60's. Our favorite song is "Cool Rider," and the ending chorus to "A Girl for All Seasons" was especially poignant. This was our generation, we are class of '63 in NJ and '64 in Georgia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sloppy Cash-in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one's got cash-in written all over it. The original Grease was no work of art, but at least it was entertaining and fun. Its sequel has all the hallmarks of studio greed, with a minimal amount of money spent in the hope of the greatest possible return. So we have mostly unfamiliar characters in familiar surroundings, and the only link to the original film  other than a few minor characters  is the fact that it's the same story with the roles reversed. This time it's bland pretty-boy Maxwell Caulfield (once touted as the next big thing, he was last seen in the equally bland English soap Emmerdale) as the straight one and a young and impossibly gorgeous Michelle Pfeiffer as the bad girl member of the T-Birds. Pfeiffer isn't really bad. She doesn't even misbehave, which is perhaps an indicator of how much the makers of this movie have watered down the contents of the original. The songs are dull and unmemorable, the humour is lame  and nobody realises Maxwell's the enigmatic biker because he's wearing goggles. To top it all, the damn thing goes on forever, clocking in at around the two hour mark.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's all pretend there was no 'Grease 2'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worse than 'Grease' in every department, this cash-in tries to recapture the bouncy atmosphere of its predecessor but fails spectacularly. In a rather desperate attempt to link the two films, Maxwell Caulfield is Sandy's cousin, who turns up at Rydell High and falls for Michelle Pfeiffer. He's bookish but she wants a biker, so Caulfield disguises himself as a mysterious goggled rider who defeats the bad guys and wins her heart, yeah! To be fair, this is likable enough and there are a couple of decent songs (with little connection to the story), but that just doesn't cut it when the tunes in 'Grease' were so memorable. It's a painless watch if you're in an iron lung and the nurse has left the TV on, but I think we all know it shouldn't exist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease 2 - (the sequel to) THE BEST MUSICAL EVER!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Grease 2! Going in to watching Grease 2 and expecting to see a musical sequel live up to the strong likes of Grease will certainly cause you to breakdown sobbing uncontrollably calling for your mommy all within a first few minutes of the film, but it's really NOT, all that bad well ya it is but still, it's a forgivable bad. Grease 2 is very ingratiating, just like Grease, but in a different vibe. The sequel just never has any chance at being as good as Grease, but still Grease 2 is such a guilty pleasure of mine. It's really not that bad. It's playful, very decent mild-mannered merriment. The songs are...so worse than the songs of Grease...let's not say that, let's say they're catchy good. I love the songs of Grease 2 even though they're not all that good, or on second thought, maybe they are good, I dunno, I do love them, I mean.....no...no they're definitely, definitely not that good. My favorite Grease 2 tunes are "Back To School Again", "Score Tonight", and "Cool Rider". I love, love, love Michelle Pfeiffer starring and singing and performing in Grease 2. Without the worthwhile Michelle Pfeiffer there's really no telling how bad it might have got. Grease 2 is enjoyable at times though it is consistently bad, but it isn't too unsavory and it tries so good. It earns a good 5 rating wholly on its fun, lighthearted goodness, and for the presence of Pfeiffer. If I love Grease 2 this much, please understand just how much it is that I love Grease......sooooooooo, so very much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as bad as some say!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rcurton29906
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has some campy moments,but overall it is entertainment at it's finest.Do not compare it to the original as it stands on it's own merit.It is a return to the days when movies were fun.Just watch this movie with an open mind and have fun.It is an hour and half vacation.The music is awesome.I really like this movie,it's just fun to watch with the whole family.Michelle does a great job of being the bad girl in high school that every guy wants.Maxwell is awesome at being the "nerdy" English student who transform's himself into the cool dude.The T-Birds are supposed to be the "tuff" guys who are just a bunch of parrots that just repeat what there told,but do it great.Again,watch this movie with an open mind.You will enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease 2 stands on its own.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    simonkie
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease 2 is not a sequel. It has new characters and new story lines. People who criticize this film only because of the tittle of the movie. If they had named this movie Glee back in 1982 it would have been a big hit but many are biased toward this movie because they expected John Travolta or Olivia Newton John to be in it. This movie is very entertaining with catchy songs and an interesting story. What's even more impressive are the performances from the Maxwell Caulfield and Michelle Pfeiffer who were making their first feature film of their careers. Disregard the enormous expectations this movie had to live up to which was impossible and judge this movie on it's own merits and you will find much to enjoy from it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than Grease 1..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paypalscam9002
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no idea what is wrong with people bashing on this movie. Grease 2 is really really a great movie. I have watched it more than 10 times in my life and each time i'm having great fun watching it. I am very picky when it comes to movies. Most movies that i enjoy usually end up with an Oscar for best movie picture or something. Grease 2 is one of the few rare movies that i enjoy watching but didn't get any award. The way i see this is that Grease 2 is meant for a different type of audience. Back when i was in college, we (guys) had to impress girls in order to get them. We had to be cool, we had to be unreal (almost fake), we were creating an image to impress the girls. Of course, i don't do that anymore, (not as much. I'm married, got kids, and still got my motorcycle etc. But one thing that has changed since my college days is that i am more connected to reality now than i was in college. Grease 2 is about a nerds (maxwell) that wants THE Chix (pfeiffer ) but to do that he can't stay natural, he can't be himself so he has to impersonate an image. You see, this is exactly the daily reality for many teenagers. Observe how our teenagers behave today. No different than in Grease 2 (minus the music). I must admit, i was also a Geek guy trying to be cool, dreaming about some (impossible to get girl), when i was in college...and there was. Girls that (20 years later) i wish i had got even if my current wife is a very cute and sexy slim woman... Watching Grease 2 reminds me how i was in college. (like maxwell actually). To be more exact, i wished i was like maxwell. Because in Grease 2 he made it, he succeed getting pfeiffer. But in really it is much more complicated almost impossible for a Geek guy to get the most beautiful girl because the most beautiful girl usually can pick any guy she want. Being an educator in a high school, i can tell you that sex is probably to most spoken subject in our teenagers conversation and concern. To summarize: Grease 2 (from a guy point of view) is a movie for anyone who felt at one point in their college year in love with an (impossible to get girl). A guy who likes to dream and do crazy things just to impress someone, a good guy in nature. Grease 2 is a masterpiece (atleast) for some audience... I give it a 10/10 to re-balance that thrash reviews this movie has got but the real score should be around 8/10 objectively.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poor casting doomed this one from the start.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TOMASBBloodhound
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease 2 is one of the most ridiculed sequels of all time, and though it pales to the original, its certainly better than the rating would imply. The film is just more musical numbers and hijinks from the kids at Rydell High. Only this time, the new kid on the block is a guy trying to impress a cool chick. As opposed to a goody-two-shoes girl trying to win over a cool guy like we saw in the original. There are some cute songs and funny moments, but the two leads (Caulfield and Pfeiffer) just cannot live up to Olivia Newton-John or John Travolta. Not even close. First of all, neither can sing terribly well, and generally you'd like your leads in a musical to be able to sing. It really helps. Caulfield is somewhat more likable in the underdog role, but Pfeiffer's acting is really poor. She was a pretty face and little more at that point of her career. Her song "Cool Rider" is one of the film's worst. While singing it, she does look kind of sexy while climbing up to the top of a ladder and then straddling it. But then when she gets down she starts doing something resembling the Elaine dance from Seinfeld. Thumbs in the air and all! Weird. Director/choreographer Pat Birch should have fixed that. There are some good performances from some of the folks playing the T-Birds and Pink Ladies. Adrian Zmed provides some chuckles with his false bravado in many scenes. Chris McDonald who plays the Goose has been a solid performer in movies and TV for years. And you're telling me Lorna Luft is a daughter of Judy Garland? Who new? Its good to see some of the faculty members are back from the original, but Didi Conn doesn't seem to belong. It seems like the producers agreed and just kind of wrote her out of the movie by the third act. It's really kind of odd how this movie has been aired seemingly more than the popular original over the years. It didn't hurt Pfeiffer's career (nor did marrying producer David E. Kelly), but this movie destroyed Caulfield's before it even began. He has kept somewhat busy, and was even considered at one point for the James Bond role. But he's never been the star he perhaps could have been. Grease 2 isn't all bad. It's worth about 5 of 10 stars. The Hound.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not very well made.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hailee-rebecca
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you watched the original "Grease" then this will most likely be a disappointment. I liked the idea - the tough chick falling for the sweet guy, but I think it could have been produced much better. The music wasn't all that great, neither with the dance sequences. I knew before I turned it on that it would not be able to the exact standards "Grease" did but I didn't expect to be this much of a disappointment. Stick to watching the classic. Though, I'll admit, the movie wasn't totally bogus. I really enjoyed Micheal's character and I liked seeing Frenchy again - she was my favourite character from the original. I thought it was weird that the 'Pink Ladies' were now owned by the T-Birds; they couldn't date outside the group because they were the T-Birds girls. That just didn't match up to me. The 'Reproduction' scene was kind of cool, I suppose.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit N Miss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nfmorse
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is a sad attempt to capitalize on the original's success. almost EVERY scene with Michelle Pfeiffer is not era appropriate clothing or hair n make-up for the times. You could 'plunk' her, (and her character) out of this movie and insert her into St Elmo's Fire or The Breakfast Club and have everything current with the fashion of the time. did she insist on only doing this movie if she could appear in a manner as she wouldn't be embarrassed? i was Born in the 60's and she does NOT represent the 60's by a LONG shot. i did not ONCE see era appropriate hair one her.. where was the structure curl of 'roller setting' on her? and the Sad portrayal of every one of the main characters as IDIOTS. the making of this movie should NEVER have been associated with the first Grease and should have been made as more of a parody for the times, but not be linked with the first Grease. the characters of the first were NOT so shallow and stupid as these people were who were supposed to be following in the footsteps of COOL people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than it's given credit for
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    urthmothr
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We saw this movie before the original "Grease," and have always preferred "2." We identify more with the characters, the humor, the whole "superhero shtick," and fell in love with Michelle Pfeiffer long before we saw her in anything else! Lorna Luft as Paulette was a hoot, and we enjoyed the rest of the cast, including the "returning faculty" from "Grease," some of whom we remember from their old TV shows. The bomb shelter scene was especially meaningful to "baby boomer's" who grew up in the 50's and 60's. Our favorite song is "Cool Rider," and the ending chorus to "A Girl for All Seasons" was especially poignant. This was our generation, we are class of '63 in NJ and '64 in Georgia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sloppy Cash-in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one's got cash-in written all over it. The original Grease was no work of art, but at least it was entertaining and fun. Its sequel has all the hallmarks of studio greed, with a minimal amount of money spent in the hope of the greatest possible return. So we have mostly unfamiliar characters in familiar surroundings, and the only link to the original film  other than a few minor characters  is the fact that it's the same story with the roles reversed. This time it's bland pretty-boy Maxwell Caulfield (once touted as the next big thing, he was last seen in the equally bland English soap Emmerdale) as the straight one and a young and impossibly gorgeous Michelle Pfeiffer as the bad girl member of the T-Birds. Pfeiffer isn't really bad. She doesn't even misbehave, which is perhaps an indicator of how much the makers of this movie have watered down the contents of the original. The songs are dull and unmemorable, the humour is lame  and nobody realises Maxwell's the enigmatic biker because he's wearing goggles. To top it all, the damn thing goes on forever, clocking in at around the two hour mark.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
