<filme>
 <id>
  1040
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118002
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Cora&ccedil;&otilde;es Roubados
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Frank O'Brien, a petty thief, and his 7-year-long girlfriend Roz want to put an end to their unsteady lifestyle and just do that _last_ job, which involves stealing a valuable painting. ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Frank O'Brien, a petty thief, and his 7-year-long girlfriend Roz want to put an end to their unsteady lifestyle and just do that _last_ job, which involves stealing a valuable painting. Frank takes Roz to an island on the coast of New England, where he wants to sell the painting and also hopes that their sagging relationship will get a positive push back up. Not everything goes as planned, as some thugs and the FBI try to recover the painting and Roz gets attracted not only to the landscape...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   painting
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   thief
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   island
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   beach
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   loud shirt
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Bill Bennett
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Denis Leary
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Mike Armstrong
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Sandra Bullock
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Denis Leary
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Stephen Dillane
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst movie I've seen in years. And I watch many...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eavan Masters
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Granted, I've never been a huge Bullock fan. The best she has done where she had to act were the Congeniality movies. The Net, Demolition Man, that one where she played Harper Lee, all terrible. I've always tended to enjoy Denis Leary. Well, his movies, not necessarily his coked up stand up routine. So this movie could've gone either way for me. However, it turned out to actually be one of the worst movies I have ever seen. Not a moment of the story was original, it plods along at a god-awful pace, the acting is sub-par. Everything about this movie is embarrassing. Or at least should be to those involved. Oh, and the theme of the ending would appear to be: "If you don't like what he is, annoy him until he changes into the man you want him to be." Because this always works in life right? Give Leary's character one week. He'll resent her so much he'll despise the sight of her. But aside from everything about this movie being terrible, it sucked. Don't waste your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Two If By Sea..B.G. performer Raymond Small
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    VegasEntertainment
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember going out to the set of Two If By Sea, I had been asked to perform a part of walking through a scene when the troopers race up behind Dennis Leary and Sandra Bullock, both of whom I have a great respect for, I think Sandra Bullock shows her depth and range in this movie. Dennis Leary can hold his character, with style, was right in sync with Roz. I enjoyed working on the set, as do many performers, I was glad Bill Mont loaned me a sweater on this day! Inside the store, I look for chips and goodies, while screeching tires suddenly stop outside....thank you to all cast and crew.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch this romantic comedy movie with your girlfriend
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (butchfilms@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the kind of movie to sit, watch and relax without demanding too much of it. The stronger point of the movie are its likable characters (except Evan Marsh). Sandra Bullock is like a fish in the water in this kind of movies and she has a good chemistry with the other leading Denis Leary. The supporting characters are good like the FBI Agent O'Malley and the group of thieves (especially when they discuss between themselves making funny comments). 'Frank' O'Brien has stolen a very expensive painting and he will go to an appointment with his girlfriend Roz to sell it, what he doesn't know it is that the FBI Agent O'Malley and his thieves friends are after them 
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Minor gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xredgarnetx
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A blonde Sandra B. and her beau of longstanding, played by the equally blond Dennis Leary, romp their way through a romantic comedy having to do with a bunch of small-time crooks and a very valuable stolen painting. Shot in scenic Nova Scotia, the backgrounds are absolutely gorgeous, and Bullock and Leary have great rapport that makes their rocky relationship very believable. FBI agent Yaphet Koto is along for the ride in a role similar to the one he essayed in MIDNIGHT RUN. Leary co-wrote this, In a manner reminiscent of Donald Westlake -- which is a very good thing, if you know who Westlake is. If not, look him up. Leary is consistently Leary (maybe he was born a fully developed adult), while Bullock in 1996 is growing into the superstar that we know today. She's playing a role that might have been Julia Roberts' a few years before, as she did in several other pictures prior to SPEED and MISS CONGENIALITY, which she made her own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Movies that are panned can sometimes be enjoyed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alice Copeland Brown (alicecbrown@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of course, I'm from Boston and Dennis' in-jokes about Bostonians gets me, especially since I've seen the Roast of Leary. And anyone who puts out a fund for firemen has my vote, as Dennis does. I loved the ode to plasterers so subtly portrayed in the finale. I also loved his deliberate skewering of the rich folks at the cocktail party, but wouldn't it be nice just once if a writer (Leary) once said to himself: "What is the movie audience expecting here? What can I put in here that would destroy this?" How about 2 rich folks who could confront him with his deliberate "How can I best offend you?" manners, showing that it is HE who may be the reverse snob? REquires perhaps more subtlety than Dennis has. He is a great writer for 'all guys, all the time' shows: so how about something confronting his homophobic or even homophilic attitudes? I ask too much, I know. and who owned the sailboat that kept sailing in and out of our view at the end of the road in the finale? Someone who Dennis owed money to? It was totally out of place, like a kid who keeps running into the camera's view just to get on TV. Just another nit: You can't have sex in the way Dennis was trying to have it in the car, unless you're hung like a donkey, which he isn't despite his big hands. Bullock: she's great, a real class act, as Leary has given homage to many times. I have ordered his "Deliver Me" to see if his acting has improved, if not his writing. WE'll see. He seems to play John Wayne, who always played himself....that school of acting.....too much for my liking. And guess what? The unsolved Isabella Gardner art heist here in Boston is probably what triggered his imagination for this movie. Now on to 'The Ref', which DID get good reviews.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not sandy's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    csauer
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie started out with some good laughs but why didn't I like it? Sandra was pretty funny but that didn't satisfy me this time. The story itself was goofy. I mean this couple was together for seven years and had nothing? Beano didn't exactly come off as a real big crime boss. I mean being the idiot of the Red Green show to king pin? I don't think so. The fishing scene was hilarious and the deer scene was great. I didn't care for Roz making a play for the rich neighbor only to run back to Frank when rich boy gets busted. The FBI, police and sheriff department were all so inept it was like the key stone cops. It had all in all some laughs but I was glad when it ended. Good enough to watch once I guess. This movie is so so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming romantic comedy about two lovers on the lam that'll make you laugh and smile from start to finish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grace Zeh (filmgirlgz@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    TWO IF BY SEA, in my opinion, is a charming romantic comedy about two lovers on the lam that'll make you laugh and smile from start to finish. If you ask me, Frank (Denis Leary) and Roz (Sandra Bullock) made an absolutely cute couple. I just don't understand why Frank felt he had to pull off that one last job before making amends with Roz. However, when she impersonated Homer Simpson, I laughed really hard. Someday, I'd like to go to somewhere in New England for a vacation. Before I wrap this up, I'd like to say that the production design was nice, the costumes were perfectly designed, and the performances were great. Now, in conclusion, I highly recommend this romantic comedy about two lovers on the lam that'll make you laugh and smile from start to finish to any Denis Leary or Sandra Bullock fan who hasn't seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First indication that it's a bad film: It has two separate titles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MovieAddict2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every bad film that flops always has a title change, nine out of ten times, and such is the case with TWO IF BY SEA, a.k.a. STOLEN HEARTS. It's not an awful film by any means, semi-entertaining as a sweet, romantic crime romp -- but it's also nothing special, and certainly not worth renting when you can just wait for it to come on television. The underrated Denis Leary and overrated Sandra Bullock are two crooks-turned-lovers who are on the flee from their last job when they accidentally assume the identity of another couple in a local neighborhood. Yeah, it doesn't make any sense and defies logic. What were you expecting? 2.5/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vickyd-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this is really funny it reminds me of "Weekend at Bernies". We really enjoyed it! And I like Sandra Bullock & Denis Leary too. You can't take this movie too seriously either. And Yaphat Kotto is funny when he plays a character named O'Malley and says to the other policeman - Top of the Morning - is that Irish enough for you. What a riot. This is not a movie the "The Net" it's just a fluffy movie and what about all the great scenery. It's wonderful and there are a lot of great actors in it that I've seen before. I would really recommend this movie - actually it's on TBS this morning so I wanted to mention that if anyone would like to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great chemistry, weak story.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jbels
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It hit me while watching this that the movie would have been better if Sandra Bullock and Dennis Leary were not criminals. I know, strange, as that is the whole basis for plot, but the two of them were such fun when they were bantering that I thought the plot just got in the way. If it would have been about the two of them sneaking up to Martha's Vineyard to rekindle their romance, this would have been a truly great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst movie I've seen in years. And I watch many...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eavan Masters
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Granted, I've never been a huge Bullock fan. The best she has done where she had to act were the Congeniality movies. The Net, Demolition Man, that one where she played Harper Lee, all terrible. I've always tended to enjoy Denis Leary. Well, his movies, not necessarily his coked up stand up routine. So this movie could've gone either way for me. However, it turned out to actually be one of the worst movies I have ever seen. Not a moment of the story was original, it plods along at a god-awful pace, the acting is sub-par. Everything about this movie is embarrassing. Or at least should be to those involved. Oh, and the theme of the ending would appear to be: "If you don't like what he is, annoy him until he changes into the man you want him to be." Because this always works in life right? Give Leary's character one week. He'll resent her so much he'll despise the sight of her. But aside from everything about this movie being terrible, it sucked. Don't waste your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Two If By Sea..B.G. performer Raymond Small
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    VegasEntertainment
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember going out to the set of Two If By Sea, I had been asked to perform a part of walking through a scene when the troopers race up behind Dennis Leary and Sandra Bullock, both of whom I have a great respect for, I think Sandra Bullock shows her depth and range in this movie. Dennis Leary can hold his character, with style, was right in sync with Roz. I enjoyed working on the set, as do many performers, I was glad Bill Mont loaned me a sweater on this day! Inside the store, I look for chips and goodies, while screeching tires suddenly stop outside....thank you to all cast and crew.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch this romantic comedy movie with your girlfriend
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (butchfilms@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the kind of movie to sit, watch and relax without demanding too much of it. The stronger point of the movie are its likable characters (except Evan Marsh). Sandra Bullock is like a fish in the water in this kind of movies and she has a good chemistry with the other leading Denis Leary. The supporting characters are good like the FBI Agent O'Malley and the group of thieves (especially when they discuss between themselves making funny comments). 'Frank' O'Brien has stolen a very expensive painting and he will go to an appointment with his girlfriend Roz to sell it, what he doesn't know it is that the FBI Agent O'Malley and his thieves friends are after them 
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Minor gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xredgarnetx
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A blonde Sandra B. and her beau of longstanding, played by the equally blond Dennis Leary, romp their way through a romantic comedy having to do with a bunch of small-time crooks and a very valuable stolen painting. Shot in scenic Nova Scotia, the backgrounds are absolutely gorgeous, and Bullock and Leary have great rapport that makes their rocky relationship very believable. FBI agent Yaphet Koto is along for the ride in a role similar to the one he essayed in MIDNIGHT RUN. Leary co-wrote this, In a manner reminiscent of Donald Westlake -- which is a very good thing, if you know who Westlake is. If not, look him up. Leary is consistently Leary (maybe he was born a fully developed adult), while Bullock in 1996 is growing into the superstar that we know today. She's playing a role that might have been Julia Roberts' a few years before, as she did in several other pictures prior to SPEED and MISS CONGENIALITY, which she made her own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Movies that are panned can sometimes be enjoyed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alice Copeland Brown (alicecbrown@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of course, I'm from Boston and Dennis' in-jokes about Bostonians gets me, especially since I've seen the Roast of Leary. And anyone who puts out a fund for firemen has my vote, as Dennis does. I loved the ode to plasterers so subtly portrayed in the finale. I also loved his deliberate skewering of the rich folks at the cocktail party, but wouldn't it be nice just once if a writer (Leary) once said to himself: "What is the movie audience expecting here? What can I put in here that would destroy this?" How about 2 rich folks who could confront him with his deliberate "How can I best offend you?" manners, showing that it is HE who may be the reverse snob? REquires perhaps more subtlety than Dennis has. He is a great writer for 'all guys, all the time' shows: so how about something confronting his homophobic or even homophilic attitudes? I ask too much, I know. and who owned the sailboat that kept sailing in and out of our view at the end of the road in the finale? Someone who Dennis owed money to? It was totally out of place, like a kid who keeps running into the camera's view just to get on TV. Just another nit: You can't have sex in the way Dennis was trying to have it in the car, unless you're hung like a donkey, which he isn't despite his big hands. Bullock: she's great, a real class act, as Leary has given homage to many times. I have ordered his "Deliver Me" to see if his acting has improved, if not his writing. WE'll see. He seems to play John Wayne, who always played himself....that school of acting.....too much for my liking. And guess what? The unsolved Isabella Gardner art heist here in Boston is probably what triggered his imagination for this movie. Now on to 'The Ref', which DID get good reviews.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not sandy's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    csauer
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie started out with some good laughs but why didn't I like it? Sandra was pretty funny but that didn't satisfy me this time. The story itself was goofy. I mean this couple was together for seven years and had nothing? Beano didn't exactly come off as a real big crime boss. I mean being the idiot of the Red Green show to king pin? I don't think so. The fishing scene was hilarious and the deer scene was great. I didn't care for Roz making a play for the rich neighbor only to run back to Frank when rich boy gets busted. The FBI, police and sheriff department were all so inept it was like the key stone cops. It had all in all some laughs but I was glad when it ended. Good enough to watch once I guess. This movie is so so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming romantic comedy about two lovers on the lam that'll make you laugh and smile from start to finish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grace Zeh (filmgirlgz@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    TWO IF BY SEA, in my opinion, is a charming romantic comedy about two lovers on the lam that'll make you laugh and smile from start to finish. If you ask me, Frank (Denis Leary) and Roz (Sandra Bullock) made an absolutely cute couple. I just don't understand why Frank felt he had to pull off that one last job before making amends with Roz. However, when she impersonated Homer Simpson, I laughed really hard. Someday, I'd like to go to somewhere in New England for a vacation. Before I wrap this up, I'd like to say that the production design was nice, the costumes were perfectly designed, and the performances were great. Now, in conclusion, I highly recommend this romantic comedy about two lovers on the lam that'll make you laugh and smile from start to finish to any Denis Leary or Sandra Bullock fan who hasn't seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First indication that it's a bad film: It has two separate titles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MovieAddict2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every bad film that flops always has a title change, nine out of ten times, and such is the case with TWO IF BY SEA, a.k.a. STOLEN HEARTS. It's not an awful film by any means, semi-entertaining as a sweet, romantic crime romp -- but it's also nothing special, and certainly not worth renting when you can just wait for it to come on television. The underrated Denis Leary and overrated Sandra Bullock are two crooks-turned-lovers who are on the flee from their last job when they accidentally assume the identity of another couple in a local neighborhood. Yeah, it doesn't make any sense and defies logic. What were you expecting? 2.5/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vickyd-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this is really funny it reminds me of "Weekend at Bernies". We really enjoyed it! And I like Sandra Bullock & Denis Leary too. You can't take this movie too seriously either. And Yaphat Kotto is funny when he plays a character named O'Malley and says to the other policeman - Top of the Morning - is that Irish enough for you. What a riot. This is not a movie the "The Net" it's just a fluffy movie and what about all the great scenery. It's wonderful and there are a lot of great actors in it that I've seen before. I would really recommend this movie - actually it's on TBS this morning so I wanted to mention that if anyone would like to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great chemistry, weak story.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jbels
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It hit me while watching this that the movie would have been better if Sandra Bullock and Dennis Leary were not criminals. I know, strange, as that is the whole basis for plot, but the two of them were such fun when they were bantering that I thought the plot just got in the way. If it would have been about the two of them sneaking up to Martha's Vineyard to rekindle their romance, this would have been a truly great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst movie I've seen in years. And I watch many...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eavan Masters
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Granted, I've never been a huge Bullock fan. The best she has done where she had to act were the Congeniality movies. The Net, Demolition Man, that one where she played Harper Lee, all terrible. I've always tended to enjoy Denis Leary. Well, his movies, not necessarily his coked up stand up routine. So this movie could've gone either way for me. However, it turned out to actually be one of the worst movies I have ever seen. Not a moment of the story was original, it plods along at a god-awful pace, the acting is sub-par. Everything about this movie is embarrassing. Or at least should be to those involved. Oh, and the theme of the ending would appear to be: "If you don't like what he is, annoy him until he changes into the man you want him to be." Because this always works in life right? Give Leary's character one week. He'll resent her so much he'll despise the sight of her. But aside from everything about this movie being terrible, it sucked. Don't waste your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Two If By Sea..B.G. performer Raymond Small
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    VegasEntertainment
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember going out to the set of Two If By Sea, I had been asked to perform a part of walking through a scene when the troopers race up behind Dennis Leary and Sandra Bullock, both of whom I have a great respect for, I think Sandra Bullock shows her depth and range in this movie. Dennis Leary can hold his character, with style, was right in sync with Roz. I enjoyed working on the set, as do many performers, I was glad Bill Mont loaned me a sweater on this day! Inside the store, I look for chips and goodies, while screeching tires suddenly stop outside....thank you to all cast and crew.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch this romantic comedy movie with your girlfriend
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (butchfilms@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the kind of movie to sit, watch and relax without demanding too much of it. The stronger point of the movie are its likable characters (except Evan Marsh). Sandra Bullock is like a fish in the water in this kind of movies and she has a good chemistry with the other leading Denis Leary. The supporting characters are good like the FBI Agent O'Malley and the group of thieves (especially when they discuss between themselves making funny comments). 'Frank' O'Brien has stolen a very expensive painting and he will go to an appointment with his girlfriend Roz to sell it, what he doesn't know it is that the FBI Agent O'Malley and his thieves friends are after them 
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Minor gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xredgarnetx
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A blonde Sandra B. and her beau of longstanding, played by the equally blond Dennis Leary, romp their way through a romantic comedy having to do with a bunch of small-time crooks and a very valuable stolen painting. Shot in scenic Nova Scotia, the backgrounds are absolutely gorgeous, and Bullock and Leary have great rapport that makes their rocky relationship very believable. FBI agent Yaphet Koto is along for the ride in a role similar to the one he essayed in MIDNIGHT RUN. Leary co-wrote this, In a manner reminiscent of Donald Westlake -- which is a very good thing, if you know who Westlake is. If not, look him up. Leary is consistently Leary (maybe he was born a fully developed adult), while Bullock in 1996 is growing into the superstar that we know today. She's playing a role that might have been Julia Roberts' a few years before, as she did in several other pictures prior to SPEED and MISS CONGENIALITY, which she made her own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Movies that are panned can sometimes be enjoyed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alice Copeland Brown (alicecbrown@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of course, I'm from Boston and Dennis' in-jokes about Bostonians gets me, especially since I've seen the Roast of Leary. And anyone who puts out a fund for firemen has my vote, as Dennis does. I loved the ode to plasterers so subtly portrayed in the finale. I also loved his deliberate skewering of the rich folks at the cocktail party, but wouldn't it be nice just once if a writer (Leary) once said to himself: "What is the movie audience expecting here? What can I put in here that would destroy this?" How about 2 rich folks who could confront him with his deliberate "How can I best offend you?" manners, showing that it is HE who may be the reverse snob? REquires perhaps more subtlety than Dennis has. He is a great writer for 'all guys, all the time' shows: so how about something confronting his homophobic or even homophilic attitudes? I ask too much, I know. and who owned the sailboat that kept sailing in and out of our view at the end of the road in the finale? Someone who Dennis owed money to? It was totally out of place, like a kid who keeps running into the camera's view just to get on TV. Just another nit: You can't have sex in the way Dennis was trying to have it in the car, unless you're hung like a donkey, which he isn't despite his big hands. Bullock: she's great, a real class act, as Leary has given homage to many times. I have ordered his "Deliver Me" to see if his acting has improved, if not his writing. WE'll see. He seems to play John Wayne, who always played himself....that school of acting.....too much for my liking. And guess what? The unsolved Isabella Gardner art heist here in Boston is probably what triggered his imagination for this movie. Now on to 'The Ref', which DID get good reviews.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not sandy's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    csauer
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie started out with some good laughs but why didn't I like it? Sandra was pretty funny but that didn't satisfy me this time. The story itself was goofy. I mean this couple was together for seven years and had nothing? Beano didn't exactly come off as a real big crime boss. I mean being the idiot of the Red Green show to king pin? I don't think so. The fishing scene was hilarious and the deer scene was great. I didn't care for Roz making a play for the rich neighbor only to run back to Frank when rich boy gets busted. The FBI, police and sheriff department were all so inept it was like the key stone cops. It had all in all some laughs but I was glad when it ended. Good enough to watch once I guess. This movie is so so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming romantic comedy about two lovers on the lam that'll make you laugh and smile from start to finish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grace Zeh (filmgirlgz@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    TWO IF BY SEA, in my opinion, is a charming romantic comedy about two lovers on the lam that'll make you laugh and smile from start to finish. If you ask me, Frank (Denis Leary) and Roz (Sandra Bullock) made an absolutely cute couple. I just don't understand why Frank felt he had to pull off that one last job before making amends with Roz. However, when she impersonated Homer Simpson, I laughed really hard. Someday, I'd like to go to somewhere in New England for a vacation. Before I wrap this up, I'd like to say that the production design was nice, the costumes were perfectly designed, and the performances were great. Now, in conclusion, I highly recommend this romantic comedy about two lovers on the lam that'll make you laugh and smile from start to finish to any Denis Leary or Sandra Bullock fan who hasn't seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First indication that it's a bad film: It has two separate titles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MovieAddict2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every bad film that flops always has a title change, nine out of ten times, and such is the case with TWO IF BY SEA, a.k.a. STOLEN HEARTS. It's not an awful film by any means, semi-entertaining as a sweet, romantic crime romp -- but it's also nothing special, and certainly not worth renting when you can just wait for it to come on television. The underrated Denis Leary and overrated Sandra Bullock are two crooks-turned-lovers who are on the flee from their last job when they accidentally assume the identity of another couple in a local neighborhood. Yeah, it doesn't make any sense and defies logic. What were you expecting? 2.5/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vickyd-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this is really funny it reminds me of "Weekend at Bernies". We really enjoyed it! And I like Sandra Bullock & Denis Leary too. You can't take this movie too seriously either. And Yaphat Kotto is funny when he plays a character named O'Malley and says to the other policeman - Top of the Morning - is that Irish enough for you. What a riot. This is not a movie the "The Net" it's just a fluffy movie and what about all the great scenery. It's wonderful and there are a lot of great actors in it that I've seen before. I would really recommend this movie - actually it's on TBS this morning so I wanted to mention that if anyone would like to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great chemistry, weak story.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jbels
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It hit me while watching this that the movie would have been better if Sandra Bullock and Dennis Leary were not criminals. I know, strange, as that is the whole basis for plot, but the two of them were such fun when they were bantering that I thought the plot just got in the way. If it would have been about the two of them sneaking up to Martha's Vineyard to rekindle their romance, this would have been a truly great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
