<filme>
 <id>
  1045
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0106881
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1993
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Sem Medo de Viver
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A man's personality is dramatically changed after surviving a major airline crash.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  After a terrible air disaster, survivor Max Klein emerges a changed person. Unable to connect to his former life or to wife Laura, he feels godlike and invulnerable. When psychologist Bill Perlman is unable to help Max, he has Max meet another survivor, Carla Rodrigo, who is racked with grief and guilt since her baby died in the crash which she and Max survived.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   disaster
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   guilt
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   grief
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   christ figure
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   laptop computer
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Peter Weir
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Rafael Yglesias
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jeff Bridges
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Isabella Rossellini
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Rosie Perez
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    PTSD Like No Other.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It helps to realize that this was directed by the Australian Peter Weir, many of whose films have oozed an ill-defined enigmatic quality. I remember the first of his movies I saw, "The Last Wave," in Palo Alto, when it was released. I'd never seen anything quite like it. And then, shortly afterward, "Picnic at Hanging Rock", which left me hanging at a much more tentative angle than the rock. Not all of his movie have been so mysterious, so bounced around, but "Fearless" is. Like "The Last Wave" it has a fuzzy supernatural element. Jeff Bridges and a few other passengers, Rosie Perez among them, survive a horrible fiery airplane crash in California. Bridges and Perez can't get their lives together afterward. Perez, having lost her baby in the accident, blames herself and is depressed almost beyond speech. Bridges, on the other hand, feels he is now indestructible and is, furthermore, some kind of supernatural agent left on earth to help Perez recover. His near-death experience has restructured his life. He feels he is invincible. He goes to lengths that anyone would describe as extreme in order to prove it. Bridges is always good. He always brings something extra to the role, although at times he overreaches. Rosie Perez isn't the Puerto Rican spitfire she usually is. She's subdued (for her) and effective in the character of a woman who has to realize that her baby's death was not her responsibility. Some comic moments are added by Tom Hulce as a bespectacled nervous wreck of a lawyer who sincerely wants to be sympathetic and get rich doing it. ("I know, I know, I'm a bad guy because I'm trying to get money. Don't bother saying it!") Isabella Rossellini is the increasingly distraught wife who can't understand why her husband is growing more distant, more ethereal, and appears to be falling in love with the woman he's trying to help. It isn't one of Weir's most provocative movies but once you get into it the narrative sweeps you up, partly because you can't help wondering where the hell it's all headed. The climax seems mundane after all that portent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A profound meditation on death, guilt, fear ... and ultimately, life ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fearless" awakened one of the most bizarre thoughts that ever crossed my mind: envy toward people who lived near death experiences, for the certitude that these people would never be the same again, and when you try to be someone else, any option is worth considering. "Fearless" takes place during the aftermath of a plane crash that presumably killed most passengers and left a few survivors in a state of shock. Are they privileged? Maybe from our perspective, but most of them would endure the trauma of having witnessed the death of a friend, a parent or even the seat neighbor. Most of them would endure the survivor's guilt. Not to mention the traumatic landing and the subsequent lottery of death. Peter Weir's movie, based on a novel by Rafael Iglesias, explores the complexities of the human soul from the different ways it reacts to a life-changing experience. The most intriguing case is Max Klein, an architect and family man, played by Jeff Bridges. Around him, it's chaos, mayhem, panic, cries and cadavers yet he walks like along the site, floating on a cloud of extraordinary serenity. He's not just a survivor, but also a savior, he gave a baby back to his mom, helped a little boy who was flying alone, he showed the safe way to many distraught passengers. Yet, the film doesn't focus on his heroic status, which he himself declines, it is more about the perception of life and death when you have been walking on the thin tightrope that separate the two worlds, when you 'saw the tunnel leading to a light'. Speaking of 'light', the narrative is punctuated by a few flashbacks that reveal how normally scared Max was during the flight, while sitting next to his best friend and colleague. It's only after the situation got more critical, that a mysterious heavenly light appeased his thoughts, and filled his heart with the serene confidence he would live. The crash sequence, which is among one of the most realistic, haunting and emotional from any other film, give some interesting insights that are later 'contradicted' by Max. The way he sees it: he's already a ghost, God can't touch him, he shares the little secret with Carla, a Hispanic mother who lost her child and can't recover from the guilt of not having held him tightly in her arms. Max and Carla form two interesting cases. Max survived and believe he's invulnerable, 'fearless' as the title suggest, with an inexorable desire to live life to its fullest, and the consequence is that it affects its relationships with his entourage. He becomes totally estranged to his wife, played by Isabella Rosselini (whose uncanny resemblance with her legendary was almost distracting), he lost the fatherly bond with his son in favor of the one he rescued, he couldn't even find the right words for his friend's widow or cooperate with the lawyer's desperate efforts to obtain a huge indemnity. Max rejects life's normality: money, convention, fear, video games, living with memories, his idea of the perfect life to live is a personal utopia that can only be fulfilled with someone who understands him. And this person is Carla. Played by Rosie Perez, Carla is the emotional core of the film, through the reaction most viewers can relate to, she's not a kind of super-human or angel, she only tried to save her son, but failed. And this failure puts her in a depressive state with suicidal impulses that only her deep Hispanic Catholic faith can alter. Contrarily to Max, Carla is much aware that she's living and that's what makes her life unbearable, for Max, the idea of death is so intolerable that he teases it by eating strawberries, a fruit he's allergic to, crossing the road, or walking on the ledge of a building's roof in the film's most emblematic scene. Fear is connected with self-preservation, but in Max' case, the fearless state doesn't mean he doesn't want to live, but it betrays his sentiment of inner immortality, yet the only way to be immortal is to be actually dead. Max is still between life and death. Either the wish to be dead out of guilt or sensation of being already dead from a weird exhilaration, both Perez and Bridges drive the film through sensitive and sensational performances. The therapist, played by John Turturro, explains to Max' wife that both Max and Carla represent two extremes in terms of reactions and on their interactions can depend chances of recovery. The relationship has a romantic vibe and maybe Max genuinely loves Carla, but "Fearless" never lures us into the idea that Carla would fall in love with him on the simple basis that they had the same experience. Love is not an end but a mean for Max to suppress all the traces of guilt in Carla's mind. Ironically, that's what Max' wife tries to do, helping him to regain his faith in life, and her many attempts to give a helping hand are concluded by 'failure to communicate', leading to what seems to be marital dead-end. But there is a reason Rosie Perez' performance was so acclaimed, she's not just a weepy, mourning mother, there is strength in her heart, and if her recovery can put and end to the mystical bond she had with Max, it leaves at least some room for the woman who really loves him. The conclusion of "Fearless", perhaps one of the most emotionally satisfying ever, is perfect because it does three things: it provides some answers about Max' enigmatic state of mind, it finds the perfect remedy, and it highlights the truth that one of the best things about life is to realize how great it is to live. Those who faced death have more awareness, and maybe this is what I consider their privilege. Do I want it? I'm not sure I'm that  fearless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When Great Character Study gets Interrupted by Hollywood Clich&eacute;s...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fearless is a drama centered around a man, played by Jeff Bridges, who survives a plane crash and can't get out of the state of being dead inside. It's very well acted film with standout performances by Jeff Bridges and Isabella Rossellini and features some brilliant direction by Peter Weir. I really liked the film and only minor annoyances that kept me from loving it. Jeff Bridges once again proves that he is one of the best living American actors out there. He truly sells the fact that he is dead inside and can't awake from the state his in. His performance is what really holds Fearless together and keeps you engaged. Isabella Rossellini and Rosie Perez provide the central supporting performances and they are very good. It's all around strongly acted film and keeps you invested in the characters and the hardships they go through. Peter Weir's direction perfectly compliments the storytelling and acting. His recreation of the plane crash was far more intense and horrifying than that of Flight. It's just a well directed film that's really well shot and gives a feeling that you are watching a real film. The script isn't as solid as the acting and the direction. The central themes and the characters are well explored and gives a good sense about what people go through when they survive terrible accidents. The problems start to pop whenever the film shoves in stupid Hollywood crap like wacky and silly lawyer, stupid subplots about greedy husband and other forced attempts of creating dramatic tension. You have so much going on with the characters already, you don't need some forced crap about things that hardly matter. Fearless is something you don't see often - a Hollywood film that wants to explore characters and leave pretension and self-importance out it. It's a very downbeat film but never depressing. Fearless is a optimistic film with a happy ending so it's a film you can actually enjoy. If you like Jeff Bridges and enjoy real films, you owe it to yourself to see it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Film; Disappointing Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruce Banner
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is an interesting character study of a man dealing with fear and death. I watched it because I'm a big fan of Jeff Bridges work as "The Dude" in The Big Lebowski but I was a bit letdown. Here's why: The movie did not deliver enough entertainment value. Thought provoking it was but entertaining- questionable. Also, the way the movie handled its core issues and themes seemed a little heavy handed to me. The old chestnut about script writing that the dialogue should never be totally "on the nose" was not adhered to, in this case to the film's detriment. I found some of the dialogue to be too direct and not leaving enough room for subtext and for the viewer to feel that there is something bubbling beneath the surface. Its always better for the writer to sketch the character's struggles as metaphors and incidental to the story rather than try to force themes to lead the story and drive its dialogue. Additionally, the Director's use of camera shots was a little slow. The style of, "Look at me, here is another important closeup on some random object for longer than we would like," coupled with the writing served to make the movie a bit melodramatic. Aside from Jeff Bridges who does a solid job in a decent role, Benicio Del Toro was very interesting in his minor role as was John Torturro. You will see a lot of rave reviews for Fearless largely because it has a small cult following who were emotionally impacted by it. As a regular viewer with no special connection to the film, I advise you to take these reviews with a grain of salt. They are biased. This is not a flawless film. It is merely an interesting one with a couple good actors. Definitely Not a must see. I also wasn't crazy about Rosie Perez. Her acting was one note, loud and amateurish rather than nuanced and intelligent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nasty movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sam hit
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched it till the end. If you the sort of person who spends a lot of time on thoughts like purpose, death and life DO NOT watch this movie. it's worse than an empty shell. it is false advertising, this movie. It tells about a man's journey after a plane crash that had changed him to someone who does not feel. He feels almost content with anything and joyous with life. there are some illogical plot occurring. It has to do with an allergy. Besides that the main character had little appeal to me. even the gorgeous women did not make up for what a fluke the movie was. I am flabbergasted that certain people felt so full of emotion after this movie but I think those are the shallow sort of people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Buying gifts for the dead....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a terrible air disaster, survivor Max Klein emerges a changed person. Unable to connect to his former life or to wife, he feels godlike and immortal. When psychologist Bill Perlman is unable to help, he has Max meet another survivor, Carla Rodrigo, who is racked with grief and guilt since her baby died in the crash.... This is one of those movies that had massive plaudits when first released, but vanished without a trace, (you can't even get it on DVD here in the UK). And I ask myself why? It's one of the best films no ones heard of in the nineties, and it may even have a career best performance from Bridges and the rest of the cast. It's a difficult subject matter to deal with, people trying to come to terms with loss, whereas one man, is doing everything in his power to prove everyone that something enigmatic, even sublime, happened to him on the plane. The film would be perfect if it had the same power in the third act, like it did in the first two, but sadly, it runs a little out of steam. The scenes on the plane are very intense and genuinely terrifying, but somewhat peaceful thanks to Bridges calming influence. The film is asking lots of questions throughout, but if you go that little much deeper, rather than look at it at face value, it gets a little lost also (there are some scenes, that are indicating that Bridges is really dead, and in purgatory, which can be confusing at times). But all in all, if you ever come across this movie, you must take some time out to see i, it's an amazing movie with an amazing message, it just loses it's way a little in the last 30 mins.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rather boring and depressing in my books. Jeff Bridges was the only saving grace
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Credit IMDb. After a terrible air disaster, survivor Max Klein emerges a changed person. Unable to connect to his former life or to wife Laura, he feels godlike and invulnerable. When psychologist Bill Perlman is unable to help Max, he has Max meet another survivor, Carla Rodrigo, who is racked with grief and guilt since her baby died in the crash which she and Max survived. It starts off with a gripping experience, with a crash sight, but from there it was all downhill for me. The acting is borderline flawless(aside from Perez). But the story is just depressing. I felt uncomfortable throughout the film, and watching them go through what they did was not rewarding, it got a bit much. Performances. Jeff Bridges is excellent no doubt about that. I felt what he was feeling, and he gives one of his finest performances. The trouble is, I didn't like the movie that was backing him up. Isabella Rossellini is good in her part, but rather an unlikable character in my opinion. Rosie Perez once again annoyed the heavens out of me, with her constant sniveling and shouting. Overrated much? John Turturro is solid in his role while Benicio Del Toro is solid too. Bottom line. Well made, well acted, but a boring experience that riddled me with depression. Worth a look, but that's about it. Maybe you'll get more out of it then I did. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Criminally underrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Elford
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A CRIMINALLY unknown film, especially in the UK, where it is close to impossible to get hold of, this Peter Weir outing, with Jeff Bridges taking the lead, also boasts star turns from John Turturro, Isabella Rossalini, and Rosie Perez, the latter of whom received an Oscar nomination. Everybody is on top form in this perfectly executed, beautiful meditation on what it is to be a human being. To explain all the subtext of "Fearless", all the symbolism, the various layers of allegory, would be an essay in itself; safe to say this is a film that sends you away reeling, thinking and talking about life for a long time. It sounds melodramatic, but when you see it, it makes perfect, serious sense. I understand it received standing ovations when it premiered, and rightly so! Many have said in the past, and I'll say it as well, that the final 10 minutes of this film is pretty much the most powerful cinema I've seen. Jeff Bridges nails it, and I find myself inexplicably in tears each time. Trying to explain it is tough; it speaks to something fundamental in you, and is truly life-affirming, if you choose to listen. A film that proves cinema, when image, performance, music and meaning are meshed perfectly, is sometimes able to convey what nothing else can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superior film of spiritual wonder.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bones Eijnar (namriggs@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching FEARLESS I clearly made up my mind about actor Jeff Bridges; he is utterly brilliant. This film is carried by his performance as a man who survives a plane crash and his the following life he lives in which his complete sense of existence is changed. The film finds mystery and tragedy and goes searching in religious places for answers that we draw out of the main character. Director Peter Weir lingers on Bridges and his inner self, and the many tender scenes that he goes through are very carefully achieved, never slipping into sentiment or boring clich&eacute;s. Throughout you really don't know whether Bridges is crazy, spiritual, dead or alive - he's yearning in something that everybody around him really don't see to understand. FEARLESS is a great film with many low-key scenes that tells a story thoroughly and thoughtfully, but it always escalates into joyous wonder, and that's where director Weir and Bridges truly captured me as a viewer. It's like that dark corridor towards the light in the magnificent ending scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Top-Notch Acting, Average Film...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Peter Weir has always been a filmmaker to admire. 'The Truman Show' is a legendary film, my all-time favorite film. 'Fearless', which released way back in 1993, sadly ranks amongst his weak efforts. However, this does become 'A Must Watch' film due to the strong performances by it's lead cast. Academy-Award-Winner Jeff Bridges stars as a man's who's personality is dramatically changed after surviving a major airline crash. The aftermath of the character and his connections with the world... is what 'Fearless' is all about. 'Fearless' begins wonderfully, but 40-minutes into the film, it loses the pace. Even the culmination leaves a lot to be desired. Weir's direction is satisfactory, but the Screenplay has loose-ends. The Cinematography is good. As mentioned, 'Fearless' is packed with strong performances. Jeff Bridges plays a highly difficult role with brilliance. This truly is one of his best performances to date. Rosie Perez is outstanding in a role that, again, is very Hard to play and execute. Isabella Rossellini is marvelous. Tom Hulce is hugely effective. Benicio del Toro leaves a mark, he's superb. On the whole, Not A Gem, but surely deserves a watch for the Performances, that leave you stunned!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    PTSD Like No Other.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It helps to realize that this was directed by the Australian Peter Weir, many of whose films have oozed an ill-defined enigmatic quality. I remember the first of his movies I saw, "The Last Wave," in Palo Alto, when it was released. I'd never seen anything quite like it. And then, shortly afterward, "Picnic at Hanging Rock", which left me hanging at a much more tentative angle than the rock. Not all of his movie have been so mysterious, so bounced around, but "Fearless" is. Like "The Last Wave" it has a fuzzy supernatural element. Jeff Bridges and a few other passengers, Rosie Perez among them, survive a horrible fiery airplane crash in California. Bridges and Perez can't get their lives together afterward. Perez, having lost her baby in the accident, blames herself and is depressed almost beyond speech. Bridges, on the other hand, feels he is now indestructible and is, furthermore, some kind of supernatural agent left on earth to help Perez recover. His near-death experience has restructured his life. He feels he is invincible. He goes to lengths that anyone would describe as extreme in order to prove it. Bridges is always good. He always brings something extra to the role, although at times he overreaches. Rosie Perez isn't the Puerto Rican spitfire she usually is. She's subdued (for her) and effective in the character of a woman who has to realize that her baby's death was not her responsibility. Some comic moments are added by Tom Hulce as a bespectacled nervous wreck of a lawyer who sincerely wants to be sympathetic and get rich doing it. ("I know, I know, I'm a bad guy because I'm trying to get money. Don't bother saying it!") Isabella Rossellini is the increasingly distraught wife who can't understand why her husband is growing more distant, more ethereal, and appears to be falling in love with the woman he's trying to help. It isn't one of Weir's most provocative movies but once you get into it the narrative sweeps you up, partly because you can't help wondering where the hell it's all headed. The climax seems mundane after all that portent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A profound meditation on death, guilt, fear ... and ultimately, life ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fearless" awakened one of the most bizarre thoughts that ever crossed my mind: envy toward people who lived near death experiences, for the certitude that these people would never be the same again, and when you try to be someone else, any option is worth considering. "Fearless" takes place during the aftermath of a plane crash that presumably killed most passengers and left a few survivors in a state of shock. Are they privileged? Maybe from our perspective, but most of them would endure the trauma of having witnessed the death of a friend, a parent or even the seat neighbor. Most of them would endure the survivor's guilt. Not to mention the traumatic landing and the subsequent lottery of death. Peter Weir's movie, based on a novel by Rafael Iglesias, explores the complexities of the human soul from the different ways it reacts to a life-changing experience. The most intriguing case is Max Klein, an architect and family man, played by Jeff Bridges. Around him, it's chaos, mayhem, panic, cries and cadavers yet he walks like along the site, floating on a cloud of extraordinary serenity. He's not just a survivor, but also a savior, he gave a baby back to his mom, helped a little boy who was flying alone, he showed the safe way to many distraught passengers. Yet, the film doesn't focus on his heroic status, which he himself declines, it is more about the perception of life and death when you have been walking on the thin tightrope that separate the two worlds, when you 'saw the tunnel leading to a light'. Speaking of 'light', the narrative is punctuated by a few flashbacks that reveal how normally scared Max was during the flight, while sitting next to his best friend and colleague. It's only after the situation got more critical, that a mysterious heavenly light appeased his thoughts, and filled his heart with the serene confidence he would live. The crash sequence, which is among one of the most realistic, haunting and emotional from any other film, give some interesting insights that are later 'contradicted' by Max. The way he sees it: he's already a ghost, God can't touch him, he shares the little secret with Carla, a Hispanic mother who lost her child and can't recover from the guilt of not having held him tightly in her arms. Max and Carla form two interesting cases. Max survived and believe he's invulnerable, 'fearless' as the title suggest, with an inexorable desire to live life to its fullest, and the consequence is that it affects its relationships with his entourage. He becomes totally estranged to his wife, played by Isabella Rosselini (whose uncanny resemblance with her legendary was almost distracting), he lost the fatherly bond with his son in favor of the one he rescued, he couldn't even find the right words for his friend's widow or cooperate with the lawyer's desperate efforts to obtain a huge indemnity. Max rejects life's normality: money, convention, fear, video games, living with memories, his idea of the perfect life to live is a personal utopia that can only be fulfilled with someone who understands him. And this person is Carla. Played by Rosie Perez, Carla is the emotional core of the film, through the reaction most viewers can relate to, she's not a kind of super-human or angel, she only tried to save her son, but failed. And this failure puts her in a depressive state with suicidal impulses that only her deep Hispanic Catholic faith can alter. Contrarily to Max, Carla is much aware that she's living and that's what makes her life unbearable, for Max, the idea of death is so intolerable that he teases it by eating strawberries, a fruit he's allergic to, crossing the road, or walking on the ledge of a building's roof in the film's most emblematic scene. Fear is connected with self-preservation, but in Max' case, the fearless state doesn't mean he doesn't want to live, but it betrays his sentiment of inner immortality, yet the only way to be immortal is to be actually dead. Max is still between life and death. Either the wish to be dead out of guilt or sensation of being already dead from a weird exhilaration, both Perez and Bridges drive the film through sensitive and sensational performances. The therapist, played by John Turturro, explains to Max' wife that both Max and Carla represent two extremes in terms of reactions and on their interactions can depend chances of recovery. The relationship has a romantic vibe and maybe Max genuinely loves Carla, but "Fearless" never lures us into the idea that Carla would fall in love with him on the simple basis that they had the same experience. Love is not an end but a mean for Max to suppress all the traces of guilt in Carla's mind. Ironically, that's what Max' wife tries to do, helping him to regain his faith in life, and her many attempts to give a helping hand are concluded by 'failure to communicate', leading to what seems to be marital dead-end. But there is a reason Rosie Perez' performance was so acclaimed, she's not just a weepy, mourning mother, there is strength in her heart, and if her recovery can put and end to the mystical bond she had with Max, it leaves at least some room for the woman who really loves him. The conclusion of "Fearless", perhaps one of the most emotionally satisfying ever, is perfect because it does three things: it provides some answers about Max' enigmatic state of mind, it finds the perfect remedy, and it highlights the truth that one of the best things about life is to realize how great it is to live. Those who faced death have more awareness, and maybe this is what I consider their privilege. Do I want it? I'm not sure I'm that  fearless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When Great Character Study gets Interrupted by Hollywood Clich&eacute;s...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fearless is a drama centered around a man, played by Jeff Bridges, who survives a plane crash and can't get out of the state of being dead inside. It's very well acted film with standout performances by Jeff Bridges and Isabella Rossellini and features some brilliant direction by Peter Weir. I really liked the film and only minor annoyances that kept me from loving it. Jeff Bridges once again proves that he is one of the best living American actors out there. He truly sells the fact that he is dead inside and can't awake from the state his in. His performance is what really holds Fearless together and keeps you engaged. Isabella Rossellini and Rosie Perez provide the central supporting performances and they are very good. It's all around strongly acted film and keeps you invested in the characters and the hardships they go through. Peter Weir's direction perfectly compliments the storytelling and acting. His recreation of the plane crash was far more intense and horrifying than that of Flight. It's just a well directed film that's really well shot and gives a feeling that you are watching a real film. The script isn't as solid as the acting and the direction. The central themes and the characters are well explored and gives a good sense about what people go through when they survive terrible accidents. The problems start to pop whenever the film shoves in stupid Hollywood crap like wacky and silly lawyer, stupid subplots about greedy husband and other forced attempts of creating dramatic tension. You have so much going on with the characters already, you don't need some forced crap about things that hardly matter. Fearless is something you don't see often - a Hollywood film that wants to explore characters and leave pretension and self-importance out it. It's a very downbeat film but never depressing. Fearless is a optimistic film with a happy ending so it's a film you can actually enjoy. If you like Jeff Bridges and enjoy real films, you owe it to yourself to see it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Film; Disappointing Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruce Banner
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is an interesting character study of a man dealing with fear and death. I watched it because I'm a big fan of Jeff Bridges work as "The Dude" in The Big Lebowski but I was a bit letdown. Here's why: The movie did not deliver enough entertainment value. Thought provoking it was but entertaining- questionable. Also, the way the movie handled its core issues and themes seemed a little heavy handed to me. The old chestnut about script writing that the dialogue should never be totally "on the nose" was not adhered to, in this case to the film's detriment. I found some of the dialogue to be too direct and not leaving enough room for subtext and for the viewer to feel that there is something bubbling beneath the surface. Its always better for the writer to sketch the character's struggles as metaphors and incidental to the story rather than try to force themes to lead the story and drive its dialogue. Additionally, the Director's use of camera shots was a little slow. The style of, "Look at me, here is another important closeup on some random object for longer than we would like," coupled with the writing served to make the movie a bit melodramatic. Aside from Jeff Bridges who does a solid job in a decent role, Benicio Del Toro was very interesting in his minor role as was John Torturro. You will see a lot of rave reviews for Fearless largely because it has a small cult following who were emotionally impacted by it. As a regular viewer with no special connection to the film, I advise you to take these reviews with a grain of salt. They are biased. This is not a flawless film. It is merely an interesting one with a couple good actors. Definitely Not a must see. I also wasn't crazy about Rosie Perez. Her acting was one note, loud and amateurish rather than nuanced and intelligent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nasty movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sam hit
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched it till the end. If you the sort of person who spends a lot of time on thoughts like purpose, death and life DO NOT watch this movie. it's worse than an empty shell. it is false advertising, this movie. It tells about a man's journey after a plane crash that had changed him to someone who does not feel. He feels almost content with anything and joyous with life. there are some illogical plot occurring. It has to do with an allergy. Besides that the main character had little appeal to me. even the gorgeous women did not make up for what a fluke the movie was. I am flabbergasted that certain people felt so full of emotion after this movie but I think those are the shallow sort of people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Buying gifts for the dead....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a terrible air disaster, survivor Max Klein emerges a changed person. Unable to connect to his former life or to wife, he feels godlike and immortal. When psychologist Bill Perlman is unable to help, he has Max meet another survivor, Carla Rodrigo, who is racked with grief and guilt since her baby died in the crash.... This is one of those movies that had massive plaudits when first released, but vanished without a trace, (you can't even get it on DVD here in the UK). And I ask myself why? It's one of the best films no ones heard of in the nineties, and it may even have a career best performance from Bridges and the rest of the cast. It's a difficult subject matter to deal with, people trying to come to terms with loss, whereas one man, is doing everything in his power to prove everyone that something enigmatic, even sublime, happened to him on the plane. The film would be perfect if it had the same power in the third act, like it did in the first two, but sadly, it runs a little out of steam. The scenes on the plane are very intense and genuinely terrifying, but somewhat peaceful thanks to Bridges calming influence. The film is asking lots of questions throughout, but if you go that little much deeper, rather than look at it at face value, it gets a little lost also (there are some scenes, that are indicating that Bridges is really dead, and in purgatory, which can be confusing at times). But all in all, if you ever come across this movie, you must take some time out to see i, it's an amazing movie with an amazing message, it just loses it's way a little in the last 30 mins.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rather boring and depressing in my books. Jeff Bridges was the only saving grace
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Credit IMDb. After a terrible air disaster, survivor Max Klein emerges a changed person. Unable to connect to his former life or to wife Laura, he feels godlike and invulnerable. When psychologist Bill Perlman is unable to help Max, he has Max meet another survivor, Carla Rodrigo, who is racked with grief and guilt since her baby died in the crash which she and Max survived. It starts off with a gripping experience, with a crash sight, but from there it was all downhill for me. The acting is borderline flawless(aside from Perez). But the story is just depressing. I felt uncomfortable throughout the film, and watching them go through what they did was not rewarding, it got a bit much. Performances. Jeff Bridges is excellent no doubt about that. I felt what he was feeling, and he gives one of his finest performances. The trouble is, I didn't like the movie that was backing him up. Isabella Rossellini is good in her part, but rather an unlikable character in my opinion. Rosie Perez once again annoyed the heavens out of me, with her constant sniveling and shouting. Overrated much? John Turturro is solid in his role while Benicio Del Toro is solid too. Bottom line. Well made, well acted, but a boring experience that riddled me with depression. Worth a look, but that's about it. Maybe you'll get more out of it then I did. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Criminally underrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Elford
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A CRIMINALLY unknown film, especially in the UK, where it is close to impossible to get hold of, this Peter Weir outing, with Jeff Bridges taking the lead, also boasts star turns from John Turturro, Isabella Rossalini, and Rosie Perez, the latter of whom received an Oscar nomination. Everybody is on top form in this perfectly executed, beautiful meditation on what it is to be a human being. To explain all the subtext of "Fearless", all the symbolism, the various layers of allegory, would be an essay in itself; safe to say this is a film that sends you away reeling, thinking and talking about life for a long time. It sounds melodramatic, but when you see it, it makes perfect, serious sense. I understand it received standing ovations when it premiered, and rightly so! Many have said in the past, and I'll say it as well, that the final 10 minutes of this film is pretty much the most powerful cinema I've seen. Jeff Bridges nails it, and I find myself inexplicably in tears each time. Trying to explain it is tough; it speaks to something fundamental in you, and is truly life-affirming, if you choose to listen. A film that proves cinema, when image, performance, music and meaning are meshed perfectly, is sometimes able to convey what nothing else can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superior film of spiritual wonder.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bones Eijnar (namriggs@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching FEARLESS I clearly made up my mind about actor Jeff Bridges; he is utterly brilliant. This film is carried by his performance as a man who survives a plane crash and his the following life he lives in which his complete sense of existence is changed. The film finds mystery and tragedy and goes searching in religious places for answers that we draw out of the main character. Director Peter Weir lingers on Bridges and his inner self, and the many tender scenes that he goes through are very carefully achieved, never slipping into sentiment or boring clich&eacute;s. Throughout you really don't know whether Bridges is crazy, spiritual, dead or alive - he's yearning in something that everybody around him really don't see to understand. FEARLESS is a great film with many low-key scenes that tells a story thoroughly and thoughtfully, but it always escalates into joyous wonder, and that's where director Weir and Bridges truly captured me as a viewer. It's like that dark corridor towards the light in the magnificent ending scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Top-Notch Acting, Average Film...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Peter Weir has always been a filmmaker to admire. 'The Truman Show' is a legendary film, my all-time favorite film. 'Fearless', which released way back in 1993, sadly ranks amongst his weak efforts. However, this does become 'A Must Watch' film due to the strong performances by it's lead cast. Academy-Award-Winner Jeff Bridges stars as a man's who's personality is dramatically changed after surviving a major airline crash. The aftermath of the character and his connections with the world... is what 'Fearless' is all about. 'Fearless' begins wonderfully, but 40-minutes into the film, it loses the pace. Even the culmination leaves a lot to be desired. Weir's direction is satisfactory, but the Screenplay has loose-ends. The Cinematography is good. As mentioned, 'Fearless' is packed with strong performances. Jeff Bridges plays a highly difficult role with brilliance. This truly is one of his best performances to date. Rosie Perez is outstanding in a role that, again, is very Hard to play and execute. Isabella Rossellini is marvelous. Tom Hulce is hugely effective. Benicio del Toro leaves a mark, he's superb. On the whole, Not A Gem, but surely deserves a watch for the Performances, that leave you stunned!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    PTSD Like No Other.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It helps to realize that this was directed by the Australian Peter Weir, many of whose films have oozed an ill-defined enigmatic quality. I remember the first of his movies I saw, "The Last Wave," in Palo Alto, when it was released. I'd never seen anything quite like it. And then, shortly afterward, "Picnic at Hanging Rock", which left me hanging at a much more tentative angle than the rock. Not all of his movie have been so mysterious, so bounced around, but "Fearless" is. Like "The Last Wave" it has a fuzzy supernatural element. Jeff Bridges and a few other passengers, Rosie Perez among them, survive a horrible fiery airplane crash in California. Bridges and Perez can't get their lives together afterward. Perez, having lost her baby in the accident, blames herself and is depressed almost beyond speech. Bridges, on the other hand, feels he is now indestructible and is, furthermore, some kind of supernatural agent left on earth to help Perez recover. His near-death experience has restructured his life. He feels he is invincible. He goes to lengths that anyone would describe as extreme in order to prove it. Bridges is always good. He always brings something extra to the role, although at times he overreaches. Rosie Perez isn't the Puerto Rican spitfire she usually is. She's subdued (for her) and effective in the character of a woman who has to realize that her baby's death was not her responsibility. Some comic moments are added by Tom Hulce as a bespectacled nervous wreck of a lawyer who sincerely wants to be sympathetic and get rich doing it. ("I know, I know, I'm a bad guy because I'm trying to get money. Don't bother saying it!") Isabella Rossellini is the increasingly distraught wife who can't understand why her husband is growing more distant, more ethereal, and appears to be falling in love with the woman he's trying to help. It isn't one of Weir's most provocative movies but once you get into it the narrative sweeps you up, partly because you can't help wondering where the hell it's all headed. The climax seems mundane after all that portent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A profound meditation on death, guilt, fear ... and ultimately, life ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fearless" awakened one of the most bizarre thoughts that ever crossed my mind: envy toward people who lived near death experiences, for the certitude that these people would never be the same again, and when you try to be someone else, any option is worth considering. "Fearless" takes place during the aftermath of a plane crash that presumably killed most passengers and left a few survivors in a state of shock. Are they privileged? Maybe from our perspective, but most of them would endure the trauma of having witnessed the death of a friend, a parent or even the seat neighbor. Most of them would endure the survivor's guilt. Not to mention the traumatic landing and the subsequent lottery of death. Peter Weir's movie, based on a novel by Rafael Iglesias, explores the complexities of the human soul from the different ways it reacts to a life-changing experience. The most intriguing case is Max Klein, an architect and family man, played by Jeff Bridges. Around him, it's chaos, mayhem, panic, cries and cadavers yet he walks like along the site, floating on a cloud of extraordinary serenity. He's not just a survivor, but also a savior, he gave a baby back to his mom, helped a little boy who was flying alone, he showed the safe way to many distraught passengers. Yet, the film doesn't focus on his heroic status, which he himself declines, it is more about the perception of life and death when you have been walking on the thin tightrope that separate the two worlds, when you 'saw the tunnel leading to a light'. Speaking of 'light', the narrative is punctuated by a few flashbacks that reveal how normally scared Max was during the flight, while sitting next to his best friend and colleague. It's only after the situation got more critical, that a mysterious heavenly light appeased his thoughts, and filled his heart with the serene confidence he would live. The crash sequence, which is among one of the most realistic, haunting and emotional from any other film, give some interesting insights that are later 'contradicted' by Max. The way he sees it: he's already a ghost, God can't touch him, he shares the little secret with Carla, a Hispanic mother who lost her child and can't recover from the guilt of not having held him tightly in her arms. Max and Carla form two interesting cases. Max survived and believe he's invulnerable, 'fearless' as the title suggest, with an inexorable desire to live life to its fullest, and the consequence is that it affects its relationships with his entourage. He becomes totally estranged to his wife, played by Isabella Rosselini (whose uncanny resemblance with her legendary was almost distracting), he lost the fatherly bond with his son in favor of the one he rescued, he couldn't even find the right words for his friend's widow or cooperate with the lawyer's desperate efforts to obtain a huge indemnity. Max rejects life's normality: money, convention, fear, video games, living with memories, his idea of the perfect life to live is a personal utopia that can only be fulfilled with someone who understands him. And this person is Carla. Played by Rosie Perez, Carla is the emotional core of the film, through the reaction most viewers can relate to, she's not a kind of super-human or angel, she only tried to save her son, but failed. And this failure puts her in a depressive state with suicidal impulses that only her deep Hispanic Catholic faith can alter. Contrarily to Max, Carla is much aware that she's living and that's what makes her life unbearable, for Max, the idea of death is so intolerable that he teases it by eating strawberries, a fruit he's allergic to, crossing the road, or walking on the ledge of a building's roof in the film's most emblematic scene. Fear is connected with self-preservation, but in Max' case, the fearless state doesn't mean he doesn't want to live, but it betrays his sentiment of inner immortality, yet the only way to be immortal is to be actually dead. Max is still between life and death. Either the wish to be dead out of guilt or sensation of being already dead from a weird exhilaration, both Perez and Bridges drive the film through sensitive and sensational performances. The therapist, played by John Turturro, explains to Max' wife that both Max and Carla represent two extremes in terms of reactions and on their interactions can depend chances of recovery. The relationship has a romantic vibe and maybe Max genuinely loves Carla, but "Fearless" never lures us into the idea that Carla would fall in love with him on the simple basis that they had the same experience. Love is not an end but a mean for Max to suppress all the traces of guilt in Carla's mind. Ironically, that's what Max' wife tries to do, helping him to regain his faith in life, and her many attempts to give a helping hand are concluded by 'failure to communicate', leading to what seems to be marital dead-end. But there is a reason Rosie Perez' performance was so acclaimed, she's not just a weepy, mourning mother, there is strength in her heart, and if her recovery can put and end to the mystical bond she had with Max, it leaves at least some room for the woman who really loves him. The conclusion of "Fearless", perhaps one of the most emotionally satisfying ever, is perfect because it does three things: it provides some answers about Max' enigmatic state of mind, it finds the perfect remedy, and it highlights the truth that one of the best things about life is to realize how great it is to live. Those who faced death have more awareness, and maybe this is what I consider their privilege. Do I want it? I'm not sure I'm that  fearless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When Great Character Study gets Interrupted by Hollywood Clich&eacute;s...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fearless is a drama centered around a man, played by Jeff Bridges, who survives a plane crash and can't get out of the state of being dead inside. It's very well acted film with standout performances by Jeff Bridges and Isabella Rossellini and features some brilliant direction by Peter Weir. I really liked the film and only minor annoyances that kept me from loving it. Jeff Bridges once again proves that he is one of the best living American actors out there. He truly sells the fact that he is dead inside and can't awake from the state his in. His performance is what really holds Fearless together and keeps you engaged. Isabella Rossellini and Rosie Perez provide the central supporting performances and they are very good. It's all around strongly acted film and keeps you invested in the characters and the hardships they go through. Peter Weir's direction perfectly compliments the storytelling and acting. His recreation of the plane crash was far more intense and horrifying than that of Flight. It's just a well directed film that's really well shot and gives a feeling that you are watching a real film. The script isn't as solid as the acting and the direction. The central themes and the characters are well explored and gives a good sense about what people go through when they survive terrible accidents. The problems start to pop whenever the film shoves in stupid Hollywood crap like wacky and silly lawyer, stupid subplots about greedy husband and other forced attempts of creating dramatic tension. You have so much going on with the characters already, you don't need some forced crap about things that hardly matter. Fearless is something you don't see often - a Hollywood film that wants to explore characters and leave pretension and self-importance out it. It's a very downbeat film but never depressing. Fearless is a optimistic film with a happy ending so it's a film you can actually enjoy. If you like Jeff Bridges and enjoy real films, you owe it to yourself to see it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Film; Disappointing Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruce Banner
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is an interesting character study of a man dealing with fear and death. I watched it because I'm a big fan of Jeff Bridges work as "The Dude" in The Big Lebowski but I was a bit letdown. Here's why: The movie did not deliver enough entertainment value. Thought provoking it was but entertaining- questionable. Also, the way the movie handled its core issues and themes seemed a little heavy handed to me. The old chestnut about script writing that the dialogue should never be totally "on the nose" was not adhered to, in this case to the film's detriment. I found some of the dialogue to be too direct and not leaving enough room for subtext and for the viewer to feel that there is something bubbling beneath the surface. Its always better for the writer to sketch the character's struggles as metaphors and incidental to the story rather than try to force themes to lead the story and drive its dialogue. Additionally, the Director's use of camera shots was a little slow. The style of, "Look at me, here is another important closeup on some random object for longer than we would like," coupled with the writing served to make the movie a bit melodramatic. Aside from Jeff Bridges who does a solid job in a decent role, Benicio Del Toro was very interesting in his minor role as was John Torturro. You will see a lot of rave reviews for Fearless largely because it has a small cult following who were emotionally impacted by it. As a regular viewer with no special connection to the film, I advise you to take these reviews with a grain of salt. They are biased. This is not a flawless film. It is merely an interesting one with a couple good actors. Definitely Not a must see. I also wasn't crazy about Rosie Perez. Her acting was one note, loud and amateurish rather than nuanced and intelligent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nasty movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sam hit
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched it till the end. If you the sort of person who spends a lot of time on thoughts like purpose, death and life DO NOT watch this movie. it's worse than an empty shell. it is false advertising, this movie. It tells about a man's journey after a plane crash that had changed him to someone who does not feel. He feels almost content with anything and joyous with life. there are some illogical plot occurring. It has to do with an allergy. Besides that the main character had little appeal to me. even the gorgeous women did not make up for what a fluke the movie was. I am flabbergasted that certain people felt so full of emotion after this movie but I think those are the shallow sort of people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Buying gifts for the dead....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a terrible air disaster, survivor Max Klein emerges a changed person. Unable to connect to his former life or to wife, he feels godlike and immortal. When psychologist Bill Perlman is unable to help, he has Max meet another survivor, Carla Rodrigo, who is racked with grief and guilt since her baby died in the crash.... This is one of those movies that had massive plaudits when first released, but vanished without a trace, (you can't even get it on DVD here in the UK). And I ask myself why? It's one of the best films no ones heard of in the nineties, and it may even have a career best performance from Bridges and the rest of the cast. It's a difficult subject matter to deal with, people trying to come to terms with loss, whereas one man, is doing everything in his power to prove everyone that something enigmatic, even sublime, happened to him on the plane. The film would be perfect if it had the same power in the third act, like it did in the first two, but sadly, it runs a little out of steam. The scenes on the plane are very intense and genuinely terrifying, but somewhat peaceful thanks to Bridges calming influence. The film is asking lots of questions throughout, but if you go that little much deeper, rather than look at it at face value, it gets a little lost also (there are some scenes, that are indicating that Bridges is really dead, and in purgatory, which can be confusing at times). But all in all, if you ever come across this movie, you must take some time out to see i, it's an amazing movie with an amazing message, it just loses it's way a little in the last 30 mins.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rather boring and depressing in my books. Jeff Bridges was the only saving grace
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Credit IMDb. After a terrible air disaster, survivor Max Klein emerges a changed person. Unable to connect to his former life or to wife Laura, he feels godlike and invulnerable. When psychologist Bill Perlman is unable to help Max, he has Max meet another survivor, Carla Rodrigo, who is racked with grief and guilt since her baby died in the crash which she and Max survived. It starts off with a gripping experience, with a crash sight, but from there it was all downhill for me. The acting is borderline flawless(aside from Perez). But the story is just depressing. I felt uncomfortable throughout the film, and watching them go through what they did was not rewarding, it got a bit much. Performances. Jeff Bridges is excellent no doubt about that. I felt what he was feeling, and he gives one of his finest performances. The trouble is, I didn't like the movie that was backing him up. Isabella Rossellini is good in her part, but rather an unlikable character in my opinion. Rosie Perez once again annoyed the heavens out of me, with her constant sniveling and shouting. Overrated much? John Turturro is solid in his role while Benicio Del Toro is solid too. Bottom line. Well made, well acted, but a boring experience that riddled me with depression. Worth a look, but that's about it. Maybe you'll get more out of it then I did. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Criminally underrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Elford
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A CRIMINALLY unknown film, especially in the UK, where it is close to impossible to get hold of, this Peter Weir outing, with Jeff Bridges taking the lead, also boasts star turns from John Turturro, Isabella Rossalini, and Rosie Perez, the latter of whom received an Oscar nomination. Everybody is on top form in this perfectly executed, beautiful meditation on what it is to be a human being. To explain all the subtext of "Fearless", all the symbolism, the various layers of allegory, would be an essay in itself; safe to say this is a film that sends you away reeling, thinking and talking about life for a long time. It sounds melodramatic, but when you see it, it makes perfect, serious sense. I understand it received standing ovations when it premiered, and rightly so! Many have said in the past, and I'll say it as well, that the final 10 minutes of this film is pretty much the most powerful cinema I've seen. Jeff Bridges nails it, and I find myself inexplicably in tears each time. Trying to explain it is tough; it speaks to something fundamental in you, and is truly life-affirming, if you choose to listen. A film that proves cinema, when image, performance, music and meaning are meshed perfectly, is sometimes able to convey what nothing else can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superior film of spiritual wonder.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bones Eijnar (namriggs@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching FEARLESS I clearly made up my mind about actor Jeff Bridges; he is utterly brilliant. This film is carried by his performance as a man who survives a plane crash and his the following life he lives in which his complete sense of existence is changed. The film finds mystery and tragedy and goes searching in religious places for answers that we draw out of the main character. Director Peter Weir lingers on Bridges and his inner self, and the many tender scenes that he goes through are very carefully achieved, never slipping into sentiment or boring clich&eacute;s. Throughout you really don't know whether Bridges is crazy, spiritual, dead or alive - he's yearning in something that everybody around him really don't see to understand. FEARLESS is a great film with many low-key scenes that tells a story thoroughly and thoughtfully, but it always escalates into joyous wonder, and that's where director Weir and Bridges truly captured me as a viewer. It's like that dark corridor towards the light in the magnificent ending scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Top-Notch Acting, Average Film...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Peter Weir has always been a filmmaker to admire. 'The Truman Show' is a legendary film, my all-time favorite film. 'Fearless', which released way back in 1993, sadly ranks amongst his weak efforts. However, this does become 'A Must Watch' film due to the strong performances by it's lead cast. Academy-Award-Winner Jeff Bridges stars as a man's who's personality is dramatically changed after surviving a major airline crash. The aftermath of the character and his connections with the world... is what 'Fearless' is all about. 'Fearless' begins wonderfully, but 40-minutes into the film, it loses the pace. Even the culmination leaves a lot to be desired. Weir's direction is satisfactory, but the Screenplay has loose-ends. The Cinematography is good. As mentioned, 'Fearless' is packed with strong performances. Jeff Bridges plays a highly difficult role with brilliance. This truly is one of his best performances to date. Rosie Perez is outstanding in a role that, again, is very Hard to play and execute. Isabella Rossellini is marvelous. Tom Hulce is hugely effective. Benicio del Toro leaves a mark, he's superb. On the whole, Not A Gem, but surely deserves a watch for the Performances, that leave you stunned!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    PTSD Like No Other.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It helps to realize that this was directed by the Australian Peter Weir, many of whose films have oozed an ill-defined enigmatic quality. I remember the first of his movies I saw, "The Last Wave," in Palo Alto, when it was released. I'd never seen anything quite like it. And then, shortly afterward, "Picnic at Hanging Rock", which left me hanging at a much more tentative angle than the rock. Not all of his movie have been so mysterious, so bounced around, but "Fearless" is. Like "The Last Wave" it has a fuzzy supernatural element. Jeff Bridges and a few other passengers, Rosie Perez among them, survive a horrible fiery airplane crash in California. Bridges and Perez can't get their lives together afterward. Perez, having lost her baby in the accident, blames herself and is depressed almost beyond speech. Bridges, on the other hand, feels he is now indestructible and is, furthermore, some kind of supernatural agent left on earth to help Perez recover. His near-death experience has restructured his life. He feels he is invincible. He goes to lengths that anyone would describe as extreme in order to prove it. Bridges is always good. He always brings something extra to the role, although at times he overreaches. Rosie Perez isn't the Puerto Rican spitfire she usually is. She's subdued (for her) and effective in the character of a woman who has to realize that her baby's death was not her responsibility. Some comic moments are added by Tom Hulce as a bespectacled nervous wreck of a lawyer who sincerely wants to be sympathetic and get rich doing it. ("I know, I know, I'm a bad guy because I'm trying to get money. Don't bother saying it!") Isabella Rossellini is the increasingly distraught wife who can't understand why her husband is growing more distant, more ethereal, and appears to be falling in love with the woman he's trying to help. It isn't one of Weir's most provocative movies but once you get into it the narrative sweeps you up, partly because you can't help wondering where the hell it's all headed. The climax seems mundane after all that portent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A profound meditation on death, guilt, fear ... and ultimately, life ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fearless" awakened one of the most bizarre thoughts that ever crossed my mind: envy toward people who lived near death experiences, for the certitude that these people would never be the same again, and when you try to be someone else, any option is worth considering. "Fearless" takes place during the aftermath of a plane crash that presumably killed most passengers and left a few survivors in a state of shock. Are they privileged? Maybe from our perspective, but most of them would endure the trauma of having witnessed the death of a friend, a parent or even the seat neighbor. Most of them would endure the survivor's guilt. Not to mention the traumatic landing and the subsequent lottery of death. Peter Weir's movie, based on a novel by Rafael Iglesias, explores the complexities of the human soul from the different ways it reacts to a life-changing experience. The most intriguing case is Max Klein, an architect and family man, played by Jeff Bridges. Around him, it's chaos, mayhem, panic, cries and cadavers yet he walks like along the site, floating on a cloud of extraordinary serenity. He's not just a survivor, but also a savior, he gave a baby back to his mom, helped a little boy who was flying alone, he showed the safe way to many distraught passengers. Yet, the film doesn't focus on his heroic status, which he himself declines, it is more about the perception of life and death when you have been walking on the thin tightrope that separate the two worlds, when you 'saw the tunnel leading to a light'. Speaking of 'light', the narrative is punctuated by a few flashbacks that reveal how normally scared Max was during the flight, while sitting next to his best friend and colleague. It's only after the situation got more critical, that a mysterious heavenly light appeased his thoughts, and filled his heart with the serene confidence he would live. The crash sequence, which is among one of the most realistic, haunting and emotional from any other film, give some interesting insights that are later 'contradicted' by Max. The way he sees it: he's already a ghost, God can't touch him, he shares the little secret with Carla, a Hispanic mother who lost her child and can't recover from the guilt of not having held him tightly in her arms. Max and Carla form two interesting cases. Max survived and believe he's invulnerable, 'fearless' as the title suggest, with an inexorable desire to live life to its fullest, and the consequence is that it affects its relationships with his entourage. He becomes totally estranged to his wife, played by Isabella Rosselini (whose uncanny resemblance with her legendary was almost distracting), he lost the fatherly bond with his son in favor of the one he rescued, he couldn't even find the right words for his friend's widow or cooperate with the lawyer's desperate efforts to obtain a huge indemnity. Max rejects life's normality: money, convention, fear, video games, living with memories, his idea of the perfect life to live is a personal utopia that can only be fulfilled with someone who understands him. And this person is Carla. Played by Rosie Perez, Carla is the emotional core of the film, through the reaction most viewers can relate to, she's not a kind of super-human or angel, she only tried to save her son, but failed. And this failure puts her in a depressive state with suicidal impulses that only her deep Hispanic Catholic faith can alter. Contrarily to Max, Carla is much aware that she's living and that's what makes her life unbearable, for Max, the idea of death is so intolerable that he teases it by eating strawberries, a fruit he's allergic to, crossing the road, or walking on the ledge of a building's roof in the film's most emblematic scene. Fear is connected with self-preservation, but in Max' case, the fearless state doesn't mean he doesn't want to live, but it betrays his sentiment of inner immortality, yet the only way to be immortal is to be actually dead. Max is still between life and death. Either the wish to be dead out of guilt or sensation of being already dead from a weird exhilaration, both Perez and Bridges drive the film through sensitive and sensational performances. The therapist, played by John Turturro, explains to Max' wife that both Max and Carla represent two extremes in terms of reactions and on their interactions can depend chances of recovery. The relationship has a romantic vibe and maybe Max genuinely loves Carla, but "Fearless" never lures us into the idea that Carla would fall in love with him on the simple basis that they had the same experience. Love is not an end but a mean for Max to suppress all the traces of guilt in Carla's mind. Ironically, that's what Max' wife tries to do, helping him to regain his faith in life, and her many attempts to give a helping hand are concluded by 'failure to communicate', leading to what seems to be marital dead-end. But there is a reason Rosie Perez' performance was so acclaimed, she's not just a weepy, mourning mother, there is strength in her heart, and if her recovery can put and end to the mystical bond she had with Max, it leaves at least some room for the woman who really loves him. The conclusion of "Fearless", perhaps one of the most emotionally satisfying ever, is perfect because it does three things: it provides some answers about Max' enigmatic state of mind, it finds the perfect remedy, and it highlights the truth that one of the best things about life is to realize how great it is to live. Those who faced death have more awareness, and maybe this is what I consider their privilege. Do I want it? I'm not sure I'm that  fearless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When Great Character Study gets Interrupted by Hollywood Clich&eacute;s...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fearless is a drama centered around a man, played by Jeff Bridges, who survives a plane crash and can't get out of the state of being dead inside. It's very well acted film with standout performances by Jeff Bridges and Isabella Rossellini and features some brilliant direction by Peter Weir. I really liked the film and only minor annoyances that kept me from loving it. Jeff Bridges once again proves that he is one of the best living American actors out there. He truly sells the fact that he is dead inside and can't awake from the state his in. His performance is what really holds Fearless together and keeps you engaged. Isabella Rossellini and Rosie Perez provide the central supporting performances and they are very good. It's all around strongly acted film and keeps you invested in the characters and the hardships they go through. Peter Weir's direction perfectly compliments the storytelling and acting. His recreation of the plane crash was far more intense and horrifying than that of Flight. It's just a well directed film that's really well shot and gives a feeling that you are watching a real film. The script isn't as solid as the acting and the direction. The central themes and the characters are well explored and gives a good sense about what people go through when they survive terrible accidents. The problems start to pop whenever the film shoves in stupid Hollywood crap like wacky and silly lawyer, stupid subplots about greedy husband and other forced attempts of creating dramatic tension. You have so much going on with the characters already, you don't need some forced crap about things that hardly matter. Fearless is something you don't see often - a Hollywood film that wants to explore characters and leave pretension and self-importance out it. It's a very downbeat film but never depressing. Fearless is a optimistic film with a happy ending so it's a film you can actually enjoy. If you like Jeff Bridges and enjoy real films, you owe it to yourself to see it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Film; Disappointing Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruce Banner
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is an interesting character study of a man dealing with fear and death. I watched it because I'm a big fan of Jeff Bridges work as "The Dude" in The Big Lebowski but I was a bit letdown. Here's why: The movie did not deliver enough entertainment value. Thought provoking it was but entertaining- questionable. Also, the way the movie handled its core issues and themes seemed a little heavy handed to me. The old chestnut about script writing that the dialogue should never be totally "on the nose" was not adhered to, in this case to the film's detriment. I found some of the dialogue to be too direct and not leaving enough room for subtext and for the viewer to feel that there is something bubbling beneath the surface. Its always better for the writer to sketch the character's struggles as metaphors and incidental to the story rather than try to force themes to lead the story and drive its dialogue. Additionally, the Director's use of camera shots was a little slow. The style of, "Look at me, here is another important closeup on some random object for longer than we would like," coupled with the writing served to make the movie a bit melodramatic. Aside from Jeff Bridges who does a solid job in a decent role, Benicio Del Toro was very interesting in his minor role as was John Torturro. You will see a lot of rave reviews for Fearless largely because it has a small cult following who were emotionally impacted by it. As a regular viewer with no special connection to the film, I advise you to take these reviews with a grain of salt. They are biased. This is not a flawless film. It is merely an interesting one with a couple good actors. Definitely Not a must see. I also wasn't crazy about Rosie Perez. Her acting was one note, loud and amateurish rather than nuanced and intelligent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nasty movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sam hit
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched it till the end. If you the sort of person who spends a lot of time on thoughts like purpose, death and life DO NOT watch this movie. it's worse than an empty shell. it is false advertising, this movie. It tells about a man's journey after a plane crash that had changed him to someone who does not feel. He feels almost content with anything and joyous with life. there are some illogical plot occurring. It has to do with an allergy. Besides that the main character had little appeal to me. even the gorgeous women did not make up for what a fluke the movie was. I am flabbergasted that certain people felt so full of emotion after this movie but I think those are the shallow sort of people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Buying gifts for the dead....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a terrible air disaster, survivor Max Klein emerges a changed person. Unable to connect to his former life or to wife, he feels godlike and immortal. When psychologist Bill Perlman is unable to help, he has Max meet another survivor, Carla Rodrigo, who is racked with grief and guilt since her baby died in the crash.... This is one of those movies that had massive plaudits when first released, but vanished without a trace, (you can't even get it on DVD here in the UK). And I ask myself why? It's one of the best films no ones heard of in the nineties, and it may even have a career best performance from Bridges and the rest of the cast. It's a difficult subject matter to deal with, people trying to come to terms with loss, whereas one man, is doing everything in his power to prove everyone that something enigmatic, even sublime, happened to him on the plane. The film would be perfect if it had the same power in the third act, like it did in the first two, but sadly, it runs a little out of steam. The scenes on the plane are very intense and genuinely terrifying, but somewhat peaceful thanks to Bridges calming influence. The film is asking lots of questions throughout, but if you go that little much deeper, rather than look at it at face value, it gets a little lost also (there are some scenes, that are indicating that Bridges is really dead, and in purgatory, which can be confusing at times). But all in all, if you ever come across this movie, you must take some time out to see i, it's an amazing movie with an amazing message, it just loses it's way a little in the last 30 mins.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rather boring and depressing in my books. Jeff Bridges was the only saving grace
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Credit IMDb. After a terrible air disaster, survivor Max Klein emerges a changed person. Unable to connect to his former life or to wife Laura, he feels godlike and invulnerable. When psychologist Bill Perlman is unable to help Max, he has Max meet another survivor, Carla Rodrigo, who is racked with grief and guilt since her baby died in the crash which she and Max survived. It starts off with a gripping experience, with a crash sight, but from there it was all downhill for me. The acting is borderline flawless(aside from Perez). But the story is just depressing. I felt uncomfortable throughout the film, and watching them go through what they did was not rewarding, it got a bit much. Performances. Jeff Bridges is excellent no doubt about that. I felt what he was feeling, and he gives one of his finest performances. The trouble is, I didn't like the movie that was backing him up. Isabella Rossellini is good in her part, but rather an unlikable character in my opinion. Rosie Perez once again annoyed the heavens out of me, with her constant sniveling and shouting. Overrated much? John Turturro is solid in his role while Benicio Del Toro is solid too. Bottom line. Well made, well acted, but a boring experience that riddled me with depression. Worth a look, but that's about it. Maybe you'll get more out of it then I did. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Criminally underrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Elford
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A CRIMINALLY unknown film, especially in the UK, where it is close to impossible to get hold of, this Peter Weir outing, with Jeff Bridges taking the lead, also boasts star turns from John Turturro, Isabella Rossalini, and Rosie Perez, the latter of whom received an Oscar nomination. Everybody is on top form in this perfectly executed, beautiful meditation on what it is to be a human being. To explain all the subtext of "Fearless", all the symbolism, the various layers of allegory, would be an essay in itself; safe to say this is a film that sends you away reeling, thinking and talking about life for a long time. It sounds melodramatic, but when you see it, it makes perfect, serious sense. I understand it received standing ovations when it premiered, and rightly so! Many have said in the past, and I'll say it as well, that the final 10 minutes of this film is pretty much the most powerful cinema I've seen. Jeff Bridges nails it, and I find myself inexplicably in tears each time. Trying to explain it is tough; it speaks to something fundamental in you, and is truly life-affirming, if you choose to listen. A film that proves cinema, when image, performance, music and meaning are meshed perfectly, is sometimes able to convey what nothing else can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superior film of spiritual wonder.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bones Eijnar (namriggs@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching FEARLESS I clearly made up my mind about actor Jeff Bridges; he is utterly brilliant. This film is carried by his performance as a man who survives a plane crash and his the following life he lives in which his complete sense of existence is changed. The film finds mystery and tragedy and goes searching in religious places for answers that we draw out of the main character. Director Peter Weir lingers on Bridges and his inner self, and the many tender scenes that he goes through are very carefully achieved, never slipping into sentiment or boring clich&eacute;s. Throughout you really don't know whether Bridges is crazy, spiritual, dead or alive - he's yearning in something that everybody around him really don't see to understand. FEARLESS is a great film with many low-key scenes that tells a story thoroughly and thoughtfully, but it always escalates into joyous wonder, and that's where director Weir and Bridges truly captured me as a viewer. It's like that dark corridor towards the light in the magnificent ending scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Top-Notch Acting, Average Film...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Peter Weir has always been a filmmaker to admire. 'The Truman Show' is a legendary film, my all-time favorite film. 'Fearless', which released way back in 1993, sadly ranks amongst his weak efforts. However, this does become 'A Must Watch' film due to the strong performances by it's lead cast. Academy-Award-Winner Jeff Bridges stars as a man's who's personality is dramatically changed after surviving a major airline crash. The aftermath of the character and his connections with the world... is what 'Fearless' is all about. 'Fearless' begins wonderfully, but 40-minutes into the film, it loses the pace. Even the culmination leaves a lot to be desired. Weir's direction is satisfactory, but the Screenplay has loose-ends. The Cinematography is good. As mentioned, 'Fearless' is packed with strong performances. Jeff Bridges plays a highly difficult role with brilliance. This truly is one of his best performances to date. Rosie Perez is outstanding in a role that, again, is very Hard to play and execute. Isabella Rossellini is marvelous. Tom Hulce is hugely effective. Benicio del Toro leaves a mark, he's superb. On the whole, Not A Gem, but surely deserves a watch for the Performances, that leave you stunned!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    PTSD Like No Other.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It helps to realize that this was directed by the Australian Peter Weir, many of whose films have oozed an ill-defined enigmatic quality. I remember the first of his movies I saw, "The Last Wave," in Palo Alto, when it was released. I'd never seen anything quite like it. And then, shortly afterward, "Picnic at Hanging Rock", which left me hanging at a much more tentative angle than the rock. Not all of his movie have been so mysterious, so bounced around, but "Fearless" is. Like "The Last Wave" it has a fuzzy supernatural element. Jeff Bridges and a few other passengers, Rosie Perez among them, survive a horrible fiery airplane crash in California. Bridges and Perez can't get their lives together afterward. Perez, having lost her baby in the accident, blames herself and is depressed almost beyond speech. Bridges, on the other hand, feels he is now indestructible and is, furthermore, some kind of supernatural agent left on earth to help Perez recover. His near-death experience has restructured his life. He feels he is invincible. He goes to lengths that anyone would describe as extreme in order to prove it. Bridges is always good. He always brings something extra to the role, although at times he overreaches. Rosie Perez isn't the Puerto Rican spitfire she usually is. She's subdued (for her) and effective in the character of a woman who has to realize that her baby's death was not her responsibility. Some comic moments are added by Tom Hulce as a bespectacled nervous wreck of a lawyer who sincerely wants to be sympathetic and get rich doing it. ("I know, I know, I'm a bad guy because I'm trying to get money. Don't bother saying it!") Isabella Rossellini is the increasingly distraught wife who can't understand why her husband is growing more distant, more ethereal, and appears to be falling in love with the woman he's trying to help. It isn't one of Weir's most provocative movies but once you get into it the narrative sweeps you up, partly because you can't help wondering where the hell it's all headed. The climax seems mundane after all that portent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A profound meditation on death, guilt, fear ... and ultimately, life ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fearless" awakened one of the most bizarre thoughts that ever crossed my mind: envy toward people who lived near death experiences, for the certitude that these people would never be the same again, and when you try to be someone else, any option is worth considering. "Fearless" takes place during the aftermath of a plane crash that presumably killed most passengers and left a few survivors in a state of shock. Are they privileged? Maybe from our perspective, but most of them would endure the trauma of having witnessed the death of a friend, a parent or even the seat neighbor. Most of them would endure the survivor's guilt. Not to mention the traumatic landing and the subsequent lottery of death. Peter Weir's movie, based on a novel by Rafael Iglesias, explores the complexities of the human soul from the different ways it reacts to a life-changing experience. The most intriguing case is Max Klein, an architect and family man, played by Jeff Bridges. Around him, it's chaos, mayhem, panic, cries and cadavers yet he walks like along the site, floating on a cloud of extraordinary serenity. He's not just a survivor, but also a savior, he gave a baby back to his mom, helped a little boy who was flying alone, he showed the safe way to many distraught passengers. Yet, the film doesn't focus on his heroic status, which he himself declines, it is more about the perception of life and death when you have been walking on the thin tightrope that separate the two worlds, when you 'saw the tunnel leading to a light'. Speaking of 'light', the narrative is punctuated by a few flashbacks that reveal how normally scared Max was during the flight, while sitting next to his best friend and colleague. It's only after the situation got more critical, that a mysterious heavenly light appeased his thoughts, and filled his heart with the serene confidence he would live. The crash sequence, which is among one of the most realistic, haunting and emotional from any other film, give some interesting insights that are later 'contradicted' by Max. The way he sees it: he's already a ghost, God can't touch him, he shares the little secret with Carla, a Hispanic mother who lost her child and can't recover from the guilt of not having held him tightly in her arms. Max and Carla form two interesting cases. Max survived and believe he's invulnerable, 'fearless' as the title suggest, with an inexorable desire to live life to its fullest, and the consequence is that it affects its relationships with his entourage. He becomes totally estranged to his wife, played by Isabella Rosselini (whose uncanny resemblance with her legendary was almost distracting), he lost the fatherly bond with his son in favor of the one he rescued, he couldn't even find the right words for his friend's widow or cooperate with the lawyer's desperate efforts to obtain a huge indemnity. Max rejects life's normality: money, convention, fear, video games, living with memories, his idea of the perfect life to live is a personal utopia that can only be fulfilled with someone who understands him. And this person is Carla. Played by Rosie Perez, Carla is the emotional core of the film, through the reaction most viewers can relate to, she's not a kind of super-human or angel, she only tried to save her son, but failed. And this failure puts her in a depressive state with suicidal impulses that only her deep Hispanic Catholic faith can alter. Contrarily to Max, Carla is much aware that she's living and that's what makes her life unbearable, for Max, the idea of death is so intolerable that he teases it by eating strawberries, a fruit he's allergic to, crossing the road, or walking on the ledge of a building's roof in the film's most emblematic scene. Fear is connected with self-preservation, but in Max' case, the fearless state doesn't mean he doesn't want to live, but it betrays his sentiment of inner immortality, yet the only way to be immortal is to be actually dead. Max is still between life and death. Either the wish to be dead out of guilt or sensation of being already dead from a weird exhilaration, both Perez and Bridges drive the film through sensitive and sensational performances. The therapist, played by John Turturro, explains to Max' wife that both Max and Carla represent two extremes in terms of reactions and on their interactions can depend chances of recovery. The relationship has a romantic vibe and maybe Max genuinely loves Carla, but "Fearless" never lures us into the idea that Carla would fall in love with him on the simple basis that they had the same experience. Love is not an end but a mean for Max to suppress all the traces of guilt in Carla's mind. Ironically, that's what Max' wife tries to do, helping him to regain his faith in life, and her many attempts to give a helping hand are concluded by 'failure to communicate', leading to what seems to be marital dead-end. But there is a reason Rosie Perez' performance was so acclaimed, she's not just a weepy, mourning mother, there is strength in her heart, and if her recovery can put and end to the mystical bond she had with Max, it leaves at least some room for the woman who really loves him. The conclusion of "Fearless", perhaps one of the most emotionally satisfying ever, is perfect because it does three things: it provides some answers about Max' enigmatic state of mind, it finds the perfect remedy, and it highlights the truth that one of the best things about life is to realize how great it is to live. Those who faced death have more awareness, and maybe this is what I consider their privilege. Do I want it? I'm not sure I'm that  fearless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When Great Character Study gets Interrupted by Hollywood Clich&eacute;s...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fearless is a drama centered around a man, played by Jeff Bridges, who survives a plane crash and can't get out of the state of being dead inside. It's very well acted film with standout performances by Jeff Bridges and Isabella Rossellini and features some brilliant direction by Peter Weir. I really liked the film and only minor annoyances that kept me from loving it. Jeff Bridges once again proves that he is one of the best living American actors out there. He truly sells the fact that he is dead inside and can't awake from the state his in. His performance is what really holds Fearless together and keeps you engaged. Isabella Rossellini and Rosie Perez provide the central supporting performances and they are very good. It's all around strongly acted film and keeps you invested in the characters and the hardships they go through. Peter Weir's direction perfectly compliments the storytelling and acting. His recreation of the plane crash was far more intense and horrifying than that of Flight. It's just a well directed film that's really well shot and gives a feeling that you are watching a real film. The script isn't as solid as the acting and the direction. The central themes and the characters are well explored and gives a good sense about what people go through when they survive terrible accidents. The problems start to pop whenever the film shoves in stupid Hollywood crap like wacky and silly lawyer, stupid subplots about greedy husband and other forced attempts of creating dramatic tension. You have so much going on with the characters already, you don't need some forced crap about things that hardly matter. Fearless is something you don't see often - a Hollywood film that wants to explore characters and leave pretension and self-importance out it. It's a very downbeat film but never depressing. Fearless is a optimistic film with a happy ending so it's a film you can actually enjoy. If you like Jeff Bridges and enjoy real films, you owe it to yourself to see it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Film; Disappointing Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruce Banner
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is an interesting character study of a man dealing with fear and death. I watched it because I'm a big fan of Jeff Bridges work as "The Dude" in The Big Lebowski but I was a bit letdown. Here's why: The movie did not deliver enough entertainment value. Thought provoking it was but entertaining- questionable. Also, the way the movie handled its core issues and themes seemed a little heavy handed to me. The old chestnut about script writing that the dialogue should never be totally "on the nose" was not adhered to, in this case to the film's detriment. I found some of the dialogue to be too direct and not leaving enough room for subtext and for the viewer to feel that there is something bubbling beneath the surface. Its always better for the writer to sketch the character's struggles as metaphors and incidental to the story rather than try to force themes to lead the story and drive its dialogue. Additionally, the Director's use of camera shots was a little slow. The style of, "Look at me, here is another important closeup on some random object for longer than we would like," coupled with the writing served to make the movie a bit melodramatic. Aside from Jeff Bridges who does a solid job in a decent role, Benicio Del Toro was very interesting in his minor role as was John Torturro. You will see a lot of rave reviews for Fearless largely because it has a small cult following who were emotionally impacted by it. As a regular viewer with no special connection to the film, I advise you to take these reviews with a grain of salt. They are biased. This is not a flawless film. It is merely an interesting one with a couple good actors. Definitely Not a must see. I also wasn't crazy about Rosie Perez. Her acting was one note, loud and amateurish rather than nuanced and intelligent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nasty movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sam hit
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched it till the end. If you the sort of person who spends a lot of time on thoughts like purpose, death and life DO NOT watch this movie. it's worse than an empty shell. it is false advertising, this movie. It tells about a man's journey after a plane crash that had changed him to someone who does not feel. He feels almost content with anything and joyous with life. there are some illogical plot occurring. It has to do with an allergy. Besides that the main character had little appeal to me. even the gorgeous women did not make up for what a fluke the movie was. I am flabbergasted that certain people felt so full of emotion after this movie but I think those are the shallow sort of people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Buying gifts for the dead....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a terrible air disaster, survivor Max Klein emerges a changed person. Unable to connect to his former life or to wife, he feels godlike and immortal. When psychologist Bill Perlman is unable to help, he has Max meet another survivor, Carla Rodrigo, who is racked with grief and guilt since her baby died in the crash.... This is one of those movies that had massive plaudits when first released, but vanished without a trace, (you can't even get it on DVD here in the UK). And I ask myself why? It's one of the best films no ones heard of in the nineties, and it may even have a career best performance from Bridges and the rest of the cast. It's a difficult subject matter to deal with, people trying to come to terms with loss, whereas one man, is doing everything in his power to prove everyone that something enigmatic, even sublime, happened to him on the plane. The film would be perfect if it had the same power in the third act, like it did in the first two, but sadly, it runs a little out of steam. The scenes on the plane are very intense and genuinely terrifying, but somewhat peaceful thanks to Bridges calming influence. The film is asking lots of questions throughout, but if you go that little much deeper, rather than look at it at face value, it gets a little lost also (there are some scenes, that are indicating that Bridges is really dead, and in purgatory, which can be confusing at times). But all in all, if you ever come across this movie, you must take some time out to see i, it's an amazing movie with an amazing message, it just loses it's way a little in the last 30 mins.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rather boring and depressing in my books. Jeff Bridges was the only saving grace
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Credit IMDb. After a terrible air disaster, survivor Max Klein emerges a changed person. Unable to connect to his former life or to wife Laura, he feels godlike and invulnerable. When psychologist Bill Perlman is unable to help Max, he has Max meet another survivor, Carla Rodrigo, who is racked with grief and guilt since her baby died in the crash which she and Max survived. It starts off with a gripping experience, with a crash sight, but from there it was all downhill for me. The acting is borderline flawless(aside from Perez). But the story is just depressing. I felt uncomfortable throughout the film, and watching them go through what they did was not rewarding, it got a bit much. Performances. Jeff Bridges is excellent no doubt about that. I felt what he was feeling, and he gives one of his finest performances. The trouble is, I didn't like the movie that was backing him up. Isabella Rossellini is good in her part, but rather an unlikable character in my opinion. Rosie Perez once again annoyed the heavens out of me, with her constant sniveling and shouting. Overrated much? John Turturro is solid in his role while Benicio Del Toro is solid too. Bottom line. Well made, well acted, but a boring experience that riddled me with depression. Worth a look, but that's about it. Maybe you'll get more out of it then I did. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Criminally underrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Elford
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A CRIMINALLY unknown film, especially in the UK, where it is close to impossible to get hold of, this Peter Weir outing, with Jeff Bridges taking the lead, also boasts star turns from John Turturro, Isabella Rossalini, and Rosie Perez, the latter of whom received an Oscar nomination. Everybody is on top form in this perfectly executed, beautiful meditation on what it is to be a human being. To explain all the subtext of "Fearless", all the symbolism, the various layers of allegory, would be an essay in itself; safe to say this is a film that sends you away reeling, thinking and talking about life for a long time. It sounds melodramatic, but when you see it, it makes perfect, serious sense. I understand it received standing ovations when it premiered, and rightly so! Many have said in the past, and I'll say it as well, that the final 10 minutes of this film is pretty much the most powerful cinema I've seen. Jeff Bridges nails it, and I find myself inexplicably in tears each time. Trying to explain it is tough; it speaks to something fundamental in you, and is truly life-affirming, if you choose to listen. A film that proves cinema, when image, performance, music and meaning are meshed perfectly, is sometimes able to convey what nothing else can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superior film of spiritual wonder.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bones Eijnar (namriggs@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching FEARLESS I clearly made up my mind about actor Jeff Bridges; he is utterly brilliant. This film is carried by his performance as a man who survives a plane crash and his the following life he lives in which his complete sense of existence is changed. The film finds mystery and tragedy and goes searching in religious places for answers that we draw out of the main character. Director Peter Weir lingers on Bridges and his inner self, and the many tender scenes that he goes through are very carefully achieved, never slipping into sentiment or boring clich&eacute;s. Throughout you really don't know whether Bridges is crazy, spiritual, dead or alive - he's yearning in something that everybody around him really don't see to understand. FEARLESS is a great film with many low-key scenes that tells a story thoroughly and thoughtfully, but it always escalates into joyous wonder, and that's where director Weir and Bridges truly captured me as a viewer. It's like that dark corridor towards the light in the magnificent ending scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Top-Notch Acting, Average Film...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Peter Weir has always been a filmmaker to admire. 'The Truman Show' is a legendary film, my all-time favorite film. 'Fearless', which released way back in 1993, sadly ranks amongst his weak efforts. However, this does become 'A Must Watch' film due to the strong performances by it's lead cast. Academy-Award-Winner Jeff Bridges stars as a man's who's personality is dramatically changed after surviving a major airline crash. The aftermath of the character and his connections with the world... is what 'Fearless' is all about. 'Fearless' begins wonderfully, but 40-minutes into the film, it loses the pace. Even the culmination leaves a lot to be desired. Weir's direction is satisfactory, but the Screenplay has loose-ends. The Cinematography is good. As mentioned, 'Fearless' is packed with strong performances. Jeff Bridges plays a highly difficult role with brilliance. This truly is one of his best performances to date. Rosie Perez is outstanding in a role that, again, is very Hard to play and execute. Isabella Rossellini is marvelous. Tom Hulce is hugely effective. Benicio del Toro leaves a mark, he's superb. On the whole, Not A Gem, but surely deserves a watch for the Performances, that leave you stunned!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    PTSD Like No Other.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It helps to realize that this was directed by the Australian Peter Weir, many of whose films have oozed an ill-defined enigmatic quality. I remember the first of his movies I saw, "The Last Wave," in Palo Alto, when it was released. I'd never seen anything quite like it. And then, shortly afterward, "Picnic at Hanging Rock", which left me hanging at a much more tentative angle than the rock. Not all of his movie have been so mysterious, so bounced around, but "Fearless" is. Like "The Last Wave" it has a fuzzy supernatural element. Jeff Bridges and a few other passengers, Rosie Perez among them, survive a horrible fiery airplane crash in California. Bridges and Perez can't get their lives together afterward. Perez, having lost her baby in the accident, blames herself and is depressed almost beyond speech. Bridges, on the other hand, feels he is now indestructible and is, furthermore, some kind of supernatural agent left on earth to help Perez recover. His near-death experience has restructured his life. He feels he is invincible. He goes to lengths that anyone would describe as extreme in order to prove it. Bridges is always good. He always brings something extra to the role, although at times he overreaches. Rosie Perez isn't the Puerto Rican spitfire she usually is. She's subdued (for her) and effective in the character of a woman who has to realize that her baby's death was not her responsibility. Some comic moments are added by Tom Hulce as a bespectacled nervous wreck of a lawyer who sincerely wants to be sympathetic and get rich doing it. ("I know, I know, I'm a bad guy because I'm trying to get money. Don't bother saying it!") Isabella Rossellini is the increasingly distraught wife who can't understand why her husband is growing more distant, more ethereal, and appears to be falling in love with the woman he's trying to help. It isn't one of Weir's most provocative movies but once you get into it the narrative sweeps you up, partly because you can't help wondering where the hell it's all headed. The climax seems mundane after all that portent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A profound meditation on death, guilt, fear ... and ultimately, life ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fearless" awakened one of the most bizarre thoughts that ever crossed my mind: envy toward people who lived near death experiences, for the certitude that these people would never be the same again, and when you try to be someone else, any option is worth considering. "Fearless" takes place during the aftermath of a plane crash that presumably killed most passengers and left a few survivors in a state of shock. Are they privileged? Maybe from our perspective, but most of them would endure the trauma of having witnessed the death of a friend, a parent or even the seat neighbor. Most of them would endure the survivor's guilt. Not to mention the traumatic landing and the subsequent lottery of death. Peter Weir's movie, based on a novel by Rafael Iglesias, explores the complexities of the human soul from the different ways it reacts to a life-changing experience. The most intriguing case is Max Klein, an architect and family man, played by Jeff Bridges. Around him, it's chaos, mayhem, panic, cries and cadavers yet he walks like along the site, floating on a cloud of extraordinary serenity. He's not just a survivor, but also a savior, he gave a baby back to his mom, helped a little boy who was flying alone, he showed the safe way to many distraught passengers. Yet, the film doesn't focus on his heroic status, which he himself declines, it is more about the perception of life and death when you have been walking on the thin tightrope that separate the two worlds, when you 'saw the tunnel leading to a light'. Speaking of 'light', the narrative is punctuated by a few flashbacks that reveal how normally scared Max was during the flight, while sitting next to his best friend and colleague. It's only after the situation got more critical, that a mysterious heavenly light appeased his thoughts, and filled his heart with the serene confidence he would live. The crash sequence, which is among one of the most realistic, haunting and emotional from any other film, give some interesting insights that are later 'contradicted' by Max. The way he sees it: he's already a ghost, God can't touch him, he shares the little secret with Carla, a Hispanic mother who lost her child and can't recover from the guilt of not having held him tightly in her arms. Max and Carla form two interesting cases. Max survived and believe he's invulnerable, 'fearless' as the title suggest, with an inexorable desire to live life to its fullest, and the consequence is that it affects its relationships with his entourage. He becomes totally estranged to his wife, played by Isabella Rosselini (whose uncanny resemblance with her legendary was almost distracting), he lost the fatherly bond with his son in favor of the one he rescued, he couldn't even find the right words for his friend's widow or cooperate with the lawyer's desperate efforts to obtain a huge indemnity. Max rejects life's normality: money, convention, fear, video games, living with memories, his idea of the perfect life to live is a personal utopia that can only be fulfilled with someone who understands him. And this person is Carla. Played by Rosie Perez, Carla is the emotional core of the film, through the reaction most viewers can relate to, she's not a kind of super-human or angel, she only tried to save her son, but failed. And this failure puts her in a depressive state with suicidal impulses that only her deep Hispanic Catholic faith can alter. Contrarily to Max, Carla is much aware that she's living and that's what makes her life unbearable, for Max, the idea of death is so intolerable that he teases it by eating strawberries, a fruit he's allergic to, crossing the road, or walking on the ledge of a building's roof in the film's most emblematic scene. Fear is connected with self-preservation, but in Max' case, the fearless state doesn't mean he doesn't want to live, but it betrays his sentiment of inner immortality, yet the only way to be immortal is to be actually dead. Max is still between life and death. Either the wish to be dead out of guilt or sensation of being already dead from a weird exhilaration, both Perez and Bridges drive the film through sensitive and sensational performances. The therapist, played by John Turturro, explains to Max' wife that both Max and Carla represent two extremes in terms of reactions and on their interactions can depend chances of recovery. The relationship has a romantic vibe and maybe Max genuinely loves Carla, but "Fearless" never lures us into the idea that Carla would fall in love with him on the simple basis that they had the same experience. Love is not an end but a mean for Max to suppress all the traces of guilt in Carla's mind. Ironically, that's what Max' wife tries to do, helping him to regain his faith in life, and her many attempts to give a helping hand are concluded by 'failure to communicate', leading to what seems to be marital dead-end. But there is a reason Rosie Perez' performance was so acclaimed, she's not just a weepy, mourning mother, there is strength in her heart, and if her recovery can put and end to the mystical bond she had with Max, it leaves at least some room for the woman who really loves him. The conclusion of "Fearless", perhaps one of the most emotionally satisfying ever, is perfect because it does three things: it provides some answers about Max' enigmatic state of mind, it finds the perfect remedy, and it highlights the truth that one of the best things about life is to realize how great it is to live. Those who faced death have more awareness, and maybe this is what I consider their privilege. Do I want it? I'm not sure I'm that  fearless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When Great Character Study gets Interrupted by Hollywood Clich&eacute;s...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fearless is a drama centered around a man, played by Jeff Bridges, who survives a plane crash and can't get out of the state of being dead inside. It's very well acted film with standout performances by Jeff Bridges and Isabella Rossellini and features some brilliant direction by Peter Weir. I really liked the film and only minor annoyances that kept me from loving it. Jeff Bridges once again proves that he is one of the best living American actors out there. He truly sells the fact that he is dead inside and can't awake from the state his in. His performance is what really holds Fearless together and keeps you engaged. Isabella Rossellini and Rosie Perez provide the central supporting performances and they are very good. It's all around strongly acted film and keeps you invested in the characters and the hardships they go through. Peter Weir's direction perfectly compliments the storytelling and acting. His recreation of the plane crash was far more intense and horrifying than that of Flight. It's just a well directed film that's really well shot and gives a feeling that you are watching a real film. The script isn't as solid as the acting and the direction. The central themes and the characters are well explored and gives a good sense about what people go through when they survive terrible accidents. The problems start to pop whenever the film shoves in stupid Hollywood crap like wacky and silly lawyer, stupid subplots about greedy husband and other forced attempts of creating dramatic tension. You have so much going on with the characters already, you don't need some forced crap about things that hardly matter. Fearless is something you don't see often - a Hollywood film that wants to explore characters and leave pretension and self-importance out it. It's a very downbeat film but never depressing. Fearless is a optimistic film with a happy ending so it's a film you can actually enjoy. If you like Jeff Bridges and enjoy real films, you owe it to yourself to see it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Film; Disappointing Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruce Banner
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is an interesting character study of a man dealing with fear and death. I watched it because I'm a big fan of Jeff Bridges work as "The Dude" in The Big Lebowski but I was a bit letdown. Here's why: The movie did not deliver enough entertainment value. Thought provoking it was but entertaining- questionable. Also, the way the movie handled its core issues and themes seemed a little heavy handed to me. The old chestnut about script writing that the dialogue should never be totally "on the nose" was not adhered to, in this case to the film's detriment. I found some of the dialogue to be too direct and not leaving enough room for subtext and for the viewer to feel that there is something bubbling beneath the surface. Its always better for the writer to sketch the character's struggles as metaphors and incidental to the story rather than try to force themes to lead the story and drive its dialogue. Additionally, the Director's use of camera shots was a little slow. The style of, "Look at me, here is another important closeup on some random object for longer than we would like," coupled with the writing served to make the movie a bit melodramatic. Aside from Jeff Bridges who does a solid job in a decent role, Benicio Del Toro was very interesting in his minor role as was John Torturro. You will see a lot of rave reviews for Fearless largely because it has a small cult following who were emotionally impacted by it. As a regular viewer with no special connection to the film, I advise you to take these reviews with a grain of salt. They are biased. This is not a flawless film. It is merely an interesting one with a couple good actors. Definitely Not a must see. I also wasn't crazy about Rosie Perez. Her acting was one note, loud and amateurish rather than nuanced and intelligent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nasty movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sam hit
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched it till the end. If you the sort of person who spends a lot of time on thoughts like purpose, death and life DO NOT watch this movie. it's worse than an empty shell. it is false advertising, this movie. It tells about a man's journey after a plane crash that had changed him to someone who does not feel. He feels almost content with anything and joyous with life. there are some illogical plot occurring. It has to do with an allergy. Besides that the main character had little appeal to me. even the gorgeous women did not make up for what a fluke the movie was. I am flabbergasted that certain people felt so full of emotion after this movie but I think those are the shallow sort of people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Buying gifts for the dead....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a terrible air disaster, survivor Max Klein emerges a changed person. Unable to connect to his former life or to wife, he feels godlike and immortal. When psychologist Bill Perlman is unable to help, he has Max meet another survivor, Carla Rodrigo, who is racked with grief and guilt since her baby died in the crash.... This is one of those movies that had massive plaudits when first released, but vanished without a trace, (you can't even get it on DVD here in the UK). And I ask myself why? It's one of the best films no ones heard of in the nineties, and it may even have a career best performance from Bridges and the rest of the cast. It's a difficult subject matter to deal with, people trying to come to terms with loss, whereas one man, is doing everything in his power to prove everyone that something enigmatic, even sublime, happened to him on the plane. The film would be perfect if it had the same power in the third act, like it did in the first two, but sadly, it runs a little out of steam. The scenes on the plane are very intense and genuinely terrifying, but somewhat peaceful thanks to Bridges calming influence. The film is asking lots of questions throughout, but if you go that little much deeper, rather than look at it at face value, it gets a little lost also (there are some scenes, that are indicating that Bridges is really dead, and in purgatory, which can be confusing at times). But all in all, if you ever come across this movie, you must take some time out to see i, it's an amazing movie with an amazing message, it just loses it's way a little in the last 30 mins.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rather boring and depressing in my books. Jeff Bridges was the only saving grace
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Credit IMDb. After a terrible air disaster, survivor Max Klein emerges a changed person. Unable to connect to his former life or to wife Laura, he feels godlike and invulnerable. When psychologist Bill Perlman is unable to help Max, he has Max meet another survivor, Carla Rodrigo, who is racked with grief and guilt since her baby died in the crash which she and Max survived. It starts off with a gripping experience, with a crash sight, but from there it was all downhill for me. The acting is borderline flawless(aside from Perez). But the story is just depressing. I felt uncomfortable throughout the film, and watching them go through what they did was not rewarding, it got a bit much. Performances. Jeff Bridges is excellent no doubt about that. I felt what he was feeling, and he gives one of his finest performances. The trouble is, I didn't like the movie that was backing him up. Isabella Rossellini is good in her part, but rather an unlikable character in my opinion. Rosie Perez once again annoyed the heavens out of me, with her constant sniveling and shouting. Overrated much? John Turturro is solid in his role while Benicio Del Toro is solid too. Bottom line. Well made, well acted, but a boring experience that riddled me with depression. Worth a look, but that's about it. Maybe you'll get more out of it then I did. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Criminally underrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Elford
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A CRIMINALLY unknown film, especially in the UK, where it is close to impossible to get hold of, this Peter Weir outing, with Jeff Bridges taking the lead, also boasts star turns from John Turturro, Isabella Rossalini, and Rosie Perez, the latter of whom received an Oscar nomination. Everybody is on top form in this perfectly executed, beautiful meditation on what it is to be a human being. To explain all the subtext of "Fearless", all the symbolism, the various layers of allegory, would be an essay in itself; safe to say this is a film that sends you away reeling, thinking and talking about life for a long time. It sounds melodramatic, but when you see it, it makes perfect, serious sense. I understand it received standing ovations when it premiered, and rightly so! Many have said in the past, and I'll say it as well, that the final 10 minutes of this film is pretty much the most powerful cinema I've seen. Jeff Bridges nails it, and I find myself inexplicably in tears each time. Trying to explain it is tough; it speaks to something fundamental in you, and is truly life-affirming, if you choose to listen. A film that proves cinema, when image, performance, music and meaning are meshed perfectly, is sometimes able to convey what nothing else can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superior film of spiritual wonder.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bones Eijnar (namriggs@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching FEARLESS I clearly made up my mind about actor Jeff Bridges; he is utterly brilliant. This film is carried by his performance as a man who survives a plane crash and his the following life he lives in which his complete sense of existence is changed. The film finds mystery and tragedy and goes searching in religious places for answers that we draw out of the main character. Director Peter Weir lingers on Bridges and his inner self, and the many tender scenes that he goes through are very carefully achieved, never slipping into sentiment or boring clich&eacute;s. Throughout you really don't know whether Bridges is crazy, spiritual, dead or alive - he's yearning in something that everybody around him really don't see to understand. FEARLESS is a great film with many low-key scenes that tells a story thoroughly and thoughtfully, but it always escalates into joyous wonder, and that's where director Weir and Bridges truly captured me as a viewer. It's like that dark corridor towards the light in the magnificent ending scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Top-Notch Acting, Average Film...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Peter Weir has always been a filmmaker to admire. 'The Truman Show' is a legendary film, my all-time favorite film. 'Fearless', which released way back in 1993, sadly ranks amongst his weak efforts. However, this does become 'A Must Watch' film due to the strong performances by it's lead cast. Academy-Award-Winner Jeff Bridges stars as a man's who's personality is dramatically changed after surviving a major airline crash. The aftermath of the character and his connections with the world... is what 'Fearless' is all about. 'Fearless' begins wonderfully, but 40-minutes into the film, it loses the pace. Even the culmination leaves a lot to be desired. Weir's direction is satisfactory, but the Screenplay has loose-ends. The Cinematography is good. As mentioned, 'Fearless' is packed with strong performances. Jeff Bridges plays a highly difficult role with brilliance. This truly is one of his best performances to date. Rosie Perez is outstanding in a role that, again, is very Hard to play and execute. Isabella Rossellini is marvelous. Tom Hulce is hugely effective. Benicio del Toro leaves a mark, he's superb. On the whole, Not A Gem, but surely deserves a watch for the Performances, that leave you stunned!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    PTSD Like No Other.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It helps to realize that this was directed by the Australian Peter Weir, many of whose films have oozed an ill-defined enigmatic quality. I remember the first of his movies I saw, "The Last Wave," in Palo Alto, when it was released. I'd never seen anything quite like it. And then, shortly afterward, "Picnic at Hanging Rock", which left me hanging at a much more tentative angle than the rock. Not all of his movie have been so mysterious, so bounced around, but "Fearless" is. Like "The Last Wave" it has a fuzzy supernatural element. Jeff Bridges and a few other passengers, Rosie Perez among them, survive a horrible fiery airplane crash in California. Bridges and Perez can't get their lives together afterward. Perez, having lost her baby in the accident, blames herself and is depressed almost beyond speech. Bridges, on the other hand, feels he is now indestructible and is, furthermore, some kind of supernatural agent left on earth to help Perez recover. His near-death experience has restructured his life. He feels he is invincible. He goes to lengths that anyone would describe as extreme in order to prove it. Bridges is always good. He always brings something extra to the role, although at times he overreaches. Rosie Perez isn't the Puerto Rican spitfire she usually is. She's subdued (for her) and effective in the character of a woman who has to realize that her baby's death was not her responsibility. Some comic moments are added by Tom Hulce as a bespectacled nervous wreck of a lawyer who sincerely wants to be sympathetic and get rich doing it. ("I know, I know, I'm a bad guy because I'm trying to get money. Don't bother saying it!") Isabella Rossellini is the increasingly distraught wife who can't understand why her husband is growing more distant, more ethereal, and appears to be falling in love with the woman he's trying to help. It isn't one of Weir's most provocative movies but once you get into it the narrative sweeps you up, partly because you can't help wondering where the hell it's all headed. The climax seems mundane after all that portent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A profound meditation on death, guilt, fear ... and ultimately, life ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fearless" awakened one of the most bizarre thoughts that ever crossed my mind: envy toward people who lived near death experiences, for the certitude that these people would never be the same again, and when you try to be someone else, any option is worth considering. "Fearless" takes place during the aftermath of a plane crash that presumably killed most passengers and left a few survivors in a state of shock. Are they privileged? Maybe from our perspective, but most of them would endure the trauma of having witnessed the death of a friend, a parent or even the seat neighbor. Most of them would endure the survivor's guilt. Not to mention the traumatic landing and the subsequent lottery of death. Peter Weir's movie, based on a novel by Rafael Iglesias, explores the complexities of the human soul from the different ways it reacts to a life-changing experience. The most intriguing case is Max Klein, an architect and family man, played by Jeff Bridges. Around him, it's chaos, mayhem, panic, cries and cadavers yet he walks like along the site, floating on a cloud of extraordinary serenity. He's not just a survivor, but also a savior, he gave a baby back to his mom, helped a little boy who was flying alone, he showed the safe way to many distraught passengers. Yet, the film doesn't focus on his heroic status, which he himself declines, it is more about the perception of life and death when you have been walking on the thin tightrope that separate the two worlds, when you 'saw the tunnel leading to a light'. Speaking of 'light', the narrative is punctuated by a few flashbacks that reveal how normally scared Max was during the flight, while sitting next to his best friend and colleague. It's only after the situation got more critical, that a mysterious heavenly light appeased his thoughts, and filled his heart with the serene confidence he would live. The crash sequence, which is among one of the most realistic, haunting and emotional from any other film, give some interesting insights that are later 'contradicted' by Max. The way he sees it: he's already a ghost, God can't touch him, he shares the little secret with Carla, a Hispanic mother who lost her child and can't recover from the guilt of not having held him tightly in her arms. Max and Carla form two interesting cases. Max survived and believe he's invulnerable, 'fearless' as the title suggest, with an inexorable desire to live life to its fullest, and the consequence is that it affects its relationships with his entourage. He becomes totally estranged to his wife, played by Isabella Rosselini (whose uncanny resemblance with her legendary was almost distracting), he lost the fatherly bond with his son in favor of the one he rescued, he couldn't even find the right words for his friend's widow or cooperate with the lawyer's desperate efforts to obtain a huge indemnity. Max rejects life's normality: money, convention, fear, video games, living with memories, his idea of the perfect life to live is a personal utopia that can only be fulfilled with someone who understands him. And this person is Carla. Played by Rosie Perez, Carla is the emotional core of the film, through the reaction most viewers can relate to, she's not a kind of super-human or angel, she only tried to save her son, but failed. And this failure puts her in a depressive state with suicidal impulses that only her deep Hispanic Catholic faith can alter. Contrarily to Max, Carla is much aware that she's living and that's what makes her life unbearable, for Max, the idea of death is so intolerable that he teases it by eating strawberries, a fruit he's allergic to, crossing the road, or walking on the ledge of a building's roof in the film's most emblematic scene. Fear is connected with self-preservation, but in Max' case, the fearless state doesn't mean he doesn't want to live, but it betrays his sentiment of inner immortality, yet the only way to be immortal is to be actually dead. Max is still between life and death. Either the wish to be dead out of guilt or sensation of being already dead from a weird exhilaration, both Perez and Bridges drive the film through sensitive and sensational performances. The therapist, played by John Turturro, explains to Max' wife that both Max and Carla represent two extremes in terms of reactions and on their interactions can depend chances of recovery. The relationship has a romantic vibe and maybe Max genuinely loves Carla, but "Fearless" never lures us into the idea that Carla would fall in love with him on the simple basis that they had the same experience. Love is not an end but a mean for Max to suppress all the traces of guilt in Carla's mind. Ironically, that's what Max' wife tries to do, helping him to regain his faith in life, and her many attempts to give a helping hand are concluded by 'failure to communicate', leading to what seems to be marital dead-end. But there is a reason Rosie Perez' performance was so acclaimed, she's not just a weepy, mourning mother, there is strength in her heart, and if her recovery can put and end to the mystical bond she had with Max, it leaves at least some room for the woman who really loves him. The conclusion of "Fearless", perhaps one of the most emotionally satisfying ever, is perfect because it does three things: it provides some answers about Max' enigmatic state of mind, it finds the perfect remedy, and it highlights the truth that one of the best things about life is to realize how great it is to live. Those who faced death have more awareness, and maybe this is what I consider their privilege. Do I want it? I'm not sure I'm that  fearless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When Great Character Study gets Interrupted by Hollywood Clich&eacute;s...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fearless is a drama centered around a man, played by Jeff Bridges, who survives a plane crash and can't get out of the state of being dead inside. It's very well acted film with standout performances by Jeff Bridges and Isabella Rossellini and features some brilliant direction by Peter Weir. I really liked the film and only minor annoyances that kept me from loving it. Jeff Bridges once again proves that he is one of the best living American actors out there. He truly sells the fact that he is dead inside and can't awake from the state his in. His performance is what really holds Fearless together and keeps you engaged. Isabella Rossellini and Rosie Perez provide the central supporting performances and they are very good. It's all around strongly acted film and keeps you invested in the characters and the hardships they go through. Peter Weir's direction perfectly compliments the storytelling and acting. His recreation of the plane crash was far more intense and horrifying than that of Flight. It's just a well directed film that's really well shot and gives a feeling that you are watching a real film. The script isn't as solid as the acting and the direction. The central themes and the characters are well explored and gives a good sense about what people go through when they survive terrible accidents. The problems start to pop whenever the film shoves in stupid Hollywood crap like wacky and silly lawyer, stupid subplots about greedy husband and other forced attempts of creating dramatic tension. You have so much going on with the characters already, you don't need some forced crap about things that hardly matter. Fearless is something you don't see often - a Hollywood film that wants to explore characters and leave pretension and self-importance out it. It's a very downbeat film but never depressing. Fearless is a optimistic film with a happy ending so it's a film you can actually enjoy. If you like Jeff Bridges and enjoy real films, you owe it to yourself to see it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Film; Disappointing Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruce Banner
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is an interesting character study of a man dealing with fear and death. I watched it because I'm a big fan of Jeff Bridges work as "The Dude" in The Big Lebowski but I was a bit letdown. Here's why: The movie did not deliver enough entertainment value. Thought provoking it was but entertaining- questionable. Also, the way the movie handled its core issues and themes seemed a little heavy handed to me. The old chestnut about script writing that the dialogue should never be totally "on the nose" was not adhered to, in this case to the film's detriment. I found some of the dialogue to be too direct and not leaving enough room for subtext and for the viewer to feel that there is something bubbling beneath the surface. Its always better for the writer to sketch the character's struggles as metaphors and incidental to the story rather than try to force themes to lead the story and drive its dialogue. Additionally, the Director's use of camera shots was a little slow. The style of, "Look at me, here is another important closeup on some random object for longer than we would like," coupled with the writing served to make the movie a bit melodramatic. Aside from Jeff Bridges who does a solid job in a decent role, Benicio Del Toro was very interesting in his minor role as was John Torturro. You will see a lot of rave reviews for Fearless largely because it has a small cult following who were emotionally impacted by it. As a regular viewer with no special connection to the film, I advise you to take these reviews with a grain of salt. They are biased. This is not a flawless film. It is merely an interesting one with a couple good actors. Definitely Not a must see. I also wasn't crazy about Rosie Perez. Her acting was one note, loud and amateurish rather than nuanced and intelligent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nasty movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sam hit
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched it till the end. If you the sort of person who spends a lot of time on thoughts like purpose, death and life DO NOT watch this movie. it's worse than an empty shell. it is false advertising, this movie. It tells about a man's journey after a plane crash that had changed him to someone who does not feel. He feels almost content with anything and joyous with life. there are some illogical plot occurring. It has to do with an allergy. Besides that the main character had little appeal to me. even the gorgeous women did not make up for what a fluke the movie was. I am flabbergasted that certain people felt so full of emotion after this movie but I think those are the shallow sort of people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Buying gifts for the dead....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a terrible air disaster, survivor Max Klein emerges a changed person. Unable to connect to his former life or to wife, he feels godlike and immortal. When psychologist Bill Perlman is unable to help, he has Max meet another survivor, Carla Rodrigo, who is racked with grief and guilt since her baby died in the crash.... This is one of those movies that had massive plaudits when first released, but vanished without a trace, (you can't even get it on DVD here in the UK). And I ask myself why? It's one of the best films no ones heard of in the nineties, and it may even have a career best performance from Bridges and the rest of the cast. It's a difficult subject matter to deal with, people trying to come to terms with loss, whereas one man, is doing everything in his power to prove everyone that something enigmatic, even sublime, happened to him on the plane. The film would be perfect if it had the same power in the third act, like it did in the first two, but sadly, it runs a little out of steam. The scenes on the plane are very intense and genuinely terrifying, but somewhat peaceful thanks to Bridges calming influence. The film is asking lots of questions throughout, but if you go that little much deeper, rather than look at it at face value, it gets a little lost also (there are some scenes, that are indicating that Bridges is really dead, and in purgatory, which can be confusing at times). But all in all, if you ever come across this movie, you must take some time out to see i, it's an amazing movie with an amazing message, it just loses it's way a little in the last 30 mins.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rather boring and depressing in my books. Jeff Bridges was the only saving grace
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Credit IMDb. After a terrible air disaster, survivor Max Klein emerges a changed person. Unable to connect to his former life or to wife Laura, he feels godlike and invulnerable. When psychologist Bill Perlman is unable to help Max, he has Max meet another survivor, Carla Rodrigo, who is racked with grief and guilt since her baby died in the crash which she and Max survived. It starts off with a gripping experience, with a crash sight, but from there it was all downhill for me. The acting is borderline flawless(aside from Perez). But the story is just depressing. I felt uncomfortable throughout the film, and watching them go through what they did was not rewarding, it got a bit much. Performances. Jeff Bridges is excellent no doubt about that. I felt what he was feeling, and he gives one of his finest performances. The trouble is, I didn't like the movie that was backing him up. Isabella Rossellini is good in her part, but rather an unlikable character in my opinion. Rosie Perez once again annoyed the heavens out of me, with her constant sniveling and shouting. Overrated much? John Turturro is solid in his role while Benicio Del Toro is solid too. Bottom line. Well made, well acted, but a boring experience that riddled me with depression. Worth a look, but that's about it. Maybe you'll get more out of it then I did. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Criminally underrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Elford
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A CRIMINALLY unknown film, especially in the UK, where it is close to impossible to get hold of, this Peter Weir outing, with Jeff Bridges taking the lead, also boasts star turns from John Turturro, Isabella Rossalini, and Rosie Perez, the latter of whom received an Oscar nomination. Everybody is on top form in this perfectly executed, beautiful meditation on what it is to be a human being. To explain all the subtext of "Fearless", all the symbolism, the various layers of allegory, would be an essay in itself; safe to say this is a film that sends you away reeling, thinking and talking about life for a long time. It sounds melodramatic, but when you see it, it makes perfect, serious sense. I understand it received standing ovations when it premiered, and rightly so! Many have said in the past, and I'll say it as well, that the final 10 minutes of this film is pretty much the most powerful cinema I've seen. Jeff Bridges nails it, and I find myself inexplicably in tears each time. Trying to explain it is tough; it speaks to something fundamental in you, and is truly life-affirming, if you choose to listen. A film that proves cinema, when image, performance, music and meaning are meshed perfectly, is sometimes able to convey what nothing else can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superior film of spiritual wonder.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bones Eijnar (namriggs@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching FEARLESS I clearly made up my mind about actor Jeff Bridges; he is utterly brilliant. This film is carried by his performance as a man who survives a plane crash and his the following life he lives in which his complete sense of existence is changed. The film finds mystery and tragedy and goes searching in religious places for answers that we draw out of the main character. Director Peter Weir lingers on Bridges and his inner self, and the many tender scenes that he goes through are very carefully achieved, never slipping into sentiment or boring clich&eacute;s. Throughout you really don't know whether Bridges is crazy, spiritual, dead or alive - he's yearning in something that everybody around him really don't see to understand. FEARLESS is a great film with many low-key scenes that tells a story thoroughly and thoughtfully, but it always escalates into joyous wonder, and that's where director Weir and Bridges truly captured me as a viewer. It's like that dark corridor towards the light in the magnificent ending scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Top-Notch Acting, Average Film...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Peter Weir has always been a filmmaker to admire. 'The Truman Show' is a legendary film, my all-time favorite film. 'Fearless', which released way back in 1993, sadly ranks amongst his weak efforts. However, this does become 'A Must Watch' film due to the strong performances by it's lead cast. Academy-Award-Winner Jeff Bridges stars as a man's who's personality is dramatically changed after surviving a major airline crash. The aftermath of the character and his connections with the world... is what 'Fearless' is all about. 'Fearless' begins wonderfully, but 40-minutes into the film, it loses the pace. Even the culmination leaves a lot to be desired. Weir's direction is satisfactory, but the Screenplay has loose-ends. The Cinematography is good. As mentioned, 'Fearless' is packed with strong performances. Jeff Bridges plays a highly difficult role with brilliance. This truly is one of his best performances to date. Rosie Perez is outstanding in a role that, again, is very Hard to play and execute. Isabella Rossellini is marvelous. Tom Hulce is hugely effective. Benicio del Toro leaves a mark, he's superb. On the whole, Not A Gem, but surely deserves a watch for the Performances, that leave you stunned!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    PTSD Like No Other.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It helps to realize that this was directed by the Australian Peter Weir, many of whose films have oozed an ill-defined enigmatic quality. I remember the first of his movies I saw, "The Last Wave," in Palo Alto, when it was released. I'd never seen anything quite like it. And then, shortly afterward, "Picnic at Hanging Rock", which left me hanging at a much more tentative angle than the rock. Not all of his movie have been so mysterious, so bounced around, but "Fearless" is. Like "The Last Wave" it has a fuzzy supernatural element. Jeff Bridges and a few other passengers, Rosie Perez among them, survive a horrible fiery airplane crash in California. Bridges and Perez can't get their lives together afterward. Perez, having lost her baby in the accident, blames herself and is depressed almost beyond speech. Bridges, on the other hand, feels he is now indestructible and is, furthermore, some kind of supernatural agent left on earth to help Perez recover. His near-death experience has restructured his life. He feels he is invincible. He goes to lengths that anyone would describe as extreme in order to prove it. Bridges is always good. He always brings something extra to the role, although at times he overreaches. Rosie Perez isn't the Puerto Rican spitfire she usually is. She's subdued (for her) and effective in the character of a woman who has to realize that her baby's death was not her responsibility. Some comic moments are added by Tom Hulce as a bespectacled nervous wreck of a lawyer who sincerely wants to be sympathetic and get rich doing it. ("I know, I know, I'm a bad guy because I'm trying to get money. Don't bother saying it!") Isabella Rossellini is the increasingly distraught wife who can't understand why her husband is growing more distant, more ethereal, and appears to be falling in love with the woman he's trying to help. It isn't one of Weir's most provocative movies but once you get into it the narrative sweeps you up, partly because you can't help wondering where the hell it's all headed. The climax seems mundane after all that portent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A profound meditation on death, guilt, fear ... and ultimately, life ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fearless" awakened one of the most bizarre thoughts that ever crossed my mind: envy toward people who lived near death experiences, for the certitude that these people would never be the same again, and when you try to be someone else, any option is worth considering. "Fearless" takes place during the aftermath of a plane crash that presumably killed most passengers and left a few survivors in a state of shock. Are they privileged? Maybe from our perspective, but most of them would endure the trauma of having witnessed the death of a friend, a parent or even the seat neighbor. Most of them would endure the survivor's guilt. Not to mention the traumatic landing and the subsequent lottery of death. Peter Weir's movie, based on a novel by Rafael Iglesias, explores the complexities of the human soul from the different ways it reacts to a life-changing experience. The most intriguing case is Max Klein, an architect and family man, played by Jeff Bridges. Around him, it's chaos, mayhem, panic, cries and cadavers yet he walks like along the site, floating on a cloud of extraordinary serenity. He's not just a survivor, but also a savior, he gave a baby back to his mom, helped a little boy who was flying alone, he showed the safe way to many distraught passengers. Yet, the film doesn't focus on his heroic status, which he himself declines, it is more about the perception of life and death when you have been walking on the thin tightrope that separate the two worlds, when you 'saw the tunnel leading to a light'. Speaking of 'light', the narrative is punctuated by a few flashbacks that reveal how normally scared Max was during the flight, while sitting next to his best friend and colleague. It's only after the situation got more critical, that a mysterious heavenly light appeased his thoughts, and filled his heart with the serene confidence he would live. The crash sequence, which is among one of the most realistic, haunting and emotional from any other film, give some interesting insights that are later 'contradicted' by Max. The way he sees it: he's already a ghost, God can't touch him, he shares the little secret with Carla, a Hispanic mother who lost her child and can't recover from the guilt of not having held him tightly in her arms. Max and Carla form two interesting cases. Max survived and believe he's invulnerable, 'fearless' as the title suggest, with an inexorable desire to live life to its fullest, and the consequence is that it affects its relationships with his entourage. He becomes totally estranged to his wife, played by Isabella Rosselini (whose uncanny resemblance with her legendary was almost distracting), he lost the fatherly bond with his son in favor of the one he rescued, he couldn't even find the right words for his friend's widow or cooperate with the lawyer's desperate efforts to obtain a huge indemnity. Max rejects life's normality: money, convention, fear, video games, living with memories, his idea of the perfect life to live is a personal utopia that can only be fulfilled with someone who understands him. And this person is Carla. Played by Rosie Perez, Carla is the emotional core of the film, through the reaction most viewers can relate to, she's not a kind of super-human or angel, she only tried to save her son, but failed. And this failure puts her in a depressive state with suicidal impulses that only her deep Hispanic Catholic faith can alter. Contrarily to Max, Carla is much aware that she's living and that's what makes her life unbearable, for Max, the idea of death is so intolerable that he teases it by eating strawberries, a fruit he's allergic to, crossing the road, or walking on the ledge of a building's roof in the film's most emblematic scene. Fear is connected with self-preservation, but in Max' case, the fearless state doesn't mean he doesn't want to live, but it betrays his sentiment of inner immortality, yet the only way to be immortal is to be actually dead. Max is still between life and death. Either the wish to be dead out of guilt or sensation of being already dead from a weird exhilaration, both Perez and Bridges drive the film through sensitive and sensational performances. The therapist, played by John Turturro, explains to Max' wife that both Max and Carla represent two extremes in terms of reactions and on their interactions can depend chances of recovery. The relationship has a romantic vibe and maybe Max genuinely loves Carla, but "Fearless" never lures us into the idea that Carla would fall in love with him on the simple basis that they had the same experience. Love is not an end but a mean for Max to suppress all the traces of guilt in Carla's mind. Ironically, that's what Max' wife tries to do, helping him to regain his faith in life, and her many attempts to give a helping hand are concluded by 'failure to communicate', leading to what seems to be marital dead-end. But there is a reason Rosie Perez' performance was so acclaimed, she's not just a weepy, mourning mother, there is strength in her heart, and if her recovery can put and end to the mystical bond she had with Max, it leaves at least some room for the woman who really loves him. The conclusion of "Fearless", perhaps one of the most emotionally satisfying ever, is perfect because it does three things: it provides some answers about Max' enigmatic state of mind, it finds the perfect remedy, and it highlights the truth that one of the best things about life is to realize how great it is to live. Those who faced death have more awareness, and maybe this is what I consider their privilege. Do I want it? I'm not sure I'm that  fearless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When Great Character Study gets Interrupted by Hollywood Clich&eacute;s...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fearless is a drama centered around a man, played by Jeff Bridges, who survives a plane crash and can't get out of the state of being dead inside. It's very well acted film with standout performances by Jeff Bridges and Isabella Rossellini and features some brilliant direction by Peter Weir. I really liked the film and only minor annoyances that kept me from loving it. Jeff Bridges once again proves that he is one of the best living American actors out there. He truly sells the fact that he is dead inside and can't awake from the state his in. His performance is what really holds Fearless together and keeps you engaged. Isabella Rossellini and Rosie Perez provide the central supporting performances and they are very good. It's all around strongly acted film and keeps you invested in the characters and the hardships they go through. Peter Weir's direction perfectly compliments the storytelling and acting. His recreation of the plane crash was far more intense and horrifying than that of Flight. It's just a well directed film that's really well shot and gives a feeling that you are watching a real film. The script isn't as solid as the acting and the direction. The central themes and the characters are well explored and gives a good sense about what people go through when they survive terrible accidents. The problems start to pop whenever the film shoves in stupid Hollywood crap like wacky and silly lawyer, stupid subplots about greedy husband and other forced attempts of creating dramatic tension. You have so much going on with the characters already, you don't need some forced crap about things that hardly matter. Fearless is something you don't see often - a Hollywood film that wants to explore characters and leave pretension and self-importance out it. It's a very downbeat film but never depressing. Fearless is a optimistic film with a happy ending so it's a film you can actually enjoy. If you like Jeff Bridges and enjoy real films, you owe it to yourself to see it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Film; Disappointing Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruce Banner
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is an interesting character study of a man dealing with fear and death. I watched it because I'm a big fan of Jeff Bridges work as "The Dude" in The Big Lebowski but I was a bit letdown. Here's why: The movie did not deliver enough entertainment value. Thought provoking it was but entertaining- questionable. Also, the way the movie handled its core issues and themes seemed a little heavy handed to me. The old chestnut about script writing that the dialogue should never be totally "on the nose" was not adhered to, in this case to the film's detriment. I found some of the dialogue to be too direct and not leaving enough room for subtext and for the viewer to feel that there is something bubbling beneath the surface. Its always better for the writer to sketch the character's struggles as metaphors and incidental to the story rather than try to force themes to lead the story and drive its dialogue. Additionally, the Director's use of camera shots was a little slow. The style of, "Look at me, here is another important closeup on some random object for longer than we would like," coupled with the writing served to make the movie a bit melodramatic. Aside from Jeff Bridges who does a solid job in a decent role, Benicio Del Toro was very interesting in his minor role as was John Torturro. You will see a lot of rave reviews for Fearless largely because it has a small cult following who were emotionally impacted by it. As a regular viewer with no special connection to the film, I advise you to take these reviews with a grain of salt. They are biased. This is not a flawless film. It is merely an interesting one with a couple good actors. Definitely Not a must see. I also wasn't crazy about Rosie Perez. Her acting was one note, loud and amateurish rather than nuanced and intelligent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nasty movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sam hit
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched it till the end. If you the sort of person who spends a lot of time on thoughts like purpose, death and life DO NOT watch this movie. it's worse than an empty shell. it is false advertising, this movie. It tells about a man's journey after a plane crash that had changed him to someone who does not feel. He feels almost content with anything and joyous with life. there are some illogical plot occurring. It has to do with an allergy. Besides that the main character had little appeal to me. even the gorgeous women did not make up for what a fluke the movie was. I am flabbergasted that certain people felt so full of emotion after this movie but I think those are the shallow sort of people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Buying gifts for the dead....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a terrible air disaster, survivor Max Klein emerges a changed person. Unable to connect to his former life or to wife, he feels godlike and immortal. When psychologist Bill Perlman is unable to help, he has Max meet another survivor, Carla Rodrigo, who is racked with grief and guilt since her baby died in the crash.... This is one of those movies that had massive plaudits when first released, but vanished without a trace, (you can't even get it on DVD here in the UK). And I ask myself why? It's one of the best films no ones heard of in the nineties, and it may even have a career best performance from Bridges and the rest of the cast. It's a difficult subject matter to deal with, people trying to come to terms with loss, whereas one man, is doing everything in his power to prove everyone that something enigmatic, even sublime, happened to him on the plane. The film would be perfect if it had the same power in the third act, like it did in the first two, but sadly, it runs a little out of steam. The scenes on the plane are very intense and genuinely terrifying, but somewhat peaceful thanks to Bridges calming influence. The film is asking lots of questions throughout, but if you go that little much deeper, rather than look at it at face value, it gets a little lost also (there are some scenes, that are indicating that Bridges is really dead, and in purgatory, which can be confusing at times). But all in all, if you ever come across this movie, you must take some time out to see i, it's an amazing movie with an amazing message, it just loses it's way a little in the last 30 mins.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rather boring and depressing in my books. Jeff Bridges was the only saving grace
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Credit IMDb. After a terrible air disaster, survivor Max Klein emerges a changed person. Unable to connect to his former life or to wife Laura, he feels godlike and invulnerable. When psychologist Bill Perlman is unable to help Max, he has Max meet another survivor, Carla Rodrigo, who is racked with grief and guilt since her baby died in the crash which she and Max survived. It starts off with a gripping experience, with a crash sight, but from there it was all downhill for me. The acting is borderline flawless(aside from Perez). But the story is just depressing. I felt uncomfortable throughout the film, and watching them go through what they did was not rewarding, it got a bit much. Performances. Jeff Bridges is excellent no doubt about that. I felt what he was feeling, and he gives one of his finest performances. The trouble is, I didn't like the movie that was backing him up. Isabella Rossellini is good in her part, but rather an unlikable character in my opinion. Rosie Perez once again annoyed the heavens out of me, with her constant sniveling and shouting. Overrated much? John Turturro is solid in his role while Benicio Del Toro is solid too. Bottom line. Well made, well acted, but a boring experience that riddled me with depression. Worth a look, but that's about it. Maybe you'll get more out of it then I did. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Criminally underrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Elford
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A CRIMINALLY unknown film, especially in the UK, where it is close to impossible to get hold of, this Peter Weir outing, with Jeff Bridges taking the lead, also boasts star turns from John Turturro, Isabella Rossalini, and Rosie Perez, the latter of whom received an Oscar nomination. Everybody is on top form in this perfectly executed, beautiful meditation on what it is to be a human being. To explain all the subtext of "Fearless", all the symbolism, the various layers of allegory, would be an essay in itself; safe to say this is a film that sends you away reeling, thinking and talking about life for a long time. It sounds melodramatic, but when you see it, it makes perfect, serious sense. I understand it received standing ovations when it premiered, and rightly so! Many have said in the past, and I'll say it as well, that the final 10 minutes of this film is pretty much the most powerful cinema I've seen. Jeff Bridges nails it, and I find myself inexplicably in tears each time. Trying to explain it is tough; it speaks to something fundamental in you, and is truly life-affirming, if you choose to listen. A film that proves cinema, when image, performance, music and meaning are meshed perfectly, is sometimes able to convey what nothing else can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superior film of spiritual wonder.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bones Eijnar (namriggs@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching FEARLESS I clearly made up my mind about actor Jeff Bridges; he is utterly brilliant. This film is carried by his performance as a man who survives a plane crash and his the following life he lives in which his complete sense of existence is changed. The film finds mystery and tragedy and goes searching in religious places for answers that we draw out of the main character. Director Peter Weir lingers on Bridges and his inner self, and the many tender scenes that he goes through are very carefully achieved, never slipping into sentiment or boring clich&eacute;s. Throughout you really don't know whether Bridges is crazy, spiritual, dead or alive - he's yearning in something that everybody around him really don't see to understand. FEARLESS is a great film with many low-key scenes that tells a story thoroughly and thoughtfully, but it always escalates into joyous wonder, and that's where director Weir and Bridges truly captured me as a viewer. It's like that dark corridor towards the light in the magnificent ending scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Top-Notch Acting, Average Film...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Peter Weir has always been a filmmaker to admire. 'The Truman Show' is a legendary film, my all-time favorite film. 'Fearless', which released way back in 1993, sadly ranks amongst his weak efforts. However, this does become 'A Must Watch' film due to the strong performances by it's lead cast. Academy-Award-Winner Jeff Bridges stars as a man's who's personality is dramatically changed after surviving a major airline crash. The aftermath of the character and his connections with the world... is what 'Fearless' is all about. 'Fearless' begins wonderfully, but 40-minutes into the film, it loses the pace. Even the culmination leaves a lot to be desired. Weir's direction is satisfactory, but the Screenplay has loose-ends. The Cinematography is good. As mentioned, 'Fearless' is packed with strong performances. Jeff Bridges plays a highly difficult role with brilliance. This truly is one of his best performances to date. Rosie Perez is outstanding in a role that, again, is very Hard to play and execute. Isabella Rossellini is marvelous. Tom Hulce is hugely effective. Benicio del Toro leaves a mark, he's superb. On the whole, Not A Gem, but surely deserves a watch for the Performances, that leave you stunned!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    PTSD Like No Other.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It helps to realize that this was directed by the Australian Peter Weir, many of whose films have oozed an ill-defined enigmatic quality. I remember the first of his movies I saw, "The Last Wave," in Palo Alto, when it was released. I'd never seen anything quite like it. And then, shortly afterward, "Picnic at Hanging Rock", which left me hanging at a much more tentative angle than the rock. Not all of his movie have been so mysterious, so bounced around, but "Fearless" is. Like "The Last Wave" it has a fuzzy supernatural element. Jeff Bridges and a few other passengers, Rosie Perez among them, survive a horrible fiery airplane crash in California. Bridges and Perez can't get their lives together afterward. Perez, having lost her baby in the accident, blames herself and is depressed almost beyond speech. Bridges, on the other hand, feels he is now indestructible and is, furthermore, some kind of supernatural agent left on earth to help Perez recover. His near-death experience has restructured his life. He feels he is invincible. He goes to lengths that anyone would describe as extreme in order to prove it. Bridges is always good. He always brings something extra to the role, although at times he overreaches. Rosie Perez isn't the Puerto Rican spitfire she usually is. She's subdued (for her) and effective in the character of a woman who has to realize that her baby's death was not her responsibility. Some comic moments are added by Tom Hulce as a bespectacled nervous wreck of a lawyer who sincerely wants to be sympathetic and get rich doing it. ("I know, I know, I'm a bad guy because I'm trying to get money. Don't bother saying it!") Isabella Rossellini is the increasingly distraught wife who can't understand why her husband is growing more distant, more ethereal, and appears to be falling in love with the woman he's trying to help. It isn't one of Weir's most provocative movies but once you get into it the narrative sweeps you up, partly because you can't help wondering where the hell it's all headed. The climax seems mundane after all that portent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A profound meditation on death, guilt, fear ... and ultimately, life ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fearless" awakened one of the most bizarre thoughts that ever crossed my mind: envy toward people who lived near death experiences, for the certitude that these people would never be the same again, and when you try to be someone else, any option is worth considering. "Fearless" takes place during the aftermath of a plane crash that presumably killed most passengers and left a few survivors in a state of shock. Are they privileged? Maybe from our perspective, but most of them would endure the trauma of having witnessed the death of a friend, a parent or even the seat neighbor. Most of them would endure the survivor's guilt. Not to mention the traumatic landing and the subsequent lottery of death. Peter Weir's movie, based on a novel by Rafael Iglesias, explores the complexities of the human soul from the different ways it reacts to a life-changing experience. The most intriguing case is Max Klein, an architect and family man, played by Jeff Bridges. Around him, it's chaos, mayhem, panic, cries and cadavers yet he walks like along the site, floating on a cloud of extraordinary serenity. He's not just a survivor, but also a savior, he gave a baby back to his mom, helped a little boy who was flying alone, he showed the safe way to many distraught passengers. Yet, the film doesn't focus on his heroic status, which he himself declines, it is more about the perception of life and death when you have been walking on the thin tightrope that separate the two worlds, when you 'saw the tunnel leading to a light'. Speaking of 'light', the narrative is punctuated by a few flashbacks that reveal how normally scared Max was during the flight, while sitting next to his best friend and colleague. It's only after the situation got more critical, that a mysterious heavenly light appeased his thoughts, and filled his heart with the serene confidence he would live. The crash sequence, which is among one of the most realistic, haunting and emotional from any other film, give some interesting insights that are later 'contradicted' by Max. The way he sees it: he's already a ghost, God can't touch him, he shares the little secret with Carla, a Hispanic mother who lost her child and can't recover from the guilt of not having held him tightly in her arms. Max and Carla form two interesting cases. Max survived and believe he's invulnerable, 'fearless' as the title suggest, with an inexorable desire to live life to its fullest, and the consequence is that it affects its relationships with his entourage. He becomes totally estranged to his wife, played by Isabella Rosselini (whose uncanny resemblance with her legendary was almost distracting), he lost the fatherly bond with his son in favor of the one he rescued, he couldn't even find the right words for his friend's widow or cooperate with the lawyer's desperate efforts to obtain a huge indemnity. Max rejects life's normality: money, convention, fear, video games, living with memories, his idea of the perfect life to live is a personal utopia that can only be fulfilled with someone who understands him. And this person is Carla. Played by Rosie Perez, Carla is the emotional core of the film, through the reaction most viewers can relate to, she's not a kind of super-human or angel, she only tried to save her son, but failed. And this failure puts her in a depressive state with suicidal impulses that only her deep Hispanic Catholic faith can alter. Contrarily to Max, Carla is much aware that she's living and that's what makes her life unbearable, for Max, the idea of death is so intolerable that he teases it by eating strawberries, a fruit he's allergic to, crossing the road, or walking on the ledge of a building's roof in the film's most emblematic scene. Fear is connected with self-preservation, but in Max' case, the fearless state doesn't mean he doesn't want to live, but it betrays his sentiment of inner immortality, yet the only way to be immortal is to be actually dead. Max is still between life and death. Either the wish to be dead out of guilt or sensation of being already dead from a weird exhilaration, both Perez and Bridges drive the film through sensitive and sensational performances. The therapist, played by John Turturro, explains to Max' wife that both Max and Carla represent two extremes in terms of reactions and on their interactions can depend chances of recovery. The relationship has a romantic vibe and maybe Max genuinely loves Carla, but "Fearless" never lures us into the idea that Carla would fall in love with him on the simple basis that they had the same experience. Love is not an end but a mean for Max to suppress all the traces of guilt in Carla's mind. Ironically, that's what Max' wife tries to do, helping him to regain his faith in life, and her many attempts to give a helping hand are concluded by 'failure to communicate', leading to what seems to be marital dead-end. But there is a reason Rosie Perez' performance was so acclaimed, she's not just a weepy, mourning mother, there is strength in her heart, and if her recovery can put and end to the mystical bond she had with Max, it leaves at least some room for the woman who really loves him. The conclusion of "Fearless", perhaps one of the most emotionally satisfying ever, is perfect because it does three things: it provides some answers about Max' enigmatic state of mind, it finds the perfect remedy, and it highlights the truth that one of the best things about life is to realize how great it is to live. Those who faced death have more awareness, and maybe this is what I consider their privilege. Do I want it? I'm not sure I'm that  fearless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When Great Character Study gets Interrupted by Hollywood Clich&eacute;s...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fearless is a drama centered around a man, played by Jeff Bridges, who survives a plane crash and can't get out of the state of being dead inside. It's very well acted film with standout performances by Jeff Bridges and Isabella Rossellini and features some brilliant direction by Peter Weir. I really liked the film and only minor annoyances that kept me from loving it. Jeff Bridges once again proves that he is one of the best living American actors out there. He truly sells the fact that he is dead inside and can't awake from the state his in. His performance is what really holds Fearless together and keeps you engaged. Isabella Rossellini and Rosie Perez provide the central supporting performances and they are very good. It's all around strongly acted film and keeps you invested in the characters and the hardships they go through. Peter Weir's direction perfectly compliments the storytelling and acting. His recreation of the plane crash was far more intense and horrifying than that of Flight. It's just a well directed film that's really well shot and gives a feeling that you are watching a real film. The script isn't as solid as the acting and the direction. The central themes and the characters are well explored and gives a good sense about what people go through when they survive terrible accidents. The problems start to pop whenever the film shoves in stupid Hollywood crap like wacky and silly lawyer, stupid subplots about greedy husband and other forced attempts of creating dramatic tension. You have so much going on with the characters already, you don't need some forced crap about things that hardly matter. Fearless is something you don't see often - a Hollywood film that wants to explore characters and leave pretension and self-importance out it. It's a very downbeat film but never depressing. Fearless is a optimistic film with a happy ending so it's a film you can actually enjoy. If you like Jeff Bridges and enjoy real films, you owe it to yourself to see it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Film; Disappointing Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruce Banner
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is an interesting character study of a man dealing with fear and death. I watched it because I'm a big fan of Jeff Bridges work as "The Dude" in The Big Lebowski but I was a bit letdown. Here's why: The movie did not deliver enough entertainment value. Thought provoking it was but entertaining- questionable. Also, the way the movie handled its core issues and themes seemed a little heavy handed to me. The old chestnut about script writing that the dialogue should never be totally "on the nose" was not adhered to, in this case to the film's detriment. I found some of the dialogue to be too direct and not leaving enough room for subtext and for the viewer to feel that there is something bubbling beneath the surface. Its always better for the writer to sketch the character's struggles as metaphors and incidental to the story rather than try to force themes to lead the story and drive its dialogue. Additionally, the Director's use of camera shots was a little slow. The style of, "Look at me, here is another important closeup on some random object for longer than we would like," coupled with the writing served to make the movie a bit melodramatic. Aside from Jeff Bridges who does a solid job in a decent role, Benicio Del Toro was very interesting in his minor role as was John Torturro. You will see a lot of rave reviews for Fearless largely because it has a small cult following who were emotionally impacted by it. As a regular viewer with no special connection to the film, I advise you to take these reviews with a grain of salt. They are biased. This is not a flawless film. It is merely an interesting one with a couple good actors. Definitely Not a must see. I also wasn't crazy about Rosie Perez. Her acting was one note, loud and amateurish rather than nuanced and intelligent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nasty movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sam hit
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched it till the end. If you the sort of person who spends a lot of time on thoughts like purpose, death and life DO NOT watch this movie. it's worse than an empty shell. it is false advertising, this movie. It tells about a man's journey after a plane crash that had changed him to someone who does not feel. He feels almost content with anything and joyous with life. there are some illogical plot occurring. It has to do with an allergy. Besides that the main character had little appeal to me. even the gorgeous women did not make up for what a fluke the movie was. I am flabbergasted that certain people felt so full of emotion after this movie but I think those are the shallow sort of people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Buying gifts for the dead....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a terrible air disaster, survivor Max Klein emerges a changed person. Unable to connect to his former life or to wife, he feels godlike and immortal. When psychologist Bill Perlman is unable to help, he has Max meet another survivor, Carla Rodrigo, who is racked with grief and guilt since her baby died in the crash.... This is one of those movies that had massive plaudits when first released, but vanished without a trace, (you can't even get it on DVD here in the UK). And I ask myself why? It's one of the best films no ones heard of in the nineties, and it may even have a career best performance from Bridges and the rest of the cast. It's a difficult subject matter to deal with, people trying to come to terms with loss, whereas one man, is doing everything in his power to prove everyone that something enigmatic, even sublime, happened to him on the plane. The film would be perfect if it had the same power in the third act, like it did in the first two, but sadly, it runs a little out of steam. The scenes on the plane are very intense and genuinely terrifying, but somewhat peaceful thanks to Bridges calming influence. The film is asking lots of questions throughout, but if you go that little much deeper, rather than look at it at face value, it gets a little lost also (there are some scenes, that are indicating that Bridges is really dead, and in purgatory, which can be confusing at times). But all in all, if you ever come across this movie, you must take some time out to see i, it's an amazing movie with an amazing message, it just loses it's way a little in the last 30 mins.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rather boring and depressing in my books. Jeff Bridges was the only saving grace
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Credit IMDb. After a terrible air disaster, survivor Max Klein emerges a changed person. Unable to connect to his former life or to wife Laura, he feels godlike and invulnerable. When psychologist Bill Perlman is unable to help Max, he has Max meet another survivor, Carla Rodrigo, who is racked with grief and guilt since her baby died in the crash which she and Max survived. It starts off with a gripping experience, with a crash sight, but from there it was all downhill for me. The acting is borderline flawless(aside from Perez). But the story is just depressing. I felt uncomfortable throughout the film, and watching them go through what they did was not rewarding, it got a bit much. Performances. Jeff Bridges is excellent no doubt about that. I felt what he was feeling, and he gives one of his finest performances. The trouble is, I didn't like the movie that was backing him up. Isabella Rossellini is good in her part, but rather an unlikable character in my opinion. Rosie Perez once again annoyed the heavens out of me, with her constant sniveling and shouting. Overrated much? John Turturro is solid in his role while Benicio Del Toro is solid too. Bottom line. Well made, well acted, but a boring experience that riddled me with depression. Worth a look, but that's about it. Maybe you'll get more out of it then I did. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Criminally underrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Elford
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A CRIMINALLY unknown film, especially in the UK, where it is close to impossible to get hold of, this Peter Weir outing, with Jeff Bridges taking the lead, also boasts star turns from John Turturro, Isabella Rossalini, and Rosie Perez, the latter of whom received an Oscar nomination. Everybody is on top form in this perfectly executed, beautiful meditation on what it is to be a human being. To explain all the subtext of "Fearless", all the symbolism, the various layers of allegory, would be an essay in itself; safe to say this is a film that sends you away reeling, thinking and talking about life for a long time. It sounds melodramatic, but when you see it, it makes perfect, serious sense. I understand it received standing ovations when it premiered, and rightly so! Many have said in the past, and I'll say it as well, that the final 10 minutes of this film is pretty much the most powerful cinema I've seen. Jeff Bridges nails it, and I find myself inexplicably in tears each time. Trying to explain it is tough; it speaks to something fundamental in you, and is truly life-affirming, if you choose to listen. A film that proves cinema, when image, performance, music and meaning are meshed perfectly, is sometimes able to convey what nothing else can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superior film of spiritual wonder.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bones Eijnar (namriggs@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching FEARLESS I clearly made up my mind about actor Jeff Bridges; he is utterly brilliant. This film is carried by his performance as a man who survives a plane crash and his the following life he lives in which his complete sense of existence is changed. The film finds mystery and tragedy and goes searching in religious places for answers that we draw out of the main character. Director Peter Weir lingers on Bridges and his inner self, and the many tender scenes that he goes through are very carefully achieved, never slipping into sentiment or boring clich&eacute;s. Throughout you really don't know whether Bridges is crazy, spiritual, dead or alive - he's yearning in something that everybody around him really don't see to understand. FEARLESS is a great film with many low-key scenes that tells a story thoroughly and thoughtfully, but it always escalates into joyous wonder, and that's where director Weir and Bridges truly captured me as a viewer. It's like that dark corridor towards the light in the magnificent ending scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Top-Notch Acting, Average Film...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Peter Weir has always been a filmmaker to admire. 'The Truman Show' is a legendary film, my all-time favorite film. 'Fearless', which released way back in 1993, sadly ranks amongst his weak efforts. However, this does become 'A Must Watch' film due to the strong performances by it's lead cast. Academy-Award-Winner Jeff Bridges stars as a man's who's personality is dramatically changed after surviving a major airline crash. The aftermath of the character and his connections with the world... is what 'Fearless' is all about. 'Fearless' begins wonderfully, but 40-minutes into the film, it loses the pace. Even the culmination leaves a lot to be desired. Weir's direction is satisfactory, but the Screenplay has loose-ends. The Cinematography is good. As mentioned, 'Fearless' is packed with strong performances. Jeff Bridges plays a highly difficult role with brilliance. This truly is one of his best performances to date. Rosie Perez is outstanding in a role that, again, is very Hard to play and execute. Isabella Rossellini is marvelous. Tom Hulce is hugely effective. Benicio del Toro leaves a mark, he's superb. On the whole, Not A Gem, but surely deserves a watch for the Performances, that leave you stunned!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    PTSD Like No Other.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It helps to realize that this was directed by the Australian Peter Weir, many of whose films have oozed an ill-defined enigmatic quality. I remember the first of his movies I saw, "The Last Wave," in Palo Alto, when it was released. I'd never seen anything quite like it. And then, shortly afterward, "Picnic at Hanging Rock", which left me hanging at a much more tentative angle than the rock. Not all of his movie have been so mysterious, so bounced around, but "Fearless" is. Like "The Last Wave" it has a fuzzy supernatural element. Jeff Bridges and a few other passengers, Rosie Perez among them, survive a horrible fiery airplane crash in California. Bridges and Perez can't get their lives together afterward. Perez, having lost her baby in the accident, blames herself and is depressed almost beyond speech. Bridges, on the other hand, feels he is now indestructible and is, furthermore, some kind of supernatural agent left on earth to help Perez recover. His near-death experience has restructured his life. He feels he is invincible. He goes to lengths that anyone would describe as extreme in order to prove it. Bridges is always good. He always brings something extra to the role, although at times he overreaches. Rosie Perez isn't the Puerto Rican spitfire she usually is. She's subdued (for her) and effective in the character of a woman who has to realize that her baby's death was not her responsibility. Some comic moments are added by Tom Hulce as a bespectacled nervous wreck of a lawyer who sincerely wants to be sympathetic and get rich doing it. ("I know, I know, I'm a bad guy because I'm trying to get money. Don't bother saying it!") Isabella Rossellini is the increasingly distraught wife who can't understand why her husband is growing more distant, more ethereal, and appears to be falling in love with the woman he's trying to help. It isn't one of Weir's most provocative movies but once you get into it the narrative sweeps you up, partly because you can't help wondering where the hell it's all headed. The climax seems mundane after all that portent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A profound meditation on death, guilt, fear ... and ultimately, life ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fearless" awakened one of the most bizarre thoughts that ever crossed my mind: envy toward people who lived near death experiences, for the certitude that these people would never be the same again, and when you try to be someone else, any option is worth considering. "Fearless" takes place during the aftermath of a plane crash that presumably killed most passengers and left a few survivors in a state of shock. Are they privileged? Maybe from our perspective, but most of them would endure the trauma of having witnessed the death of a friend, a parent or even the seat neighbor. Most of them would endure the survivor's guilt. Not to mention the traumatic landing and the subsequent lottery of death. Peter Weir's movie, based on a novel by Rafael Iglesias, explores the complexities of the human soul from the different ways it reacts to a life-changing experience. The most intriguing case is Max Klein, an architect and family man, played by Jeff Bridges. Around him, it's chaos, mayhem, panic, cries and cadavers yet he walks like along the site, floating on a cloud of extraordinary serenity. He's not just a survivor, but also a savior, he gave a baby back to his mom, helped a little boy who was flying alone, he showed the safe way to many distraught passengers. Yet, the film doesn't focus on his heroic status, which he himself declines, it is more about the perception of life and death when you have been walking on the thin tightrope that separate the two worlds, when you 'saw the tunnel leading to a light'. Speaking of 'light', the narrative is punctuated by a few flashbacks that reveal how normally scared Max was during the flight, while sitting next to his best friend and colleague. It's only after the situation got more critical, that a mysterious heavenly light appeased his thoughts, and filled his heart with the serene confidence he would live. The crash sequence, which is among one of the most realistic, haunting and emotional from any other film, give some interesting insights that are later 'contradicted' by Max. The way he sees it: he's already a ghost, God can't touch him, he shares the little secret with Carla, a Hispanic mother who lost her child and can't recover from the guilt of not having held him tightly in her arms. Max and Carla form two interesting cases. Max survived and believe he's invulnerable, 'fearless' as the title suggest, with an inexorable desire to live life to its fullest, and the consequence is that it affects its relationships with his entourage. He becomes totally estranged to his wife, played by Isabella Rosselini (whose uncanny resemblance with her legendary was almost distracting), he lost the fatherly bond with his son in favor of the one he rescued, he couldn't even find the right words for his friend's widow or cooperate with the lawyer's desperate efforts to obtain a huge indemnity. Max rejects life's normality: money, convention, fear, video games, living with memories, his idea of the perfect life to live is a personal utopia that can only be fulfilled with someone who understands him. And this person is Carla. Played by Rosie Perez, Carla is the emotional core of the film, through the reaction most viewers can relate to, she's not a kind of super-human or angel, she only tried to save her son, but failed. And this failure puts her in a depressive state with suicidal impulses that only her deep Hispanic Catholic faith can alter. Contrarily to Max, Carla is much aware that she's living and that's what makes her life unbearable, for Max, the idea of death is so intolerable that he teases it by eating strawberries, a fruit he's allergic to, crossing the road, or walking on the ledge of a building's roof in the film's most emblematic scene. Fear is connected with self-preservation, but in Max' case, the fearless state doesn't mean he doesn't want to live, but it betrays his sentiment of inner immortality, yet the only way to be immortal is to be actually dead. Max is still between life and death. Either the wish to be dead out of guilt or sensation of being already dead from a weird exhilaration, both Perez and Bridges drive the film through sensitive and sensational performances. The therapist, played by John Turturro, explains to Max' wife that both Max and Carla represent two extremes in terms of reactions and on their interactions can depend chances of recovery. The relationship has a romantic vibe and maybe Max genuinely loves Carla, but "Fearless" never lures us into the idea that Carla would fall in love with him on the simple basis that they had the same experience. Love is not an end but a mean for Max to suppress all the traces of guilt in Carla's mind. Ironically, that's what Max' wife tries to do, helping him to regain his faith in life, and her many attempts to give a helping hand are concluded by 'failure to communicate', leading to what seems to be marital dead-end. But there is a reason Rosie Perez' performance was so acclaimed, she's not just a weepy, mourning mother, there is strength in her heart, and if her recovery can put and end to the mystical bond she had with Max, it leaves at least some room for the woman who really loves him. The conclusion of "Fearless", perhaps one of the most emotionally satisfying ever, is perfect because it does three things: it provides some answers about Max' enigmatic state of mind, it finds the perfect remedy, and it highlights the truth that one of the best things about life is to realize how great it is to live. Those who faced death have more awareness, and maybe this is what I consider their privilege. Do I want it? I'm not sure I'm that  fearless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When Great Character Study gets Interrupted by Hollywood Clich&eacute;s...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fearless is a drama centered around a man, played by Jeff Bridges, who survives a plane crash and can't get out of the state of being dead inside. It's very well acted film with standout performances by Jeff Bridges and Isabella Rossellini and features some brilliant direction by Peter Weir. I really liked the film and only minor annoyances that kept me from loving it. Jeff Bridges once again proves that he is one of the best living American actors out there. He truly sells the fact that he is dead inside and can't awake from the state his in. His performance is what really holds Fearless together and keeps you engaged. Isabella Rossellini and Rosie Perez provide the central supporting performances and they are very good. It's all around strongly acted film and keeps you invested in the characters and the hardships they go through. Peter Weir's direction perfectly compliments the storytelling and acting. His recreation of the plane crash was far more intense and horrifying than that of Flight. It's just a well directed film that's really well shot and gives a feeling that you are watching a real film. The script isn't as solid as the acting and the direction. The central themes and the characters are well explored and gives a good sense about what people go through when they survive terrible accidents. The problems start to pop whenever the film shoves in stupid Hollywood crap like wacky and silly lawyer, stupid subplots about greedy husband and other forced attempts of creating dramatic tension. You have so much going on with the characters already, you don't need some forced crap about things that hardly matter. Fearless is something you don't see often - a Hollywood film that wants to explore characters and leave pretension and self-importance out it. It's a very downbeat film but never depressing. Fearless is a optimistic film with a happy ending so it's a film you can actually enjoy. If you like Jeff Bridges and enjoy real films, you owe it to yourself to see it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Film; Disappointing Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruce Banner
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is an interesting character study of a man dealing with fear and death. I watched it because I'm a big fan of Jeff Bridges work as "The Dude" in The Big Lebowski but I was a bit letdown. Here's why: The movie did not deliver enough entertainment value. Thought provoking it was but entertaining- questionable. Also, the way the movie handled its core issues and themes seemed a little heavy handed to me. The old chestnut about script writing that the dialogue should never be totally "on the nose" was not adhered to, in this case to the film's detriment. I found some of the dialogue to be too direct and not leaving enough room for subtext and for the viewer to feel that there is something bubbling beneath the surface. Its always better for the writer to sketch the character's struggles as metaphors and incidental to the story rather than try to force themes to lead the story and drive its dialogue. Additionally, the Director's use of camera shots was a little slow. The style of, "Look at me, here is another important closeup on some random object for longer than we would like," coupled with the writing served to make the movie a bit melodramatic. Aside from Jeff Bridges who does a solid job in a decent role, Benicio Del Toro was very interesting in his minor role as was John Torturro. You will see a lot of rave reviews for Fearless largely because it has a small cult following who were emotionally impacted by it. As a regular viewer with no special connection to the film, I advise you to take these reviews with a grain of salt. They are biased. This is not a flawless film. It is merely an interesting one with a couple good actors. Definitely Not a must see. I also wasn't crazy about Rosie Perez. Her acting was one note, loud and amateurish rather than nuanced and intelligent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nasty movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sam hit
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched it till the end. If you the sort of person who spends a lot of time on thoughts like purpose, death and life DO NOT watch this movie. it's worse than an empty shell. it is false advertising, this movie. It tells about a man's journey after a plane crash that had changed him to someone who does not feel. He feels almost content with anything and joyous with life. there are some illogical plot occurring. It has to do with an allergy. Besides that the main character had little appeal to me. even the gorgeous women did not make up for what a fluke the movie was. I am flabbergasted that certain people felt so full of emotion after this movie but I think those are the shallow sort of people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Buying gifts for the dead....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a terrible air disaster, survivor Max Klein emerges a changed person. Unable to connect to his former life or to wife, he feels godlike and immortal. When psychologist Bill Perlman is unable to help, he has Max meet another survivor, Carla Rodrigo, who is racked with grief and guilt since her baby died in the crash.... This is one of those movies that had massive plaudits when first released, but vanished without a trace, (you can't even get it on DVD here in the UK). And I ask myself why? It's one of the best films no ones heard of in the nineties, and it may even have a career best performance from Bridges and the rest of the cast. It's a difficult subject matter to deal with, people trying to come to terms with loss, whereas one man, is doing everything in his power to prove everyone that something enigmatic, even sublime, happened to him on the plane. The film would be perfect if it had the same power in the third act, like it did in the first two, but sadly, it runs a little out of steam. The scenes on the plane are very intense and genuinely terrifying, but somewhat peaceful thanks to Bridges calming influence. The film is asking lots of questions throughout, but if you go that little much deeper, rather than look at it at face value, it gets a little lost also (there are some scenes, that are indicating that Bridges is really dead, and in purgatory, which can be confusing at times). But all in all, if you ever come across this movie, you must take some time out to see i, it's an amazing movie with an amazing message, it just loses it's way a little in the last 30 mins.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rather boring and depressing in my books. Jeff Bridges was the only saving grace
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Credit IMDb. After a terrible air disaster, survivor Max Klein emerges a changed person. Unable to connect to his former life or to wife Laura, he feels godlike and invulnerable. When psychologist Bill Perlman is unable to help Max, he has Max meet another survivor, Carla Rodrigo, who is racked with grief and guilt since her baby died in the crash which she and Max survived. It starts off with a gripping experience, with a crash sight, but from there it was all downhill for me. The acting is borderline flawless(aside from Perez). But the story is just depressing. I felt uncomfortable throughout the film, and watching them go through what they did was not rewarding, it got a bit much. Performances. Jeff Bridges is excellent no doubt about that. I felt what he was feeling, and he gives one of his finest performances. The trouble is, I didn't like the movie that was backing him up. Isabella Rossellini is good in her part, but rather an unlikable character in my opinion. Rosie Perez once again annoyed the heavens out of me, with her constant sniveling and shouting. Overrated much? John Turturro is solid in his role while Benicio Del Toro is solid too. Bottom line. Well made, well acted, but a boring experience that riddled me with depression. Worth a look, but that's about it. Maybe you'll get more out of it then I did. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Criminally underrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Elford
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A CRIMINALLY unknown film, especially in the UK, where it is close to impossible to get hold of, this Peter Weir outing, with Jeff Bridges taking the lead, also boasts star turns from John Turturro, Isabella Rossalini, and Rosie Perez, the latter of whom received an Oscar nomination. Everybody is on top form in this perfectly executed, beautiful meditation on what it is to be a human being. To explain all the subtext of "Fearless", all the symbolism, the various layers of allegory, would be an essay in itself; safe to say this is a film that sends you away reeling, thinking and talking about life for a long time. It sounds melodramatic, but when you see it, it makes perfect, serious sense. I understand it received standing ovations when it premiered, and rightly so! Many have said in the past, and I'll say it as well, that the final 10 minutes of this film is pretty much the most powerful cinema I've seen. Jeff Bridges nails it, and I find myself inexplicably in tears each time. Trying to explain it is tough; it speaks to something fundamental in you, and is truly life-affirming, if you choose to listen. A film that proves cinema, when image, performance, music and meaning are meshed perfectly, is sometimes able to convey what nothing else can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superior film of spiritual wonder.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bones Eijnar (namriggs@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching FEARLESS I clearly made up my mind about actor Jeff Bridges; he is utterly brilliant. This film is carried by his performance as a man who survives a plane crash and his the following life he lives in which his complete sense of existence is changed. The film finds mystery and tragedy and goes searching in religious places for answers that we draw out of the main character. Director Peter Weir lingers on Bridges and his inner self, and the many tender scenes that he goes through are very carefully achieved, never slipping into sentiment or boring clich&eacute;s. Throughout you really don't know whether Bridges is crazy, spiritual, dead or alive - he's yearning in something that everybody around him really don't see to understand. FEARLESS is a great film with many low-key scenes that tells a story thoroughly and thoughtfully, but it always escalates into joyous wonder, and that's where director Weir and Bridges truly captured me as a viewer. It's like that dark corridor towards the light in the magnificent ending scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Top-Notch Acting, Average Film...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Peter Weir has always been a filmmaker to admire. 'The Truman Show' is a legendary film, my all-time favorite film. 'Fearless', which released way back in 1993, sadly ranks amongst his weak efforts. However, this does become 'A Must Watch' film due to the strong performances by it's lead cast. Academy-Award-Winner Jeff Bridges stars as a man's who's personality is dramatically changed after surviving a major airline crash. The aftermath of the character and his connections with the world... is what 'Fearless' is all about. 'Fearless' begins wonderfully, but 40-minutes into the film, it loses the pace. Even the culmination leaves a lot to be desired. Weir's direction is satisfactory, but the Screenplay has loose-ends. The Cinematography is good. As mentioned, 'Fearless' is packed with strong performances. Jeff Bridges plays a highly difficult role with brilliance. This truly is one of his best performances to date. Rosie Perez is outstanding in a role that, again, is very Hard to play and execute. Isabella Rossellini is marvelous. Tom Hulce is hugely effective. Benicio del Toro leaves a mark, he's superb. On the whole, Not A Gem, but surely deserves a watch for the Performances, that leave you stunned!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
