<filme>
 <id>
  105
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0117608
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Bilko - O Sargento Trapalh&atilde;o
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  This movie is a remake of the hit series which starred, Phil Silvers as Sgt. Bilko. In this movie, Bilko runs the motor pool and has all sorts of scams going on like gambling, renting out ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  This movie is a remake of the hit series which starred, Phil Silvers as Sgt. Bilko. In this movie, Bilko runs the motor pool and has all sorts of scams going on like gambling, renting out military vehicles, and so on, which are all violations. However, his commanding officer, Colonel Hall overlooks them, cause he is more concerned about his future, cause a lot of bases are being closed, and the inspector, Major Thorn was on the verge of doing that. But when he heard that Bilko was on the base, he turned into a mad dog. It seems that Thorn was a "thorn" in Bilko's side many years ago but through a series of misunderstandings, Thorn was accused of carrying out or being the brains behind one of Bilko's schemes, he would be sent to Greenland and his career has not gone as he hoped it would and now wants revenge on Bilko.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   greenland
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   military
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   revenge
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   soldier
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   las vegas nevada
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Jonathan Lynn
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Nat Hiken
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Andy Breckman
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Steve Martin
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Dan Aykroyd
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Phil Hartman
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A VERY good film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mightyzebra
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have watched a few films with Steve Martin and really enjoyed them all, but this is, so far, my definite favourite. I have not watched the original series of "Sgt. Bilko", but I picked up the idea of this film pretty quickly and I enjoyed almost every minute. The humour is very crazy, similar to cartoon humour, but at the same time it is often very intelligent. I felt many "YES!" moments in this film, lines or scenes where the hilarity, words and or slapstick were just about PERFECT. Not only were the lines and funny scenes mostly very well-written and done, but the characters were memorable and (mostly) relatable and the plot itself was engaging enough, though sometimes a little too farcical. I recommend this film to people who love "mad," but clever humour, people who like Steve Martin and already have an idea of his acting style and to people who like to see a "unique" portrayal of what goes on in the US army (not that it's realistic of course...). Enjoy "Sgt. Bilko"! :-)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Steve Martin At His Best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steve Martin is At His Best in 'Sgt. Bilko'. He delivers a hilarious & lovable performance, that easily is among his finest. And even as a film, 'Sgt. Bilko' is great fun! 'Sgt. Bilko' Synopsis: Bilko runs the motor pool and has all sorts of scams going on like gambling, renting out military vehicles, and so on, which are all violations. 'Sgt. Bilko', an adaptation of the 1950s television series, turns out to be one great cinematic experience. The film is full of comedic moments, that definitely will you in splits. Nat Hiken & Andy Breckman's Screenplay is genuinely funny & very entertaining. Jonathan Lynn's Direction, is perfect. Cinematography, Editing & Art Design, are mention-worthy. Performance-Wise: Martin is the life of the show. He stands out from scene A to Z. Dan Aykroyd is first-rate. Phil Hartman is excellent as the bad-guy. Glenne Headly is wonderfully relaxed. Chris Rock, John Marshall Jones & Pamela Adlon are quite good. Others lend good support. On the whole, 'Sgt. Bilko' is great fun! A Must See for Martin Fanatics!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    After Bathing at Baxter's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A movie starring Steve Martin, Dan Aykroyd and Phil Hartman based on the classic situation comedy has to be hilarious, right? No cigar and not even close. Phil Silvers put a lot of "Phil Silvers" into his "Ernie Bilko" and Mr. Martin wisely substitutes "Steve Martin" manners for his interpretation. This is a smart move on Martin's part, as the two comedians possess a completely different type of energy. However, Martin does not work well with this material, in this situation. Consequently, it falls apart... While certainly no guarantee, it might have been better to star Mr. Hartman attempting a Silvers impersonation. It's relatively interesting to see Cathy Silvers (as Monday) and Chris Rock (as Oster) appear as a genuinely funny team of lieutenants (last saw Ms. Silvers at "Greenblatt's" deli in the 1990s, and she was a delight). Imagine Entertainment's "Bilko" adds likable Daryl Mitchell (as Walter "Wally" Holbrook), but does little with him. The jokes about Fort Baxter's men failing to bathe do not pass the smell test. *** Sgt. Bilko (3/29/96) Jonathan Lynn ~ Steve Martin, Dan Aykroyd, Phil Hartman, Daryl Mitchell
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "What's that music?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ackstasis
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last night, I watched 'Sgt. Bilko (1996)' for the first time in a few years, and was surprised at the number of quotes that have crept their way into my everyday conversation. Just yesterday at the gym, for example, I declared to a struggling friend: "one, we're going for one!"). Directed by Jonathan Lynn, co-creator of the British sitcom "Yes Minister" and its sequel, 'Sgt. Bilko' is a tightly-scripted classic, one of my favourite 90s comedies. The film is a screen adaptation of "The Phil Silvers Show," which ran from 1955 to 1959. I haven't seen the series, so I have no point of comparison, but I would certainly like to at some point. Master Sergeant Ernest G. Bilko (Steve Martin) commands the motor pool at Fort Baxter, but his involvement with the army is in name only. Whenever his bewildered commander (Dan Ackroyd) is looking the other way, Bilko dedicates his not-inconsiderable energies towards gambling and other worthwhile pursuits. He has a girlfriend (Glenne Headly) who is mostly on his wavelength, but who perhaps resents being left at the altar on multiple occasions. When an old nemesis (Phil Hartman) arrives on the base, Bilko finds out that army isn't as leisurely as he'd come to believe. 'Sgt Bilko' moves along at a headlong pace, with Steve Martin cracking one-liners without even drawing a breath ("All I've ever wanted was an honest week's pay for an honest day's work"). Highlights include the most uneventful boxing match in cinematic history ("For three rounds, nobody hit anybody. It was a dance recital"), a surprise inspection of somebody else's barracks ("It is my understanding that you can no longer ask me these questions, sir"), and Bilko's attempt to dissuade his girlfriend from marrying Major Thorn ("Think of the children. You're a Catholic and he's an arsehole, how will you raise them?").
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Steve Martin makes it seem better than it really is.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Realistically, the dubbo's have been the stingiest or most disappointing decade for comedy heroes. I've whinged about this before, but the days of reliable comedy icons monopolising the box office on an annual basis appear over. Consider the 80s and 90s, Eddie Murphy, Steve Martin and Bill Murray, Vs the 00s, Sandler, Ferrell, Stiller, (and I'll throw Carrey in there). Who will history be more kind to? This brings us to Steve Martin, the master of being fake. Fake happy, fake sincere, fake angry, fake remorseful. In Dirty Rotten Scoundrels, LA Story, Little Shop of Horrors, Leap of Faith, My Blue Heaven (underrated) and Bowfinger you always knew Steve was too everything mentioned above, happy, sincere etc but he was always convincing enough in a funny way that set him apart from everyone before or since. I still maintain that Bill Murray and Steve Martin are the two guys I would laugh at regardless of what they were doing, if they were trying to be funny or not. So why have I wasted words telling you what you probably already know? Because if you don't already like Steve Martin there is a 99% chance that you will find Sgt Bilko very underwhelming, as he makes the film his own. Steve is Bilko, a corrupt, conniving, deceitful and untrustworthy soldier in command of the motor pool an the army base Fort Baxter, but he is all those things in the most PG friendly Disney way. I would waste a lot of time describing his mannerisms and what would ordinarily be inane chit chat between he and the officers hell bent on bringing him down, as it is generally not what he says or even how he says it to a point. It is just that he is Steve while he is doing and saying these things, which should be obvious. I just can't imagine Ferrell being Bilko without hamming and getting near naked or Sandler without yelling and trying all the while to be endearing (there is NO-ONE in comedy that wants to be liked more than Sandler, regardless of who he is playing). This leaves Stiller as the logical next up, but I just don't think he has the personality to pull it off. Consider this: Stiller's two best roles, a vain, clueless moron model in Zoolander and a vain, clueless moron actor in Tropic Thunder. Coincidence? Back to Sgt Bilko, you'll have to take my word for this, Sgt Bilko is a paint by numbers Disney comedy that should be pointless. It has cookie cutter characters and situations but again if you like Steve Martin you should get more than a couple of chuckles. Put it this way, about 5 minutes in Bilko asks a superior officer "Have you lost weight?", if that doesn't turn the corners of your mouth up switch off the DVD because that is about as funny as Sgt Bilko gets, and even that is only funny because of Martin's delivery. For some reason that made me laugh, and I laughed often enough to want to see this again in the future at some point. Final Rating  6.5 / 10. Shouldn't work but the presence of Steve Martin adds value to any film and he does enough here to warrant a rental. If you liked this (or even if you didn't) check out oneguyrambling.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dismissed, and it's being considered for a court martial
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now, to be fair, I haven't watched a moment of the original show. I know nothing about the Sergeant. With that said, I can't imagine that this does justice to him. You see, if he was always this unfunny, I cannot imagine that he would be popular. I mean, none of the characters garner a single laugh(they aren't even entirely consistent; early in this, from one scene to the next, one of the leads behave in a manner that directly contradicts everything we've learned about him up to that point), and they are all one-note cardboard cut-outs, but you'd at least expect the dude they titled this after to be worth watching(yes, he is pretty smooth with the ladies, however, that's all; he's not charming). The plot is completely predictable. Gags and jokes are uninspired. OK, we get it, they are undisciplined, fine... if we laugh at it, will you move on? Martin and Aykroyd are hilarious... elsewhere. Tanks aren't that effective in combat anymore; they're slow, useless against the air and too easy to disable. The concept of a type that can hover is a worn-out sci-fi idea. This isn't devoid of positives... Phil Hartman is one, and the other is the great music. I don't know, I suppose this is what you get for hiring the director of Greedy and The Whole Nine Yards. Then again, I do still intend to catch Clue. There is a little moderate to strong language in this. I recommend this to... I don't know, people who like these flicks. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know what's weird? My mom was the biggest Steve Martin fan you would ever meet, she had(what I thought) all of his movies and watched every biography on him. So since she had a lot of his movies, I watched most of them with her. But my boyfriend kept telling me about a film called St. Bilko and how hilarious it was. I was stumped, I couldn't find it in my mom's collection nor did I ever hear of it. So my boyfriend and I went shopping and he found it on DVD, so we went home and watched it. This film just took me back to the classic comedies I grew up with like Trading Places, The Great Outdoors and Planes, Trains and Automobiles. Steve Martin is always a great comedic actor who is a pleasure to watch, same with Dan Aykroyd. While this movie doesn't stand out as well as their other films, this was still a lot of fun to watch. Master Sergeant Ernest G. Bilko is in charge of the motor pool at Fort Baxter, a small US Army base. Exploiting this position, he directs a number of scams ranging from gambling to renting out military vehicles. His commanding officer, Colonel Hall, overlooks Bilko's money making schemes, as he is more concerned with his own affairs. Bad news begins when inspector Major Thorn, Bilko's rival, arrives at the camp and begins to cast scrutiny on Bilko's record. The motivation for Thorn's actions is due to the intense rivalry between the two due to several mishaps in the past, particularly because Thorn's career was ruined due to one of Bilko's scams. Thorn's revenge ensues and ultimately it becomes a battle of wits between the two men. Thorn's reliance on sabotage ultimately leads to his downfall and he is sent to Greenland. Also Bilko's fianc&eacute;e, Rita, whom Bilko has stood up several times at the altar. Bilko is given an ultimatum to win her back within 30 days or to lose her forever. I have to say that I did enjoy St. Bilko, it was great seeing this army crew just goof off and enjoying boot camp. I think my favorite scene was when Bilko has to prove that his crew are hard workers and could complete the obstacle course that the other army recruits could do. Just their reactions of course being as if they've never exercised before in their lives was a good laugh. Steve Martin and his fianc&eacute;e constantly taking a trip up and down the aisle was fun too. Plus this has one of my favorite comedic actors, Phil Hartman, who is again a great watch is always guaranteed to give you a good laugh. While the film may not stand out, this was definitely worth the watch. I would recommend it if you need a good laugh, you're always in good company with Steve Martin, Dan Aykroyd and Phil Hartman, not to mention a baby Chris Rock. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlushingCaps
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I missed this when it came out, and just caught it after one of those free weekends for premium channels. As a long-time fan of Phil Silvers' fabulous series of the 1950s, I was skeptical about this movie, although I usually like Steve Martin's films--especially Planes, Trains, and Automobiles. I thought it was quite true to the spirit of the TV show. I was pleased that it was PG and not full of foul language and other things not fit for children. They didn't try to duplicate everything in the original, merely to present a similar group of characters, with the same names. The plot was not unlike one in the series, but was not a remake of any episode from the series. They had some lines that sounded like they could have come from the series. They had a way to signal "brass coming" so Bilko's men could quickly put away all their gambling devices and make the motor pool look like one--just as the series did, only more elaborate. Col. Hall in the film, just like on TV, acknowledged that Bilko knew more about what was going on, and, in effect, ran the post. Other reviewers have detailed the plot. One highlight for me was the clever way Bilko arranged for his adversary to give himself away after ruining the test of the hover tank, not knowing the machine was not going to work in the first place. That was thinking like the Phil Silvers' version would have done. I agree that Silvers, and Nat Hiken, would be proud that their series was re-created as a feature film 40 years later. It wasn't the funniest movie ever, but it was surely no worse than a "very funny" film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny movie for people who possess a sense of humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (imdb@michaelbauers.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Seems to me like most of the negative votes come from fans of the original show. I am glad I never saw it, because I think this is one of the funniest movies I have ever seen. I love Bilko's character. Martin plays a charismatic, scheming yet kind hearted con artist. I love his comic timing in this movie. It's definitely my favorite Steve Martin role. I think part of the reason I like Martin, is for the same reason I like characters like Bugs Bunny. He always comes out on top, and is usually in complete control of a situation. I love that type of role - who does not want to be more like a Sgt Bilko? I thought almost every scene was funny. I liked pretty much every actor in it. It's not for serious people. I sometimes wonder why serious people bother to rate comedies at all - some people were born with no sense of humor, from what I can tell. For those people who dislike (or are bored of) put down humor, sex humor, or gross out humor, this is none of those (Not that I don't mind some of that, but a change of pace is always welcome.) It's a politer, lighter, silly humor almost cartoonish, in a good way. I have seen this movie at least three times, and still laugh at it. So if you are not a fan of the TV show, I think you will like this in spite of the shockingly low review of this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sergeant Bilko
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    crichton_ius
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK I'm not an American, but in my humble Scottish opinion Steve Martin is not, never has been, and never will be a funny man as long as our posteriors point in a southerly direction. Phil Silvers as Sergeant Bilko was a funny man, no doubt due to the skilled writers and directors and all the other talented team working characters in the series who contributed perfectly to one of the funniest and dateless situation comedies America has ever produced. How anyone could have the audacity to even attempt to replicate the Phil Silvers character is beyond me. To compound things the exercise was repeated in Martin's unfunny attempt to be Peter Seller's Inspector Clouseau, another abortive attempt, in my opinion, to rekindle a demonstrably unfunny career. Some of your contributers say 'Steve Martin puts his own stamp on the character', to that I would say 'balderdash' , his portrayals will be long forgotten when those of Silvers and Sellars will be treasured for generations to come
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A VERY good film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mightyzebra
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have watched a few films with Steve Martin and really enjoyed them all, but this is, so far, my definite favourite. I have not watched the original series of "Sgt. Bilko", but I picked up the idea of this film pretty quickly and I enjoyed almost every minute. The humour is very crazy, similar to cartoon humour, but at the same time it is often very intelligent. I felt many "YES!" moments in this film, lines or scenes where the hilarity, words and or slapstick were just about PERFECT. Not only were the lines and funny scenes mostly very well-written and done, but the characters were memorable and (mostly) relatable and the plot itself was engaging enough, though sometimes a little too farcical. I recommend this film to people who love "mad," but clever humour, people who like Steve Martin and already have an idea of his acting style and to people who like to see a "unique" portrayal of what goes on in the US army (not that it's realistic of course...). Enjoy "Sgt. Bilko"! :-)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Steve Martin At His Best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steve Martin is At His Best in 'Sgt. Bilko'. He delivers a hilarious & lovable performance, that easily is among his finest. And even as a film, 'Sgt. Bilko' is great fun! 'Sgt. Bilko' Synopsis: Bilko runs the motor pool and has all sorts of scams going on like gambling, renting out military vehicles, and so on, which are all violations. 'Sgt. Bilko', an adaptation of the 1950s television series, turns out to be one great cinematic experience. The film is full of comedic moments, that definitely will you in splits. Nat Hiken & Andy Breckman's Screenplay is genuinely funny & very entertaining. Jonathan Lynn's Direction, is perfect. Cinematography, Editing & Art Design, are mention-worthy. Performance-Wise: Martin is the life of the show. He stands out from scene A to Z. Dan Aykroyd is first-rate. Phil Hartman is excellent as the bad-guy. Glenne Headly is wonderfully relaxed. Chris Rock, John Marshall Jones & Pamela Adlon are quite good. Others lend good support. On the whole, 'Sgt. Bilko' is great fun! A Must See for Martin Fanatics!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    After Bathing at Baxter's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A movie starring Steve Martin, Dan Aykroyd and Phil Hartman based on the classic situation comedy has to be hilarious, right? No cigar and not even close. Phil Silvers put a lot of "Phil Silvers" into his "Ernie Bilko" and Mr. Martin wisely substitutes "Steve Martin" manners for his interpretation. This is a smart move on Martin's part, as the two comedians possess a completely different type of energy. However, Martin does not work well with this material, in this situation. Consequently, it falls apart... While certainly no guarantee, it might have been better to star Mr. Hartman attempting a Silvers impersonation. It's relatively interesting to see Cathy Silvers (as Monday) and Chris Rock (as Oster) appear as a genuinely funny team of lieutenants (last saw Ms. Silvers at "Greenblatt's" deli in the 1990s, and she was a delight). Imagine Entertainment's "Bilko" adds likable Daryl Mitchell (as Walter "Wally" Holbrook), but does little with him. The jokes about Fort Baxter's men failing to bathe do not pass the smell test. *** Sgt. Bilko (3/29/96) Jonathan Lynn ~ Steve Martin, Dan Aykroyd, Phil Hartman, Daryl Mitchell
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "What's that music?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ackstasis
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last night, I watched 'Sgt. Bilko (1996)' for the first time in a few years, and was surprised at the number of quotes that have crept their way into my everyday conversation. Just yesterday at the gym, for example, I declared to a struggling friend: "one, we're going for one!"). Directed by Jonathan Lynn, co-creator of the British sitcom "Yes Minister" and its sequel, 'Sgt. Bilko' is a tightly-scripted classic, one of my favourite 90s comedies. The film is a screen adaptation of "The Phil Silvers Show," which ran from 1955 to 1959. I haven't seen the series, so I have no point of comparison, but I would certainly like to at some point. Master Sergeant Ernest G. Bilko (Steve Martin) commands the motor pool at Fort Baxter, but his involvement with the army is in name only. Whenever his bewildered commander (Dan Ackroyd) is looking the other way, Bilko dedicates his not-inconsiderable energies towards gambling and other worthwhile pursuits. He has a girlfriend (Glenne Headly) who is mostly on his wavelength, but who perhaps resents being left at the altar on multiple occasions. When an old nemesis (Phil Hartman) arrives on the base, Bilko finds out that army isn't as leisurely as he'd come to believe. 'Sgt Bilko' moves along at a headlong pace, with Steve Martin cracking one-liners without even drawing a breath ("All I've ever wanted was an honest week's pay for an honest day's work"). Highlights include the most uneventful boxing match in cinematic history ("For three rounds, nobody hit anybody. It was a dance recital"), a surprise inspection of somebody else's barracks ("It is my understanding that you can no longer ask me these questions, sir"), and Bilko's attempt to dissuade his girlfriend from marrying Major Thorn ("Think of the children. You're a Catholic and he's an arsehole, how will you raise them?").
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Steve Martin makes it seem better than it really is.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Realistically, the dubbo's have been the stingiest or most disappointing decade for comedy heroes. I've whinged about this before, but the days of reliable comedy icons monopolising the box office on an annual basis appear over. Consider the 80s and 90s, Eddie Murphy, Steve Martin and Bill Murray, Vs the 00s, Sandler, Ferrell, Stiller, (and I'll throw Carrey in there). Who will history be more kind to? This brings us to Steve Martin, the master of being fake. Fake happy, fake sincere, fake angry, fake remorseful. In Dirty Rotten Scoundrels, LA Story, Little Shop of Horrors, Leap of Faith, My Blue Heaven (underrated) and Bowfinger you always knew Steve was too everything mentioned above, happy, sincere etc but he was always convincing enough in a funny way that set him apart from everyone before or since. I still maintain that Bill Murray and Steve Martin are the two guys I would laugh at regardless of what they were doing, if they were trying to be funny or not. So why have I wasted words telling you what you probably already know? Because if you don't already like Steve Martin there is a 99% chance that you will find Sgt Bilko very underwhelming, as he makes the film his own. Steve is Bilko, a corrupt, conniving, deceitful and untrustworthy soldier in command of the motor pool an the army base Fort Baxter, but he is all those things in the most PG friendly Disney way. I would waste a lot of time describing his mannerisms and what would ordinarily be inane chit chat between he and the officers hell bent on bringing him down, as it is generally not what he says or even how he says it to a point. It is just that he is Steve while he is doing and saying these things, which should be obvious. I just can't imagine Ferrell being Bilko without hamming and getting near naked or Sandler without yelling and trying all the while to be endearing (there is NO-ONE in comedy that wants to be liked more than Sandler, regardless of who he is playing). This leaves Stiller as the logical next up, but I just don't think he has the personality to pull it off. Consider this: Stiller's two best roles, a vain, clueless moron model in Zoolander and a vain, clueless moron actor in Tropic Thunder. Coincidence? Back to Sgt Bilko, you'll have to take my word for this, Sgt Bilko is a paint by numbers Disney comedy that should be pointless. It has cookie cutter characters and situations but again if you like Steve Martin you should get more than a couple of chuckles. Put it this way, about 5 minutes in Bilko asks a superior officer "Have you lost weight?", if that doesn't turn the corners of your mouth up switch off the DVD because that is about as funny as Sgt Bilko gets, and even that is only funny because of Martin's delivery. For some reason that made me laugh, and I laughed often enough to want to see this again in the future at some point. Final Rating  6.5 / 10. Shouldn't work but the presence of Steve Martin adds value to any film and he does enough here to warrant a rental. If you liked this (or even if you didn't) check out oneguyrambling.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dismissed, and it's being considered for a court martial
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now, to be fair, I haven't watched a moment of the original show. I know nothing about the Sergeant. With that said, I can't imagine that this does justice to him. You see, if he was always this unfunny, I cannot imagine that he would be popular. I mean, none of the characters garner a single laugh(they aren't even entirely consistent; early in this, from one scene to the next, one of the leads behave in a manner that directly contradicts everything we've learned about him up to that point), and they are all one-note cardboard cut-outs, but you'd at least expect the dude they titled this after to be worth watching(yes, he is pretty smooth with the ladies, however, that's all; he's not charming). The plot is completely predictable. Gags and jokes are uninspired. OK, we get it, they are undisciplined, fine... if we laugh at it, will you move on? Martin and Aykroyd are hilarious... elsewhere. Tanks aren't that effective in combat anymore; they're slow, useless against the air and too easy to disable. The concept of a type that can hover is a worn-out sci-fi idea. This isn't devoid of positives... Phil Hartman is one, and the other is the great music. I don't know, I suppose this is what you get for hiring the director of Greedy and The Whole Nine Yards. Then again, I do still intend to catch Clue. There is a little moderate to strong language in this. I recommend this to... I don't know, people who like these flicks. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know what's weird? My mom was the biggest Steve Martin fan you would ever meet, she had(what I thought) all of his movies and watched every biography on him. So since she had a lot of his movies, I watched most of them with her. But my boyfriend kept telling me about a film called St. Bilko and how hilarious it was. I was stumped, I couldn't find it in my mom's collection nor did I ever hear of it. So my boyfriend and I went shopping and he found it on DVD, so we went home and watched it. This film just took me back to the classic comedies I grew up with like Trading Places, The Great Outdoors and Planes, Trains and Automobiles. Steve Martin is always a great comedic actor who is a pleasure to watch, same with Dan Aykroyd. While this movie doesn't stand out as well as their other films, this was still a lot of fun to watch. Master Sergeant Ernest G. Bilko is in charge of the motor pool at Fort Baxter, a small US Army base. Exploiting this position, he directs a number of scams ranging from gambling to renting out military vehicles. His commanding officer, Colonel Hall, overlooks Bilko's money making schemes, as he is more concerned with his own affairs. Bad news begins when inspector Major Thorn, Bilko's rival, arrives at the camp and begins to cast scrutiny on Bilko's record. The motivation for Thorn's actions is due to the intense rivalry between the two due to several mishaps in the past, particularly because Thorn's career was ruined due to one of Bilko's scams. Thorn's revenge ensues and ultimately it becomes a battle of wits between the two men. Thorn's reliance on sabotage ultimately leads to his downfall and he is sent to Greenland. Also Bilko's fianc&eacute;e, Rita, whom Bilko has stood up several times at the altar. Bilko is given an ultimatum to win her back within 30 days or to lose her forever. I have to say that I did enjoy St. Bilko, it was great seeing this army crew just goof off and enjoying boot camp. I think my favorite scene was when Bilko has to prove that his crew are hard workers and could complete the obstacle course that the other army recruits could do. Just their reactions of course being as if they've never exercised before in their lives was a good laugh. Steve Martin and his fianc&eacute;e constantly taking a trip up and down the aisle was fun too. Plus this has one of my favorite comedic actors, Phil Hartman, who is again a great watch is always guaranteed to give you a good laugh. While the film may not stand out, this was definitely worth the watch. I would recommend it if you need a good laugh, you're always in good company with Steve Martin, Dan Aykroyd and Phil Hartman, not to mention a baby Chris Rock. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlushingCaps
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I missed this when it came out, and just caught it after one of those free weekends for premium channels. As a long-time fan of Phil Silvers' fabulous series of the 1950s, I was skeptical about this movie, although I usually like Steve Martin's films--especially Planes, Trains, and Automobiles. I thought it was quite true to the spirit of the TV show. I was pleased that it was PG and not full of foul language and other things not fit for children. They didn't try to duplicate everything in the original, merely to present a similar group of characters, with the same names. The plot was not unlike one in the series, but was not a remake of any episode from the series. They had some lines that sounded like they could have come from the series. They had a way to signal "brass coming" so Bilko's men could quickly put away all their gambling devices and make the motor pool look like one--just as the series did, only more elaborate. Col. Hall in the film, just like on TV, acknowledged that Bilko knew more about what was going on, and, in effect, ran the post. Other reviewers have detailed the plot. One highlight for me was the clever way Bilko arranged for his adversary to give himself away after ruining the test of the hover tank, not knowing the machine was not going to work in the first place. That was thinking like the Phil Silvers' version would have done. I agree that Silvers, and Nat Hiken, would be proud that their series was re-created as a feature film 40 years later. It wasn't the funniest movie ever, but it was surely no worse than a "very funny" film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny movie for people who possess a sense of humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (imdb@michaelbauers.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Seems to me like most of the negative votes come from fans of the original show. I am glad I never saw it, because I think this is one of the funniest movies I have ever seen. I love Bilko's character. Martin plays a charismatic, scheming yet kind hearted con artist. I love his comic timing in this movie. It's definitely my favorite Steve Martin role. I think part of the reason I like Martin, is for the same reason I like characters like Bugs Bunny. He always comes out on top, and is usually in complete control of a situation. I love that type of role - who does not want to be more like a Sgt Bilko? I thought almost every scene was funny. I liked pretty much every actor in it. It's not for serious people. I sometimes wonder why serious people bother to rate comedies at all - some people were born with no sense of humor, from what I can tell. For those people who dislike (or are bored of) put down humor, sex humor, or gross out humor, this is none of those (Not that I don't mind some of that, but a change of pace is always welcome.) It's a politer, lighter, silly humor almost cartoonish, in a good way. I have seen this movie at least three times, and still laugh at it. So if you are not a fan of the TV show, I think you will like this in spite of the shockingly low review of this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sergeant Bilko
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    crichton_ius
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK I'm not an American, but in my humble Scottish opinion Steve Martin is not, never has been, and never will be a funny man as long as our posteriors point in a southerly direction. Phil Silvers as Sergeant Bilko was a funny man, no doubt due to the skilled writers and directors and all the other talented team working characters in the series who contributed perfectly to one of the funniest and dateless situation comedies America has ever produced. How anyone could have the audacity to even attempt to replicate the Phil Silvers character is beyond me. To compound things the exercise was repeated in Martin's unfunny attempt to be Peter Seller's Inspector Clouseau, another abortive attempt, in my opinion, to rekindle a demonstrably unfunny career. Some of your contributers say 'Steve Martin puts his own stamp on the character', to that I would say 'balderdash' , his portrayals will be long forgotten when those of Silvers and Sellars will be treasured for generations to come
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A VERY good film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mightyzebra
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have watched a few films with Steve Martin and really enjoyed them all, but this is, so far, my definite favourite. I have not watched the original series of "Sgt. Bilko", but I picked up the idea of this film pretty quickly and I enjoyed almost every minute. The humour is very crazy, similar to cartoon humour, but at the same time it is often very intelligent. I felt many "YES!" moments in this film, lines or scenes where the hilarity, words and or slapstick were just about PERFECT. Not only were the lines and funny scenes mostly very well-written and done, but the characters were memorable and (mostly) relatable and the plot itself was engaging enough, though sometimes a little too farcical. I recommend this film to people who love "mad," but clever humour, people who like Steve Martin and already have an idea of his acting style and to people who like to see a "unique" portrayal of what goes on in the US army (not that it's realistic of course...). Enjoy "Sgt. Bilko"! :-)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Steve Martin At His Best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steve Martin is At His Best in 'Sgt. Bilko'. He delivers a hilarious & lovable performance, that easily is among his finest. And even as a film, 'Sgt. Bilko' is great fun! 'Sgt. Bilko' Synopsis: Bilko runs the motor pool and has all sorts of scams going on like gambling, renting out military vehicles, and so on, which are all violations. 'Sgt. Bilko', an adaptation of the 1950s television series, turns out to be one great cinematic experience. The film is full of comedic moments, that definitely will you in splits. Nat Hiken & Andy Breckman's Screenplay is genuinely funny & very entertaining. Jonathan Lynn's Direction, is perfect. Cinematography, Editing & Art Design, are mention-worthy. Performance-Wise: Martin is the life of the show. He stands out from scene A to Z. Dan Aykroyd is first-rate. Phil Hartman is excellent as the bad-guy. Glenne Headly is wonderfully relaxed. Chris Rock, John Marshall Jones & Pamela Adlon are quite good. Others lend good support. On the whole, 'Sgt. Bilko' is great fun! A Must See for Martin Fanatics!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    After Bathing at Baxter's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A movie starring Steve Martin, Dan Aykroyd and Phil Hartman based on the classic situation comedy has to be hilarious, right? No cigar and not even close. Phil Silvers put a lot of "Phil Silvers" into his "Ernie Bilko" and Mr. Martin wisely substitutes "Steve Martin" manners for his interpretation. This is a smart move on Martin's part, as the two comedians possess a completely different type of energy. However, Martin does not work well with this material, in this situation. Consequently, it falls apart... While certainly no guarantee, it might have been better to star Mr. Hartman attempting a Silvers impersonation. It's relatively interesting to see Cathy Silvers (as Monday) and Chris Rock (as Oster) appear as a genuinely funny team of lieutenants (last saw Ms. Silvers at "Greenblatt's" deli in the 1990s, and she was a delight). Imagine Entertainment's "Bilko" adds likable Daryl Mitchell (as Walter "Wally" Holbrook), but does little with him. The jokes about Fort Baxter's men failing to bathe do not pass the smell test. *** Sgt. Bilko (3/29/96) Jonathan Lynn ~ Steve Martin, Dan Aykroyd, Phil Hartman, Daryl Mitchell
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "What's that music?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ackstasis
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last night, I watched 'Sgt. Bilko (1996)' for the first time in a few years, and was surprised at the number of quotes that have crept their way into my everyday conversation. Just yesterday at the gym, for example, I declared to a struggling friend: "one, we're going for one!"). Directed by Jonathan Lynn, co-creator of the British sitcom "Yes Minister" and its sequel, 'Sgt. Bilko' is a tightly-scripted classic, one of my favourite 90s comedies. The film is a screen adaptation of "The Phil Silvers Show," which ran from 1955 to 1959. I haven't seen the series, so I have no point of comparison, but I would certainly like to at some point. Master Sergeant Ernest G. Bilko (Steve Martin) commands the motor pool at Fort Baxter, but his involvement with the army is in name only. Whenever his bewildered commander (Dan Ackroyd) is looking the other way, Bilko dedicates his not-inconsiderable energies towards gambling and other worthwhile pursuits. He has a girlfriend (Glenne Headly) who is mostly on his wavelength, but who perhaps resents being left at the altar on multiple occasions. When an old nemesis (Phil Hartman) arrives on the base, Bilko finds out that army isn't as leisurely as he'd come to believe. 'Sgt Bilko' moves along at a headlong pace, with Steve Martin cracking one-liners without even drawing a breath ("All I've ever wanted was an honest week's pay for an honest day's work"). Highlights include the most uneventful boxing match in cinematic history ("For three rounds, nobody hit anybody. It was a dance recital"), a surprise inspection of somebody else's barracks ("It is my understanding that you can no longer ask me these questions, sir"), and Bilko's attempt to dissuade his girlfriend from marrying Major Thorn ("Think of the children. You're a Catholic and he's an arsehole, how will you raise them?").
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Steve Martin makes it seem better than it really is.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Realistically, the dubbo's have been the stingiest or most disappointing decade for comedy heroes. I've whinged about this before, but the days of reliable comedy icons monopolising the box office on an annual basis appear over. Consider the 80s and 90s, Eddie Murphy, Steve Martin and Bill Murray, Vs the 00s, Sandler, Ferrell, Stiller, (and I'll throw Carrey in there). Who will history be more kind to? This brings us to Steve Martin, the master of being fake. Fake happy, fake sincere, fake angry, fake remorseful. In Dirty Rotten Scoundrels, LA Story, Little Shop of Horrors, Leap of Faith, My Blue Heaven (underrated) and Bowfinger you always knew Steve was too everything mentioned above, happy, sincere etc but he was always convincing enough in a funny way that set him apart from everyone before or since. I still maintain that Bill Murray and Steve Martin are the two guys I would laugh at regardless of what they were doing, if they were trying to be funny or not. So why have I wasted words telling you what you probably already know? Because if you don't already like Steve Martin there is a 99% chance that you will find Sgt Bilko very underwhelming, as he makes the film his own. Steve is Bilko, a corrupt, conniving, deceitful and untrustworthy soldier in command of the motor pool an the army base Fort Baxter, but he is all those things in the most PG friendly Disney way. I would waste a lot of time describing his mannerisms and what would ordinarily be inane chit chat between he and the officers hell bent on bringing him down, as it is generally not what he says or even how he says it to a point. It is just that he is Steve while he is doing and saying these things, which should be obvious. I just can't imagine Ferrell being Bilko without hamming and getting near naked or Sandler without yelling and trying all the while to be endearing (there is NO-ONE in comedy that wants to be liked more than Sandler, regardless of who he is playing). This leaves Stiller as the logical next up, but I just don't think he has the personality to pull it off. Consider this: Stiller's two best roles, a vain, clueless moron model in Zoolander and a vain, clueless moron actor in Tropic Thunder. Coincidence? Back to Sgt Bilko, you'll have to take my word for this, Sgt Bilko is a paint by numbers Disney comedy that should be pointless. It has cookie cutter characters and situations but again if you like Steve Martin you should get more than a couple of chuckles. Put it this way, about 5 minutes in Bilko asks a superior officer "Have you lost weight?", if that doesn't turn the corners of your mouth up switch off the DVD because that is about as funny as Sgt Bilko gets, and even that is only funny because of Martin's delivery. For some reason that made me laugh, and I laughed often enough to want to see this again in the future at some point. Final Rating  6.5 / 10. Shouldn't work but the presence of Steve Martin adds value to any film and he does enough here to warrant a rental. If you liked this (or even if you didn't) check out oneguyrambling.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dismissed, and it's being considered for a court martial
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now, to be fair, I haven't watched a moment of the original show. I know nothing about the Sergeant. With that said, I can't imagine that this does justice to him. You see, if he was always this unfunny, I cannot imagine that he would be popular. I mean, none of the characters garner a single laugh(they aren't even entirely consistent; early in this, from one scene to the next, one of the leads behave in a manner that directly contradicts everything we've learned about him up to that point), and they are all one-note cardboard cut-outs, but you'd at least expect the dude they titled this after to be worth watching(yes, he is pretty smooth with the ladies, however, that's all; he's not charming). The plot is completely predictable. Gags and jokes are uninspired. OK, we get it, they are undisciplined, fine... if we laugh at it, will you move on? Martin and Aykroyd are hilarious... elsewhere. Tanks aren't that effective in combat anymore; they're slow, useless against the air and too easy to disable. The concept of a type that can hover is a worn-out sci-fi idea. This isn't devoid of positives... Phil Hartman is one, and the other is the great music. I don't know, I suppose this is what you get for hiring the director of Greedy and The Whole Nine Yards. Then again, I do still intend to catch Clue. There is a little moderate to strong language in this. I recommend this to... I don't know, people who like these flicks. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know what's weird? My mom was the biggest Steve Martin fan you would ever meet, she had(what I thought) all of his movies and watched every biography on him. So since she had a lot of his movies, I watched most of them with her. But my boyfriend kept telling me about a film called St. Bilko and how hilarious it was. I was stumped, I couldn't find it in my mom's collection nor did I ever hear of it. So my boyfriend and I went shopping and he found it on DVD, so we went home and watched it. This film just took me back to the classic comedies I grew up with like Trading Places, The Great Outdoors and Planes, Trains and Automobiles. Steve Martin is always a great comedic actor who is a pleasure to watch, same with Dan Aykroyd. While this movie doesn't stand out as well as their other films, this was still a lot of fun to watch. Master Sergeant Ernest G. Bilko is in charge of the motor pool at Fort Baxter, a small US Army base. Exploiting this position, he directs a number of scams ranging from gambling to renting out military vehicles. His commanding officer, Colonel Hall, overlooks Bilko's money making schemes, as he is more concerned with his own affairs. Bad news begins when inspector Major Thorn, Bilko's rival, arrives at the camp and begins to cast scrutiny on Bilko's record. The motivation for Thorn's actions is due to the intense rivalry between the two due to several mishaps in the past, particularly because Thorn's career was ruined due to one of Bilko's scams. Thorn's revenge ensues and ultimately it becomes a battle of wits between the two men. Thorn's reliance on sabotage ultimately leads to his downfall and he is sent to Greenland. Also Bilko's fianc&eacute;e, Rita, whom Bilko has stood up several times at the altar. Bilko is given an ultimatum to win her back within 30 days or to lose her forever. I have to say that I did enjoy St. Bilko, it was great seeing this army crew just goof off and enjoying boot camp. I think my favorite scene was when Bilko has to prove that his crew are hard workers and could complete the obstacle course that the other army recruits could do. Just their reactions of course being as if they've never exercised before in their lives was a good laugh. Steve Martin and his fianc&eacute;e constantly taking a trip up and down the aisle was fun too. Plus this has one of my favorite comedic actors, Phil Hartman, who is again a great watch is always guaranteed to give you a good laugh. While the film may not stand out, this was definitely worth the watch. I would recommend it if you need a good laugh, you're always in good company with Steve Martin, Dan Aykroyd and Phil Hartman, not to mention a baby Chris Rock. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlushingCaps
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I missed this when it came out, and just caught it after one of those free weekends for premium channels. As a long-time fan of Phil Silvers' fabulous series of the 1950s, I was skeptical about this movie, although I usually like Steve Martin's films--especially Planes, Trains, and Automobiles. I thought it was quite true to the spirit of the TV show. I was pleased that it was PG and not full of foul language and other things not fit for children. They didn't try to duplicate everything in the original, merely to present a similar group of characters, with the same names. The plot was not unlike one in the series, but was not a remake of any episode from the series. They had some lines that sounded like they could have come from the series. They had a way to signal "brass coming" so Bilko's men could quickly put away all their gambling devices and make the motor pool look like one--just as the series did, only more elaborate. Col. Hall in the film, just like on TV, acknowledged that Bilko knew more about what was going on, and, in effect, ran the post. Other reviewers have detailed the plot. One highlight for me was the clever way Bilko arranged for his adversary to give himself away after ruining the test of the hover tank, not knowing the machine was not going to work in the first place. That was thinking like the Phil Silvers' version would have done. I agree that Silvers, and Nat Hiken, would be proud that their series was re-created as a feature film 40 years later. It wasn't the funniest movie ever, but it was surely no worse than a "very funny" film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny movie for people who possess a sense of humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (imdb@michaelbauers.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Seems to me like most of the negative votes come from fans of the original show. I am glad I never saw it, because I think this is one of the funniest movies I have ever seen. I love Bilko's character. Martin plays a charismatic, scheming yet kind hearted con artist. I love his comic timing in this movie. It's definitely my favorite Steve Martin role. I think part of the reason I like Martin, is for the same reason I like characters like Bugs Bunny. He always comes out on top, and is usually in complete control of a situation. I love that type of role - who does not want to be more like a Sgt Bilko? I thought almost every scene was funny. I liked pretty much every actor in it. It's not for serious people. I sometimes wonder why serious people bother to rate comedies at all - some people were born with no sense of humor, from what I can tell. For those people who dislike (or are bored of) put down humor, sex humor, or gross out humor, this is none of those (Not that I don't mind some of that, but a change of pace is always welcome.) It's a politer, lighter, silly humor almost cartoonish, in a good way. I have seen this movie at least three times, and still laugh at it. So if you are not a fan of the TV show, I think you will like this in spite of the shockingly low review of this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sergeant Bilko
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    crichton_ius
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK I'm not an American, but in my humble Scottish opinion Steve Martin is not, never has been, and never will be a funny man as long as our posteriors point in a southerly direction. Phil Silvers as Sergeant Bilko was a funny man, no doubt due to the skilled writers and directors and all the other talented team working characters in the series who contributed perfectly to one of the funniest and dateless situation comedies America has ever produced. How anyone could have the audacity to even attempt to replicate the Phil Silvers character is beyond me. To compound things the exercise was repeated in Martin's unfunny attempt to be Peter Seller's Inspector Clouseau, another abortive attempt, in my opinion, to rekindle a demonstrably unfunny career. Some of your contributers say 'Steve Martin puts his own stamp on the character', to that I would say 'balderdash' , his portrayals will be long forgotten when those of Silvers and Sellars will be treasured for generations to come
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A VERY good film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mightyzebra
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have watched a few films with Steve Martin and really enjoyed them all, but this is, so far, my definite favourite. I have not watched the original series of "Sgt. Bilko", but I picked up the idea of this film pretty quickly and I enjoyed almost every minute. The humour is very crazy, similar to cartoon humour, but at the same time it is often very intelligent. I felt many "YES!" moments in this film, lines or scenes where the hilarity, words and or slapstick were just about PERFECT. Not only were the lines and funny scenes mostly very well-written and done, but the characters were memorable and (mostly) relatable and the plot itself was engaging enough, though sometimes a little too farcical. I recommend this film to people who love "mad," but clever humour, people who like Steve Martin and already have an idea of his acting style and to people who like to see a "unique" portrayal of what goes on in the US army (not that it's realistic of course...). Enjoy "Sgt. Bilko"! :-)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Steve Martin At His Best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steve Martin is At His Best in 'Sgt. Bilko'. He delivers a hilarious & lovable performance, that easily is among his finest. And even as a film, 'Sgt. Bilko' is great fun! 'Sgt. Bilko' Synopsis: Bilko runs the motor pool and has all sorts of scams going on like gambling, renting out military vehicles, and so on, which are all violations. 'Sgt. Bilko', an adaptation of the 1950s television series, turns out to be one great cinematic experience. The film is full of comedic moments, that definitely will you in splits. Nat Hiken & Andy Breckman's Screenplay is genuinely funny & very entertaining. Jonathan Lynn's Direction, is perfect. Cinematography, Editing & Art Design, are mention-worthy. Performance-Wise: Martin is the life of the show. He stands out from scene A to Z. Dan Aykroyd is first-rate. Phil Hartman is excellent as the bad-guy. Glenne Headly is wonderfully relaxed. Chris Rock, John Marshall Jones & Pamela Adlon are quite good. Others lend good support. On the whole, 'Sgt. Bilko' is great fun! A Must See for Martin Fanatics!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    After Bathing at Baxter's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A movie starring Steve Martin, Dan Aykroyd and Phil Hartman based on the classic situation comedy has to be hilarious, right? No cigar and not even close. Phil Silvers put a lot of "Phil Silvers" into his "Ernie Bilko" and Mr. Martin wisely substitutes "Steve Martin" manners for his interpretation. This is a smart move on Martin's part, as the two comedians possess a completely different type of energy. However, Martin does not work well with this material, in this situation. Consequently, it falls apart... While certainly no guarantee, it might have been better to star Mr. Hartman attempting a Silvers impersonation. It's relatively interesting to see Cathy Silvers (as Monday) and Chris Rock (as Oster) appear as a genuinely funny team of lieutenants (last saw Ms. Silvers at "Greenblatt's" deli in the 1990s, and she was a delight). Imagine Entertainment's "Bilko" adds likable Daryl Mitchell (as Walter "Wally" Holbrook), but does little with him. The jokes about Fort Baxter's men failing to bathe do not pass the smell test. *** Sgt. Bilko (3/29/96) Jonathan Lynn ~ Steve Martin, Dan Aykroyd, Phil Hartman, Daryl Mitchell
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "What's that music?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ackstasis
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last night, I watched 'Sgt. Bilko (1996)' for the first time in a few years, and was surprised at the number of quotes that have crept their way into my everyday conversation. Just yesterday at the gym, for example, I declared to a struggling friend: "one, we're going for one!"). Directed by Jonathan Lynn, co-creator of the British sitcom "Yes Minister" and its sequel, 'Sgt. Bilko' is a tightly-scripted classic, one of my favourite 90s comedies. The film is a screen adaptation of "The Phil Silvers Show," which ran from 1955 to 1959. I haven't seen the series, so I have no point of comparison, but I would certainly like to at some point. Master Sergeant Ernest G. Bilko (Steve Martin) commands the motor pool at Fort Baxter, but his involvement with the army is in name only. Whenever his bewildered commander (Dan Ackroyd) is looking the other way, Bilko dedicates his not-inconsiderable energies towards gambling and other worthwhile pursuits. He has a girlfriend (Glenne Headly) who is mostly on his wavelength, but who perhaps resents being left at the altar on multiple occasions. When an old nemesis (Phil Hartman) arrives on the base, Bilko finds out that army isn't as leisurely as he'd come to believe. 'Sgt Bilko' moves along at a headlong pace, with Steve Martin cracking one-liners without even drawing a breath ("All I've ever wanted was an honest week's pay for an honest day's work"). Highlights include the most uneventful boxing match in cinematic history ("For three rounds, nobody hit anybody. It was a dance recital"), a surprise inspection of somebody else's barracks ("It is my understanding that you can no longer ask me these questions, sir"), and Bilko's attempt to dissuade his girlfriend from marrying Major Thorn ("Think of the children. You're a Catholic and he's an arsehole, how will you raise them?").
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Steve Martin makes it seem better than it really is.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Realistically, the dubbo's have been the stingiest or most disappointing decade for comedy heroes. I've whinged about this before, but the days of reliable comedy icons monopolising the box office on an annual basis appear over. Consider the 80s and 90s, Eddie Murphy, Steve Martin and Bill Murray, Vs the 00s, Sandler, Ferrell, Stiller, (and I'll throw Carrey in there). Who will history be more kind to? This brings us to Steve Martin, the master of being fake. Fake happy, fake sincere, fake angry, fake remorseful. In Dirty Rotten Scoundrels, LA Story, Little Shop of Horrors, Leap of Faith, My Blue Heaven (underrated) and Bowfinger you always knew Steve was too everything mentioned above, happy, sincere etc but he was always convincing enough in a funny way that set him apart from everyone before or since. I still maintain that Bill Murray and Steve Martin are the two guys I would laugh at regardless of what they were doing, if they were trying to be funny or not. So why have I wasted words telling you what you probably already know? Because if you don't already like Steve Martin there is a 99% chance that you will find Sgt Bilko very underwhelming, as he makes the film his own. Steve is Bilko, a corrupt, conniving, deceitful and untrustworthy soldier in command of the motor pool an the army base Fort Baxter, but he is all those things in the most PG friendly Disney way. I would waste a lot of time describing his mannerisms and what would ordinarily be inane chit chat between he and the officers hell bent on bringing him down, as it is generally not what he says or even how he says it to a point. It is just that he is Steve while he is doing and saying these things, which should be obvious. I just can't imagine Ferrell being Bilko without hamming and getting near naked or Sandler without yelling and trying all the while to be endearing (there is NO-ONE in comedy that wants to be liked more than Sandler, regardless of who he is playing). This leaves Stiller as the logical next up, but I just don't think he has the personality to pull it off. Consider this: Stiller's two best roles, a vain, clueless moron model in Zoolander and a vain, clueless moron actor in Tropic Thunder. Coincidence? Back to Sgt Bilko, you'll have to take my word for this, Sgt Bilko is a paint by numbers Disney comedy that should be pointless. It has cookie cutter characters and situations but again if you like Steve Martin you should get more than a couple of chuckles. Put it this way, about 5 minutes in Bilko asks a superior officer "Have you lost weight?", if that doesn't turn the corners of your mouth up switch off the DVD because that is about as funny as Sgt Bilko gets, and even that is only funny because of Martin's delivery. For some reason that made me laugh, and I laughed often enough to want to see this again in the future at some point. Final Rating  6.5 / 10. Shouldn't work but the presence of Steve Martin adds value to any film and he does enough here to warrant a rental. If you liked this (or even if you didn't) check out oneguyrambling.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dismissed, and it's being considered for a court martial
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now, to be fair, I haven't watched a moment of the original show. I know nothing about the Sergeant. With that said, I can't imagine that this does justice to him. You see, if he was always this unfunny, I cannot imagine that he would be popular. I mean, none of the characters garner a single laugh(they aren't even entirely consistent; early in this, from one scene to the next, one of the leads behave in a manner that directly contradicts everything we've learned about him up to that point), and they are all one-note cardboard cut-outs, but you'd at least expect the dude they titled this after to be worth watching(yes, he is pretty smooth with the ladies, however, that's all; he's not charming). The plot is completely predictable. Gags and jokes are uninspired. OK, we get it, they are undisciplined, fine... if we laugh at it, will you move on? Martin and Aykroyd are hilarious... elsewhere. Tanks aren't that effective in combat anymore; they're slow, useless against the air and too easy to disable. The concept of a type that can hover is a worn-out sci-fi idea. This isn't devoid of positives... Phil Hartman is one, and the other is the great music. I don't know, I suppose this is what you get for hiring the director of Greedy and The Whole Nine Yards. Then again, I do still intend to catch Clue. There is a little moderate to strong language in this. I recommend this to... I don't know, people who like these flicks. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know what's weird? My mom was the biggest Steve Martin fan you would ever meet, she had(what I thought) all of his movies and watched every biography on him. So since she had a lot of his movies, I watched most of them with her. But my boyfriend kept telling me about a film called St. Bilko and how hilarious it was. I was stumped, I couldn't find it in my mom's collection nor did I ever hear of it. So my boyfriend and I went shopping and he found it on DVD, so we went home and watched it. This film just took me back to the classic comedies I grew up with like Trading Places, The Great Outdoors and Planes, Trains and Automobiles. Steve Martin is always a great comedic actor who is a pleasure to watch, same with Dan Aykroyd. While this movie doesn't stand out as well as their other films, this was still a lot of fun to watch. Master Sergeant Ernest G. Bilko is in charge of the motor pool at Fort Baxter, a small US Army base. Exploiting this position, he directs a number of scams ranging from gambling to renting out military vehicles. His commanding officer, Colonel Hall, overlooks Bilko's money making schemes, as he is more concerned with his own affairs. Bad news begins when inspector Major Thorn, Bilko's rival, arrives at the camp and begins to cast scrutiny on Bilko's record. The motivation for Thorn's actions is due to the intense rivalry between the two due to several mishaps in the past, particularly because Thorn's career was ruined due to one of Bilko's scams. Thorn's revenge ensues and ultimately it becomes a battle of wits between the two men. Thorn's reliance on sabotage ultimately leads to his downfall and he is sent to Greenland. Also Bilko's fianc&eacute;e, Rita, whom Bilko has stood up several times at the altar. Bilko is given an ultimatum to win her back within 30 days or to lose her forever. I have to say that I did enjoy St. Bilko, it was great seeing this army crew just goof off and enjoying boot camp. I think my favorite scene was when Bilko has to prove that his crew are hard workers and could complete the obstacle course that the other army recruits could do. Just their reactions of course being as if they've never exercised before in their lives was a good laugh. Steve Martin and his fianc&eacute;e constantly taking a trip up and down the aisle was fun too. Plus this has one of my favorite comedic actors, Phil Hartman, who is again a great watch is always guaranteed to give you a good laugh. While the film may not stand out, this was definitely worth the watch. I would recommend it if you need a good laugh, you're always in good company with Steve Martin, Dan Aykroyd and Phil Hartman, not to mention a baby Chris Rock. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlushingCaps
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I missed this when it came out, and just caught it after one of those free weekends for premium channels. As a long-time fan of Phil Silvers' fabulous series of the 1950s, I was skeptical about this movie, although I usually like Steve Martin's films--especially Planes, Trains, and Automobiles. I thought it was quite true to the spirit of the TV show. I was pleased that it was PG and not full of foul language and other things not fit for children. They didn't try to duplicate everything in the original, merely to present a similar group of characters, with the same names. The plot was not unlike one in the series, but was not a remake of any episode from the series. They had some lines that sounded like they could have come from the series. They had a way to signal "brass coming" so Bilko's men could quickly put away all their gambling devices and make the motor pool look like one--just as the series did, only more elaborate. Col. Hall in the film, just like on TV, acknowledged that Bilko knew more about what was going on, and, in effect, ran the post. Other reviewers have detailed the plot. One highlight for me was the clever way Bilko arranged for his adversary to give himself away after ruining the test of the hover tank, not knowing the machine was not going to work in the first place. That was thinking like the Phil Silvers' version would have done. I agree that Silvers, and Nat Hiken, would be proud that their series was re-created as a feature film 40 years later. It wasn't the funniest movie ever, but it was surely no worse than a "very funny" film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny movie for people who possess a sense of humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (imdb@michaelbauers.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Seems to me like most of the negative votes come from fans of the original show. I am glad I never saw it, because I think this is one of the funniest movies I have ever seen. I love Bilko's character. Martin plays a charismatic, scheming yet kind hearted con artist. I love his comic timing in this movie. It's definitely my favorite Steve Martin role. I think part of the reason I like Martin, is for the same reason I like characters like Bugs Bunny. He always comes out on top, and is usually in complete control of a situation. I love that type of role - who does not want to be more like a Sgt Bilko? I thought almost every scene was funny. I liked pretty much every actor in it. It's not for serious people. I sometimes wonder why serious people bother to rate comedies at all - some people were born with no sense of humor, from what I can tell. For those people who dislike (or are bored of) put down humor, sex humor, or gross out humor, this is none of those (Not that I don't mind some of that, but a change of pace is always welcome.) It's a politer, lighter, silly humor almost cartoonish, in a good way. I have seen this movie at least three times, and still laugh at it. So if you are not a fan of the TV show, I think you will like this in spite of the shockingly low review of this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sergeant Bilko
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    crichton_ius
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK I'm not an American, but in my humble Scottish opinion Steve Martin is not, never has been, and never will be a funny man as long as our posteriors point in a southerly direction. Phil Silvers as Sergeant Bilko was a funny man, no doubt due to the skilled writers and directors and all the other talented team working characters in the series who contributed perfectly to one of the funniest and dateless situation comedies America has ever produced. How anyone could have the audacity to even attempt to replicate the Phil Silvers character is beyond me. To compound things the exercise was repeated in Martin's unfunny attempt to be Peter Seller's Inspector Clouseau, another abortive attempt, in my opinion, to rekindle a demonstrably unfunny career. Some of your contributers say 'Steve Martin puts his own stamp on the character', to that I would say 'balderdash' , his portrayals will be long forgotten when those of Silvers and Sellars will be treasured for generations to come
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A VERY good film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mightyzebra
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have watched a few films with Steve Martin and really enjoyed them all, but this is, so far, my definite favourite. I have not watched the original series of "Sgt. Bilko", but I picked up the idea of this film pretty quickly and I enjoyed almost every minute. The humour is very crazy, similar to cartoon humour, but at the same time it is often very intelligent. I felt many "YES!" moments in this film, lines or scenes where the hilarity, words and or slapstick were just about PERFECT. Not only were the lines and funny scenes mostly very well-written and done, but the characters were memorable and (mostly) relatable and the plot itself was engaging enough, though sometimes a little too farcical. I recommend this film to people who love "mad," but clever humour, people who like Steve Martin and already have an idea of his acting style and to people who like to see a "unique" portrayal of what goes on in the US army (not that it's realistic of course...). Enjoy "Sgt. Bilko"! :-)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Steve Martin At His Best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steve Martin is At His Best in 'Sgt. Bilko'. He delivers a hilarious & lovable performance, that easily is among his finest. And even as a film, 'Sgt. Bilko' is great fun! 'Sgt. Bilko' Synopsis: Bilko runs the motor pool and has all sorts of scams going on like gambling, renting out military vehicles, and so on, which are all violations. 'Sgt. Bilko', an adaptation of the 1950s television series, turns out to be one great cinematic experience. The film is full of comedic moments, that definitely will you in splits. Nat Hiken & Andy Breckman's Screenplay is genuinely funny & very entertaining. Jonathan Lynn's Direction, is perfect. Cinematography, Editing & Art Design, are mention-worthy. Performance-Wise: Martin is the life of the show. He stands out from scene A to Z. Dan Aykroyd is first-rate. Phil Hartman is excellent as the bad-guy. Glenne Headly is wonderfully relaxed. Chris Rock, John Marshall Jones & Pamela Adlon are quite good. Others lend good support. On the whole, 'Sgt. Bilko' is great fun! A Must See for Martin Fanatics!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    After Bathing at Baxter's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A movie starring Steve Martin, Dan Aykroyd and Phil Hartman based on the classic situation comedy has to be hilarious, right? No cigar and not even close. Phil Silvers put a lot of "Phil Silvers" into his "Ernie Bilko" and Mr. Martin wisely substitutes "Steve Martin" manners for his interpretation. This is a smart move on Martin's part, as the two comedians possess a completely different type of energy. However, Martin does not work well with this material, in this situation. Consequently, it falls apart... While certainly no guarantee, it might have been better to star Mr. Hartman attempting a Silvers impersonation. It's relatively interesting to see Cathy Silvers (as Monday) and Chris Rock (as Oster) appear as a genuinely funny team of lieutenants (last saw Ms. Silvers at "Greenblatt's" deli in the 1990s, and she was a delight). Imagine Entertainment's "Bilko" adds likable Daryl Mitchell (as Walter "Wally" Holbrook), but does little with him. The jokes about Fort Baxter's men failing to bathe do not pass the smell test. *** Sgt. Bilko (3/29/96) Jonathan Lynn ~ Steve Martin, Dan Aykroyd, Phil Hartman, Daryl Mitchell
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "What's that music?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ackstasis
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last night, I watched 'Sgt. Bilko (1996)' for the first time in a few years, and was surprised at the number of quotes that have crept their way into my everyday conversation. Just yesterday at the gym, for example, I declared to a struggling friend: "one, we're going for one!"). Directed by Jonathan Lynn, co-creator of the British sitcom "Yes Minister" and its sequel, 'Sgt. Bilko' is a tightly-scripted classic, one of my favourite 90s comedies. The film is a screen adaptation of "The Phil Silvers Show," which ran from 1955 to 1959. I haven't seen the series, so I have no point of comparison, but I would certainly like to at some point. Master Sergeant Ernest G. Bilko (Steve Martin) commands the motor pool at Fort Baxter, but his involvement with the army is in name only. Whenever his bewildered commander (Dan Ackroyd) is looking the other way, Bilko dedicates his not-inconsiderable energies towards gambling and other worthwhile pursuits. He has a girlfriend (Glenne Headly) who is mostly on his wavelength, but who perhaps resents being left at the altar on multiple occasions. When an old nemesis (Phil Hartman) arrives on the base, Bilko finds out that army isn't as leisurely as he'd come to believe. 'Sgt Bilko' moves along at a headlong pace, with Steve Martin cracking one-liners without even drawing a breath ("All I've ever wanted was an honest week's pay for an honest day's work"). Highlights include the most uneventful boxing match in cinematic history ("For three rounds, nobody hit anybody. It was a dance recital"), a surprise inspection of somebody else's barracks ("It is my understanding that you can no longer ask me these questions, sir"), and Bilko's attempt to dissuade his girlfriend from marrying Major Thorn ("Think of the children. You're a Catholic and he's an arsehole, how will you raise them?").
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Steve Martin makes it seem better than it really is.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Realistically, the dubbo's have been the stingiest or most disappointing decade for comedy heroes. I've whinged about this before, but the days of reliable comedy icons monopolising the box office on an annual basis appear over. Consider the 80s and 90s, Eddie Murphy, Steve Martin and Bill Murray, Vs the 00s, Sandler, Ferrell, Stiller, (and I'll throw Carrey in there). Who will history be more kind to? This brings us to Steve Martin, the master of being fake. Fake happy, fake sincere, fake angry, fake remorseful. In Dirty Rotten Scoundrels, LA Story, Little Shop of Horrors, Leap of Faith, My Blue Heaven (underrated) and Bowfinger you always knew Steve was too everything mentioned above, happy, sincere etc but he was always convincing enough in a funny way that set him apart from everyone before or since. I still maintain that Bill Murray and Steve Martin are the two guys I would laugh at regardless of what they were doing, if they were trying to be funny or not. So why have I wasted words telling you what you probably already know? Because if you don't already like Steve Martin there is a 99% chance that you will find Sgt Bilko very underwhelming, as he makes the film his own. Steve is Bilko, a corrupt, conniving, deceitful and untrustworthy soldier in command of the motor pool an the army base Fort Baxter, but he is all those things in the most PG friendly Disney way. I would waste a lot of time describing his mannerisms and what would ordinarily be inane chit chat between he and the officers hell bent on bringing him down, as it is generally not what he says or even how he says it to a point. It is just that he is Steve while he is doing and saying these things, which should be obvious. I just can't imagine Ferrell being Bilko without hamming and getting near naked or Sandler without yelling and trying all the while to be endearing (there is NO-ONE in comedy that wants to be liked more than Sandler, regardless of who he is playing). This leaves Stiller as the logical next up, but I just don't think he has the personality to pull it off. Consider this: Stiller's two best roles, a vain, clueless moron model in Zoolander and a vain, clueless moron actor in Tropic Thunder. Coincidence? Back to Sgt Bilko, you'll have to take my word for this, Sgt Bilko is a paint by numbers Disney comedy that should be pointless. It has cookie cutter characters and situations but again if you like Steve Martin you should get more than a couple of chuckles. Put it this way, about 5 minutes in Bilko asks a superior officer "Have you lost weight?", if that doesn't turn the corners of your mouth up switch off the DVD because that is about as funny as Sgt Bilko gets, and even that is only funny because of Martin's delivery. For some reason that made me laugh, and I laughed often enough to want to see this again in the future at some point. Final Rating  6.5 / 10. Shouldn't work but the presence of Steve Martin adds value to any film and he does enough here to warrant a rental. If you liked this (or even if you didn't) check out oneguyrambling.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dismissed, and it's being considered for a court martial
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now, to be fair, I haven't watched a moment of the original show. I know nothing about the Sergeant. With that said, I can't imagine that this does justice to him. You see, if he was always this unfunny, I cannot imagine that he would be popular. I mean, none of the characters garner a single laugh(they aren't even entirely consistent; early in this, from one scene to the next, one of the leads behave in a manner that directly contradicts everything we've learned about him up to that point), and they are all one-note cardboard cut-outs, but you'd at least expect the dude they titled this after to be worth watching(yes, he is pretty smooth with the ladies, however, that's all; he's not charming). The plot is completely predictable. Gags and jokes are uninspired. OK, we get it, they are undisciplined, fine... if we laugh at it, will you move on? Martin and Aykroyd are hilarious... elsewhere. Tanks aren't that effective in combat anymore; they're slow, useless against the air and too easy to disable. The concept of a type that can hover is a worn-out sci-fi idea. This isn't devoid of positives... Phil Hartman is one, and the other is the great music. I don't know, I suppose this is what you get for hiring the director of Greedy and The Whole Nine Yards. Then again, I do still intend to catch Clue. There is a little moderate to strong language in this. I recommend this to... I don't know, people who like these flicks. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know what's weird? My mom was the biggest Steve Martin fan you would ever meet, she had(what I thought) all of his movies and watched every biography on him. So since she had a lot of his movies, I watched most of them with her. But my boyfriend kept telling me about a film called St. Bilko and how hilarious it was. I was stumped, I couldn't find it in my mom's collection nor did I ever hear of it. So my boyfriend and I went shopping and he found it on DVD, so we went home and watched it. This film just took me back to the classic comedies I grew up with like Trading Places, The Great Outdoors and Planes, Trains and Automobiles. Steve Martin is always a great comedic actor who is a pleasure to watch, same with Dan Aykroyd. While this movie doesn't stand out as well as their other films, this was still a lot of fun to watch. Master Sergeant Ernest G. Bilko is in charge of the motor pool at Fort Baxter, a small US Army base. Exploiting this position, he directs a number of scams ranging from gambling to renting out military vehicles. His commanding officer, Colonel Hall, overlooks Bilko's money making schemes, as he is more concerned with his own affairs. Bad news begins when inspector Major Thorn, Bilko's rival, arrives at the camp and begins to cast scrutiny on Bilko's record. The motivation for Thorn's actions is due to the intense rivalry between the two due to several mishaps in the past, particularly because Thorn's career was ruined due to one of Bilko's scams. Thorn's revenge ensues and ultimately it becomes a battle of wits between the two men. Thorn's reliance on sabotage ultimately leads to his downfall and he is sent to Greenland. Also Bilko's fianc&eacute;e, Rita, whom Bilko has stood up several times at the altar. Bilko is given an ultimatum to win her back within 30 days or to lose her forever. I have to say that I did enjoy St. Bilko, it was great seeing this army crew just goof off and enjoying boot camp. I think my favorite scene was when Bilko has to prove that his crew are hard workers and could complete the obstacle course that the other army recruits could do. Just their reactions of course being as if they've never exercised before in their lives was a good laugh. Steve Martin and his fianc&eacute;e constantly taking a trip up and down the aisle was fun too. Plus this has one of my favorite comedic actors, Phil Hartman, who is again a great watch is always guaranteed to give you a good laugh. While the film may not stand out, this was definitely worth the watch. I would recommend it if you need a good laugh, you're always in good company with Steve Martin, Dan Aykroyd and Phil Hartman, not to mention a baby Chris Rock. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlushingCaps
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I missed this when it came out, and just caught it after one of those free weekends for premium channels. As a long-time fan of Phil Silvers' fabulous series of the 1950s, I was skeptical about this movie, although I usually like Steve Martin's films--especially Planes, Trains, and Automobiles. I thought it was quite true to the spirit of the TV show. I was pleased that it was PG and not full of foul language and other things not fit for children. They didn't try to duplicate everything in the original, merely to present a similar group of characters, with the same names. The plot was not unlike one in the series, but was not a remake of any episode from the series. They had some lines that sounded like they could have come from the series. They had a way to signal "brass coming" so Bilko's men could quickly put away all their gambling devices and make the motor pool look like one--just as the series did, only more elaborate. Col. Hall in the film, just like on TV, acknowledged that Bilko knew more about what was going on, and, in effect, ran the post. Other reviewers have detailed the plot. One highlight for me was the clever way Bilko arranged for his adversary to give himself away after ruining the test of the hover tank, not knowing the machine was not going to work in the first place. That was thinking like the Phil Silvers' version would have done. I agree that Silvers, and Nat Hiken, would be proud that their series was re-created as a feature film 40 years later. It wasn't the funniest movie ever, but it was surely no worse than a "very funny" film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny movie for people who possess a sense of humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (imdb@michaelbauers.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Seems to me like most of the negative votes come from fans of the original show. I am glad I never saw it, because I think this is one of the funniest movies I have ever seen. I love Bilko's character. Martin plays a charismatic, scheming yet kind hearted con artist. I love his comic timing in this movie. It's definitely my favorite Steve Martin role. I think part of the reason I like Martin, is for the same reason I like characters like Bugs Bunny. He always comes out on top, and is usually in complete control of a situation. I love that type of role - who does not want to be more like a Sgt Bilko? I thought almost every scene was funny. I liked pretty much every actor in it. It's not for serious people. I sometimes wonder why serious people bother to rate comedies at all - some people were born with no sense of humor, from what I can tell. For those people who dislike (or are bored of) put down humor, sex humor, or gross out humor, this is none of those (Not that I don't mind some of that, but a change of pace is always welcome.) It's a politer, lighter, silly humor almost cartoonish, in a good way. I have seen this movie at least three times, and still laugh at it. So if you are not a fan of the TV show, I think you will like this in spite of the shockingly low review of this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sergeant Bilko
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    crichton_ius
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK I'm not an American, but in my humble Scottish opinion Steve Martin is not, never has been, and never will be a funny man as long as our posteriors point in a southerly direction. Phil Silvers as Sergeant Bilko was a funny man, no doubt due to the skilled writers and directors and all the other talented team working characters in the series who contributed perfectly to one of the funniest and dateless situation comedies America has ever produced. How anyone could have the audacity to even attempt to replicate the Phil Silvers character is beyond me. To compound things the exercise was repeated in Martin's unfunny attempt to be Peter Seller's Inspector Clouseau, another abortive attempt, in my opinion, to rekindle a demonstrably unfunny career. Some of your contributers say 'Steve Martin puts his own stamp on the character', to that I would say 'balderdash' , his portrayals will be long forgotten when those of Silvers and Sellars will be treasured for generations to come
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A VERY good film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mightyzebra
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have watched a few films with Steve Martin and really enjoyed them all, but this is, so far, my definite favourite. I have not watched the original series of "Sgt. Bilko", but I picked up the idea of this film pretty quickly and I enjoyed almost every minute. The humour is very crazy, similar to cartoon humour, but at the same time it is often very intelligent. I felt many "YES!" moments in this film, lines or scenes where the hilarity, words and or slapstick were just about PERFECT. Not only were the lines and funny scenes mostly very well-written and done, but the characters were memorable and (mostly) relatable and the plot itself was engaging enough, though sometimes a little too farcical. I recommend this film to people who love "mad," but clever humour, people who like Steve Martin and already have an idea of his acting style and to people who like to see a "unique" portrayal of what goes on in the US army (not that it's realistic of course...). Enjoy "Sgt. Bilko"! :-)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Steve Martin At His Best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steve Martin is At His Best in 'Sgt. Bilko'. He delivers a hilarious & lovable performance, that easily is among his finest. And even as a film, 'Sgt. Bilko' is great fun! 'Sgt. Bilko' Synopsis: Bilko runs the motor pool and has all sorts of scams going on like gambling, renting out military vehicles, and so on, which are all violations. 'Sgt. Bilko', an adaptation of the 1950s television series, turns out to be one great cinematic experience. The film is full of comedic moments, that definitely will you in splits. Nat Hiken & Andy Breckman's Screenplay is genuinely funny & very entertaining. Jonathan Lynn's Direction, is perfect. Cinematography, Editing & Art Design, are mention-worthy. Performance-Wise: Martin is the life of the show. He stands out from scene A to Z. Dan Aykroyd is first-rate. Phil Hartman is excellent as the bad-guy. Glenne Headly is wonderfully relaxed. Chris Rock, John Marshall Jones & Pamela Adlon are quite good. Others lend good support. On the whole, 'Sgt. Bilko' is great fun! A Must See for Martin Fanatics!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    After Bathing at Baxter's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A movie starring Steve Martin, Dan Aykroyd and Phil Hartman based on the classic situation comedy has to be hilarious, right? No cigar and not even close. Phil Silvers put a lot of "Phil Silvers" into his "Ernie Bilko" and Mr. Martin wisely substitutes "Steve Martin" manners for his interpretation. This is a smart move on Martin's part, as the two comedians possess a completely different type of energy. However, Martin does not work well with this material, in this situation. Consequently, it falls apart... While certainly no guarantee, it might have been better to star Mr. Hartman attempting a Silvers impersonation. It's relatively interesting to see Cathy Silvers (as Monday) and Chris Rock (as Oster) appear as a genuinely funny team of lieutenants (last saw Ms. Silvers at "Greenblatt's" deli in the 1990s, and she was a delight). Imagine Entertainment's "Bilko" adds likable Daryl Mitchell (as Walter "Wally" Holbrook), but does little with him. The jokes about Fort Baxter's men failing to bathe do not pass the smell test. *** Sgt. Bilko (3/29/96) Jonathan Lynn ~ Steve Martin, Dan Aykroyd, Phil Hartman, Daryl Mitchell
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "What's that music?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ackstasis
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last night, I watched 'Sgt. Bilko (1996)' for the first time in a few years, and was surprised at the number of quotes that have crept their way into my everyday conversation. Just yesterday at the gym, for example, I declared to a struggling friend: "one, we're going for one!"). Directed by Jonathan Lynn, co-creator of the British sitcom "Yes Minister" and its sequel, 'Sgt. Bilko' is a tightly-scripted classic, one of my favourite 90s comedies. The film is a screen adaptation of "The Phil Silvers Show," which ran from 1955 to 1959. I haven't seen the series, so I have no point of comparison, but I would certainly like to at some point. Master Sergeant Ernest G. Bilko (Steve Martin) commands the motor pool at Fort Baxter, but his involvement with the army is in name only. Whenever his bewildered commander (Dan Ackroyd) is looking the other way, Bilko dedicates his not-inconsiderable energies towards gambling and other worthwhile pursuits. He has a girlfriend (Glenne Headly) who is mostly on his wavelength, but who perhaps resents being left at the altar on multiple occasions. When an old nemesis (Phil Hartman) arrives on the base, Bilko finds out that army isn't as leisurely as he'd come to believe. 'Sgt Bilko' moves along at a headlong pace, with Steve Martin cracking one-liners without even drawing a breath ("All I've ever wanted was an honest week's pay for an honest day's work"). Highlights include the most uneventful boxing match in cinematic history ("For three rounds, nobody hit anybody. It was a dance recital"), a surprise inspection of somebody else's barracks ("It is my understanding that you can no longer ask me these questions, sir"), and Bilko's attempt to dissuade his girlfriend from marrying Major Thorn ("Think of the children. You're a Catholic and he's an arsehole, how will you raise them?").
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Steve Martin makes it seem better than it really is.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Realistically, the dubbo's have been the stingiest or most disappointing decade for comedy heroes. I've whinged about this before, but the days of reliable comedy icons monopolising the box office on an annual basis appear over. Consider the 80s and 90s, Eddie Murphy, Steve Martin and Bill Murray, Vs the 00s, Sandler, Ferrell, Stiller, (and I'll throw Carrey in there). Who will history be more kind to? This brings us to Steve Martin, the master of being fake. Fake happy, fake sincere, fake angry, fake remorseful. In Dirty Rotten Scoundrels, LA Story, Little Shop of Horrors, Leap of Faith, My Blue Heaven (underrated) and Bowfinger you always knew Steve was too everything mentioned above, happy, sincere etc but he was always convincing enough in a funny way that set him apart from everyone before or since. I still maintain that Bill Murray and Steve Martin are the two guys I would laugh at regardless of what they were doing, if they were trying to be funny or not. So why have I wasted words telling you what you probably already know? Because if you don't already like Steve Martin there is a 99% chance that you will find Sgt Bilko very underwhelming, as he makes the film his own. Steve is Bilko, a corrupt, conniving, deceitful and untrustworthy soldier in command of the motor pool an the army base Fort Baxter, but he is all those things in the most PG friendly Disney way. I would waste a lot of time describing his mannerisms and what would ordinarily be inane chit chat between he and the officers hell bent on bringing him down, as it is generally not what he says or even how he says it to a point. It is just that he is Steve while he is doing and saying these things, which should be obvious. I just can't imagine Ferrell being Bilko without hamming and getting near naked or Sandler without yelling and trying all the while to be endearing (there is NO-ONE in comedy that wants to be liked more than Sandler, regardless of who he is playing). This leaves Stiller as the logical next up, but I just don't think he has the personality to pull it off. Consider this: Stiller's two best roles, a vain, clueless moron model in Zoolander and a vain, clueless moron actor in Tropic Thunder. Coincidence? Back to Sgt Bilko, you'll have to take my word for this, Sgt Bilko is a paint by numbers Disney comedy that should be pointless. It has cookie cutter characters and situations but again if you like Steve Martin you should get more than a couple of chuckles. Put it this way, about 5 minutes in Bilko asks a superior officer "Have you lost weight?", if that doesn't turn the corners of your mouth up switch off the DVD because that is about as funny as Sgt Bilko gets, and even that is only funny because of Martin's delivery. For some reason that made me laugh, and I laughed often enough to want to see this again in the future at some point. Final Rating  6.5 / 10. Shouldn't work but the presence of Steve Martin adds value to any film and he does enough here to warrant a rental. If you liked this (or even if you didn't) check out oneguyrambling.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dismissed, and it's being considered for a court martial
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now, to be fair, I haven't watched a moment of the original show. I know nothing about the Sergeant. With that said, I can't imagine that this does justice to him. You see, if he was always this unfunny, I cannot imagine that he would be popular. I mean, none of the characters garner a single laugh(they aren't even entirely consistent; early in this, from one scene to the next, one of the leads behave in a manner that directly contradicts everything we've learned about him up to that point), and they are all one-note cardboard cut-outs, but you'd at least expect the dude they titled this after to be worth watching(yes, he is pretty smooth with the ladies, however, that's all; he's not charming). The plot is completely predictable. Gags and jokes are uninspired. OK, we get it, they are undisciplined, fine... if we laugh at it, will you move on? Martin and Aykroyd are hilarious... elsewhere. Tanks aren't that effective in combat anymore; they're slow, useless against the air and too easy to disable. The concept of a type that can hover is a worn-out sci-fi idea. This isn't devoid of positives... Phil Hartman is one, and the other is the great music. I don't know, I suppose this is what you get for hiring the director of Greedy and The Whole Nine Yards. Then again, I do still intend to catch Clue. There is a little moderate to strong language in this. I recommend this to... I don't know, people who like these flicks. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know what's weird? My mom was the biggest Steve Martin fan you would ever meet, she had(what I thought) all of his movies and watched every biography on him. So since she had a lot of his movies, I watched most of them with her. But my boyfriend kept telling me about a film called St. Bilko and how hilarious it was. I was stumped, I couldn't find it in my mom's collection nor did I ever hear of it. So my boyfriend and I went shopping and he found it on DVD, so we went home and watched it. This film just took me back to the classic comedies I grew up with like Trading Places, The Great Outdoors and Planes, Trains and Automobiles. Steve Martin is always a great comedic actor who is a pleasure to watch, same with Dan Aykroyd. While this movie doesn't stand out as well as their other films, this was still a lot of fun to watch. Master Sergeant Ernest G. Bilko is in charge of the motor pool at Fort Baxter, a small US Army base. Exploiting this position, he directs a number of scams ranging from gambling to renting out military vehicles. His commanding officer, Colonel Hall, overlooks Bilko's money making schemes, as he is more concerned with his own affairs. Bad news begins when inspector Major Thorn, Bilko's rival, arrives at the camp and begins to cast scrutiny on Bilko's record. The motivation for Thorn's actions is due to the intense rivalry between the two due to several mishaps in the past, particularly because Thorn's career was ruined due to one of Bilko's scams. Thorn's revenge ensues and ultimately it becomes a battle of wits between the two men. Thorn's reliance on sabotage ultimately leads to his downfall and he is sent to Greenland. Also Bilko's fianc&eacute;e, Rita, whom Bilko has stood up several times at the altar. Bilko is given an ultimatum to win her back within 30 days or to lose her forever. I have to say that I did enjoy St. Bilko, it was great seeing this army crew just goof off and enjoying boot camp. I think my favorite scene was when Bilko has to prove that his crew are hard workers and could complete the obstacle course that the other army recruits could do. Just their reactions of course being as if they've never exercised before in their lives was a good laugh. Steve Martin and his fianc&eacute;e constantly taking a trip up and down the aisle was fun too. Plus this has one of my favorite comedic actors, Phil Hartman, who is again a great watch is always guaranteed to give you a good laugh. While the film may not stand out, this was definitely worth the watch. I would recommend it if you need a good laugh, you're always in good company with Steve Martin, Dan Aykroyd and Phil Hartman, not to mention a baby Chris Rock. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlushingCaps
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I missed this when it came out, and just caught it after one of those free weekends for premium channels. As a long-time fan of Phil Silvers' fabulous series of the 1950s, I was skeptical about this movie, although I usually like Steve Martin's films--especially Planes, Trains, and Automobiles. I thought it was quite true to the spirit of the TV show. I was pleased that it was PG and not full of foul language and other things not fit for children. They didn't try to duplicate everything in the original, merely to present a similar group of characters, with the same names. The plot was not unlike one in the series, but was not a remake of any episode from the series. They had some lines that sounded like they could have come from the series. They had a way to signal "brass coming" so Bilko's men could quickly put away all their gambling devices and make the motor pool look like one--just as the series did, only more elaborate. Col. Hall in the film, just like on TV, acknowledged that Bilko knew more about what was going on, and, in effect, ran the post. Other reviewers have detailed the plot. One highlight for me was the clever way Bilko arranged for his adversary to give himself away after ruining the test of the hover tank, not knowing the machine was not going to work in the first place. That was thinking like the Phil Silvers' version would have done. I agree that Silvers, and Nat Hiken, would be proud that their series was re-created as a feature film 40 years later. It wasn't the funniest movie ever, but it was surely no worse than a "very funny" film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny movie for people who possess a sense of humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (imdb@michaelbauers.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Seems to me like most of the negative votes come from fans of the original show. I am glad I never saw it, because I think this is one of the funniest movies I have ever seen. I love Bilko's character. Martin plays a charismatic, scheming yet kind hearted con artist. I love his comic timing in this movie. It's definitely my favorite Steve Martin role. I think part of the reason I like Martin, is for the same reason I like characters like Bugs Bunny. He always comes out on top, and is usually in complete control of a situation. I love that type of role - who does not want to be more like a Sgt Bilko? I thought almost every scene was funny. I liked pretty much every actor in it. It's not for serious people. I sometimes wonder why serious people bother to rate comedies at all - some people were born with no sense of humor, from what I can tell. For those people who dislike (or are bored of) put down humor, sex humor, or gross out humor, this is none of those (Not that I don't mind some of that, but a change of pace is always welcome.) It's a politer, lighter, silly humor almost cartoonish, in a good way. I have seen this movie at least three times, and still laugh at it. So if you are not a fan of the TV show, I think you will like this in spite of the shockingly low review of this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sergeant Bilko
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    crichton_ius
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK I'm not an American, but in my humble Scottish opinion Steve Martin is not, never has been, and never will be a funny man as long as our posteriors point in a southerly direction. Phil Silvers as Sergeant Bilko was a funny man, no doubt due to the skilled writers and directors and all the other talented team working characters in the series who contributed perfectly to one of the funniest and dateless situation comedies America has ever produced. How anyone could have the audacity to even attempt to replicate the Phil Silvers character is beyond me. To compound things the exercise was repeated in Martin's unfunny attempt to be Peter Seller's Inspector Clouseau, another abortive attempt, in my opinion, to rekindle a demonstrably unfunny career. Some of your contributers say 'Steve Martin puts his own stamp on the character', to that I would say 'balderdash' , his portrayals will be long forgotten when those of Silvers and Sellars will be treasured for generations to come
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A VERY good film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mightyzebra
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have watched a few films with Steve Martin and really enjoyed them all, but this is, so far, my definite favourite. I have not watched the original series of "Sgt. Bilko", but I picked up the idea of this film pretty quickly and I enjoyed almost every minute. The humour is very crazy, similar to cartoon humour, but at the same time it is often very intelligent. I felt many "YES!" moments in this film, lines or scenes where the hilarity, words and or slapstick were just about PERFECT. Not only were the lines and funny scenes mostly very well-written and done, but the characters were memorable and (mostly) relatable and the plot itself was engaging enough, though sometimes a little too farcical. I recommend this film to people who love "mad," but clever humour, people who like Steve Martin and already have an idea of his acting style and to people who like to see a "unique" portrayal of what goes on in the US army (not that it's realistic of course...). Enjoy "Sgt. Bilko"! :-)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Steve Martin At His Best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steve Martin is At His Best in 'Sgt. Bilko'. He delivers a hilarious & lovable performance, that easily is among his finest. And even as a film, 'Sgt. Bilko' is great fun! 'Sgt. Bilko' Synopsis: Bilko runs the motor pool and has all sorts of scams going on like gambling, renting out military vehicles, and so on, which are all violations. 'Sgt. Bilko', an adaptation of the 1950s television series, turns out to be one great cinematic experience. The film is full of comedic moments, that definitely will you in splits. Nat Hiken & Andy Breckman's Screenplay is genuinely funny & very entertaining. Jonathan Lynn's Direction, is perfect. Cinematography, Editing & Art Design, are mention-worthy. Performance-Wise: Martin is the life of the show. He stands out from scene A to Z. Dan Aykroyd is first-rate. Phil Hartman is excellent as the bad-guy. Glenne Headly is wonderfully relaxed. Chris Rock, John Marshall Jones & Pamela Adlon are quite good. Others lend good support. On the whole, 'Sgt. Bilko' is great fun! A Must See for Martin Fanatics!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    After Bathing at Baxter's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A movie starring Steve Martin, Dan Aykroyd and Phil Hartman based on the classic situation comedy has to be hilarious, right? No cigar and not even close. Phil Silvers put a lot of "Phil Silvers" into his "Ernie Bilko" and Mr. Martin wisely substitutes "Steve Martin" manners for his interpretation. This is a smart move on Martin's part, as the two comedians possess a completely different type of energy. However, Martin does not work well with this material, in this situation. Consequently, it falls apart... While certainly no guarantee, it might have been better to star Mr. Hartman attempting a Silvers impersonation. It's relatively interesting to see Cathy Silvers (as Monday) and Chris Rock (as Oster) appear as a genuinely funny team of lieutenants (last saw Ms. Silvers at "Greenblatt's" deli in the 1990s, and she was a delight). Imagine Entertainment's "Bilko" adds likable Daryl Mitchell (as Walter "Wally" Holbrook), but does little with him. The jokes about Fort Baxter's men failing to bathe do not pass the smell test. *** Sgt. Bilko (3/29/96) Jonathan Lynn ~ Steve Martin, Dan Aykroyd, Phil Hartman, Daryl Mitchell
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "What's that music?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ackstasis
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last night, I watched 'Sgt. Bilko (1996)' for the first time in a few years, and was surprised at the number of quotes that have crept their way into my everyday conversation. Just yesterday at the gym, for example, I declared to a struggling friend: "one, we're going for one!"). Directed by Jonathan Lynn, co-creator of the British sitcom "Yes Minister" and its sequel, 'Sgt. Bilko' is a tightly-scripted classic, one of my favourite 90s comedies. The film is a screen adaptation of "The Phil Silvers Show," which ran from 1955 to 1959. I haven't seen the series, so I have no point of comparison, but I would certainly like to at some point. Master Sergeant Ernest G. Bilko (Steve Martin) commands the motor pool at Fort Baxter, but his involvement with the army is in name only. Whenever his bewildered commander (Dan Ackroyd) is looking the other way, Bilko dedicates his not-inconsiderable energies towards gambling and other worthwhile pursuits. He has a girlfriend (Glenne Headly) who is mostly on his wavelength, but who perhaps resents being left at the altar on multiple occasions. When an old nemesis (Phil Hartman) arrives on the base, Bilko finds out that army isn't as leisurely as he'd come to believe. 'Sgt Bilko' moves along at a headlong pace, with Steve Martin cracking one-liners without even drawing a breath ("All I've ever wanted was an honest week's pay for an honest day's work"). Highlights include the most uneventful boxing match in cinematic history ("For three rounds, nobody hit anybody. It was a dance recital"), a surprise inspection of somebody else's barracks ("It is my understanding that you can no longer ask me these questions, sir"), and Bilko's attempt to dissuade his girlfriend from marrying Major Thorn ("Think of the children. You're a Catholic and he's an arsehole, how will you raise them?").
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Steve Martin makes it seem better than it really is.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Realistically, the dubbo's have been the stingiest or most disappointing decade for comedy heroes. I've whinged about this before, but the days of reliable comedy icons monopolising the box office on an annual basis appear over. Consider the 80s and 90s, Eddie Murphy, Steve Martin and Bill Murray, Vs the 00s, Sandler, Ferrell, Stiller, (and I'll throw Carrey in there). Who will history be more kind to? This brings us to Steve Martin, the master of being fake. Fake happy, fake sincere, fake angry, fake remorseful. In Dirty Rotten Scoundrels, LA Story, Little Shop of Horrors, Leap of Faith, My Blue Heaven (underrated) and Bowfinger you always knew Steve was too everything mentioned above, happy, sincere etc but he was always convincing enough in a funny way that set him apart from everyone before or since. I still maintain that Bill Murray and Steve Martin are the two guys I would laugh at regardless of what they were doing, if they were trying to be funny or not. So why have I wasted words telling you what you probably already know? Because if you don't already like Steve Martin there is a 99% chance that you will find Sgt Bilko very underwhelming, as he makes the film his own. Steve is Bilko, a corrupt, conniving, deceitful and untrustworthy soldier in command of the motor pool an the army base Fort Baxter, but he is all those things in the most PG friendly Disney way. I would waste a lot of time describing his mannerisms and what would ordinarily be inane chit chat between he and the officers hell bent on bringing him down, as it is generally not what he says or even how he says it to a point. It is just that he is Steve while he is doing and saying these things, which should be obvious. I just can't imagine Ferrell being Bilko without hamming and getting near naked or Sandler without yelling and trying all the while to be endearing (there is NO-ONE in comedy that wants to be liked more than Sandler, regardless of who he is playing). This leaves Stiller as the logical next up, but I just don't think he has the personality to pull it off. Consider this: Stiller's two best roles, a vain, clueless moron model in Zoolander and a vain, clueless moron actor in Tropic Thunder. Coincidence? Back to Sgt Bilko, you'll have to take my word for this, Sgt Bilko is a paint by numbers Disney comedy that should be pointless. It has cookie cutter characters and situations but again if you like Steve Martin you should get more than a couple of chuckles. Put it this way, about 5 minutes in Bilko asks a superior officer "Have you lost weight?", if that doesn't turn the corners of your mouth up switch off the DVD because that is about as funny as Sgt Bilko gets, and even that is only funny because of Martin's delivery. For some reason that made me laugh, and I laughed often enough to want to see this again in the future at some point. Final Rating  6.5 / 10. Shouldn't work but the presence of Steve Martin adds value to any film and he does enough here to warrant a rental. If you liked this (or even if you didn't) check out oneguyrambling.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dismissed, and it's being considered for a court martial
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now, to be fair, I haven't watched a moment of the original show. I know nothing about the Sergeant. With that said, I can't imagine that this does justice to him. You see, if he was always this unfunny, I cannot imagine that he would be popular. I mean, none of the characters garner a single laugh(they aren't even entirely consistent; early in this, from one scene to the next, one of the leads behave in a manner that directly contradicts everything we've learned about him up to that point), and they are all one-note cardboard cut-outs, but you'd at least expect the dude they titled this after to be worth watching(yes, he is pretty smooth with the ladies, however, that's all; he's not charming). The plot is completely predictable. Gags and jokes are uninspired. OK, we get it, they are undisciplined, fine... if we laugh at it, will you move on? Martin and Aykroyd are hilarious... elsewhere. Tanks aren't that effective in combat anymore; they're slow, useless against the air and too easy to disable. The concept of a type that can hover is a worn-out sci-fi idea. This isn't devoid of positives... Phil Hartman is one, and the other is the great music. I don't know, I suppose this is what you get for hiring the director of Greedy and The Whole Nine Yards. Then again, I do still intend to catch Clue. There is a little moderate to strong language in this. I recommend this to... I don't know, people who like these flicks. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know what's weird? My mom was the biggest Steve Martin fan you would ever meet, she had(what I thought) all of his movies and watched every biography on him. So since she had a lot of his movies, I watched most of them with her. But my boyfriend kept telling me about a film called St. Bilko and how hilarious it was. I was stumped, I couldn't find it in my mom's collection nor did I ever hear of it. So my boyfriend and I went shopping and he found it on DVD, so we went home and watched it. This film just took me back to the classic comedies I grew up with like Trading Places, The Great Outdoors and Planes, Trains and Automobiles. Steve Martin is always a great comedic actor who is a pleasure to watch, same with Dan Aykroyd. While this movie doesn't stand out as well as their other films, this was still a lot of fun to watch. Master Sergeant Ernest G. Bilko is in charge of the motor pool at Fort Baxter, a small US Army base. Exploiting this position, he directs a number of scams ranging from gambling to renting out military vehicles. His commanding officer, Colonel Hall, overlooks Bilko's money making schemes, as he is more concerned with his own affairs. Bad news begins when inspector Major Thorn, Bilko's rival, arrives at the camp and begins to cast scrutiny on Bilko's record. The motivation for Thorn's actions is due to the intense rivalry between the two due to several mishaps in the past, particularly because Thorn's career was ruined due to one of Bilko's scams. Thorn's revenge ensues and ultimately it becomes a battle of wits between the two men. Thorn's reliance on sabotage ultimately leads to his downfall and he is sent to Greenland. Also Bilko's fianc&eacute;e, Rita, whom Bilko has stood up several times at the altar. Bilko is given an ultimatum to win her back within 30 days or to lose her forever. I have to say that I did enjoy St. Bilko, it was great seeing this army crew just goof off and enjoying boot camp. I think my favorite scene was when Bilko has to prove that his crew are hard workers and could complete the obstacle course that the other army recruits could do. Just their reactions of course being as if they've never exercised before in their lives was a good laugh. Steve Martin and his fianc&eacute;e constantly taking a trip up and down the aisle was fun too. Plus this has one of my favorite comedic actors, Phil Hartman, who is again a great watch is always guaranteed to give you a good laugh. While the film may not stand out, this was definitely worth the watch. I would recommend it if you need a good laugh, you're always in good company with Steve Martin, Dan Aykroyd and Phil Hartman, not to mention a baby Chris Rock. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlushingCaps
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I missed this when it came out, and just caught it after one of those free weekends for premium channels. As a long-time fan of Phil Silvers' fabulous series of the 1950s, I was skeptical about this movie, although I usually like Steve Martin's films--especially Planes, Trains, and Automobiles. I thought it was quite true to the spirit of the TV show. I was pleased that it was PG and not full of foul language and other things not fit for children. They didn't try to duplicate everything in the original, merely to present a similar group of characters, with the same names. The plot was not unlike one in the series, but was not a remake of any episode from the series. They had some lines that sounded like they could have come from the series. They had a way to signal "brass coming" so Bilko's men could quickly put away all their gambling devices and make the motor pool look like one--just as the series did, only more elaborate. Col. Hall in the film, just like on TV, acknowledged that Bilko knew more about what was going on, and, in effect, ran the post. Other reviewers have detailed the plot. One highlight for me was the clever way Bilko arranged for his adversary to give himself away after ruining the test of the hover tank, not knowing the machine was not going to work in the first place. That was thinking like the Phil Silvers' version would have done. I agree that Silvers, and Nat Hiken, would be proud that their series was re-created as a feature film 40 years later. It wasn't the funniest movie ever, but it was surely no worse than a "very funny" film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny movie for people who possess a sense of humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (imdb@michaelbauers.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Seems to me like most of the negative votes come from fans of the original show. I am glad I never saw it, because I think this is one of the funniest movies I have ever seen. I love Bilko's character. Martin plays a charismatic, scheming yet kind hearted con artist. I love his comic timing in this movie. It's definitely my favorite Steve Martin role. I think part of the reason I like Martin, is for the same reason I like characters like Bugs Bunny. He always comes out on top, and is usually in complete control of a situation. I love that type of role - who does not want to be more like a Sgt Bilko? I thought almost every scene was funny. I liked pretty much every actor in it. It's not for serious people. I sometimes wonder why serious people bother to rate comedies at all - some people were born with no sense of humor, from what I can tell. For those people who dislike (or are bored of) put down humor, sex humor, or gross out humor, this is none of those (Not that I don't mind some of that, but a change of pace is always welcome.) It's a politer, lighter, silly humor almost cartoonish, in a good way. I have seen this movie at least three times, and still laugh at it. So if you are not a fan of the TV show, I think you will like this in spite of the shockingly low review of this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sergeant Bilko
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    crichton_ius
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK I'm not an American, but in my humble Scottish opinion Steve Martin is not, never has been, and never will be a funny man as long as our posteriors point in a southerly direction. Phil Silvers as Sergeant Bilko was a funny man, no doubt due to the skilled writers and directors and all the other talented team working characters in the series who contributed perfectly to one of the funniest and dateless situation comedies America has ever produced. How anyone could have the audacity to even attempt to replicate the Phil Silvers character is beyond me. To compound things the exercise was repeated in Martin's unfunny attempt to be Peter Seller's Inspector Clouseau, another abortive attempt, in my opinion, to rekindle a demonstrably unfunny career. Some of your contributers say 'Steve Martin puts his own stamp on the character', to that I would say 'balderdash' , his portrayals will be long forgotten when those of Silvers and Sellars will be treasured for generations to come
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
