<filme>
 <id>
  1053
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0114011
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Agora e Sempre
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Four 12-year-old girls grow up together during an eventful small-town summer in 1970.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Four childhood friends gather together to prepare for the birth of Chrissey's baby. While together, they reminisce about when they were kids in 1970.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   1970s
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   summer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   small town
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   12 year old
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   childhood friend
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Lesli Linka Glatter
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   I. Marlene King
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Christina Ricci
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Demi Moore
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Rosie O'Donnell
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent and clean
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mere Humsafar
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you watch this 1995 movie in 2012, you wish all children grow up in small towns with the simplicity and innocence that comes with it.. it has its own share of maturity, " it is normal when things are shitty ".. the movie shows that real understanding can lead to a life-long friendship among four characteristically different kids..one having a tragic past, another having quarrelling parents, yet another being given unreal sex education by an embarrassed, yet caring mother.. The kids have done excellent acting.. the pace is smooth.. the biggest lesson comes from from a mysterious man who visits a particular grave in a cemetery.. A must-see for all parents and also for all children who want to avoid loneliness
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    angelawang
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Now And Then' is about a group of women who return to their old treehouse and reminisce about the one summer that truly changed their lives... With an all star cast, 'Now And Then' features Melanie Griffith, Demi Moore, Rita Wilson and Rosie O'Donnell, with Thora Birch, Gaby Hoffman, Ashleigh Aston Moore and Christina Ricci playing their younger counterparts. Teen star Christina Ricci ('Casper', 'The Adams Family') is great - as is Ricci's 'Gold Diggers' co-star, Ashleigh Aston Moore - as the mis-informed Chrissy. Bonnie Hunt ('Jumangi') and Devon Sawa ('Wild America') also star. The story is great - plenty of laughs to be had here, with sad moments, too. The acting is A-Grade (the young girls look very promising) and the finished product is a film all the cast should be proud of.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Can be a nostalgic flick for girls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching this reminded me of the Korean movie "Sunny" although this came out first. Well it wouldn't be a shock if the director of "Sunny" was influenced by this movie. The dialogue however didn't seem as natural sometimes and seemed like watching some southern novel that isn't really down to earth. It just didn't seem like what a group of women would be saying to each other, but than again the story switches back from the 70's to 90's when it comes to the characters. The dialogue just seemed too safe to be natural despite the sexual stuff and it's a girly movie. Since the 4 main character are 4 girls in the 70's and women in the 90's. Anyways the story is about 4 women getting together after spending there childhood together and reminisce of the past and adventures they had together. Although most of it takes place during a summer. Now I am not a fan of Rosie O'Donnell, to be honest I think she is irritating to watch sometimes. Her character is like the main character or leader of the pack and I thought it was ridiculous her younger version would be played by Christina Ricci. Not that I am a fan of Ricci either, but the comparison is too big to the point you can get confused who is who sometimes when it comes to the younger version with the older version or visa versa. So yeah I don't know if Rosie picked her younger version but it's just absurd. Overall this is a touching movie that most girls and maybe some boys will probably enjoy watching and parents will probably enjoy it as well. It really does give off a nostalgic feel because of the friendship, even if you didn't go through the same things the girls did in the movie. I give this movie a 6.8 because the development of the characters aren't done all that great and somethings are not explained and not for good reasons. Some say this is a female version of "Stand By Me" and I agree to certain extent. 6.8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    aging world
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Now and Then" isn't really anything that I would recommend. It's about some women reminiscing about what happened in their lives in summer 1970. The truly interesting subplot was their search for the story of the deceased boy, but the whole movie came across as contrived. "Stand by Me" was similar but much grittier. This movie isn't terrible, but I just got the feeling that there wasn't much to it. Maybe I like it too much when movies contain a lot of historical context, and so I kept waiting for "Now and Then" to depict the Vietnam War on TV. Anyway, all the cast members have done much better roles. To be certain, Thora Birch co-starred in "American Beauty" a few years after this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doctorjagger
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is horrible all over. It is compared to "Stand By Me". That movie is a classic. This one does not even come close to measuring up to SBM. Some say this is an inspirational movie for young girls. Just so you know, they are wrong! If you're a parent do not show this to your child. It promotes sexism in the worst ways. The girls as children are all persecuted by boys. This is taken to the absolute extreme. This is not like real life. Every interaction with the boys these girls have they act as if they are being attacked. In response they proceed to become violent physically, verbally, and by their actions. This is a horrible movie and a bad influence. 0/10. Do not watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, But Not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    NotPavlovsDog
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just recently watched "Now and Then" again, I decided to check out what other people thought. Reading through a lot of the comments, I noticed that many compared this film to Rob Reiner's "Stand By Me." I guess I would consider the two to be of the same genre (coming of age), but, to me, that's really the only thing the two have in common. "Now and Then" is a fun film. It's got quick and easy laughs that many (not just teenage girls) people will find humorous. I will say that "Then" is vastly more entertaining than "Now"; the adult versions of the characters briefly open and close the story, with forgettable filler in between. "Then" offers some slight depth of character for the four girls who embody stereotypes of adolescent girls (the princess, the tomboy, the sheltered one, the seemingly normal one). "Now" still embraces those stereotypes (the princess has become an actress, still obsessed with body image; the normal one has become a writer, who showcases her intellect by wearing black and smoking). There is no growth amongst the adults. "Now" is focused on Chrissy's pregnancy and reminiscing, while "Then" seems to get distracted amongst its various subplots (unraveling Crazy Pete, watching parents fight, bicker with boys, watch movies, build a tree house, ride bikes) without ever really coming to a true conclusion. For a movie hailed as a "Stand By Me" for girls, the film is lacking in its overall sincerity. Whereas Reiner's film grapples (and in some cases overcomes) 'mature' themes like death, acceptance, and separation, Glatter's film skates over the big issues. "Stand By Me" captures true childhood friendship (friends help friends get leeches off their backs) "Now and Then" is only truly poignant, well, now and then. I'd recommend "Now and Then" for a time when you are in the mood for something lighthearted and distracting. I'd second the opinion that it's great for a girl's sleepover or something. But if you are looking for something a little deeper and, in my opinion, more true to childhood friendship, I'd tell you to skip this movie and go straight to "Stand By Me." Note: "Stand By Me" is rated R; "Now and Then" PG-13. Both films have great soundtracks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sloppy Production Values and Continuity, BAD Acting from the Adults
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deetdee12
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, all 4 younger actresses are quite engaging, likable and amazingly unaffected---they can even almost sell me on the "Stand by Me" plot rip off (or what passes for a plot). I don't mind sweet, small town retro (that never really existed) and I am a feminist, so girl power is fine by me. BUT...it still doesn't cut it. For starters, all the homes exteriors are unquestionably mid-80's/90's style homes. EVERY house should have been a split level or a ranch (I grew up in exactly that type of sub division). While the interiors are overall more accurate,. houses that small wouldn't possibly have such large interior rooms. Teeny's room has painted art deco furniture---fashionable in 1995, NOT 1970 (and Teeny appears to be the wealthiest of the group). Really, couldn't they have borrowed "The Wonder Years" set? The other thing is the truly, utterly horrible acting from the adults. Rita Wilson portrays Chrissy as fully mentally unbalanced. Keeps her home exactly the way her mother had it decorated??? Races around like a shrill harpy??? I kept waiting for someone in a white coat with a net to come and take her away. Yes, she could be nerdy and traditional--that doesn't equal totally crazy. Since they're also all 37 now, it doesn't hold water on that level (they all still act twelve, with apologies to 12 year old). Unless she had serious fertility problems, Chrissy would have wanted to get pregnant the second she got married. Athletic, cute Christina Ricci turns into fat, ugly Rosie O'Donnnel??? And Melanie Griffith (more like 18 in 1970) is already far too old, and simply horrible. In all, if nothing else is on, watch it. But it isn't even fun in a campy way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Used to Like It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dmills9
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was a teen I loved this film. I thought it was great. I don't know what I was thinking. Although the acting is fine, there are so many off elements here that I can't believe I sat through the whole thing. For one thing, I would not let my teenager watch this. Their focus on sex is astounding for a group of 4 twelve year olds. Yuck! This is sooo disturbing to me. I assume that when I was a teen and that was on my mind constantly I was relating to them and their curiosity, but that also would have caused me to think of those things even more, which is (I'm sure) not what any parent wants for their child. There are also the regular profane outbursts by one particular child, the fights and more that promote a way of life that is not desirable for children and that I cannot be entertained by them acting it out. If you are going to watch this, please leave the kids out of it. You don't want them molded into this 'cool' persona.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A comedy for the ages
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danmax
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film. Well, let's be honest, I will love any movie with Roseanne. Add Demi "Mrs. Kutcher" Moore, Melanie "Mrs. Banderas" Griffith, and you will just have a bang. The story goes back and forth between now and then, and it is a testament of the power of female friendship. The heroes, or maybe I should call them She-roes, are able to stand by each other through thick and thin. I know that some men cried (not me, but i know for a fact that my friend Derek went through a full box of Kleenex watching this lovely film). There are my two cents. Girls kick a**. Forever. Definitely. See you next time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not incredibly memorable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Would be "Stand by Me" for the girls, about growing up and making lasting friendships. The plot from I. Marlene King (a semi-autobiographical piece) has little substance and never really manages to captivate, reducing the target audience to teen girls twelve to sixteen years of age. Director Lesli Linka Glatter's film is almost entirely about "Then" and rarely covers "Now". Top line stars Demi Moore, Melanie Griffith and Rosie O'Donnel are wasted completely, playing less than a handful of paltry scenes. Whatever Miss Glatter was trying to create, she fails to make "Now and Then" into anything incredibly memorable. All pic. contains is a few light hearted adventures of four girls' discovery that they are on the verge of womanhood during the summer of 1970. Christina Ricci, Gaby Hoffman, Thora Birch and Ashleigh Aston Moore (the girls in question) do a reasonable job, but stars Hoffman and Ricci need to be challenged with meatier roles. Average film over all. Saturday, March 30, 1996 - Knox District Centre
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent and clean
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mere Humsafar
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you watch this 1995 movie in 2012, you wish all children grow up in small towns with the simplicity and innocence that comes with it.. it has its own share of maturity, " it is normal when things are shitty ".. the movie shows that real understanding can lead to a life-long friendship among four characteristically different kids..one having a tragic past, another having quarrelling parents, yet another being given unreal sex education by an embarrassed, yet caring mother.. The kids have done excellent acting.. the pace is smooth.. the biggest lesson comes from from a mysterious man who visits a particular grave in a cemetery.. A must-see for all parents and also for all children who want to avoid loneliness
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    angelawang
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Now And Then' is about a group of women who return to their old treehouse and reminisce about the one summer that truly changed their lives... With an all star cast, 'Now And Then' features Melanie Griffith, Demi Moore, Rita Wilson and Rosie O'Donnell, with Thora Birch, Gaby Hoffman, Ashleigh Aston Moore and Christina Ricci playing their younger counterparts. Teen star Christina Ricci ('Casper', 'The Adams Family') is great - as is Ricci's 'Gold Diggers' co-star, Ashleigh Aston Moore - as the mis-informed Chrissy. Bonnie Hunt ('Jumangi') and Devon Sawa ('Wild America') also star. The story is great - plenty of laughs to be had here, with sad moments, too. The acting is A-Grade (the young girls look very promising) and the finished product is a film all the cast should be proud of.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Can be a nostalgic flick for girls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching this reminded me of the Korean movie "Sunny" although this came out first. Well it wouldn't be a shock if the director of "Sunny" was influenced by this movie. The dialogue however didn't seem as natural sometimes and seemed like watching some southern novel that isn't really down to earth. It just didn't seem like what a group of women would be saying to each other, but than again the story switches back from the 70's to 90's when it comes to the characters. The dialogue just seemed too safe to be natural despite the sexual stuff and it's a girly movie. Since the 4 main character are 4 girls in the 70's and women in the 90's. Anyways the story is about 4 women getting together after spending there childhood together and reminisce of the past and adventures they had together. Although most of it takes place during a summer. Now I am not a fan of Rosie O'Donnell, to be honest I think she is irritating to watch sometimes. Her character is like the main character or leader of the pack and I thought it was ridiculous her younger version would be played by Christina Ricci. Not that I am a fan of Ricci either, but the comparison is too big to the point you can get confused who is who sometimes when it comes to the younger version with the older version or visa versa. So yeah I don't know if Rosie picked her younger version but it's just absurd. Overall this is a touching movie that most girls and maybe some boys will probably enjoy watching and parents will probably enjoy it as well. It really does give off a nostalgic feel because of the friendship, even if you didn't go through the same things the girls did in the movie. I give this movie a 6.8 because the development of the characters aren't done all that great and somethings are not explained and not for good reasons. Some say this is a female version of "Stand By Me" and I agree to certain extent. 6.8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    aging world
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Now and Then" isn't really anything that I would recommend. It's about some women reminiscing about what happened in their lives in summer 1970. The truly interesting subplot was their search for the story of the deceased boy, but the whole movie came across as contrived. "Stand by Me" was similar but much grittier. This movie isn't terrible, but I just got the feeling that there wasn't much to it. Maybe I like it too much when movies contain a lot of historical context, and so I kept waiting for "Now and Then" to depict the Vietnam War on TV. Anyway, all the cast members have done much better roles. To be certain, Thora Birch co-starred in "American Beauty" a few years after this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doctorjagger
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is horrible all over. It is compared to "Stand By Me". That movie is a classic. This one does not even come close to measuring up to SBM. Some say this is an inspirational movie for young girls. Just so you know, they are wrong! If you're a parent do not show this to your child. It promotes sexism in the worst ways. The girls as children are all persecuted by boys. This is taken to the absolute extreme. This is not like real life. Every interaction with the boys these girls have they act as if they are being attacked. In response they proceed to become violent physically, verbally, and by their actions. This is a horrible movie and a bad influence. 0/10. Do not watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, But Not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    NotPavlovsDog
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just recently watched "Now and Then" again, I decided to check out what other people thought. Reading through a lot of the comments, I noticed that many compared this film to Rob Reiner's "Stand By Me." I guess I would consider the two to be of the same genre (coming of age), but, to me, that's really the only thing the two have in common. "Now and Then" is a fun film. It's got quick and easy laughs that many (not just teenage girls) people will find humorous. I will say that "Then" is vastly more entertaining than "Now"; the adult versions of the characters briefly open and close the story, with forgettable filler in between. "Then" offers some slight depth of character for the four girls who embody stereotypes of adolescent girls (the princess, the tomboy, the sheltered one, the seemingly normal one). "Now" still embraces those stereotypes (the princess has become an actress, still obsessed with body image; the normal one has become a writer, who showcases her intellect by wearing black and smoking). There is no growth amongst the adults. "Now" is focused on Chrissy's pregnancy and reminiscing, while "Then" seems to get distracted amongst its various subplots (unraveling Crazy Pete, watching parents fight, bicker with boys, watch movies, build a tree house, ride bikes) without ever really coming to a true conclusion. For a movie hailed as a "Stand By Me" for girls, the film is lacking in its overall sincerity. Whereas Reiner's film grapples (and in some cases overcomes) 'mature' themes like death, acceptance, and separation, Glatter's film skates over the big issues. "Stand By Me" captures true childhood friendship (friends help friends get leeches off their backs) "Now and Then" is only truly poignant, well, now and then. I'd recommend "Now and Then" for a time when you are in the mood for something lighthearted and distracting. I'd second the opinion that it's great for a girl's sleepover or something. But if you are looking for something a little deeper and, in my opinion, more true to childhood friendship, I'd tell you to skip this movie and go straight to "Stand By Me." Note: "Stand By Me" is rated R; "Now and Then" PG-13. Both films have great soundtracks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sloppy Production Values and Continuity, BAD Acting from the Adults
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deetdee12
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, all 4 younger actresses are quite engaging, likable and amazingly unaffected---they can even almost sell me on the "Stand by Me" plot rip off (or what passes for a plot). I don't mind sweet, small town retro (that never really existed) and I am a feminist, so girl power is fine by me. BUT...it still doesn't cut it. For starters, all the homes exteriors are unquestionably mid-80's/90's style homes. EVERY house should have been a split level or a ranch (I grew up in exactly that type of sub division). While the interiors are overall more accurate,. houses that small wouldn't possibly have such large interior rooms. Teeny's room has painted art deco furniture---fashionable in 1995, NOT 1970 (and Teeny appears to be the wealthiest of the group). Really, couldn't they have borrowed "The Wonder Years" set? The other thing is the truly, utterly horrible acting from the adults. Rita Wilson portrays Chrissy as fully mentally unbalanced. Keeps her home exactly the way her mother had it decorated??? Races around like a shrill harpy??? I kept waiting for someone in a white coat with a net to come and take her away. Yes, she could be nerdy and traditional--that doesn't equal totally crazy. Since they're also all 37 now, it doesn't hold water on that level (they all still act twelve, with apologies to 12 year old). Unless she had serious fertility problems, Chrissy would have wanted to get pregnant the second she got married. Athletic, cute Christina Ricci turns into fat, ugly Rosie O'Donnnel??? And Melanie Griffith (more like 18 in 1970) is already far too old, and simply horrible. In all, if nothing else is on, watch it. But it isn't even fun in a campy way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Used to Like It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dmills9
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was a teen I loved this film. I thought it was great. I don't know what I was thinking. Although the acting is fine, there are so many off elements here that I can't believe I sat through the whole thing. For one thing, I would not let my teenager watch this. Their focus on sex is astounding for a group of 4 twelve year olds. Yuck! This is sooo disturbing to me. I assume that when I was a teen and that was on my mind constantly I was relating to them and their curiosity, but that also would have caused me to think of those things even more, which is (I'm sure) not what any parent wants for their child. There are also the regular profane outbursts by one particular child, the fights and more that promote a way of life that is not desirable for children and that I cannot be entertained by them acting it out. If you are going to watch this, please leave the kids out of it. You don't want them molded into this 'cool' persona.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A comedy for the ages
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danmax
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film. Well, let's be honest, I will love any movie with Roseanne. Add Demi "Mrs. Kutcher" Moore, Melanie "Mrs. Banderas" Griffith, and you will just have a bang. The story goes back and forth between now and then, and it is a testament of the power of female friendship. The heroes, or maybe I should call them She-roes, are able to stand by each other through thick and thin. I know that some men cried (not me, but i know for a fact that my friend Derek went through a full box of Kleenex watching this lovely film). There are my two cents. Girls kick a**. Forever. Definitely. See you next time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not incredibly memorable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Would be "Stand by Me" for the girls, about growing up and making lasting friendships. The plot from I. Marlene King (a semi-autobiographical piece) has little substance and never really manages to captivate, reducing the target audience to teen girls twelve to sixteen years of age. Director Lesli Linka Glatter's film is almost entirely about "Then" and rarely covers "Now". Top line stars Demi Moore, Melanie Griffith and Rosie O'Donnel are wasted completely, playing less than a handful of paltry scenes. Whatever Miss Glatter was trying to create, she fails to make "Now and Then" into anything incredibly memorable. All pic. contains is a few light hearted adventures of four girls' discovery that they are on the verge of womanhood during the summer of 1970. Christina Ricci, Gaby Hoffman, Thora Birch and Ashleigh Aston Moore (the girls in question) do a reasonable job, but stars Hoffman and Ricci need to be challenged with meatier roles. Average film over all. Saturday, March 30, 1996 - Knox District Centre
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent and clean
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mere Humsafar
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you watch this 1995 movie in 2012, you wish all children grow up in small towns with the simplicity and innocence that comes with it.. it has its own share of maturity, " it is normal when things are shitty ".. the movie shows that real understanding can lead to a life-long friendship among four characteristically different kids..one having a tragic past, another having quarrelling parents, yet another being given unreal sex education by an embarrassed, yet caring mother.. The kids have done excellent acting.. the pace is smooth.. the biggest lesson comes from from a mysterious man who visits a particular grave in a cemetery.. A must-see for all parents and also for all children who want to avoid loneliness
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    angelawang
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Now And Then' is about a group of women who return to their old treehouse and reminisce about the one summer that truly changed their lives... With an all star cast, 'Now And Then' features Melanie Griffith, Demi Moore, Rita Wilson and Rosie O'Donnell, with Thora Birch, Gaby Hoffman, Ashleigh Aston Moore and Christina Ricci playing their younger counterparts. Teen star Christina Ricci ('Casper', 'The Adams Family') is great - as is Ricci's 'Gold Diggers' co-star, Ashleigh Aston Moore - as the mis-informed Chrissy. Bonnie Hunt ('Jumangi') and Devon Sawa ('Wild America') also star. The story is great - plenty of laughs to be had here, with sad moments, too. The acting is A-Grade (the young girls look very promising) and the finished product is a film all the cast should be proud of.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Can be a nostalgic flick for girls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching this reminded me of the Korean movie "Sunny" although this came out first. Well it wouldn't be a shock if the director of "Sunny" was influenced by this movie. The dialogue however didn't seem as natural sometimes and seemed like watching some southern novel that isn't really down to earth. It just didn't seem like what a group of women would be saying to each other, but than again the story switches back from the 70's to 90's when it comes to the characters. The dialogue just seemed too safe to be natural despite the sexual stuff and it's a girly movie. Since the 4 main character are 4 girls in the 70's and women in the 90's. Anyways the story is about 4 women getting together after spending there childhood together and reminisce of the past and adventures they had together. Although most of it takes place during a summer. Now I am not a fan of Rosie O'Donnell, to be honest I think she is irritating to watch sometimes. Her character is like the main character or leader of the pack and I thought it was ridiculous her younger version would be played by Christina Ricci. Not that I am a fan of Ricci either, but the comparison is too big to the point you can get confused who is who sometimes when it comes to the younger version with the older version or visa versa. So yeah I don't know if Rosie picked her younger version but it's just absurd. Overall this is a touching movie that most girls and maybe some boys will probably enjoy watching and parents will probably enjoy it as well. It really does give off a nostalgic feel because of the friendship, even if you didn't go through the same things the girls did in the movie. I give this movie a 6.8 because the development of the characters aren't done all that great and somethings are not explained and not for good reasons. Some say this is a female version of "Stand By Me" and I agree to certain extent. 6.8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    aging world
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Now and Then" isn't really anything that I would recommend. It's about some women reminiscing about what happened in their lives in summer 1970. The truly interesting subplot was their search for the story of the deceased boy, but the whole movie came across as contrived. "Stand by Me" was similar but much grittier. This movie isn't terrible, but I just got the feeling that there wasn't much to it. Maybe I like it too much when movies contain a lot of historical context, and so I kept waiting for "Now and Then" to depict the Vietnam War on TV. Anyway, all the cast members have done much better roles. To be certain, Thora Birch co-starred in "American Beauty" a few years after this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doctorjagger
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is horrible all over. It is compared to "Stand By Me". That movie is a classic. This one does not even come close to measuring up to SBM. Some say this is an inspirational movie for young girls. Just so you know, they are wrong! If you're a parent do not show this to your child. It promotes sexism in the worst ways. The girls as children are all persecuted by boys. This is taken to the absolute extreme. This is not like real life. Every interaction with the boys these girls have they act as if they are being attacked. In response they proceed to become violent physically, verbally, and by their actions. This is a horrible movie and a bad influence. 0/10. Do not watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, But Not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    NotPavlovsDog
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just recently watched "Now and Then" again, I decided to check out what other people thought. Reading through a lot of the comments, I noticed that many compared this film to Rob Reiner's "Stand By Me." I guess I would consider the two to be of the same genre (coming of age), but, to me, that's really the only thing the two have in common. "Now and Then" is a fun film. It's got quick and easy laughs that many (not just teenage girls) people will find humorous. I will say that "Then" is vastly more entertaining than "Now"; the adult versions of the characters briefly open and close the story, with forgettable filler in between. "Then" offers some slight depth of character for the four girls who embody stereotypes of adolescent girls (the princess, the tomboy, the sheltered one, the seemingly normal one). "Now" still embraces those stereotypes (the princess has become an actress, still obsessed with body image; the normal one has become a writer, who showcases her intellect by wearing black and smoking). There is no growth amongst the adults. "Now" is focused on Chrissy's pregnancy and reminiscing, while "Then" seems to get distracted amongst its various subplots (unraveling Crazy Pete, watching parents fight, bicker with boys, watch movies, build a tree house, ride bikes) without ever really coming to a true conclusion. For a movie hailed as a "Stand By Me" for girls, the film is lacking in its overall sincerity. Whereas Reiner's film grapples (and in some cases overcomes) 'mature' themes like death, acceptance, and separation, Glatter's film skates over the big issues. "Stand By Me" captures true childhood friendship (friends help friends get leeches off their backs) "Now and Then" is only truly poignant, well, now and then. I'd recommend "Now and Then" for a time when you are in the mood for something lighthearted and distracting. I'd second the opinion that it's great for a girl's sleepover or something. But if you are looking for something a little deeper and, in my opinion, more true to childhood friendship, I'd tell you to skip this movie and go straight to "Stand By Me." Note: "Stand By Me" is rated R; "Now and Then" PG-13. Both films have great soundtracks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sloppy Production Values and Continuity, BAD Acting from the Adults
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deetdee12
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, all 4 younger actresses are quite engaging, likable and amazingly unaffected---they can even almost sell me on the "Stand by Me" plot rip off (or what passes for a plot). I don't mind sweet, small town retro (that never really existed) and I am a feminist, so girl power is fine by me. BUT...it still doesn't cut it. For starters, all the homes exteriors are unquestionably mid-80's/90's style homes. EVERY house should have been a split level or a ranch (I grew up in exactly that type of sub division). While the interiors are overall more accurate,. houses that small wouldn't possibly have such large interior rooms. Teeny's room has painted art deco furniture---fashionable in 1995, NOT 1970 (and Teeny appears to be the wealthiest of the group). Really, couldn't they have borrowed "The Wonder Years" set? The other thing is the truly, utterly horrible acting from the adults. Rita Wilson portrays Chrissy as fully mentally unbalanced. Keeps her home exactly the way her mother had it decorated??? Races around like a shrill harpy??? I kept waiting for someone in a white coat with a net to come and take her away. Yes, she could be nerdy and traditional--that doesn't equal totally crazy. Since they're also all 37 now, it doesn't hold water on that level (they all still act twelve, with apologies to 12 year old). Unless she had serious fertility problems, Chrissy would have wanted to get pregnant the second she got married. Athletic, cute Christina Ricci turns into fat, ugly Rosie O'Donnnel??? And Melanie Griffith (more like 18 in 1970) is already far too old, and simply horrible. In all, if nothing else is on, watch it. But it isn't even fun in a campy way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Used to Like It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dmills9
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was a teen I loved this film. I thought it was great. I don't know what I was thinking. Although the acting is fine, there are so many off elements here that I can't believe I sat through the whole thing. For one thing, I would not let my teenager watch this. Their focus on sex is astounding for a group of 4 twelve year olds. Yuck! This is sooo disturbing to me. I assume that when I was a teen and that was on my mind constantly I was relating to them and their curiosity, but that also would have caused me to think of those things even more, which is (I'm sure) not what any parent wants for their child. There are also the regular profane outbursts by one particular child, the fights and more that promote a way of life that is not desirable for children and that I cannot be entertained by them acting it out. If you are going to watch this, please leave the kids out of it. You don't want them molded into this 'cool' persona.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A comedy for the ages
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danmax
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film. Well, let's be honest, I will love any movie with Roseanne. Add Demi "Mrs. Kutcher" Moore, Melanie "Mrs. Banderas" Griffith, and you will just have a bang. The story goes back and forth between now and then, and it is a testament of the power of female friendship. The heroes, or maybe I should call them She-roes, are able to stand by each other through thick and thin. I know that some men cried (not me, but i know for a fact that my friend Derek went through a full box of Kleenex watching this lovely film). There are my two cents. Girls kick a**. Forever. Definitely. See you next time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not incredibly memorable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Would be "Stand by Me" for the girls, about growing up and making lasting friendships. The plot from I. Marlene King (a semi-autobiographical piece) has little substance and never really manages to captivate, reducing the target audience to teen girls twelve to sixteen years of age. Director Lesli Linka Glatter's film is almost entirely about "Then" and rarely covers "Now". Top line stars Demi Moore, Melanie Griffith and Rosie O'Donnel are wasted completely, playing less than a handful of paltry scenes. Whatever Miss Glatter was trying to create, she fails to make "Now and Then" into anything incredibly memorable. All pic. contains is a few light hearted adventures of four girls' discovery that they are on the verge of womanhood during the summer of 1970. Christina Ricci, Gaby Hoffman, Thora Birch and Ashleigh Aston Moore (the girls in question) do a reasonable job, but stars Hoffman and Ricci need to be challenged with meatier roles. Average film over all. Saturday, March 30, 1996 - Knox District Centre
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent and clean
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mere Humsafar
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you watch this 1995 movie in 2012, you wish all children grow up in small towns with the simplicity and innocence that comes with it.. it has its own share of maturity, " it is normal when things are shitty ".. the movie shows that real understanding can lead to a life-long friendship among four characteristically different kids..one having a tragic past, another having quarrelling parents, yet another being given unreal sex education by an embarrassed, yet caring mother.. The kids have done excellent acting.. the pace is smooth.. the biggest lesson comes from from a mysterious man who visits a particular grave in a cemetery.. A must-see for all parents and also for all children who want to avoid loneliness
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    angelawang
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Now And Then' is about a group of women who return to their old treehouse and reminisce about the one summer that truly changed their lives... With an all star cast, 'Now And Then' features Melanie Griffith, Demi Moore, Rita Wilson and Rosie O'Donnell, with Thora Birch, Gaby Hoffman, Ashleigh Aston Moore and Christina Ricci playing their younger counterparts. Teen star Christina Ricci ('Casper', 'The Adams Family') is great - as is Ricci's 'Gold Diggers' co-star, Ashleigh Aston Moore - as the mis-informed Chrissy. Bonnie Hunt ('Jumangi') and Devon Sawa ('Wild America') also star. The story is great - plenty of laughs to be had here, with sad moments, too. The acting is A-Grade (the young girls look very promising) and the finished product is a film all the cast should be proud of.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Can be a nostalgic flick for girls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching this reminded me of the Korean movie "Sunny" although this came out first. Well it wouldn't be a shock if the director of "Sunny" was influenced by this movie. The dialogue however didn't seem as natural sometimes and seemed like watching some southern novel that isn't really down to earth. It just didn't seem like what a group of women would be saying to each other, but than again the story switches back from the 70's to 90's when it comes to the characters. The dialogue just seemed too safe to be natural despite the sexual stuff and it's a girly movie. Since the 4 main character are 4 girls in the 70's and women in the 90's. Anyways the story is about 4 women getting together after spending there childhood together and reminisce of the past and adventures they had together. Although most of it takes place during a summer. Now I am not a fan of Rosie O'Donnell, to be honest I think she is irritating to watch sometimes. Her character is like the main character or leader of the pack and I thought it was ridiculous her younger version would be played by Christina Ricci. Not that I am a fan of Ricci either, but the comparison is too big to the point you can get confused who is who sometimes when it comes to the younger version with the older version or visa versa. So yeah I don't know if Rosie picked her younger version but it's just absurd. Overall this is a touching movie that most girls and maybe some boys will probably enjoy watching and parents will probably enjoy it as well. It really does give off a nostalgic feel because of the friendship, even if you didn't go through the same things the girls did in the movie. I give this movie a 6.8 because the development of the characters aren't done all that great and somethings are not explained and not for good reasons. Some say this is a female version of "Stand By Me" and I agree to certain extent. 6.8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    aging world
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Now and Then" isn't really anything that I would recommend. It's about some women reminiscing about what happened in their lives in summer 1970. The truly interesting subplot was their search for the story of the deceased boy, but the whole movie came across as contrived. "Stand by Me" was similar but much grittier. This movie isn't terrible, but I just got the feeling that there wasn't much to it. Maybe I like it too much when movies contain a lot of historical context, and so I kept waiting for "Now and Then" to depict the Vietnam War on TV. Anyway, all the cast members have done much better roles. To be certain, Thora Birch co-starred in "American Beauty" a few years after this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doctorjagger
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is horrible all over. It is compared to "Stand By Me". That movie is a classic. This one does not even come close to measuring up to SBM. Some say this is an inspirational movie for young girls. Just so you know, they are wrong! If you're a parent do not show this to your child. It promotes sexism in the worst ways. The girls as children are all persecuted by boys. This is taken to the absolute extreme. This is not like real life. Every interaction with the boys these girls have they act as if they are being attacked. In response they proceed to become violent physically, verbally, and by their actions. This is a horrible movie and a bad influence. 0/10. Do not watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, But Not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    NotPavlovsDog
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just recently watched "Now and Then" again, I decided to check out what other people thought. Reading through a lot of the comments, I noticed that many compared this film to Rob Reiner's "Stand By Me." I guess I would consider the two to be of the same genre (coming of age), but, to me, that's really the only thing the two have in common. "Now and Then" is a fun film. It's got quick and easy laughs that many (not just teenage girls) people will find humorous. I will say that "Then" is vastly more entertaining than "Now"; the adult versions of the characters briefly open and close the story, with forgettable filler in between. "Then" offers some slight depth of character for the four girls who embody stereotypes of adolescent girls (the princess, the tomboy, the sheltered one, the seemingly normal one). "Now" still embraces those stereotypes (the princess has become an actress, still obsessed with body image; the normal one has become a writer, who showcases her intellect by wearing black and smoking). There is no growth amongst the adults. "Now" is focused on Chrissy's pregnancy and reminiscing, while "Then" seems to get distracted amongst its various subplots (unraveling Crazy Pete, watching parents fight, bicker with boys, watch movies, build a tree house, ride bikes) without ever really coming to a true conclusion. For a movie hailed as a "Stand By Me" for girls, the film is lacking in its overall sincerity. Whereas Reiner's film grapples (and in some cases overcomes) 'mature' themes like death, acceptance, and separation, Glatter's film skates over the big issues. "Stand By Me" captures true childhood friendship (friends help friends get leeches off their backs) "Now and Then" is only truly poignant, well, now and then. I'd recommend "Now and Then" for a time when you are in the mood for something lighthearted and distracting. I'd second the opinion that it's great for a girl's sleepover or something. But if you are looking for something a little deeper and, in my opinion, more true to childhood friendship, I'd tell you to skip this movie and go straight to "Stand By Me." Note: "Stand By Me" is rated R; "Now and Then" PG-13. Both films have great soundtracks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sloppy Production Values and Continuity, BAD Acting from the Adults
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deetdee12
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, all 4 younger actresses are quite engaging, likable and amazingly unaffected---they can even almost sell me on the "Stand by Me" plot rip off (or what passes for a plot). I don't mind sweet, small town retro (that never really existed) and I am a feminist, so girl power is fine by me. BUT...it still doesn't cut it. For starters, all the homes exteriors are unquestionably mid-80's/90's style homes. EVERY house should have been a split level or a ranch (I grew up in exactly that type of sub division). While the interiors are overall more accurate,. houses that small wouldn't possibly have such large interior rooms. Teeny's room has painted art deco furniture---fashionable in 1995, NOT 1970 (and Teeny appears to be the wealthiest of the group). Really, couldn't they have borrowed "The Wonder Years" set? The other thing is the truly, utterly horrible acting from the adults. Rita Wilson portrays Chrissy as fully mentally unbalanced. Keeps her home exactly the way her mother had it decorated??? Races around like a shrill harpy??? I kept waiting for someone in a white coat with a net to come and take her away. Yes, she could be nerdy and traditional--that doesn't equal totally crazy. Since they're also all 37 now, it doesn't hold water on that level (they all still act twelve, with apologies to 12 year old). Unless she had serious fertility problems, Chrissy would have wanted to get pregnant the second she got married. Athletic, cute Christina Ricci turns into fat, ugly Rosie O'Donnnel??? And Melanie Griffith (more like 18 in 1970) is already far too old, and simply horrible. In all, if nothing else is on, watch it. But it isn't even fun in a campy way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Used to Like It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dmills9
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was a teen I loved this film. I thought it was great. I don't know what I was thinking. Although the acting is fine, there are so many off elements here that I can't believe I sat through the whole thing. For one thing, I would not let my teenager watch this. Their focus on sex is astounding for a group of 4 twelve year olds. Yuck! This is sooo disturbing to me. I assume that when I was a teen and that was on my mind constantly I was relating to them and their curiosity, but that also would have caused me to think of those things even more, which is (I'm sure) not what any parent wants for their child. There are also the regular profane outbursts by one particular child, the fights and more that promote a way of life that is not desirable for children and that I cannot be entertained by them acting it out. If you are going to watch this, please leave the kids out of it. You don't want them molded into this 'cool' persona.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A comedy for the ages
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danmax
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film. Well, let's be honest, I will love any movie with Roseanne. Add Demi "Mrs. Kutcher" Moore, Melanie "Mrs. Banderas" Griffith, and you will just have a bang. The story goes back and forth between now and then, and it is a testament of the power of female friendship. The heroes, or maybe I should call them She-roes, are able to stand by each other through thick and thin. I know that some men cried (not me, but i know for a fact that my friend Derek went through a full box of Kleenex watching this lovely film). There are my two cents. Girls kick a**. Forever. Definitely. See you next time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not incredibly memorable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Would be "Stand by Me" for the girls, about growing up and making lasting friendships. The plot from I. Marlene King (a semi-autobiographical piece) has little substance and never really manages to captivate, reducing the target audience to teen girls twelve to sixteen years of age. Director Lesli Linka Glatter's film is almost entirely about "Then" and rarely covers "Now". Top line stars Demi Moore, Melanie Griffith and Rosie O'Donnel are wasted completely, playing less than a handful of paltry scenes. Whatever Miss Glatter was trying to create, she fails to make "Now and Then" into anything incredibly memorable. All pic. contains is a few light hearted adventures of four girls' discovery that they are on the verge of womanhood during the summer of 1970. Christina Ricci, Gaby Hoffman, Thora Birch and Ashleigh Aston Moore (the girls in question) do a reasonable job, but stars Hoffman and Ricci need to be challenged with meatier roles. Average film over all. Saturday, March 30, 1996 - Knox District Centre
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent and clean
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mere Humsafar
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you watch this 1995 movie in 2012, you wish all children grow up in small towns with the simplicity and innocence that comes with it.. it has its own share of maturity, " it is normal when things are shitty ".. the movie shows that real understanding can lead to a life-long friendship among four characteristically different kids..one having a tragic past, another having quarrelling parents, yet another being given unreal sex education by an embarrassed, yet caring mother.. The kids have done excellent acting.. the pace is smooth.. the biggest lesson comes from from a mysterious man who visits a particular grave in a cemetery.. A must-see for all parents and also for all children who want to avoid loneliness
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    angelawang
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Now And Then' is about a group of women who return to their old treehouse and reminisce about the one summer that truly changed their lives... With an all star cast, 'Now And Then' features Melanie Griffith, Demi Moore, Rita Wilson and Rosie O'Donnell, with Thora Birch, Gaby Hoffman, Ashleigh Aston Moore and Christina Ricci playing their younger counterparts. Teen star Christina Ricci ('Casper', 'The Adams Family') is great - as is Ricci's 'Gold Diggers' co-star, Ashleigh Aston Moore - as the mis-informed Chrissy. Bonnie Hunt ('Jumangi') and Devon Sawa ('Wild America') also star. The story is great - plenty of laughs to be had here, with sad moments, too. The acting is A-Grade (the young girls look very promising) and the finished product is a film all the cast should be proud of.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Can be a nostalgic flick for girls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching this reminded me of the Korean movie "Sunny" although this came out first. Well it wouldn't be a shock if the director of "Sunny" was influenced by this movie. The dialogue however didn't seem as natural sometimes and seemed like watching some southern novel that isn't really down to earth. It just didn't seem like what a group of women would be saying to each other, but than again the story switches back from the 70's to 90's when it comes to the characters. The dialogue just seemed too safe to be natural despite the sexual stuff and it's a girly movie. Since the 4 main character are 4 girls in the 70's and women in the 90's. Anyways the story is about 4 women getting together after spending there childhood together and reminisce of the past and adventures they had together. Although most of it takes place during a summer. Now I am not a fan of Rosie O'Donnell, to be honest I think she is irritating to watch sometimes. Her character is like the main character or leader of the pack and I thought it was ridiculous her younger version would be played by Christina Ricci. Not that I am a fan of Ricci either, but the comparison is too big to the point you can get confused who is who sometimes when it comes to the younger version with the older version or visa versa. So yeah I don't know if Rosie picked her younger version but it's just absurd. Overall this is a touching movie that most girls and maybe some boys will probably enjoy watching and parents will probably enjoy it as well. It really does give off a nostalgic feel because of the friendship, even if you didn't go through the same things the girls did in the movie. I give this movie a 6.8 because the development of the characters aren't done all that great and somethings are not explained and not for good reasons. Some say this is a female version of "Stand By Me" and I agree to certain extent. 6.8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    aging world
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Now and Then" isn't really anything that I would recommend. It's about some women reminiscing about what happened in their lives in summer 1970. The truly interesting subplot was their search for the story of the deceased boy, but the whole movie came across as contrived. "Stand by Me" was similar but much grittier. This movie isn't terrible, but I just got the feeling that there wasn't much to it. Maybe I like it too much when movies contain a lot of historical context, and so I kept waiting for "Now and Then" to depict the Vietnam War on TV. Anyway, all the cast members have done much better roles. To be certain, Thora Birch co-starred in "American Beauty" a few years after this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doctorjagger
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is horrible all over. It is compared to "Stand By Me". That movie is a classic. This one does not even come close to measuring up to SBM. Some say this is an inspirational movie for young girls. Just so you know, they are wrong! If you're a parent do not show this to your child. It promotes sexism in the worst ways. The girls as children are all persecuted by boys. This is taken to the absolute extreme. This is not like real life. Every interaction with the boys these girls have they act as if they are being attacked. In response they proceed to become violent physically, verbally, and by their actions. This is a horrible movie and a bad influence. 0/10. Do not watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, But Not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    NotPavlovsDog
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just recently watched "Now and Then" again, I decided to check out what other people thought. Reading through a lot of the comments, I noticed that many compared this film to Rob Reiner's "Stand By Me." I guess I would consider the two to be of the same genre (coming of age), but, to me, that's really the only thing the two have in common. "Now and Then" is a fun film. It's got quick and easy laughs that many (not just teenage girls) people will find humorous. I will say that "Then" is vastly more entertaining than "Now"; the adult versions of the characters briefly open and close the story, with forgettable filler in between. "Then" offers some slight depth of character for the four girls who embody stereotypes of adolescent girls (the princess, the tomboy, the sheltered one, the seemingly normal one). "Now" still embraces those stereotypes (the princess has become an actress, still obsessed with body image; the normal one has become a writer, who showcases her intellect by wearing black and smoking). There is no growth amongst the adults. "Now" is focused on Chrissy's pregnancy and reminiscing, while "Then" seems to get distracted amongst its various subplots (unraveling Crazy Pete, watching parents fight, bicker with boys, watch movies, build a tree house, ride bikes) without ever really coming to a true conclusion. For a movie hailed as a "Stand By Me" for girls, the film is lacking in its overall sincerity. Whereas Reiner's film grapples (and in some cases overcomes) 'mature' themes like death, acceptance, and separation, Glatter's film skates over the big issues. "Stand By Me" captures true childhood friendship (friends help friends get leeches off their backs) "Now and Then" is only truly poignant, well, now and then. I'd recommend "Now and Then" for a time when you are in the mood for something lighthearted and distracting. I'd second the opinion that it's great for a girl's sleepover or something. But if you are looking for something a little deeper and, in my opinion, more true to childhood friendship, I'd tell you to skip this movie and go straight to "Stand By Me." Note: "Stand By Me" is rated R; "Now and Then" PG-13. Both films have great soundtracks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sloppy Production Values and Continuity, BAD Acting from the Adults
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deetdee12
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, all 4 younger actresses are quite engaging, likable and amazingly unaffected---they can even almost sell me on the "Stand by Me" plot rip off (or what passes for a plot). I don't mind sweet, small town retro (that never really existed) and I am a feminist, so girl power is fine by me. BUT...it still doesn't cut it. For starters, all the homes exteriors are unquestionably mid-80's/90's style homes. EVERY house should have been a split level or a ranch (I grew up in exactly that type of sub division). While the interiors are overall more accurate,. houses that small wouldn't possibly have such large interior rooms. Teeny's room has painted art deco furniture---fashionable in 1995, NOT 1970 (and Teeny appears to be the wealthiest of the group). Really, couldn't they have borrowed "The Wonder Years" set? The other thing is the truly, utterly horrible acting from the adults. Rita Wilson portrays Chrissy as fully mentally unbalanced. Keeps her home exactly the way her mother had it decorated??? Races around like a shrill harpy??? I kept waiting for someone in a white coat with a net to come and take her away. Yes, she could be nerdy and traditional--that doesn't equal totally crazy. Since they're also all 37 now, it doesn't hold water on that level (they all still act twelve, with apologies to 12 year old). Unless she had serious fertility problems, Chrissy would have wanted to get pregnant the second she got married. Athletic, cute Christina Ricci turns into fat, ugly Rosie O'Donnnel??? And Melanie Griffith (more like 18 in 1970) is already far too old, and simply horrible. In all, if nothing else is on, watch it. But it isn't even fun in a campy way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Used to Like It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dmills9
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was a teen I loved this film. I thought it was great. I don't know what I was thinking. Although the acting is fine, there are so many off elements here that I can't believe I sat through the whole thing. For one thing, I would not let my teenager watch this. Their focus on sex is astounding for a group of 4 twelve year olds. Yuck! This is sooo disturbing to me. I assume that when I was a teen and that was on my mind constantly I was relating to them and their curiosity, but that also would have caused me to think of those things even more, which is (I'm sure) not what any parent wants for their child. There are also the regular profane outbursts by one particular child, the fights and more that promote a way of life that is not desirable for children and that I cannot be entertained by them acting it out. If you are going to watch this, please leave the kids out of it. You don't want them molded into this 'cool' persona.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A comedy for the ages
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danmax
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film. Well, let's be honest, I will love any movie with Roseanne. Add Demi "Mrs. Kutcher" Moore, Melanie "Mrs. Banderas" Griffith, and you will just have a bang. The story goes back and forth between now and then, and it is a testament of the power of female friendship. The heroes, or maybe I should call them She-roes, are able to stand by each other through thick and thin. I know that some men cried (not me, but i know for a fact that my friend Derek went through a full box of Kleenex watching this lovely film). There are my two cents. Girls kick a**. Forever. Definitely. See you next time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not incredibly memorable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Would be "Stand by Me" for the girls, about growing up and making lasting friendships. The plot from I. Marlene King (a semi-autobiographical piece) has little substance and never really manages to captivate, reducing the target audience to teen girls twelve to sixteen years of age. Director Lesli Linka Glatter's film is almost entirely about "Then" and rarely covers "Now". Top line stars Demi Moore, Melanie Griffith and Rosie O'Donnel are wasted completely, playing less than a handful of paltry scenes. Whatever Miss Glatter was trying to create, she fails to make "Now and Then" into anything incredibly memorable. All pic. contains is a few light hearted adventures of four girls' discovery that they are on the verge of womanhood during the summer of 1970. Christina Ricci, Gaby Hoffman, Thora Birch and Ashleigh Aston Moore (the girls in question) do a reasonable job, but stars Hoffman and Ricci need to be challenged with meatier roles. Average film over all. Saturday, March 30, 1996 - Knox District Centre
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent and clean
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mere Humsafar
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you watch this 1995 movie in 2012, you wish all children grow up in small towns with the simplicity and innocence that comes with it.. it has its own share of maturity, " it is normal when things are shitty ".. the movie shows that real understanding can lead to a life-long friendship among four characteristically different kids..one having a tragic past, another having quarrelling parents, yet another being given unreal sex education by an embarrassed, yet caring mother.. The kids have done excellent acting.. the pace is smooth.. the biggest lesson comes from from a mysterious man who visits a particular grave in a cemetery.. A must-see for all parents and also for all children who want to avoid loneliness
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    angelawang
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Now And Then' is about a group of women who return to their old treehouse and reminisce about the one summer that truly changed their lives... With an all star cast, 'Now And Then' features Melanie Griffith, Demi Moore, Rita Wilson and Rosie O'Donnell, with Thora Birch, Gaby Hoffman, Ashleigh Aston Moore and Christina Ricci playing their younger counterparts. Teen star Christina Ricci ('Casper', 'The Adams Family') is great - as is Ricci's 'Gold Diggers' co-star, Ashleigh Aston Moore - as the mis-informed Chrissy. Bonnie Hunt ('Jumangi') and Devon Sawa ('Wild America') also star. The story is great - plenty of laughs to be had here, with sad moments, too. The acting is A-Grade (the young girls look very promising) and the finished product is a film all the cast should be proud of.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Can be a nostalgic flick for girls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching this reminded me of the Korean movie "Sunny" although this came out first. Well it wouldn't be a shock if the director of "Sunny" was influenced by this movie. The dialogue however didn't seem as natural sometimes and seemed like watching some southern novel that isn't really down to earth. It just didn't seem like what a group of women would be saying to each other, but than again the story switches back from the 70's to 90's when it comes to the characters. The dialogue just seemed too safe to be natural despite the sexual stuff and it's a girly movie. Since the 4 main character are 4 girls in the 70's and women in the 90's. Anyways the story is about 4 women getting together after spending there childhood together and reminisce of the past and adventures they had together. Although most of it takes place during a summer. Now I am not a fan of Rosie O'Donnell, to be honest I think she is irritating to watch sometimes. Her character is like the main character or leader of the pack and I thought it was ridiculous her younger version would be played by Christina Ricci. Not that I am a fan of Ricci either, but the comparison is too big to the point you can get confused who is who sometimes when it comes to the younger version with the older version or visa versa. So yeah I don't know if Rosie picked her younger version but it's just absurd. Overall this is a touching movie that most girls and maybe some boys will probably enjoy watching and parents will probably enjoy it as well. It really does give off a nostalgic feel because of the friendship, even if you didn't go through the same things the girls did in the movie. I give this movie a 6.8 because the development of the characters aren't done all that great and somethings are not explained and not for good reasons. Some say this is a female version of "Stand By Me" and I agree to certain extent. 6.8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    aging world
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Now and Then" isn't really anything that I would recommend. It's about some women reminiscing about what happened in their lives in summer 1970. The truly interesting subplot was their search for the story of the deceased boy, but the whole movie came across as contrived. "Stand by Me" was similar but much grittier. This movie isn't terrible, but I just got the feeling that there wasn't much to it. Maybe I like it too much when movies contain a lot of historical context, and so I kept waiting for "Now and Then" to depict the Vietnam War on TV. Anyway, all the cast members have done much better roles. To be certain, Thora Birch co-starred in "American Beauty" a few years after this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doctorjagger
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is horrible all over. It is compared to "Stand By Me". That movie is a classic. This one does not even come close to measuring up to SBM. Some say this is an inspirational movie for young girls. Just so you know, they are wrong! If you're a parent do not show this to your child. It promotes sexism in the worst ways. The girls as children are all persecuted by boys. This is taken to the absolute extreme. This is not like real life. Every interaction with the boys these girls have they act as if they are being attacked. In response they proceed to become violent physically, verbally, and by their actions. This is a horrible movie and a bad influence. 0/10. Do not watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, But Not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    NotPavlovsDog
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just recently watched "Now and Then" again, I decided to check out what other people thought. Reading through a lot of the comments, I noticed that many compared this film to Rob Reiner's "Stand By Me." I guess I would consider the two to be of the same genre (coming of age), but, to me, that's really the only thing the two have in common. "Now and Then" is a fun film. It's got quick and easy laughs that many (not just teenage girls) people will find humorous. I will say that "Then" is vastly more entertaining than "Now"; the adult versions of the characters briefly open and close the story, with forgettable filler in between. "Then" offers some slight depth of character for the four girls who embody stereotypes of adolescent girls (the princess, the tomboy, the sheltered one, the seemingly normal one). "Now" still embraces those stereotypes (the princess has become an actress, still obsessed with body image; the normal one has become a writer, who showcases her intellect by wearing black and smoking). There is no growth amongst the adults. "Now" is focused on Chrissy's pregnancy and reminiscing, while "Then" seems to get distracted amongst its various subplots (unraveling Crazy Pete, watching parents fight, bicker with boys, watch movies, build a tree house, ride bikes) without ever really coming to a true conclusion. For a movie hailed as a "Stand By Me" for girls, the film is lacking in its overall sincerity. Whereas Reiner's film grapples (and in some cases overcomes) 'mature' themes like death, acceptance, and separation, Glatter's film skates over the big issues. "Stand By Me" captures true childhood friendship (friends help friends get leeches off their backs) "Now and Then" is only truly poignant, well, now and then. I'd recommend "Now and Then" for a time when you are in the mood for something lighthearted and distracting. I'd second the opinion that it's great for a girl's sleepover or something. But if you are looking for something a little deeper and, in my opinion, more true to childhood friendship, I'd tell you to skip this movie and go straight to "Stand By Me." Note: "Stand By Me" is rated R; "Now and Then" PG-13. Both films have great soundtracks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sloppy Production Values and Continuity, BAD Acting from the Adults
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deetdee12
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, all 4 younger actresses are quite engaging, likable and amazingly unaffected---they can even almost sell me on the "Stand by Me" plot rip off (or what passes for a plot). I don't mind sweet, small town retro (that never really existed) and I am a feminist, so girl power is fine by me. BUT...it still doesn't cut it. For starters, all the homes exteriors are unquestionably mid-80's/90's style homes. EVERY house should have been a split level or a ranch (I grew up in exactly that type of sub division). While the interiors are overall more accurate,. houses that small wouldn't possibly have such large interior rooms. Teeny's room has painted art deco furniture---fashionable in 1995, NOT 1970 (and Teeny appears to be the wealthiest of the group). Really, couldn't they have borrowed "The Wonder Years" set? The other thing is the truly, utterly horrible acting from the adults. Rita Wilson portrays Chrissy as fully mentally unbalanced. Keeps her home exactly the way her mother had it decorated??? Races around like a shrill harpy??? I kept waiting for someone in a white coat with a net to come and take her away. Yes, she could be nerdy and traditional--that doesn't equal totally crazy. Since they're also all 37 now, it doesn't hold water on that level (they all still act twelve, with apologies to 12 year old). Unless she had serious fertility problems, Chrissy would have wanted to get pregnant the second she got married. Athletic, cute Christina Ricci turns into fat, ugly Rosie O'Donnnel??? And Melanie Griffith (more like 18 in 1970) is already far too old, and simply horrible. In all, if nothing else is on, watch it. But it isn't even fun in a campy way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Used to Like It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dmills9
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was a teen I loved this film. I thought it was great. I don't know what I was thinking. Although the acting is fine, there are so many off elements here that I can't believe I sat through the whole thing. For one thing, I would not let my teenager watch this. Their focus on sex is astounding for a group of 4 twelve year olds. Yuck! This is sooo disturbing to me. I assume that when I was a teen and that was on my mind constantly I was relating to them and their curiosity, but that also would have caused me to think of those things even more, which is (I'm sure) not what any parent wants for their child. There are also the regular profane outbursts by one particular child, the fights and more that promote a way of life that is not desirable for children and that I cannot be entertained by them acting it out. If you are going to watch this, please leave the kids out of it. You don't want them molded into this 'cool' persona.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A comedy for the ages
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danmax
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film. Well, let's be honest, I will love any movie with Roseanne. Add Demi "Mrs. Kutcher" Moore, Melanie "Mrs. Banderas" Griffith, and you will just have a bang. The story goes back and forth between now and then, and it is a testament of the power of female friendship. The heroes, or maybe I should call them She-roes, are able to stand by each other through thick and thin. I know that some men cried (not me, but i know for a fact that my friend Derek went through a full box of Kleenex watching this lovely film). There are my two cents. Girls kick a**. Forever. Definitely. See you next time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not incredibly memorable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Would be "Stand by Me" for the girls, about growing up and making lasting friendships. The plot from I. Marlene King (a semi-autobiographical piece) has little substance and never really manages to captivate, reducing the target audience to teen girls twelve to sixteen years of age. Director Lesli Linka Glatter's film is almost entirely about "Then" and rarely covers "Now". Top line stars Demi Moore, Melanie Griffith and Rosie O'Donnel are wasted completely, playing less than a handful of paltry scenes. Whatever Miss Glatter was trying to create, she fails to make "Now and Then" into anything incredibly memorable. All pic. contains is a few light hearted adventures of four girls' discovery that they are on the verge of womanhood during the summer of 1970. Christina Ricci, Gaby Hoffman, Thora Birch and Ashleigh Aston Moore (the girls in question) do a reasonable job, but stars Hoffman and Ricci need to be challenged with meatier roles. Average film over all. Saturday, March 30, 1996 - Knox District Centre
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent and clean
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mere Humsafar
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you watch this 1995 movie in 2012, you wish all children grow up in small towns with the simplicity and innocence that comes with it.. it has its own share of maturity, " it is normal when things are shitty ".. the movie shows that real understanding can lead to a life-long friendship among four characteristically different kids..one having a tragic past, another having quarrelling parents, yet another being given unreal sex education by an embarrassed, yet caring mother.. The kids have done excellent acting.. the pace is smooth.. the biggest lesson comes from from a mysterious man who visits a particular grave in a cemetery.. A must-see for all parents and also for all children who want to avoid loneliness
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    angelawang
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Now And Then' is about a group of women who return to their old treehouse and reminisce about the one summer that truly changed their lives... With an all star cast, 'Now And Then' features Melanie Griffith, Demi Moore, Rita Wilson and Rosie O'Donnell, with Thora Birch, Gaby Hoffman, Ashleigh Aston Moore and Christina Ricci playing their younger counterparts. Teen star Christina Ricci ('Casper', 'The Adams Family') is great - as is Ricci's 'Gold Diggers' co-star, Ashleigh Aston Moore - as the mis-informed Chrissy. Bonnie Hunt ('Jumangi') and Devon Sawa ('Wild America') also star. The story is great - plenty of laughs to be had here, with sad moments, too. The acting is A-Grade (the young girls look very promising) and the finished product is a film all the cast should be proud of.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Can be a nostalgic flick for girls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching this reminded me of the Korean movie "Sunny" although this came out first. Well it wouldn't be a shock if the director of "Sunny" was influenced by this movie. The dialogue however didn't seem as natural sometimes and seemed like watching some southern novel that isn't really down to earth. It just didn't seem like what a group of women would be saying to each other, but than again the story switches back from the 70's to 90's when it comes to the characters. The dialogue just seemed too safe to be natural despite the sexual stuff and it's a girly movie. Since the 4 main character are 4 girls in the 70's and women in the 90's. Anyways the story is about 4 women getting together after spending there childhood together and reminisce of the past and adventures they had together. Although most of it takes place during a summer. Now I am not a fan of Rosie O'Donnell, to be honest I think she is irritating to watch sometimes. Her character is like the main character or leader of the pack and I thought it was ridiculous her younger version would be played by Christina Ricci. Not that I am a fan of Ricci either, but the comparison is too big to the point you can get confused who is who sometimes when it comes to the younger version with the older version or visa versa. So yeah I don't know if Rosie picked her younger version but it's just absurd. Overall this is a touching movie that most girls and maybe some boys will probably enjoy watching and parents will probably enjoy it as well. It really does give off a nostalgic feel because of the friendship, even if you didn't go through the same things the girls did in the movie. I give this movie a 6.8 because the development of the characters aren't done all that great and somethings are not explained and not for good reasons. Some say this is a female version of "Stand By Me" and I agree to certain extent. 6.8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    aging world
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Now and Then" isn't really anything that I would recommend. It's about some women reminiscing about what happened in their lives in summer 1970. The truly interesting subplot was their search for the story of the deceased boy, but the whole movie came across as contrived. "Stand by Me" was similar but much grittier. This movie isn't terrible, but I just got the feeling that there wasn't much to it. Maybe I like it too much when movies contain a lot of historical context, and so I kept waiting for "Now and Then" to depict the Vietnam War on TV. Anyway, all the cast members have done much better roles. To be certain, Thora Birch co-starred in "American Beauty" a few years after this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doctorjagger
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is horrible all over. It is compared to "Stand By Me". That movie is a classic. This one does not even come close to measuring up to SBM. Some say this is an inspirational movie for young girls. Just so you know, they are wrong! If you're a parent do not show this to your child. It promotes sexism in the worst ways. The girls as children are all persecuted by boys. This is taken to the absolute extreme. This is not like real life. Every interaction with the boys these girls have they act as if they are being attacked. In response they proceed to become violent physically, verbally, and by their actions. This is a horrible movie and a bad influence. 0/10. Do not watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, But Not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    NotPavlovsDog
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just recently watched "Now and Then" again, I decided to check out what other people thought. Reading through a lot of the comments, I noticed that many compared this film to Rob Reiner's "Stand By Me." I guess I would consider the two to be of the same genre (coming of age), but, to me, that's really the only thing the two have in common. "Now and Then" is a fun film. It's got quick and easy laughs that many (not just teenage girls) people will find humorous. I will say that "Then" is vastly more entertaining than "Now"; the adult versions of the characters briefly open and close the story, with forgettable filler in between. "Then" offers some slight depth of character for the four girls who embody stereotypes of adolescent girls (the princess, the tomboy, the sheltered one, the seemingly normal one). "Now" still embraces those stereotypes (the princess has become an actress, still obsessed with body image; the normal one has become a writer, who showcases her intellect by wearing black and smoking). There is no growth amongst the adults. "Now" is focused on Chrissy's pregnancy and reminiscing, while "Then" seems to get distracted amongst its various subplots (unraveling Crazy Pete, watching parents fight, bicker with boys, watch movies, build a tree house, ride bikes) without ever really coming to a true conclusion. For a movie hailed as a "Stand By Me" for girls, the film is lacking in its overall sincerity. Whereas Reiner's film grapples (and in some cases overcomes) 'mature' themes like death, acceptance, and separation, Glatter's film skates over the big issues. "Stand By Me" captures true childhood friendship (friends help friends get leeches off their backs) "Now and Then" is only truly poignant, well, now and then. I'd recommend "Now and Then" for a time when you are in the mood for something lighthearted and distracting. I'd second the opinion that it's great for a girl's sleepover or something. But if you are looking for something a little deeper and, in my opinion, more true to childhood friendship, I'd tell you to skip this movie and go straight to "Stand By Me." Note: "Stand By Me" is rated R; "Now and Then" PG-13. Both films have great soundtracks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sloppy Production Values and Continuity, BAD Acting from the Adults
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deetdee12
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, all 4 younger actresses are quite engaging, likable and amazingly unaffected---they can even almost sell me on the "Stand by Me" plot rip off (or what passes for a plot). I don't mind sweet, small town retro (that never really existed) and I am a feminist, so girl power is fine by me. BUT...it still doesn't cut it. For starters, all the homes exteriors are unquestionably mid-80's/90's style homes. EVERY house should have been a split level or a ranch (I grew up in exactly that type of sub division). While the interiors are overall more accurate,. houses that small wouldn't possibly have such large interior rooms. Teeny's room has painted art deco furniture---fashionable in 1995, NOT 1970 (and Teeny appears to be the wealthiest of the group). Really, couldn't they have borrowed "The Wonder Years" set? The other thing is the truly, utterly horrible acting from the adults. Rita Wilson portrays Chrissy as fully mentally unbalanced. Keeps her home exactly the way her mother had it decorated??? Races around like a shrill harpy??? I kept waiting for someone in a white coat with a net to come and take her away. Yes, she could be nerdy and traditional--that doesn't equal totally crazy. Since they're also all 37 now, it doesn't hold water on that level (they all still act twelve, with apologies to 12 year old). Unless she had serious fertility problems, Chrissy would have wanted to get pregnant the second she got married. Athletic, cute Christina Ricci turns into fat, ugly Rosie O'Donnnel??? And Melanie Griffith (more like 18 in 1970) is already far too old, and simply horrible. In all, if nothing else is on, watch it. But it isn't even fun in a campy way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Used to Like It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dmills9
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was a teen I loved this film. I thought it was great. I don't know what I was thinking. Although the acting is fine, there are so many off elements here that I can't believe I sat through the whole thing. For one thing, I would not let my teenager watch this. Their focus on sex is astounding for a group of 4 twelve year olds. Yuck! This is sooo disturbing to me. I assume that when I was a teen and that was on my mind constantly I was relating to them and their curiosity, but that also would have caused me to think of those things even more, which is (I'm sure) not what any parent wants for their child. There are also the regular profane outbursts by one particular child, the fights and more that promote a way of life that is not desirable for children and that I cannot be entertained by them acting it out. If you are going to watch this, please leave the kids out of it. You don't want them molded into this 'cool' persona.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A comedy for the ages
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danmax
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film. Well, let's be honest, I will love any movie with Roseanne. Add Demi "Mrs. Kutcher" Moore, Melanie "Mrs. Banderas" Griffith, and you will just have a bang. The story goes back and forth between now and then, and it is a testament of the power of female friendship. The heroes, or maybe I should call them She-roes, are able to stand by each other through thick and thin. I know that some men cried (not me, but i know for a fact that my friend Derek went through a full box of Kleenex watching this lovely film). There are my two cents. Girls kick a**. Forever. Definitely. See you next time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not incredibly memorable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Would be "Stand by Me" for the girls, about growing up and making lasting friendships. The plot from I. Marlene King (a semi-autobiographical piece) has little substance and never really manages to captivate, reducing the target audience to teen girls twelve to sixteen years of age. Director Lesli Linka Glatter's film is almost entirely about "Then" and rarely covers "Now". Top line stars Demi Moore, Melanie Griffith and Rosie O'Donnel are wasted completely, playing less than a handful of paltry scenes. Whatever Miss Glatter was trying to create, she fails to make "Now and Then" into anything incredibly memorable. All pic. contains is a few light hearted adventures of four girls' discovery that they are on the verge of womanhood during the summer of 1970. Christina Ricci, Gaby Hoffman, Thora Birch and Ashleigh Aston Moore (the girls in question) do a reasonable job, but stars Hoffman and Ricci need to be challenged with meatier roles. Average film over all. Saturday, March 30, 1996 - Knox District Centre
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent and clean
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mere Humsafar
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you watch this 1995 movie in 2012, you wish all children grow up in small towns with the simplicity and innocence that comes with it.. it has its own share of maturity, " it is normal when things are shitty ".. the movie shows that real understanding can lead to a life-long friendship among four characteristically different kids..one having a tragic past, another having quarrelling parents, yet another being given unreal sex education by an embarrassed, yet caring mother.. The kids have done excellent acting.. the pace is smooth.. the biggest lesson comes from from a mysterious man who visits a particular grave in a cemetery.. A must-see for all parents and also for all children who want to avoid loneliness
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    angelawang
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Now And Then' is about a group of women who return to their old treehouse and reminisce about the one summer that truly changed their lives... With an all star cast, 'Now And Then' features Melanie Griffith, Demi Moore, Rita Wilson and Rosie O'Donnell, with Thora Birch, Gaby Hoffman, Ashleigh Aston Moore and Christina Ricci playing their younger counterparts. Teen star Christina Ricci ('Casper', 'The Adams Family') is great - as is Ricci's 'Gold Diggers' co-star, Ashleigh Aston Moore - as the mis-informed Chrissy. Bonnie Hunt ('Jumangi') and Devon Sawa ('Wild America') also star. The story is great - plenty of laughs to be had here, with sad moments, too. The acting is A-Grade (the young girls look very promising) and the finished product is a film all the cast should be proud of.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Can be a nostalgic flick for girls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching this reminded me of the Korean movie "Sunny" although this came out first. Well it wouldn't be a shock if the director of "Sunny" was influenced by this movie. The dialogue however didn't seem as natural sometimes and seemed like watching some southern novel that isn't really down to earth. It just didn't seem like what a group of women would be saying to each other, but than again the story switches back from the 70's to 90's when it comes to the characters. The dialogue just seemed too safe to be natural despite the sexual stuff and it's a girly movie. Since the 4 main character are 4 girls in the 70's and women in the 90's. Anyways the story is about 4 women getting together after spending there childhood together and reminisce of the past and adventures they had together. Although most of it takes place during a summer. Now I am not a fan of Rosie O'Donnell, to be honest I think she is irritating to watch sometimes. Her character is like the main character or leader of the pack and I thought it was ridiculous her younger version would be played by Christina Ricci. Not that I am a fan of Ricci either, but the comparison is too big to the point you can get confused who is who sometimes when it comes to the younger version with the older version or visa versa. So yeah I don't know if Rosie picked her younger version but it's just absurd. Overall this is a touching movie that most girls and maybe some boys will probably enjoy watching and parents will probably enjoy it as well. It really does give off a nostalgic feel because of the friendship, even if you didn't go through the same things the girls did in the movie. I give this movie a 6.8 because the development of the characters aren't done all that great and somethings are not explained and not for good reasons. Some say this is a female version of "Stand By Me" and I agree to certain extent. 6.8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    aging world
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Now and Then" isn't really anything that I would recommend. It's about some women reminiscing about what happened in their lives in summer 1970. The truly interesting subplot was their search for the story of the deceased boy, but the whole movie came across as contrived. "Stand by Me" was similar but much grittier. This movie isn't terrible, but I just got the feeling that there wasn't much to it. Maybe I like it too much when movies contain a lot of historical context, and so I kept waiting for "Now and Then" to depict the Vietnam War on TV. Anyway, all the cast members have done much better roles. To be certain, Thora Birch co-starred in "American Beauty" a few years after this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doctorjagger
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is horrible all over. It is compared to "Stand By Me". That movie is a classic. This one does not even come close to measuring up to SBM. Some say this is an inspirational movie for young girls. Just so you know, they are wrong! If you're a parent do not show this to your child. It promotes sexism in the worst ways. The girls as children are all persecuted by boys. This is taken to the absolute extreme. This is not like real life. Every interaction with the boys these girls have they act as if they are being attacked. In response they proceed to become violent physically, verbally, and by their actions. This is a horrible movie and a bad influence. 0/10. Do not watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, But Not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    NotPavlovsDog
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just recently watched "Now and Then" again, I decided to check out what other people thought. Reading through a lot of the comments, I noticed that many compared this film to Rob Reiner's "Stand By Me." I guess I would consider the two to be of the same genre (coming of age), but, to me, that's really the only thing the two have in common. "Now and Then" is a fun film. It's got quick and easy laughs that many (not just teenage girls) people will find humorous. I will say that "Then" is vastly more entertaining than "Now"; the adult versions of the characters briefly open and close the story, with forgettable filler in between. "Then" offers some slight depth of character for the four girls who embody stereotypes of adolescent girls (the princess, the tomboy, the sheltered one, the seemingly normal one). "Now" still embraces those stereotypes (the princess has become an actress, still obsessed with body image; the normal one has become a writer, who showcases her intellect by wearing black and smoking). There is no growth amongst the adults. "Now" is focused on Chrissy's pregnancy and reminiscing, while "Then" seems to get distracted amongst its various subplots (unraveling Crazy Pete, watching parents fight, bicker with boys, watch movies, build a tree house, ride bikes) without ever really coming to a true conclusion. For a movie hailed as a "Stand By Me" for girls, the film is lacking in its overall sincerity. Whereas Reiner's film grapples (and in some cases overcomes) 'mature' themes like death, acceptance, and separation, Glatter's film skates over the big issues. "Stand By Me" captures true childhood friendship (friends help friends get leeches off their backs) "Now and Then" is only truly poignant, well, now and then. I'd recommend "Now and Then" for a time when you are in the mood for something lighthearted and distracting. I'd second the opinion that it's great for a girl's sleepover or something. But if you are looking for something a little deeper and, in my opinion, more true to childhood friendship, I'd tell you to skip this movie and go straight to "Stand By Me." Note: "Stand By Me" is rated R; "Now and Then" PG-13. Both films have great soundtracks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sloppy Production Values and Continuity, BAD Acting from the Adults
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deetdee12
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, all 4 younger actresses are quite engaging, likable and amazingly unaffected---they can even almost sell me on the "Stand by Me" plot rip off (or what passes for a plot). I don't mind sweet, small town retro (that never really existed) and I am a feminist, so girl power is fine by me. BUT...it still doesn't cut it. For starters, all the homes exteriors are unquestionably mid-80's/90's style homes. EVERY house should have been a split level or a ranch (I grew up in exactly that type of sub division). While the interiors are overall more accurate,. houses that small wouldn't possibly have such large interior rooms. Teeny's room has painted art deco furniture---fashionable in 1995, NOT 1970 (and Teeny appears to be the wealthiest of the group). Really, couldn't they have borrowed "The Wonder Years" set? The other thing is the truly, utterly horrible acting from the adults. Rita Wilson portrays Chrissy as fully mentally unbalanced. Keeps her home exactly the way her mother had it decorated??? Races around like a shrill harpy??? I kept waiting for someone in a white coat with a net to come and take her away. Yes, she could be nerdy and traditional--that doesn't equal totally crazy. Since they're also all 37 now, it doesn't hold water on that level (they all still act twelve, with apologies to 12 year old). Unless she had serious fertility problems, Chrissy would have wanted to get pregnant the second she got married. Athletic, cute Christina Ricci turns into fat, ugly Rosie O'Donnnel??? And Melanie Griffith (more like 18 in 1970) is already far too old, and simply horrible. In all, if nothing else is on, watch it. But it isn't even fun in a campy way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Used to Like It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dmills9
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was a teen I loved this film. I thought it was great. I don't know what I was thinking. Although the acting is fine, there are so many off elements here that I can't believe I sat through the whole thing. For one thing, I would not let my teenager watch this. Their focus on sex is astounding for a group of 4 twelve year olds. Yuck! This is sooo disturbing to me. I assume that when I was a teen and that was on my mind constantly I was relating to them and their curiosity, but that also would have caused me to think of those things even more, which is (I'm sure) not what any parent wants for their child. There are also the regular profane outbursts by one particular child, the fights and more that promote a way of life that is not desirable for children and that I cannot be entertained by them acting it out. If you are going to watch this, please leave the kids out of it. You don't want them molded into this 'cool' persona.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A comedy for the ages
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danmax
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film. Well, let's be honest, I will love any movie with Roseanne. Add Demi "Mrs. Kutcher" Moore, Melanie "Mrs. Banderas" Griffith, and you will just have a bang. The story goes back and forth between now and then, and it is a testament of the power of female friendship. The heroes, or maybe I should call them She-roes, are able to stand by each other through thick and thin. I know that some men cried (not me, but i know for a fact that my friend Derek went through a full box of Kleenex watching this lovely film). There are my two cents. Girls kick a**. Forever. Definitely. See you next time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not incredibly memorable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Would be "Stand by Me" for the girls, about growing up and making lasting friendships. The plot from I. Marlene King (a semi-autobiographical piece) has little substance and never really manages to captivate, reducing the target audience to teen girls twelve to sixteen years of age. Director Lesli Linka Glatter's film is almost entirely about "Then" and rarely covers "Now". Top line stars Demi Moore, Melanie Griffith and Rosie O'Donnel are wasted completely, playing less than a handful of paltry scenes. Whatever Miss Glatter was trying to create, she fails to make "Now and Then" into anything incredibly memorable. All pic. contains is a few light hearted adventures of four girls' discovery that they are on the verge of womanhood during the summer of 1970. Christina Ricci, Gaby Hoffman, Thora Birch and Ashleigh Aston Moore (the girls in question) do a reasonable job, but stars Hoffman and Ricci need to be challenged with meatier roles. Average film over all. Saturday, March 30, 1996 - Knox District Centre
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent and clean
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mere Humsafar
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you watch this 1995 movie in 2012, you wish all children grow up in small towns with the simplicity and innocence that comes with it.. it has its own share of maturity, " it is normal when things are shitty ".. the movie shows that real understanding can lead to a life-long friendship among four characteristically different kids..one having a tragic past, another having quarrelling parents, yet another being given unreal sex education by an embarrassed, yet caring mother.. The kids have done excellent acting.. the pace is smooth.. the biggest lesson comes from from a mysterious man who visits a particular grave in a cemetery.. A must-see for all parents and also for all children who want to avoid loneliness
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    angelawang
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Now And Then' is about a group of women who return to their old treehouse and reminisce about the one summer that truly changed their lives... With an all star cast, 'Now And Then' features Melanie Griffith, Demi Moore, Rita Wilson and Rosie O'Donnell, with Thora Birch, Gaby Hoffman, Ashleigh Aston Moore and Christina Ricci playing their younger counterparts. Teen star Christina Ricci ('Casper', 'The Adams Family') is great - as is Ricci's 'Gold Diggers' co-star, Ashleigh Aston Moore - as the mis-informed Chrissy. Bonnie Hunt ('Jumangi') and Devon Sawa ('Wild America') also star. The story is great - plenty of laughs to be had here, with sad moments, too. The acting is A-Grade (the young girls look very promising) and the finished product is a film all the cast should be proud of.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Can be a nostalgic flick for girls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching this reminded me of the Korean movie "Sunny" although this came out first. Well it wouldn't be a shock if the director of "Sunny" was influenced by this movie. The dialogue however didn't seem as natural sometimes and seemed like watching some southern novel that isn't really down to earth. It just didn't seem like what a group of women would be saying to each other, but than again the story switches back from the 70's to 90's when it comes to the characters. The dialogue just seemed too safe to be natural despite the sexual stuff and it's a girly movie. Since the 4 main character are 4 girls in the 70's and women in the 90's. Anyways the story is about 4 women getting together after spending there childhood together and reminisce of the past and adventures they had together. Although most of it takes place during a summer. Now I am not a fan of Rosie O'Donnell, to be honest I think she is irritating to watch sometimes. Her character is like the main character or leader of the pack and I thought it was ridiculous her younger version would be played by Christina Ricci. Not that I am a fan of Ricci either, but the comparison is too big to the point you can get confused who is who sometimes when it comes to the younger version with the older version or visa versa. So yeah I don't know if Rosie picked her younger version but it's just absurd. Overall this is a touching movie that most girls and maybe some boys will probably enjoy watching and parents will probably enjoy it as well. It really does give off a nostalgic feel because of the friendship, even if you didn't go through the same things the girls did in the movie. I give this movie a 6.8 because the development of the characters aren't done all that great and somethings are not explained and not for good reasons. Some say this is a female version of "Stand By Me" and I agree to certain extent. 6.8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    aging world
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Now and Then" isn't really anything that I would recommend. It's about some women reminiscing about what happened in their lives in summer 1970. The truly interesting subplot was their search for the story of the deceased boy, but the whole movie came across as contrived. "Stand by Me" was similar but much grittier. This movie isn't terrible, but I just got the feeling that there wasn't much to it. Maybe I like it too much when movies contain a lot of historical context, and so I kept waiting for "Now and Then" to depict the Vietnam War on TV. Anyway, all the cast members have done much better roles. To be certain, Thora Birch co-starred in "American Beauty" a few years after this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doctorjagger
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is horrible all over. It is compared to "Stand By Me". That movie is a classic. This one does not even come close to measuring up to SBM. Some say this is an inspirational movie for young girls. Just so you know, they are wrong! If you're a parent do not show this to your child. It promotes sexism in the worst ways. The girls as children are all persecuted by boys. This is taken to the absolute extreme. This is not like real life. Every interaction with the boys these girls have they act as if they are being attacked. In response they proceed to become violent physically, verbally, and by their actions. This is a horrible movie and a bad influence. 0/10. Do not watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, But Not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    NotPavlovsDog
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just recently watched "Now and Then" again, I decided to check out what other people thought. Reading through a lot of the comments, I noticed that many compared this film to Rob Reiner's "Stand By Me." I guess I would consider the two to be of the same genre (coming of age), but, to me, that's really the only thing the two have in common. "Now and Then" is a fun film. It's got quick and easy laughs that many (not just teenage girls) people will find humorous. I will say that "Then" is vastly more entertaining than "Now"; the adult versions of the characters briefly open and close the story, with forgettable filler in between. "Then" offers some slight depth of character for the four girls who embody stereotypes of adolescent girls (the princess, the tomboy, the sheltered one, the seemingly normal one). "Now" still embraces those stereotypes (the princess has become an actress, still obsessed with body image; the normal one has become a writer, who showcases her intellect by wearing black and smoking). There is no growth amongst the adults. "Now" is focused on Chrissy's pregnancy and reminiscing, while "Then" seems to get distracted amongst its various subplots (unraveling Crazy Pete, watching parents fight, bicker with boys, watch movies, build a tree house, ride bikes) without ever really coming to a true conclusion. For a movie hailed as a "Stand By Me" for girls, the film is lacking in its overall sincerity. Whereas Reiner's film grapples (and in some cases overcomes) 'mature' themes like death, acceptance, and separation, Glatter's film skates over the big issues. "Stand By Me" captures true childhood friendship (friends help friends get leeches off their backs) "Now and Then" is only truly poignant, well, now and then. I'd recommend "Now and Then" for a time when you are in the mood for something lighthearted and distracting. I'd second the opinion that it's great for a girl's sleepover or something. But if you are looking for something a little deeper and, in my opinion, more true to childhood friendship, I'd tell you to skip this movie and go straight to "Stand By Me." Note: "Stand By Me" is rated R; "Now and Then" PG-13. Both films have great soundtracks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sloppy Production Values and Continuity, BAD Acting from the Adults
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deetdee12
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, all 4 younger actresses are quite engaging, likable and amazingly unaffected---they can even almost sell me on the "Stand by Me" plot rip off (or what passes for a plot). I don't mind sweet, small town retro (that never really existed) and I am a feminist, so girl power is fine by me. BUT...it still doesn't cut it. For starters, all the homes exteriors are unquestionably mid-80's/90's style homes. EVERY house should have been a split level or a ranch (I grew up in exactly that type of sub division). While the interiors are overall more accurate,. houses that small wouldn't possibly have such large interior rooms. Teeny's room has painted art deco furniture---fashionable in 1995, NOT 1970 (and Teeny appears to be the wealthiest of the group). Really, couldn't they have borrowed "The Wonder Years" set? The other thing is the truly, utterly horrible acting from the adults. Rita Wilson portrays Chrissy as fully mentally unbalanced. Keeps her home exactly the way her mother had it decorated??? Races around like a shrill harpy??? I kept waiting for someone in a white coat with a net to come and take her away. Yes, she could be nerdy and traditional--that doesn't equal totally crazy. Since they're also all 37 now, it doesn't hold water on that level (they all still act twelve, with apologies to 12 year old). Unless she had serious fertility problems, Chrissy would have wanted to get pregnant the second she got married. Athletic, cute Christina Ricci turns into fat, ugly Rosie O'Donnnel??? And Melanie Griffith (more like 18 in 1970) is already far too old, and simply horrible. In all, if nothing else is on, watch it. But it isn't even fun in a campy way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Used to Like It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dmills9
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was a teen I loved this film. I thought it was great. I don't know what I was thinking. Although the acting is fine, there are so many off elements here that I can't believe I sat through the whole thing. For one thing, I would not let my teenager watch this. Their focus on sex is astounding for a group of 4 twelve year olds. Yuck! This is sooo disturbing to me. I assume that when I was a teen and that was on my mind constantly I was relating to them and their curiosity, but that also would have caused me to think of those things even more, which is (I'm sure) not what any parent wants for their child. There are also the regular profane outbursts by one particular child, the fights and more that promote a way of life that is not desirable for children and that I cannot be entertained by them acting it out. If you are going to watch this, please leave the kids out of it. You don't want them molded into this 'cool' persona.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A comedy for the ages
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danmax
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film. Well, let's be honest, I will love any movie with Roseanne. Add Demi "Mrs. Kutcher" Moore, Melanie "Mrs. Banderas" Griffith, and you will just have a bang. The story goes back and forth between now and then, and it is a testament of the power of female friendship. The heroes, or maybe I should call them She-roes, are able to stand by each other through thick and thin. I know that some men cried (not me, but i know for a fact that my friend Derek went through a full box of Kleenex watching this lovely film). There are my two cents. Girls kick a**. Forever. Definitely. See you next time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not incredibly memorable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Would be "Stand by Me" for the girls, about growing up and making lasting friendships. The plot from I. Marlene King (a semi-autobiographical piece) has little substance and never really manages to captivate, reducing the target audience to teen girls twelve to sixteen years of age. Director Lesli Linka Glatter's film is almost entirely about "Then" and rarely covers "Now". Top line stars Demi Moore, Melanie Griffith and Rosie O'Donnel are wasted completely, playing less than a handful of paltry scenes. Whatever Miss Glatter was trying to create, she fails to make "Now and Then" into anything incredibly memorable. All pic. contains is a few light hearted adventures of four girls' discovery that they are on the verge of womanhood during the summer of 1970. Christina Ricci, Gaby Hoffman, Thora Birch and Ashleigh Aston Moore (the girls in question) do a reasonable job, but stars Hoffman and Ricci need to be challenged with meatier roles. Average film over all. Saturday, March 30, 1996 - Knox District Centre
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent and clean
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mere Humsafar
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you watch this 1995 movie in 2012, you wish all children grow up in small towns with the simplicity and innocence that comes with it.. it has its own share of maturity, " it is normal when things are shitty ".. the movie shows that real understanding can lead to a life-long friendship among four characteristically different kids..one having a tragic past, another having quarrelling parents, yet another being given unreal sex education by an embarrassed, yet caring mother.. The kids have done excellent acting.. the pace is smooth.. the biggest lesson comes from from a mysterious man who visits a particular grave in a cemetery.. A must-see for all parents and also for all children who want to avoid loneliness
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    angelawang
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Now And Then' is about a group of women who return to their old treehouse and reminisce about the one summer that truly changed their lives... With an all star cast, 'Now And Then' features Melanie Griffith, Demi Moore, Rita Wilson and Rosie O'Donnell, with Thora Birch, Gaby Hoffman, Ashleigh Aston Moore and Christina Ricci playing their younger counterparts. Teen star Christina Ricci ('Casper', 'The Adams Family') is great - as is Ricci's 'Gold Diggers' co-star, Ashleigh Aston Moore - as the mis-informed Chrissy. Bonnie Hunt ('Jumangi') and Devon Sawa ('Wild America') also star. The story is great - plenty of laughs to be had here, with sad moments, too. The acting is A-Grade (the young girls look very promising) and the finished product is a film all the cast should be proud of.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Can be a nostalgic flick for girls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching this reminded me of the Korean movie "Sunny" although this came out first. Well it wouldn't be a shock if the director of "Sunny" was influenced by this movie. The dialogue however didn't seem as natural sometimes and seemed like watching some southern novel that isn't really down to earth. It just didn't seem like what a group of women would be saying to each other, but than again the story switches back from the 70's to 90's when it comes to the characters. The dialogue just seemed too safe to be natural despite the sexual stuff and it's a girly movie. Since the 4 main character are 4 girls in the 70's and women in the 90's. Anyways the story is about 4 women getting together after spending there childhood together and reminisce of the past and adventures they had together. Although most of it takes place during a summer. Now I am not a fan of Rosie O'Donnell, to be honest I think she is irritating to watch sometimes. Her character is like the main character or leader of the pack and I thought it was ridiculous her younger version would be played by Christina Ricci. Not that I am a fan of Ricci either, but the comparison is too big to the point you can get confused who is who sometimes when it comes to the younger version with the older version or visa versa. So yeah I don't know if Rosie picked her younger version but it's just absurd. Overall this is a touching movie that most girls and maybe some boys will probably enjoy watching and parents will probably enjoy it as well. It really does give off a nostalgic feel because of the friendship, even if you didn't go through the same things the girls did in the movie. I give this movie a 6.8 because the development of the characters aren't done all that great and somethings are not explained and not for good reasons. Some say this is a female version of "Stand By Me" and I agree to certain extent. 6.8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    aging world
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Now and Then" isn't really anything that I would recommend. It's about some women reminiscing about what happened in their lives in summer 1970. The truly interesting subplot was their search for the story of the deceased boy, but the whole movie came across as contrived. "Stand by Me" was similar but much grittier. This movie isn't terrible, but I just got the feeling that there wasn't much to it. Maybe I like it too much when movies contain a lot of historical context, and so I kept waiting for "Now and Then" to depict the Vietnam War on TV. Anyway, all the cast members have done much better roles. To be certain, Thora Birch co-starred in "American Beauty" a few years after this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doctorjagger
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is horrible all over. It is compared to "Stand By Me". That movie is a classic. This one does not even come close to measuring up to SBM. Some say this is an inspirational movie for young girls. Just so you know, they are wrong! If you're a parent do not show this to your child. It promotes sexism in the worst ways. The girls as children are all persecuted by boys. This is taken to the absolute extreme. This is not like real life. Every interaction with the boys these girls have they act as if they are being attacked. In response they proceed to become violent physically, verbally, and by their actions. This is a horrible movie and a bad influence. 0/10. Do not watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, But Not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    NotPavlovsDog
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just recently watched "Now and Then" again, I decided to check out what other people thought. Reading through a lot of the comments, I noticed that many compared this film to Rob Reiner's "Stand By Me." I guess I would consider the two to be of the same genre (coming of age), but, to me, that's really the only thing the two have in common. "Now and Then" is a fun film. It's got quick and easy laughs that many (not just teenage girls) people will find humorous. I will say that "Then" is vastly more entertaining than "Now"; the adult versions of the characters briefly open and close the story, with forgettable filler in between. "Then" offers some slight depth of character for the four girls who embody stereotypes of adolescent girls (the princess, the tomboy, the sheltered one, the seemingly normal one). "Now" still embraces those stereotypes (the princess has become an actress, still obsessed with body image; the normal one has become a writer, who showcases her intellect by wearing black and smoking). There is no growth amongst the adults. "Now" is focused on Chrissy's pregnancy and reminiscing, while "Then" seems to get distracted amongst its various subplots (unraveling Crazy Pete, watching parents fight, bicker with boys, watch movies, build a tree house, ride bikes) without ever really coming to a true conclusion. For a movie hailed as a "Stand By Me" for girls, the film is lacking in its overall sincerity. Whereas Reiner's film grapples (and in some cases overcomes) 'mature' themes like death, acceptance, and separation, Glatter's film skates over the big issues. "Stand By Me" captures true childhood friendship (friends help friends get leeches off their backs) "Now and Then" is only truly poignant, well, now and then. I'd recommend "Now and Then" for a time when you are in the mood for something lighthearted and distracting. I'd second the opinion that it's great for a girl's sleepover or something. But if you are looking for something a little deeper and, in my opinion, more true to childhood friendship, I'd tell you to skip this movie and go straight to "Stand By Me." Note: "Stand By Me" is rated R; "Now and Then" PG-13. Both films have great soundtracks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sloppy Production Values and Continuity, BAD Acting from the Adults
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deetdee12
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, all 4 younger actresses are quite engaging, likable and amazingly unaffected---they can even almost sell me on the "Stand by Me" plot rip off (or what passes for a plot). I don't mind sweet, small town retro (that never really existed) and I am a feminist, so girl power is fine by me. BUT...it still doesn't cut it. For starters, all the homes exteriors are unquestionably mid-80's/90's style homes. EVERY house should have been a split level or a ranch (I grew up in exactly that type of sub division). While the interiors are overall more accurate,. houses that small wouldn't possibly have such large interior rooms. Teeny's room has painted art deco furniture---fashionable in 1995, NOT 1970 (and Teeny appears to be the wealthiest of the group). Really, couldn't they have borrowed "The Wonder Years" set? The other thing is the truly, utterly horrible acting from the adults. Rita Wilson portrays Chrissy as fully mentally unbalanced. Keeps her home exactly the way her mother had it decorated??? Races around like a shrill harpy??? I kept waiting for someone in a white coat with a net to come and take her away. Yes, she could be nerdy and traditional--that doesn't equal totally crazy. Since they're also all 37 now, it doesn't hold water on that level (they all still act twelve, with apologies to 12 year old). Unless she had serious fertility problems, Chrissy would have wanted to get pregnant the second she got married. Athletic, cute Christina Ricci turns into fat, ugly Rosie O'Donnnel??? And Melanie Griffith (more like 18 in 1970) is already far too old, and simply horrible. In all, if nothing else is on, watch it. But it isn't even fun in a campy way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Used to Like It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dmills9
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was a teen I loved this film. I thought it was great. I don't know what I was thinking. Although the acting is fine, there are so many off elements here that I can't believe I sat through the whole thing. For one thing, I would not let my teenager watch this. Their focus on sex is astounding for a group of 4 twelve year olds. Yuck! This is sooo disturbing to me. I assume that when I was a teen and that was on my mind constantly I was relating to them and their curiosity, but that also would have caused me to think of those things even more, which is (I'm sure) not what any parent wants for their child. There are also the regular profane outbursts by one particular child, the fights and more that promote a way of life that is not desirable for children and that I cannot be entertained by them acting it out. If you are going to watch this, please leave the kids out of it. You don't want them molded into this 'cool' persona.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A comedy for the ages
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danmax
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film. Well, let's be honest, I will love any movie with Roseanne. Add Demi "Mrs. Kutcher" Moore, Melanie "Mrs. Banderas" Griffith, and you will just have a bang. The story goes back and forth between now and then, and it is a testament of the power of female friendship. The heroes, or maybe I should call them She-roes, are able to stand by each other through thick and thin. I know that some men cried (not me, but i know for a fact that my friend Derek went through a full box of Kleenex watching this lovely film). There are my two cents. Girls kick a**. Forever. Definitely. See you next time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not incredibly memorable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Would be "Stand by Me" for the girls, about growing up and making lasting friendships. The plot from I. Marlene King (a semi-autobiographical piece) has little substance and never really manages to captivate, reducing the target audience to teen girls twelve to sixteen years of age. Director Lesli Linka Glatter's film is almost entirely about "Then" and rarely covers "Now". Top line stars Demi Moore, Melanie Griffith and Rosie O'Donnel are wasted completely, playing less than a handful of paltry scenes. Whatever Miss Glatter was trying to create, she fails to make "Now and Then" into anything incredibly memorable. All pic. contains is a few light hearted adventures of four girls' discovery that they are on the verge of womanhood during the summer of 1970. Christina Ricci, Gaby Hoffman, Thora Birch and Ashleigh Aston Moore (the girls in question) do a reasonable job, but stars Hoffman and Ricci need to be challenged with meatier roles. Average film over all. Saturday, March 30, 1996 - Knox District Centre
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
