<filme>
 <id>
  1054
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0117102
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Deu Tudo Errado
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  3.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A single and lonely woman finds the seemingly perfect man to date, but soon regrets it when his deranged and possessive other personality emerges and worst still, she cannot convince anyone else of his Jekyll/Hyde true nature.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Martha is a single woman working at a television talk show. When her younger sister gets married, everyone's wondering when Martha is going to meet Mr. Right and tie the knot. When by chance, Martha meets a handsome stranger named Whitman, the two fall madly in love with each other. But soon Martha discovers little quirks in Whitman... little quirks that become horrifying nightmares. But by the time Martha realizes that she must break up with him, it'll take more than subtle hints to make him go away -- she'll have to get into the most outrageous predicaments to rid herself of Mr. Wrong.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   date
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   single woman
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   threat
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   wedding
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   jukebox
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Nick Castle
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Chris Matheson
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Kerry Ehrin
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Ellen DeGeneres
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Bill Pullman
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Joan Cusack
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ellen Goes Wrong
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thirty-one and still single Ellen DeGeneres (as Martha Alston) works on an early morning TV talk show in San Diego. She's feeling intense pressure to get married, but has no luck. There is attractive John Livingston (as Walter) at work, but Ms. DeGeneres considers him too boyish. Suddenly, while listening to Chris Isaak's version of Hank Williams' "I'm So Lonesome I Could Cry" on a jukebox, DeGeneres meets a man who seems to be "Mr. Right". Investor and poetry writer Bill Pullman (as Whitman Crawford) and DeGeneres have a whirlwind romance. All goes well until Mr. Pullman proves himself to be "Mr. Wrong"... This comedy is based on an outdated premise and DeGeneres is far too modern and intelligent for her role. She's witty, but stuck in an unfunny situation. More thoughtful acting is needed to overcome these hurdles... Pullman and director Nick Castle make the scenes involving the personality change interesting to watch, at least. After this, the film becomes unfocused and farcical. When the action switches to Mexico, some of it looks poorly improvised. In the "mother" roles, Joan Plowright and Polly Holliday are serviceable. Detective Dean Stockwell (as Jack Tramonte) has one good bit, when he switches allegiance. Joan Cusack (as Inga Gunther) is more annoying than funny. Her rotund sidekick, Brad Henke is better off solo. The best impressions are made by Mr. Livingston and photographer John Schwartzman. **** Mr. Wrong (2/16/96) Nick Castle ~ Ellen DeGeneres, Bill Pullman, John Livingston, Joan Cusack
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite shocked at how bad this film was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I do love comedy, and I like romance, together they can be a mixed bag. Some work, some don't. Mr. Wrong sadly is one of those romantic comedy films that doesn't work. In fact I was quite shocked at how bad the film was. It does have a talented cast, Ellen DeGeneres, Bill Pullman and Joan Cusack, but they are wasted by tedious direction, a predictable story, shallow and clich&eacute;d characters and unfunny and unfocused script. DeGeneres can be very funny, but because of her material even she is quite horrendous. Pullman is bland, and Cusack tries hard but it is an example of wasted talent at the end of the day. The pace is off as well, the film just ambles along and at no point does it recover. The film looks okay locations wise, but the editing could have been tighter. Overall, lame and unfunny and makes a waste of a good cast, as far as the movies of 1996 go it is not as abysmal as Ed and Bio Dome but it is among the worst. 1/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mr. Frightening!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a PG-13 rated film which came into theatres when I was a little less than 9&frac12; years old, so I was too young to see it and never heard of it at the time. Sometime probably in the late nineties, I noticed a copy of "Mr. Wrong" in the video store, and after that happened, I could remember the front cover but not the title. It wasn't until probably sometime within the past couple years that I finally came across a copy of it again, and this time, I saw that the woman on the front cover was Ellen DeGeneres. I wouldn't have recognized her the first time I saw that cover, and am still not THAT familiar with her work, but at least I found her amusing as the voice of Dory in "Finding Nemo". This film, however, has left me flabbergasted, and not in a good way! Martha Alston is a shy talk show producer who is still single at the age of 31, when she watches her younger sister get married. The older Alston sister is pressured by her parents and coworkers to find her true love, but things don't look good for her after an unsuccessful blind date on Valentine's Day. Depressed, she goes to a bar, where she meets a charming man named Whitman Crawford, and soon falls in love. So, does this mean Martha's search is over and she has finally found her Mr. Right? Well, it certainly does look like it at first, but unfortunately, it doesn't last. After a while, it's clear to her that Whitman is actually a nutcase, and not a 100% law-abiding citizen. When Martha wants to break up with him, he just won't get a clue, and it doesn't help that his jealous and insane ex-girlfriend, Inga Gunther, who has a big accomplice named Bob, threatens violence on Martha if she doesn't stay away from Whitman! For much of the film, I wasn't sure if I had any right to judge it. Nothing was making me laugh, and I found the beginning of Martha and Whitman's relationship to be badly scripted and not the only part the can be described that way. However, I was wondering if the film was actually bad, or I just wasn't getting it. I did some research before watching "Mr. Wrong" and heard it described as a "chick flick," and I'm not female. As I watched, that "chick flick" description was making sense to me. If I had the same feeling throughout the film, I doubt I would be writing a review of it, but things change later on. To me, it remained unfunny, but eventually got really weird and little disturbing! Towards the end, it no longer looked like much of a "chick flick" to me. It basically just looked like one insane story! Bill Pullman is quite lame as Whitman, a character who seems to be a maniac for the sake of being a maniac, and Joan Cusack is also lame here, in the role of Inga, and I've certainly seen her do much better. Watching these characters putting poor Martha through a nightmarish adventure is not fun! Even if this didn't do well back when it was released fifteen years ago and is still somewhat obscure today, it does seem to have a following. I've looked at the votes for this film, and have seen that the female rating is bit higher than the male one, but still certainly not high. Even if this 1996 romantic comedy has more female fans than male, it clearly has impressed some male viewers, and even with the "chick flick" label, there are definitely female viewers dislike it more than I do. Many of those who like "Mr. Wrong" might say that I'm of the wrong gender to get this film, and/or I don't have the right experience to get it, and they may be right, especially with the latter, but I will still say that I personally agree with the low rating here. If you like this film, regardless of your gender, that's cool with me, and I'm still not 100% sure whether I should have written this review or not, but there's not a single film in the world that can impress absolutely everybody who sees it, and I think I will always be one who doesn't like this particular romantic comedy, for whatever reason.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Terrible, NOT black comedy people!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    apefoot
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying that the only reason I gave this movie a 2 was because Ellen is awesome. But really the movie itself deserves a 1, if not a 0. Let me address the defense that this is a "black comedy": Definition of black comedy: "Black comedy or dark comedy is a sub-genre of comedy and satire in which topics and events that are usually regarded as taboo, are treated in an unusually humorous or satirical manner while retaining their seriousness. The intent of black comedy, therefore, is often for the audience to experience both laughter and discomfort, sometimes even simultaneously." I did not at any point experience laughter during this movie, except while laughing at how terrible it is. Perhaps one could argue that the topic of stalking is the element of black comedy here, but in no way does this movie, with its "madcap" soundtrack and completely horrible script, "retain its seriousness." If you want a black comedy, then go watch "Death to Smoochy," or even better, Todd Solondz's brilliant "Happiness." Don't watch this dreck. Also, the scene where she is supposedly high on LSD (oft-named by this movie's necessarily idiotic supporters as one of it's funniest) is only funny because the filmmakers so clearly have no idea what it is like to be on hallucinogens. If you absolutely must watch this, get drunk during it so that at the end, it seems funny rather than infuriating that you just wasted two hours of your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too Bad Mr. Or Ms.Right Didn't Write The Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    getyourdander
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What we got here is a wasted but talented cast not being able to over-come a script which was not ready for being filmed. The script is so bad that it even makes the directing and continuity make no sense. Ellen herself is a great talent. I am glad she got married recently as she deserves happiness as much as anyone, and even though her idea of marriage does not match everyones, she is as sincere in it as anyone else is in their beliefs. Along with that, my wife doesn't have to worry if I should ever meet her as with both of us married & sincere, safety is assured. It has turned out the historic irony of this films title reflects the entertainment value of the film. It is the right cast, with the wrong script and the wrong filmmakers. That Ellen has not been slowed down by this shows how much talent she has. I am not sure my talent would survive anything near this. If I were ever on her hit daytime show, I'd congratulate her on that. Being a shy person, I'd be afraid to tell her how attractive I find her, because she is attractive and intelligent, more so than most people. Those qualities are almost totally hidden by this script.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's talk about "black comedy"...and how this is a total failure...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Mr. Wrong" had to be written as a "black comedy", but unfortunately misses the mark by a wide margin. The main problem is that the film is not outrageous enough. Bill Pullman's character resorts to becoming a mean stalker after his rejection by Ellen DeGeneris. At this point the movie turns into nothing more than a glorified cartoon. In order for dark comedy to succeed, it can be outrageous, but not mean spirited. Killing perverts to finance their dream restaurant worked wonders in "Eating Raoul". Here, simply destroying someone's life, for one's own pleasure, is totally off-putting, and not funny. A big disappointment, and definitely not "black comedy". - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite disturbing. Don't know what it's supposed to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    policy134
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's quite horrible. Ellen DeGeneres has been one of my favorite comedians for a long time, but her first foray into feature films was quite a mind blowing experience and mostly in a negative way. It's not that there is anything wrong with the premise. DeGeneres plays a woman who's getting on in years and meets a seemingly perfect man, Whit played by Bill Pullman. He seems to be perfect until Martha (DeGeneres' character) makes the fatal mistake of telling him to be himself. What happens next: Martha discovers he's a complete lunatic. Everyone is terrible in this movie, even a seasoned pro like Dean Stockwell as a slimy private detective and by far the worst comedic performance of that year is performed by Joan Cusack as Whit's even more psychotic ex. If one can call it a redeeming quality, the film does spark some weird curiosity of how it all ends. However, the end is incomprehensible and totally unbelievable. It seems as if the writers just gave up and said: "Well, we can't make it any worse!" DeGeneres hasn't had a starring role since this disaster, although she had a fairly good supporting role in EdTV. What more can you say except this was a total misfire from everyone involved. Bob Goulet did however do a fairly good job of playing, Bob Goulet.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good acting, bad script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Yonzie
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My girlfriend told me to tape this from TV and I had no idea what it was about. Initially I was pleasantly surprised by seeing Bill Pullman in a lead role. The last movie I saw featuring him was "While You Were Sleeping" which I thought was great. Mr. Wrong starts out reasonably good, but fairly quickly the stupidness becomes too much. Ultimately, it is made bearable by good acting from Degeneres and Pullman and a lot of funny moments. The moments in-between was unfortunately not just boring or neutral but plainly painful. This is obvious from the start when Martha Alstons (Degeneres) secretary brays on about receiving flowers from her boyfriend on valentine's day and Martha returns it in a totally non-funny way. I guess it could have been funny, but it was just painful to watch. Repeat ad nauseum with some genuinely funny moments in-between and you have this movie. In conclusion, its watchable and good for a few laughs, but if there's something more interesting available, just steer clear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Under the radar...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    whraglyn-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...and dropping bombs on marriage, men, and mainstream American culture. Isn't it interesting that this film was released BEFORE she outed herself? IOW, this film was intended to subvert cultural norms regarding marriage, but it wouldn't work at all, (as badly as it DOES work), if the viewer knows the protagonist is a lesbian. Another question: Why does Ellen keep getting funding for her projects, when her record of success is precisely zero? Every film or TV show she has done has lost money for it's producers. Why do they keep giving her a public platform?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good cast, not so great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    triple8
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS THROUGH: I watched this movie never having heard anything about it so I was able to decide for myself, without knowing anything about what it was going to be about. I'm not going to say there wasn't any comedy in this movie because there was. There were moments of total hilarity due to an hysterical Bill Pullman who was really in top comedic form. The problem is, when those moments were NOT happening the movie just wasn't very good. It was a great premise but there were a lot of things about the movie overall, that I did not enjoy. This movie was strongest in the beginning, where I thought it was going to be a movie similar to "Bridget Jones Diary". But I felt the movie went downhill fairly quickly. I guess this is what one would call a "black comedy" but as with many of this genre, I felt the movie was to focused on the meanness and not so much on the comedy. When Pullman's character first starts unraveling it's OK but after awhile it becomes a bit of overkill. The movie just becomes way to cruel, as more and more bad things happen to Ellen's character. That's the focus of the movie really, not the comedy. It's almost like the movie's seeing how many awful things can happen to Ellen'c character, and how much of her life can be destroyed etc etc. It didn't make me laugh, it made me a bit dazed and frankly I just wanted the movie to end. Throwing ants and gum on someone, and that person losing their job etc etc is not what I consider to be funny. The truly funny moments existed when Pullman was on screen because, as utterly annoying as his character came to be, he was hilarious. So yes there were a few moments where I laughed out loud. But those moments did not make the movie, for me, a great one. Another thing I didn't like was that the movie became way to over the top, a Virtual cornucopia of melodrama. Inga & Bob,rather then being funny, were a bit obnoxious. The whole wedding storyline was way to much. And the movie felt so LONG. I mean I know it wasn't but it FELT like it was. Ellen was very good as the lead though and Pullman, as mentioned was REALLY good and should probably have his own comedy television show. In a way I think I would have liked this better as a straight on comedy without the mean element or as a romance where Pullman's character did NOT change but stayed Normal. Or maybe even as a thriller or a film Noir. Basically I just felt this movie didn't work as a black comedy. I wouldn't consider this one of the worst movies ever made however. I would not recommend it either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ellen Goes Wrong
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thirty-one and still single Ellen DeGeneres (as Martha Alston) works on an early morning TV talk show in San Diego. She's feeling intense pressure to get married, but has no luck. There is attractive John Livingston (as Walter) at work, but Ms. DeGeneres considers him too boyish. Suddenly, while listening to Chris Isaak's version of Hank Williams' "I'm So Lonesome I Could Cry" on a jukebox, DeGeneres meets a man who seems to be "Mr. Right". Investor and poetry writer Bill Pullman (as Whitman Crawford) and DeGeneres have a whirlwind romance. All goes well until Mr. Pullman proves himself to be "Mr. Wrong"... This comedy is based on an outdated premise and DeGeneres is far too modern and intelligent for her role. She's witty, but stuck in an unfunny situation. More thoughtful acting is needed to overcome these hurdles... Pullman and director Nick Castle make the scenes involving the personality change interesting to watch, at least. After this, the film becomes unfocused and farcical. When the action switches to Mexico, some of it looks poorly improvised. In the "mother" roles, Joan Plowright and Polly Holliday are serviceable. Detective Dean Stockwell (as Jack Tramonte) has one good bit, when he switches allegiance. Joan Cusack (as Inga Gunther) is more annoying than funny. Her rotund sidekick, Brad Henke is better off solo. The best impressions are made by Mr. Livingston and photographer John Schwartzman. **** Mr. Wrong (2/16/96) Nick Castle ~ Ellen DeGeneres, Bill Pullman, John Livingston, Joan Cusack
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite shocked at how bad this film was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I do love comedy, and I like romance, together they can be a mixed bag. Some work, some don't. Mr. Wrong sadly is one of those romantic comedy films that doesn't work. In fact I was quite shocked at how bad the film was. It does have a talented cast, Ellen DeGeneres, Bill Pullman and Joan Cusack, but they are wasted by tedious direction, a predictable story, shallow and clich&eacute;d characters and unfunny and unfocused script. DeGeneres can be very funny, but because of her material even she is quite horrendous. Pullman is bland, and Cusack tries hard but it is an example of wasted talent at the end of the day. The pace is off as well, the film just ambles along and at no point does it recover. The film looks okay locations wise, but the editing could have been tighter. Overall, lame and unfunny and makes a waste of a good cast, as far as the movies of 1996 go it is not as abysmal as Ed and Bio Dome but it is among the worst. 1/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mr. Frightening!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a PG-13 rated film which came into theatres when I was a little less than 9&frac12; years old, so I was too young to see it and never heard of it at the time. Sometime probably in the late nineties, I noticed a copy of "Mr. Wrong" in the video store, and after that happened, I could remember the front cover but not the title. It wasn't until probably sometime within the past couple years that I finally came across a copy of it again, and this time, I saw that the woman on the front cover was Ellen DeGeneres. I wouldn't have recognized her the first time I saw that cover, and am still not THAT familiar with her work, but at least I found her amusing as the voice of Dory in "Finding Nemo". This film, however, has left me flabbergasted, and not in a good way! Martha Alston is a shy talk show producer who is still single at the age of 31, when she watches her younger sister get married. The older Alston sister is pressured by her parents and coworkers to find her true love, but things don't look good for her after an unsuccessful blind date on Valentine's Day. Depressed, she goes to a bar, where she meets a charming man named Whitman Crawford, and soon falls in love. So, does this mean Martha's search is over and she has finally found her Mr. Right? Well, it certainly does look like it at first, but unfortunately, it doesn't last. After a while, it's clear to her that Whitman is actually a nutcase, and not a 100% law-abiding citizen. When Martha wants to break up with him, he just won't get a clue, and it doesn't help that his jealous and insane ex-girlfriend, Inga Gunther, who has a big accomplice named Bob, threatens violence on Martha if she doesn't stay away from Whitman! For much of the film, I wasn't sure if I had any right to judge it. Nothing was making me laugh, and I found the beginning of Martha and Whitman's relationship to be badly scripted and not the only part the can be described that way. However, I was wondering if the film was actually bad, or I just wasn't getting it. I did some research before watching "Mr. Wrong" and heard it described as a "chick flick," and I'm not female. As I watched, that "chick flick" description was making sense to me. If I had the same feeling throughout the film, I doubt I would be writing a review of it, but things change later on. To me, it remained unfunny, but eventually got really weird and little disturbing! Towards the end, it no longer looked like much of a "chick flick" to me. It basically just looked like one insane story! Bill Pullman is quite lame as Whitman, a character who seems to be a maniac for the sake of being a maniac, and Joan Cusack is also lame here, in the role of Inga, and I've certainly seen her do much better. Watching these characters putting poor Martha through a nightmarish adventure is not fun! Even if this didn't do well back when it was released fifteen years ago and is still somewhat obscure today, it does seem to have a following. I've looked at the votes for this film, and have seen that the female rating is bit higher than the male one, but still certainly not high. Even if this 1996 romantic comedy has more female fans than male, it clearly has impressed some male viewers, and even with the "chick flick" label, there are definitely female viewers dislike it more than I do. Many of those who like "Mr. Wrong" might say that I'm of the wrong gender to get this film, and/or I don't have the right experience to get it, and they may be right, especially with the latter, but I will still say that I personally agree with the low rating here. If you like this film, regardless of your gender, that's cool with me, and I'm still not 100% sure whether I should have written this review or not, but there's not a single film in the world that can impress absolutely everybody who sees it, and I think I will always be one who doesn't like this particular romantic comedy, for whatever reason.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Terrible, NOT black comedy people!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    apefoot
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying that the only reason I gave this movie a 2 was because Ellen is awesome. But really the movie itself deserves a 1, if not a 0. Let me address the defense that this is a "black comedy": Definition of black comedy: "Black comedy or dark comedy is a sub-genre of comedy and satire in which topics and events that are usually regarded as taboo, are treated in an unusually humorous or satirical manner while retaining their seriousness. The intent of black comedy, therefore, is often for the audience to experience both laughter and discomfort, sometimes even simultaneously." I did not at any point experience laughter during this movie, except while laughing at how terrible it is. Perhaps one could argue that the topic of stalking is the element of black comedy here, but in no way does this movie, with its "madcap" soundtrack and completely horrible script, "retain its seriousness." If you want a black comedy, then go watch "Death to Smoochy," or even better, Todd Solondz's brilliant "Happiness." Don't watch this dreck. Also, the scene where she is supposedly high on LSD (oft-named by this movie's necessarily idiotic supporters as one of it's funniest) is only funny because the filmmakers so clearly have no idea what it is like to be on hallucinogens. If you absolutely must watch this, get drunk during it so that at the end, it seems funny rather than infuriating that you just wasted two hours of your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too Bad Mr. Or Ms.Right Didn't Write The Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    getyourdander
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What we got here is a wasted but talented cast not being able to over-come a script which was not ready for being filmed. The script is so bad that it even makes the directing and continuity make no sense. Ellen herself is a great talent. I am glad she got married recently as she deserves happiness as much as anyone, and even though her idea of marriage does not match everyones, she is as sincere in it as anyone else is in their beliefs. Along with that, my wife doesn't have to worry if I should ever meet her as with both of us married & sincere, safety is assured. It has turned out the historic irony of this films title reflects the entertainment value of the film. It is the right cast, with the wrong script and the wrong filmmakers. That Ellen has not been slowed down by this shows how much talent she has. I am not sure my talent would survive anything near this. If I were ever on her hit daytime show, I'd congratulate her on that. Being a shy person, I'd be afraid to tell her how attractive I find her, because she is attractive and intelligent, more so than most people. Those qualities are almost totally hidden by this script.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's talk about "black comedy"...and how this is a total failure...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Mr. Wrong" had to be written as a "black comedy", but unfortunately misses the mark by a wide margin. The main problem is that the film is not outrageous enough. Bill Pullman's character resorts to becoming a mean stalker after his rejection by Ellen DeGeneris. At this point the movie turns into nothing more than a glorified cartoon. In order for dark comedy to succeed, it can be outrageous, but not mean spirited. Killing perverts to finance their dream restaurant worked wonders in "Eating Raoul". Here, simply destroying someone's life, for one's own pleasure, is totally off-putting, and not funny. A big disappointment, and definitely not "black comedy". - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite disturbing. Don't know what it's supposed to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    policy134
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's quite horrible. Ellen DeGeneres has been one of my favorite comedians for a long time, but her first foray into feature films was quite a mind blowing experience and mostly in a negative way. It's not that there is anything wrong with the premise. DeGeneres plays a woman who's getting on in years and meets a seemingly perfect man, Whit played by Bill Pullman. He seems to be perfect until Martha (DeGeneres' character) makes the fatal mistake of telling him to be himself. What happens next: Martha discovers he's a complete lunatic. Everyone is terrible in this movie, even a seasoned pro like Dean Stockwell as a slimy private detective and by far the worst comedic performance of that year is performed by Joan Cusack as Whit's even more psychotic ex. If one can call it a redeeming quality, the film does spark some weird curiosity of how it all ends. However, the end is incomprehensible and totally unbelievable. It seems as if the writers just gave up and said: "Well, we can't make it any worse!" DeGeneres hasn't had a starring role since this disaster, although she had a fairly good supporting role in EdTV. What more can you say except this was a total misfire from everyone involved. Bob Goulet did however do a fairly good job of playing, Bob Goulet.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good acting, bad script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Yonzie
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My girlfriend told me to tape this from TV and I had no idea what it was about. Initially I was pleasantly surprised by seeing Bill Pullman in a lead role. The last movie I saw featuring him was "While You Were Sleeping" which I thought was great. Mr. Wrong starts out reasonably good, but fairly quickly the stupidness becomes too much. Ultimately, it is made bearable by good acting from Degeneres and Pullman and a lot of funny moments. The moments in-between was unfortunately not just boring or neutral but plainly painful. This is obvious from the start when Martha Alstons (Degeneres) secretary brays on about receiving flowers from her boyfriend on valentine's day and Martha returns it in a totally non-funny way. I guess it could have been funny, but it was just painful to watch. Repeat ad nauseum with some genuinely funny moments in-between and you have this movie. In conclusion, its watchable and good for a few laughs, but if there's something more interesting available, just steer clear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Under the radar...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    whraglyn-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...and dropping bombs on marriage, men, and mainstream American culture. Isn't it interesting that this film was released BEFORE she outed herself? IOW, this film was intended to subvert cultural norms regarding marriage, but it wouldn't work at all, (as badly as it DOES work), if the viewer knows the protagonist is a lesbian. Another question: Why does Ellen keep getting funding for her projects, when her record of success is precisely zero? Every film or TV show she has done has lost money for it's producers. Why do they keep giving her a public platform?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good cast, not so great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    triple8
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS THROUGH: I watched this movie never having heard anything about it so I was able to decide for myself, without knowing anything about what it was going to be about. I'm not going to say there wasn't any comedy in this movie because there was. There were moments of total hilarity due to an hysterical Bill Pullman who was really in top comedic form. The problem is, when those moments were NOT happening the movie just wasn't very good. It was a great premise but there were a lot of things about the movie overall, that I did not enjoy. This movie was strongest in the beginning, where I thought it was going to be a movie similar to "Bridget Jones Diary". But I felt the movie went downhill fairly quickly. I guess this is what one would call a "black comedy" but as with many of this genre, I felt the movie was to focused on the meanness and not so much on the comedy. When Pullman's character first starts unraveling it's OK but after awhile it becomes a bit of overkill. The movie just becomes way to cruel, as more and more bad things happen to Ellen's character. That's the focus of the movie really, not the comedy. It's almost like the movie's seeing how many awful things can happen to Ellen'c character, and how much of her life can be destroyed etc etc. It didn't make me laugh, it made me a bit dazed and frankly I just wanted the movie to end. Throwing ants and gum on someone, and that person losing their job etc etc is not what I consider to be funny. The truly funny moments existed when Pullman was on screen because, as utterly annoying as his character came to be, he was hilarious. So yes there were a few moments where I laughed out loud. But those moments did not make the movie, for me, a great one. Another thing I didn't like was that the movie became way to over the top, a Virtual cornucopia of melodrama. Inga & Bob,rather then being funny, were a bit obnoxious. The whole wedding storyline was way to much. And the movie felt so LONG. I mean I know it wasn't but it FELT like it was. Ellen was very good as the lead though and Pullman, as mentioned was REALLY good and should probably have his own comedy television show. In a way I think I would have liked this better as a straight on comedy without the mean element or as a romance where Pullman's character did NOT change but stayed Normal. Or maybe even as a thriller or a film Noir. Basically I just felt this movie didn't work as a black comedy. I wouldn't consider this one of the worst movies ever made however. I would not recommend it either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ellen Goes Wrong
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thirty-one and still single Ellen DeGeneres (as Martha Alston) works on an early morning TV talk show in San Diego. She's feeling intense pressure to get married, but has no luck. There is attractive John Livingston (as Walter) at work, but Ms. DeGeneres considers him too boyish. Suddenly, while listening to Chris Isaak's version of Hank Williams' "I'm So Lonesome I Could Cry" on a jukebox, DeGeneres meets a man who seems to be "Mr. Right". Investor and poetry writer Bill Pullman (as Whitman Crawford) and DeGeneres have a whirlwind romance. All goes well until Mr. Pullman proves himself to be "Mr. Wrong"... This comedy is based on an outdated premise and DeGeneres is far too modern and intelligent for her role. She's witty, but stuck in an unfunny situation. More thoughtful acting is needed to overcome these hurdles... Pullman and director Nick Castle make the scenes involving the personality change interesting to watch, at least. After this, the film becomes unfocused and farcical. When the action switches to Mexico, some of it looks poorly improvised. In the "mother" roles, Joan Plowright and Polly Holliday are serviceable. Detective Dean Stockwell (as Jack Tramonte) has one good bit, when he switches allegiance. Joan Cusack (as Inga Gunther) is more annoying than funny. Her rotund sidekick, Brad Henke is better off solo. The best impressions are made by Mr. Livingston and photographer John Schwartzman. **** Mr. Wrong (2/16/96) Nick Castle ~ Ellen DeGeneres, Bill Pullman, John Livingston, Joan Cusack
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite shocked at how bad this film was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I do love comedy, and I like romance, together they can be a mixed bag. Some work, some don't. Mr. Wrong sadly is one of those romantic comedy films that doesn't work. In fact I was quite shocked at how bad the film was. It does have a talented cast, Ellen DeGeneres, Bill Pullman and Joan Cusack, but they are wasted by tedious direction, a predictable story, shallow and clich&eacute;d characters and unfunny and unfocused script. DeGeneres can be very funny, but because of her material even she is quite horrendous. Pullman is bland, and Cusack tries hard but it is an example of wasted talent at the end of the day. The pace is off as well, the film just ambles along and at no point does it recover. The film looks okay locations wise, but the editing could have been tighter. Overall, lame and unfunny and makes a waste of a good cast, as far as the movies of 1996 go it is not as abysmal as Ed and Bio Dome but it is among the worst. 1/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mr. Frightening!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a PG-13 rated film which came into theatres when I was a little less than 9&frac12; years old, so I was too young to see it and never heard of it at the time. Sometime probably in the late nineties, I noticed a copy of "Mr. Wrong" in the video store, and after that happened, I could remember the front cover but not the title. It wasn't until probably sometime within the past couple years that I finally came across a copy of it again, and this time, I saw that the woman on the front cover was Ellen DeGeneres. I wouldn't have recognized her the first time I saw that cover, and am still not THAT familiar with her work, but at least I found her amusing as the voice of Dory in "Finding Nemo". This film, however, has left me flabbergasted, and not in a good way! Martha Alston is a shy talk show producer who is still single at the age of 31, when she watches her younger sister get married. The older Alston sister is pressured by her parents and coworkers to find her true love, but things don't look good for her after an unsuccessful blind date on Valentine's Day. Depressed, she goes to a bar, where she meets a charming man named Whitman Crawford, and soon falls in love. So, does this mean Martha's search is over and she has finally found her Mr. Right? Well, it certainly does look like it at first, but unfortunately, it doesn't last. After a while, it's clear to her that Whitman is actually a nutcase, and not a 100% law-abiding citizen. When Martha wants to break up with him, he just won't get a clue, and it doesn't help that his jealous and insane ex-girlfriend, Inga Gunther, who has a big accomplice named Bob, threatens violence on Martha if she doesn't stay away from Whitman! For much of the film, I wasn't sure if I had any right to judge it. Nothing was making me laugh, and I found the beginning of Martha and Whitman's relationship to be badly scripted and not the only part the can be described that way. However, I was wondering if the film was actually bad, or I just wasn't getting it. I did some research before watching "Mr. Wrong" and heard it described as a "chick flick," and I'm not female. As I watched, that "chick flick" description was making sense to me. If I had the same feeling throughout the film, I doubt I would be writing a review of it, but things change later on. To me, it remained unfunny, but eventually got really weird and little disturbing! Towards the end, it no longer looked like much of a "chick flick" to me. It basically just looked like one insane story! Bill Pullman is quite lame as Whitman, a character who seems to be a maniac for the sake of being a maniac, and Joan Cusack is also lame here, in the role of Inga, and I've certainly seen her do much better. Watching these characters putting poor Martha through a nightmarish adventure is not fun! Even if this didn't do well back when it was released fifteen years ago and is still somewhat obscure today, it does seem to have a following. I've looked at the votes for this film, and have seen that the female rating is bit higher than the male one, but still certainly not high. Even if this 1996 romantic comedy has more female fans than male, it clearly has impressed some male viewers, and even with the "chick flick" label, there are definitely female viewers dislike it more than I do. Many of those who like "Mr. Wrong" might say that I'm of the wrong gender to get this film, and/or I don't have the right experience to get it, and they may be right, especially with the latter, but I will still say that I personally agree with the low rating here. If you like this film, regardless of your gender, that's cool with me, and I'm still not 100% sure whether I should have written this review or not, but there's not a single film in the world that can impress absolutely everybody who sees it, and I think I will always be one who doesn't like this particular romantic comedy, for whatever reason.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Terrible, NOT black comedy people!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    apefoot
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying that the only reason I gave this movie a 2 was because Ellen is awesome. But really the movie itself deserves a 1, if not a 0. Let me address the defense that this is a "black comedy": Definition of black comedy: "Black comedy or dark comedy is a sub-genre of comedy and satire in which topics and events that are usually regarded as taboo, are treated in an unusually humorous or satirical manner while retaining their seriousness. The intent of black comedy, therefore, is often for the audience to experience both laughter and discomfort, sometimes even simultaneously." I did not at any point experience laughter during this movie, except while laughing at how terrible it is. Perhaps one could argue that the topic of stalking is the element of black comedy here, but in no way does this movie, with its "madcap" soundtrack and completely horrible script, "retain its seriousness." If you want a black comedy, then go watch "Death to Smoochy," or even better, Todd Solondz's brilliant "Happiness." Don't watch this dreck. Also, the scene where she is supposedly high on LSD (oft-named by this movie's necessarily idiotic supporters as one of it's funniest) is only funny because the filmmakers so clearly have no idea what it is like to be on hallucinogens. If you absolutely must watch this, get drunk during it so that at the end, it seems funny rather than infuriating that you just wasted two hours of your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too Bad Mr. Or Ms.Right Didn't Write The Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    getyourdander
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What we got here is a wasted but talented cast not being able to over-come a script which was not ready for being filmed. The script is so bad that it even makes the directing and continuity make no sense. Ellen herself is a great talent. I am glad she got married recently as she deserves happiness as much as anyone, and even though her idea of marriage does not match everyones, she is as sincere in it as anyone else is in their beliefs. Along with that, my wife doesn't have to worry if I should ever meet her as with both of us married & sincere, safety is assured. It has turned out the historic irony of this films title reflects the entertainment value of the film. It is the right cast, with the wrong script and the wrong filmmakers. That Ellen has not been slowed down by this shows how much talent she has. I am not sure my talent would survive anything near this. If I were ever on her hit daytime show, I'd congratulate her on that. Being a shy person, I'd be afraid to tell her how attractive I find her, because she is attractive and intelligent, more so than most people. Those qualities are almost totally hidden by this script.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's talk about "black comedy"...and how this is a total failure...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Mr. Wrong" had to be written as a "black comedy", but unfortunately misses the mark by a wide margin. The main problem is that the film is not outrageous enough. Bill Pullman's character resorts to becoming a mean stalker after his rejection by Ellen DeGeneris. At this point the movie turns into nothing more than a glorified cartoon. In order for dark comedy to succeed, it can be outrageous, but not mean spirited. Killing perverts to finance their dream restaurant worked wonders in "Eating Raoul". Here, simply destroying someone's life, for one's own pleasure, is totally off-putting, and not funny. A big disappointment, and definitely not "black comedy". - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite disturbing. Don't know what it's supposed to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    policy134
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's quite horrible. Ellen DeGeneres has been one of my favorite comedians for a long time, but her first foray into feature films was quite a mind blowing experience and mostly in a negative way. It's not that there is anything wrong with the premise. DeGeneres plays a woman who's getting on in years and meets a seemingly perfect man, Whit played by Bill Pullman. He seems to be perfect until Martha (DeGeneres' character) makes the fatal mistake of telling him to be himself. What happens next: Martha discovers he's a complete lunatic. Everyone is terrible in this movie, even a seasoned pro like Dean Stockwell as a slimy private detective and by far the worst comedic performance of that year is performed by Joan Cusack as Whit's even more psychotic ex. If one can call it a redeeming quality, the film does spark some weird curiosity of how it all ends. However, the end is incomprehensible and totally unbelievable. It seems as if the writers just gave up and said: "Well, we can't make it any worse!" DeGeneres hasn't had a starring role since this disaster, although she had a fairly good supporting role in EdTV. What more can you say except this was a total misfire from everyone involved. Bob Goulet did however do a fairly good job of playing, Bob Goulet.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good acting, bad script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Yonzie
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My girlfriend told me to tape this from TV and I had no idea what it was about. Initially I was pleasantly surprised by seeing Bill Pullman in a lead role. The last movie I saw featuring him was "While You Were Sleeping" which I thought was great. Mr. Wrong starts out reasonably good, but fairly quickly the stupidness becomes too much. Ultimately, it is made bearable by good acting from Degeneres and Pullman and a lot of funny moments. The moments in-between was unfortunately not just boring or neutral but plainly painful. This is obvious from the start when Martha Alstons (Degeneres) secretary brays on about receiving flowers from her boyfriend on valentine's day and Martha returns it in a totally non-funny way. I guess it could have been funny, but it was just painful to watch. Repeat ad nauseum with some genuinely funny moments in-between and you have this movie. In conclusion, its watchable and good for a few laughs, but if there's something more interesting available, just steer clear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Under the radar...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    whraglyn-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...and dropping bombs on marriage, men, and mainstream American culture. Isn't it interesting that this film was released BEFORE she outed herself? IOW, this film was intended to subvert cultural norms regarding marriage, but it wouldn't work at all, (as badly as it DOES work), if the viewer knows the protagonist is a lesbian. Another question: Why does Ellen keep getting funding for her projects, when her record of success is precisely zero? Every film or TV show she has done has lost money for it's producers. Why do they keep giving her a public platform?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good cast, not so great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    triple8
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS THROUGH: I watched this movie never having heard anything about it so I was able to decide for myself, without knowing anything about what it was going to be about. I'm not going to say there wasn't any comedy in this movie because there was. There were moments of total hilarity due to an hysterical Bill Pullman who was really in top comedic form. The problem is, when those moments were NOT happening the movie just wasn't very good. It was a great premise but there were a lot of things about the movie overall, that I did not enjoy. This movie was strongest in the beginning, where I thought it was going to be a movie similar to "Bridget Jones Diary". But I felt the movie went downhill fairly quickly. I guess this is what one would call a "black comedy" but as with many of this genre, I felt the movie was to focused on the meanness and not so much on the comedy. When Pullman's character first starts unraveling it's OK but after awhile it becomes a bit of overkill. The movie just becomes way to cruel, as more and more bad things happen to Ellen's character. That's the focus of the movie really, not the comedy. It's almost like the movie's seeing how many awful things can happen to Ellen'c character, and how much of her life can be destroyed etc etc. It didn't make me laugh, it made me a bit dazed and frankly I just wanted the movie to end. Throwing ants and gum on someone, and that person losing their job etc etc is not what I consider to be funny. The truly funny moments existed when Pullman was on screen because, as utterly annoying as his character came to be, he was hilarious. So yes there were a few moments where I laughed out loud. But those moments did not make the movie, for me, a great one. Another thing I didn't like was that the movie became way to over the top, a Virtual cornucopia of melodrama. Inga & Bob,rather then being funny, were a bit obnoxious. The whole wedding storyline was way to much. And the movie felt so LONG. I mean I know it wasn't but it FELT like it was. Ellen was very good as the lead though and Pullman, as mentioned was REALLY good and should probably have his own comedy television show. In a way I think I would have liked this better as a straight on comedy without the mean element or as a romance where Pullman's character did NOT change but stayed Normal. Or maybe even as a thriller or a film Noir. Basically I just felt this movie didn't work as a black comedy. I wouldn't consider this one of the worst movies ever made however. I would not recommend it either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ellen Goes Wrong
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thirty-one and still single Ellen DeGeneres (as Martha Alston) works on an early morning TV talk show in San Diego. She's feeling intense pressure to get married, but has no luck. There is attractive John Livingston (as Walter) at work, but Ms. DeGeneres considers him too boyish. Suddenly, while listening to Chris Isaak's version of Hank Williams' "I'm So Lonesome I Could Cry" on a jukebox, DeGeneres meets a man who seems to be "Mr. Right". Investor and poetry writer Bill Pullman (as Whitman Crawford) and DeGeneres have a whirlwind romance. All goes well until Mr. Pullman proves himself to be "Mr. Wrong"... This comedy is based on an outdated premise and DeGeneres is far too modern and intelligent for her role. She's witty, but stuck in an unfunny situation. More thoughtful acting is needed to overcome these hurdles... Pullman and director Nick Castle make the scenes involving the personality change interesting to watch, at least. After this, the film becomes unfocused and farcical. When the action switches to Mexico, some of it looks poorly improvised. In the "mother" roles, Joan Plowright and Polly Holliday are serviceable. Detective Dean Stockwell (as Jack Tramonte) has one good bit, when he switches allegiance. Joan Cusack (as Inga Gunther) is more annoying than funny. Her rotund sidekick, Brad Henke is better off solo. The best impressions are made by Mr. Livingston and photographer John Schwartzman. **** Mr. Wrong (2/16/96) Nick Castle ~ Ellen DeGeneres, Bill Pullman, John Livingston, Joan Cusack
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite shocked at how bad this film was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I do love comedy, and I like romance, together they can be a mixed bag. Some work, some don't. Mr. Wrong sadly is one of those romantic comedy films that doesn't work. In fact I was quite shocked at how bad the film was. It does have a talented cast, Ellen DeGeneres, Bill Pullman and Joan Cusack, but they are wasted by tedious direction, a predictable story, shallow and clich&eacute;d characters and unfunny and unfocused script. DeGeneres can be very funny, but because of her material even she is quite horrendous. Pullman is bland, and Cusack tries hard but it is an example of wasted talent at the end of the day. The pace is off as well, the film just ambles along and at no point does it recover. The film looks okay locations wise, but the editing could have been tighter. Overall, lame and unfunny and makes a waste of a good cast, as far as the movies of 1996 go it is not as abysmal as Ed and Bio Dome but it is among the worst. 1/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mr. Frightening!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a PG-13 rated film which came into theatres when I was a little less than 9&frac12; years old, so I was too young to see it and never heard of it at the time. Sometime probably in the late nineties, I noticed a copy of "Mr. Wrong" in the video store, and after that happened, I could remember the front cover but not the title. It wasn't until probably sometime within the past couple years that I finally came across a copy of it again, and this time, I saw that the woman on the front cover was Ellen DeGeneres. I wouldn't have recognized her the first time I saw that cover, and am still not THAT familiar with her work, but at least I found her amusing as the voice of Dory in "Finding Nemo". This film, however, has left me flabbergasted, and not in a good way! Martha Alston is a shy talk show producer who is still single at the age of 31, when she watches her younger sister get married. The older Alston sister is pressured by her parents and coworkers to find her true love, but things don't look good for her after an unsuccessful blind date on Valentine's Day. Depressed, she goes to a bar, where she meets a charming man named Whitman Crawford, and soon falls in love. So, does this mean Martha's search is over and she has finally found her Mr. Right? Well, it certainly does look like it at first, but unfortunately, it doesn't last. After a while, it's clear to her that Whitman is actually a nutcase, and not a 100% law-abiding citizen. When Martha wants to break up with him, he just won't get a clue, and it doesn't help that his jealous and insane ex-girlfriend, Inga Gunther, who has a big accomplice named Bob, threatens violence on Martha if she doesn't stay away from Whitman! For much of the film, I wasn't sure if I had any right to judge it. Nothing was making me laugh, and I found the beginning of Martha and Whitman's relationship to be badly scripted and not the only part the can be described that way. However, I was wondering if the film was actually bad, or I just wasn't getting it. I did some research before watching "Mr. Wrong" and heard it described as a "chick flick," and I'm not female. As I watched, that "chick flick" description was making sense to me. If I had the same feeling throughout the film, I doubt I would be writing a review of it, but things change later on. To me, it remained unfunny, but eventually got really weird and little disturbing! Towards the end, it no longer looked like much of a "chick flick" to me. It basically just looked like one insane story! Bill Pullman is quite lame as Whitman, a character who seems to be a maniac for the sake of being a maniac, and Joan Cusack is also lame here, in the role of Inga, and I've certainly seen her do much better. Watching these characters putting poor Martha through a nightmarish adventure is not fun! Even if this didn't do well back when it was released fifteen years ago and is still somewhat obscure today, it does seem to have a following. I've looked at the votes for this film, and have seen that the female rating is bit higher than the male one, but still certainly not high. Even if this 1996 romantic comedy has more female fans than male, it clearly has impressed some male viewers, and even with the "chick flick" label, there are definitely female viewers dislike it more than I do. Many of those who like "Mr. Wrong" might say that I'm of the wrong gender to get this film, and/or I don't have the right experience to get it, and they may be right, especially with the latter, but I will still say that I personally agree with the low rating here. If you like this film, regardless of your gender, that's cool with me, and I'm still not 100% sure whether I should have written this review or not, but there's not a single film in the world that can impress absolutely everybody who sees it, and I think I will always be one who doesn't like this particular romantic comedy, for whatever reason.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Terrible, NOT black comedy people!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    apefoot
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying that the only reason I gave this movie a 2 was because Ellen is awesome. But really the movie itself deserves a 1, if not a 0. Let me address the defense that this is a "black comedy": Definition of black comedy: "Black comedy or dark comedy is a sub-genre of comedy and satire in which topics and events that are usually regarded as taboo, are treated in an unusually humorous or satirical manner while retaining their seriousness. The intent of black comedy, therefore, is often for the audience to experience both laughter and discomfort, sometimes even simultaneously." I did not at any point experience laughter during this movie, except while laughing at how terrible it is. Perhaps one could argue that the topic of stalking is the element of black comedy here, but in no way does this movie, with its "madcap" soundtrack and completely horrible script, "retain its seriousness." If you want a black comedy, then go watch "Death to Smoochy," or even better, Todd Solondz's brilliant "Happiness." Don't watch this dreck. Also, the scene where she is supposedly high on LSD (oft-named by this movie's necessarily idiotic supporters as one of it's funniest) is only funny because the filmmakers so clearly have no idea what it is like to be on hallucinogens. If you absolutely must watch this, get drunk during it so that at the end, it seems funny rather than infuriating that you just wasted two hours of your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too Bad Mr. Or Ms.Right Didn't Write The Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    getyourdander
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What we got here is a wasted but talented cast not being able to over-come a script which was not ready for being filmed. The script is so bad that it even makes the directing and continuity make no sense. Ellen herself is a great talent. I am glad she got married recently as she deserves happiness as much as anyone, and even though her idea of marriage does not match everyones, she is as sincere in it as anyone else is in their beliefs. Along with that, my wife doesn't have to worry if I should ever meet her as with both of us married & sincere, safety is assured. It has turned out the historic irony of this films title reflects the entertainment value of the film. It is the right cast, with the wrong script and the wrong filmmakers. That Ellen has not been slowed down by this shows how much talent she has. I am not sure my talent would survive anything near this. If I were ever on her hit daytime show, I'd congratulate her on that. Being a shy person, I'd be afraid to tell her how attractive I find her, because she is attractive and intelligent, more so than most people. Those qualities are almost totally hidden by this script.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's talk about "black comedy"...and how this is a total failure...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Mr. Wrong" had to be written as a "black comedy", but unfortunately misses the mark by a wide margin. The main problem is that the film is not outrageous enough. Bill Pullman's character resorts to becoming a mean stalker after his rejection by Ellen DeGeneris. At this point the movie turns into nothing more than a glorified cartoon. In order for dark comedy to succeed, it can be outrageous, but not mean spirited. Killing perverts to finance their dream restaurant worked wonders in "Eating Raoul". Here, simply destroying someone's life, for one's own pleasure, is totally off-putting, and not funny. A big disappointment, and definitely not "black comedy". - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite disturbing. Don't know what it's supposed to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    policy134
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's quite horrible. Ellen DeGeneres has been one of my favorite comedians for a long time, but her first foray into feature films was quite a mind blowing experience and mostly in a negative way. It's not that there is anything wrong with the premise. DeGeneres plays a woman who's getting on in years and meets a seemingly perfect man, Whit played by Bill Pullman. He seems to be perfect until Martha (DeGeneres' character) makes the fatal mistake of telling him to be himself. What happens next: Martha discovers he's a complete lunatic. Everyone is terrible in this movie, even a seasoned pro like Dean Stockwell as a slimy private detective and by far the worst comedic performance of that year is performed by Joan Cusack as Whit's even more psychotic ex. If one can call it a redeeming quality, the film does spark some weird curiosity of how it all ends. However, the end is incomprehensible and totally unbelievable. It seems as if the writers just gave up and said: "Well, we can't make it any worse!" DeGeneres hasn't had a starring role since this disaster, although she had a fairly good supporting role in EdTV. What more can you say except this was a total misfire from everyone involved. Bob Goulet did however do a fairly good job of playing, Bob Goulet.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good acting, bad script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Yonzie
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My girlfriend told me to tape this from TV and I had no idea what it was about. Initially I was pleasantly surprised by seeing Bill Pullman in a lead role. The last movie I saw featuring him was "While You Were Sleeping" which I thought was great. Mr. Wrong starts out reasonably good, but fairly quickly the stupidness becomes too much. Ultimately, it is made bearable by good acting from Degeneres and Pullman and a lot of funny moments. The moments in-between was unfortunately not just boring or neutral but plainly painful. This is obvious from the start when Martha Alstons (Degeneres) secretary brays on about receiving flowers from her boyfriend on valentine's day and Martha returns it in a totally non-funny way. I guess it could have been funny, but it was just painful to watch. Repeat ad nauseum with some genuinely funny moments in-between and you have this movie. In conclusion, its watchable and good for a few laughs, but if there's something more interesting available, just steer clear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Under the radar...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    whraglyn-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...and dropping bombs on marriage, men, and mainstream American culture. Isn't it interesting that this film was released BEFORE she outed herself? IOW, this film was intended to subvert cultural norms regarding marriage, but it wouldn't work at all, (as badly as it DOES work), if the viewer knows the protagonist is a lesbian. Another question: Why does Ellen keep getting funding for her projects, when her record of success is precisely zero? Every film or TV show she has done has lost money for it's producers. Why do they keep giving her a public platform?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good cast, not so great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    triple8
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS THROUGH: I watched this movie never having heard anything about it so I was able to decide for myself, without knowing anything about what it was going to be about. I'm not going to say there wasn't any comedy in this movie because there was. There were moments of total hilarity due to an hysterical Bill Pullman who was really in top comedic form. The problem is, when those moments were NOT happening the movie just wasn't very good. It was a great premise but there were a lot of things about the movie overall, that I did not enjoy. This movie was strongest in the beginning, where I thought it was going to be a movie similar to "Bridget Jones Diary". But I felt the movie went downhill fairly quickly. I guess this is what one would call a "black comedy" but as with many of this genre, I felt the movie was to focused on the meanness and not so much on the comedy. When Pullman's character first starts unraveling it's OK but after awhile it becomes a bit of overkill. The movie just becomes way to cruel, as more and more bad things happen to Ellen's character. That's the focus of the movie really, not the comedy. It's almost like the movie's seeing how many awful things can happen to Ellen'c character, and how much of her life can be destroyed etc etc. It didn't make me laugh, it made me a bit dazed and frankly I just wanted the movie to end. Throwing ants and gum on someone, and that person losing their job etc etc is not what I consider to be funny. The truly funny moments existed when Pullman was on screen because, as utterly annoying as his character came to be, he was hilarious. So yes there were a few moments where I laughed out loud. But those moments did not make the movie, for me, a great one. Another thing I didn't like was that the movie became way to over the top, a Virtual cornucopia of melodrama. Inga & Bob,rather then being funny, were a bit obnoxious. The whole wedding storyline was way to much. And the movie felt so LONG. I mean I know it wasn't but it FELT like it was. Ellen was very good as the lead though and Pullman, as mentioned was REALLY good and should probably have his own comedy television show. In a way I think I would have liked this better as a straight on comedy without the mean element or as a romance where Pullman's character did NOT change but stayed Normal. Or maybe even as a thriller or a film Noir. Basically I just felt this movie didn't work as a black comedy. I wouldn't consider this one of the worst movies ever made however. I would not recommend it either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ellen Goes Wrong
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thirty-one and still single Ellen DeGeneres (as Martha Alston) works on an early morning TV talk show in San Diego. She's feeling intense pressure to get married, but has no luck. There is attractive John Livingston (as Walter) at work, but Ms. DeGeneres considers him too boyish. Suddenly, while listening to Chris Isaak's version of Hank Williams' "I'm So Lonesome I Could Cry" on a jukebox, DeGeneres meets a man who seems to be "Mr. Right". Investor and poetry writer Bill Pullman (as Whitman Crawford) and DeGeneres have a whirlwind romance. All goes well until Mr. Pullman proves himself to be "Mr. Wrong"... This comedy is based on an outdated premise and DeGeneres is far too modern and intelligent for her role. She's witty, but stuck in an unfunny situation. More thoughtful acting is needed to overcome these hurdles... Pullman and director Nick Castle make the scenes involving the personality change interesting to watch, at least. After this, the film becomes unfocused and farcical. When the action switches to Mexico, some of it looks poorly improvised. In the "mother" roles, Joan Plowright and Polly Holliday are serviceable. Detective Dean Stockwell (as Jack Tramonte) has one good bit, when he switches allegiance. Joan Cusack (as Inga Gunther) is more annoying than funny. Her rotund sidekick, Brad Henke is better off solo. The best impressions are made by Mr. Livingston and photographer John Schwartzman. **** Mr. Wrong (2/16/96) Nick Castle ~ Ellen DeGeneres, Bill Pullman, John Livingston, Joan Cusack
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite shocked at how bad this film was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I do love comedy, and I like romance, together they can be a mixed bag. Some work, some don't. Mr. Wrong sadly is one of those romantic comedy films that doesn't work. In fact I was quite shocked at how bad the film was. It does have a talented cast, Ellen DeGeneres, Bill Pullman and Joan Cusack, but they are wasted by tedious direction, a predictable story, shallow and clich&eacute;d characters and unfunny and unfocused script. DeGeneres can be very funny, but because of her material even she is quite horrendous. Pullman is bland, and Cusack tries hard but it is an example of wasted talent at the end of the day. The pace is off as well, the film just ambles along and at no point does it recover. The film looks okay locations wise, but the editing could have been tighter. Overall, lame and unfunny and makes a waste of a good cast, as far as the movies of 1996 go it is not as abysmal as Ed and Bio Dome but it is among the worst. 1/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mr. Frightening!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a PG-13 rated film which came into theatres when I was a little less than 9&frac12; years old, so I was too young to see it and never heard of it at the time. Sometime probably in the late nineties, I noticed a copy of "Mr. Wrong" in the video store, and after that happened, I could remember the front cover but not the title. It wasn't until probably sometime within the past couple years that I finally came across a copy of it again, and this time, I saw that the woman on the front cover was Ellen DeGeneres. I wouldn't have recognized her the first time I saw that cover, and am still not THAT familiar with her work, but at least I found her amusing as the voice of Dory in "Finding Nemo". This film, however, has left me flabbergasted, and not in a good way! Martha Alston is a shy talk show producer who is still single at the age of 31, when she watches her younger sister get married. The older Alston sister is pressured by her parents and coworkers to find her true love, but things don't look good for her after an unsuccessful blind date on Valentine's Day. Depressed, she goes to a bar, where she meets a charming man named Whitman Crawford, and soon falls in love. So, does this mean Martha's search is over and she has finally found her Mr. Right? Well, it certainly does look like it at first, but unfortunately, it doesn't last. After a while, it's clear to her that Whitman is actually a nutcase, and not a 100% law-abiding citizen. When Martha wants to break up with him, he just won't get a clue, and it doesn't help that his jealous and insane ex-girlfriend, Inga Gunther, who has a big accomplice named Bob, threatens violence on Martha if she doesn't stay away from Whitman! For much of the film, I wasn't sure if I had any right to judge it. Nothing was making me laugh, and I found the beginning of Martha and Whitman's relationship to be badly scripted and not the only part the can be described that way. However, I was wondering if the film was actually bad, or I just wasn't getting it. I did some research before watching "Mr. Wrong" and heard it described as a "chick flick," and I'm not female. As I watched, that "chick flick" description was making sense to me. If I had the same feeling throughout the film, I doubt I would be writing a review of it, but things change later on. To me, it remained unfunny, but eventually got really weird and little disturbing! Towards the end, it no longer looked like much of a "chick flick" to me. It basically just looked like one insane story! Bill Pullman is quite lame as Whitman, a character who seems to be a maniac for the sake of being a maniac, and Joan Cusack is also lame here, in the role of Inga, and I've certainly seen her do much better. Watching these characters putting poor Martha through a nightmarish adventure is not fun! Even if this didn't do well back when it was released fifteen years ago and is still somewhat obscure today, it does seem to have a following. I've looked at the votes for this film, and have seen that the female rating is bit higher than the male one, but still certainly not high. Even if this 1996 romantic comedy has more female fans than male, it clearly has impressed some male viewers, and even with the "chick flick" label, there are definitely female viewers dislike it more than I do. Many of those who like "Mr. Wrong" might say that I'm of the wrong gender to get this film, and/or I don't have the right experience to get it, and they may be right, especially with the latter, but I will still say that I personally agree with the low rating here. If you like this film, regardless of your gender, that's cool with me, and I'm still not 100% sure whether I should have written this review or not, but there's not a single film in the world that can impress absolutely everybody who sees it, and I think I will always be one who doesn't like this particular romantic comedy, for whatever reason.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Terrible, NOT black comedy people!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    apefoot
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying that the only reason I gave this movie a 2 was because Ellen is awesome. But really the movie itself deserves a 1, if not a 0. Let me address the defense that this is a "black comedy": Definition of black comedy: "Black comedy or dark comedy is a sub-genre of comedy and satire in which topics and events that are usually regarded as taboo, are treated in an unusually humorous or satirical manner while retaining their seriousness. The intent of black comedy, therefore, is often for the audience to experience both laughter and discomfort, sometimes even simultaneously." I did not at any point experience laughter during this movie, except while laughing at how terrible it is. Perhaps one could argue that the topic of stalking is the element of black comedy here, but in no way does this movie, with its "madcap" soundtrack and completely horrible script, "retain its seriousness." If you want a black comedy, then go watch "Death to Smoochy," or even better, Todd Solondz's brilliant "Happiness." Don't watch this dreck. Also, the scene where she is supposedly high on LSD (oft-named by this movie's necessarily idiotic supporters as one of it's funniest) is only funny because the filmmakers so clearly have no idea what it is like to be on hallucinogens. If you absolutely must watch this, get drunk during it so that at the end, it seems funny rather than infuriating that you just wasted two hours of your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too Bad Mr. Or Ms.Right Didn't Write The Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    getyourdander
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What we got here is a wasted but talented cast not being able to over-come a script which was not ready for being filmed. The script is so bad that it even makes the directing and continuity make no sense. Ellen herself is a great talent. I am glad she got married recently as she deserves happiness as much as anyone, and even though her idea of marriage does not match everyones, she is as sincere in it as anyone else is in their beliefs. Along with that, my wife doesn't have to worry if I should ever meet her as with both of us married & sincere, safety is assured. It has turned out the historic irony of this films title reflects the entertainment value of the film. It is the right cast, with the wrong script and the wrong filmmakers. That Ellen has not been slowed down by this shows how much talent she has. I am not sure my talent would survive anything near this. If I were ever on her hit daytime show, I'd congratulate her on that. Being a shy person, I'd be afraid to tell her how attractive I find her, because she is attractive and intelligent, more so than most people. Those qualities are almost totally hidden by this script.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's talk about "black comedy"...and how this is a total failure...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Mr. Wrong" had to be written as a "black comedy", but unfortunately misses the mark by a wide margin. The main problem is that the film is not outrageous enough. Bill Pullman's character resorts to becoming a mean stalker after his rejection by Ellen DeGeneris. At this point the movie turns into nothing more than a glorified cartoon. In order for dark comedy to succeed, it can be outrageous, but not mean spirited. Killing perverts to finance their dream restaurant worked wonders in "Eating Raoul". Here, simply destroying someone's life, for one's own pleasure, is totally off-putting, and not funny. A big disappointment, and definitely not "black comedy". - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite disturbing. Don't know what it's supposed to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    policy134
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's quite horrible. Ellen DeGeneres has been one of my favorite comedians for a long time, but her first foray into feature films was quite a mind blowing experience and mostly in a negative way. It's not that there is anything wrong with the premise. DeGeneres plays a woman who's getting on in years and meets a seemingly perfect man, Whit played by Bill Pullman. He seems to be perfect until Martha (DeGeneres' character) makes the fatal mistake of telling him to be himself. What happens next: Martha discovers he's a complete lunatic. Everyone is terrible in this movie, even a seasoned pro like Dean Stockwell as a slimy private detective and by far the worst comedic performance of that year is performed by Joan Cusack as Whit's even more psychotic ex. If one can call it a redeeming quality, the film does spark some weird curiosity of how it all ends. However, the end is incomprehensible and totally unbelievable. It seems as if the writers just gave up and said: "Well, we can't make it any worse!" DeGeneres hasn't had a starring role since this disaster, although she had a fairly good supporting role in EdTV. What more can you say except this was a total misfire from everyone involved. Bob Goulet did however do a fairly good job of playing, Bob Goulet.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good acting, bad script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Yonzie
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My girlfriend told me to tape this from TV and I had no idea what it was about. Initially I was pleasantly surprised by seeing Bill Pullman in a lead role. The last movie I saw featuring him was "While You Were Sleeping" which I thought was great. Mr. Wrong starts out reasonably good, but fairly quickly the stupidness becomes too much. Ultimately, it is made bearable by good acting from Degeneres and Pullman and a lot of funny moments. The moments in-between was unfortunately not just boring or neutral but plainly painful. This is obvious from the start when Martha Alstons (Degeneres) secretary brays on about receiving flowers from her boyfriend on valentine's day and Martha returns it in a totally non-funny way. I guess it could have been funny, but it was just painful to watch. Repeat ad nauseum with some genuinely funny moments in-between and you have this movie. In conclusion, its watchable and good for a few laughs, but if there's something more interesting available, just steer clear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Under the radar...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    whraglyn-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...and dropping bombs on marriage, men, and mainstream American culture. Isn't it interesting that this film was released BEFORE she outed herself? IOW, this film was intended to subvert cultural norms regarding marriage, but it wouldn't work at all, (as badly as it DOES work), if the viewer knows the protagonist is a lesbian. Another question: Why does Ellen keep getting funding for her projects, when her record of success is precisely zero? Every film or TV show she has done has lost money for it's producers. Why do they keep giving her a public platform?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good cast, not so great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    triple8
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS THROUGH: I watched this movie never having heard anything about it so I was able to decide for myself, without knowing anything about what it was going to be about. I'm not going to say there wasn't any comedy in this movie because there was. There were moments of total hilarity due to an hysterical Bill Pullman who was really in top comedic form. The problem is, when those moments were NOT happening the movie just wasn't very good. It was a great premise but there were a lot of things about the movie overall, that I did not enjoy. This movie was strongest in the beginning, where I thought it was going to be a movie similar to "Bridget Jones Diary". But I felt the movie went downhill fairly quickly. I guess this is what one would call a "black comedy" but as with many of this genre, I felt the movie was to focused on the meanness and not so much on the comedy. When Pullman's character first starts unraveling it's OK but after awhile it becomes a bit of overkill. The movie just becomes way to cruel, as more and more bad things happen to Ellen's character. That's the focus of the movie really, not the comedy. It's almost like the movie's seeing how many awful things can happen to Ellen'c character, and how much of her life can be destroyed etc etc. It didn't make me laugh, it made me a bit dazed and frankly I just wanted the movie to end. Throwing ants and gum on someone, and that person losing their job etc etc is not what I consider to be funny. The truly funny moments existed when Pullman was on screen because, as utterly annoying as his character came to be, he was hilarious. So yes there were a few moments where I laughed out loud. But those moments did not make the movie, for me, a great one. Another thing I didn't like was that the movie became way to over the top, a Virtual cornucopia of melodrama. Inga & Bob,rather then being funny, were a bit obnoxious. The whole wedding storyline was way to much. And the movie felt so LONG. I mean I know it wasn't but it FELT like it was. Ellen was very good as the lead though and Pullman, as mentioned was REALLY good and should probably have his own comedy television show. In a way I think I would have liked this better as a straight on comedy without the mean element or as a romance where Pullman's character did NOT change but stayed Normal. Or maybe even as a thriller or a film Noir. Basically I just felt this movie didn't work as a black comedy. I wouldn't consider this one of the worst movies ever made however. I would not recommend it either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ellen Goes Wrong
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thirty-one and still single Ellen DeGeneres (as Martha Alston) works on an early morning TV talk show in San Diego. She's feeling intense pressure to get married, but has no luck. There is attractive John Livingston (as Walter) at work, but Ms. DeGeneres considers him too boyish. Suddenly, while listening to Chris Isaak's version of Hank Williams' "I'm So Lonesome I Could Cry" on a jukebox, DeGeneres meets a man who seems to be "Mr. Right". Investor and poetry writer Bill Pullman (as Whitman Crawford) and DeGeneres have a whirlwind romance. All goes well until Mr. Pullman proves himself to be "Mr. Wrong"... This comedy is based on an outdated premise and DeGeneres is far too modern and intelligent for her role. She's witty, but stuck in an unfunny situation. More thoughtful acting is needed to overcome these hurdles... Pullman and director Nick Castle make the scenes involving the personality change interesting to watch, at least. After this, the film becomes unfocused and farcical. When the action switches to Mexico, some of it looks poorly improvised. In the "mother" roles, Joan Plowright and Polly Holliday are serviceable. Detective Dean Stockwell (as Jack Tramonte) has one good bit, when he switches allegiance. Joan Cusack (as Inga Gunther) is more annoying than funny. Her rotund sidekick, Brad Henke is better off solo. The best impressions are made by Mr. Livingston and photographer John Schwartzman. **** Mr. Wrong (2/16/96) Nick Castle ~ Ellen DeGeneres, Bill Pullman, John Livingston, Joan Cusack
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite shocked at how bad this film was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I do love comedy, and I like romance, together they can be a mixed bag. Some work, some don't. Mr. Wrong sadly is one of those romantic comedy films that doesn't work. In fact I was quite shocked at how bad the film was. It does have a talented cast, Ellen DeGeneres, Bill Pullman and Joan Cusack, but they are wasted by tedious direction, a predictable story, shallow and clich&eacute;d characters and unfunny and unfocused script. DeGeneres can be very funny, but because of her material even she is quite horrendous. Pullman is bland, and Cusack tries hard but it is an example of wasted talent at the end of the day. The pace is off as well, the film just ambles along and at no point does it recover. The film looks okay locations wise, but the editing could have been tighter. Overall, lame and unfunny and makes a waste of a good cast, as far as the movies of 1996 go it is not as abysmal as Ed and Bio Dome but it is among the worst. 1/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mr. Frightening!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a PG-13 rated film which came into theatres when I was a little less than 9&frac12; years old, so I was too young to see it and never heard of it at the time. Sometime probably in the late nineties, I noticed a copy of "Mr. Wrong" in the video store, and after that happened, I could remember the front cover but not the title. It wasn't until probably sometime within the past couple years that I finally came across a copy of it again, and this time, I saw that the woman on the front cover was Ellen DeGeneres. I wouldn't have recognized her the first time I saw that cover, and am still not THAT familiar with her work, but at least I found her amusing as the voice of Dory in "Finding Nemo". This film, however, has left me flabbergasted, and not in a good way! Martha Alston is a shy talk show producer who is still single at the age of 31, when she watches her younger sister get married. The older Alston sister is pressured by her parents and coworkers to find her true love, but things don't look good for her after an unsuccessful blind date on Valentine's Day. Depressed, she goes to a bar, where she meets a charming man named Whitman Crawford, and soon falls in love. So, does this mean Martha's search is over and she has finally found her Mr. Right? Well, it certainly does look like it at first, but unfortunately, it doesn't last. After a while, it's clear to her that Whitman is actually a nutcase, and not a 100% law-abiding citizen. When Martha wants to break up with him, he just won't get a clue, and it doesn't help that his jealous and insane ex-girlfriend, Inga Gunther, who has a big accomplice named Bob, threatens violence on Martha if she doesn't stay away from Whitman! For much of the film, I wasn't sure if I had any right to judge it. Nothing was making me laugh, and I found the beginning of Martha and Whitman's relationship to be badly scripted and not the only part the can be described that way. However, I was wondering if the film was actually bad, or I just wasn't getting it. I did some research before watching "Mr. Wrong" and heard it described as a "chick flick," and I'm not female. As I watched, that "chick flick" description was making sense to me. If I had the same feeling throughout the film, I doubt I would be writing a review of it, but things change later on. To me, it remained unfunny, but eventually got really weird and little disturbing! Towards the end, it no longer looked like much of a "chick flick" to me. It basically just looked like one insane story! Bill Pullman is quite lame as Whitman, a character who seems to be a maniac for the sake of being a maniac, and Joan Cusack is also lame here, in the role of Inga, and I've certainly seen her do much better. Watching these characters putting poor Martha through a nightmarish adventure is not fun! Even if this didn't do well back when it was released fifteen years ago and is still somewhat obscure today, it does seem to have a following. I've looked at the votes for this film, and have seen that the female rating is bit higher than the male one, but still certainly not high. Even if this 1996 romantic comedy has more female fans than male, it clearly has impressed some male viewers, and even with the "chick flick" label, there are definitely female viewers dislike it more than I do. Many of those who like "Mr. Wrong" might say that I'm of the wrong gender to get this film, and/or I don't have the right experience to get it, and they may be right, especially with the latter, but I will still say that I personally agree with the low rating here. If you like this film, regardless of your gender, that's cool with me, and I'm still not 100% sure whether I should have written this review or not, but there's not a single film in the world that can impress absolutely everybody who sees it, and I think I will always be one who doesn't like this particular romantic comedy, for whatever reason.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Terrible, NOT black comedy people!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    apefoot
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying that the only reason I gave this movie a 2 was because Ellen is awesome. But really the movie itself deserves a 1, if not a 0. Let me address the defense that this is a "black comedy": Definition of black comedy: "Black comedy or dark comedy is a sub-genre of comedy and satire in which topics and events that are usually regarded as taboo, are treated in an unusually humorous or satirical manner while retaining their seriousness. The intent of black comedy, therefore, is often for the audience to experience both laughter and discomfort, sometimes even simultaneously." I did not at any point experience laughter during this movie, except while laughing at how terrible it is. Perhaps one could argue that the topic of stalking is the element of black comedy here, but in no way does this movie, with its "madcap" soundtrack and completely horrible script, "retain its seriousness." If you want a black comedy, then go watch "Death to Smoochy," or even better, Todd Solondz's brilliant "Happiness." Don't watch this dreck. Also, the scene where she is supposedly high on LSD (oft-named by this movie's necessarily idiotic supporters as one of it's funniest) is only funny because the filmmakers so clearly have no idea what it is like to be on hallucinogens. If you absolutely must watch this, get drunk during it so that at the end, it seems funny rather than infuriating that you just wasted two hours of your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too Bad Mr. Or Ms.Right Didn't Write The Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    getyourdander
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What we got here is a wasted but talented cast not being able to over-come a script which was not ready for being filmed. The script is so bad that it even makes the directing and continuity make no sense. Ellen herself is a great talent. I am glad she got married recently as she deserves happiness as much as anyone, and even though her idea of marriage does not match everyones, she is as sincere in it as anyone else is in their beliefs. Along with that, my wife doesn't have to worry if I should ever meet her as with both of us married & sincere, safety is assured. It has turned out the historic irony of this films title reflects the entertainment value of the film. It is the right cast, with the wrong script and the wrong filmmakers. That Ellen has not been slowed down by this shows how much talent she has. I am not sure my talent would survive anything near this. If I were ever on her hit daytime show, I'd congratulate her on that. Being a shy person, I'd be afraid to tell her how attractive I find her, because she is attractive and intelligent, more so than most people. Those qualities are almost totally hidden by this script.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's talk about "black comedy"...and how this is a total failure...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Mr. Wrong" had to be written as a "black comedy", but unfortunately misses the mark by a wide margin. The main problem is that the film is not outrageous enough. Bill Pullman's character resorts to becoming a mean stalker after his rejection by Ellen DeGeneris. At this point the movie turns into nothing more than a glorified cartoon. In order for dark comedy to succeed, it can be outrageous, but not mean spirited. Killing perverts to finance their dream restaurant worked wonders in "Eating Raoul". Here, simply destroying someone's life, for one's own pleasure, is totally off-putting, and not funny. A big disappointment, and definitely not "black comedy". - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite disturbing. Don't know what it's supposed to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    policy134
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's quite horrible. Ellen DeGeneres has been one of my favorite comedians for a long time, but her first foray into feature films was quite a mind blowing experience and mostly in a negative way. It's not that there is anything wrong with the premise. DeGeneres plays a woman who's getting on in years and meets a seemingly perfect man, Whit played by Bill Pullman. He seems to be perfect until Martha (DeGeneres' character) makes the fatal mistake of telling him to be himself. What happens next: Martha discovers he's a complete lunatic. Everyone is terrible in this movie, even a seasoned pro like Dean Stockwell as a slimy private detective and by far the worst comedic performance of that year is performed by Joan Cusack as Whit's even more psychotic ex. If one can call it a redeeming quality, the film does spark some weird curiosity of how it all ends. However, the end is incomprehensible and totally unbelievable. It seems as if the writers just gave up and said: "Well, we can't make it any worse!" DeGeneres hasn't had a starring role since this disaster, although she had a fairly good supporting role in EdTV. What more can you say except this was a total misfire from everyone involved. Bob Goulet did however do a fairly good job of playing, Bob Goulet.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good acting, bad script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Yonzie
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My girlfriend told me to tape this from TV and I had no idea what it was about. Initially I was pleasantly surprised by seeing Bill Pullman in a lead role. The last movie I saw featuring him was "While You Were Sleeping" which I thought was great. Mr. Wrong starts out reasonably good, but fairly quickly the stupidness becomes too much. Ultimately, it is made bearable by good acting from Degeneres and Pullman and a lot of funny moments. The moments in-between was unfortunately not just boring or neutral but plainly painful. This is obvious from the start when Martha Alstons (Degeneres) secretary brays on about receiving flowers from her boyfriend on valentine's day and Martha returns it in a totally non-funny way. I guess it could have been funny, but it was just painful to watch. Repeat ad nauseum with some genuinely funny moments in-between and you have this movie. In conclusion, its watchable and good for a few laughs, but if there's something more interesting available, just steer clear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Under the radar...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    whraglyn-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...and dropping bombs on marriage, men, and mainstream American culture. Isn't it interesting that this film was released BEFORE she outed herself? IOW, this film was intended to subvert cultural norms regarding marriage, but it wouldn't work at all, (as badly as it DOES work), if the viewer knows the protagonist is a lesbian. Another question: Why does Ellen keep getting funding for her projects, when her record of success is precisely zero? Every film or TV show she has done has lost money for it's producers. Why do they keep giving her a public platform?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good cast, not so great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    triple8
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS THROUGH: I watched this movie never having heard anything about it so I was able to decide for myself, without knowing anything about what it was going to be about. I'm not going to say there wasn't any comedy in this movie because there was. There were moments of total hilarity due to an hysterical Bill Pullman who was really in top comedic form. The problem is, when those moments were NOT happening the movie just wasn't very good. It was a great premise but there were a lot of things about the movie overall, that I did not enjoy. This movie was strongest in the beginning, where I thought it was going to be a movie similar to "Bridget Jones Diary". But I felt the movie went downhill fairly quickly. I guess this is what one would call a "black comedy" but as with many of this genre, I felt the movie was to focused on the meanness and not so much on the comedy. When Pullman's character first starts unraveling it's OK but after awhile it becomes a bit of overkill. The movie just becomes way to cruel, as more and more bad things happen to Ellen's character. That's the focus of the movie really, not the comedy. It's almost like the movie's seeing how many awful things can happen to Ellen'c character, and how much of her life can be destroyed etc etc. It didn't make me laugh, it made me a bit dazed and frankly I just wanted the movie to end. Throwing ants and gum on someone, and that person losing their job etc etc is not what I consider to be funny. The truly funny moments existed when Pullman was on screen because, as utterly annoying as his character came to be, he was hilarious. So yes there were a few moments where I laughed out loud. But those moments did not make the movie, for me, a great one. Another thing I didn't like was that the movie became way to over the top, a Virtual cornucopia of melodrama. Inga & Bob,rather then being funny, were a bit obnoxious. The whole wedding storyline was way to much. And the movie felt so LONG. I mean I know it wasn't but it FELT like it was. Ellen was very good as the lead though and Pullman, as mentioned was REALLY good and should probably have his own comedy television show. In a way I think I would have liked this better as a straight on comedy without the mean element or as a romance where Pullman's character did NOT change but stayed Normal. Or maybe even as a thriller or a film Noir. Basically I just felt this movie didn't work as a black comedy. I wouldn't consider this one of the worst movies ever made however. I would not recommend it either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ellen Goes Wrong
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thirty-one and still single Ellen DeGeneres (as Martha Alston) works on an early morning TV talk show in San Diego. She's feeling intense pressure to get married, but has no luck. There is attractive John Livingston (as Walter) at work, but Ms. DeGeneres considers him too boyish. Suddenly, while listening to Chris Isaak's version of Hank Williams' "I'm So Lonesome I Could Cry" on a jukebox, DeGeneres meets a man who seems to be "Mr. Right". Investor and poetry writer Bill Pullman (as Whitman Crawford) and DeGeneres have a whirlwind romance. All goes well until Mr. Pullman proves himself to be "Mr. Wrong"... This comedy is based on an outdated premise and DeGeneres is far too modern and intelligent for her role. She's witty, but stuck in an unfunny situation. More thoughtful acting is needed to overcome these hurdles... Pullman and director Nick Castle make the scenes involving the personality change interesting to watch, at least. After this, the film becomes unfocused and farcical. When the action switches to Mexico, some of it looks poorly improvised. In the "mother" roles, Joan Plowright and Polly Holliday are serviceable. Detective Dean Stockwell (as Jack Tramonte) has one good bit, when he switches allegiance. Joan Cusack (as Inga Gunther) is more annoying than funny. Her rotund sidekick, Brad Henke is better off solo. The best impressions are made by Mr. Livingston and photographer John Schwartzman. **** Mr. Wrong (2/16/96) Nick Castle ~ Ellen DeGeneres, Bill Pullman, John Livingston, Joan Cusack
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite shocked at how bad this film was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I do love comedy, and I like romance, together they can be a mixed bag. Some work, some don't. Mr. Wrong sadly is one of those romantic comedy films that doesn't work. In fact I was quite shocked at how bad the film was. It does have a talented cast, Ellen DeGeneres, Bill Pullman and Joan Cusack, but they are wasted by tedious direction, a predictable story, shallow and clich&eacute;d characters and unfunny and unfocused script. DeGeneres can be very funny, but because of her material even she is quite horrendous. Pullman is bland, and Cusack tries hard but it is an example of wasted talent at the end of the day. The pace is off as well, the film just ambles along and at no point does it recover. The film looks okay locations wise, but the editing could have been tighter. Overall, lame and unfunny and makes a waste of a good cast, as far as the movies of 1996 go it is not as abysmal as Ed and Bio Dome but it is among the worst. 1/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mr. Frightening!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a PG-13 rated film which came into theatres when I was a little less than 9&frac12; years old, so I was too young to see it and never heard of it at the time. Sometime probably in the late nineties, I noticed a copy of "Mr. Wrong" in the video store, and after that happened, I could remember the front cover but not the title. It wasn't until probably sometime within the past couple years that I finally came across a copy of it again, and this time, I saw that the woman on the front cover was Ellen DeGeneres. I wouldn't have recognized her the first time I saw that cover, and am still not THAT familiar with her work, but at least I found her amusing as the voice of Dory in "Finding Nemo". This film, however, has left me flabbergasted, and not in a good way! Martha Alston is a shy talk show producer who is still single at the age of 31, when she watches her younger sister get married. The older Alston sister is pressured by her parents and coworkers to find her true love, but things don't look good for her after an unsuccessful blind date on Valentine's Day. Depressed, she goes to a bar, where she meets a charming man named Whitman Crawford, and soon falls in love. So, does this mean Martha's search is over and she has finally found her Mr. Right? Well, it certainly does look like it at first, but unfortunately, it doesn't last. After a while, it's clear to her that Whitman is actually a nutcase, and not a 100% law-abiding citizen. When Martha wants to break up with him, he just won't get a clue, and it doesn't help that his jealous and insane ex-girlfriend, Inga Gunther, who has a big accomplice named Bob, threatens violence on Martha if she doesn't stay away from Whitman! For much of the film, I wasn't sure if I had any right to judge it. Nothing was making me laugh, and I found the beginning of Martha and Whitman's relationship to be badly scripted and not the only part the can be described that way. However, I was wondering if the film was actually bad, or I just wasn't getting it. I did some research before watching "Mr. Wrong" and heard it described as a "chick flick," and I'm not female. As I watched, that "chick flick" description was making sense to me. If I had the same feeling throughout the film, I doubt I would be writing a review of it, but things change later on. To me, it remained unfunny, but eventually got really weird and little disturbing! Towards the end, it no longer looked like much of a "chick flick" to me. It basically just looked like one insane story! Bill Pullman is quite lame as Whitman, a character who seems to be a maniac for the sake of being a maniac, and Joan Cusack is also lame here, in the role of Inga, and I've certainly seen her do much better. Watching these characters putting poor Martha through a nightmarish adventure is not fun! Even if this didn't do well back when it was released fifteen years ago and is still somewhat obscure today, it does seem to have a following. I've looked at the votes for this film, and have seen that the female rating is bit higher than the male one, but still certainly not high. Even if this 1996 romantic comedy has more female fans than male, it clearly has impressed some male viewers, and even with the "chick flick" label, there are definitely female viewers dislike it more than I do. Many of those who like "Mr. Wrong" might say that I'm of the wrong gender to get this film, and/or I don't have the right experience to get it, and they may be right, especially with the latter, but I will still say that I personally agree with the low rating here. If you like this film, regardless of your gender, that's cool with me, and I'm still not 100% sure whether I should have written this review or not, but there's not a single film in the world that can impress absolutely everybody who sees it, and I think I will always be one who doesn't like this particular romantic comedy, for whatever reason.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Terrible, NOT black comedy people!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    apefoot
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying that the only reason I gave this movie a 2 was because Ellen is awesome. But really the movie itself deserves a 1, if not a 0. Let me address the defense that this is a "black comedy": Definition of black comedy: "Black comedy or dark comedy is a sub-genre of comedy and satire in which topics and events that are usually regarded as taboo, are treated in an unusually humorous or satirical manner while retaining their seriousness. The intent of black comedy, therefore, is often for the audience to experience both laughter and discomfort, sometimes even simultaneously." I did not at any point experience laughter during this movie, except while laughing at how terrible it is. Perhaps one could argue that the topic of stalking is the element of black comedy here, but in no way does this movie, with its "madcap" soundtrack and completely horrible script, "retain its seriousness." If you want a black comedy, then go watch "Death to Smoochy," or even better, Todd Solondz's brilliant "Happiness." Don't watch this dreck. Also, the scene where she is supposedly high on LSD (oft-named by this movie's necessarily idiotic supporters as one of it's funniest) is only funny because the filmmakers so clearly have no idea what it is like to be on hallucinogens. If you absolutely must watch this, get drunk during it so that at the end, it seems funny rather than infuriating that you just wasted two hours of your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too Bad Mr. Or Ms.Right Didn't Write The Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    getyourdander
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What we got here is a wasted but talented cast not being able to over-come a script which was not ready for being filmed. The script is so bad that it even makes the directing and continuity make no sense. Ellen herself is a great talent. I am glad she got married recently as she deserves happiness as much as anyone, and even though her idea of marriage does not match everyones, she is as sincere in it as anyone else is in their beliefs. Along with that, my wife doesn't have to worry if I should ever meet her as with both of us married & sincere, safety is assured. It has turned out the historic irony of this films title reflects the entertainment value of the film. It is the right cast, with the wrong script and the wrong filmmakers. That Ellen has not been slowed down by this shows how much talent she has. I am not sure my talent would survive anything near this. If I were ever on her hit daytime show, I'd congratulate her on that. Being a shy person, I'd be afraid to tell her how attractive I find her, because she is attractive and intelligent, more so than most people. Those qualities are almost totally hidden by this script.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's talk about "black comedy"...and how this is a total failure...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Mr. Wrong" had to be written as a "black comedy", but unfortunately misses the mark by a wide margin. The main problem is that the film is not outrageous enough. Bill Pullman's character resorts to becoming a mean stalker after his rejection by Ellen DeGeneris. At this point the movie turns into nothing more than a glorified cartoon. In order for dark comedy to succeed, it can be outrageous, but not mean spirited. Killing perverts to finance their dream restaurant worked wonders in "Eating Raoul". Here, simply destroying someone's life, for one's own pleasure, is totally off-putting, and not funny. A big disappointment, and definitely not "black comedy". - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite disturbing. Don't know what it's supposed to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    policy134
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's quite horrible. Ellen DeGeneres has been one of my favorite comedians for a long time, but her first foray into feature films was quite a mind blowing experience and mostly in a negative way. It's not that there is anything wrong with the premise. DeGeneres plays a woman who's getting on in years and meets a seemingly perfect man, Whit played by Bill Pullman. He seems to be perfect until Martha (DeGeneres' character) makes the fatal mistake of telling him to be himself. What happens next: Martha discovers he's a complete lunatic. Everyone is terrible in this movie, even a seasoned pro like Dean Stockwell as a slimy private detective and by far the worst comedic performance of that year is performed by Joan Cusack as Whit's even more psychotic ex. If one can call it a redeeming quality, the film does spark some weird curiosity of how it all ends. However, the end is incomprehensible and totally unbelievable. It seems as if the writers just gave up and said: "Well, we can't make it any worse!" DeGeneres hasn't had a starring role since this disaster, although she had a fairly good supporting role in EdTV. What more can you say except this was a total misfire from everyone involved. Bob Goulet did however do a fairly good job of playing, Bob Goulet.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good acting, bad script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Yonzie
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My girlfriend told me to tape this from TV and I had no idea what it was about. Initially I was pleasantly surprised by seeing Bill Pullman in a lead role. The last movie I saw featuring him was "While You Were Sleeping" which I thought was great. Mr. Wrong starts out reasonably good, but fairly quickly the stupidness becomes too much. Ultimately, it is made bearable by good acting from Degeneres and Pullman and a lot of funny moments. The moments in-between was unfortunately not just boring or neutral but plainly painful. This is obvious from the start when Martha Alstons (Degeneres) secretary brays on about receiving flowers from her boyfriend on valentine's day and Martha returns it in a totally non-funny way. I guess it could have been funny, but it was just painful to watch. Repeat ad nauseum with some genuinely funny moments in-between and you have this movie. In conclusion, its watchable and good for a few laughs, but if there's something more interesting available, just steer clear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Under the radar...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    whraglyn-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...and dropping bombs on marriage, men, and mainstream American culture. Isn't it interesting that this film was released BEFORE she outed herself? IOW, this film was intended to subvert cultural norms regarding marriage, but it wouldn't work at all, (as badly as it DOES work), if the viewer knows the protagonist is a lesbian. Another question: Why does Ellen keep getting funding for her projects, when her record of success is precisely zero? Every film or TV show she has done has lost money for it's producers. Why do they keep giving her a public platform?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good cast, not so great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    triple8
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS THROUGH: I watched this movie never having heard anything about it so I was able to decide for myself, without knowing anything about what it was going to be about. I'm not going to say there wasn't any comedy in this movie because there was. There were moments of total hilarity due to an hysterical Bill Pullman who was really in top comedic form. The problem is, when those moments were NOT happening the movie just wasn't very good. It was a great premise but there were a lot of things about the movie overall, that I did not enjoy. This movie was strongest in the beginning, where I thought it was going to be a movie similar to "Bridget Jones Diary". But I felt the movie went downhill fairly quickly. I guess this is what one would call a "black comedy" but as with many of this genre, I felt the movie was to focused on the meanness and not so much on the comedy. When Pullman's character first starts unraveling it's OK but after awhile it becomes a bit of overkill. The movie just becomes way to cruel, as more and more bad things happen to Ellen's character. That's the focus of the movie really, not the comedy. It's almost like the movie's seeing how many awful things can happen to Ellen'c character, and how much of her life can be destroyed etc etc. It didn't make me laugh, it made me a bit dazed and frankly I just wanted the movie to end. Throwing ants and gum on someone, and that person losing their job etc etc is not what I consider to be funny. The truly funny moments existed when Pullman was on screen because, as utterly annoying as his character came to be, he was hilarious. So yes there were a few moments where I laughed out loud. But those moments did not make the movie, for me, a great one. Another thing I didn't like was that the movie became way to over the top, a Virtual cornucopia of melodrama. Inga & Bob,rather then being funny, were a bit obnoxious. The whole wedding storyline was way to much. And the movie felt so LONG. I mean I know it wasn't but it FELT like it was. Ellen was very good as the lead though and Pullman, as mentioned was REALLY good and should probably have his own comedy television show. In a way I think I would have liked this better as a straight on comedy without the mean element or as a romance where Pullman's character did NOT change but stayed Normal. Or maybe even as a thriller or a film Noir. Basically I just felt this movie didn't work as a black comedy. I wouldn't consider this one of the worst movies ever made however. I would not recommend it either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
