<filme>
 <id>
  1055
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0111194
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Uma Virada do Destino
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  His life was emotionally closed off from the world, until an orphaned baby showed up at his house.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Michael McCann is a man who feels totally betrayed by the world, after his wife revealed to him that their child was not his. A few years after his break-up we find him living alone in a small town. But, everything in his miserable life changes when he adopts a little girl whose mother died outside his house. After several years, the real father returns to claim the girl from Michael, thinking that she will be an advantage for his political career.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   girl
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   gold
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   adopted daughter
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   baby
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   secret
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Gillies MacKinnon
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   George Eliot
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Steve Martin
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Steve Martin
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Gabriel Byrne
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Laura Linney
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    destiny of necessity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a departure from his usual roles, Steve Martin plays a lonely man who adopts a girl after she happens into his house. "A Simple Twist of Fate" is an almost mystifying movie, and a very good one. While there are certainly some funny parts, it's mainly about how the entry of this girl into his existence changes the course of his life, and also turns out to have a link to something else in his life. The movie has really good character development. Along with Martin, there's Gabriel Byrne as a slimy politician, Laura Linney as his unfulfilled wife, and Catherine O'Hara as a shopkeeper who helps Martin. This is a movie that I very much recommend to everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Custody Battle With Steve Martin-Simple Twist of Fate ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Something very different for Steve Martin as he portrays a man who divorced his wife when he found out that the child they expected was not his. Enter another child in his life when a young woman dies on her way to the baby girl's wealthy political father. The father, who knew this was his child when he saw the dead woman, made no effort to claim the child as his. Instead, the child stays with Martin who loves her dearly and takes care of her in a manner of a true parent. 10 years later, the real father, Gabriel Byrne and his wife, Laura Linney, are childless and when Martin brings the child along with him to deliver furniture, Byrne confesses to all that he is the father of the child and a custody battle ensues. These custody battles are very clich&eacute; in movies. Of course, everyone is wooed by the child's kind words for Martin. The ending is unexpected, but a good one. Everyone gets what they deserve.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent family law movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anthony Wright, Esq.
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When facing losing your child in the court system, a parent suffers a roller-coaster of emotions. Here, two wannabe fathers are fighting for their parental rights to a daughter. One father had been highly regarded in the community and had unbounded political ambitions. The other father was a town drunk and miser who lived on the land of the other father. The movie is suspenseful at times, dark at times, light at times, and has a great ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Real Silas Marner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mulierose
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As we all know, the real book, "Silas Marner" was first published in 1861 by "George Eliot". Well, in the time the book was published, women weren't "supposed" to write books like this. George Eliot's real name is Mary Ann Evans 1819-1880. Her understanding of the "Human condition" and the effects of loneliness on a person are greatly adapted into the book. If you read the novel, even though the wording of the book is different than modern English, well... that's part of the charm of the book. It takes you into a time when that's how they spoke. When considering the era of the book, and once again the adaptation of the movie "A Simple Twist of Fate", I believe that Steve Martin did an excellent job. Although... there's no substitution for the original work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I simply adore this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CoffeeGoddess
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is so understated and underrated as to be in danger of completely disappearing from the radar screen. For Steve Martin to be in a non-Jerk type roll makes seeing this movie next to impossible for a great number of people. No, he's not acting weird. No, he doesn't have an arrow on his head. No, he isn't going for the laugh. This is Mr. Martin at his acting best. If you were impressed by his recent turn in 'Shopgirl' the do yourself a favor and go out of your way to find a copy of this movie. Are there times when humor finds its way into this movie? Oh yeah but for the most part there is nothing but good solid storytelling with excellent casting and an excellent script. See this movie if you want to see a wonderful character study acted out by a superb cast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A misunderstood classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yoda87960
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Note: This doesn't really contain spoilers, but hey, one slip of the mouse could blacklist me. I just finished watching the outstanding Shopgirl and I couldn't help but think of this film. I've probably seen it around ten times. Only two or three times at home, but in high school I swear teachers showed it once or twice a year to kill some time. It didn't matter if we were reading Silas Marner or not. It has never gotten old. People seem to go into this movie expecting a comedy, but it's really not. It's a haunting and beautiful movie filled with imagery that I can still see in my head, even though I haven't seen the movie in a couple of years. I assume when this came out, it was largely ignored because it had the look and conventions of other lesser movies of the time. Besides, who would want to see a drama from Steve Martin? Now that it's years removed from the climate it was released, it can truly be appreciated for what it is. A true gem.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This one's a sleeper
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dragon_grl_19
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is what I like to call a sleeper. The cable descriptions are usually terrible and uninteresting but this a wonderful heartwarming movie about love and family. When I played it for my sister one day she argued that she didn't want to watch it but after it was over she fell in love with the sometimes sad, often times humorous story of a man with nothing left to lose and the baby that saves him! Steve Martin flexes his acting talent showing that he isn't always funny/stupid. And the young actress playing Mathilda at age 10 is amazing and really reminds me of Amy Smart. Even though this movie is a little bit older it still applies to life today and it is highly recommended by me!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good story, terrible script and acting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wildferalfemme
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a real disappointment. Steve Martin did okay in the lead role about a man whose wife tells him that their unborn child belongs to another man and they divorce and he becomes a recluse who drinks and counts his gold coins...but it was hard to see past the many years of outrageous comedy Martin did to take him too seriously here. The acting and dialogue were just awful. Linney and Bryne were wooden and lacked any depth whatsoever and I didn't care about anything that happened to them. The little girl, who rarely uttered a word (which seemed a bit unrealistic for any child)was played by so many child actors it was hard to tell it was even the same character in any particular scene. Overall it was mediocre and I would not recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wonderful well-written and well-acted film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Billie Rae Bates (BRBTVcom)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always enjoyed Steve Martin. It doesn't matter what he's in; I just admire his talent and I've been downright crazy about his humor since I first saw him do that "King Tut" thing back in the 1970s. Here, he tackles a more dramatic role with so much warmth and sincerity, and he even manages to inject some comic moments in his typical style. To know that he also wrote this screenplay is not surprising, as he's a gifted writer, as well. The story in this film is tremendously life-affirming. If nothing else, it illustrates how even the most serious or threatening situation can turn around, just like that, in the blink of an eye. As with M. Night Shyamalan's "Signs," Christians might be thinking of Romans 8:28 when they see this film -- how events, good or bad, are so often intricately orchestrated to a better end that we really can't see coming. My favorite point in the film is when Steve Martin's character, having just been robbed of the fortune he's amassed in gold coins (he stored his cash in these coins rather than in a bank), sees this sweet toddler girl wandering aimlessly into his home as an event that was simply meant to be, as the "gift" he is given because his money has been taken away. His faithful perspective is greatly rewarded.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A well-intentioned movie suffering from an identity crisis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    glazed_doughnut
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying that I am a Steve Martin fan and anyone who questions his ability to do serious work has never seen Grand Canyon. I picked up this movie with the intent of watching it with my kids, aged 12 and 6. About 15 minutes or so into the movie, after witnessing shot-drinking, a heroin needle and two people sharing a joint, I seriously considered turning the movie off. The fact is that once past these moments, the movie does begin to work as a more heart-warming family tale. What irks me however is that I don't understand why people making a movie that kids can watch have to resort to adult imagery in some feeble attempt to generate adult interest. If one wishes to make a grown-up movie with adult images, then by all means do so, but this movie simply does not work on that level; it maintains too much of a superficial and sweet flavor to be considered as such. So, why then, if I am watching a family movie, should I be forced to lie to my children about some of the imagery they are seeing? I certainly don't want to explain to them what heroin or marijuana is and the truth is that none of these images were necessary to the telling of the story. Therein lies my biggest problem with this movie as a whole. There are simply too many small scenes and images that are forcibly interjected into the story without necessity. The baseball scene, the scene by the edge of the quarry as well as many other smaller moments almost seem randomly inserted into the movie as though after the final cut the producers felt they need 20 minutes more to fill. My kids, fortunately, asked no questions, but did ask to watch the movie again the next day (a practice they inherited from their father), so I would honestly say that the movie does function on their level and I would recommend it to any parent who doesn't feel uncomfortable by the occasional adult imagery passing before their child's eyes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    destiny of necessity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a departure from his usual roles, Steve Martin plays a lonely man who adopts a girl after she happens into his house. "A Simple Twist of Fate" is an almost mystifying movie, and a very good one. While there are certainly some funny parts, it's mainly about how the entry of this girl into his existence changes the course of his life, and also turns out to have a link to something else in his life. The movie has really good character development. Along with Martin, there's Gabriel Byrne as a slimy politician, Laura Linney as his unfulfilled wife, and Catherine O'Hara as a shopkeeper who helps Martin. This is a movie that I very much recommend to everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Custody Battle With Steve Martin-Simple Twist of Fate ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Something very different for Steve Martin as he portrays a man who divorced his wife when he found out that the child they expected was not his. Enter another child in his life when a young woman dies on her way to the baby girl's wealthy political father. The father, who knew this was his child when he saw the dead woman, made no effort to claim the child as his. Instead, the child stays with Martin who loves her dearly and takes care of her in a manner of a true parent. 10 years later, the real father, Gabriel Byrne and his wife, Laura Linney, are childless and when Martin brings the child along with him to deliver furniture, Byrne confesses to all that he is the father of the child and a custody battle ensues. These custody battles are very clich&eacute; in movies. Of course, everyone is wooed by the child's kind words for Martin. The ending is unexpected, but a good one. Everyone gets what they deserve.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent family law movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anthony Wright, Esq.
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When facing losing your child in the court system, a parent suffers a roller-coaster of emotions. Here, two wannabe fathers are fighting for their parental rights to a daughter. One father had been highly regarded in the community and had unbounded political ambitions. The other father was a town drunk and miser who lived on the land of the other father. The movie is suspenseful at times, dark at times, light at times, and has a great ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Real Silas Marner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mulierose
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As we all know, the real book, "Silas Marner" was first published in 1861 by "George Eliot". Well, in the time the book was published, women weren't "supposed" to write books like this. George Eliot's real name is Mary Ann Evans 1819-1880. Her understanding of the "Human condition" and the effects of loneliness on a person are greatly adapted into the book. If you read the novel, even though the wording of the book is different than modern English, well... that's part of the charm of the book. It takes you into a time when that's how they spoke. When considering the era of the book, and once again the adaptation of the movie "A Simple Twist of Fate", I believe that Steve Martin did an excellent job. Although... there's no substitution for the original work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I simply adore this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CoffeeGoddess
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is so understated and underrated as to be in danger of completely disappearing from the radar screen. For Steve Martin to be in a non-Jerk type roll makes seeing this movie next to impossible for a great number of people. No, he's not acting weird. No, he doesn't have an arrow on his head. No, he isn't going for the laugh. This is Mr. Martin at his acting best. If you were impressed by his recent turn in 'Shopgirl' the do yourself a favor and go out of your way to find a copy of this movie. Are there times when humor finds its way into this movie? Oh yeah but for the most part there is nothing but good solid storytelling with excellent casting and an excellent script. See this movie if you want to see a wonderful character study acted out by a superb cast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A misunderstood classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yoda87960
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Note: This doesn't really contain spoilers, but hey, one slip of the mouse could blacklist me. I just finished watching the outstanding Shopgirl and I couldn't help but think of this film. I've probably seen it around ten times. Only two or three times at home, but in high school I swear teachers showed it once or twice a year to kill some time. It didn't matter if we were reading Silas Marner or not. It has never gotten old. People seem to go into this movie expecting a comedy, but it's really not. It's a haunting and beautiful movie filled with imagery that I can still see in my head, even though I haven't seen the movie in a couple of years. I assume when this came out, it was largely ignored because it had the look and conventions of other lesser movies of the time. Besides, who would want to see a drama from Steve Martin? Now that it's years removed from the climate it was released, it can truly be appreciated for what it is. A true gem.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This one's a sleeper
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dragon_grl_19
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is what I like to call a sleeper. The cable descriptions are usually terrible and uninteresting but this a wonderful heartwarming movie about love and family. When I played it for my sister one day she argued that she didn't want to watch it but after it was over she fell in love with the sometimes sad, often times humorous story of a man with nothing left to lose and the baby that saves him! Steve Martin flexes his acting talent showing that he isn't always funny/stupid. And the young actress playing Mathilda at age 10 is amazing and really reminds me of Amy Smart. Even though this movie is a little bit older it still applies to life today and it is highly recommended by me!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good story, terrible script and acting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wildferalfemme
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a real disappointment. Steve Martin did okay in the lead role about a man whose wife tells him that their unborn child belongs to another man and they divorce and he becomes a recluse who drinks and counts his gold coins...but it was hard to see past the many years of outrageous comedy Martin did to take him too seriously here. The acting and dialogue were just awful. Linney and Bryne were wooden and lacked any depth whatsoever and I didn't care about anything that happened to them. The little girl, who rarely uttered a word (which seemed a bit unrealistic for any child)was played by so many child actors it was hard to tell it was even the same character in any particular scene. Overall it was mediocre and I would not recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wonderful well-written and well-acted film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Billie Rae Bates (BRBTVcom)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always enjoyed Steve Martin. It doesn't matter what he's in; I just admire his talent and I've been downright crazy about his humor since I first saw him do that "King Tut" thing back in the 1970s. Here, he tackles a more dramatic role with so much warmth and sincerity, and he even manages to inject some comic moments in his typical style. To know that he also wrote this screenplay is not surprising, as he's a gifted writer, as well. The story in this film is tremendously life-affirming. If nothing else, it illustrates how even the most serious or threatening situation can turn around, just like that, in the blink of an eye. As with M. Night Shyamalan's "Signs," Christians might be thinking of Romans 8:28 when they see this film -- how events, good or bad, are so often intricately orchestrated to a better end that we really can't see coming. My favorite point in the film is when Steve Martin's character, having just been robbed of the fortune he's amassed in gold coins (he stored his cash in these coins rather than in a bank), sees this sweet toddler girl wandering aimlessly into his home as an event that was simply meant to be, as the "gift" he is given because his money has been taken away. His faithful perspective is greatly rewarded.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A well-intentioned movie suffering from an identity crisis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    glazed_doughnut
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying that I am a Steve Martin fan and anyone who questions his ability to do serious work has never seen Grand Canyon. I picked up this movie with the intent of watching it with my kids, aged 12 and 6. About 15 minutes or so into the movie, after witnessing shot-drinking, a heroin needle and two people sharing a joint, I seriously considered turning the movie off. The fact is that once past these moments, the movie does begin to work as a more heart-warming family tale. What irks me however is that I don't understand why people making a movie that kids can watch have to resort to adult imagery in some feeble attempt to generate adult interest. If one wishes to make a grown-up movie with adult images, then by all means do so, but this movie simply does not work on that level; it maintains too much of a superficial and sweet flavor to be considered as such. So, why then, if I am watching a family movie, should I be forced to lie to my children about some of the imagery they are seeing? I certainly don't want to explain to them what heroin or marijuana is and the truth is that none of these images were necessary to the telling of the story. Therein lies my biggest problem with this movie as a whole. There are simply too many small scenes and images that are forcibly interjected into the story without necessity. The baseball scene, the scene by the edge of the quarry as well as many other smaller moments almost seem randomly inserted into the movie as though after the final cut the producers felt they need 20 minutes more to fill. My kids, fortunately, asked no questions, but did ask to watch the movie again the next day (a practice they inherited from their father), so I would honestly say that the movie does function on their level and I would recommend it to any parent who doesn't feel uncomfortable by the occasional adult imagery passing before their child's eyes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    destiny of necessity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a departure from his usual roles, Steve Martin plays a lonely man who adopts a girl after she happens into his house. "A Simple Twist of Fate" is an almost mystifying movie, and a very good one. While there are certainly some funny parts, it's mainly about how the entry of this girl into his existence changes the course of his life, and also turns out to have a link to something else in his life. The movie has really good character development. Along with Martin, there's Gabriel Byrne as a slimy politician, Laura Linney as his unfulfilled wife, and Catherine O'Hara as a shopkeeper who helps Martin. This is a movie that I very much recommend to everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Custody Battle With Steve Martin-Simple Twist of Fate ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Something very different for Steve Martin as he portrays a man who divorced his wife when he found out that the child they expected was not his. Enter another child in his life when a young woman dies on her way to the baby girl's wealthy political father. The father, who knew this was his child when he saw the dead woman, made no effort to claim the child as his. Instead, the child stays with Martin who loves her dearly and takes care of her in a manner of a true parent. 10 years later, the real father, Gabriel Byrne and his wife, Laura Linney, are childless and when Martin brings the child along with him to deliver furniture, Byrne confesses to all that he is the father of the child and a custody battle ensues. These custody battles are very clich&eacute; in movies. Of course, everyone is wooed by the child's kind words for Martin. The ending is unexpected, but a good one. Everyone gets what they deserve.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent family law movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anthony Wright, Esq.
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When facing losing your child in the court system, a parent suffers a roller-coaster of emotions. Here, two wannabe fathers are fighting for their parental rights to a daughter. One father had been highly regarded in the community and had unbounded political ambitions. The other father was a town drunk and miser who lived on the land of the other father. The movie is suspenseful at times, dark at times, light at times, and has a great ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Real Silas Marner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mulierose
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As we all know, the real book, "Silas Marner" was first published in 1861 by "George Eliot". Well, in the time the book was published, women weren't "supposed" to write books like this. George Eliot's real name is Mary Ann Evans 1819-1880. Her understanding of the "Human condition" and the effects of loneliness on a person are greatly adapted into the book. If you read the novel, even though the wording of the book is different than modern English, well... that's part of the charm of the book. It takes you into a time when that's how they spoke. When considering the era of the book, and once again the adaptation of the movie "A Simple Twist of Fate", I believe that Steve Martin did an excellent job. Although... there's no substitution for the original work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I simply adore this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CoffeeGoddess
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is so understated and underrated as to be in danger of completely disappearing from the radar screen. For Steve Martin to be in a non-Jerk type roll makes seeing this movie next to impossible for a great number of people. No, he's not acting weird. No, he doesn't have an arrow on his head. No, he isn't going for the laugh. This is Mr. Martin at his acting best. If you were impressed by his recent turn in 'Shopgirl' the do yourself a favor and go out of your way to find a copy of this movie. Are there times when humor finds its way into this movie? Oh yeah but for the most part there is nothing but good solid storytelling with excellent casting and an excellent script. See this movie if you want to see a wonderful character study acted out by a superb cast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A misunderstood classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yoda87960
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Note: This doesn't really contain spoilers, but hey, one slip of the mouse could blacklist me. I just finished watching the outstanding Shopgirl and I couldn't help but think of this film. I've probably seen it around ten times. Only two or three times at home, but in high school I swear teachers showed it once or twice a year to kill some time. It didn't matter if we were reading Silas Marner or not. It has never gotten old. People seem to go into this movie expecting a comedy, but it's really not. It's a haunting and beautiful movie filled with imagery that I can still see in my head, even though I haven't seen the movie in a couple of years. I assume when this came out, it was largely ignored because it had the look and conventions of other lesser movies of the time. Besides, who would want to see a drama from Steve Martin? Now that it's years removed from the climate it was released, it can truly be appreciated for what it is. A true gem.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This one's a sleeper
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dragon_grl_19
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is what I like to call a sleeper. The cable descriptions are usually terrible and uninteresting but this a wonderful heartwarming movie about love and family. When I played it for my sister one day she argued that she didn't want to watch it but after it was over she fell in love with the sometimes sad, often times humorous story of a man with nothing left to lose and the baby that saves him! Steve Martin flexes his acting talent showing that he isn't always funny/stupid. And the young actress playing Mathilda at age 10 is amazing and really reminds me of Amy Smart. Even though this movie is a little bit older it still applies to life today and it is highly recommended by me!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good story, terrible script and acting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wildferalfemme
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a real disappointment. Steve Martin did okay in the lead role about a man whose wife tells him that their unborn child belongs to another man and they divorce and he becomes a recluse who drinks and counts his gold coins...but it was hard to see past the many years of outrageous comedy Martin did to take him too seriously here. The acting and dialogue were just awful. Linney and Bryne were wooden and lacked any depth whatsoever and I didn't care about anything that happened to them. The little girl, who rarely uttered a word (which seemed a bit unrealistic for any child)was played by so many child actors it was hard to tell it was even the same character in any particular scene. Overall it was mediocre and I would not recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wonderful well-written and well-acted film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Billie Rae Bates (BRBTVcom)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always enjoyed Steve Martin. It doesn't matter what he's in; I just admire his talent and I've been downright crazy about his humor since I first saw him do that "King Tut" thing back in the 1970s. Here, he tackles a more dramatic role with so much warmth and sincerity, and he even manages to inject some comic moments in his typical style. To know that he also wrote this screenplay is not surprising, as he's a gifted writer, as well. The story in this film is tremendously life-affirming. If nothing else, it illustrates how even the most serious or threatening situation can turn around, just like that, in the blink of an eye. As with M. Night Shyamalan's "Signs," Christians might be thinking of Romans 8:28 when they see this film -- how events, good or bad, are so often intricately orchestrated to a better end that we really can't see coming. My favorite point in the film is when Steve Martin's character, having just been robbed of the fortune he's amassed in gold coins (he stored his cash in these coins rather than in a bank), sees this sweet toddler girl wandering aimlessly into his home as an event that was simply meant to be, as the "gift" he is given because his money has been taken away. His faithful perspective is greatly rewarded.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A well-intentioned movie suffering from an identity crisis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    glazed_doughnut
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying that I am a Steve Martin fan and anyone who questions his ability to do serious work has never seen Grand Canyon. I picked up this movie with the intent of watching it with my kids, aged 12 and 6. About 15 minutes or so into the movie, after witnessing shot-drinking, a heroin needle and two people sharing a joint, I seriously considered turning the movie off. The fact is that once past these moments, the movie does begin to work as a more heart-warming family tale. What irks me however is that I don't understand why people making a movie that kids can watch have to resort to adult imagery in some feeble attempt to generate adult interest. If one wishes to make a grown-up movie with adult images, then by all means do so, but this movie simply does not work on that level; it maintains too much of a superficial and sweet flavor to be considered as such. So, why then, if I am watching a family movie, should I be forced to lie to my children about some of the imagery they are seeing? I certainly don't want to explain to them what heroin or marijuana is and the truth is that none of these images were necessary to the telling of the story. Therein lies my biggest problem with this movie as a whole. There are simply too many small scenes and images that are forcibly interjected into the story without necessity. The baseball scene, the scene by the edge of the quarry as well as many other smaller moments almost seem randomly inserted into the movie as though after the final cut the producers felt they need 20 minutes more to fill. My kids, fortunately, asked no questions, but did ask to watch the movie again the next day (a practice they inherited from their father), so I would honestly say that the movie does function on their level and I would recommend it to any parent who doesn't feel uncomfortable by the occasional adult imagery passing before their child's eyes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    destiny of necessity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a departure from his usual roles, Steve Martin plays a lonely man who adopts a girl after she happens into his house. "A Simple Twist of Fate" is an almost mystifying movie, and a very good one. While there are certainly some funny parts, it's mainly about how the entry of this girl into his existence changes the course of his life, and also turns out to have a link to something else in his life. The movie has really good character development. Along with Martin, there's Gabriel Byrne as a slimy politician, Laura Linney as his unfulfilled wife, and Catherine O'Hara as a shopkeeper who helps Martin. This is a movie that I very much recommend to everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Custody Battle With Steve Martin-Simple Twist of Fate ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Something very different for Steve Martin as he portrays a man who divorced his wife when he found out that the child they expected was not his. Enter another child in his life when a young woman dies on her way to the baby girl's wealthy political father. The father, who knew this was his child when he saw the dead woman, made no effort to claim the child as his. Instead, the child stays with Martin who loves her dearly and takes care of her in a manner of a true parent. 10 years later, the real father, Gabriel Byrne and his wife, Laura Linney, are childless and when Martin brings the child along with him to deliver furniture, Byrne confesses to all that he is the father of the child and a custody battle ensues. These custody battles are very clich&eacute; in movies. Of course, everyone is wooed by the child's kind words for Martin. The ending is unexpected, but a good one. Everyone gets what they deserve.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent family law movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anthony Wright, Esq.
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When facing losing your child in the court system, a parent suffers a roller-coaster of emotions. Here, two wannabe fathers are fighting for their parental rights to a daughter. One father had been highly regarded in the community and had unbounded political ambitions. The other father was a town drunk and miser who lived on the land of the other father. The movie is suspenseful at times, dark at times, light at times, and has a great ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Real Silas Marner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mulierose
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As we all know, the real book, "Silas Marner" was first published in 1861 by "George Eliot". Well, in the time the book was published, women weren't "supposed" to write books like this. George Eliot's real name is Mary Ann Evans 1819-1880. Her understanding of the "Human condition" and the effects of loneliness on a person are greatly adapted into the book. If you read the novel, even though the wording of the book is different than modern English, well... that's part of the charm of the book. It takes you into a time when that's how they spoke. When considering the era of the book, and once again the adaptation of the movie "A Simple Twist of Fate", I believe that Steve Martin did an excellent job. Although... there's no substitution for the original work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I simply adore this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CoffeeGoddess
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is so understated and underrated as to be in danger of completely disappearing from the radar screen. For Steve Martin to be in a non-Jerk type roll makes seeing this movie next to impossible for a great number of people. No, he's not acting weird. No, he doesn't have an arrow on his head. No, he isn't going for the laugh. This is Mr. Martin at his acting best. If you were impressed by his recent turn in 'Shopgirl' the do yourself a favor and go out of your way to find a copy of this movie. Are there times when humor finds its way into this movie? Oh yeah but for the most part there is nothing but good solid storytelling with excellent casting and an excellent script. See this movie if you want to see a wonderful character study acted out by a superb cast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A misunderstood classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yoda87960
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Note: This doesn't really contain spoilers, but hey, one slip of the mouse could blacklist me. I just finished watching the outstanding Shopgirl and I couldn't help but think of this film. I've probably seen it around ten times. Only two or three times at home, but in high school I swear teachers showed it once or twice a year to kill some time. It didn't matter if we were reading Silas Marner or not. It has never gotten old. People seem to go into this movie expecting a comedy, but it's really not. It's a haunting and beautiful movie filled with imagery that I can still see in my head, even though I haven't seen the movie in a couple of years. I assume when this came out, it was largely ignored because it had the look and conventions of other lesser movies of the time. Besides, who would want to see a drama from Steve Martin? Now that it's years removed from the climate it was released, it can truly be appreciated for what it is. A true gem.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This one's a sleeper
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dragon_grl_19
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is what I like to call a sleeper. The cable descriptions are usually terrible and uninteresting but this a wonderful heartwarming movie about love and family. When I played it for my sister one day she argued that she didn't want to watch it but after it was over she fell in love with the sometimes sad, often times humorous story of a man with nothing left to lose and the baby that saves him! Steve Martin flexes his acting talent showing that he isn't always funny/stupid. And the young actress playing Mathilda at age 10 is amazing and really reminds me of Amy Smart. Even though this movie is a little bit older it still applies to life today and it is highly recommended by me!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good story, terrible script and acting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wildferalfemme
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a real disappointment. Steve Martin did okay in the lead role about a man whose wife tells him that their unborn child belongs to another man and they divorce and he becomes a recluse who drinks and counts his gold coins...but it was hard to see past the many years of outrageous comedy Martin did to take him too seriously here. The acting and dialogue were just awful. Linney and Bryne were wooden and lacked any depth whatsoever and I didn't care about anything that happened to them. The little girl, who rarely uttered a word (which seemed a bit unrealistic for any child)was played by so many child actors it was hard to tell it was even the same character in any particular scene. Overall it was mediocre and I would not recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wonderful well-written and well-acted film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Billie Rae Bates (BRBTVcom)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always enjoyed Steve Martin. It doesn't matter what he's in; I just admire his talent and I've been downright crazy about his humor since I first saw him do that "King Tut" thing back in the 1970s. Here, he tackles a more dramatic role with so much warmth and sincerity, and he even manages to inject some comic moments in his typical style. To know that he also wrote this screenplay is not surprising, as he's a gifted writer, as well. The story in this film is tremendously life-affirming. If nothing else, it illustrates how even the most serious or threatening situation can turn around, just like that, in the blink of an eye. As with M. Night Shyamalan's "Signs," Christians might be thinking of Romans 8:28 when they see this film -- how events, good or bad, are so often intricately orchestrated to a better end that we really can't see coming. My favorite point in the film is when Steve Martin's character, having just been robbed of the fortune he's amassed in gold coins (he stored his cash in these coins rather than in a bank), sees this sweet toddler girl wandering aimlessly into his home as an event that was simply meant to be, as the "gift" he is given because his money has been taken away. His faithful perspective is greatly rewarded.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A well-intentioned movie suffering from an identity crisis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    glazed_doughnut
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying that I am a Steve Martin fan and anyone who questions his ability to do serious work has never seen Grand Canyon. I picked up this movie with the intent of watching it with my kids, aged 12 and 6. About 15 minutes or so into the movie, after witnessing shot-drinking, a heroin needle and two people sharing a joint, I seriously considered turning the movie off. The fact is that once past these moments, the movie does begin to work as a more heart-warming family tale. What irks me however is that I don't understand why people making a movie that kids can watch have to resort to adult imagery in some feeble attempt to generate adult interest. If one wishes to make a grown-up movie with adult images, then by all means do so, but this movie simply does not work on that level; it maintains too much of a superficial and sweet flavor to be considered as such. So, why then, if I am watching a family movie, should I be forced to lie to my children about some of the imagery they are seeing? I certainly don't want to explain to them what heroin or marijuana is and the truth is that none of these images were necessary to the telling of the story. Therein lies my biggest problem with this movie as a whole. There are simply too many small scenes and images that are forcibly interjected into the story without necessity. The baseball scene, the scene by the edge of the quarry as well as many other smaller moments almost seem randomly inserted into the movie as though after the final cut the producers felt they need 20 minutes more to fill. My kids, fortunately, asked no questions, but did ask to watch the movie again the next day (a practice they inherited from their father), so I would honestly say that the movie does function on their level and I would recommend it to any parent who doesn't feel uncomfortable by the occasional adult imagery passing before their child's eyes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
