<filme>
 <id>
  1059
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116126
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Vizinhan&ccedil;a do Barulho
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  "Don't Be a Menace to South Central While Drinking your Juice in the Hood" is a parody of a lot of Afro-American movies, for instance "Boyz N the Hood", "South Central", "Menace II Society"... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  "Don't Be a Menace to South Central While Drinking your Juice in the Hood" is a parody of a lot of Afro-American movies, for instance "Boyz N the Hood", "South Central", "Menace II Society", "Higher Learning" and "Juice". We follow Ashtray as he returns to the place he grew up in and meet his father and his basket-case friends. A lot of crazy stuff happens, for example, Ashtray is older than his father and his best friend Loc Dog's grandmother is a trigger-happy old lady who blames her eccentric-looking kid for not being tough enough.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   hood
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   friend
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   parody
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   grandmother
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   revenge
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Paris Barclay
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Shawn Wayans
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Marlon Wayans
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Shawn Wayans
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Marlon Wayans
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Keenen Ivory Wayans
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surreal? no...this is real life!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tulhamano
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great movie, I saw it when i was around 14 it played on Portuguese TV, I didn't knew its name but i kept searching all this years, finally i got it and watched it again, same fun. People told me get "friday" get "half baked" and was never it...this is it!! You don't need to watch any other "hood" movie to understand or like this movie, you probably just need to know a little bit about the hood or about the street life or what you may like to call it. Im not American, Im not black, and I liked the movie and understood the humor on it completely, also helped that I listen to some American rap and I can more fully understand some references related to racial issues. About the movie itself it has no plot so its impossible for anyone to come here and write a spoiler. It's a succession of events, and the plot is just an excuse to keep it going. I find it a very smart, lively and audacious caricature/satire of hood life, all the stereotypes exaggerated and pointed out in a very straight fashion, straight and real enough to hurt many "sensitive" feelings, not every scene in the movie is hilarious some are not so funny, but it is made in such a relaxed and flowing atmosphere that everything is fine is all good. Music is excellent and it has many quality details from the production creating the right atmosphere. Well I loved this movie and I wish they would make more of this kind, at the same time it is a surreal or a nonsense comedy it has very deep meaning on it and it can look so real, because reality is so much like this, day to day life is not full of drama, its more full of comedy, and full of crazy and superficial characters somehow similar to the ones on this movie. Also reference to many talented actors here that became famous, almost every face is familiar. Comparing this with "Friday" or "Scary movie" for me is more hilarious than the movie itself. Just watch it, its a whole different level. Sorry if I got carried away with the review, this one deserves a big text and a 9.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A funny theme
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lrbast
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie that hits on many truths. Its a funny movie that represents the ghetto. in the white eyes its a exaggerated truth of the hood. in the ghetto eyes its a joke of the code of the streets. The movie will bring up allot of controversy and plays fun of and spoofs of the real world. Almost every part of this movie will bring up personal or beliefs of what you see the perfect hood. Its worth seeing and paying attention to every word and scene in this movie over and over again. Even behind the main parts of the movie can be funny to you. The Waynes brothers are the most genius in this movie then every thing that they have done. I have never seen any movie that is so on and so wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Than I Expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alfonso Snell
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was genuinely pretty funny. It's a pretty good parody of hood movies, a genre that has some good flicks and some real steamers. It's accurate and clever and I laughed out loud. I recommend to anyone who just wants to laugh and people who are interested in the subject of race and it's effect on culture and media. I usually turn on bad movies on weekends just to pass time and have a laugh, or to get some sleep. I found this on demand and thought it would be pretty bad considering it was Wayans Bros. They've only done a few movies worth watching. But I liked the title and I liked the idea, and it made me laugh for the right reasons. A solid 7.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest movies of all time... you will never see another one like this...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nazia1987
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't be a Menace is one of the funniest films of all times. It takes a serious genre of film and picks apart every detail of it. This film shows no mercy. It is only out for entertainment. The most pivotal, gritty, and shocking scenes from hood movies, the ones that defined the genre and changed the way Americans thought about cinema and society, are spoofed mercilessly from the preachy Ice-Cube monologue at the end of Boyz in the Hood to the Asian convenience store in the beginning of Menace II Society... This movie has gotten shockingly bad reviews but I imagine these people have never seen hood films. Either that or they are the type that want to take everything too seriously. This is not a movie to think about and analyze or drag politics into... it is a film to enjoy From the opening comment spoofing the Boyz intro ("one out of every ten black males will be forced to sit through at least one growing up in the hood movie in their lifetimes") to the ending scene, you will be in pain from the laughter this film will ensue if you have grown up watching hood films. This movie is one giant stereotype which people might pick at, but that is ultimately the point. While films like Menace II Society and Boyz have become classics of the 90s, they have also played on age old stereotypes and that is the heart of this film. Pickles, anyone?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No need to know the spoofees
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rogerdowe2000
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually never seen most of the movies that they were spoofing about but still thought it was one of the funniest and I mean funniest movies of all time this movie is filled with hidden puns that should tickle your funny bone. To give this movie an overall 6.5 is a disgrace both to the wayans bro's and comedy lovers all around the world at least an 8 8.5 minimum I really don't think anyone can name me a movie that is even remotely as funny or as good as this one. If you love quirky comedy than this movie is definitely for you I recommend it and so does my brother after watching menace 2 society ( which is the movie this movie is based upon) I really did have a true understanding of it but didn't really matter cause it was funny either way
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Laughed So Hard!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BGonzo081185
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I laughed for hours after the first time I saw this movie. I can still watch it today and crack up. As long as you've seen "Boyz in the Hood" "Menace to Society" "Dead Presidents" and "Poetic Justice" you will think this movie is one of the best comedy spoofs ever. My buddies and I still quote this movie all the time. I love how they even got some of the people from those movies to do the spoofs. The funniest part belonged to Bernie Mac as the black cop. I would strongly recommend this movie to anyone just wanting to get some laughs. I give it a 10 for being a great spoof. You will especially like this if you are a fan of the scary movie series.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A parody we can all learn from.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Wafford
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard to find a good parody these days. The likes of scary movie, and other movies in the same vein are wearing kind of thin on actual humor but big on crude sexual gags. This movie however, manages to find a pleasant balance between the two. It manages to be intelligent and at the same time completely disgusting (crackhead lovin' anyone?)I guarantee you'll be in tears the whole movie, from references to other great works of Afro-drama to self parodies so great it almost becomes paradoxical (Like a mailman that just happens to have a "MESSAGE!" every time a character has something wise to say.) I give this movie one of my highest recommendations.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    timing is everything
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (winner55)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was watching an old "Honeymooners" rerun with a friend and we came to Jackie Gleason's Ralph's inevitable "To the moon, Alice!" expression of frustration with his wife, and suddenly I realized that it WAS inevitable, so why were we laughing, having heard it a dozen times before? My friend pointed out that Gleason's timing - the manner in which he held his slow-burn, the widening of his eyes, the sudden "Bang! Zoom" take off into the line - was what always made it funny. We weren't laughing at the line so much at the performance of it. "Don't Be A Menace" is the most obvious collection of predictable gags and bits I have seen in a long time, but it is by far the funniest. The Wayans are rather stuck - the genres they parody here have very rigid conventions, so much so that there is usually only one or two gags one can use to mock them - e.g., when a young gangsta warns us that many young men in the 'hood don't live to see their 21st birthday, we all know what's coming next. So the Wayans handle it in a manner that delays the punchline while emphasizing its obviousness. Thus we laugh with them, appreciating the way they pull it off, and recognizing the gangsta genre limit that's getting parodied, rather than at the bit itself. Just about the whole movie operates on this level, and for this reason has become one of my favorite comedies. The Wayans capture every moment with a dead-on rhythm that blends the gags into a kind of music. Shawn plays the steady bass while Marlon does some wild riffing. Other characters and bits drop in and out like improvisation and sound effects. Keenan Wayans drops in every now and then like the voice on a scratch dub. The tempo could have been a little swifter, but the rhythm itself is excellent. Comedy like this is very tricky, and I personally didn't think the Wayans' efforts in the "Scary Movie" films were quite as successful - but here they move it right along. It's rude, it's crude, it's in-yor-face - and it's just a delight to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way On, Right On
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nearly all movies are about other movies. Nearly all life acts are from movies; nearly all stereotypes are from acts. The Wayons merely close the loop: movies where the acts are stereotypes of stereotypes. They really know what they are doing, disguising it as social commentary. But that you get enough of in the first five minutes. Check out how many jokes are about acting, about every third one. And then check out what they did next, with "Scary Movies," which takes the circle one more loop. I admit that I'm a fan. They seem to be the only ones who can do what Zucker used to: serve up what are generally called spoofs. I think it is because they start knowing that the target isn't bits of movies, but the bits we use in inventing the stories of who we are. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The one before 'Scary' movies etc...Homie plays that!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Wolfe
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie title alone, takes two hours to say. And talk about breaking all the stereotypical rules, if they weren't breaking all the rules I don't know what they would be doing. "Don't be a menace" I'm not surprised that there wasn't a sequel to this although it was ghetto -cutting humor that ate just about every other 'Hood' movie around then. If their comedy was a shotgun then there would be comedy-spatter all over the screen. Kim Wayans and the whole happy bunch bring their 'creative juices' to this hoodster-Rama, a ton of vulgarity, but a mountain of wit and eccentric brains, The Wayans make this a colorful and tasty treat for every fan. From the entry at Tray's room to the seven kids looking for their daddy and finding a step dad with a small car, this was a rap-hop malt-liquor adventure that really packs a staggering punch! See this if you liked "In Living Color" or if you just want to get comfortably into ghetto styled laugher-riotousness. (****). Thx --Imdb.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surreal? no...this is real life!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tulhamano
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great movie, I saw it when i was around 14 it played on Portuguese TV, I didn't knew its name but i kept searching all this years, finally i got it and watched it again, same fun. People told me get "friday" get "half baked" and was never it...this is it!! You don't need to watch any other "hood" movie to understand or like this movie, you probably just need to know a little bit about the hood or about the street life or what you may like to call it. Im not American, Im not black, and I liked the movie and understood the humor on it completely, also helped that I listen to some American rap and I can more fully understand some references related to racial issues. About the movie itself it has no plot so its impossible for anyone to come here and write a spoiler. It's a succession of events, and the plot is just an excuse to keep it going. I find it a very smart, lively and audacious caricature/satire of hood life, all the stereotypes exaggerated and pointed out in a very straight fashion, straight and real enough to hurt many "sensitive" feelings, not every scene in the movie is hilarious some are not so funny, but it is made in such a relaxed and flowing atmosphere that everything is fine is all good. Music is excellent and it has many quality details from the production creating the right atmosphere. Well I loved this movie and I wish they would make more of this kind, at the same time it is a surreal or a nonsense comedy it has very deep meaning on it and it can look so real, because reality is so much like this, day to day life is not full of drama, its more full of comedy, and full of crazy and superficial characters somehow similar to the ones on this movie. Also reference to many talented actors here that became famous, almost every face is familiar. Comparing this with "Friday" or "Scary movie" for me is more hilarious than the movie itself. Just watch it, its a whole different level. Sorry if I got carried away with the review, this one deserves a big text and a 9.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A funny theme
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lrbast
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie that hits on many truths. Its a funny movie that represents the ghetto. in the white eyes its a exaggerated truth of the hood. in the ghetto eyes its a joke of the code of the streets. The movie will bring up allot of controversy and plays fun of and spoofs of the real world. Almost every part of this movie will bring up personal or beliefs of what you see the perfect hood. Its worth seeing and paying attention to every word and scene in this movie over and over again. Even behind the main parts of the movie can be funny to you. The Waynes brothers are the most genius in this movie then every thing that they have done. I have never seen any movie that is so on and so wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Than I Expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alfonso Snell
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was genuinely pretty funny. It's a pretty good parody of hood movies, a genre that has some good flicks and some real steamers. It's accurate and clever and I laughed out loud. I recommend to anyone who just wants to laugh and people who are interested in the subject of race and it's effect on culture and media. I usually turn on bad movies on weekends just to pass time and have a laugh, or to get some sleep. I found this on demand and thought it would be pretty bad considering it was Wayans Bros. They've only done a few movies worth watching. But I liked the title and I liked the idea, and it made me laugh for the right reasons. A solid 7.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest movies of all time... you will never see another one like this...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nazia1987
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't be a Menace is one of the funniest films of all times. It takes a serious genre of film and picks apart every detail of it. This film shows no mercy. It is only out for entertainment. The most pivotal, gritty, and shocking scenes from hood movies, the ones that defined the genre and changed the way Americans thought about cinema and society, are spoofed mercilessly from the preachy Ice-Cube monologue at the end of Boyz in the Hood to the Asian convenience store in the beginning of Menace II Society... This movie has gotten shockingly bad reviews but I imagine these people have never seen hood films. Either that or they are the type that want to take everything too seriously. This is not a movie to think about and analyze or drag politics into... it is a film to enjoy From the opening comment spoofing the Boyz intro ("one out of every ten black males will be forced to sit through at least one growing up in the hood movie in their lifetimes") to the ending scene, you will be in pain from the laughter this film will ensue if you have grown up watching hood films. This movie is one giant stereotype which people might pick at, but that is ultimately the point. While films like Menace II Society and Boyz have become classics of the 90s, they have also played on age old stereotypes and that is the heart of this film. Pickles, anyone?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No need to know the spoofees
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rogerdowe2000
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually never seen most of the movies that they were spoofing about but still thought it was one of the funniest and I mean funniest movies of all time this movie is filled with hidden puns that should tickle your funny bone. To give this movie an overall 6.5 is a disgrace both to the wayans bro's and comedy lovers all around the world at least an 8 8.5 minimum I really don't think anyone can name me a movie that is even remotely as funny or as good as this one. If you love quirky comedy than this movie is definitely for you I recommend it and so does my brother after watching menace 2 society ( which is the movie this movie is based upon) I really did have a true understanding of it but didn't really matter cause it was funny either way
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Laughed So Hard!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BGonzo081185
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I laughed for hours after the first time I saw this movie. I can still watch it today and crack up. As long as you've seen "Boyz in the Hood" "Menace to Society" "Dead Presidents" and "Poetic Justice" you will think this movie is one of the best comedy spoofs ever. My buddies and I still quote this movie all the time. I love how they even got some of the people from those movies to do the spoofs. The funniest part belonged to Bernie Mac as the black cop. I would strongly recommend this movie to anyone just wanting to get some laughs. I give it a 10 for being a great spoof. You will especially like this if you are a fan of the scary movie series.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A parody we can all learn from.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Wafford
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard to find a good parody these days. The likes of scary movie, and other movies in the same vein are wearing kind of thin on actual humor but big on crude sexual gags. This movie however, manages to find a pleasant balance between the two. It manages to be intelligent and at the same time completely disgusting (crackhead lovin' anyone?)I guarantee you'll be in tears the whole movie, from references to other great works of Afro-drama to self parodies so great it almost becomes paradoxical (Like a mailman that just happens to have a "MESSAGE!" every time a character has something wise to say.) I give this movie one of my highest recommendations.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    timing is everything
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (winner55)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was watching an old "Honeymooners" rerun with a friend and we came to Jackie Gleason's Ralph's inevitable "To the moon, Alice!" expression of frustration with his wife, and suddenly I realized that it WAS inevitable, so why were we laughing, having heard it a dozen times before? My friend pointed out that Gleason's timing - the manner in which he held his slow-burn, the widening of his eyes, the sudden "Bang! Zoom" take off into the line - was what always made it funny. We weren't laughing at the line so much at the performance of it. "Don't Be A Menace" is the most obvious collection of predictable gags and bits I have seen in a long time, but it is by far the funniest. The Wayans are rather stuck - the genres they parody here have very rigid conventions, so much so that there is usually only one or two gags one can use to mock them - e.g., when a young gangsta warns us that many young men in the 'hood don't live to see their 21st birthday, we all know what's coming next. So the Wayans handle it in a manner that delays the punchline while emphasizing its obviousness. Thus we laugh with them, appreciating the way they pull it off, and recognizing the gangsta genre limit that's getting parodied, rather than at the bit itself. Just about the whole movie operates on this level, and for this reason has become one of my favorite comedies. The Wayans capture every moment with a dead-on rhythm that blends the gags into a kind of music. Shawn plays the steady bass while Marlon does some wild riffing. Other characters and bits drop in and out like improvisation and sound effects. Keenan Wayans drops in every now and then like the voice on a scratch dub. The tempo could have been a little swifter, but the rhythm itself is excellent. Comedy like this is very tricky, and I personally didn't think the Wayans' efforts in the "Scary Movie" films were quite as successful - but here they move it right along. It's rude, it's crude, it's in-yor-face - and it's just a delight to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way On, Right On
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nearly all movies are about other movies. Nearly all life acts are from movies; nearly all stereotypes are from acts. The Wayons merely close the loop: movies where the acts are stereotypes of stereotypes. They really know what they are doing, disguising it as social commentary. But that you get enough of in the first five minutes. Check out how many jokes are about acting, about every third one. And then check out what they did next, with "Scary Movies," which takes the circle one more loop. I admit that I'm a fan. They seem to be the only ones who can do what Zucker used to: serve up what are generally called spoofs. I think it is because they start knowing that the target isn't bits of movies, but the bits we use in inventing the stories of who we are. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The one before 'Scary' movies etc...Homie plays that!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Wolfe
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie title alone, takes two hours to say. And talk about breaking all the stereotypical rules, if they weren't breaking all the rules I don't know what they would be doing. "Don't be a menace" I'm not surprised that there wasn't a sequel to this although it was ghetto -cutting humor that ate just about every other 'Hood' movie around then. If their comedy was a shotgun then there would be comedy-spatter all over the screen. Kim Wayans and the whole happy bunch bring their 'creative juices' to this hoodster-Rama, a ton of vulgarity, but a mountain of wit and eccentric brains, The Wayans make this a colorful and tasty treat for every fan. From the entry at Tray's room to the seven kids looking for their daddy and finding a step dad with a small car, this was a rap-hop malt-liquor adventure that really packs a staggering punch! See this if you liked "In Living Color" or if you just want to get comfortably into ghetto styled laugher-riotousness. (****). Thx --Imdb.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surreal? no...this is real life!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tulhamano
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great movie, I saw it when i was around 14 it played on Portuguese TV, I didn't knew its name but i kept searching all this years, finally i got it and watched it again, same fun. People told me get "friday" get "half baked" and was never it...this is it!! You don't need to watch any other "hood" movie to understand or like this movie, you probably just need to know a little bit about the hood or about the street life or what you may like to call it. Im not American, Im not black, and I liked the movie and understood the humor on it completely, also helped that I listen to some American rap and I can more fully understand some references related to racial issues. About the movie itself it has no plot so its impossible for anyone to come here and write a spoiler. It's a succession of events, and the plot is just an excuse to keep it going. I find it a very smart, lively and audacious caricature/satire of hood life, all the stereotypes exaggerated and pointed out in a very straight fashion, straight and real enough to hurt many "sensitive" feelings, not every scene in the movie is hilarious some are not so funny, but it is made in such a relaxed and flowing atmosphere that everything is fine is all good. Music is excellent and it has many quality details from the production creating the right atmosphere. Well I loved this movie and I wish they would make more of this kind, at the same time it is a surreal or a nonsense comedy it has very deep meaning on it and it can look so real, because reality is so much like this, day to day life is not full of drama, its more full of comedy, and full of crazy and superficial characters somehow similar to the ones on this movie. Also reference to many talented actors here that became famous, almost every face is familiar. Comparing this with "Friday" or "Scary movie" for me is more hilarious than the movie itself. Just watch it, its a whole different level. Sorry if I got carried away with the review, this one deserves a big text and a 9.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A funny theme
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lrbast
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie that hits on many truths. Its a funny movie that represents the ghetto. in the white eyes its a exaggerated truth of the hood. in the ghetto eyes its a joke of the code of the streets. The movie will bring up allot of controversy and plays fun of and spoofs of the real world. Almost every part of this movie will bring up personal or beliefs of what you see the perfect hood. Its worth seeing and paying attention to every word and scene in this movie over and over again. Even behind the main parts of the movie can be funny to you. The Waynes brothers are the most genius in this movie then every thing that they have done. I have never seen any movie that is so on and so wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Than I Expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alfonso Snell
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was genuinely pretty funny. It's a pretty good parody of hood movies, a genre that has some good flicks and some real steamers. It's accurate and clever and I laughed out loud. I recommend to anyone who just wants to laugh and people who are interested in the subject of race and it's effect on culture and media. I usually turn on bad movies on weekends just to pass time and have a laugh, or to get some sleep. I found this on demand and thought it would be pretty bad considering it was Wayans Bros. They've only done a few movies worth watching. But I liked the title and I liked the idea, and it made me laugh for the right reasons. A solid 7.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest movies of all time... you will never see another one like this...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nazia1987
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't be a Menace is one of the funniest films of all times. It takes a serious genre of film and picks apart every detail of it. This film shows no mercy. It is only out for entertainment. The most pivotal, gritty, and shocking scenes from hood movies, the ones that defined the genre and changed the way Americans thought about cinema and society, are spoofed mercilessly from the preachy Ice-Cube monologue at the end of Boyz in the Hood to the Asian convenience store in the beginning of Menace II Society... This movie has gotten shockingly bad reviews but I imagine these people have never seen hood films. Either that or they are the type that want to take everything too seriously. This is not a movie to think about and analyze or drag politics into... it is a film to enjoy From the opening comment spoofing the Boyz intro ("one out of every ten black males will be forced to sit through at least one growing up in the hood movie in their lifetimes") to the ending scene, you will be in pain from the laughter this film will ensue if you have grown up watching hood films. This movie is one giant stereotype which people might pick at, but that is ultimately the point. While films like Menace II Society and Boyz have become classics of the 90s, they have also played on age old stereotypes and that is the heart of this film. Pickles, anyone?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No need to know the spoofees
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rogerdowe2000
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually never seen most of the movies that they were spoofing about but still thought it was one of the funniest and I mean funniest movies of all time this movie is filled with hidden puns that should tickle your funny bone. To give this movie an overall 6.5 is a disgrace both to the wayans bro's and comedy lovers all around the world at least an 8 8.5 minimum I really don't think anyone can name me a movie that is even remotely as funny or as good as this one. If you love quirky comedy than this movie is definitely for you I recommend it and so does my brother after watching menace 2 society ( which is the movie this movie is based upon) I really did have a true understanding of it but didn't really matter cause it was funny either way
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Laughed So Hard!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BGonzo081185
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I laughed for hours after the first time I saw this movie. I can still watch it today and crack up. As long as you've seen "Boyz in the Hood" "Menace to Society" "Dead Presidents" and "Poetic Justice" you will think this movie is one of the best comedy spoofs ever. My buddies and I still quote this movie all the time. I love how they even got some of the people from those movies to do the spoofs. The funniest part belonged to Bernie Mac as the black cop. I would strongly recommend this movie to anyone just wanting to get some laughs. I give it a 10 for being a great spoof. You will especially like this if you are a fan of the scary movie series.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A parody we can all learn from.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Wafford
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard to find a good parody these days. The likes of scary movie, and other movies in the same vein are wearing kind of thin on actual humor but big on crude sexual gags. This movie however, manages to find a pleasant balance between the two. It manages to be intelligent and at the same time completely disgusting (crackhead lovin' anyone?)I guarantee you'll be in tears the whole movie, from references to other great works of Afro-drama to self parodies so great it almost becomes paradoxical (Like a mailman that just happens to have a "MESSAGE!" every time a character has something wise to say.) I give this movie one of my highest recommendations.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    timing is everything
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (winner55)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was watching an old "Honeymooners" rerun with a friend and we came to Jackie Gleason's Ralph's inevitable "To the moon, Alice!" expression of frustration with his wife, and suddenly I realized that it WAS inevitable, so why were we laughing, having heard it a dozen times before? My friend pointed out that Gleason's timing - the manner in which he held his slow-burn, the widening of his eyes, the sudden "Bang! Zoom" take off into the line - was what always made it funny. We weren't laughing at the line so much at the performance of it. "Don't Be A Menace" is the most obvious collection of predictable gags and bits I have seen in a long time, but it is by far the funniest. The Wayans are rather stuck - the genres they parody here have very rigid conventions, so much so that there is usually only one or two gags one can use to mock them - e.g., when a young gangsta warns us that many young men in the 'hood don't live to see their 21st birthday, we all know what's coming next. So the Wayans handle it in a manner that delays the punchline while emphasizing its obviousness. Thus we laugh with them, appreciating the way they pull it off, and recognizing the gangsta genre limit that's getting parodied, rather than at the bit itself. Just about the whole movie operates on this level, and for this reason has become one of my favorite comedies. The Wayans capture every moment with a dead-on rhythm that blends the gags into a kind of music. Shawn plays the steady bass while Marlon does some wild riffing. Other characters and bits drop in and out like improvisation and sound effects. Keenan Wayans drops in every now and then like the voice on a scratch dub. The tempo could have been a little swifter, but the rhythm itself is excellent. Comedy like this is very tricky, and I personally didn't think the Wayans' efforts in the "Scary Movie" films were quite as successful - but here they move it right along. It's rude, it's crude, it's in-yor-face - and it's just a delight to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way On, Right On
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nearly all movies are about other movies. Nearly all life acts are from movies; nearly all stereotypes are from acts. The Wayons merely close the loop: movies where the acts are stereotypes of stereotypes. They really know what they are doing, disguising it as social commentary. But that you get enough of in the first five minutes. Check out how many jokes are about acting, about every third one. And then check out what they did next, with "Scary Movies," which takes the circle one more loop. I admit that I'm a fan. They seem to be the only ones who can do what Zucker used to: serve up what are generally called spoofs. I think it is because they start knowing that the target isn't bits of movies, but the bits we use in inventing the stories of who we are. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The one before 'Scary' movies etc...Homie plays that!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Wolfe
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie title alone, takes two hours to say. And talk about breaking all the stereotypical rules, if they weren't breaking all the rules I don't know what they would be doing. "Don't be a menace" I'm not surprised that there wasn't a sequel to this although it was ghetto -cutting humor that ate just about every other 'Hood' movie around then. If their comedy was a shotgun then there would be comedy-spatter all over the screen. Kim Wayans and the whole happy bunch bring their 'creative juices' to this hoodster-Rama, a ton of vulgarity, but a mountain of wit and eccentric brains, The Wayans make this a colorful and tasty treat for every fan. From the entry at Tray's room to the seven kids looking for their daddy and finding a step dad with a small car, this was a rap-hop malt-liquor adventure that really packs a staggering punch! See this if you liked "In Living Color" or if you just want to get comfortably into ghetto styled laugher-riotousness. (****). Thx --Imdb.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surreal? no...this is real life!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tulhamano
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great movie, I saw it when i was around 14 it played on Portuguese TV, I didn't knew its name but i kept searching all this years, finally i got it and watched it again, same fun. People told me get "friday" get "half baked" and was never it...this is it!! You don't need to watch any other "hood" movie to understand or like this movie, you probably just need to know a little bit about the hood or about the street life or what you may like to call it. Im not American, Im not black, and I liked the movie and understood the humor on it completely, also helped that I listen to some American rap and I can more fully understand some references related to racial issues. About the movie itself it has no plot so its impossible for anyone to come here and write a spoiler. It's a succession of events, and the plot is just an excuse to keep it going. I find it a very smart, lively and audacious caricature/satire of hood life, all the stereotypes exaggerated and pointed out in a very straight fashion, straight and real enough to hurt many "sensitive" feelings, not every scene in the movie is hilarious some are not so funny, but it is made in such a relaxed and flowing atmosphere that everything is fine is all good. Music is excellent and it has many quality details from the production creating the right atmosphere. Well I loved this movie and I wish they would make more of this kind, at the same time it is a surreal or a nonsense comedy it has very deep meaning on it and it can look so real, because reality is so much like this, day to day life is not full of drama, its more full of comedy, and full of crazy and superficial characters somehow similar to the ones on this movie. Also reference to many talented actors here that became famous, almost every face is familiar. Comparing this with "Friday" or "Scary movie" for me is more hilarious than the movie itself. Just watch it, its a whole different level. Sorry if I got carried away with the review, this one deserves a big text and a 9.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A funny theme
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lrbast
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie that hits on many truths. Its a funny movie that represents the ghetto. in the white eyes its a exaggerated truth of the hood. in the ghetto eyes its a joke of the code of the streets. The movie will bring up allot of controversy and plays fun of and spoofs of the real world. Almost every part of this movie will bring up personal or beliefs of what you see the perfect hood. Its worth seeing and paying attention to every word and scene in this movie over and over again. Even behind the main parts of the movie can be funny to you. The Waynes brothers are the most genius in this movie then every thing that they have done. I have never seen any movie that is so on and so wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Than I Expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alfonso Snell
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was genuinely pretty funny. It's a pretty good parody of hood movies, a genre that has some good flicks and some real steamers. It's accurate and clever and I laughed out loud. I recommend to anyone who just wants to laugh and people who are interested in the subject of race and it's effect on culture and media. I usually turn on bad movies on weekends just to pass time and have a laugh, or to get some sleep. I found this on demand and thought it would be pretty bad considering it was Wayans Bros. They've only done a few movies worth watching. But I liked the title and I liked the idea, and it made me laugh for the right reasons. A solid 7.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest movies of all time... you will never see another one like this...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nazia1987
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't be a Menace is one of the funniest films of all times. It takes a serious genre of film and picks apart every detail of it. This film shows no mercy. It is only out for entertainment. The most pivotal, gritty, and shocking scenes from hood movies, the ones that defined the genre and changed the way Americans thought about cinema and society, are spoofed mercilessly from the preachy Ice-Cube monologue at the end of Boyz in the Hood to the Asian convenience store in the beginning of Menace II Society... This movie has gotten shockingly bad reviews but I imagine these people have never seen hood films. Either that or they are the type that want to take everything too seriously. This is not a movie to think about and analyze or drag politics into... it is a film to enjoy From the opening comment spoofing the Boyz intro ("one out of every ten black males will be forced to sit through at least one growing up in the hood movie in their lifetimes") to the ending scene, you will be in pain from the laughter this film will ensue if you have grown up watching hood films. This movie is one giant stereotype which people might pick at, but that is ultimately the point. While films like Menace II Society and Boyz have become classics of the 90s, they have also played on age old stereotypes and that is the heart of this film. Pickles, anyone?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No need to know the spoofees
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rogerdowe2000
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually never seen most of the movies that they were spoofing about but still thought it was one of the funniest and I mean funniest movies of all time this movie is filled with hidden puns that should tickle your funny bone. To give this movie an overall 6.5 is a disgrace both to the wayans bro's and comedy lovers all around the world at least an 8 8.5 minimum I really don't think anyone can name me a movie that is even remotely as funny or as good as this one. If you love quirky comedy than this movie is definitely for you I recommend it and so does my brother after watching menace 2 society ( which is the movie this movie is based upon) I really did have a true understanding of it but didn't really matter cause it was funny either way
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Laughed So Hard!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BGonzo081185
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I laughed for hours after the first time I saw this movie. I can still watch it today and crack up. As long as you've seen "Boyz in the Hood" "Menace to Society" "Dead Presidents" and "Poetic Justice" you will think this movie is one of the best comedy spoofs ever. My buddies and I still quote this movie all the time. I love how they even got some of the people from those movies to do the spoofs. The funniest part belonged to Bernie Mac as the black cop. I would strongly recommend this movie to anyone just wanting to get some laughs. I give it a 10 for being a great spoof. You will especially like this if you are a fan of the scary movie series.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A parody we can all learn from.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Wafford
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard to find a good parody these days. The likes of scary movie, and other movies in the same vein are wearing kind of thin on actual humor but big on crude sexual gags. This movie however, manages to find a pleasant balance between the two. It manages to be intelligent and at the same time completely disgusting (crackhead lovin' anyone?)I guarantee you'll be in tears the whole movie, from references to other great works of Afro-drama to self parodies so great it almost becomes paradoxical (Like a mailman that just happens to have a "MESSAGE!" every time a character has something wise to say.) I give this movie one of my highest recommendations.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    timing is everything
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (winner55)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was watching an old "Honeymooners" rerun with a friend and we came to Jackie Gleason's Ralph's inevitable "To the moon, Alice!" expression of frustration with his wife, and suddenly I realized that it WAS inevitable, so why were we laughing, having heard it a dozen times before? My friend pointed out that Gleason's timing - the manner in which he held his slow-burn, the widening of his eyes, the sudden "Bang! Zoom" take off into the line - was what always made it funny. We weren't laughing at the line so much at the performance of it. "Don't Be A Menace" is the most obvious collection of predictable gags and bits I have seen in a long time, but it is by far the funniest. The Wayans are rather stuck - the genres they parody here have very rigid conventions, so much so that there is usually only one or two gags one can use to mock them - e.g., when a young gangsta warns us that many young men in the 'hood don't live to see their 21st birthday, we all know what's coming next. So the Wayans handle it in a manner that delays the punchline while emphasizing its obviousness. Thus we laugh with them, appreciating the way they pull it off, and recognizing the gangsta genre limit that's getting parodied, rather than at the bit itself. Just about the whole movie operates on this level, and for this reason has become one of my favorite comedies. The Wayans capture every moment with a dead-on rhythm that blends the gags into a kind of music. Shawn plays the steady bass while Marlon does some wild riffing. Other characters and bits drop in and out like improvisation and sound effects. Keenan Wayans drops in every now and then like the voice on a scratch dub. The tempo could have been a little swifter, but the rhythm itself is excellent. Comedy like this is very tricky, and I personally didn't think the Wayans' efforts in the "Scary Movie" films were quite as successful - but here they move it right along. It's rude, it's crude, it's in-yor-face - and it's just a delight to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way On, Right On
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nearly all movies are about other movies. Nearly all life acts are from movies; nearly all stereotypes are from acts. The Wayons merely close the loop: movies where the acts are stereotypes of stereotypes. They really know what they are doing, disguising it as social commentary. But that you get enough of in the first five minutes. Check out how many jokes are about acting, about every third one. And then check out what they did next, with "Scary Movies," which takes the circle one more loop. I admit that I'm a fan. They seem to be the only ones who can do what Zucker used to: serve up what are generally called spoofs. I think it is because they start knowing that the target isn't bits of movies, but the bits we use in inventing the stories of who we are. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The one before 'Scary' movies etc...Homie plays that!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Wolfe
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie title alone, takes two hours to say. And talk about breaking all the stereotypical rules, if they weren't breaking all the rules I don't know what they would be doing. "Don't be a menace" I'm not surprised that there wasn't a sequel to this although it was ghetto -cutting humor that ate just about every other 'Hood' movie around then. If their comedy was a shotgun then there would be comedy-spatter all over the screen. Kim Wayans and the whole happy bunch bring their 'creative juices' to this hoodster-Rama, a ton of vulgarity, but a mountain of wit and eccentric brains, The Wayans make this a colorful and tasty treat for every fan. From the entry at Tray's room to the seven kids looking for their daddy and finding a step dad with a small car, this was a rap-hop malt-liquor adventure that really packs a staggering punch! See this if you liked "In Living Color" or if you just want to get comfortably into ghetto styled laugher-riotousness. (****). Thx --Imdb.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surreal? no...this is real life!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tulhamano
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great movie, I saw it when i was around 14 it played on Portuguese TV, I didn't knew its name but i kept searching all this years, finally i got it and watched it again, same fun. People told me get "friday" get "half baked" and was never it...this is it!! You don't need to watch any other "hood" movie to understand or like this movie, you probably just need to know a little bit about the hood or about the street life or what you may like to call it. Im not American, Im not black, and I liked the movie and understood the humor on it completely, also helped that I listen to some American rap and I can more fully understand some references related to racial issues. About the movie itself it has no plot so its impossible for anyone to come here and write a spoiler. It's a succession of events, and the plot is just an excuse to keep it going. I find it a very smart, lively and audacious caricature/satire of hood life, all the stereotypes exaggerated and pointed out in a very straight fashion, straight and real enough to hurt many "sensitive" feelings, not every scene in the movie is hilarious some are not so funny, but it is made in such a relaxed and flowing atmosphere that everything is fine is all good. Music is excellent and it has many quality details from the production creating the right atmosphere. Well I loved this movie and I wish they would make more of this kind, at the same time it is a surreal or a nonsense comedy it has very deep meaning on it and it can look so real, because reality is so much like this, day to day life is not full of drama, its more full of comedy, and full of crazy and superficial characters somehow similar to the ones on this movie. Also reference to many talented actors here that became famous, almost every face is familiar. Comparing this with "Friday" or "Scary movie" for me is more hilarious than the movie itself. Just watch it, its a whole different level. Sorry if I got carried away with the review, this one deserves a big text and a 9.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A funny theme
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lrbast
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie that hits on many truths. Its a funny movie that represents the ghetto. in the white eyes its a exaggerated truth of the hood. in the ghetto eyes its a joke of the code of the streets. The movie will bring up allot of controversy and plays fun of and spoofs of the real world. Almost every part of this movie will bring up personal or beliefs of what you see the perfect hood. Its worth seeing and paying attention to every word and scene in this movie over and over again. Even behind the main parts of the movie can be funny to you. The Waynes brothers are the most genius in this movie then every thing that they have done. I have never seen any movie that is so on and so wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Than I Expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alfonso Snell
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was genuinely pretty funny. It's a pretty good parody of hood movies, a genre that has some good flicks and some real steamers. It's accurate and clever and I laughed out loud. I recommend to anyone who just wants to laugh and people who are interested in the subject of race and it's effect on culture and media. I usually turn on bad movies on weekends just to pass time and have a laugh, or to get some sleep. I found this on demand and thought it would be pretty bad considering it was Wayans Bros. They've only done a few movies worth watching. But I liked the title and I liked the idea, and it made me laugh for the right reasons. A solid 7.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest movies of all time... you will never see another one like this...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nazia1987
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't be a Menace is one of the funniest films of all times. It takes a serious genre of film and picks apart every detail of it. This film shows no mercy. It is only out for entertainment. The most pivotal, gritty, and shocking scenes from hood movies, the ones that defined the genre and changed the way Americans thought about cinema and society, are spoofed mercilessly from the preachy Ice-Cube monologue at the end of Boyz in the Hood to the Asian convenience store in the beginning of Menace II Society... This movie has gotten shockingly bad reviews but I imagine these people have never seen hood films. Either that or they are the type that want to take everything too seriously. This is not a movie to think about and analyze or drag politics into... it is a film to enjoy From the opening comment spoofing the Boyz intro ("one out of every ten black males will be forced to sit through at least one growing up in the hood movie in their lifetimes") to the ending scene, you will be in pain from the laughter this film will ensue if you have grown up watching hood films. This movie is one giant stereotype which people might pick at, but that is ultimately the point. While films like Menace II Society and Boyz have become classics of the 90s, they have also played on age old stereotypes and that is the heart of this film. Pickles, anyone?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No need to know the spoofees
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rogerdowe2000
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually never seen most of the movies that they were spoofing about but still thought it was one of the funniest and I mean funniest movies of all time this movie is filled with hidden puns that should tickle your funny bone. To give this movie an overall 6.5 is a disgrace both to the wayans bro's and comedy lovers all around the world at least an 8 8.5 minimum I really don't think anyone can name me a movie that is even remotely as funny or as good as this one. If you love quirky comedy than this movie is definitely for you I recommend it and so does my brother after watching menace 2 society ( which is the movie this movie is based upon) I really did have a true understanding of it but didn't really matter cause it was funny either way
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Laughed So Hard!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BGonzo081185
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I laughed for hours after the first time I saw this movie. I can still watch it today and crack up. As long as you've seen "Boyz in the Hood" "Menace to Society" "Dead Presidents" and "Poetic Justice" you will think this movie is one of the best comedy spoofs ever. My buddies and I still quote this movie all the time. I love how they even got some of the people from those movies to do the spoofs. The funniest part belonged to Bernie Mac as the black cop. I would strongly recommend this movie to anyone just wanting to get some laughs. I give it a 10 for being a great spoof. You will especially like this if you are a fan of the scary movie series.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A parody we can all learn from.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Wafford
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard to find a good parody these days. The likes of scary movie, and other movies in the same vein are wearing kind of thin on actual humor but big on crude sexual gags. This movie however, manages to find a pleasant balance between the two. It manages to be intelligent and at the same time completely disgusting (crackhead lovin' anyone?)I guarantee you'll be in tears the whole movie, from references to other great works of Afro-drama to self parodies so great it almost becomes paradoxical (Like a mailman that just happens to have a "MESSAGE!" every time a character has something wise to say.) I give this movie one of my highest recommendations.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    timing is everything
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (winner55)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was watching an old "Honeymooners" rerun with a friend and we came to Jackie Gleason's Ralph's inevitable "To the moon, Alice!" expression of frustration with his wife, and suddenly I realized that it WAS inevitable, so why were we laughing, having heard it a dozen times before? My friend pointed out that Gleason's timing - the manner in which he held his slow-burn, the widening of his eyes, the sudden "Bang! Zoom" take off into the line - was what always made it funny. We weren't laughing at the line so much at the performance of it. "Don't Be A Menace" is the most obvious collection of predictable gags and bits I have seen in a long time, but it is by far the funniest. The Wayans are rather stuck - the genres they parody here have very rigid conventions, so much so that there is usually only one or two gags one can use to mock them - e.g., when a young gangsta warns us that many young men in the 'hood don't live to see their 21st birthday, we all know what's coming next. So the Wayans handle it in a manner that delays the punchline while emphasizing its obviousness. Thus we laugh with them, appreciating the way they pull it off, and recognizing the gangsta genre limit that's getting parodied, rather than at the bit itself. Just about the whole movie operates on this level, and for this reason has become one of my favorite comedies. The Wayans capture every moment with a dead-on rhythm that blends the gags into a kind of music. Shawn plays the steady bass while Marlon does some wild riffing. Other characters and bits drop in and out like improvisation and sound effects. Keenan Wayans drops in every now and then like the voice on a scratch dub. The tempo could have been a little swifter, but the rhythm itself is excellent. Comedy like this is very tricky, and I personally didn't think the Wayans' efforts in the "Scary Movie" films were quite as successful - but here they move it right along. It's rude, it's crude, it's in-yor-face - and it's just a delight to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way On, Right On
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nearly all movies are about other movies. Nearly all life acts are from movies; nearly all stereotypes are from acts. The Wayons merely close the loop: movies where the acts are stereotypes of stereotypes. They really know what they are doing, disguising it as social commentary. But that you get enough of in the first five minutes. Check out how many jokes are about acting, about every third one. And then check out what they did next, with "Scary Movies," which takes the circle one more loop. I admit that I'm a fan. They seem to be the only ones who can do what Zucker used to: serve up what are generally called spoofs. I think it is because they start knowing that the target isn't bits of movies, but the bits we use in inventing the stories of who we are. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The one before 'Scary' movies etc...Homie plays that!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Wolfe
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie title alone, takes two hours to say. And talk about breaking all the stereotypical rules, if they weren't breaking all the rules I don't know what they would be doing. "Don't be a menace" I'm not surprised that there wasn't a sequel to this although it was ghetto -cutting humor that ate just about every other 'Hood' movie around then. If their comedy was a shotgun then there would be comedy-spatter all over the screen. Kim Wayans and the whole happy bunch bring their 'creative juices' to this hoodster-Rama, a ton of vulgarity, but a mountain of wit and eccentric brains, The Wayans make this a colorful and tasty treat for every fan. From the entry at Tray's room to the seven kids looking for their daddy and finding a step dad with a small car, this was a rap-hop malt-liquor adventure that really packs a staggering punch! See this if you liked "In Living Color" or if you just want to get comfortably into ghetto styled laugher-riotousness. (****). Thx --Imdb.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surreal? no...this is real life!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tulhamano
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great movie, I saw it when i was around 14 it played on Portuguese TV, I didn't knew its name but i kept searching all this years, finally i got it and watched it again, same fun. People told me get "friday" get "half baked" and was never it...this is it!! You don't need to watch any other "hood" movie to understand or like this movie, you probably just need to know a little bit about the hood or about the street life or what you may like to call it. Im not American, Im not black, and I liked the movie and understood the humor on it completely, also helped that I listen to some American rap and I can more fully understand some references related to racial issues. About the movie itself it has no plot so its impossible for anyone to come here and write a spoiler. It's a succession of events, and the plot is just an excuse to keep it going. I find it a very smart, lively and audacious caricature/satire of hood life, all the stereotypes exaggerated and pointed out in a very straight fashion, straight and real enough to hurt many "sensitive" feelings, not every scene in the movie is hilarious some are not so funny, but it is made in such a relaxed and flowing atmosphere that everything is fine is all good. Music is excellent and it has many quality details from the production creating the right atmosphere. Well I loved this movie and I wish they would make more of this kind, at the same time it is a surreal or a nonsense comedy it has very deep meaning on it and it can look so real, because reality is so much like this, day to day life is not full of drama, its more full of comedy, and full of crazy and superficial characters somehow similar to the ones on this movie. Also reference to many talented actors here that became famous, almost every face is familiar. Comparing this with "Friday" or "Scary movie" for me is more hilarious than the movie itself. Just watch it, its a whole different level. Sorry if I got carried away with the review, this one deserves a big text and a 9.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A funny theme
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lrbast
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie that hits on many truths. Its a funny movie that represents the ghetto. in the white eyes its a exaggerated truth of the hood. in the ghetto eyes its a joke of the code of the streets. The movie will bring up allot of controversy and plays fun of and spoofs of the real world. Almost every part of this movie will bring up personal or beliefs of what you see the perfect hood. Its worth seeing and paying attention to every word and scene in this movie over and over again. Even behind the main parts of the movie can be funny to you. The Waynes brothers are the most genius in this movie then every thing that they have done. I have never seen any movie that is so on and so wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Than I Expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alfonso Snell
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was genuinely pretty funny. It's a pretty good parody of hood movies, a genre that has some good flicks and some real steamers. It's accurate and clever and I laughed out loud. I recommend to anyone who just wants to laugh and people who are interested in the subject of race and it's effect on culture and media. I usually turn on bad movies on weekends just to pass time and have a laugh, or to get some sleep. I found this on demand and thought it would be pretty bad considering it was Wayans Bros. They've only done a few movies worth watching. But I liked the title and I liked the idea, and it made me laugh for the right reasons. A solid 7.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest movies of all time... you will never see another one like this...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nazia1987
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't be a Menace is one of the funniest films of all times. It takes a serious genre of film and picks apart every detail of it. This film shows no mercy. It is only out for entertainment. The most pivotal, gritty, and shocking scenes from hood movies, the ones that defined the genre and changed the way Americans thought about cinema and society, are spoofed mercilessly from the preachy Ice-Cube monologue at the end of Boyz in the Hood to the Asian convenience store in the beginning of Menace II Society... This movie has gotten shockingly bad reviews but I imagine these people have never seen hood films. Either that or they are the type that want to take everything too seriously. This is not a movie to think about and analyze or drag politics into... it is a film to enjoy From the opening comment spoofing the Boyz intro ("one out of every ten black males will be forced to sit through at least one growing up in the hood movie in their lifetimes") to the ending scene, you will be in pain from the laughter this film will ensue if you have grown up watching hood films. This movie is one giant stereotype which people might pick at, but that is ultimately the point. While films like Menace II Society and Boyz have become classics of the 90s, they have also played on age old stereotypes and that is the heart of this film. Pickles, anyone?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No need to know the spoofees
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rogerdowe2000
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually never seen most of the movies that they were spoofing about but still thought it was one of the funniest and I mean funniest movies of all time this movie is filled with hidden puns that should tickle your funny bone. To give this movie an overall 6.5 is a disgrace both to the wayans bro's and comedy lovers all around the world at least an 8 8.5 minimum I really don't think anyone can name me a movie that is even remotely as funny or as good as this one. If you love quirky comedy than this movie is definitely for you I recommend it and so does my brother after watching menace 2 society ( which is the movie this movie is based upon) I really did have a true understanding of it but didn't really matter cause it was funny either way
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Laughed So Hard!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BGonzo081185
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I laughed for hours after the first time I saw this movie. I can still watch it today and crack up. As long as you've seen "Boyz in the Hood" "Menace to Society" "Dead Presidents" and "Poetic Justice" you will think this movie is one of the best comedy spoofs ever. My buddies and I still quote this movie all the time. I love how they even got some of the people from those movies to do the spoofs. The funniest part belonged to Bernie Mac as the black cop. I would strongly recommend this movie to anyone just wanting to get some laughs. I give it a 10 for being a great spoof. You will especially like this if you are a fan of the scary movie series.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A parody we can all learn from.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Wafford
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard to find a good parody these days. The likes of scary movie, and other movies in the same vein are wearing kind of thin on actual humor but big on crude sexual gags. This movie however, manages to find a pleasant balance between the two. It manages to be intelligent and at the same time completely disgusting (crackhead lovin' anyone?)I guarantee you'll be in tears the whole movie, from references to other great works of Afro-drama to self parodies so great it almost becomes paradoxical (Like a mailman that just happens to have a "MESSAGE!" every time a character has something wise to say.) I give this movie one of my highest recommendations.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    timing is everything
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (winner55)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was watching an old "Honeymooners" rerun with a friend and we came to Jackie Gleason's Ralph's inevitable "To the moon, Alice!" expression of frustration with his wife, and suddenly I realized that it WAS inevitable, so why were we laughing, having heard it a dozen times before? My friend pointed out that Gleason's timing - the manner in which he held his slow-burn, the widening of his eyes, the sudden "Bang! Zoom" take off into the line - was what always made it funny. We weren't laughing at the line so much at the performance of it. "Don't Be A Menace" is the most obvious collection of predictable gags and bits I have seen in a long time, but it is by far the funniest. The Wayans are rather stuck - the genres they parody here have very rigid conventions, so much so that there is usually only one or two gags one can use to mock them - e.g., when a young gangsta warns us that many young men in the 'hood don't live to see their 21st birthday, we all know what's coming next. So the Wayans handle it in a manner that delays the punchline while emphasizing its obviousness. Thus we laugh with them, appreciating the way they pull it off, and recognizing the gangsta genre limit that's getting parodied, rather than at the bit itself. Just about the whole movie operates on this level, and for this reason has become one of my favorite comedies. The Wayans capture every moment with a dead-on rhythm that blends the gags into a kind of music. Shawn plays the steady bass while Marlon does some wild riffing. Other characters and bits drop in and out like improvisation and sound effects. Keenan Wayans drops in every now and then like the voice on a scratch dub. The tempo could have been a little swifter, but the rhythm itself is excellent. Comedy like this is very tricky, and I personally didn't think the Wayans' efforts in the "Scary Movie" films were quite as successful - but here they move it right along. It's rude, it's crude, it's in-yor-face - and it's just a delight to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way On, Right On
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nearly all movies are about other movies. Nearly all life acts are from movies; nearly all stereotypes are from acts. The Wayons merely close the loop: movies where the acts are stereotypes of stereotypes. They really know what they are doing, disguising it as social commentary. But that you get enough of in the first five minutes. Check out how many jokes are about acting, about every third one. And then check out what they did next, with "Scary Movies," which takes the circle one more loop. I admit that I'm a fan. They seem to be the only ones who can do what Zucker used to: serve up what are generally called spoofs. I think it is because they start knowing that the target isn't bits of movies, but the bits we use in inventing the stories of who we are. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The one before 'Scary' movies etc...Homie plays that!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Wolfe
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie title alone, takes two hours to say. And talk about breaking all the stereotypical rules, if they weren't breaking all the rules I don't know what they would be doing. "Don't be a menace" I'm not surprised that there wasn't a sequel to this although it was ghetto -cutting humor that ate just about every other 'Hood' movie around then. If their comedy was a shotgun then there would be comedy-spatter all over the screen. Kim Wayans and the whole happy bunch bring their 'creative juices' to this hoodster-Rama, a ton of vulgarity, but a mountain of wit and eccentric brains, The Wayans make this a colorful and tasty treat for every fan. From the entry at Tray's room to the seven kids looking for their daddy and finding a step dad with a small car, this was a rap-hop malt-liquor adventure that really packs a staggering punch! See this if you liked "In Living Color" or if you just want to get comfortably into ghetto styled laugher-riotousness. (****). Thx --Imdb.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surreal? no...this is real life!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tulhamano
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great movie, I saw it when i was around 14 it played on Portuguese TV, I didn't knew its name but i kept searching all this years, finally i got it and watched it again, same fun. People told me get "friday" get "half baked" and was never it...this is it!! You don't need to watch any other "hood" movie to understand or like this movie, you probably just need to know a little bit about the hood or about the street life or what you may like to call it. Im not American, Im not black, and I liked the movie and understood the humor on it completely, also helped that I listen to some American rap and I can more fully understand some references related to racial issues. About the movie itself it has no plot so its impossible for anyone to come here and write a spoiler. It's a succession of events, and the plot is just an excuse to keep it going. I find it a very smart, lively and audacious caricature/satire of hood life, all the stereotypes exaggerated and pointed out in a very straight fashion, straight and real enough to hurt many "sensitive" feelings, not every scene in the movie is hilarious some are not so funny, but it is made in such a relaxed and flowing atmosphere that everything is fine is all good. Music is excellent and it has many quality details from the production creating the right atmosphere. Well I loved this movie and I wish they would make more of this kind, at the same time it is a surreal or a nonsense comedy it has very deep meaning on it and it can look so real, because reality is so much like this, day to day life is not full of drama, its more full of comedy, and full of crazy and superficial characters somehow similar to the ones on this movie. Also reference to many talented actors here that became famous, almost every face is familiar. Comparing this with "Friday" or "Scary movie" for me is more hilarious than the movie itself. Just watch it, its a whole different level. Sorry if I got carried away with the review, this one deserves a big text and a 9.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A funny theme
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lrbast
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie that hits on many truths. Its a funny movie that represents the ghetto. in the white eyes its a exaggerated truth of the hood. in the ghetto eyes its a joke of the code of the streets. The movie will bring up allot of controversy and plays fun of and spoofs of the real world. Almost every part of this movie will bring up personal or beliefs of what you see the perfect hood. Its worth seeing and paying attention to every word and scene in this movie over and over again. Even behind the main parts of the movie can be funny to you. The Waynes brothers are the most genius in this movie then every thing that they have done. I have never seen any movie that is so on and so wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Than I Expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alfonso Snell
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was genuinely pretty funny. It's a pretty good parody of hood movies, a genre that has some good flicks and some real steamers. It's accurate and clever and I laughed out loud. I recommend to anyone who just wants to laugh and people who are interested in the subject of race and it's effect on culture and media. I usually turn on bad movies on weekends just to pass time and have a laugh, or to get some sleep. I found this on demand and thought it would be pretty bad considering it was Wayans Bros. They've only done a few movies worth watching. But I liked the title and I liked the idea, and it made me laugh for the right reasons. A solid 7.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest movies of all time... you will never see another one like this...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nazia1987
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't be a Menace is one of the funniest films of all times. It takes a serious genre of film and picks apart every detail of it. This film shows no mercy. It is only out for entertainment. The most pivotal, gritty, and shocking scenes from hood movies, the ones that defined the genre and changed the way Americans thought about cinema and society, are spoofed mercilessly from the preachy Ice-Cube monologue at the end of Boyz in the Hood to the Asian convenience store in the beginning of Menace II Society... This movie has gotten shockingly bad reviews but I imagine these people have never seen hood films. Either that or they are the type that want to take everything too seriously. This is not a movie to think about and analyze or drag politics into... it is a film to enjoy From the opening comment spoofing the Boyz intro ("one out of every ten black males will be forced to sit through at least one growing up in the hood movie in their lifetimes") to the ending scene, you will be in pain from the laughter this film will ensue if you have grown up watching hood films. This movie is one giant stereotype which people might pick at, but that is ultimately the point. While films like Menace II Society and Boyz have become classics of the 90s, they have also played on age old stereotypes and that is the heart of this film. Pickles, anyone?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No need to know the spoofees
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rogerdowe2000
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually never seen most of the movies that they were spoofing about but still thought it was one of the funniest and I mean funniest movies of all time this movie is filled with hidden puns that should tickle your funny bone. To give this movie an overall 6.5 is a disgrace both to the wayans bro's and comedy lovers all around the world at least an 8 8.5 minimum I really don't think anyone can name me a movie that is even remotely as funny or as good as this one. If you love quirky comedy than this movie is definitely for you I recommend it and so does my brother after watching menace 2 society ( which is the movie this movie is based upon) I really did have a true understanding of it but didn't really matter cause it was funny either way
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Laughed So Hard!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BGonzo081185
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I laughed for hours after the first time I saw this movie. I can still watch it today and crack up. As long as you've seen "Boyz in the Hood" "Menace to Society" "Dead Presidents" and "Poetic Justice" you will think this movie is one of the best comedy spoofs ever. My buddies and I still quote this movie all the time. I love how they even got some of the people from those movies to do the spoofs. The funniest part belonged to Bernie Mac as the black cop. I would strongly recommend this movie to anyone just wanting to get some laughs. I give it a 10 for being a great spoof. You will especially like this if you are a fan of the scary movie series.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A parody we can all learn from.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Wafford
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard to find a good parody these days. The likes of scary movie, and other movies in the same vein are wearing kind of thin on actual humor but big on crude sexual gags. This movie however, manages to find a pleasant balance between the two. It manages to be intelligent and at the same time completely disgusting (crackhead lovin' anyone?)I guarantee you'll be in tears the whole movie, from references to other great works of Afro-drama to self parodies so great it almost becomes paradoxical (Like a mailman that just happens to have a "MESSAGE!" every time a character has something wise to say.) I give this movie one of my highest recommendations.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    timing is everything
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (winner55)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was watching an old "Honeymooners" rerun with a friend and we came to Jackie Gleason's Ralph's inevitable "To the moon, Alice!" expression of frustration with his wife, and suddenly I realized that it WAS inevitable, so why were we laughing, having heard it a dozen times before? My friend pointed out that Gleason's timing - the manner in which he held his slow-burn, the widening of his eyes, the sudden "Bang! Zoom" take off into the line - was what always made it funny. We weren't laughing at the line so much at the performance of it. "Don't Be A Menace" is the most obvious collection of predictable gags and bits I have seen in a long time, but it is by far the funniest. The Wayans are rather stuck - the genres they parody here have very rigid conventions, so much so that there is usually only one or two gags one can use to mock them - e.g., when a young gangsta warns us that many young men in the 'hood don't live to see their 21st birthday, we all know what's coming next. So the Wayans handle it in a manner that delays the punchline while emphasizing its obviousness. Thus we laugh with them, appreciating the way they pull it off, and recognizing the gangsta genre limit that's getting parodied, rather than at the bit itself. Just about the whole movie operates on this level, and for this reason has become one of my favorite comedies. The Wayans capture every moment with a dead-on rhythm that blends the gags into a kind of music. Shawn plays the steady bass while Marlon does some wild riffing. Other characters and bits drop in and out like improvisation and sound effects. Keenan Wayans drops in every now and then like the voice on a scratch dub. The tempo could have been a little swifter, but the rhythm itself is excellent. Comedy like this is very tricky, and I personally didn't think the Wayans' efforts in the "Scary Movie" films were quite as successful - but here they move it right along. It's rude, it's crude, it's in-yor-face - and it's just a delight to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way On, Right On
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nearly all movies are about other movies. Nearly all life acts are from movies; nearly all stereotypes are from acts. The Wayons merely close the loop: movies where the acts are stereotypes of stereotypes. They really know what they are doing, disguising it as social commentary. But that you get enough of in the first five minutes. Check out how many jokes are about acting, about every third one. And then check out what they did next, with "Scary Movies," which takes the circle one more loop. I admit that I'm a fan. They seem to be the only ones who can do what Zucker used to: serve up what are generally called spoofs. I think it is because they start knowing that the target isn't bits of movies, but the bits we use in inventing the stories of who we are. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The one before 'Scary' movies etc...Homie plays that!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Wolfe
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie title alone, takes two hours to say. And talk about breaking all the stereotypical rules, if they weren't breaking all the rules I don't know what they would be doing. "Don't be a menace" I'm not surprised that there wasn't a sequel to this although it was ghetto -cutting humor that ate just about every other 'Hood' movie around then. If their comedy was a shotgun then there would be comedy-spatter all over the screen. Kim Wayans and the whole happy bunch bring their 'creative juices' to this hoodster-Rama, a ton of vulgarity, but a mountain of wit and eccentric brains, The Wayans make this a colorful and tasty treat for every fan. From the entry at Tray's room to the seven kids looking for their daddy and finding a step dad with a small car, this was a rap-hop malt-liquor adventure that really packs a staggering punch! See this if you liked "In Living Color" or if you just want to get comfortably into ghetto styled laugher-riotousness. (****). Thx --Imdb.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surreal? no...this is real life!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tulhamano
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great movie, I saw it when i was around 14 it played on Portuguese TV, I didn't knew its name but i kept searching all this years, finally i got it and watched it again, same fun. People told me get "friday" get "half baked" and was never it...this is it!! You don't need to watch any other "hood" movie to understand or like this movie, you probably just need to know a little bit about the hood or about the street life or what you may like to call it. Im not American, Im not black, and I liked the movie and understood the humor on it completely, also helped that I listen to some American rap and I can more fully understand some references related to racial issues. About the movie itself it has no plot so its impossible for anyone to come here and write a spoiler. It's a succession of events, and the plot is just an excuse to keep it going. I find it a very smart, lively and audacious caricature/satire of hood life, all the stereotypes exaggerated and pointed out in a very straight fashion, straight and real enough to hurt many "sensitive" feelings, not every scene in the movie is hilarious some are not so funny, but it is made in such a relaxed and flowing atmosphere that everything is fine is all good. Music is excellent and it has many quality details from the production creating the right atmosphere. Well I loved this movie and I wish they would make more of this kind, at the same time it is a surreal or a nonsense comedy it has very deep meaning on it and it can look so real, because reality is so much like this, day to day life is not full of drama, its more full of comedy, and full of crazy and superficial characters somehow similar to the ones on this movie. Also reference to many talented actors here that became famous, almost every face is familiar. Comparing this with "Friday" or "Scary movie" for me is more hilarious than the movie itself. Just watch it, its a whole different level. Sorry if I got carried away with the review, this one deserves a big text and a 9.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A funny theme
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lrbast
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie that hits on many truths. Its a funny movie that represents the ghetto. in the white eyes its a exaggerated truth of the hood. in the ghetto eyes its a joke of the code of the streets. The movie will bring up allot of controversy and plays fun of and spoofs of the real world. Almost every part of this movie will bring up personal or beliefs of what you see the perfect hood. Its worth seeing and paying attention to every word and scene in this movie over and over again. Even behind the main parts of the movie can be funny to you. The Waynes brothers are the most genius in this movie then every thing that they have done. I have never seen any movie that is so on and so wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Than I Expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alfonso Snell
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was genuinely pretty funny. It's a pretty good parody of hood movies, a genre that has some good flicks and some real steamers. It's accurate and clever and I laughed out loud. I recommend to anyone who just wants to laugh and people who are interested in the subject of race and it's effect on culture and media. I usually turn on bad movies on weekends just to pass time and have a laugh, or to get some sleep. I found this on demand and thought it would be pretty bad considering it was Wayans Bros. They've only done a few movies worth watching. But I liked the title and I liked the idea, and it made me laugh for the right reasons. A solid 7.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest movies of all time... you will never see another one like this...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nazia1987
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't be a Menace is one of the funniest films of all times. It takes a serious genre of film and picks apart every detail of it. This film shows no mercy. It is only out for entertainment. The most pivotal, gritty, and shocking scenes from hood movies, the ones that defined the genre and changed the way Americans thought about cinema and society, are spoofed mercilessly from the preachy Ice-Cube monologue at the end of Boyz in the Hood to the Asian convenience store in the beginning of Menace II Society... This movie has gotten shockingly bad reviews but I imagine these people have never seen hood films. Either that or they are the type that want to take everything too seriously. This is not a movie to think about and analyze or drag politics into... it is a film to enjoy From the opening comment spoofing the Boyz intro ("one out of every ten black males will be forced to sit through at least one growing up in the hood movie in their lifetimes") to the ending scene, you will be in pain from the laughter this film will ensue if you have grown up watching hood films. This movie is one giant stereotype which people might pick at, but that is ultimately the point. While films like Menace II Society and Boyz have become classics of the 90s, they have also played on age old stereotypes and that is the heart of this film. Pickles, anyone?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No need to know the spoofees
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rogerdowe2000
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually never seen most of the movies that they were spoofing about but still thought it was one of the funniest and I mean funniest movies of all time this movie is filled with hidden puns that should tickle your funny bone. To give this movie an overall 6.5 is a disgrace both to the wayans bro's and comedy lovers all around the world at least an 8 8.5 minimum I really don't think anyone can name me a movie that is even remotely as funny or as good as this one. If you love quirky comedy than this movie is definitely for you I recommend it and so does my brother after watching menace 2 society ( which is the movie this movie is based upon) I really did have a true understanding of it but didn't really matter cause it was funny either way
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Laughed So Hard!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BGonzo081185
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I laughed for hours after the first time I saw this movie. I can still watch it today and crack up. As long as you've seen "Boyz in the Hood" "Menace to Society" "Dead Presidents" and "Poetic Justice" you will think this movie is one of the best comedy spoofs ever. My buddies and I still quote this movie all the time. I love how they even got some of the people from those movies to do the spoofs. The funniest part belonged to Bernie Mac as the black cop. I would strongly recommend this movie to anyone just wanting to get some laughs. I give it a 10 for being a great spoof. You will especially like this if you are a fan of the scary movie series.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A parody we can all learn from.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Wafford
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard to find a good parody these days. The likes of scary movie, and other movies in the same vein are wearing kind of thin on actual humor but big on crude sexual gags. This movie however, manages to find a pleasant balance between the two. It manages to be intelligent and at the same time completely disgusting (crackhead lovin' anyone?)I guarantee you'll be in tears the whole movie, from references to other great works of Afro-drama to self parodies so great it almost becomes paradoxical (Like a mailman that just happens to have a "MESSAGE!" every time a character has something wise to say.) I give this movie one of my highest recommendations.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    timing is everything
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (winner55)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was watching an old "Honeymooners" rerun with a friend and we came to Jackie Gleason's Ralph's inevitable "To the moon, Alice!" expression of frustration with his wife, and suddenly I realized that it WAS inevitable, so why were we laughing, having heard it a dozen times before? My friend pointed out that Gleason's timing - the manner in which he held his slow-burn, the widening of his eyes, the sudden "Bang! Zoom" take off into the line - was what always made it funny. We weren't laughing at the line so much at the performance of it. "Don't Be A Menace" is the most obvious collection of predictable gags and bits I have seen in a long time, but it is by far the funniest. The Wayans are rather stuck - the genres they parody here have very rigid conventions, so much so that there is usually only one or two gags one can use to mock them - e.g., when a young gangsta warns us that many young men in the 'hood don't live to see their 21st birthday, we all know what's coming next. So the Wayans handle it in a manner that delays the punchline while emphasizing its obviousness. Thus we laugh with them, appreciating the way they pull it off, and recognizing the gangsta genre limit that's getting parodied, rather than at the bit itself. Just about the whole movie operates on this level, and for this reason has become one of my favorite comedies. The Wayans capture every moment with a dead-on rhythm that blends the gags into a kind of music. Shawn plays the steady bass while Marlon does some wild riffing. Other characters and bits drop in and out like improvisation and sound effects. Keenan Wayans drops in every now and then like the voice on a scratch dub. The tempo could have been a little swifter, but the rhythm itself is excellent. Comedy like this is very tricky, and I personally didn't think the Wayans' efforts in the "Scary Movie" films were quite as successful - but here they move it right along. It's rude, it's crude, it's in-yor-face - and it's just a delight to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way On, Right On
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nearly all movies are about other movies. Nearly all life acts are from movies; nearly all stereotypes are from acts. The Wayons merely close the loop: movies where the acts are stereotypes of stereotypes. They really know what they are doing, disguising it as social commentary. But that you get enough of in the first five minutes. Check out how many jokes are about acting, about every third one. And then check out what they did next, with "Scary Movies," which takes the circle one more loop. I admit that I'm a fan. They seem to be the only ones who can do what Zucker used to: serve up what are generally called spoofs. I think it is because they start knowing that the target isn't bits of movies, but the bits we use in inventing the stories of who we are. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The one before 'Scary' movies etc...Homie plays that!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Wolfe
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie title alone, takes two hours to say. And talk about breaking all the stereotypical rules, if they weren't breaking all the rules I don't know what they would be doing. "Don't be a menace" I'm not surprised that there wasn't a sequel to this although it was ghetto -cutting humor that ate just about every other 'Hood' movie around then. If their comedy was a shotgun then there would be comedy-spatter all over the screen. Kim Wayans and the whole happy bunch bring their 'creative juices' to this hoodster-Rama, a ton of vulgarity, but a mountain of wit and eccentric brains, The Wayans make this a colorful and tasty treat for every fan. From the entry at Tray's room to the seven kids looking for their daddy and finding a step dad with a small car, this was a rap-hop malt-liquor adventure that really packs a staggering punch! See this if you liked "In Living Color" or if you just want to get comfortably into ghetto styled laugher-riotousness. (****). Thx --Imdb.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surreal? no...this is real life!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tulhamano
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great movie, I saw it when i was around 14 it played on Portuguese TV, I didn't knew its name but i kept searching all this years, finally i got it and watched it again, same fun. People told me get "friday" get "half baked" and was never it...this is it!! You don't need to watch any other "hood" movie to understand or like this movie, you probably just need to know a little bit about the hood or about the street life or what you may like to call it. Im not American, Im not black, and I liked the movie and understood the humor on it completely, also helped that I listen to some American rap and I can more fully understand some references related to racial issues. About the movie itself it has no plot so its impossible for anyone to come here and write a spoiler. It's a succession of events, and the plot is just an excuse to keep it going. I find it a very smart, lively and audacious caricature/satire of hood life, all the stereotypes exaggerated and pointed out in a very straight fashion, straight and real enough to hurt many "sensitive" feelings, not every scene in the movie is hilarious some are not so funny, but it is made in such a relaxed and flowing atmosphere that everything is fine is all good. Music is excellent and it has many quality details from the production creating the right atmosphere. Well I loved this movie and I wish they would make more of this kind, at the same time it is a surreal or a nonsense comedy it has very deep meaning on it and it can look so real, because reality is so much like this, day to day life is not full of drama, its more full of comedy, and full of crazy and superficial characters somehow similar to the ones on this movie. Also reference to many talented actors here that became famous, almost every face is familiar. Comparing this with "Friday" or "Scary movie" for me is more hilarious than the movie itself. Just watch it, its a whole different level. Sorry if I got carried away with the review, this one deserves a big text and a 9.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A funny theme
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lrbast
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie that hits on many truths. Its a funny movie that represents the ghetto. in the white eyes its a exaggerated truth of the hood. in the ghetto eyes its a joke of the code of the streets. The movie will bring up allot of controversy and plays fun of and spoofs of the real world. Almost every part of this movie will bring up personal or beliefs of what you see the perfect hood. Its worth seeing and paying attention to every word and scene in this movie over and over again. Even behind the main parts of the movie can be funny to you. The Waynes brothers are the most genius in this movie then every thing that they have done. I have never seen any movie that is so on and so wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Than I Expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alfonso Snell
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was genuinely pretty funny. It's a pretty good parody of hood movies, a genre that has some good flicks and some real steamers. It's accurate and clever and I laughed out loud. I recommend to anyone who just wants to laugh and people who are interested in the subject of race and it's effect on culture and media. I usually turn on bad movies on weekends just to pass time and have a laugh, or to get some sleep. I found this on demand and thought it would be pretty bad considering it was Wayans Bros. They've only done a few movies worth watching. But I liked the title and I liked the idea, and it made me laugh for the right reasons. A solid 7.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest movies of all time... you will never see another one like this...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nazia1987
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't be a Menace is one of the funniest films of all times. It takes a serious genre of film and picks apart every detail of it. This film shows no mercy. It is only out for entertainment. The most pivotal, gritty, and shocking scenes from hood movies, the ones that defined the genre and changed the way Americans thought about cinema and society, are spoofed mercilessly from the preachy Ice-Cube monologue at the end of Boyz in the Hood to the Asian convenience store in the beginning of Menace II Society... This movie has gotten shockingly bad reviews but I imagine these people have never seen hood films. Either that or they are the type that want to take everything too seriously. This is not a movie to think about and analyze or drag politics into... it is a film to enjoy From the opening comment spoofing the Boyz intro ("one out of every ten black males will be forced to sit through at least one growing up in the hood movie in their lifetimes") to the ending scene, you will be in pain from the laughter this film will ensue if you have grown up watching hood films. This movie is one giant stereotype which people might pick at, but that is ultimately the point. While films like Menace II Society and Boyz have become classics of the 90s, they have also played on age old stereotypes and that is the heart of this film. Pickles, anyone?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No need to know the spoofees
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rogerdowe2000
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually never seen most of the movies that they were spoofing about but still thought it was one of the funniest and I mean funniest movies of all time this movie is filled with hidden puns that should tickle your funny bone. To give this movie an overall 6.5 is a disgrace both to the wayans bro's and comedy lovers all around the world at least an 8 8.5 minimum I really don't think anyone can name me a movie that is even remotely as funny or as good as this one. If you love quirky comedy than this movie is definitely for you I recommend it and so does my brother after watching menace 2 society ( which is the movie this movie is based upon) I really did have a true understanding of it but didn't really matter cause it was funny either way
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Laughed So Hard!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BGonzo081185
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I laughed for hours after the first time I saw this movie. I can still watch it today and crack up. As long as you've seen "Boyz in the Hood" "Menace to Society" "Dead Presidents" and "Poetic Justice" you will think this movie is one of the best comedy spoofs ever. My buddies and I still quote this movie all the time. I love how they even got some of the people from those movies to do the spoofs. The funniest part belonged to Bernie Mac as the black cop. I would strongly recommend this movie to anyone just wanting to get some laughs. I give it a 10 for being a great spoof. You will especially like this if you are a fan of the scary movie series.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A parody we can all learn from.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Wafford
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard to find a good parody these days. The likes of scary movie, and other movies in the same vein are wearing kind of thin on actual humor but big on crude sexual gags. This movie however, manages to find a pleasant balance between the two. It manages to be intelligent and at the same time completely disgusting (crackhead lovin' anyone?)I guarantee you'll be in tears the whole movie, from references to other great works of Afro-drama to self parodies so great it almost becomes paradoxical (Like a mailman that just happens to have a "MESSAGE!" every time a character has something wise to say.) I give this movie one of my highest recommendations.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    timing is everything
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (winner55)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was watching an old "Honeymooners" rerun with a friend and we came to Jackie Gleason's Ralph's inevitable "To the moon, Alice!" expression of frustration with his wife, and suddenly I realized that it WAS inevitable, so why were we laughing, having heard it a dozen times before? My friend pointed out that Gleason's timing - the manner in which he held his slow-burn, the widening of his eyes, the sudden "Bang! Zoom" take off into the line - was what always made it funny. We weren't laughing at the line so much at the performance of it. "Don't Be A Menace" is the most obvious collection of predictable gags and bits I have seen in a long time, but it is by far the funniest. The Wayans are rather stuck - the genres they parody here have very rigid conventions, so much so that there is usually only one or two gags one can use to mock them - e.g., when a young gangsta warns us that many young men in the 'hood don't live to see their 21st birthday, we all know what's coming next. So the Wayans handle it in a manner that delays the punchline while emphasizing its obviousness. Thus we laugh with them, appreciating the way they pull it off, and recognizing the gangsta genre limit that's getting parodied, rather than at the bit itself. Just about the whole movie operates on this level, and for this reason has become one of my favorite comedies. The Wayans capture every moment with a dead-on rhythm that blends the gags into a kind of music. Shawn plays the steady bass while Marlon does some wild riffing. Other characters and bits drop in and out like improvisation and sound effects. Keenan Wayans drops in every now and then like the voice on a scratch dub. The tempo could have been a little swifter, but the rhythm itself is excellent. Comedy like this is very tricky, and I personally didn't think the Wayans' efforts in the "Scary Movie" films were quite as successful - but here they move it right along. It's rude, it's crude, it's in-yor-face - and it's just a delight to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way On, Right On
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nearly all movies are about other movies. Nearly all life acts are from movies; nearly all stereotypes are from acts. The Wayons merely close the loop: movies where the acts are stereotypes of stereotypes. They really know what they are doing, disguising it as social commentary. But that you get enough of in the first five minutes. Check out how many jokes are about acting, about every third one. And then check out what they did next, with "Scary Movies," which takes the circle one more loop. I admit that I'm a fan. They seem to be the only ones who can do what Zucker used to: serve up what are generally called spoofs. I think it is because they start knowing that the target isn't bits of movies, but the bits we use in inventing the stories of who we are. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The one before 'Scary' movies etc...Homie plays that!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Wolfe
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie title alone, takes two hours to say. And talk about breaking all the stereotypical rules, if they weren't breaking all the rules I don't know what they would be doing. "Don't be a menace" I'm not surprised that there wasn't a sequel to this although it was ghetto -cutting humor that ate just about every other 'Hood' movie around then. If their comedy was a shotgun then there would be comedy-spatter all over the screen. Kim Wayans and the whole happy bunch bring their 'creative juices' to this hoodster-Rama, a ton of vulgarity, but a mountain of wit and eccentric brains, The Wayans make this a colorful and tasty treat for every fan. From the entry at Tray's room to the seven kids looking for their daddy and finding a step dad with a small car, this was a rap-hop malt-liquor adventure that really packs a staggering punch! See this if you liked "In Living Color" or if you just want to get comfortably into ghetto styled laugher-riotousness. (****). Thx --Imdb.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surreal? no...this is real life!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tulhamano
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great movie, I saw it when i was around 14 it played on Portuguese TV, I didn't knew its name but i kept searching all this years, finally i got it and watched it again, same fun. People told me get "friday" get "half baked" and was never it...this is it!! You don't need to watch any other "hood" movie to understand or like this movie, you probably just need to know a little bit about the hood or about the street life or what you may like to call it. Im not American, Im not black, and I liked the movie and understood the humor on it completely, also helped that I listen to some American rap and I can more fully understand some references related to racial issues. About the movie itself it has no plot so its impossible for anyone to come here and write a spoiler. It's a succession of events, and the plot is just an excuse to keep it going. I find it a very smart, lively and audacious caricature/satire of hood life, all the stereotypes exaggerated and pointed out in a very straight fashion, straight and real enough to hurt many "sensitive" feelings, not every scene in the movie is hilarious some are not so funny, but it is made in such a relaxed and flowing atmosphere that everything is fine is all good. Music is excellent and it has many quality details from the production creating the right atmosphere. Well I loved this movie and I wish they would make more of this kind, at the same time it is a surreal or a nonsense comedy it has very deep meaning on it and it can look so real, because reality is so much like this, day to day life is not full of drama, its more full of comedy, and full of crazy and superficial characters somehow similar to the ones on this movie. Also reference to many talented actors here that became famous, almost every face is familiar. Comparing this with "Friday" or "Scary movie" for me is more hilarious than the movie itself. Just watch it, its a whole different level. Sorry if I got carried away with the review, this one deserves a big text and a 9.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A funny theme
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lrbast
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie that hits on many truths. Its a funny movie that represents the ghetto. in the white eyes its a exaggerated truth of the hood. in the ghetto eyes its a joke of the code of the streets. The movie will bring up allot of controversy and plays fun of and spoofs of the real world. Almost every part of this movie will bring up personal or beliefs of what you see the perfect hood. Its worth seeing and paying attention to every word and scene in this movie over and over again. Even behind the main parts of the movie can be funny to you. The Waynes brothers are the most genius in this movie then every thing that they have done. I have never seen any movie that is so on and so wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Than I Expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alfonso Snell
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was genuinely pretty funny. It's a pretty good parody of hood movies, a genre that has some good flicks and some real steamers. It's accurate and clever and I laughed out loud. I recommend to anyone who just wants to laugh and people who are interested in the subject of race and it's effect on culture and media. I usually turn on bad movies on weekends just to pass time and have a laugh, or to get some sleep. I found this on demand and thought it would be pretty bad considering it was Wayans Bros. They've only done a few movies worth watching. But I liked the title and I liked the idea, and it made me laugh for the right reasons. A solid 7.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest movies of all time... you will never see another one like this...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nazia1987
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't be a Menace is one of the funniest films of all times. It takes a serious genre of film and picks apart every detail of it. This film shows no mercy. It is only out for entertainment. The most pivotal, gritty, and shocking scenes from hood movies, the ones that defined the genre and changed the way Americans thought about cinema and society, are spoofed mercilessly from the preachy Ice-Cube monologue at the end of Boyz in the Hood to the Asian convenience store in the beginning of Menace II Society... This movie has gotten shockingly bad reviews but I imagine these people have never seen hood films. Either that or they are the type that want to take everything too seriously. This is not a movie to think about and analyze or drag politics into... it is a film to enjoy From the opening comment spoofing the Boyz intro ("one out of every ten black males will be forced to sit through at least one growing up in the hood movie in their lifetimes") to the ending scene, you will be in pain from the laughter this film will ensue if you have grown up watching hood films. This movie is one giant stereotype which people might pick at, but that is ultimately the point. While films like Menace II Society and Boyz have become classics of the 90s, they have also played on age old stereotypes and that is the heart of this film. Pickles, anyone?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No need to know the spoofees
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rogerdowe2000
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually never seen most of the movies that they were spoofing about but still thought it was one of the funniest and I mean funniest movies of all time this movie is filled with hidden puns that should tickle your funny bone. To give this movie an overall 6.5 is a disgrace both to the wayans bro's and comedy lovers all around the world at least an 8 8.5 minimum I really don't think anyone can name me a movie that is even remotely as funny or as good as this one. If you love quirky comedy than this movie is definitely for you I recommend it and so does my brother after watching menace 2 society ( which is the movie this movie is based upon) I really did have a true understanding of it but didn't really matter cause it was funny either way
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Laughed So Hard!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BGonzo081185
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I laughed for hours after the first time I saw this movie. I can still watch it today and crack up. As long as you've seen "Boyz in the Hood" "Menace to Society" "Dead Presidents" and "Poetic Justice" you will think this movie is one of the best comedy spoofs ever. My buddies and I still quote this movie all the time. I love how they even got some of the people from those movies to do the spoofs. The funniest part belonged to Bernie Mac as the black cop. I would strongly recommend this movie to anyone just wanting to get some laughs. I give it a 10 for being a great spoof. You will especially like this if you are a fan of the scary movie series.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A parody we can all learn from.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Wafford
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard to find a good parody these days. The likes of scary movie, and other movies in the same vein are wearing kind of thin on actual humor but big on crude sexual gags. This movie however, manages to find a pleasant balance between the two. It manages to be intelligent and at the same time completely disgusting (crackhead lovin' anyone?)I guarantee you'll be in tears the whole movie, from references to other great works of Afro-drama to self parodies so great it almost becomes paradoxical (Like a mailman that just happens to have a "MESSAGE!" every time a character has something wise to say.) I give this movie one of my highest recommendations.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    timing is everything
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (winner55)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was watching an old "Honeymooners" rerun with a friend and we came to Jackie Gleason's Ralph's inevitable "To the moon, Alice!" expression of frustration with his wife, and suddenly I realized that it WAS inevitable, so why were we laughing, having heard it a dozen times before? My friend pointed out that Gleason's timing - the manner in which he held his slow-burn, the widening of his eyes, the sudden "Bang! Zoom" take off into the line - was what always made it funny. We weren't laughing at the line so much at the performance of it. "Don't Be A Menace" is the most obvious collection of predictable gags and bits I have seen in a long time, but it is by far the funniest. The Wayans are rather stuck - the genres they parody here have very rigid conventions, so much so that there is usually only one or two gags one can use to mock them - e.g., when a young gangsta warns us that many young men in the 'hood don't live to see their 21st birthday, we all know what's coming next. So the Wayans handle it in a manner that delays the punchline while emphasizing its obviousness. Thus we laugh with them, appreciating the way they pull it off, and recognizing the gangsta genre limit that's getting parodied, rather than at the bit itself. Just about the whole movie operates on this level, and for this reason has become one of my favorite comedies. The Wayans capture every moment with a dead-on rhythm that blends the gags into a kind of music. Shawn plays the steady bass while Marlon does some wild riffing. Other characters and bits drop in and out like improvisation and sound effects. Keenan Wayans drops in every now and then like the voice on a scratch dub. The tempo could have been a little swifter, but the rhythm itself is excellent. Comedy like this is very tricky, and I personally didn't think the Wayans' efforts in the "Scary Movie" films were quite as successful - but here they move it right along. It's rude, it's crude, it's in-yor-face - and it's just a delight to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way On, Right On
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nearly all movies are about other movies. Nearly all life acts are from movies; nearly all stereotypes are from acts. The Wayons merely close the loop: movies where the acts are stereotypes of stereotypes. They really know what they are doing, disguising it as social commentary. But that you get enough of in the first five minutes. Check out how many jokes are about acting, about every third one. And then check out what they did next, with "Scary Movies," which takes the circle one more loop. I admit that I'm a fan. They seem to be the only ones who can do what Zucker used to: serve up what are generally called spoofs. I think it is because they start knowing that the target isn't bits of movies, but the bits we use in inventing the stories of who we are. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The one before 'Scary' movies etc...Homie plays that!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Wolfe
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie title alone, takes two hours to say. And talk about breaking all the stereotypical rules, if they weren't breaking all the rules I don't know what they would be doing. "Don't be a menace" I'm not surprised that there wasn't a sequel to this although it was ghetto -cutting humor that ate just about every other 'Hood' movie around then. If their comedy was a shotgun then there would be comedy-spatter all over the screen. Kim Wayans and the whole happy bunch bring their 'creative juices' to this hoodster-Rama, a ton of vulgarity, but a mountain of wit and eccentric brains, The Wayans make this a colorful and tasty treat for every fan. From the entry at Tray's room to the seven kids looking for their daddy and finding a step dad with a small car, this was a rap-hop malt-liquor adventure that really packs a staggering punch! See this if you liked "In Living Color" or if you just want to get comfortably into ghetto styled laugher-riotousness. (****). Thx --Imdb.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
