<filme>
 <id>
  1063
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0113670
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Princesinha
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A young girl is relegated to servitude at a boarding school when her father goes missing and is presumed dead.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  When her father enlists to fight for the British in WWI, young Sara Crewe goes to New York to attend the same boarding school her late mother attended. She soon clashes with the severe headmistress, Miss Minchin, who attempts to stifle Sara's creativity and sense of self-worth. Sara's belief that "every girl's a princess" is tested to the limit, however, when word comes that her father was killed in action and his estate has been seized by the British government.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   girl
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   boarding school
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   school
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   british
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   presumed dead
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Frances Hodgson Burnett
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Richard LaGravenese
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Liesel Matthews
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Eleanor Bron
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Liam Cunningham
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thrwmbsbgkdoepmcjrmrdw
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a good film, but different from the book. It's been a while since I've read the book, or until today seen the movie. It's well acted for the most part. I thought the father didn't do that great of a job. But other than him well acted, we directed, well put together. I do have a question though. How is it possible to regain your memory in two seconds like the father did? That part I don't get. I liked how dark they made the head mistress staying true to the character of her. And I love that they made her a sweeper at the end. Good punishment. The sister was probably my favorite with her love affair with the milkman. Very charming and cute. I really enjoyed the movie and would recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hiddenags
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before I begin I'd like to say I have not read the original "A Little Princess" and maybe one day in the future I shall read it. However this movie generally moved me. I'm not the type that usually gets emotional over movies but this movie is exceptional. The main role of Sara Crewe is played by Liesel Matthews, a really cute young girl (in this movie anyway), although her acting skills aren't great , she really gets the message across. The music of the movie is also beautifully crafted and co-ordinates with the movie really well. I recommend you watch this movie and please keep an open mind. ***WARNING*** This movie may be a bit "girly"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A whimsical family film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Alfonso Cuaron's adaptation of A Little Princess is a film filled with magically realism, whimsy and sickly sweetness. It is a popular film for young girls and women for these reasons. In 1914 Britain has entered into the First World War. Sara Crewe (Liesel Matthews) is a British girl (even though she has an American accent), living in India. She is a kind-hearted girl with a big imagine, intelligence and a keen storyteller. When her father (Liam Cunningham) is called up to serve in the war, Sara is sent to the same boarding school her descended mother went to, the Miss Minchin's Seminary for Girls in New York. Sara quickly becomes a popular girl at the school because of her wit, storytelling and willingness to stand up wrongdoing. But when her father is declared killed in action Sara's wealth is taken away and the crude hearted headmistress (Eleanor Bron) makes Sara into a servant girl. Despite Sara's grief she sets out to keep her dignity and her charitable spirit. A Little Princess was weighted around a strong performance from a talented young actress, Matthews. She gave a heart felt performance and mixed with Cuaron's emotionally manipulating direction you felt her pain and sorrow as she suffers from grief and the enforced poverty but keeps her determination and spirit. There is a theme of the rewards of charity and kindness, that if keep those attitudes and do not the world grind you then your good deals will be acknowledged. It is story about a girl needs to keep her determination, hope, kindness and imaginable that strength of friendship. I personally love Cuaron as a director, especially for his work on Harry Potter and Children of Men. With A Little Princess he was in full manipulation mode and it very much like a Spielberg film in the emotional scenes to more comically toned involving the girls causing mischief, playing jokes to a scene where the bully of school is 'cursed' and sees the outcome of it. Unfortunately because of the The art direction and cinematography are striking and fitting for the themes of the film, that India is a bright, colourful wondrous place, to the more harsh, cold reality of the street of New York in the winter. Peter Doyle's score added to getting the audience sunk into this world, using Indian music, a traditional score, a choir and a song sung by a young girl. A Little Princess is an orphan story similar in the vain of Oliver Twist, Annie and The Matchstick Girl, a young girl forced into the big bad city. Like Annie and The Matchstick Girl Sara is forced into servitude and the emotional scenes on the streets was very much like The Matchstick Girl. Because of the boarding school setting and Sara's background it is clear why Cuaron was a sensible choice to take on Harry Potter. A big criticism is the setting. The film changes the location from London to New York to cater to American auditions (seeing that the film flopped in America that change was pointless) and the time from the Victorian era to 1914. By changing it to 1914 it made the scenario less believable, that Sara becomes slave labour when she should would be education and child labour is still being used when in most Western countries had at this point introduced some sort of compulsory education. A Little Princess truly is a family film, children of all ages will find something to enjoy in this whimsical film. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Alfonso Cuaron best film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    haterofcrap
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was such a beautiful film. It is one of the best kids movies ever made, and it is also the best movie directed by Alfonso Cuaron, a very good movie director (Despite the fact that sometimes he made bad movies such as "Y tu Mama Tambi&eacute;n") This version was a much better adaptation than the 1939 (Which is a very good film, but honestly I think this was a better adaptation of the book) This film had the heart in the right place, and captures perfectly all the emotion and beauty from the book. It has an excellent visual style, the music and the performances were quite good too. I loved this movie. I wish there were more kid's films like this. I highly recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Princess (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin Teller
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the book, but I have read outraged IMDb comments from fans of it. Some of the comments seem delusional, but there are some that sound like legitimate gripes. Certainly the ending is far too easy... not for children perhaps, but for me it felt cheap. And the pathology of the wicked headmistress is only hinted at, but never explored and as a result she just comes off like a one-dimensional evil bitch. But there's a lot of delight to be had in the movie. As with PRISONER OF AZKABAN, Cuaron demonstrates a masterful sense of style and ability to craft a tale that's enjoyable for the kids and also engaging for the grown-ups. The set design and color palette is gorgeous, and young Liesel Matthews is endearing in the lead. I also enjoyed the Indian flights of fancy and the general spirit of the thing. Despite some missteps, a charming little picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Princess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n (Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban, Children of Men), I had seen the trailer for this film many times and always been curious to try the film, especially with it being rated the full five out of five stars, so when it was available I watched enthusiastically. Basically eleven year old Sara Crewe (introducing Liesel Matthews) and her wealthy father Capt. Crewe (Liam Cunningham) leave their home in India and move to New York, and he leaves her in an all girls boarding school while he enlists in the British Army. The school is run by the severe Miss Minchin (Eleanor Bron), and soon enough the bored and mundane lives of the girls are made better by Sara who becomes popular with her stories of "The Ramayana", much to the dislike of Miss Minchin and the irritation of spoilt bully Lavinia (Taylor Fry). After throwing a lavish birthday party, in which Miss Minchin wanted to extract money from Sara's father, word reaches them that he has apparently died in action, and with his estate seized by the British government the headmistress forces the innocent little girl to become a servant, alongside black servant Becky (The Lost World: Jurassic Park's Vanessa Lee Chester). Forced to stop telling stories and have her possessions, including her father's locket, taken from her, Sara only has her spirits lifted with the girls being on her side and helping her however they can, and with her belief that "every girl is a princess". Next door to the school is the mansion of rich old Charles Randolph (Arthur Malet) who wants his son to return from the war, and an injured soldier is brought to his home, it is not his son, but Capt. Crewe, suffering temporary blindness and memory loss, but Indian immigrant Ram Dass (Errol Sitahal) insists he be taken care of. One night Miss Minchin catches the other girls with Sara telling stories, and she punishes her and Becky with no food the next night, but they awaken to find a feast and palace setting, they originally imagined it, courtesy of Ram Dass. After Miss Minchin finds this she decides the police should be involved, because of possible stealing, and using a long plank Sara makes her escape across to Randolph's mansion next door. It is there she obviously is shocked and happy to see her father alive, but he does not recognise her, and Miss Minchin cruelly says that she has no family to get her away from him, but Ram Dass helps him remember and rescue her. In the end, Capt. Crewe has his fortune restored and buys himself the boarding school as the new headmaster and to make life for the girls much better, Miss Minchin is forced to be a chimney sweep alongside a young boy she originally mistreated, and Sara and Becky are going back to India together to live happily ever after, and all the girls, including Lavinia, saying their tearful goodbyes. Also starring Rusty Schwimmer as Amelia Minchin, Heather DeLoach as Ermengarde, Vincent Schiavelli as Mr. Barrow, The Ring's Rachael Bella as Betsy, The Lost World: Jurassic Park's Camilla Belle as Jane and Kelsey Mulrooney as Lottie. Matthews is wonderful as the imaginative and sweet young girl with her good spirit pushed to the limit, and Bron is fantastically vulgar as the subtly but equally knowingly evil (like Nurse Ratched style) villain headmistress, it is charming story with plenty of delightful and sweet moments, as well as true emotion, and the special effects give us moments in a surreal magical world, and it is a film that will appeal both to the adults and the children watching, a brilliant period fantasy drama. It was nominated the Oscars for Best Art Direction-Set Decoration and Best Cinematography. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not MY Little Princess, but better than Shirley Temple
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Left-Handed_Liz
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I hesitated in seeing this film for a very long time. I wasn't aware of it when it was in theaters, and I adored the book so much, and the BBC-produced miniseries starring Amelia Shankley, that I didn't want to ruin my image of the book by seeing a Hollywoodized adaptation, even into my teens. However, I'll try anything once, and the number of fans that it seems to have made me think that it might not be so bad. And it really isn't. Compared to a lot of live- action "family entertainment," which can be obnoxious and formulaic, it's exquisite. The cinematography is lush and warmly lit (perhaps a little too warm, when it comes to depicting Sara's somewhat gloomy life in poverty), and what the studio was able to do with such a small budget is more than some people could do with ten million to spend on a movie- ironic, considering the theme of wealth, or lack thereof. I found myself really warming up to the film's focus on the relationship between Sara and her father as they struggled to carry on in the midst of two very different sets of trials, as well as the emphasis on Sara's childhood in India, such as the "Ramayana" fantasy sequences, and the sitars reverberating alongside the more classical instruments on the soundtrack. The acting was at least passable throughout, though it sometimes veered into community theater-level skill. Even Liesel Matthews gave an endearing performance as Sara- certainly less stoicism and solemnity than the original, but thankfully with none of the dimple-faced pouting of the 1937 Shirley Temple film, which I couldn't stand for more than the first 30 minutes. At least Matthews's Sara is a real storyteller, and has the presence of one, rather than arbitrarily pretending things for her own amusement. The bad news is that, while a significant improvement on the aforementioned Little Princess "adaptation," this movie is nonetheless an Americanized version of a classic British children's novel, and its roots definitely show as a stereotypically Hollywood effort. Namely, since the screenplay resets the story in America- I suppose to make it more relatable to stateside audiences- it also deems it necessary to put "spunk" into a character who is supposed to be tenacious, but reserved, even having her occasionally talk back and pull pranks. Thankfully, this never goes into Home Alone territory, but is very uncharacteristic of someone who strives to behave like a princess. Finally, there is the much-maligned happy ending pulled straight from the Temple version, which I only had a problem with because it was too over-the-top, where most of the time, the movie had the sense to pull back and have an occasional reflective moment. To make a very, very long story short: Not my favorite, has no nostalgia attached to it for me, but I can accept it, and even enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really a spoiler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironmn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just wanted to say, that i enjoyed this film a lot, but at the end i was fuming mad and shouting at the TV. i was livid that all that Sarah went through it would have been fantastic that as her father was hugging her she turned just as the miss minchin was walking away Sarah turns and shouts she has stolen my locket and then the police go inside and find it and on opening it you see the fathers picture, and then the police drag the screaming miss minchin away in front of the rest of the school. then it would be a satisfying end, i would been shouting, yes you rotten cow now you will get what you deserve. So just wanted to vent this as I've just finished watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All Girls Are Princesses!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anastasia-cessano-writes
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is wonderful! I am 13 almost 14 years old and I still watch this movie regularly! I watched it so much the DVD messed up and I had to buy a new one! I HAVE read the book, and at the time I liked the book, but then I watched this-and I was blown away! This movie is a perfect example of a kids' movie that isn't horrible garbage without being overly intense. I have to admit, this is quit different from the book, but who really CARES? Sara (Liesel Matthews) is a thoughtful, smart, sweet child, not spoiled and stupidly cheerful like Shirley Temple's version. Oh no! She IS a little princess! And her father (Liam Cunningham) is so devoted and loving! But the best acted part of this entire movie has to go to: Eleanor Bron (yes, the lady in Help, and Wimbledon!!) as Miss Minchin! She was an amazing evil woman but at the same time, you see that she has never been loved and that's why she's so HEARTLESS! I believe that woman should have won an Oscar for this! And Cuaron's directing is unbelievably great! Seriously, go see this film. If you hate it, email me at anastasia.cessano.writes@aol.com with your complaints.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an absolute piece of .....(you supply the negative words ) of a movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    melee-3
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    an absolute waste of time and money....... if one is going to see a film .... do the smart thing and get the Shirley Temple movie. My girlfriend had NEVER seen OLD movies before meeting me. She'd seen the Mummy and I introduced her to the old Boris Karloff 1932 movie. She saw the Jackie Chan piece of crap Around the World in 80 Days, so I showed her the 1956 movie. She saw the Harrison Ford Sabrina and then the Bogart, Hepburn, Holden movie. The pathetic Eddie Murphy The Nutty Professor was watched by her some time in the past, so I found the 1963 Jerry Lewis movie for her. Need I say that the old one was the one appreciated more in each case? (I could have listed more, like Belushi vs Bogart (Sahara) or War of the Worlds 2005 vs 1953...and several others like The Seven Samurai vs The Magnificent 7) The next thing to find is a Rat Pack Ocean's 11 for her :) Most remakes of a story line do NOT live up to the older one..... and this A Little Princess is probably the second worst remake I have ever seen. Jackie Chan's Around the World in 80 Days is the only remake I can think of that tops this one in terms of patheticness
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thrwmbsbgkdoepmcjrmrdw
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a good film, but different from the book. It's been a while since I've read the book, or until today seen the movie. It's well acted for the most part. I thought the father didn't do that great of a job. But other than him well acted, we directed, well put together. I do have a question though. How is it possible to regain your memory in two seconds like the father did? That part I don't get. I liked how dark they made the head mistress staying true to the character of her. And I love that they made her a sweeper at the end. Good punishment. The sister was probably my favorite with her love affair with the milkman. Very charming and cute. I really enjoyed the movie and would recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hiddenags
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before I begin I'd like to say I have not read the original "A Little Princess" and maybe one day in the future I shall read it. However this movie generally moved me. I'm not the type that usually gets emotional over movies but this movie is exceptional. The main role of Sara Crewe is played by Liesel Matthews, a really cute young girl (in this movie anyway), although her acting skills aren't great , she really gets the message across. The music of the movie is also beautifully crafted and co-ordinates with the movie really well. I recommend you watch this movie and please keep an open mind. ***WARNING*** This movie may be a bit "girly"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A whimsical family film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Alfonso Cuaron's adaptation of A Little Princess is a film filled with magically realism, whimsy and sickly sweetness. It is a popular film for young girls and women for these reasons. In 1914 Britain has entered into the First World War. Sara Crewe (Liesel Matthews) is a British girl (even though she has an American accent), living in India. She is a kind-hearted girl with a big imagine, intelligence and a keen storyteller. When her father (Liam Cunningham) is called up to serve in the war, Sara is sent to the same boarding school her descended mother went to, the Miss Minchin's Seminary for Girls in New York. Sara quickly becomes a popular girl at the school because of her wit, storytelling and willingness to stand up wrongdoing. But when her father is declared killed in action Sara's wealth is taken away and the crude hearted headmistress (Eleanor Bron) makes Sara into a servant girl. Despite Sara's grief she sets out to keep her dignity and her charitable spirit. A Little Princess was weighted around a strong performance from a talented young actress, Matthews. She gave a heart felt performance and mixed with Cuaron's emotionally manipulating direction you felt her pain and sorrow as she suffers from grief and the enforced poverty but keeps her determination and spirit. There is a theme of the rewards of charity and kindness, that if keep those attitudes and do not the world grind you then your good deals will be acknowledged. It is story about a girl needs to keep her determination, hope, kindness and imaginable that strength of friendship. I personally love Cuaron as a director, especially for his work on Harry Potter and Children of Men. With A Little Princess he was in full manipulation mode and it very much like a Spielberg film in the emotional scenes to more comically toned involving the girls causing mischief, playing jokes to a scene where the bully of school is 'cursed' and sees the outcome of it. Unfortunately because of the The art direction and cinematography are striking and fitting for the themes of the film, that India is a bright, colourful wondrous place, to the more harsh, cold reality of the street of New York in the winter. Peter Doyle's score added to getting the audience sunk into this world, using Indian music, a traditional score, a choir and a song sung by a young girl. A Little Princess is an orphan story similar in the vain of Oliver Twist, Annie and The Matchstick Girl, a young girl forced into the big bad city. Like Annie and The Matchstick Girl Sara is forced into servitude and the emotional scenes on the streets was very much like The Matchstick Girl. Because of the boarding school setting and Sara's background it is clear why Cuaron was a sensible choice to take on Harry Potter. A big criticism is the setting. The film changes the location from London to New York to cater to American auditions (seeing that the film flopped in America that change was pointless) and the time from the Victorian era to 1914. By changing it to 1914 it made the scenario less believable, that Sara becomes slave labour when she should would be education and child labour is still being used when in most Western countries had at this point introduced some sort of compulsory education. A Little Princess truly is a family film, children of all ages will find something to enjoy in this whimsical film. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Alfonso Cuaron best film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    haterofcrap
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was such a beautiful film. It is one of the best kids movies ever made, and it is also the best movie directed by Alfonso Cuaron, a very good movie director (Despite the fact that sometimes he made bad movies such as "Y tu Mama Tambi&eacute;n") This version was a much better adaptation than the 1939 (Which is a very good film, but honestly I think this was a better adaptation of the book) This film had the heart in the right place, and captures perfectly all the emotion and beauty from the book. It has an excellent visual style, the music and the performances were quite good too. I loved this movie. I wish there were more kid's films like this. I highly recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Princess (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin Teller
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the book, but I have read outraged IMDb comments from fans of it. Some of the comments seem delusional, but there are some that sound like legitimate gripes. Certainly the ending is far too easy... not for children perhaps, but for me it felt cheap. And the pathology of the wicked headmistress is only hinted at, but never explored and as a result she just comes off like a one-dimensional evil bitch. But there's a lot of delight to be had in the movie. As with PRISONER OF AZKABAN, Cuaron demonstrates a masterful sense of style and ability to craft a tale that's enjoyable for the kids and also engaging for the grown-ups. The set design and color palette is gorgeous, and young Liesel Matthews is endearing in the lead. I also enjoyed the Indian flights of fancy and the general spirit of the thing. Despite some missteps, a charming little picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Princess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n (Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban, Children of Men), I had seen the trailer for this film many times and always been curious to try the film, especially with it being rated the full five out of five stars, so when it was available I watched enthusiastically. Basically eleven year old Sara Crewe (introducing Liesel Matthews) and her wealthy father Capt. Crewe (Liam Cunningham) leave their home in India and move to New York, and he leaves her in an all girls boarding school while he enlists in the British Army. The school is run by the severe Miss Minchin (Eleanor Bron), and soon enough the bored and mundane lives of the girls are made better by Sara who becomes popular with her stories of "The Ramayana", much to the dislike of Miss Minchin and the irritation of spoilt bully Lavinia (Taylor Fry). After throwing a lavish birthday party, in which Miss Minchin wanted to extract money from Sara's father, word reaches them that he has apparently died in action, and with his estate seized by the British government the headmistress forces the innocent little girl to become a servant, alongside black servant Becky (The Lost World: Jurassic Park's Vanessa Lee Chester). Forced to stop telling stories and have her possessions, including her father's locket, taken from her, Sara only has her spirits lifted with the girls being on her side and helping her however they can, and with her belief that "every girl is a princess". Next door to the school is the mansion of rich old Charles Randolph (Arthur Malet) who wants his son to return from the war, and an injured soldier is brought to his home, it is not his son, but Capt. Crewe, suffering temporary blindness and memory loss, but Indian immigrant Ram Dass (Errol Sitahal) insists he be taken care of. One night Miss Minchin catches the other girls with Sara telling stories, and she punishes her and Becky with no food the next night, but they awaken to find a feast and palace setting, they originally imagined it, courtesy of Ram Dass. After Miss Minchin finds this she decides the police should be involved, because of possible stealing, and using a long plank Sara makes her escape across to Randolph's mansion next door. It is there she obviously is shocked and happy to see her father alive, but he does not recognise her, and Miss Minchin cruelly says that she has no family to get her away from him, but Ram Dass helps him remember and rescue her. In the end, Capt. Crewe has his fortune restored and buys himself the boarding school as the new headmaster and to make life for the girls much better, Miss Minchin is forced to be a chimney sweep alongside a young boy she originally mistreated, and Sara and Becky are going back to India together to live happily ever after, and all the girls, including Lavinia, saying their tearful goodbyes. Also starring Rusty Schwimmer as Amelia Minchin, Heather DeLoach as Ermengarde, Vincent Schiavelli as Mr. Barrow, The Ring's Rachael Bella as Betsy, The Lost World: Jurassic Park's Camilla Belle as Jane and Kelsey Mulrooney as Lottie. Matthews is wonderful as the imaginative and sweet young girl with her good spirit pushed to the limit, and Bron is fantastically vulgar as the subtly but equally knowingly evil (like Nurse Ratched style) villain headmistress, it is charming story with plenty of delightful and sweet moments, as well as true emotion, and the special effects give us moments in a surreal magical world, and it is a film that will appeal both to the adults and the children watching, a brilliant period fantasy drama. It was nominated the Oscars for Best Art Direction-Set Decoration and Best Cinematography. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not MY Little Princess, but better than Shirley Temple
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Left-Handed_Liz
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I hesitated in seeing this film for a very long time. I wasn't aware of it when it was in theaters, and I adored the book so much, and the BBC-produced miniseries starring Amelia Shankley, that I didn't want to ruin my image of the book by seeing a Hollywoodized adaptation, even into my teens. However, I'll try anything once, and the number of fans that it seems to have made me think that it might not be so bad. And it really isn't. Compared to a lot of live- action "family entertainment," which can be obnoxious and formulaic, it's exquisite. The cinematography is lush and warmly lit (perhaps a little too warm, when it comes to depicting Sara's somewhat gloomy life in poverty), and what the studio was able to do with such a small budget is more than some people could do with ten million to spend on a movie- ironic, considering the theme of wealth, or lack thereof. I found myself really warming up to the film's focus on the relationship between Sara and her father as they struggled to carry on in the midst of two very different sets of trials, as well as the emphasis on Sara's childhood in India, such as the "Ramayana" fantasy sequences, and the sitars reverberating alongside the more classical instruments on the soundtrack. The acting was at least passable throughout, though it sometimes veered into community theater-level skill. Even Liesel Matthews gave an endearing performance as Sara- certainly less stoicism and solemnity than the original, but thankfully with none of the dimple-faced pouting of the 1937 Shirley Temple film, which I couldn't stand for more than the first 30 minutes. At least Matthews's Sara is a real storyteller, and has the presence of one, rather than arbitrarily pretending things for her own amusement. The bad news is that, while a significant improvement on the aforementioned Little Princess "adaptation," this movie is nonetheless an Americanized version of a classic British children's novel, and its roots definitely show as a stereotypically Hollywood effort. Namely, since the screenplay resets the story in America- I suppose to make it more relatable to stateside audiences- it also deems it necessary to put "spunk" into a character who is supposed to be tenacious, but reserved, even having her occasionally talk back and pull pranks. Thankfully, this never goes into Home Alone territory, but is very uncharacteristic of someone who strives to behave like a princess. Finally, there is the much-maligned happy ending pulled straight from the Temple version, which I only had a problem with because it was too over-the-top, where most of the time, the movie had the sense to pull back and have an occasional reflective moment. To make a very, very long story short: Not my favorite, has no nostalgia attached to it for me, but I can accept it, and even enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really a spoiler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironmn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just wanted to say, that i enjoyed this film a lot, but at the end i was fuming mad and shouting at the TV. i was livid that all that Sarah went through it would have been fantastic that as her father was hugging her she turned just as the miss minchin was walking away Sarah turns and shouts she has stolen my locket and then the police go inside and find it and on opening it you see the fathers picture, and then the police drag the screaming miss minchin away in front of the rest of the school. then it would be a satisfying end, i would been shouting, yes you rotten cow now you will get what you deserve. So just wanted to vent this as I've just finished watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All Girls Are Princesses!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anastasia-cessano-writes
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is wonderful! I am 13 almost 14 years old and I still watch this movie regularly! I watched it so much the DVD messed up and I had to buy a new one! I HAVE read the book, and at the time I liked the book, but then I watched this-and I was blown away! This movie is a perfect example of a kids' movie that isn't horrible garbage without being overly intense. I have to admit, this is quit different from the book, but who really CARES? Sara (Liesel Matthews) is a thoughtful, smart, sweet child, not spoiled and stupidly cheerful like Shirley Temple's version. Oh no! She IS a little princess! And her father (Liam Cunningham) is so devoted and loving! But the best acted part of this entire movie has to go to: Eleanor Bron (yes, the lady in Help, and Wimbledon!!) as Miss Minchin! She was an amazing evil woman but at the same time, you see that she has never been loved and that's why she's so HEARTLESS! I believe that woman should have won an Oscar for this! And Cuaron's directing is unbelievably great! Seriously, go see this film. If you hate it, email me at anastasia.cessano.writes@aol.com with your complaints.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an absolute piece of .....(you supply the negative words ) of a movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    melee-3
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    an absolute waste of time and money....... if one is going to see a film .... do the smart thing and get the Shirley Temple movie. My girlfriend had NEVER seen OLD movies before meeting me. She'd seen the Mummy and I introduced her to the old Boris Karloff 1932 movie. She saw the Jackie Chan piece of crap Around the World in 80 Days, so I showed her the 1956 movie. She saw the Harrison Ford Sabrina and then the Bogart, Hepburn, Holden movie. The pathetic Eddie Murphy The Nutty Professor was watched by her some time in the past, so I found the 1963 Jerry Lewis movie for her. Need I say that the old one was the one appreciated more in each case? (I could have listed more, like Belushi vs Bogart (Sahara) or War of the Worlds 2005 vs 1953...and several others like The Seven Samurai vs The Magnificent 7) The next thing to find is a Rat Pack Ocean's 11 for her :) Most remakes of a story line do NOT live up to the older one..... and this A Little Princess is probably the second worst remake I have ever seen. Jackie Chan's Around the World in 80 Days is the only remake I can think of that tops this one in terms of patheticness
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thrwmbsbgkdoepmcjrmrdw
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a good film, but different from the book. It's been a while since I've read the book, or until today seen the movie. It's well acted for the most part. I thought the father didn't do that great of a job. But other than him well acted, we directed, well put together. I do have a question though. How is it possible to regain your memory in two seconds like the father did? That part I don't get. I liked how dark they made the head mistress staying true to the character of her. And I love that they made her a sweeper at the end. Good punishment. The sister was probably my favorite with her love affair with the milkman. Very charming and cute. I really enjoyed the movie and would recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hiddenags
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before I begin I'd like to say I have not read the original "A Little Princess" and maybe one day in the future I shall read it. However this movie generally moved me. I'm not the type that usually gets emotional over movies but this movie is exceptional. The main role of Sara Crewe is played by Liesel Matthews, a really cute young girl (in this movie anyway), although her acting skills aren't great , she really gets the message across. The music of the movie is also beautifully crafted and co-ordinates with the movie really well. I recommend you watch this movie and please keep an open mind. ***WARNING*** This movie may be a bit "girly"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A whimsical family film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Alfonso Cuaron's adaptation of A Little Princess is a film filled with magically realism, whimsy and sickly sweetness. It is a popular film for young girls and women for these reasons. In 1914 Britain has entered into the First World War. Sara Crewe (Liesel Matthews) is a British girl (even though she has an American accent), living in India. She is a kind-hearted girl with a big imagine, intelligence and a keen storyteller. When her father (Liam Cunningham) is called up to serve in the war, Sara is sent to the same boarding school her descended mother went to, the Miss Minchin's Seminary for Girls in New York. Sara quickly becomes a popular girl at the school because of her wit, storytelling and willingness to stand up wrongdoing. But when her father is declared killed in action Sara's wealth is taken away and the crude hearted headmistress (Eleanor Bron) makes Sara into a servant girl. Despite Sara's grief she sets out to keep her dignity and her charitable spirit. A Little Princess was weighted around a strong performance from a talented young actress, Matthews. She gave a heart felt performance and mixed with Cuaron's emotionally manipulating direction you felt her pain and sorrow as she suffers from grief and the enforced poverty but keeps her determination and spirit. There is a theme of the rewards of charity and kindness, that if keep those attitudes and do not the world grind you then your good deals will be acknowledged. It is story about a girl needs to keep her determination, hope, kindness and imaginable that strength of friendship. I personally love Cuaron as a director, especially for his work on Harry Potter and Children of Men. With A Little Princess he was in full manipulation mode and it very much like a Spielberg film in the emotional scenes to more comically toned involving the girls causing mischief, playing jokes to a scene where the bully of school is 'cursed' and sees the outcome of it. Unfortunately because of the The art direction and cinematography are striking and fitting for the themes of the film, that India is a bright, colourful wondrous place, to the more harsh, cold reality of the street of New York in the winter. Peter Doyle's score added to getting the audience sunk into this world, using Indian music, a traditional score, a choir and a song sung by a young girl. A Little Princess is an orphan story similar in the vain of Oliver Twist, Annie and The Matchstick Girl, a young girl forced into the big bad city. Like Annie and The Matchstick Girl Sara is forced into servitude and the emotional scenes on the streets was very much like The Matchstick Girl. Because of the boarding school setting and Sara's background it is clear why Cuaron was a sensible choice to take on Harry Potter. A big criticism is the setting. The film changes the location from London to New York to cater to American auditions (seeing that the film flopped in America that change was pointless) and the time from the Victorian era to 1914. By changing it to 1914 it made the scenario less believable, that Sara becomes slave labour when she should would be education and child labour is still being used when in most Western countries had at this point introduced some sort of compulsory education. A Little Princess truly is a family film, children of all ages will find something to enjoy in this whimsical film. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Alfonso Cuaron best film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    haterofcrap
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was such a beautiful film. It is one of the best kids movies ever made, and it is also the best movie directed by Alfonso Cuaron, a very good movie director (Despite the fact that sometimes he made bad movies such as "Y tu Mama Tambi&eacute;n") This version was a much better adaptation than the 1939 (Which is a very good film, but honestly I think this was a better adaptation of the book) This film had the heart in the right place, and captures perfectly all the emotion and beauty from the book. It has an excellent visual style, the music and the performances were quite good too. I loved this movie. I wish there were more kid's films like this. I highly recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Princess (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin Teller
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the book, but I have read outraged IMDb comments from fans of it. Some of the comments seem delusional, but there are some that sound like legitimate gripes. Certainly the ending is far too easy... not for children perhaps, but for me it felt cheap. And the pathology of the wicked headmistress is only hinted at, but never explored and as a result she just comes off like a one-dimensional evil bitch. But there's a lot of delight to be had in the movie. As with PRISONER OF AZKABAN, Cuaron demonstrates a masterful sense of style and ability to craft a tale that's enjoyable for the kids and also engaging for the grown-ups. The set design and color palette is gorgeous, and young Liesel Matthews is endearing in the lead. I also enjoyed the Indian flights of fancy and the general spirit of the thing. Despite some missteps, a charming little picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Princess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n (Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban, Children of Men), I had seen the trailer for this film many times and always been curious to try the film, especially with it being rated the full five out of five stars, so when it was available I watched enthusiastically. Basically eleven year old Sara Crewe (introducing Liesel Matthews) and her wealthy father Capt. Crewe (Liam Cunningham) leave their home in India and move to New York, and he leaves her in an all girls boarding school while he enlists in the British Army. The school is run by the severe Miss Minchin (Eleanor Bron), and soon enough the bored and mundane lives of the girls are made better by Sara who becomes popular with her stories of "The Ramayana", much to the dislike of Miss Minchin and the irritation of spoilt bully Lavinia (Taylor Fry). After throwing a lavish birthday party, in which Miss Minchin wanted to extract money from Sara's father, word reaches them that he has apparently died in action, and with his estate seized by the British government the headmistress forces the innocent little girl to become a servant, alongside black servant Becky (The Lost World: Jurassic Park's Vanessa Lee Chester). Forced to stop telling stories and have her possessions, including her father's locket, taken from her, Sara only has her spirits lifted with the girls being on her side and helping her however they can, and with her belief that "every girl is a princess". Next door to the school is the mansion of rich old Charles Randolph (Arthur Malet) who wants his son to return from the war, and an injured soldier is brought to his home, it is not his son, but Capt. Crewe, suffering temporary blindness and memory loss, but Indian immigrant Ram Dass (Errol Sitahal) insists he be taken care of. One night Miss Minchin catches the other girls with Sara telling stories, and she punishes her and Becky with no food the next night, but they awaken to find a feast and palace setting, they originally imagined it, courtesy of Ram Dass. After Miss Minchin finds this she decides the police should be involved, because of possible stealing, and using a long plank Sara makes her escape across to Randolph's mansion next door. It is there she obviously is shocked and happy to see her father alive, but he does not recognise her, and Miss Minchin cruelly says that she has no family to get her away from him, but Ram Dass helps him remember and rescue her. In the end, Capt. Crewe has his fortune restored and buys himself the boarding school as the new headmaster and to make life for the girls much better, Miss Minchin is forced to be a chimney sweep alongside a young boy she originally mistreated, and Sara and Becky are going back to India together to live happily ever after, and all the girls, including Lavinia, saying their tearful goodbyes. Also starring Rusty Schwimmer as Amelia Minchin, Heather DeLoach as Ermengarde, Vincent Schiavelli as Mr. Barrow, The Ring's Rachael Bella as Betsy, The Lost World: Jurassic Park's Camilla Belle as Jane and Kelsey Mulrooney as Lottie. Matthews is wonderful as the imaginative and sweet young girl with her good spirit pushed to the limit, and Bron is fantastically vulgar as the subtly but equally knowingly evil (like Nurse Ratched style) villain headmistress, it is charming story with plenty of delightful and sweet moments, as well as true emotion, and the special effects give us moments in a surreal magical world, and it is a film that will appeal both to the adults and the children watching, a brilliant period fantasy drama. It was nominated the Oscars for Best Art Direction-Set Decoration and Best Cinematography. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not MY Little Princess, but better than Shirley Temple
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Left-Handed_Liz
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I hesitated in seeing this film for a very long time. I wasn't aware of it when it was in theaters, and I adored the book so much, and the BBC-produced miniseries starring Amelia Shankley, that I didn't want to ruin my image of the book by seeing a Hollywoodized adaptation, even into my teens. However, I'll try anything once, and the number of fans that it seems to have made me think that it might not be so bad. And it really isn't. Compared to a lot of live- action "family entertainment," which can be obnoxious and formulaic, it's exquisite. The cinematography is lush and warmly lit (perhaps a little too warm, when it comes to depicting Sara's somewhat gloomy life in poverty), and what the studio was able to do with such a small budget is more than some people could do with ten million to spend on a movie- ironic, considering the theme of wealth, or lack thereof. I found myself really warming up to the film's focus on the relationship between Sara and her father as they struggled to carry on in the midst of two very different sets of trials, as well as the emphasis on Sara's childhood in India, such as the "Ramayana" fantasy sequences, and the sitars reverberating alongside the more classical instruments on the soundtrack. The acting was at least passable throughout, though it sometimes veered into community theater-level skill. Even Liesel Matthews gave an endearing performance as Sara- certainly less stoicism and solemnity than the original, but thankfully with none of the dimple-faced pouting of the 1937 Shirley Temple film, which I couldn't stand for more than the first 30 minutes. At least Matthews's Sara is a real storyteller, and has the presence of one, rather than arbitrarily pretending things for her own amusement. The bad news is that, while a significant improvement on the aforementioned Little Princess "adaptation," this movie is nonetheless an Americanized version of a classic British children's novel, and its roots definitely show as a stereotypically Hollywood effort. Namely, since the screenplay resets the story in America- I suppose to make it more relatable to stateside audiences- it also deems it necessary to put "spunk" into a character who is supposed to be tenacious, but reserved, even having her occasionally talk back and pull pranks. Thankfully, this never goes into Home Alone territory, but is very uncharacteristic of someone who strives to behave like a princess. Finally, there is the much-maligned happy ending pulled straight from the Temple version, which I only had a problem with because it was too over-the-top, where most of the time, the movie had the sense to pull back and have an occasional reflective moment. To make a very, very long story short: Not my favorite, has no nostalgia attached to it for me, but I can accept it, and even enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really a spoiler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironmn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just wanted to say, that i enjoyed this film a lot, but at the end i was fuming mad and shouting at the TV. i was livid that all that Sarah went through it would have been fantastic that as her father was hugging her she turned just as the miss minchin was walking away Sarah turns and shouts she has stolen my locket and then the police go inside and find it and on opening it you see the fathers picture, and then the police drag the screaming miss minchin away in front of the rest of the school. then it would be a satisfying end, i would been shouting, yes you rotten cow now you will get what you deserve. So just wanted to vent this as I've just finished watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All Girls Are Princesses!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anastasia-cessano-writes
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is wonderful! I am 13 almost 14 years old and I still watch this movie regularly! I watched it so much the DVD messed up and I had to buy a new one! I HAVE read the book, and at the time I liked the book, but then I watched this-and I was blown away! This movie is a perfect example of a kids' movie that isn't horrible garbage without being overly intense. I have to admit, this is quit different from the book, but who really CARES? Sara (Liesel Matthews) is a thoughtful, smart, sweet child, not spoiled and stupidly cheerful like Shirley Temple's version. Oh no! She IS a little princess! And her father (Liam Cunningham) is so devoted and loving! But the best acted part of this entire movie has to go to: Eleanor Bron (yes, the lady in Help, and Wimbledon!!) as Miss Minchin! She was an amazing evil woman but at the same time, you see that she has never been loved and that's why she's so HEARTLESS! I believe that woman should have won an Oscar for this! And Cuaron's directing is unbelievably great! Seriously, go see this film. If you hate it, email me at anastasia.cessano.writes@aol.com with your complaints.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an absolute piece of .....(you supply the negative words ) of a movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    melee-3
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    an absolute waste of time and money....... if one is going to see a film .... do the smart thing and get the Shirley Temple movie. My girlfriend had NEVER seen OLD movies before meeting me. She'd seen the Mummy and I introduced her to the old Boris Karloff 1932 movie. She saw the Jackie Chan piece of crap Around the World in 80 Days, so I showed her the 1956 movie. She saw the Harrison Ford Sabrina and then the Bogart, Hepburn, Holden movie. The pathetic Eddie Murphy The Nutty Professor was watched by her some time in the past, so I found the 1963 Jerry Lewis movie for her. Need I say that the old one was the one appreciated more in each case? (I could have listed more, like Belushi vs Bogart (Sahara) or War of the Worlds 2005 vs 1953...and several others like The Seven Samurai vs The Magnificent 7) The next thing to find is a Rat Pack Ocean's 11 for her :) Most remakes of a story line do NOT live up to the older one..... and this A Little Princess is probably the second worst remake I have ever seen. Jackie Chan's Around the World in 80 Days is the only remake I can think of that tops this one in terms of patheticness
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thrwmbsbgkdoepmcjrmrdw
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a good film, but different from the book. It's been a while since I've read the book, or until today seen the movie. It's well acted for the most part. I thought the father didn't do that great of a job. But other than him well acted, we directed, well put together. I do have a question though. How is it possible to regain your memory in two seconds like the father did? That part I don't get. I liked how dark they made the head mistress staying true to the character of her. And I love that they made her a sweeper at the end. Good punishment. The sister was probably my favorite with her love affair with the milkman. Very charming and cute. I really enjoyed the movie and would recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hiddenags
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before I begin I'd like to say I have not read the original "A Little Princess" and maybe one day in the future I shall read it. However this movie generally moved me. I'm not the type that usually gets emotional over movies but this movie is exceptional. The main role of Sara Crewe is played by Liesel Matthews, a really cute young girl (in this movie anyway), although her acting skills aren't great , she really gets the message across. The music of the movie is also beautifully crafted and co-ordinates with the movie really well. I recommend you watch this movie and please keep an open mind. ***WARNING*** This movie may be a bit "girly"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A whimsical family film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Alfonso Cuaron's adaptation of A Little Princess is a film filled with magically realism, whimsy and sickly sweetness. It is a popular film for young girls and women for these reasons. In 1914 Britain has entered into the First World War. Sara Crewe (Liesel Matthews) is a British girl (even though she has an American accent), living in India. She is a kind-hearted girl with a big imagine, intelligence and a keen storyteller. When her father (Liam Cunningham) is called up to serve in the war, Sara is sent to the same boarding school her descended mother went to, the Miss Minchin's Seminary for Girls in New York. Sara quickly becomes a popular girl at the school because of her wit, storytelling and willingness to stand up wrongdoing. But when her father is declared killed in action Sara's wealth is taken away and the crude hearted headmistress (Eleanor Bron) makes Sara into a servant girl. Despite Sara's grief she sets out to keep her dignity and her charitable spirit. A Little Princess was weighted around a strong performance from a talented young actress, Matthews. She gave a heart felt performance and mixed with Cuaron's emotionally manipulating direction you felt her pain and sorrow as she suffers from grief and the enforced poverty but keeps her determination and spirit. There is a theme of the rewards of charity and kindness, that if keep those attitudes and do not the world grind you then your good deals will be acknowledged. It is story about a girl needs to keep her determination, hope, kindness and imaginable that strength of friendship. I personally love Cuaron as a director, especially for his work on Harry Potter and Children of Men. With A Little Princess he was in full manipulation mode and it very much like a Spielberg film in the emotional scenes to more comically toned involving the girls causing mischief, playing jokes to a scene where the bully of school is 'cursed' and sees the outcome of it. Unfortunately because of the The art direction and cinematography are striking and fitting for the themes of the film, that India is a bright, colourful wondrous place, to the more harsh, cold reality of the street of New York in the winter. Peter Doyle's score added to getting the audience sunk into this world, using Indian music, a traditional score, a choir and a song sung by a young girl. A Little Princess is an orphan story similar in the vain of Oliver Twist, Annie and The Matchstick Girl, a young girl forced into the big bad city. Like Annie and The Matchstick Girl Sara is forced into servitude and the emotional scenes on the streets was very much like The Matchstick Girl. Because of the boarding school setting and Sara's background it is clear why Cuaron was a sensible choice to take on Harry Potter. A big criticism is the setting. The film changes the location from London to New York to cater to American auditions (seeing that the film flopped in America that change was pointless) and the time from the Victorian era to 1914. By changing it to 1914 it made the scenario less believable, that Sara becomes slave labour when she should would be education and child labour is still being used when in most Western countries had at this point introduced some sort of compulsory education. A Little Princess truly is a family film, children of all ages will find something to enjoy in this whimsical film. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Alfonso Cuaron best film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    haterofcrap
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was such a beautiful film. It is one of the best kids movies ever made, and it is also the best movie directed by Alfonso Cuaron, a very good movie director (Despite the fact that sometimes he made bad movies such as "Y tu Mama Tambi&eacute;n") This version was a much better adaptation than the 1939 (Which is a very good film, but honestly I think this was a better adaptation of the book) This film had the heart in the right place, and captures perfectly all the emotion and beauty from the book. It has an excellent visual style, the music and the performances were quite good too. I loved this movie. I wish there were more kid's films like this. I highly recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Princess (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin Teller
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the book, but I have read outraged IMDb comments from fans of it. Some of the comments seem delusional, but there are some that sound like legitimate gripes. Certainly the ending is far too easy... not for children perhaps, but for me it felt cheap. And the pathology of the wicked headmistress is only hinted at, but never explored and as a result she just comes off like a one-dimensional evil bitch. But there's a lot of delight to be had in the movie. As with PRISONER OF AZKABAN, Cuaron demonstrates a masterful sense of style and ability to craft a tale that's enjoyable for the kids and also engaging for the grown-ups. The set design and color palette is gorgeous, and young Liesel Matthews is endearing in the lead. I also enjoyed the Indian flights of fancy and the general spirit of the thing. Despite some missteps, a charming little picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Princess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n (Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban, Children of Men), I had seen the trailer for this film many times and always been curious to try the film, especially with it being rated the full five out of five stars, so when it was available I watched enthusiastically. Basically eleven year old Sara Crewe (introducing Liesel Matthews) and her wealthy father Capt. Crewe (Liam Cunningham) leave their home in India and move to New York, and he leaves her in an all girls boarding school while he enlists in the British Army. The school is run by the severe Miss Minchin (Eleanor Bron), and soon enough the bored and mundane lives of the girls are made better by Sara who becomes popular with her stories of "The Ramayana", much to the dislike of Miss Minchin and the irritation of spoilt bully Lavinia (Taylor Fry). After throwing a lavish birthday party, in which Miss Minchin wanted to extract money from Sara's father, word reaches them that he has apparently died in action, and with his estate seized by the British government the headmistress forces the innocent little girl to become a servant, alongside black servant Becky (The Lost World: Jurassic Park's Vanessa Lee Chester). Forced to stop telling stories and have her possessions, including her father's locket, taken from her, Sara only has her spirits lifted with the girls being on her side and helping her however they can, and with her belief that "every girl is a princess". Next door to the school is the mansion of rich old Charles Randolph (Arthur Malet) who wants his son to return from the war, and an injured soldier is brought to his home, it is not his son, but Capt. Crewe, suffering temporary blindness and memory loss, but Indian immigrant Ram Dass (Errol Sitahal) insists he be taken care of. One night Miss Minchin catches the other girls with Sara telling stories, and she punishes her and Becky with no food the next night, but they awaken to find a feast and palace setting, they originally imagined it, courtesy of Ram Dass. After Miss Minchin finds this she decides the police should be involved, because of possible stealing, and using a long plank Sara makes her escape across to Randolph's mansion next door. It is there she obviously is shocked and happy to see her father alive, but he does not recognise her, and Miss Minchin cruelly says that she has no family to get her away from him, but Ram Dass helps him remember and rescue her. In the end, Capt. Crewe has his fortune restored and buys himself the boarding school as the new headmaster and to make life for the girls much better, Miss Minchin is forced to be a chimney sweep alongside a young boy she originally mistreated, and Sara and Becky are going back to India together to live happily ever after, and all the girls, including Lavinia, saying their tearful goodbyes. Also starring Rusty Schwimmer as Amelia Minchin, Heather DeLoach as Ermengarde, Vincent Schiavelli as Mr. Barrow, The Ring's Rachael Bella as Betsy, The Lost World: Jurassic Park's Camilla Belle as Jane and Kelsey Mulrooney as Lottie. Matthews is wonderful as the imaginative and sweet young girl with her good spirit pushed to the limit, and Bron is fantastically vulgar as the subtly but equally knowingly evil (like Nurse Ratched style) villain headmistress, it is charming story with plenty of delightful and sweet moments, as well as true emotion, and the special effects give us moments in a surreal magical world, and it is a film that will appeal both to the adults and the children watching, a brilliant period fantasy drama. It was nominated the Oscars for Best Art Direction-Set Decoration and Best Cinematography. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not MY Little Princess, but better than Shirley Temple
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Left-Handed_Liz
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I hesitated in seeing this film for a very long time. I wasn't aware of it when it was in theaters, and I adored the book so much, and the BBC-produced miniseries starring Amelia Shankley, that I didn't want to ruin my image of the book by seeing a Hollywoodized adaptation, even into my teens. However, I'll try anything once, and the number of fans that it seems to have made me think that it might not be so bad. And it really isn't. Compared to a lot of live- action "family entertainment," which can be obnoxious and formulaic, it's exquisite. The cinematography is lush and warmly lit (perhaps a little too warm, when it comes to depicting Sara's somewhat gloomy life in poverty), and what the studio was able to do with such a small budget is more than some people could do with ten million to spend on a movie- ironic, considering the theme of wealth, or lack thereof. I found myself really warming up to the film's focus on the relationship between Sara and her father as they struggled to carry on in the midst of two very different sets of trials, as well as the emphasis on Sara's childhood in India, such as the "Ramayana" fantasy sequences, and the sitars reverberating alongside the more classical instruments on the soundtrack. The acting was at least passable throughout, though it sometimes veered into community theater-level skill. Even Liesel Matthews gave an endearing performance as Sara- certainly less stoicism and solemnity than the original, but thankfully with none of the dimple-faced pouting of the 1937 Shirley Temple film, which I couldn't stand for more than the first 30 minutes. At least Matthews's Sara is a real storyteller, and has the presence of one, rather than arbitrarily pretending things for her own amusement. The bad news is that, while a significant improvement on the aforementioned Little Princess "adaptation," this movie is nonetheless an Americanized version of a classic British children's novel, and its roots definitely show as a stereotypically Hollywood effort. Namely, since the screenplay resets the story in America- I suppose to make it more relatable to stateside audiences- it also deems it necessary to put "spunk" into a character who is supposed to be tenacious, but reserved, even having her occasionally talk back and pull pranks. Thankfully, this never goes into Home Alone territory, but is very uncharacteristic of someone who strives to behave like a princess. Finally, there is the much-maligned happy ending pulled straight from the Temple version, which I only had a problem with because it was too over-the-top, where most of the time, the movie had the sense to pull back and have an occasional reflective moment. To make a very, very long story short: Not my favorite, has no nostalgia attached to it for me, but I can accept it, and even enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really a spoiler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironmn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just wanted to say, that i enjoyed this film a lot, but at the end i was fuming mad and shouting at the TV. i was livid that all that Sarah went through it would have been fantastic that as her father was hugging her she turned just as the miss minchin was walking away Sarah turns and shouts she has stolen my locket and then the police go inside and find it and on opening it you see the fathers picture, and then the police drag the screaming miss minchin away in front of the rest of the school. then it would be a satisfying end, i would been shouting, yes you rotten cow now you will get what you deserve. So just wanted to vent this as I've just finished watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All Girls Are Princesses!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anastasia-cessano-writes
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is wonderful! I am 13 almost 14 years old and I still watch this movie regularly! I watched it so much the DVD messed up and I had to buy a new one! I HAVE read the book, and at the time I liked the book, but then I watched this-and I was blown away! This movie is a perfect example of a kids' movie that isn't horrible garbage without being overly intense. I have to admit, this is quit different from the book, but who really CARES? Sara (Liesel Matthews) is a thoughtful, smart, sweet child, not spoiled and stupidly cheerful like Shirley Temple's version. Oh no! She IS a little princess! And her father (Liam Cunningham) is so devoted and loving! But the best acted part of this entire movie has to go to: Eleanor Bron (yes, the lady in Help, and Wimbledon!!) as Miss Minchin! She was an amazing evil woman but at the same time, you see that she has never been loved and that's why she's so HEARTLESS! I believe that woman should have won an Oscar for this! And Cuaron's directing is unbelievably great! Seriously, go see this film. If you hate it, email me at anastasia.cessano.writes@aol.com with your complaints.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an absolute piece of .....(you supply the negative words ) of a movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    melee-3
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    an absolute waste of time and money....... if one is going to see a film .... do the smart thing and get the Shirley Temple movie. My girlfriend had NEVER seen OLD movies before meeting me. She'd seen the Mummy and I introduced her to the old Boris Karloff 1932 movie. She saw the Jackie Chan piece of crap Around the World in 80 Days, so I showed her the 1956 movie. She saw the Harrison Ford Sabrina and then the Bogart, Hepburn, Holden movie. The pathetic Eddie Murphy The Nutty Professor was watched by her some time in the past, so I found the 1963 Jerry Lewis movie for her. Need I say that the old one was the one appreciated more in each case? (I could have listed more, like Belushi vs Bogart (Sahara) or War of the Worlds 2005 vs 1953...and several others like The Seven Samurai vs The Magnificent 7) The next thing to find is a Rat Pack Ocean's 11 for her :) Most remakes of a story line do NOT live up to the older one..... and this A Little Princess is probably the second worst remake I have ever seen. Jackie Chan's Around the World in 80 Days is the only remake I can think of that tops this one in terms of patheticness
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thrwmbsbgkdoepmcjrmrdw
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a good film, but different from the book. It's been a while since I've read the book, or until today seen the movie. It's well acted for the most part. I thought the father didn't do that great of a job. But other than him well acted, we directed, well put together. I do have a question though. How is it possible to regain your memory in two seconds like the father did? That part I don't get. I liked how dark they made the head mistress staying true to the character of her. And I love that they made her a sweeper at the end. Good punishment. The sister was probably my favorite with her love affair with the milkman. Very charming and cute. I really enjoyed the movie and would recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hiddenags
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before I begin I'd like to say I have not read the original "A Little Princess" and maybe one day in the future I shall read it. However this movie generally moved me. I'm not the type that usually gets emotional over movies but this movie is exceptional. The main role of Sara Crewe is played by Liesel Matthews, a really cute young girl (in this movie anyway), although her acting skills aren't great , she really gets the message across. The music of the movie is also beautifully crafted and co-ordinates with the movie really well. I recommend you watch this movie and please keep an open mind. ***WARNING*** This movie may be a bit "girly"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A whimsical family film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Alfonso Cuaron's adaptation of A Little Princess is a film filled with magically realism, whimsy and sickly sweetness. It is a popular film for young girls and women for these reasons. In 1914 Britain has entered into the First World War. Sara Crewe (Liesel Matthews) is a British girl (even though she has an American accent), living in India. She is a kind-hearted girl with a big imagine, intelligence and a keen storyteller. When her father (Liam Cunningham) is called up to serve in the war, Sara is sent to the same boarding school her descended mother went to, the Miss Minchin's Seminary for Girls in New York. Sara quickly becomes a popular girl at the school because of her wit, storytelling and willingness to stand up wrongdoing. But when her father is declared killed in action Sara's wealth is taken away and the crude hearted headmistress (Eleanor Bron) makes Sara into a servant girl. Despite Sara's grief she sets out to keep her dignity and her charitable spirit. A Little Princess was weighted around a strong performance from a talented young actress, Matthews. She gave a heart felt performance and mixed with Cuaron's emotionally manipulating direction you felt her pain and sorrow as she suffers from grief and the enforced poverty but keeps her determination and spirit. There is a theme of the rewards of charity and kindness, that if keep those attitudes and do not the world grind you then your good deals will be acknowledged. It is story about a girl needs to keep her determination, hope, kindness and imaginable that strength of friendship. I personally love Cuaron as a director, especially for his work on Harry Potter and Children of Men. With A Little Princess he was in full manipulation mode and it very much like a Spielberg film in the emotional scenes to more comically toned involving the girls causing mischief, playing jokes to a scene where the bully of school is 'cursed' and sees the outcome of it. Unfortunately because of the The art direction and cinematography are striking and fitting for the themes of the film, that India is a bright, colourful wondrous place, to the more harsh, cold reality of the street of New York in the winter. Peter Doyle's score added to getting the audience sunk into this world, using Indian music, a traditional score, a choir and a song sung by a young girl. A Little Princess is an orphan story similar in the vain of Oliver Twist, Annie and The Matchstick Girl, a young girl forced into the big bad city. Like Annie and The Matchstick Girl Sara is forced into servitude and the emotional scenes on the streets was very much like The Matchstick Girl. Because of the boarding school setting and Sara's background it is clear why Cuaron was a sensible choice to take on Harry Potter. A big criticism is the setting. The film changes the location from London to New York to cater to American auditions (seeing that the film flopped in America that change was pointless) and the time from the Victorian era to 1914. By changing it to 1914 it made the scenario less believable, that Sara becomes slave labour when she should would be education and child labour is still being used when in most Western countries had at this point introduced some sort of compulsory education. A Little Princess truly is a family film, children of all ages will find something to enjoy in this whimsical film. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Alfonso Cuaron best film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    haterofcrap
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was such a beautiful film. It is one of the best kids movies ever made, and it is also the best movie directed by Alfonso Cuaron, a very good movie director (Despite the fact that sometimes he made bad movies such as "Y tu Mama Tambi&eacute;n") This version was a much better adaptation than the 1939 (Which is a very good film, but honestly I think this was a better adaptation of the book) This film had the heart in the right place, and captures perfectly all the emotion and beauty from the book. It has an excellent visual style, the music and the performances were quite good too. I loved this movie. I wish there were more kid's films like this. I highly recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Princess (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin Teller
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the book, but I have read outraged IMDb comments from fans of it. Some of the comments seem delusional, but there are some that sound like legitimate gripes. Certainly the ending is far too easy... not for children perhaps, but for me it felt cheap. And the pathology of the wicked headmistress is only hinted at, but never explored and as a result she just comes off like a one-dimensional evil bitch. But there's a lot of delight to be had in the movie. As with PRISONER OF AZKABAN, Cuaron demonstrates a masterful sense of style and ability to craft a tale that's enjoyable for the kids and also engaging for the grown-ups. The set design and color palette is gorgeous, and young Liesel Matthews is endearing in the lead. I also enjoyed the Indian flights of fancy and the general spirit of the thing. Despite some missteps, a charming little picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Princess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n (Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban, Children of Men), I had seen the trailer for this film many times and always been curious to try the film, especially with it being rated the full five out of five stars, so when it was available I watched enthusiastically. Basically eleven year old Sara Crewe (introducing Liesel Matthews) and her wealthy father Capt. Crewe (Liam Cunningham) leave their home in India and move to New York, and he leaves her in an all girls boarding school while he enlists in the British Army. The school is run by the severe Miss Minchin (Eleanor Bron), and soon enough the bored and mundane lives of the girls are made better by Sara who becomes popular with her stories of "The Ramayana", much to the dislike of Miss Minchin and the irritation of spoilt bully Lavinia (Taylor Fry). After throwing a lavish birthday party, in which Miss Minchin wanted to extract money from Sara's father, word reaches them that he has apparently died in action, and with his estate seized by the British government the headmistress forces the innocent little girl to become a servant, alongside black servant Becky (The Lost World: Jurassic Park's Vanessa Lee Chester). Forced to stop telling stories and have her possessions, including her father's locket, taken from her, Sara only has her spirits lifted with the girls being on her side and helping her however they can, and with her belief that "every girl is a princess". Next door to the school is the mansion of rich old Charles Randolph (Arthur Malet) who wants his son to return from the war, and an injured soldier is brought to his home, it is not his son, but Capt. Crewe, suffering temporary blindness and memory loss, but Indian immigrant Ram Dass (Errol Sitahal) insists he be taken care of. One night Miss Minchin catches the other girls with Sara telling stories, and she punishes her and Becky with no food the next night, but they awaken to find a feast and palace setting, they originally imagined it, courtesy of Ram Dass. After Miss Minchin finds this she decides the police should be involved, because of possible stealing, and using a long plank Sara makes her escape across to Randolph's mansion next door. It is there she obviously is shocked and happy to see her father alive, but he does not recognise her, and Miss Minchin cruelly says that she has no family to get her away from him, but Ram Dass helps him remember and rescue her. In the end, Capt. Crewe has his fortune restored and buys himself the boarding school as the new headmaster and to make life for the girls much better, Miss Minchin is forced to be a chimney sweep alongside a young boy she originally mistreated, and Sara and Becky are going back to India together to live happily ever after, and all the girls, including Lavinia, saying their tearful goodbyes. Also starring Rusty Schwimmer as Amelia Minchin, Heather DeLoach as Ermengarde, Vincent Schiavelli as Mr. Barrow, The Ring's Rachael Bella as Betsy, The Lost World: Jurassic Park's Camilla Belle as Jane and Kelsey Mulrooney as Lottie. Matthews is wonderful as the imaginative and sweet young girl with her good spirit pushed to the limit, and Bron is fantastically vulgar as the subtly but equally knowingly evil (like Nurse Ratched style) villain headmistress, it is charming story with plenty of delightful and sweet moments, as well as true emotion, and the special effects give us moments in a surreal magical world, and it is a film that will appeal both to the adults and the children watching, a brilliant period fantasy drama. It was nominated the Oscars for Best Art Direction-Set Decoration and Best Cinematography. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not MY Little Princess, but better than Shirley Temple
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Left-Handed_Liz
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I hesitated in seeing this film for a very long time. I wasn't aware of it when it was in theaters, and I adored the book so much, and the BBC-produced miniseries starring Amelia Shankley, that I didn't want to ruin my image of the book by seeing a Hollywoodized adaptation, even into my teens. However, I'll try anything once, and the number of fans that it seems to have made me think that it might not be so bad. And it really isn't. Compared to a lot of live- action "family entertainment," which can be obnoxious and formulaic, it's exquisite. The cinematography is lush and warmly lit (perhaps a little too warm, when it comes to depicting Sara's somewhat gloomy life in poverty), and what the studio was able to do with such a small budget is more than some people could do with ten million to spend on a movie- ironic, considering the theme of wealth, or lack thereof. I found myself really warming up to the film's focus on the relationship between Sara and her father as they struggled to carry on in the midst of two very different sets of trials, as well as the emphasis on Sara's childhood in India, such as the "Ramayana" fantasy sequences, and the sitars reverberating alongside the more classical instruments on the soundtrack. The acting was at least passable throughout, though it sometimes veered into community theater-level skill. Even Liesel Matthews gave an endearing performance as Sara- certainly less stoicism and solemnity than the original, but thankfully with none of the dimple-faced pouting of the 1937 Shirley Temple film, which I couldn't stand for more than the first 30 minutes. At least Matthews's Sara is a real storyteller, and has the presence of one, rather than arbitrarily pretending things for her own amusement. The bad news is that, while a significant improvement on the aforementioned Little Princess "adaptation," this movie is nonetheless an Americanized version of a classic British children's novel, and its roots definitely show as a stereotypically Hollywood effort. Namely, since the screenplay resets the story in America- I suppose to make it more relatable to stateside audiences- it also deems it necessary to put "spunk" into a character who is supposed to be tenacious, but reserved, even having her occasionally talk back and pull pranks. Thankfully, this never goes into Home Alone territory, but is very uncharacteristic of someone who strives to behave like a princess. Finally, there is the much-maligned happy ending pulled straight from the Temple version, which I only had a problem with because it was too over-the-top, where most of the time, the movie had the sense to pull back and have an occasional reflective moment. To make a very, very long story short: Not my favorite, has no nostalgia attached to it for me, but I can accept it, and even enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really a spoiler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironmn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just wanted to say, that i enjoyed this film a lot, but at the end i was fuming mad and shouting at the TV. i was livid that all that Sarah went through it would have been fantastic that as her father was hugging her she turned just as the miss minchin was walking away Sarah turns and shouts she has stolen my locket and then the police go inside and find it and on opening it you see the fathers picture, and then the police drag the screaming miss minchin away in front of the rest of the school. then it would be a satisfying end, i would been shouting, yes you rotten cow now you will get what you deserve. So just wanted to vent this as I've just finished watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All Girls Are Princesses!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anastasia-cessano-writes
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is wonderful! I am 13 almost 14 years old and I still watch this movie regularly! I watched it so much the DVD messed up and I had to buy a new one! I HAVE read the book, and at the time I liked the book, but then I watched this-and I was blown away! This movie is a perfect example of a kids' movie that isn't horrible garbage without being overly intense. I have to admit, this is quit different from the book, but who really CARES? Sara (Liesel Matthews) is a thoughtful, smart, sweet child, not spoiled and stupidly cheerful like Shirley Temple's version. Oh no! She IS a little princess! And her father (Liam Cunningham) is so devoted and loving! But the best acted part of this entire movie has to go to: Eleanor Bron (yes, the lady in Help, and Wimbledon!!) as Miss Minchin! She was an amazing evil woman but at the same time, you see that she has never been loved and that's why she's so HEARTLESS! I believe that woman should have won an Oscar for this! And Cuaron's directing is unbelievably great! Seriously, go see this film. If you hate it, email me at anastasia.cessano.writes@aol.com with your complaints.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an absolute piece of .....(you supply the negative words ) of a movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    melee-3
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    an absolute waste of time and money....... if one is going to see a film .... do the smart thing and get the Shirley Temple movie. My girlfriend had NEVER seen OLD movies before meeting me. She'd seen the Mummy and I introduced her to the old Boris Karloff 1932 movie. She saw the Jackie Chan piece of crap Around the World in 80 Days, so I showed her the 1956 movie. She saw the Harrison Ford Sabrina and then the Bogart, Hepburn, Holden movie. The pathetic Eddie Murphy The Nutty Professor was watched by her some time in the past, so I found the 1963 Jerry Lewis movie for her. Need I say that the old one was the one appreciated more in each case? (I could have listed more, like Belushi vs Bogart (Sahara) or War of the Worlds 2005 vs 1953...and several others like The Seven Samurai vs The Magnificent 7) The next thing to find is a Rat Pack Ocean's 11 for her :) Most remakes of a story line do NOT live up to the older one..... and this A Little Princess is probably the second worst remake I have ever seen. Jackie Chan's Around the World in 80 Days is the only remake I can think of that tops this one in terms of patheticness
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thrwmbsbgkdoepmcjrmrdw
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a good film, but different from the book. It's been a while since I've read the book, or until today seen the movie. It's well acted for the most part. I thought the father didn't do that great of a job. But other than him well acted, we directed, well put together. I do have a question though. How is it possible to regain your memory in two seconds like the father did? That part I don't get. I liked how dark they made the head mistress staying true to the character of her. And I love that they made her a sweeper at the end. Good punishment. The sister was probably my favorite with her love affair with the milkman. Very charming and cute. I really enjoyed the movie and would recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hiddenags
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before I begin I'd like to say I have not read the original "A Little Princess" and maybe one day in the future I shall read it. However this movie generally moved me. I'm not the type that usually gets emotional over movies but this movie is exceptional. The main role of Sara Crewe is played by Liesel Matthews, a really cute young girl (in this movie anyway), although her acting skills aren't great , she really gets the message across. The music of the movie is also beautifully crafted and co-ordinates with the movie really well. I recommend you watch this movie and please keep an open mind. ***WARNING*** This movie may be a bit "girly"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A whimsical family film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Alfonso Cuaron's adaptation of A Little Princess is a film filled with magically realism, whimsy and sickly sweetness. It is a popular film for young girls and women for these reasons. In 1914 Britain has entered into the First World War. Sara Crewe (Liesel Matthews) is a British girl (even though she has an American accent), living in India. She is a kind-hearted girl with a big imagine, intelligence and a keen storyteller. When her father (Liam Cunningham) is called up to serve in the war, Sara is sent to the same boarding school her descended mother went to, the Miss Minchin's Seminary for Girls in New York. Sara quickly becomes a popular girl at the school because of her wit, storytelling and willingness to stand up wrongdoing. But when her father is declared killed in action Sara's wealth is taken away and the crude hearted headmistress (Eleanor Bron) makes Sara into a servant girl. Despite Sara's grief she sets out to keep her dignity and her charitable spirit. A Little Princess was weighted around a strong performance from a talented young actress, Matthews. She gave a heart felt performance and mixed with Cuaron's emotionally manipulating direction you felt her pain and sorrow as she suffers from grief and the enforced poverty but keeps her determination and spirit. There is a theme of the rewards of charity and kindness, that if keep those attitudes and do not the world grind you then your good deals will be acknowledged. It is story about a girl needs to keep her determination, hope, kindness and imaginable that strength of friendship. I personally love Cuaron as a director, especially for his work on Harry Potter and Children of Men. With A Little Princess he was in full manipulation mode and it very much like a Spielberg film in the emotional scenes to more comically toned involving the girls causing mischief, playing jokes to a scene where the bully of school is 'cursed' and sees the outcome of it. Unfortunately because of the The art direction and cinematography are striking and fitting for the themes of the film, that India is a bright, colourful wondrous place, to the more harsh, cold reality of the street of New York in the winter. Peter Doyle's score added to getting the audience sunk into this world, using Indian music, a traditional score, a choir and a song sung by a young girl. A Little Princess is an orphan story similar in the vain of Oliver Twist, Annie and The Matchstick Girl, a young girl forced into the big bad city. Like Annie and The Matchstick Girl Sara is forced into servitude and the emotional scenes on the streets was very much like The Matchstick Girl. Because of the boarding school setting and Sara's background it is clear why Cuaron was a sensible choice to take on Harry Potter. A big criticism is the setting. The film changes the location from London to New York to cater to American auditions (seeing that the film flopped in America that change was pointless) and the time from the Victorian era to 1914. By changing it to 1914 it made the scenario less believable, that Sara becomes slave labour when she should would be education and child labour is still being used when in most Western countries had at this point introduced some sort of compulsory education. A Little Princess truly is a family film, children of all ages will find something to enjoy in this whimsical film. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Alfonso Cuaron best film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    haterofcrap
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was such a beautiful film. It is one of the best kids movies ever made, and it is also the best movie directed by Alfonso Cuaron, a very good movie director (Despite the fact that sometimes he made bad movies such as "Y tu Mama Tambi&eacute;n") This version was a much better adaptation than the 1939 (Which is a very good film, but honestly I think this was a better adaptation of the book) This film had the heart in the right place, and captures perfectly all the emotion and beauty from the book. It has an excellent visual style, the music and the performances were quite good too. I loved this movie. I wish there were more kid's films like this. I highly recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Princess (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin Teller
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the book, but I have read outraged IMDb comments from fans of it. Some of the comments seem delusional, but there are some that sound like legitimate gripes. Certainly the ending is far too easy... not for children perhaps, but for me it felt cheap. And the pathology of the wicked headmistress is only hinted at, but never explored and as a result she just comes off like a one-dimensional evil bitch. But there's a lot of delight to be had in the movie. As with PRISONER OF AZKABAN, Cuaron demonstrates a masterful sense of style and ability to craft a tale that's enjoyable for the kids and also engaging for the grown-ups. The set design and color palette is gorgeous, and young Liesel Matthews is endearing in the lead. I also enjoyed the Indian flights of fancy and the general spirit of the thing. Despite some missteps, a charming little picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Princess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n (Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban, Children of Men), I had seen the trailer for this film many times and always been curious to try the film, especially with it being rated the full five out of five stars, so when it was available I watched enthusiastically. Basically eleven year old Sara Crewe (introducing Liesel Matthews) and her wealthy father Capt. Crewe (Liam Cunningham) leave their home in India and move to New York, and he leaves her in an all girls boarding school while he enlists in the British Army. The school is run by the severe Miss Minchin (Eleanor Bron), and soon enough the bored and mundane lives of the girls are made better by Sara who becomes popular with her stories of "The Ramayana", much to the dislike of Miss Minchin and the irritation of spoilt bully Lavinia (Taylor Fry). After throwing a lavish birthday party, in which Miss Minchin wanted to extract money from Sara's father, word reaches them that he has apparently died in action, and with his estate seized by the British government the headmistress forces the innocent little girl to become a servant, alongside black servant Becky (The Lost World: Jurassic Park's Vanessa Lee Chester). Forced to stop telling stories and have her possessions, including her father's locket, taken from her, Sara only has her spirits lifted with the girls being on her side and helping her however they can, and with her belief that "every girl is a princess". Next door to the school is the mansion of rich old Charles Randolph (Arthur Malet) who wants his son to return from the war, and an injured soldier is brought to his home, it is not his son, but Capt. Crewe, suffering temporary blindness and memory loss, but Indian immigrant Ram Dass (Errol Sitahal) insists he be taken care of. One night Miss Minchin catches the other girls with Sara telling stories, and she punishes her and Becky with no food the next night, but they awaken to find a feast and palace setting, they originally imagined it, courtesy of Ram Dass. After Miss Minchin finds this she decides the police should be involved, because of possible stealing, and using a long plank Sara makes her escape across to Randolph's mansion next door. It is there she obviously is shocked and happy to see her father alive, but he does not recognise her, and Miss Minchin cruelly says that she has no family to get her away from him, but Ram Dass helps him remember and rescue her. In the end, Capt. Crewe has his fortune restored and buys himself the boarding school as the new headmaster and to make life for the girls much better, Miss Minchin is forced to be a chimney sweep alongside a young boy she originally mistreated, and Sara and Becky are going back to India together to live happily ever after, and all the girls, including Lavinia, saying their tearful goodbyes. Also starring Rusty Schwimmer as Amelia Minchin, Heather DeLoach as Ermengarde, Vincent Schiavelli as Mr. Barrow, The Ring's Rachael Bella as Betsy, The Lost World: Jurassic Park's Camilla Belle as Jane and Kelsey Mulrooney as Lottie. Matthews is wonderful as the imaginative and sweet young girl with her good spirit pushed to the limit, and Bron is fantastically vulgar as the subtly but equally knowingly evil (like Nurse Ratched style) villain headmistress, it is charming story with plenty of delightful and sweet moments, as well as true emotion, and the special effects give us moments in a surreal magical world, and it is a film that will appeal both to the adults and the children watching, a brilliant period fantasy drama. It was nominated the Oscars for Best Art Direction-Set Decoration and Best Cinematography. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not MY Little Princess, but better than Shirley Temple
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Left-Handed_Liz
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I hesitated in seeing this film for a very long time. I wasn't aware of it when it was in theaters, and I adored the book so much, and the BBC-produced miniseries starring Amelia Shankley, that I didn't want to ruin my image of the book by seeing a Hollywoodized adaptation, even into my teens. However, I'll try anything once, and the number of fans that it seems to have made me think that it might not be so bad. And it really isn't. Compared to a lot of live- action "family entertainment," which can be obnoxious and formulaic, it's exquisite. The cinematography is lush and warmly lit (perhaps a little too warm, when it comes to depicting Sara's somewhat gloomy life in poverty), and what the studio was able to do with such a small budget is more than some people could do with ten million to spend on a movie- ironic, considering the theme of wealth, or lack thereof. I found myself really warming up to the film's focus on the relationship between Sara and her father as they struggled to carry on in the midst of two very different sets of trials, as well as the emphasis on Sara's childhood in India, such as the "Ramayana" fantasy sequences, and the sitars reverberating alongside the more classical instruments on the soundtrack. The acting was at least passable throughout, though it sometimes veered into community theater-level skill. Even Liesel Matthews gave an endearing performance as Sara- certainly less stoicism and solemnity than the original, but thankfully with none of the dimple-faced pouting of the 1937 Shirley Temple film, which I couldn't stand for more than the first 30 minutes. At least Matthews's Sara is a real storyteller, and has the presence of one, rather than arbitrarily pretending things for her own amusement. The bad news is that, while a significant improvement on the aforementioned Little Princess "adaptation," this movie is nonetheless an Americanized version of a classic British children's novel, and its roots definitely show as a stereotypically Hollywood effort. Namely, since the screenplay resets the story in America- I suppose to make it more relatable to stateside audiences- it also deems it necessary to put "spunk" into a character who is supposed to be tenacious, but reserved, even having her occasionally talk back and pull pranks. Thankfully, this never goes into Home Alone territory, but is very uncharacteristic of someone who strives to behave like a princess. Finally, there is the much-maligned happy ending pulled straight from the Temple version, which I only had a problem with because it was too over-the-top, where most of the time, the movie had the sense to pull back and have an occasional reflective moment. To make a very, very long story short: Not my favorite, has no nostalgia attached to it for me, but I can accept it, and even enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really a spoiler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironmn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just wanted to say, that i enjoyed this film a lot, but at the end i was fuming mad and shouting at the TV. i was livid that all that Sarah went through it would have been fantastic that as her father was hugging her she turned just as the miss minchin was walking away Sarah turns and shouts she has stolen my locket and then the police go inside and find it and on opening it you see the fathers picture, and then the police drag the screaming miss minchin away in front of the rest of the school. then it would be a satisfying end, i would been shouting, yes you rotten cow now you will get what you deserve. So just wanted to vent this as I've just finished watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All Girls Are Princesses!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anastasia-cessano-writes
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is wonderful! I am 13 almost 14 years old and I still watch this movie regularly! I watched it so much the DVD messed up and I had to buy a new one! I HAVE read the book, and at the time I liked the book, but then I watched this-and I was blown away! This movie is a perfect example of a kids' movie that isn't horrible garbage without being overly intense. I have to admit, this is quit different from the book, but who really CARES? Sara (Liesel Matthews) is a thoughtful, smart, sweet child, not spoiled and stupidly cheerful like Shirley Temple's version. Oh no! She IS a little princess! And her father (Liam Cunningham) is so devoted and loving! But the best acted part of this entire movie has to go to: Eleanor Bron (yes, the lady in Help, and Wimbledon!!) as Miss Minchin! She was an amazing evil woman but at the same time, you see that she has never been loved and that's why she's so HEARTLESS! I believe that woman should have won an Oscar for this! And Cuaron's directing is unbelievably great! Seriously, go see this film. If you hate it, email me at anastasia.cessano.writes@aol.com with your complaints.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an absolute piece of .....(you supply the negative words ) of a movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    melee-3
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    an absolute waste of time and money....... if one is going to see a film .... do the smart thing and get the Shirley Temple movie. My girlfriend had NEVER seen OLD movies before meeting me. She'd seen the Mummy and I introduced her to the old Boris Karloff 1932 movie. She saw the Jackie Chan piece of crap Around the World in 80 Days, so I showed her the 1956 movie. She saw the Harrison Ford Sabrina and then the Bogart, Hepburn, Holden movie. The pathetic Eddie Murphy The Nutty Professor was watched by her some time in the past, so I found the 1963 Jerry Lewis movie for her. Need I say that the old one was the one appreciated more in each case? (I could have listed more, like Belushi vs Bogart (Sahara) or War of the Worlds 2005 vs 1953...and several others like The Seven Samurai vs The Magnificent 7) The next thing to find is a Rat Pack Ocean's 11 for her :) Most remakes of a story line do NOT live up to the older one..... and this A Little Princess is probably the second worst remake I have ever seen. Jackie Chan's Around the World in 80 Days is the only remake I can think of that tops this one in terms of patheticness
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thrwmbsbgkdoepmcjrmrdw
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a good film, but different from the book. It's been a while since I've read the book, or until today seen the movie. It's well acted for the most part. I thought the father didn't do that great of a job. But other than him well acted, we directed, well put together. I do have a question though. How is it possible to regain your memory in two seconds like the father did? That part I don't get. I liked how dark they made the head mistress staying true to the character of her. And I love that they made her a sweeper at the end. Good punishment. The sister was probably my favorite with her love affair with the milkman. Very charming and cute. I really enjoyed the movie and would recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hiddenags
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before I begin I'd like to say I have not read the original "A Little Princess" and maybe one day in the future I shall read it. However this movie generally moved me. I'm not the type that usually gets emotional over movies but this movie is exceptional. The main role of Sara Crewe is played by Liesel Matthews, a really cute young girl (in this movie anyway), although her acting skills aren't great , she really gets the message across. The music of the movie is also beautifully crafted and co-ordinates with the movie really well. I recommend you watch this movie and please keep an open mind. ***WARNING*** This movie may be a bit "girly"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A whimsical family film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Alfonso Cuaron's adaptation of A Little Princess is a film filled with magically realism, whimsy and sickly sweetness. It is a popular film for young girls and women for these reasons. In 1914 Britain has entered into the First World War. Sara Crewe (Liesel Matthews) is a British girl (even though she has an American accent), living in India. She is a kind-hearted girl with a big imagine, intelligence and a keen storyteller. When her father (Liam Cunningham) is called up to serve in the war, Sara is sent to the same boarding school her descended mother went to, the Miss Minchin's Seminary for Girls in New York. Sara quickly becomes a popular girl at the school because of her wit, storytelling and willingness to stand up wrongdoing. But when her father is declared killed in action Sara's wealth is taken away and the crude hearted headmistress (Eleanor Bron) makes Sara into a servant girl. Despite Sara's grief she sets out to keep her dignity and her charitable spirit. A Little Princess was weighted around a strong performance from a talented young actress, Matthews. She gave a heart felt performance and mixed with Cuaron's emotionally manipulating direction you felt her pain and sorrow as she suffers from grief and the enforced poverty but keeps her determination and spirit. There is a theme of the rewards of charity and kindness, that if keep those attitudes and do not the world grind you then your good deals will be acknowledged. It is story about a girl needs to keep her determination, hope, kindness and imaginable that strength of friendship. I personally love Cuaron as a director, especially for his work on Harry Potter and Children of Men. With A Little Princess he was in full manipulation mode and it very much like a Spielberg film in the emotional scenes to more comically toned involving the girls causing mischief, playing jokes to a scene where the bully of school is 'cursed' and sees the outcome of it. Unfortunately because of the The art direction and cinematography are striking and fitting for the themes of the film, that India is a bright, colourful wondrous place, to the more harsh, cold reality of the street of New York in the winter. Peter Doyle's score added to getting the audience sunk into this world, using Indian music, a traditional score, a choir and a song sung by a young girl. A Little Princess is an orphan story similar in the vain of Oliver Twist, Annie and The Matchstick Girl, a young girl forced into the big bad city. Like Annie and The Matchstick Girl Sara is forced into servitude and the emotional scenes on the streets was very much like The Matchstick Girl. Because of the boarding school setting and Sara's background it is clear why Cuaron was a sensible choice to take on Harry Potter. A big criticism is the setting. The film changes the location from London to New York to cater to American auditions (seeing that the film flopped in America that change was pointless) and the time from the Victorian era to 1914. By changing it to 1914 it made the scenario less believable, that Sara becomes slave labour when she should would be education and child labour is still being used when in most Western countries had at this point introduced some sort of compulsory education. A Little Princess truly is a family film, children of all ages will find something to enjoy in this whimsical film. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Alfonso Cuaron best film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    haterofcrap
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was such a beautiful film. It is one of the best kids movies ever made, and it is also the best movie directed by Alfonso Cuaron, a very good movie director (Despite the fact that sometimes he made bad movies such as "Y tu Mama Tambi&eacute;n") This version was a much better adaptation than the 1939 (Which is a very good film, but honestly I think this was a better adaptation of the book) This film had the heart in the right place, and captures perfectly all the emotion and beauty from the book. It has an excellent visual style, the music and the performances were quite good too. I loved this movie. I wish there were more kid's films like this. I highly recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Princess (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin Teller
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the book, but I have read outraged IMDb comments from fans of it. Some of the comments seem delusional, but there are some that sound like legitimate gripes. Certainly the ending is far too easy... not for children perhaps, but for me it felt cheap. And the pathology of the wicked headmistress is only hinted at, but never explored and as a result she just comes off like a one-dimensional evil bitch. But there's a lot of delight to be had in the movie. As with PRISONER OF AZKABAN, Cuaron demonstrates a masterful sense of style and ability to craft a tale that's enjoyable for the kids and also engaging for the grown-ups. The set design and color palette is gorgeous, and young Liesel Matthews is endearing in the lead. I also enjoyed the Indian flights of fancy and the general spirit of the thing. Despite some missteps, a charming little picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Princess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n (Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban, Children of Men), I had seen the trailer for this film many times and always been curious to try the film, especially with it being rated the full five out of five stars, so when it was available I watched enthusiastically. Basically eleven year old Sara Crewe (introducing Liesel Matthews) and her wealthy father Capt. Crewe (Liam Cunningham) leave their home in India and move to New York, and he leaves her in an all girls boarding school while he enlists in the British Army. The school is run by the severe Miss Minchin (Eleanor Bron), and soon enough the bored and mundane lives of the girls are made better by Sara who becomes popular with her stories of "The Ramayana", much to the dislike of Miss Minchin and the irritation of spoilt bully Lavinia (Taylor Fry). After throwing a lavish birthday party, in which Miss Minchin wanted to extract money from Sara's father, word reaches them that he has apparently died in action, and with his estate seized by the British government the headmistress forces the innocent little girl to become a servant, alongside black servant Becky (The Lost World: Jurassic Park's Vanessa Lee Chester). Forced to stop telling stories and have her possessions, including her father's locket, taken from her, Sara only has her spirits lifted with the girls being on her side and helping her however they can, and with her belief that "every girl is a princess". Next door to the school is the mansion of rich old Charles Randolph (Arthur Malet) who wants his son to return from the war, and an injured soldier is brought to his home, it is not his son, but Capt. Crewe, suffering temporary blindness and memory loss, but Indian immigrant Ram Dass (Errol Sitahal) insists he be taken care of. One night Miss Minchin catches the other girls with Sara telling stories, and she punishes her and Becky with no food the next night, but they awaken to find a feast and palace setting, they originally imagined it, courtesy of Ram Dass. After Miss Minchin finds this she decides the police should be involved, because of possible stealing, and using a long plank Sara makes her escape across to Randolph's mansion next door. It is there she obviously is shocked and happy to see her father alive, but he does not recognise her, and Miss Minchin cruelly says that she has no family to get her away from him, but Ram Dass helps him remember and rescue her. In the end, Capt. Crewe has his fortune restored and buys himself the boarding school as the new headmaster and to make life for the girls much better, Miss Minchin is forced to be a chimney sweep alongside a young boy she originally mistreated, and Sara and Becky are going back to India together to live happily ever after, and all the girls, including Lavinia, saying their tearful goodbyes. Also starring Rusty Schwimmer as Amelia Minchin, Heather DeLoach as Ermengarde, Vincent Schiavelli as Mr. Barrow, The Ring's Rachael Bella as Betsy, The Lost World: Jurassic Park's Camilla Belle as Jane and Kelsey Mulrooney as Lottie. Matthews is wonderful as the imaginative and sweet young girl with her good spirit pushed to the limit, and Bron is fantastically vulgar as the subtly but equally knowingly evil (like Nurse Ratched style) villain headmistress, it is charming story with plenty of delightful and sweet moments, as well as true emotion, and the special effects give us moments in a surreal magical world, and it is a film that will appeal both to the adults and the children watching, a brilliant period fantasy drama. It was nominated the Oscars for Best Art Direction-Set Decoration and Best Cinematography. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not MY Little Princess, but better than Shirley Temple
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Left-Handed_Liz
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I hesitated in seeing this film for a very long time. I wasn't aware of it when it was in theaters, and I adored the book so much, and the BBC-produced miniseries starring Amelia Shankley, that I didn't want to ruin my image of the book by seeing a Hollywoodized adaptation, even into my teens. However, I'll try anything once, and the number of fans that it seems to have made me think that it might not be so bad. And it really isn't. Compared to a lot of live- action "family entertainment," which can be obnoxious and formulaic, it's exquisite. The cinematography is lush and warmly lit (perhaps a little too warm, when it comes to depicting Sara's somewhat gloomy life in poverty), and what the studio was able to do with such a small budget is more than some people could do with ten million to spend on a movie- ironic, considering the theme of wealth, or lack thereof. I found myself really warming up to the film's focus on the relationship between Sara and her father as they struggled to carry on in the midst of two very different sets of trials, as well as the emphasis on Sara's childhood in India, such as the "Ramayana" fantasy sequences, and the sitars reverberating alongside the more classical instruments on the soundtrack. The acting was at least passable throughout, though it sometimes veered into community theater-level skill. Even Liesel Matthews gave an endearing performance as Sara- certainly less stoicism and solemnity than the original, but thankfully with none of the dimple-faced pouting of the 1937 Shirley Temple film, which I couldn't stand for more than the first 30 minutes. At least Matthews's Sara is a real storyteller, and has the presence of one, rather than arbitrarily pretending things for her own amusement. The bad news is that, while a significant improvement on the aforementioned Little Princess "adaptation," this movie is nonetheless an Americanized version of a classic British children's novel, and its roots definitely show as a stereotypically Hollywood effort. Namely, since the screenplay resets the story in America- I suppose to make it more relatable to stateside audiences- it also deems it necessary to put "spunk" into a character who is supposed to be tenacious, but reserved, even having her occasionally talk back and pull pranks. Thankfully, this never goes into Home Alone territory, but is very uncharacteristic of someone who strives to behave like a princess. Finally, there is the much-maligned happy ending pulled straight from the Temple version, which I only had a problem with because it was too over-the-top, where most of the time, the movie had the sense to pull back and have an occasional reflective moment. To make a very, very long story short: Not my favorite, has no nostalgia attached to it for me, but I can accept it, and even enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really a spoiler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironmn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just wanted to say, that i enjoyed this film a lot, but at the end i was fuming mad and shouting at the TV. i was livid that all that Sarah went through it would have been fantastic that as her father was hugging her she turned just as the miss minchin was walking away Sarah turns and shouts she has stolen my locket and then the police go inside and find it and on opening it you see the fathers picture, and then the police drag the screaming miss minchin away in front of the rest of the school. then it would be a satisfying end, i would been shouting, yes you rotten cow now you will get what you deserve. So just wanted to vent this as I've just finished watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All Girls Are Princesses!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anastasia-cessano-writes
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is wonderful! I am 13 almost 14 years old and I still watch this movie regularly! I watched it so much the DVD messed up and I had to buy a new one! I HAVE read the book, and at the time I liked the book, but then I watched this-and I was blown away! This movie is a perfect example of a kids' movie that isn't horrible garbage without being overly intense. I have to admit, this is quit different from the book, but who really CARES? Sara (Liesel Matthews) is a thoughtful, smart, sweet child, not spoiled and stupidly cheerful like Shirley Temple's version. Oh no! She IS a little princess! And her father (Liam Cunningham) is so devoted and loving! But the best acted part of this entire movie has to go to: Eleanor Bron (yes, the lady in Help, and Wimbledon!!) as Miss Minchin! She was an amazing evil woman but at the same time, you see that she has never been loved and that's why she's so HEARTLESS! I believe that woman should have won an Oscar for this! And Cuaron's directing is unbelievably great! Seriously, go see this film. If you hate it, email me at anastasia.cessano.writes@aol.com with your complaints.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an absolute piece of .....(you supply the negative words ) of a movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    melee-3
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    an absolute waste of time and money....... if one is going to see a film .... do the smart thing and get the Shirley Temple movie. My girlfriend had NEVER seen OLD movies before meeting me. She'd seen the Mummy and I introduced her to the old Boris Karloff 1932 movie. She saw the Jackie Chan piece of crap Around the World in 80 Days, so I showed her the 1956 movie. She saw the Harrison Ford Sabrina and then the Bogart, Hepburn, Holden movie. The pathetic Eddie Murphy The Nutty Professor was watched by her some time in the past, so I found the 1963 Jerry Lewis movie for her. Need I say that the old one was the one appreciated more in each case? (I could have listed more, like Belushi vs Bogart (Sahara) or War of the Worlds 2005 vs 1953...and several others like The Seven Samurai vs The Magnificent 7) The next thing to find is a Rat Pack Ocean's 11 for her :) Most remakes of a story line do NOT live up to the older one..... and this A Little Princess is probably the second worst remake I have ever seen. Jackie Chan's Around the World in 80 Days is the only remake I can think of that tops this one in terms of patheticness
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thrwmbsbgkdoepmcjrmrdw
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a good film, but different from the book. It's been a while since I've read the book, or until today seen the movie. It's well acted for the most part. I thought the father didn't do that great of a job. But other than him well acted, we directed, well put together. I do have a question though. How is it possible to regain your memory in two seconds like the father did? That part I don't get. I liked how dark they made the head mistress staying true to the character of her. And I love that they made her a sweeper at the end. Good punishment. The sister was probably my favorite with her love affair with the milkman. Very charming and cute. I really enjoyed the movie and would recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hiddenags
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before I begin I'd like to say I have not read the original "A Little Princess" and maybe one day in the future I shall read it. However this movie generally moved me. I'm not the type that usually gets emotional over movies but this movie is exceptional. The main role of Sara Crewe is played by Liesel Matthews, a really cute young girl (in this movie anyway), although her acting skills aren't great , she really gets the message across. The music of the movie is also beautifully crafted and co-ordinates with the movie really well. I recommend you watch this movie and please keep an open mind. ***WARNING*** This movie may be a bit "girly"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A whimsical family film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Alfonso Cuaron's adaptation of A Little Princess is a film filled with magically realism, whimsy and sickly sweetness. It is a popular film for young girls and women for these reasons. In 1914 Britain has entered into the First World War. Sara Crewe (Liesel Matthews) is a British girl (even though she has an American accent), living in India. She is a kind-hearted girl with a big imagine, intelligence and a keen storyteller. When her father (Liam Cunningham) is called up to serve in the war, Sara is sent to the same boarding school her descended mother went to, the Miss Minchin's Seminary for Girls in New York. Sara quickly becomes a popular girl at the school because of her wit, storytelling and willingness to stand up wrongdoing. But when her father is declared killed in action Sara's wealth is taken away and the crude hearted headmistress (Eleanor Bron) makes Sara into a servant girl. Despite Sara's grief she sets out to keep her dignity and her charitable spirit. A Little Princess was weighted around a strong performance from a talented young actress, Matthews. She gave a heart felt performance and mixed with Cuaron's emotionally manipulating direction you felt her pain and sorrow as she suffers from grief and the enforced poverty but keeps her determination and spirit. There is a theme of the rewards of charity and kindness, that if keep those attitudes and do not the world grind you then your good deals will be acknowledged. It is story about a girl needs to keep her determination, hope, kindness and imaginable that strength of friendship. I personally love Cuaron as a director, especially for his work on Harry Potter and Children of Men. With A Little Princess he was in full manipulation mode and it very much like a Spielberg film in the emotional scenes to more comically toned involving the girls causing mischief, playing jokes to a scene where the bully of school is 'cursed' and sees the outcome of it. Unfortunately because of the The art direction and cinematography are striking and fitting for the themes of the film, that India is a bright, colourful wondrous place, to the more harsh, cold reality of the street of New York in the winter. Peter Doyle's score added to getting the audience sunk into this world, using Indian music, a traditional score, a choir and a song sung by a young girl. A Little Princess is an orphan story similar in the vain of Oliver Twist, Annie and The Matchstick Girl, a young girl forced into the big bad city. Like Annie and The Matchstick Girl Sara is forced into servitude and the emotional scenes on the streets was very much like The Matchstick Girl. Because of the boarding school setting and Sara's background it is clear why Cuaron was a sensible choice to take on Harry Potter. A big criticism is the setting. The film changes the location from London to New York to cater to American auditions (seeing that the film flopped in America that change was pointless) and the time from the Victorian era to 1914. By changing it to 1914 it made the scenario less believable, that Sara becomes slave labour when she should would be education and child labour is still being used when in most Western countries had at this point introduced some sort of compulsory education. A Little Princess truly is a family film, children of all ages will find something to enjoy in this whimsical film. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Alfonso Cuaron best film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    haterofcrap
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was such a beautiful film. It is one of the best kids movies ever made, and it is also the best movie directed by Alfonso Cuaron, a very good movie director (Despite the fact that sometimes he made bad movies such as "Y tu Mama Tambi&eacute;n") This version was a much better adaptation than the 1939 (Which is a very good film, but honestly I think this was a better adaptation of the book) This film had the heart in the right place, and captures perfectly all the emotion and beauty from the book. It has an excellent visual style, the music and the performances were quite good too. I loved this movie. I wish there were more kid's films like this. I highly recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Princess (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin Teller
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the book, but I have read outraged IMDb comments from fans of it. Some of the comments seem delusional, but there are some that sound like legitimate gripes. Certainly the ending is far too easy... not for children perhaps, but for me it felt cheap. And the pathology of the wicked headmistress is only hinted at, but never explored and as a result she just comes off like a one-dimensional evil bitch. But there's a lot of delight to be had in the movie. As with PRISONER OF AZKABAN, Cuaron demonstrates a masterful sense of style and ability to craft a tale that's enjoyable for the kids and also engaging for the grown-ups. The set design and color palette is gorgeous, and young Liesel Matthews is endearing in the lead. I also enjoyed the Indian flights of fancy and the general spirit of the thing. Despite some missteps, a charming little picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Princess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n (Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban, Children of Men), I had seen the trailer for this film many times and always been curious to try the film, especially with it being rated the full five out of five stars, so when it was available I watched enthusiastically. Basically eleven year old Sara Crewe (introducing Liesel Matthews) and her wealthy father Capt. Crewe (Liam Cunningham) leave their home in India and move to New York, and he leaves her in an all girls boarding school while he enlists in the British Army. The school is run by the severe Miss Minchin (Eleanor Bron), and soon enough the bored and mundane lives of the girls are made better by Sara who becomes popular with her stories of "The Ramayana", much to the dislike of Miss Minchin and the irritation of spoilt bully Lavinia (Taylor Fry). After throwing a lavish birthday party, in which Miss Minchin wanted to extract money from Sara's father, word reaches them that he has apparently died in action, and with his estate seized by the British government the headmistress forces the innocent little girl to become a servant, alongside black servant Becky (The Lost World: Jurassic Park's Vanessa Lee Chester). Forced to stop telling stories and have her possessions, including her father's locket, taken from her, Sara only has her spirits lifted with the girls being on her side and helping her however they can, and with her belief that "every girl is a princess". Next door to the school is the mansion of rich old Charles Randolph (Arthur Malet) who wants his son to return from the war, and an injured soldier is brought to his home, it is not his son, but Capt. Crewe, suffering temporary blindness and memory loss, but Indian immigrant Ram Dass (Errol Sitahal) insists he be taken care of. One night Miss Minchin catches the other girls with Sara telling stories, and she punishes her and Becky with no food the next night, but they awaken to find a feast and palace setting, they originally imagined it, courtesy of Ram Dass. After Miss Minchin finds this she decides the police should be involved, because of possible stealing, and using a long plank Sara makes her escape across to Randolph's mansion next door. It is there she obviously is shocked and happy to see her father alive, but he does not recognise her, and Miss Minchin cruelly says that she has no family to get her away from him, but Ram Dass helps him remember and rescue her. In the end, Capt. Crewe has his fortune restored and buys himself the boarding school as the new headmaster and to make life for the girls much better, Miss Minchin is forced to be a chimney sweep alongside a young boy she originally mistreated, and Sara and Becky are going back to India together to live happily ever after, and all the girls, including Lavinia, saying their tearful goodbyes. Also starring Rusty Schwimmer as Amelia Minchin, Heather DeLoach as Ermengarde, Vincent Schiavelli as Mr. Barrow, The Ring's Rachael Bella as Betsy, The Lost World: Jurassic Park's Camilla Belle as Jane and Kelsey Mulrooney as Lottie. Matthews is wonderful as the imaginative and sweet young girl with her good spirit pushed to the limit, and Bron is fantastically vulgar as the subtly but equally knowingly evil (like Nurse Ratched style) villain headmistress, it is charming story with plenty of delightful and sweet moments, as well as true emotion, and the special effects give us moments in a surreal magical world, and it is a film that will appeal both to the adults and the children watching, a brilliant period fantasy drama. It was nominated the Oscars for Best Art Direction-Set Decoration and Best Cinematography. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not MY Little Princess, but better than Shirley Temple
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Left-Handed_Liz
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I hesitated in seeing this film for a very long time. I wasn't aware of it when it was in theaters, and I adored the book so much, and the BBC-produced miniseries starring Amelia Shankley, that I didn't want to ruin my image of the book by seeing a Hollywoodized adaptation, even into my teens. However, I'll try anything once, and the number of fans that it seems to have made me think that it might not be so bad. And it really isn't. Compared to a lot of live- action "family entertainment," which can be obnoxious and formulaic, it's exquisite. The cinematography is lush and warmly lit (perhaps a little too warm, when it comes to depicting Sara's somewhat gloomy life in poverty), and what the studio was able to do with such a small budget is more than some people could do with ten million to spend on a movie- ironic, considering the theme of wealth, or lack thereof. I found myself really warming up to the film's focus on the relationship between Sara and her father as they struggled to carry on in the midst of two very different sets of trials, as well as the emphasis on Sara's childhood in India, such as the "Ramayana" fantasy sequences, and the sitars reverberating alongside the more classical instruments on the soundtrack. The acting was at least passable throughout, though it sometimes veered into community theater-level skill. Even Liesel Matthews gave an endearing performance as Sara- certainly less stoicism and solemnity than the original, but thankfully with none of the dimple-faced pouting of the 1937 Shirley Temple film, which I couldn't stand for more than the first 30 minutes. At least Matthews's Sara is a real storyteller, and has the presence of one, rather than arbitrarily pretending things for her own amusement. The bad news is that, while a significant improvement on the aforementioned Little Princess "adaptation," this movie is nonetheless an Americanized version of a classic British children's novel, and its roots definitely show as a stereotypically Hollywood effort. Namely, since the screenplay resets the story in America- I suppose to make it more relatable to stateside audiences- it also deems it necessary to put "spunk" into a character who is supposed to be tenacious, but reserved, even having her occasionally talk back and pull pranks. Thankfully, this never goes into Home Alone territory, but is very uncharacteristic of someone who strives to behave like a princess. Finally, there is the much-maligned happy ending pulled straight from the Temple version, which I only had a problem with because it was too over-the-top, where most of the time, the movie had the sense to pull back and have an occasional reflective moment. To make a very, very long story short: Not my favorite, has no nostalgia attached to it for me, but I can accept it, and even enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really a spoiler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironmn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just wanted to say, that i enjoyed this film a lot, but at the end i was fuming mad and shouting at the TV. i was livid that all that Sarah went through it would have been fantastic that as her father was hugging her she turned just as the miss minchin was walking away Sarah turns and shouts she has stolen my locket and then the police go inside and find it and on opening it you see the fathers picture, and then the police drag the screaming miss minchin away in front of the rest of the school. then it would be a satisfying end, i would been shouting, yes you rotten cow now you will get what you deserve. So just wanted to vent this as I've just finished watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All Girls Are Princesses!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anastasia-cessano-writes
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is wonderful! I am 13 almost 14 years old and I still watch this movie regularly! I watched it so much the DVD messed up and I had to buy a new one! I HAVE read the book, and at the time I liked the book, but then I watched this-and I was blown away! This movie is a perfect example of a kids' movie that isn't horrible garbage without being overly intense. I have to admit, this is quit different from the book, but who really CARES? Sara (Liesel Matthews) is a thoughtful, smart, sweet child, not spoiled and stupidly cheerful like Shirley Temple's version. Oh no! She IS a little princess! And her father (Liam Cunningham) is so devoted and loving! But the best acted part of this entire movie has to go to: Eleanor Bron (yes, the lady in Help, and Wimbledon!!) as Miss Minchin! She was an amazing evil woman but at the same time, you see that she has never been loved and that's why she's so HEARTLESS! I believe that woman should have won an Oscar for this! And Cuaron's directing is unbelievably great! Seriously, go see this film. If you hate it, email me at anastasia.cessano.writes@aol.com with your complaints.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an absolute piece of .....(you supply the negative words ) of a movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    melee-3
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    an absolute waste of time and money....... if one is going to see a film .... do the smart thing and get the Shirley Temple movie. My girlfriend had NEVER seen OLD movies before meeting me. She'd seen the Mummy and I introduced her to the old Boris Karloff 1932 movie. She saw the Jackie Chan piece of crap Around the World in 80 Days, so I showed her the 1956 movie. She saw the Harrison Ford Sabrina and then the Bogart, Hepburn, Holden movie. The pathetic Eddie Murphy The Nutty Professor was watched by her some time in the past, so I found the 1963 Jerry Lewis movie for her. Need I say that the old one was the one appreciated more in each case? (I could have listed more, like Belushi vs Bogart (Sahara) or War of the Worlds 2005 vs 1953...and several others like The Seven Samurai vs The Magnificent 7) The next thing to find is a Rat Pack Ocean's 11 for her :) Most remakes of a story line do NOT live up to the older one..... and this A Little Princess is probably the second worst remake I have ever seen. Jackie Chan's Around the World in 80 Days is the only remake I can think of that tops this one in terms of patheticness
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thrwmbsbgkdoepmcjrmrdw
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a good film, but different from the book. It's been a while since I've read the book, or until today seen the movie. It's well acted for the most part. I thought the father didn't do that great of a job. But other than him well acted, we directed, well put together. I do have a question though. How is it possible to regain your memory in two seconds like the father did? That part I don't get. I liked how dark they made the head mistress staying true to the character of her. And I love that they made her a sweeper at the end. Good punishment. The sister was probably my favorite with her love affair with the milkman. Very charming and cute. I really enjoyed the movie and would recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hiddenags
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before I begin I'd like to say I have not read the original "A Little Princess" and maybe one day in the future I shall read it. However this movie generally moved me. I'm not the type that usually gets emotional over movies but this movie is exceptional. The main role of Sara Crewe is played by Liesel Matthews, a really cute young girl (in this movie anyway), although her acting skills aren't great , she really gets the message across. The music of the movie is also beautifully crafted and co-ordinates with the movie really well. I recommend you watch this movie and please keep an open mind. ***WARNING*** This movie may be a bit "girly"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A whimsical family film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Alfonso Cuaron's adaptation of A Little Princess is a film filled with magically realism, whimsy and sickly sweetness. It is a popular film for young girls and women for these reasons. In 1914 Britain has entered into the First World War. Sara Crewe (Liesel Matthews) is a British girl (even though she has an American accent), living in India. She is a kind-hearted girl with a big imagine, intelligence and a keen storyteller. When her father (Liam Cunningham) is called up to serve in the war, Sara is sent to the same boarding school her descended mother went to, the Miss Minchin's Seminary for Girls in New York. Sara quickly becomes a popular girl at the school because of her wit, storytelling and willingness to stand up wrongdoing. But when her father is declared killed in action Sara's wealth is taken away and the crude hearted headmistress (Eleanor Bron) makes Sara into a servant girl. Despite Sara's grief she sets out to keep her dignity and her charitable spirit. A Little Princess was weighted around a strong performance from a talented young actress, Matthews. She gave a heart felt performance and mixed with Cuaron's emotionally manipulating direction you felt her pain and sorrow as she suffers from grief and the enforced poverty but keeps her determination and spirit. There is a theme of the rewards of charity and kindness, that if keep those attitudes and do not the world grind you then your good deals will be acknowledged. It is story about a girl needs to keep her determination, hope, kindness and imaginable that strength of friendship. I personally love Cuaron as a director, especially for his work on Harry Potter and Children of Men. With A Little Princess he was in full manipulation mode and it very much like a Spielberg film in the emotional scenes to more comically toned involving the girls causing mischief, playing jokes to a scene where the bully of school is 'cursed' and sees the outcome of it. Unfortunately because of the The art direction and cinematography are striking and fitting for the themes of the film, that India is a bright, colourful wondrous place, to the more harsh, cold reality of the street of New York in the winter. Peter Doyle's score added to getting the audience sunk into this world, using Indian music, a traditional score, a choir and a song sung by a young girl. A Little Princess is an orphan story similar in the vain of Oliver Twist, Annie and The Matchstick Girl, a young girl forced into the big bad city. Like Annie and The Matchstick Girl Sara is forced into servitude and the emotional scenes on the streets was very much like The Matchstick Girl. Because of the boarding school setting and Sara's background it is clear why Cuaron was a sensible choice to take on Harry Potter. A big criticism is the setting. The film changes the location from London to New York to cater to American auditions (seeing that the film flopped in America that change was pointless) and the time from the Victorian era to 1914. By changing it to 1914 it made the scenario less believable, that Sara becomes slave labour when she should would be education and child labour is still being used when in most Western countries had at this point introduced some sort of compulsory education. A Little Princess truly is a family film, children of all ages will find something to enjoy in this whimsical film. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Alfonso Cuaron best film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    haterofcrap
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was such a beautiful film. It is one of the best kids movies ever made, and it is also the best movie directed by Alfonso Cuaron, a very good movie director (Despite the fact that sometimes he made bad movies such as "Y tu Mama Tambi&eacute;n") This version was a much better adaptation than the 1939 (Which is a very good film, but honestly I think this was a better adaptation of the book) This film had the heart in the right place, and captures perfectly all the emotion and beauty from the book. It has an excellent visual style, the music and the performances were quite good too. I loved this movie. I wish there were more kid's films like this. I highly recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Princess (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin Teller
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the book, but I have read outraged IMDb comments from fans of it. Some of the comments seem delusional, but there are some that sound like legitimate gripes. Certainly the ending is far too easy... not for children perhaps, but for me it felt cheap. And the pathology of the wicked headmistress is only hinted at, but never explored and as a result she just comes off like a one-dimensional evil bitch. But there's a lot of delight to be had in the movie. As with PRISONER OF AZKABAN, Cuaron demonstrates a masterful sense of style and ability to craft a tale that's enjoyable for the kids and also engaging for the grown-ups. The set design and color palette is gorgeous, and young Liesel Matthews is endearing in the lead. I also enjoyed the Indian flights of fancy and the general spirit of the thing. Despite some missteps, a charming little picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Princess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n (Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban, Children of Men), I had seen the trailer for this film many times and always been curious to try the film, especially with it being rated the full five out of five stars, so when it was available I watched enthusiastically. Basically eleven year old Sara Crewe (introducing Liesel Matthews) and her wealthy father Capt. Crewe (Liam Cunningham) leave their home in India and move to New York, and he leaves her in an all girls boarding school while he enlists in the British Army. The school is run by the severe Miss Minchin (Eleanor Bron), and soon enough the bored and mundane lives of the girls are made better by Sara who becomes popular with her stories of "The Ramayana", much to the dislike of Miss Minchin and the irritation of spoilt bully Lavinia (Taylor Fry). After throwing a lavish birthday party, in which Miss Minchin wanted to extract money from Sara's father, word reaches them that he has apparently died in action, and with his estate seized by the British government the headmistress forces the innocent little girl to become a servant, alongside black servant Becky (The Lost World: Jurassic Park's Vanessa Lee Chester). Forced to stop telling stories and have her possessions, including her father's locket, taken from her, Sara only has her spirits lifted with the girls being on her side and helping her however they can, and with her belief that "every girl is a princess". Next door to the school is the mansion of rich old Charles Randolph (Arthur Malet) who wants his son to return from the war, and an injured soldier is brought to his home, it is not his son, but Capt. Crewe, suffering temporary blindness and memory loss, but Indian immigrant Ram Dass (Errol Sitahal) insists he be taken care of. One night Miss Minchin catches the other girls with Sara telling stories, and she punishes her and Becky with no food the next night, but they awaken to find a feast and palace setting, they originally imagined it, courtesy of Ram Dass. After Miss Minchin finds this she decides the police should be involved, because of possible stealing, and using a long plank Sara makes her escape across to Randolph's mansion next door. It is there she obviously is shocked and happy to see her father alive, but he does not recognise her, and Miss Minchin cruelly says that she has no family to get her away from him, but Ram Dass helps him remember and rescue her. In the end, Capt. Crewe has his fortune restored and buys himself the boarding school as the new headmaster and to make life for the girls much better, Miss Minchin is forced to be a chimney sweep alongside a young boy she originally mistreated, and Sara and Becky are going back to India together to live happily ever after, and all the girls, including Lavinia, saying their tearful goodbyes. Also starring Rusty Schwimmer as Amelia Minchin, Heather DeLoach as Ermengarde, Vincent Schiavelli as Mr. Barrow, The Ring's Rachael Bella as Betsy, The Lost World: Jurassic Park's Camilla Belle as Jane and Kelsey Mulrooney as Lottie. Matthews is wonderful as the imaginative and sweet young girl with her good spirit pushed to the limit, and Bron is fantastically vulgar as the subtly but equally knowingly evil (like Nurse Ratched style) villain headmistress, it is charming story with plenty of delightful and sweet moments, as well as true emotion, and the special effects give us moments in a surreal magical world, and it is a film that will appeal both to the adults and the children watching, a brilliant period fantasy drama. It was nominated the Oscars for Best Art Direction-Set Decoration and Best Cinematography. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not MY Little Princess, but better than Shirley Temple
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Left-Handed_Liz
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I hesitated in seeing this film for a very long time. I wasn't aware of it when it was in theaters, and I adored the book so much, and the BBC-produced miniseries starring Amelia Shankley, that I didn't want to ruin my image of the book by seeing a Hollywoodized adaptation, even into my teens. However, I'll try anything once, and the number of fans that it seems to have made me think that it might not be so bad. And it really isn't. Compared to a lot of live- action "family entertainment," which can be obnoxious and formulaic, it's exquisite. The cinematography is lush and warmly lit (perhaps a little too warm, when it comes to depicting Sara's somewhat gloomy life in poverty), and what the studio was able to do with such a small budget is more than some people could do with ten million to spend on a movie- ironic, considering the theme of wealth, or lack thereof. I found myself really warming up to the film's focus on the relationship between Sara and her father as they struggled to carry on in the midst of two very different sets of trials, as well as the emphasis on Sara's childhood in India, such as the "Ramayana" fantasy sequences, and the sitars reverberating alongside the more classical instruments on the soundtrack. The acting was at least passable throughout, though it sometimes veered into community theater-level skill. Even Liesel Matthews gave an endearing performance as Sara- certainly less stoicism and solemnity than the original, but thankfully with none of the dimple-faced pouting of the 1937 Shirley Temple film, which I couldn't stand for more than the first 30 minutes. At least Matthews's Sara is a real storyteller, and has the presence of one, rather than arbitrarily pretending things for her own amusement. The bad news is that, while a significant improvement on the aforementioned Little Princess "adaptation," this movie is nonetheless an Americanized version of a classic British children's novel, and its roots definitely show as a stereotypically Hollywood effort. Namely, since the screenplay resets the story in America- I suppose to make it more relatable to stateside audiences- it also deems it necessary to put "spunk" into a character who is supposed to be tenacious, but reserved, even having her occasionally talk back and pull pranks. Thankfully, this never goes into Home Alone territory, but is very uncharacteristic of someone who strives to behave like a princess. Finally, there is the much-maligned happy ending pulled straight from the Temple version, which I only had a problem with because it was too over-the-top, where most of the time, the movie had the sense to pull back and have an occasional reflective moment. To make a very, very long story short: Not my favorite, has no nostalgia attached to it for me, but I can accept it, and even enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really a spoiler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironmn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just wanted to say, that i enjoyed this film a lot, but at the end i was fuming mad and shouting at the TV. i was livid that all that Sarah went through it would have been fantastic that as her father was hugging her she turned just as the miss minchin was walking away Sarah turns and shouts she has stolen my locket and then the police go inside and find it and on opening it you see the fathers picture, and then the police drag the screaming miss minchin away in front of the rest of the school. then it would be a satisfying end, i would been shouting, yes you rotten cow now you will get what you deserve. So just wanted to vent this as I've just finished watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All Girls Are Princesses!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anastasia-cessano-writes
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is wonderful! I am 13 almost 14 years old and I still watch this movie regularly! I watched it so much the DVD messed up and I had to buy a new one! I HAVE read the book, and at the time I liked the book, but then I watched this-and I was blown away! This movie is a perfect example of a kids' movie that isn't horrible garbage without being overly intense. I have to admit, this is quit different from the book, but who really CARES? Sara (Liesel Matthews) is a thoughtful, smart, sweet child, not spoiled and stupidly cheerful like Shirley Temple's version. Oh no! She IS a little princess! And her father (Liam Cunningham) is so devoted and loving! But the best acted part of this entire movie has to go to: Eleanor Bron (yes, the lady in Help, and Wimbledon!!) as Miss Minchin! She was an amazing evil woman but at the same time, you see that she has never been loved and that's why she's so HEARTLESS! I believe that woman should have won an Oscar for this! And Cuaron's directing is unbelievably great! Seriously, go see this film. If you hate it, email me at anastasia.cessano.writes@aol.com with your complaints.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an absolute piece of .....(you supply the negative words ) of a movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    melee-3
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    an absolute waste of time and money....... if one is going to see a film .... do the smart thing and get the Shirley Temple movie. My girlfriend had NEVER seen OLD movies before meeting me. She'd seen the Mummy and I introduced her to the old Boris Karloff 1932 movie. She saw the Jackie Chan piece of crap Around the World in 80 Days, so I showed her the 1956 movie. She saw the Harrison Ford Sabrina and then the Bogart, Hepburn, Holden movie. The pathetic Eddie Murphy The Nutty Professor was watched by her some time in the past, so I found the 1963 Jerry Lewis movie for her. Need I say that the old one was the one appreciated more in each case? (I could have listed more, like Belushi vs Bogart (Sahara) or War of the Worlds 2005 vs 1953...and several others like The Seven Samurai vs The Magnificent 7) The next thing to find is a Rat Pack Ocean's 11 for her :) Most remakes of a story line do NOT live up to the older one..... and this A Little Princess is probably the second worst remake I have ever seen. Jackie Chan's Around the World in 80 Days is the only remake I can think of that tops this one in terms of patheticness
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thrwmbsbgkdoepmcjrmrdw
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a good film, but different from the book. It's been a while since I've read the book, or until today seen the movie. It's well acted for the most part. I thought the father didn't do that great of a job. But other than him well acted, we directed, well put together. I do have a question though. How is it possible to regain your memory in two seconds like the father did? That part I don't get. I liked how dark they made the head mistress staying true to the character of her. And I love that they made her a sweeper at the end. Good punishment. The sister was probably my favorite with her love affair with the milkman. Very charming and cute. I really enjoyed the movie and would recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hiddenags
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before I begin I'd like to say I have not read the original "A Little Princess" and maybe one day in the future I shall read it. However this movie generally moved me. I'm not the type that usually gets emotional over movies but this movie is exceptional. The main role of Sara Crewe is played by Liesel Matthews, a really cute young girl (in this movie anyway), although her acting skills aren't great , she really gets the message across. The music of the movie is also beautifully crafted and co-ordinates with the movie really well. I recommend you watch this movie and please keep an open mind. ***WARNING*** This movie may be a bit "girly"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A whimsical family film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Alfonso Cuaron's adaptation of A Little Princess is a film filled with magically realism, whimsy and sickly sweetness. It is a popular film for young girls and women for these reasons. In 1914 Britain has entered into the First World War. Sara Crewe (Liesel Matthews) is a British girl (even though she has an American accent), living in India. She is a kind-hearted girl with a big imagine, intelligence and a keen storyteller. When her father (Liam Cunningham) is called up to serve in the war, Sara is sent to the same boarding school her descended mother went to, the Miss Minchin's Seminary for Girls in New York. Sara quickly becomes a popular girl at the school because of her wit, storytelling and willingness to stand up wrongdoing. But when her father is declared killed in action Sara's wealth is taken away and the crude hearted headmistress (Eleanor Bron) makes Sara into a servant girl. Despite Sara's grief she sets out to keep her dignity and her charitable spirit. A Little Princess was weighted around a strong performance from a talented young actress, Matthews. She gave a heart felt performance and mixed with Cuaron's emotionally manipulating direction you felt her pain and sorrow as she suffers from grief and the enforced poverty but keeps her determination and spirit. There is a theme of the rewards of charity and kindness, that if keep those attitudes and do not the world grind you then your good deals will be acknowledged. It is story about a girl needs to keep her determination, hope, kindness and imaginable that strength of friendship. I personally love Cuaron as a director, especially for his work on Harry Potter and Children of Men. With A Little Princess he was in full manipulation mode and it very much like a Spielberg film in the emotional scenes to more comically toned involving the girls causing mischief, playing jokes to a scene where the bully of school is 'cursed' and sees the outcome of it. Unfortunately because of the The art direction and cinematography are striking and fitting for the themes of the film, that India is a bright, colourful wondrous place, to the more harsh, cold reality of the street of New York in the winter. Peter Doyle's score added to getting the audience sunk into this world, using Indian music, a traditional score, a choir and a song sung by a young girl. A Little Princess is an orphan story similar in the vain of Oliver Twist, Annie and The Matchstick Girl, a young girl forced into the big bad city. Like Annie and The Matchstick Girl Sara is forced into servitude and the emotional scenes on the streets was very much like The Matchstick Girl. Because of the boarding school setting and Sara's background it is clear why Cuaron was a sensible choice to take on Harry Potter. A big criticism is the setting. The film changes the location from London to New York to cater to American auditions (seeing that the film flopped in America that change was pointless) and the time from the Victorian era to 1914. By changing it to 1914 it made the scenario less believable, that Sara becomes slave labour when she should would be education and child labour is still being used when in most Western countries had at this point introduced some sort of compulsory education. A Little Princess truly is a family film, children of all ages will find something to enjoy in this whimsical film. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Alfonso Cuaron best film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    haterofcrap
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was such a beautiful film. It is one of the best kids movies ever made, and it is also the best movie directed by Alfonso Cuaron, a very good movie director (Despite the fact that sometimes he made bad movies such as "Y tu Mama Tambi&eacute;n") This version was a much better adaptation than the 1939 (Which is a very good film, but honestly I think this was a better adaptation of the book) This film had the heart in the right place, and captures perfectly all the emotion and beauty from the book. It has an excellent visual style, the music and the performances were quite good too. I loved this movie. I wish there were more kid's films like this. I highly recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Princess (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin Teller
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the book, but I have read outraged IMDb comments from fans of it. Some of the comments seem delusional, but there are some that sound like legitimate gripes. Certainly the ending is far too easy... not for children perhaps, but for me it felt cheap. And the pathology of the wicked headmistress is only hinted at, but never explored and as a result she just comes off like a one-dimensional evil bitch. But there's a lot of delight to be had in the movie. As with PRISONER OF AZKABAN, Cuaron demonstrates a masterful sense of style and ability to craft a tale that's enjoyable for the kids and also engaging for the grown-ups. The set design and color palette is gorgeous, and young Liesel Matthews is endearing in the lead. I also enjoyed the Indian flights of fancy and the general spirit of the thing. Despite some missteps, a charming little picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Princess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n (Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban, Children of Men), I had seen the trailer for this film many times and always been curious to try the film, especially with it being rated the full five out of five stars, so when it was available I watched enthusiastically. Basically eleven year old Sara Crewe (introducing Liesel Matthews) and her wealthy father Capt. Crewe (Liam Cunningham) leave their home in India and move to New York, and he leaves her in an all girls boarding school while he enlists in the British Army. The school is run by the severe Miss Minchin (Eleanor Bron), and soon enough the bored and mundane lives of the girls are made better by Sara who becomes popular with her stories of "The Ramayana", much to the dislike of Miss Minchin and the irritation of spoilt bully Lavinia (Taylor Fry). After throwing a lavish birthday party, in which Miss Minchin wanted to extract money from Sara's father, word reaches them that he has apparently died in action, and with his estate seized by the British government the headmistress forces the innocent little girl to become a servant, alongside black servant Becky (The Lost World: Jurassic Park's Vanessa Lee Chester). Forced to stop telling stories and have her possessions, including her father's locket, taken from her, Sara only has her spirits lifted with the girls being on her side and helping her however they can, and with her belief that "every girl is a princess". Next door to the school is the mansion of rich old Charles Randolph (Arthur Malet) who wants his son to return from the war, and an injured soldier is brought to his home, it is not his son, but Capt. Crewe, suffering temporary blindness and memory loss, but Indian immigrant Ram Dass (Errol Sitahal) insists he be taken care of. One night Miss Minchin catches the other girls with Sara telling stories, and she punishes her and Becky with no food the next night, but they awaken to find a feast and palace setting, they originally imagined it, courtesy of Ram Dass. After Miss Minchin finds this she decides the police should be involved, because of possible stealing, and using a long plank Sara makes her escape across to Randolph's mansion next door. It is there she obviously is shocked and happy to see her father alive, but he does not recognise her, and Miss Minchin cruelly says that she has no family to get her away from him, but Ram Dass helps him remember and rescue her. In the end, Capt. Crewe has his fortune restored and buys himself the boarding school as the new headmaster and to make life for the girls much better, Miss Minchin is forced to be a chimney sweep alongside a young boy she originally mistreated, and Sara and Becky are going back to India together to live happily ever after, and all the girls, including Lavinia, saying their tearful goodbyes. Also starring Rusty Schwimmer as Amelia Minchin, Heather DeLoach as Ermengarde, Vincent Schiavelli as Mr. Barrow, The Ring's Rachael Bella as Betsy, The Lost World: Jurassic Park's Camilla Belle as Jane and Kelsey Mulrooney as Lottie. Matthews is wonderful as the imaginative and sweet young girl with her good spirit pushed to the limit, and Bron is fantastically vulgar as the subtly but equally knowingly evil (like Nurse Ratched style) villain headmistress, it is charming story with plenty of delightful and sweet moments, as well as true emotion, and the special effects give us moments in a surreal magical world, and it is a film that will appeal both to the adults and the children watching, a brilliant period fantasy drama. It was nominated the Oscars for Best Art Direction-Set Decoration and Best Cinematography. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not MY Little Princess, but better than Shirley Temple
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Left-Handed_Liz
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I hesitated in seeing this film for a very long time. I wasn't aware of it when it was in theaters, and I adored the book so much, and the BBC-produced miniseries starring Amelia Shankley, that I didn't want to ruin my image of the book by seeing a Hollywoodized adaptation, even into my teens. However, I'll try anything once, and the number of fans that it seems to have made me think that it might not be so bad. And it really isn't. Compared to a lot of live- action "family entertainment," which can be obnoxious and formulaic, it's exquisite. The cinematography is lush and warmly lit (perhaps a little too warm, when it comes to depicting Sara's somewhat gloomy life in poverty), and what the studio was able to do with such a small budget is more than some people could do with ten million to spend on a movie- ironic, considering the theme of wealth, or lack thereof. I found myself really warming up to the film's focus on the relationship between Sara and her father as they struggled to carry on in the midst of two very different sets of trials, as well as the emphasis on Sara's childhood in India, such as the "Ramayana" fantasy sequences, and the sitars reverberating alongside the more classical instruments on the soundtrack. The acting was at least passable throughout, though it sometimes veered into community theater-level skill. Even Liesel Matthews gave an endearing performance as Sara- certainly less stoicism and solemnity than the original, but thankfully with none of the dimple-faced pouting of the 1937 Shirley Temple film, which I couldn't stand for more than the first 30 minutes. At least Matthews's Sara is a real storyteller, and has the presence of one, rather than arbitrarily pretending things for her own amusement. The bad news is that, while a significant improvement on the aforementioned Little Princess "adaptation," this movie is nonetheless an Americanized version of a classic British children's novel, and its roots definitely show as a stereotypically Hollywood effort. Namely, since the screenplay resets the story in America- I suppose to make it more relatable to stateside audiences- it also deems it necessary to put "spunk" into a character who is supposed to be tenacious, but reserved, even having her occasionally talk back and pull pranks. Thankfully, this never goes into Home Alone territory, but is very uncharacteristic of someone who strives to behave like a princess. Finally, there is the much-maligned happy ending pulled straight from the Temple version, which I only had a problem with because it was too over-the-top, where most of the time, the movie had the sense to pull back and have an occasional reflective moment. To make a very, very long story short: Not my favorite, has no nostalgia attached to it for me, but I can accept it, and even enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really a spoiler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironmn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just wanted to say, that i enjoyed this film a lot, but at the end i was fuming mad and shouting at the TV. i was livid that all that Sarah went through it would have been fantastic that as her father was hugging her she turned just as the miss minchin was walking away Sarah turns and shouts she has stolen my locket and then the police go inside and find it and on opening it you see the fathers picture, and then the police drag the screaming miss minchin away in front of the rest of the school. then it would be a satisfying end, i would been shouting, yes you rotten cow now you will get what you deserve. So just wanted to vent this as I've just finished watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All Girls Are Princesses!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anastasia-cessano-writes
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is wonderful! I am 13 almost 14 years old and I still watch this movie regularly! I watched it so much the DVD messed up and I had to buy a new one! I HAVE read the book, and at the time I liked the book, but then I watched this-and I was blown away! This movie is a perfect example of a kids' movie that isn't horrible garbage without being overly intense. I have to admit, this is quit different from the book, but who really CARES? Sara (Liesel Matthews) is a thoughtful, smart, sweet child, not spoiled and stupidly cheerful like Shirley Temple's version. Oh no! She IS a little princess! And her father (Liam Cunningham) is so devoted and loving! But the best acted part of this entire movie has to go to: Eleanor Bron (yes, the lady in Help, and Wimbledon!!) as Miss Minchin! She was an amazing evil woman but at the same time, you see that she has never been loved and that's why she's so HEARTLESS! I believe that woman should have won an Oscar for this! And Cuaron's directing is unbelievably great! Seriously, go see this film. If you hate it, email me at anastasia.cessano.writes@aol.com with your complaints.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an absolute piece of .....(you supply the negative words ) of a movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    melee-3
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    an absolute waste of time and money....... if one is going to see a film .... do the smart thing and get the Shirley Temple movie. My girlfriend had NEVER seen OLD movies before meeting me. She'd seen the Mummy and I introduced her to the old Boris Karloff 1932 movie. She saw the Jackie Chan piece of crap Around the World in 80 Days, so I showed her the 1956 movie. She saw the Harrison Ford Sabrina and then the Bogart, Hepburn, Holden movie. The pathetic Eddie Murphy The Nutty Professor was watched by her some time in the past, so I found the 1963 Jerry Lewis movie for her. Need I say that the old one was the one appreciated more in each case? (I could have listed more, like Belushi vs Bogart (Sahara) or War of the Worlds 2005 vs 1953...and several others like The Seven Samurai vs The Magnificent 7) The next thing to find is a Rat Pack Ocean's 11 for her :) Most remakes of a story line do NOT live up to the older one..... and this A Little Princess is probably the second worst remake I have ever seen. Jackie Chan's Around the World in 80 Days is the only remake I can think of that tops this one in terms of patheticness
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
