<filme>
 <id>
  1069
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109093
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Amateur
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Isabelle is an ex-nun waiting for her special mission from God. In the meantime, she is making a living writing pornography. She meets Thomas, a sweet, confused amnesiac who cannot remember... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Isabelle is an ex-nun waiting for her special mission from God. In the meantime, she is making a living writing pornography. She meets Thomas, a sweet, confused amnesiac who cannot remember that he used to be a vicious pornographer, responsible for turning his young wife, Sofia, into the world's most notorious porn queen. Sofia's on the run, convinced she's killed him. Together, Isabelle and Thomas set out to discover his past, a past waiting to catch up with him.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   pornographer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   torture
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   amnesia
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   female nudity
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   new york city
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Hal Hartley
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Hal Hartley
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Isabelle Huppert
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Martin Donovan
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Elina L&ouml;wensohn
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Killed My DVD Player!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark L. Kahnt
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe Isabelle Huppert rubs me the wrong way, maybe trying to do European work in an American context confused the crew and writers, maybe the cast and director realised that this just wasn't going to connect for most people, but it proved unwatchable for me. I'd try it for a while, and then go back to channel hopping. The DVD, which I bought at a liquidation store, sat in the player for three months, watching a chapter here, a chapter there, until I got into the eighth chapter. I elected to bite my tongue and watch the rest, finding myself pushed away further by acting that just did not seem to be trying or allowed to try, from actors that I have seen do much better. In the end, the player would no longer open, possibly fearing that others may have to see the movie. Much of the cinema I seek out is European, not in English, with writing and concepts of depth. I watch and enjoy art movies, great films that explore people, concepts, relations, but that is not what this was for me. It reminded me of what someone trying to live the concept of The Producers would do - irrelevant and unbelievable dialogue, a gunfight that belongs in Police Squad, and characters that are almost universally unsympathetic - except the missing persons officer who aspires to make up for all the rest. I laughed at the production that seemed to have been asking the cast to weaken their performances, a presentation that increasingly seemed like theatresports without the humour as the rendition gave up in even believing the movie would work. I'm sorry, but this is closer to Plan 9 from Outer Space and Spaceballs than it is to Kolya or L'Ennui.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So so so so so so so so so so so so boring boring and slow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danielle_m_d
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Completely flat, unfathomably long, completely unwatchable. Nondimensional characters deliver trite deadpan lines and it I'm supposed to think its brilliant and funny? This movie had almost nothing in it that was genuinely amusing. It had anti-stereotypes like accountant-torturers that wouldn't sustain a SNL sketch let alone what felt like a 16 hour movie. It wasn't sexy or smart. There wasn't one likable character (if you could argue that this film had characters), and for the most part there was no plot, nothing at all to keep you interested. If I hadn't agreed to watch it, I would have turned it off during every scene. I just don't get the joke. Is the film-loving community so desiccated by ennui that they adore a film that shakes its angry fist at the concept of being entertaining?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Words fail me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernie-122
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am ashamed to admit that I have only just discovered Hal Hartley. Fortunately, not too late, as I think I still have enough time remaining on this planet to hunt up and watch all of his other films. I'm getting a real chuckle out of reading all the one-star reviews here by people who just don't "get it". I don't blame them, really, but there should be some way of warning them not to do it; not to embarrass themselves by displaying their shallowness. If it's slick predigested Hollywood pap liberally peppered with explosions they're looking for, they're in the wrong place. Hal Hartley rules. If he's made better films than "Amateur" then I'm in for a real treat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misfire from Hal Hartley
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wonderfully aloof writer-director Hal Hartley hits a speedbump with this heavy-handed comic oddity about eccentrics, losers and assorted misfits. Isabelle Huppert plays a former nun who is trying her hand at writing sexual fiction; Martin Donovan is an amnesiac (groan) she picks up in a diner. Hartley, who had his biggest success with this formula via 1991's dryly goofy and charming "Trust", is too self-conscious this time out, and the results are twee. Several funny lines cannot compensate for an ugly look and an overall lack of interest in these characters. Supporting cast of crazies includes Parker Posey, but "Amateur" skirts a dead-eyed blandness at every turn. * from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Off-beat, funny drama from a true original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LouE15
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hal Hartley is just my all-out favourite auteur director, brought me through my teens and helped form my world view. When he makes a film you're in for something that is at the very least interesting, and at best, moves you, creates a new world out of the one you're already in, shows you the art in life. That sounds pretentious and some might think his films are too; but that's just the knee-jerk effect that comes with overexposure to rubbish presented as if it's art. But one good Hal Hartley film cures a soul wearied with too much dross. "Amateur" is up there with "Trust" and "The Unbelievable Truth" if you have any time at all for films which are off-kilter, intelligent and which depart from the linear norm. They're also very funny, in a low-key way. His actors are usually regulars, skilled at his unique, poetic and rhythmic script style. His America is intriguing, a place painted with the eye of a true original, and presented with a rigour entirely absent from many more recent so-called independent American films. Another reviewer here noted the strong European flavour in his work; this is quite right; and if you enjoy a varied experience of film I can't see how you wouldn't like his best. The plot of "Amateur" is crazy and contorted, like a dance, with a fascinating premise and a weird logic of its own. Martin Donovan here is Hartley's muse; he perfectly captures the rapid, deadpan delivery and manages to be charming and mysterious, dangerous and vulnerable with minimal changes in expression. Why his career has stayed largely small-scale is beyond me. Perhaps he goes about his work too quietly; perhaps his jaw isn't chiselled enough, I don't know. But Isabelle Huppert is outstanding as the struggling porn writer fresh out of the convent. Says her scumbag-with-a-heart publisher of her attempts: "The problem is, it's quitebad. It's poetry, and don't you try and deny it." And it is poetry; heartbreakingly so. She looks out at the strange world, uniquely innocent, with her big, solemn eyes, and you instinctively feel with her, and wish her a knight to watch over her. And of course, this being Hal Hartley's world, her protector arrives, uniquely flawed. He could be Grandma; or he could be the Wolf. Excellent, good-looking and intriguing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a must see
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    delirious_angel
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its been a while since I've this movie but its always stayed with me and I would strongly recommend it. This film has Hal Hartley's trademark sparse, artsy atmosphere, with the slightly surreal characters, the staged dialogue and set pieces. All the characters are quirky and memorable, I loved Isabelle Huppert's character - the nymphomanical nun - in particular and the story dissects amnesia in a really interesting way. Above all the central love story will draw you in more than you realise; the ending was both crushing and fitting. This is due to the acting, as every movement and expression helps to build characters and relationships. Isabelle Huppert and Martin Donovan both do this perfectly, and the impact of the ending owes a lot to them. The odd 'staging' of the film may put off those expecting a more conventional thriller but open minded viewers will be rewarded.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film school pap: amateurish, tedious, fake.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyeseehot
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Characters and story dreamed up by an auteur without imagination. Fake to the bone. No relation to life. Dialog pretentiously abstract, meant to be funny but isn't. Caricatured characters can sometimes be fun--see Dr. Strangelove--but the caricature has to grow from a sense of life. This is so airless, so film-schooly, watching it is like trying to breathe in a vacuum. An ex-nun nymphomaniac, so she says, who has not had sex because "I'm choosy", and a porn star, some gangsters, etc., adds up to a labored, dead, badly acted pseudo movie. I watched it because of all the good comments, so I'm warning those with ears to hear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Two complete lives lasting few days
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    przgzr
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a surprising movie. It's more crime genre than you expect with Isabelle Huppert in cast, but much more French style than you expect from American director. First part of the movie was Chabrol-like (and it's a complement), second is more action but far from modern American action movies (that I don't like). This change is well made, it has reasons according to the development of the plot. *** spoilers, including end of movie !! *** The movie shows a few days that make a whole life for two main characters. Isabelle was lethargic, almost in a hibernation, living in a nunnery and later waiting for things to happen; now she feels she found the purpose of her existence, to fulfill the task she has been given by Holy Virgin, and starts living. At the end of the movie she succeeded in doing it, her possible lover is killed, she is left empty and seems emotionally dead. For Thomas the situation is even more extreme: suffering complete amnesia it's as if he was born on the beginning of the movie, and (physically) dies at the end. His death is absurd: though he was a criminal, ruining many lives, he is punished for crimes he (because of amnesia) doesn't even know he did. And it makes this execution as pointless as in Easy Rider or Blue Soldier. Photography was better indoors than outdoors (restaurant in the beginning, Sofia and the rose, or empty room where Edward was tortured); good camera angles in country house when Edward looks for Thomas. In a border-reality movie like this some use of slow-motion or Hamilton-like soft photo could be expected, but maybe it would look to much like a dream (Isabelle) or nightmare (Thomas), or too profane, so the director didn't do it. Interesting use of carefully chosen objects, like a lamp in empty room: it seems to be the guy's only possession in a place he uses to make love, and now it is used for violence, for torturing. * spoilers-free part * I don't know how many people will enjoy this movie. It's not like old French crime movies (Delon, Belmondo, Ventura) or modern American action movies, so if you expect it, be careful. Maybe you'll like it, I did. But I like Chabrol and old film-noir movies, so if you're closer to my taste, and if you prefer visual beauty and mood instead of action and dynamic change of scenes, this could be a movie for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of those movies after which you shake your head and say bemusedly, "Wow."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jj9675
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hal Hartley where have you been all my movie-loving life? This was the sort of movie-watching experience which required my calling my best friend and telling her about it, as I would any noteworthy experience. Yes, the ending was dismal... yet perfect! So much about redemption: This was clear if one remembers Thomas's feet at the beginning of the movie, and then Thomas's feet at the end. At that point, I saw the (one of) point to the story. I enjoyed the clipped dialogue, the clarity, AND the ironic absurdity. The story was not meant to be reality-driven, but limited to the raison d'etre of Thomas and the other characters: as in a dream, but not. Discovering it was a marvelous channel-surfing accident. Now I must do a search on Hal Hartley. Check out his portfolio, so to speak. Rating 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Abstract Porn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hartley is one of the most interesting directors working. Many associate him with French intuitives, but I think his experiments are more intellectual, more New York. His films are not only about other films, but exist in a world abstracted from them where almost everyone else insists on wallowing in the same space they reference. This is still an early work, which I had the opportunity to see with its purported referent: 'Band of Outsiders.' Writing as a fulcrum; performance as porn; film humor as a selfaware deadpan. Sex as an abstract creation. Pain as an act. Huppert as walking hair, early Posey on her way to Jackie K. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Killed My DVD Player!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark L. Kahnt
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe Isabelle Huppert rubs me the wrong way, maybe trying to do European work in an American context confused the crew and writers, maybe the cast and director realised that this just wasn't going to connect for most people, but it proved unwatchable for me. I'd try it for a while, and then go back to channel hopping. The DVD, which I bought at a liquidation store, sat in the player for three months, watching a chapter here, a chapter there, until I got into the eighth chapter. I elected to bite my tongue and watch the rest, finding myself pushed away further by acting that just did not seem to be trying or allowed to try, from actors that I have seen do much better. In the end, the player would no longer open, possibly fearing that others may have to see the movie. Much of the cinema I seek out is European, not in English, with writing and concepts of depth. I watch and enjoy art movies, great films that explore people, concepts, relations, but that is not what this was for me. It reminded me of what someone trying to live the concept of The Producers would do - irrelevant and unbelievable dialogue, a gunfight that belongs in Police Squad, and characters that are almost universally unsympathetic - except the missing persons officer who aspires to make up for all the rest. I laughed at the production that seemed to have been asking the cast to weaken their performances, a presentation that increasingly seemed like theatresports without the humour as the rendition gave up in even believing the movie would work. I'm sorry, but this is closer to Plan 9 from Outer Space and Spaceballs than it is to Kolya or L'Ennui.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So so so so so so so so so so so so boring boring and slow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danielle_m_d
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Completely flat, unfathomably long, completely unwatchable. Nondimensional characters deliver trite deadpan lines and it I'm supposed to think its brilliant and funny? This movie had almost nothing in it that was genuinely amusing. It had anti-stereotypes like accountant-torturers that wouldn't sustain a SNL sketch let alone what felt like a 16 hour movie. It wasn't sexy or smart. There wasn't one likable character (if you could argue that this film had characters), and for the most part there was no plot, nothing at all to keep you interested. If I hadn't agreed to watch it, I would have turned it off during every scene. I just don't get the joke. Is the film-loving community so desiccated by ennui that they adore a film that shakes its angry fist at the concept of being entertaining?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Words fail me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernie-122
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am ashamed to admit that I have only just discovered Hal Hartley. Fortunately, not too late, as I think I still have enough time remaining on this planet to hunt up and watch all of his other films. I'm getting a real chuckle out of reading all the one-star reviews here by people who just don't "get it". I don't blame them, really, but there should be some way of warning them not to do it; not to embarrass themselves by displaying their shallowness. If it's slick predigested Hollywood pap liberally peppered with explosions they're looking for, they're in the wrong place. Hal Hartley rules. If he's made better films than "Amateur" then I'm in for a real treat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misfire from Hal Hartley
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wonderfully aloof writer-director Hal Hartley hits a speedbump with this heavy-handed comic oddity about eccentrics, losers and assorted misfits. Isabelle Huppert plays a former nun who is trying her hand at writing sexual fiction; Martin Donovan is an amnesiac (groan) she picks up in a diner. Hartley, who had his biggest success with this formula via 1991's dryly goofy and charming "Trust", is too self-conscious this time out, and the results are twee. Several funny lines cannot compensate for an ugly look and an overall lack of interest in these characters. Supporting cast of crazies includes Parker Posey, but "Amateur" skirts a dead-eyed blandness at every turn. * from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Off-beat, funny drama from a true original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LouE15
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hal Hartley is just my all-out favourite auteur director, brought me through my teens and helped form my world view. When he makes a film you're in for something that is at the very least interesting, and at best, moves you, creates a new world out of the one you're already in, shows you the art in life. That sounds pretentious and some might think his films are too; but that's just the knee-jerk effect that comes with overexposure to rubbish presented as if it's art. But one good Hal Hartley film cures a soul wearied with too much dross. "Amateur" is up there with "Trust" and "The Unbelievable Truth" if you have any time at all for films which are off-kilter, intelligent and which depart from the linear norm. They're also very funny, in a low-key way. His actors are usually regulars, skilled at his unique, poetic and rhythmic script style. His America is intriguing, a place painted with the eye of a true original, and presented with a rigour entirely absent from many more recent so-called independent American films. Another reviewer here noted the strong European flavour in his work; this is quite right; and if you enjoy a varied experience of film I can't see how you wouldn't like his best. The plot of "Amateur" is crazy and contorted, like a dance, with a fascinating premise and a weird logic of its own. Martin Donovan here is Hartley's muse; he perfectly captures the rapid, deadpan delivery and manages to be charming and mysterious, dangerous and vulnerable with minimal changes in expression. Why his career has stayed largely small-scale is beyond me. Perhaps he goes about his work too quietly; perhaps his jaw isn't chiselled enough, I don't know. But Isabelle Huppert is outstanding as the struggling porn writer fresh out of the convent. Says her scumbag-with-a-heart publisher of her attempts: "The problem is, it's quitebad. It's poetry, and don't you try and deny it." And it is poetry; heartbreakingly so. She looks out at the strange world, uniquely innocent, with her big, solemn eyes, and you instinctively feel with her, and wish her a knight to watch over her. And of course, this being Hal Hartley's world, her protector arrives, uniquely flawed. He could be Grandma; or he could be the Wolf. Excellent, good-looking and intriguing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a must see
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    delirious_angel
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its been a while since I've this movie but its always stayed with me and I would strongly recommend it. This film has Hal Hartley's trademark sparse, artsy atmosphere, with the slightly surreal characters, the staged dialogue and set pieces. All the characters are quirky and memorable, I loved Isabelle Huppert's character - the nymphomanical nun - in particular and the story dissects amnesia in a really interesting way. Above all the central love story will draw you in more than you realise; the ending was both crushing and fitting. This is due to the acting, as every movement and expression helps to build characters and relationships. Isabelle Huppert and Martin Donovan both do this perfectly, and the impact of the ending owes a lot to them. The odd 'staging' of the film may put off those expecting a more conventional thriller but open minded viewers will be rewarded.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film school pap: amateurish, tedious, fake.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyeseehot
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Characters and story dreamed up by an auteur without imagination. Fake to the bone. No relation to life. Dialog pretentiously abstract, meant to be funny but isn't. Caricatured characters can sometimes be fun--see Dr. Strangelove--but the caricature has to grow from a sense of life. This is so airless, so film-schooly, watching it is like trying to breathe in a vacuum. An ex-nun nymphomaniac, so she says, who has not had sex because "I'm choosy", and a porn star, some gangsters, etc., adds up to a labored, dead, badly acted pseudo movie. I watched it because of all the good comments, so I'm warning those with ears to hear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Two complete lives lasting few days
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    przgzr
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a surprising movie. It's more crime genre than you expect with Isabelle Huppert in cast, but much more French style than you expect from American director. First part of the movie was Chabrol-like (and it's a complement), second is more action but far from modern American action movies (that I don't like). This change is well made, it has reasons according to the development of the plot. *** spoilers, including end of movie !! *** The movie shows a few days that make a whole life for two main characters. Isabelle was lethargic, almost in a hibernation, living in a nunnery and later waiting for things to happen; now she feels she found the purpose of her existence, to fulfill the task she has been given by Holy Virgin, and starts living. At the end of the movie she succeeded in doing it, her possible lover is killed, she is left empty and seems emotionally dead. For Thomas the situation is even more extreme: suffering complete amnesia it's as if he was born on the beginning of the movie, and (physically) dies at the end. His death is absurd: though he was a criminal, ruining many lives, he is punished for crimes he (because of amnesia) doesn't even know he did. And it makes this execution as pointless as in Easy Rider or Blue Soldier. Photography was better indoors than outdoors (restaurant in the beginning, Sofia and the rose, or empty room where Edward was tortured); good camera angles in country house when Edward looks for Thomas. In a border-reality movie like this some use of slow-motion or Hamilton-like soft photo could be expected, but maybe it would look to much like a dream (Isabelle) or nightmare (Thomas), or too profane, so the director didn't do it. Interesting use of carefully chosen objects, like a lamp in empty room: it seems to be the guy's only possession in a place he uses to make love, and now it is used for violence, for torturing. * spoilers-free part * I don't know how many people will enjoy this movie. It's not like old French crime movies (Delon, Belmondo, Ventura) or modern American action movies, so if you expect it, be careful. Maybe you'll like it, I did. But I like Chabrol and old film-noir movies, so if you're closer to my taste, and if you prefer visual beauty and mood instead of action and dynamic change of scenes, this could be a movie for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of those movies after which you shake your head and say bemusedly, "Wow."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jj9675
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hal Hartley where have you been all my movie-loving life? This was the sort of movie-watching experience which required my calling my best friend and telling her about it, as I would any noteworthy experience. Yes, the ending was dismal... yet perfect! So much about redemption: This was clear if one remembers Thomas's feet at the beginning of the movie, and then Thomas's feet at the end. At that point, I saw the (one of) point to the story. I enjoyed the clipped dialogue, the clarity, AND the ironic absurdity. The story was not meant to be reality-driven, but limited to the raison d'etre of Thomas and the other characters: as in a dream, but not. Discovering it was a marvelous channel-surfing accident. Now I must do a search on Hal Hartley. Check out his portfolio, so to speak. Rating 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Abstract Porn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hartley is one of the most interesting directors working. Many associate him with French intuitives, but I think his experiments are more intellectual, more New York. His films are not only about other films, but exist in a world abstracted from them where almost everyone else insists on wallowing in the same space they reference. This is still an early work, which I had the opportunity to see with its purported referent: 'Band of Outsiders.' Writing as a fulcrum; performance as porn; film humor as a selfaware deadpan. Sex as an abstract creation. Pain as an act. Huppert as walking hair, early Posey on her way to Jackie K. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Killed My DVD Player!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark L. Kahnt
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe Isabelle Huppert rubs me the wrong way, maybe trying to do European work in an American context confused the crew and writers, maybe the cast and director realised that this just wasn't going to connect for most people, but it proved unwatchable for me. I'd try it for a while, and then go back to channel hopping. The DVD, which I bought at a liquidation store, sat in the player for three months, watching a chapter here, a chapter there, until I got into the eighth chapter. I elected to bite my tongue and watch the rest, finding myself pushed away further by acting that just did not seem to be trying or allowed to try, from actors that I have seen do much better. In the end, the player would no longer open, possibly fearing that others may have to see the movie. Much of the cinema I seek out is European, not in English, with writing and concepts of depth. I watch and enjoy art movies, great films that explore people, concepts, relations, but that is not what this was for me. It reminded me of what someone trying to live the concept of The Producers would do - irrelevant and unbelievable dialogue, a gunfight that belongs in Police Squad, and characters that are almost universally unsympathetic - except the missing persons officer who aspires to make up for all the rest. I laughed at the production that seemed to have been asking the cast to weaken their performances, a presentation that increasingly seemed like theatresports without the humour as the rendition gave up in even believing the movie would work. I'm sorry, but this is closer to Plan 9 from Outer Space and Spaceballs than it is to Kolya or L'Ennui.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So so so so so so so so so so so so boring boring and slow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danielle_m_d
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Completely flat, unfathomably long, completely unwatchable. Nondimensional characters deliver trite deadpan lines and it I'm supposed to think its brilliant and funny? This movie had almost nothing in it that was genuinely amusing. It had anti-stereotypes like accountant-torturers that wouldn't sustain a SNL sketch let alone what felt like a 16 hour movie. It wasn't sexy or smart. There wasn't one likable character (if you could argue that this film had characters), and for the most part there was no plot, nothing at all to keep you interested. If I hadn't agreed to watch it, I would have turned it off during every scene. I just don't get the joke. Is the film-loving community so desiccated by ennui that they adore a film that shakes its angry fist at the concept of being entertaining?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Words fail me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernie-122
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am ashamed to admit that I have only just discovered Hal Hartley. Fortunately, not too late, as I think I still have enough time remaining on this planet to hunt up and watch all of his other films. I'm getting a real chuckle out of reading all the one-star reviews here by people who just don't "get it". I don't blame them, really, but there should be some way of warning them not to do it; not to embarrass themselves by displaying their shallowness. If it's slick predigested Hollywood pap liberally peppered with explosions they're looking for, they're in the wrong place. Hal Hartley rules. If he's made better films than "Amateur" then I'm in for a real treat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misfire from Hal Hartley
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wonderfully aloof writer-director Hal Hartley hits a speedbump with this heavy-handed comic oddity about eccentrics, losers and assorted misfits. Isabelle Huppert plays a former nun who is trying her hand at writing sexual fiction; Martin Donovan is an amnesiac (groan) she picks up in a diner. Hartley, who had his biggest success with this formula via 1991's dryly goofy and charming "Trust", is too self-conscious this time out, and the results are twee. Several funny lines cannot compensate for an ugly look and an overall lack of interest in these characters. Supporting cast of crazies includes Parker Posey, but "Amateur" skirts a dead-eyed blandness at every turn. * from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Off-beat, funny drama from a true original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LouE15
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hal Hartley is just my all-out favourite auteur director, brought me through my teens and helped form my world view. When he makes a film you're in for something that is at the very least interesting, and at best, moves you, creates a new world out of the one you're already in, shows you the art in life. That sounds pretentious and some might think his films are too; but that's just the knee-jerk effect that comes with overexposure to rubbish presented as if it's art. But one good Hal Hartley film cures a soul wearied with too much dross. "Amateur" is up there with "Trust" and "The Unbelievable Truth" if you have any time at all for films which are off-kilter, intelligent and which depart from the linear norm. They're also very funny, in a low-key way. His actors are usually regulars, skilled at his unique, poetic and rhythmic script style. His America is intriguing, a place painted with the eye of a true original, and presented with a rigour entirely absent from many more recent so-called independent American films. Another reviewer here noted the strong European flavour in his work; this is quite right; and if you enjoy a varied experience of film I can't see how you wouldn't like his best. The plot of "Amateur" is crazy and contorted, like a dance, with a fascinating premise and a weird logic of its own. Martin Donovan here is Hartley's muse; he perfectly captures the rapid, deadpan delivery and manages to be charming and mysterious, dangerous and vulnerable with minimal changes in expression. Why his career has stayed largely small-scale is beyond me. Perhaps he goes about his work too quietly; perhaps his jaw isn't chiselled enough, I don't know. But Isabelle Huppert is outstanding as the struggling porn writer fresh out of the convent. Says her scumbag-with-a-heart publisher of her attempts: "The problem is, it's quitebad. It's poetry, and don't you try and deny it." And it is poetry; heartbreakingly so. She looks out at the strange world, uniquely innocent, with her big, solemn eyes, and you instinctively feel with her, and wish her a knight to watch over her. And of course, this being Hal Hartley's world, her protector arrives, uniquely flawed. He could be Grandma; or he could be the Wolf. Excellent, good-looking and intriguing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a must see
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    delirious_angel
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its been a while since I've this movie but its always stayed with me and I would strongly recommend it. This film has Hal Hartley's trademark sparse, artsy atmosphere, with the slightly surreal characters, the staged dialogue and set pieces. All the characters are quirky and memorable, I loved Isabelle Huppert's character - the nymphomanical nun - in particular and the story dissects amnesia in a really interesting way. Above all the central love story will draw you in more than you realise; the ending was both crushing and fitting. This is due to the acting, as every movement and expression helps to build characters and relationships. Isabelle Huppert and Martin Donovan both do this perfectly, and the impact of the ending owes a lot to them. The odd 'staging' of the film may put off those expecting a more conventional thriller but open minded viewers will be rewarded.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film school pap: amateurish, tedious, fake.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyeseehot
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Characters and story dreamed up by an auteur without imagination. Fake to the bone. No relation to life. Dialog pretentiously abstract, meant to be funny but isn't. Caricatured characters can sometimes be fun--see Dr. Strangelove--but the caricature has to grow from a sense of life. This is so airless, so film-schooly, watching it is like trying to breathe in a vacuum. An ex-nun nymphomaniac, so she says, who has not had sex because "I'm choosy", and a porn star, some gangsters, etc., adds up to a labored, dead, badly acted pseudo movie. I watched it because of all the good comments, so I'm warning those with ears to hear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Two complete lives lasting few days
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    przgzr
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a surprising movie. It's more crime genre than you expect with Isabelle Huppert in cast, but much more French style than you expect from American director. First part of the movie was Chabrol-like (and it's a complement), second is more action but far from modern American action movies (that I don't like). This change is well made, it has reasons according to the development of the plot. *** spoilers, including end of movie !! *** The movie shows a few days that make a whole life for two main characters. Isabelle was lethargic, almost in a hibernation, living in a nunnery and later waiting for things to happen; now she feels she found the purpose of her existence, to fulfill the task she has been given by Holy Virgin, and starts living. At the end of the movie she succeeded in doing it, her possible lover is killed, she is left empty and seems emotionally dead. For Thomas the situation is even more extreme: suffering complete amnesia it's as if he was born on the beginning of the movie, and (physically) dies at the end. His death is absurd: though he was a criminal, ruining many lives, he is punished for crimes he (because of amnesia) doesn't even know he did. And it makes this execution as pointless as in Easy Rider or Blue Soldier. Photography was better indoors than outdoors (restaurant in the beginning, Sofia and the rose, or empty room where Edward was tortured); good camera angles in country house when Edward looks for Thomas. In a border-reality movie like this some use of slow-motion or Hamilton-like soft photo could be expected, but maybe it would look to much like a dream (Isabelle) or nightmare (Thomas), or too profane, so the director didn't do it. Interesting use of carefully chosen objects, like a lamp in empty room: it seems to be the guy's only possession in a place he uses to make love, and now it is used for violence, for torturing. * spoilers-free part * I don't know how many people will enjoy this movie. It's not like old French crime movies (Delon, Belmondo, Ventura) or modern American action movies, so if you expect it, be careful. Maybe you'll like it, I did. But I like Chabrol and old film-noir movies, so if you're closer to my taste, and if you prefer visual beauty and mood instead of action and dynamic change of scenes, this could be a movie for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of those movies after which you shake your head and say bemusedly, "Wow."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jj9675
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hal Hartley where have you been all my movie-loving life? This was the sort of movie-watching experience which required my calling my best friend and telling her about it, as I would any noteworthy experience. Yes, the ending was dismal... yet perfect! So much about redemption: This was clear if one remembers Thomas's feet at the beginning of the movie, and then Thomas's feet at the end. At that point, I saw the (one of) point to the story. I enjoyed the clipped dialogue, the clarity, AND the ironic absurdity. The story was not meant to be reality-driven, but limited to the raison d'etre of Thomas and the other characters: as in a dream, but not. Discovering it was a marvelous channel-surfing accident. Now I must do a search on Hal Hartley. Check out his portfolio, so to speak. Rating 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Abstract Porn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hartley is one of the most interesting directors working. Many associate him with French intuitives, but I think his experiments are more intellectual, more New York. His films are not only about other films, but exist in a world abstracted from them where almost everyone else insists on wallowing in the same space they reference. This is still an early work, which I had the opportunity to see with its purported referent: 'Band of Outsiders.' Writing as a fulcrum; performance as porn; film humor as a selfaware deadpan. Sex as an abstract creation. Pain as an act. Huppert as walking hair, early Posey on her way to Jackie K. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Killed My DVD Player!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark L. Kahnt
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe Isabelle Huppert rubs me the wrong way, maybe trying to do European work in an American context confused the crew and writers, maybe the cast and director realised that this just wasn't going to connect for most people, but it proved unwatchable for me. I'd try it for a while, and then go back to channel hopping. The DVD, which I bought at a liquidation store, sat in the player for three months, watching a chapter here, a chapter there, until I got into the eighth chapter. I elected to bite my tongue and watch the rest, finding myself pushed away further by acting that just did not seem to be trying or allowed to try, from actors that I have seen do much better. In the end, the player would no longer open, possibly fearing that others may have to see the movie. Much of the cinema I seek out is European, not in English, with writing and concepts of depth. I watch and enjoy art movies, great films that explore people, concepts, relations, but that is not what this was for me. It reminded me of what someone trying to live the concept of The Producers would do - irrelevant and unbelievable dialogue, a gunfight that belongs in Police Squad, and characters that are almost universally unsympathetic - except the missing persons officer who aspires to make up for all the rest. I laughed at the production that seemed to have been asking the cast to weaken their performances, a presentation that increasingly seemed like theatresports without the humour as the rendition gave up in even believing the movie would work. I'm sorry, but this is closer to Plan 9 from Outer Space and Spaceballs than it is to Kolya or L'Ennui.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So so so so so so so so so so so so boring boring and slow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danielle_m_d
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Completely flat, unfathomably long, completely unwatchable. Nondimensional characters deliver trite deadpan lines and it I'm supposed to think its brilliant and funny? This movie had almost nothing in it that was genuinely amusing. It had anti-stereotypes like accountant-torturers that wouldn't sustain a SNL sketch let alone what felt like a 16 hour movie. It wasn't sexy or smart. There wasn't one likable character (if you could argue that this film had characters), and for the most part there was no plot, nothing at all to keep you interested. If I hadn't agreed to watch it, I would have turned it off during every scene. I just don't get the joke. Is the film-loving community so desiccated by ennui that they adore a film that shakes its angry fist at the concept of being entertaining?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Words fail me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernie-122
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am ashamed to admit that I have only just discovered Hal Hartley. Fortunately, not too late, as I think I still have enough time remaining on this planet to hunt up and watch all of his other films. I'm getting a real chuckle out of reading all the one-star reviews here by people who just don't "get it". I don't blame them, really, but there should be some way of warning them not to do it; not to embarrass themselves by displaying their shallowness. If it's slick predigested Hollywood pap liberally peppered with explosions they're looking for, they're in the wrong place. Hal Hartley rules. If he's made better films than "Amateur" then I'm in for a real treat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misfire from Hal Hartley
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wonderfully aloof writer-director Hal Hartley hits a speedbump with this heavy-handed comic oddity about eccentrics, losers and assorted misfits. Isabelle Huppert plays a former nun who is trying her hand at writing sexual fiction; Martin Donovan is an amnesiac (groan) she picks up in a diner. Hartley, who had his biggest success with this formula via 1991's dryly goofy and charming "Trust", is too self-conscious this time out, and the results are twee. Several funny lines cannot compensate for an ugly look and an overall lack of interest in these characters. Supporting cast of crazies includes Parker Posey, but "Amateur" skirts a dead-eyed blandness at every turn. * from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Off-beat, funny drama from a true original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LouE15
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hal Hartley is just my all-out favourite auteur director, brought me through my teens and helped form my world view. When he makes a film you're in for something that is at the very least interesting, and at best, moves you, creates a new world out of the one you're already in, shows you the art in life. That sounds pretentious and some might think his films are too; but that's just the knee-jerk effect that comes with overexposure to rubbish presented as if it's art. But one good Hal Hartley film cures a soul wearied with too much dross. "Amateur" is up there with "Trust" and "The Unbelievable Truth" if you have any time at all for films which are off-kilter, intelligent and which depart from the linear norm. They're also very funny, in a low-key way. His actors are usually regulars, skilled at his unique, poetic and rhythmic script style. His America is intriguing, a place painted with the eye of a true original, and presented with a rigour entirely absent from many more recent so-called independent American films. Another reviewer here noted the strong European flavour in his work; this is quite right; and if you enjoy a varied experience of film I can't see how you wouldn't like his best. The plot of "Amateur" is crazy and contorted, like a dance, with a fascinating premise and a weird logic of its own. Martin Donovan here is Hartley's muse; he perfectly captures the rapid, deadpan delivery and manages to be charming and mysterious, dangerous and vulnerable with minimal changes in expression. Why his career has stayed largely small-scale is beyond me. Perhaps he goes about his work too quietly; perhaps his jaw isn't chiselled enough, I don't know. But Isabelle Huppert is outstanding as the struggling porn writer fresh out of the convent. Says her scumbag-with-a-heart publisher of her attempts: "The problem is, it's quitebad. It's poetry, and don't you try and deny it." And it is poetry; heartbreakingly so. She looks out at the strange world, uniquely innocent, with her big, solemn eyes, and you instinctively feel with her, and wish her a knight to watch over her. And of course, this being Hal Hartley's world, her protector arrives, uniquely flawed. He could be Grandma; or he could be the Wolf. Excellent, good-looking and intriguing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a must see
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    delirious_angel
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its been a while since I've this movie but its always stayed with me and I would strongly recommend it. This film has Hal Hartley's trademark sparse, artsy atmosphere, with the slightly surreal characters, the staged dialogue and set pieces. All the characters are quirky and memorable, I loved Isabelle Huppert's character - the nymphomanical nun - in particular and the story dissects amnesia in a really interesting way. Above all the central love story will draw you in more than you realise; the ending was both crushing and fitting. This is due to the acting, as every movement and expression helps to build characters and relationships. Isabelle Huppert and Martin Donovan both do this perfectly, and the impact of the ending owes a lot to them. The odd 'staging' of the film may put off those expecting a more conventional thriller but open minded viewers will be rewarded.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film school pap: amateurish, tedious, fake.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyeseehot
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Characters and story dreamed up by an auteur without imagination. Fake to the bone. No relation to life. Dialog pretentiously abstract, meant to be funny but isn't. Caricatured characters can sometimes be fun--see Dr. Strangelove--but the caricature has to grow from a sense of life. This is so airless, so film-schooly, watching it is like trying to breathe in a vacuum. An ex-nun nymphomaniac, so she says, who has not had sex because "I'm choosy", and a porn star, some gangsters, etc., adds up to a labored, dead, badly acted pseudo movie. I watched it because of all the good comments, so I'm warning those with ears to hear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Two complete lives lasting few days
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    przgzr
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a surprising movie. It's more crime genre than you expect with Isabelle Huppert in cast, but much more French style than you expect from American director. First part of the movie was Chabrol-like (and it's a complement), second is more action but far from modern American action movies (that I don't like). This change is well made, it has reasons according to the development of the plot. *** spoilers, including end of movie !! *** The movie shows a few days that make a whole life for two main characters. Isabelle was lethargic, almost in a hibernation, living in a nunnery and later waiting for things to happen; now she feels she found the purpose of her existence, to fulfill the task she has been given by Holy Virgin, and starts living. At the end of the movie she succeeded in doing it, her possible lover is killed, she is left empty and seems emotionally dead. For Thomas the situation is even more extreme: suffering complete amnesia it's as if he was born on the beginning of the movie, and (physically) dies at the end. His death is absurd: though he was a criminal, ruining many lives, he is punished for crimes he (because of amnesia) doesn't even know he did. And it makes this execution as pointless as in Easy Rider or Blue Soldier. Photography was better indoors than outdoors (restaurant in the beginning, Sofia and the rose, or empty room where Edward was tortured); good camera angles in country house when Edward looks for Thomas. In a border-reality movie like this some use of slow-motion or Hamilton-like soft photo could be expected, but maybe it would look to much like a dream (Isabelle) or nightmare (Thomas), or too profane, so the director didn't do it. Interesting use of carefully chosen objects, like a lamp in empty room: it seems to be the guy's only possession in a place he uses to make love, and now it is used for violence, for torturing. * spoilers-free part * I don't know how many people will enjoy this movie. It's not like old French crime movies (Delon, Belmondo, Ventura) or modern American action movies, so if you expect it, be careful. Maybe you'll like it, I did. But I like Chabrol and old film-noir movies, so if you're closer to my taste, and if you prefer visual beauty and mood instead of action and dynamic change of scenes, this could be a movie for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of those movies after which you shake your head and say bemusedly, "Wow."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jj9675
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hal Hartley where have you been all my movie-loving life? This was the sort of movie-watching experience which required my calling my best friend and telling her about it, as I would any noteworthy experience. Yes, the ending was dismal... yet perfect! So much about redemption: This was clear if one remembers Thomas's feet at the beginning of the movie, and then Thomas's feet at the end. At that point, I saw the (one of) point to the story. I enjoyed the clipped dialogue, the clarity, AND the ironic absurdity. The story was not meant to be reality-driven, but limited to the raison d'etre of Thomas and the other characters: as in a dream, but not. Discovering it was a marvelous channel-surfing accident. Now I must do a search on Hal Hartley. Check out his portfolio, so to speak. Rating 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Abstract Porn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hartley is one of the most interesting directors working. Many associate him with French intuitives, but I think his experiments are more intellectual, more New York. His films are not only about other films, but exist in a world abstracted from them where almost everyone else insists on wallowing in the same space they reference. This is still an early work, which I had the opportunity to see with its purported referent: 'Band of Outsiders.' Writing as a fulcrum; performance as porn; film humor as a selfaware deadpan. Sex as an abstract creation. Pain as an act. Huppert as walking hair, early Posey on her way to Jackie K. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
