<filme>
 <id>
  108
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116768
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Em Alto Astral
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A pharmaceutical scientist creates a pill that makes people remember their happiest memory, and although it's successful, it has unfortunate side effects.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A team of scientists working for a pharmaceutical company discovers a cure for depression. When the company finds itself in trouble financially, they rush the new drug into production without doing enough testing. Things seem to go fine until some of the users of the drug start slipping into comas. It becomes a race between the scientists who want to tell the world the truth and the company's marketing department who wants to protect their profit margin.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   drugs
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   pharmaceuticals
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   scientist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   side effect
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   marketing
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Kelly Makin
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Norm Hiscock
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Bruce McCulloch
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Dave Foley
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Bruce McCulloch
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kevin McDonald
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very Enjoyable, Quotable Cult Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A group of researchers for a pharmaceutical company release Gleemonex, a drug that brings people's happiest memory to the surface and cures depression. All is right in the world, at least until the drug is discovered to have some side effects down the road. The Kids in the Hall had a great show, and it's no surprise they were able to make a great movie. With a very limited cast, they play dozens of parts and keep the humor rolling from the very beginning. If there's a group that is the spiritual successor to Monty Python, it is probably KITH. Some of the best jokes are just throw-aways: a cop that dreams about sex with toast, a therapist who doesn't speak German, and a scientist who develops a drug that gives ex-girlfriends worms. One of the running jokes throughout the film is a man who is obviously gay but is unable to admit it. He is consistently funny, even after he comes out in the middle of a musical scene. Some people allegedly thought that including Cancer Boy was insensitive and not funny in the slightest. I disagree. If it's okay to make fun of depression and homosexuals, I think cancer should be perfectly acceptable. I may not be easily offended, but I think this was fine. A couple other things made this film great: a great soundtrack with bands like They Might Be Giants and The Odds. One of the earliest film appearances of Selma Blair. Seriously, the only way you would not find this funny is if you had a stick up your butt or you were a flipper baby.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    watch as prescribed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    belair82g
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "i realized that i would never be happy and i am much happier because of it". I remember when I first watched the film many years ago (on VHS) I didn't think much of it and years later I gave it another go because I am a Kids in the Hall fan. It turns out there are many who prefer the movie who have given it a second or more viewings. The movie is silly (which is one thing I love) and also quite brilliant. I have to say it has earned the title of being a cult classic and is up there with the Monty Python movies. Much of the dialogue itself is funny and the characters just add so much humour to the screen. The only real problem I have with the movie is the DVD. The DVD lacks completely of special features (and is now out of print). Where is the trailer? (which is totally worth seeing over and over again). Where are the deleted scenes? (There happens to be several deleted scenes). What about the alternate ending (Which is worth watching). Maybe the movie could have been funnier if some of the removed scenes had made it's way into the movie. But still the movie is fine the way it is but again the DVD should feature the removed content in order to appreciate this movie even more. I've seen the work print of the movie and of course the movie itself and yet the trailer has moments that is in neither. What is that all about? Anyway I think the Kids have done a great job here and this movie is perfect for a good laugh but it makes me sad and depressed to see all the missing content from the DVD. Then again watching this movie is a great cure for depression.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seth-287
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw this movie I had never seen the TV series, so I didn't have any preconceived ideas about what this movie was going to be like. I belong to a group of people who question the pharmaceutical industry and the premise of the movie appealed to me. Every time I see this film I find new funny details. At my house we have shown this movie to our friends and they all seemed to love it. Each actor portrays several characters and they are very distinctive. I also think the message throughout is important and this movie is worth watching! It's too bad some people didn't like this movie. I think since the movie wasn't heavily publicized it didn't reach the potential but it's a cult favorite in my circle of friends. I'm surprised Scientology hasn't promoted this movie because it portrays psych meds in an unfavorable light.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Positively Priceless!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RaiderJack
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As this is the only full-length movie of one of the smartest comedy ensembles ever, this is indeed a classic already and worth every second. It is amazing the wealth of characters The Kids in the Hall are capable of drawing upon which further fuels a very well-written satire on society's eagerness to address and cure any and every thing via a pill - notwithstanding the side effects. To be sure, some of the routines may be uncomfortable, especially because they end up being so funny (most notably Cancer Boy) but sometimes this is the only way - either confront a particular societal flaw with a harsh unfunny reality or, in this case, make them laugh so hard they are bound to see the absurdity in a given situation and thus be able to move toward rectifying it. For KITH fans, this is a must; for those of you who enjoy cutting edge comedy, you will not be disappointed!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sub-amateurish, non-talented and puerile
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aristides-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A 1 because there's no way I can rate this a minus 10. Though alive I was figuratively turning over in my grave every time someone likened this 'thing' to a Monty Python show or movie. The Python writers/performers were all brilliant and could skewer society and culture either with a broadsword or a stiletto. These dopes, less talented than Moe, Larry and Curly, can be summed up with one word and that word is "unsubtle". If there was a god of comedy, bolts of lighting would fry the people for uttering the heresy of comparing them to Python. Anything this amateurish and unfunny makes me either reach for my pistol, walk rapidly to the exit or push the off button on the remote in an excessively heavy manner. (Actually I disliked this movie so much I wanted to do all three things simultaneously.) 'Kids' is the absolute bottom of the comedic barrel and could be the worst comedy in motion picture history (maybe there is a god after all because some Force has intervened and determined that they will never make another movie and so thank you Jesus, thank you Muhammed, thank you Vishnu, thank you Buddha!).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a HUGE disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was a fan of THE KIDS IN THE HALL. Yeah, sometimes the jokes went a little flat, but so often it was gosh darn funny and always was quick to take a risk or poke fun at nearly anything. Unfortunately, once the series ended, they decided to make a farewell film. In hindsight, they should have just left well-enough alone. Boy, was I disappointed. So often, when TV shows go to the big screen, the basic chemistry and formula that made them great is adulterated--this is truly the case with this film. Instead of being weird and funny, it was only slightly weird and not the least bit funny or entertaining. I would have been much happier if they had just strung together three episodes as the movie, instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Freakin' Awesome!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    foureyeblindman7
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Holy god! Can comedy get any funnier? I am an absolutely enormous Kids in the Hall fan and although at first this movie didn't strike me as a "Kids" masterpiece like their series was I soon came to realize that the reason I was somewhat disappointed was because I didn't get to see appearances from the legendary "Head-Crusher" or "Buddy" but once I kept watching past the first few minutes and got to catch a glimpse at the classic Don character and of course who can forget Bruce McCulloch as Cancer Boy? So if you don't get to see some classic head crushing bits, what do you get to see? Well, I'm going to answer my own question. You get to see Michael McDonald finding the formula for "happy," Bruce McColloch rockin' out to Happiness Pie and giving us an amazing "Whistle if You're Loved" performance, Mark McKinney playing one of my favorite characters (Don), Dave Foley's awkward moment as the New Scientist, and Scott Thompson dressed up as an old lady spinning around in a giant and pointless testing machine. Probably my favorite scene in the entire movie is Chris Cooper's flash back to his depressed father coming home from working and having trouble shooting himself (which he finally does after 2-hours worth of tries). And then of course there is the kiss shared by Michael McDonald and Bruce McCulloch at the end of the movie. But does this mean that the Kids have strayed away from their roots? Of course not! There is still plenty of cross-dressing, jokes about business men, jokes about Scott Thompson's sexuality, and of course, many absurdly random moments (bird flying into Bruce McCulloch's eye). So if you are a Kids in the Hall fan or a patient diagnosed with depression there is no way you can miss this absolutely hilarious, clever, absurd, and well-written performance by our friends from up North. I can safely say this is classic comedy worthy of Groucho Marx Level praise. WATCH IT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my Top 10 Films Of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JD WaySide
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "It'll make you laugh, it'll make you cry, and maybe - just maybe - you'll learn something about yourself..." ...Seriously! This movie just blew me away on so many levels. First level: Being a longtime fan of the Kids and getting to see many familiar characters once again was a gas. Not to mention some of the new ones they cooked up for the film. Second level: As an exercise in the absurd (Cancer Boy, the gay guy coming out in a big neighbourhood production number, the German psychiatrist). Next level: Satire and stereotype (the CEO screaming, "MY... EMPIRE... IS... CRUUUMMMMBLINNGG!", the punk rocker, the talkshow hostess). Yet another level: Makes a HUGE statement about the corporate-media-industrial complex and its usurpation of contemporary culture and mores. And so on, and so on... Finally, the film, while purporting to be a comedy masking itself as a tragedy (or is it the other way round?) and beneath that pretending to send a negative message about the human condition (like the cabbie says, "This is not a happy story"), manages to have a positive message as well. This movie is an enigma. And as such it's basically indescribable: It'll move you in about six different directions at once. And it might even make you think about a few things. If you've never seen it, get out and rent the bloody thing already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious Even WIthout Knowing The Show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rphguy
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The TV show was funny as hell, although it was sometimes hit-and-miss ; but what sketch show isn't. This movie contains a well planned plot executed by a diverse but motley crew of characters. It makes you think that the BBC show League of Gentlemen isn't as original as you thought it was! Also, the impersonation of Lorne Michaels is spot-on, and makes you think the Dr Evil character from Austin Powers isn't as original as you thought either (as they are both spoofing Mr Michaels - who produced both SNL for Myers and Kids in the Hall). Great fun... and try not to laugh out loud at the 'cancer boy' character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Film Is Gay
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KIDS IN THE HALL ? This is a sketch show I remembered being broadcast in the wee small hours in Britain on channel 4 . I didn't think much of it . No strike that - I hated it . It was composed of a bunch of Canadian MONTY PYTHON wannabes who dressed in drag more often than not and made sketches that fell flat . I can remember the " I'm crushing your head " character because of the simple reason it was so unfunny and it's no surprise that Canadians I know much prefer British TV like THE OFFICE and DOCTOR WHO BRAIN CANDY is a feature length film by the KITH troupe and as many people have already pointed out you'll only enjoy this movie if you're already a fan , if you've never heard of these kids you will probably dislike with a vengeance with the humour being either underdeveloped or plain crude like the scene where a NCO orders one of his men into battle: " You see these two men beside the wall ? You run over there and f*ck them while we stay here and masturbate " I also couldn't help thinking that because BRAIN CANDY is a spin off from a sketch show the screenplay lacks cohesion , events and scenes happen without any rhyme nor reason like for example a scene cutting to a music award show where Cancer Boy performs a song only for the action to then cut away to another location with Cancer Boy then absent for the rest of the film I certainly didn't enjoy BRAIN CANDY and unless you're a KIDS IN THE HALL fan or someone who enjoys watching men dress up as woman it's highly likely you'll feel the same way
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very Enjoyable, Quotable Cult Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A group of researchers for a pharmaceutical company release Gleemonex, a drug that brings people's happiest memory to the surface and cures depression. All is right in the world, at least until the drug is discovered to have some side effects down the road. The Kids in the Hall had a great show, and it's no surprise they were able to make a great movie. With a very limited cast, they play dozens of parts and keep the humor rolling from the very beginning. If there's a group that is the spiritual successor to Monty Python, it is probably KITH. Some of the best jokes are just throw-aways: a cop that dreams about sex with toast, a therapist who doesn't speak German, and a scientist who develops a drug that gives ex-girlfriends worms. One of the running jokes throughout the film is a man who is obviously gay but is unable to admit it. He is consistently funny, even after he comes out in the middle of a musical scene. Some people allegedly thought that including Cancer Boy was insensitive and not funny in the slightest. I disagree. If it's okay to make fun of depression and homosexuals, I think cancer should be perfectly acceptable. I may not be easily offended, but I think this was fine. A couple other things made this film great: a great soundtrack with bands like They Might Be Giants and The Odds. One of the earliest film appearances of Selma Blair. Seriously, the only way you would not find this funny is if you had a stick up your butt or you were a flipper baby.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    watch as prescribed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    belair82g
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "i realized that i would never be happy and i am much happier because of it". I remember when I first watched the film many years ago (on VHS) I didn't think much of it and years later I gave it another go because I am a Kids in the Hall fan. It turns out there are many who prefer the movie who have given it a second or more viewings. The movie is silly (which is one thing I love) and also quite brilliant. I have to say it has earned the title of being a cult classic and is up there with the Monty Python movies. Much of the dialogue itself is funny and the characters just add so much humour to the screen. The only real problem I have with the movie is the DVD. The DVD lacks completely of special features (and is now out of print). Where is the trailer? (which is totally worth seeing over and over again). Where are the deleted scenes? (There happens to be several deleted scenes). What about the alternate ending (Which is worth watching). Maybe the movie could have been funnier if some of the removed scenes had made it's way into the movie. But still the movie is fine the way it is but again the DVD should feature the removed content in order to appreciate this movie even more. I've seen the work print of the movie and of course the movie itself and yet the trailer has moments that is in neither. What is that all about? Anyway I think the Kids have done a great job here and this movie is perfect for a good laugh but it makes me sad and depressed to see all the missing content from the DVD. Then again watching this movie is a great cure for depression.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seth-287
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw this movie I had never seen the TV series, so I didn't have any preconceived ideas about what this movie was going to be like. I belong to a group of people who question the pharmaceutical industry and the premise of the movie appealed to me. Every time I see this film I find new funny details. At my house we have shown this movie to our friends and they all seemed to love it. Each actor portrays several characters and they are very distinctive. I also think the message throughout is important and this movie is worth watching! It's too bad some people didn't like this movie. I think since the movie wasn't heavily publicized it didn't reach the potential but it's a cult favorite in my circle of friends. I'm surprised Scientology hasn't promoted this movie because it portrays psych meds in an unfavorable light.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Positively Priceless!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RaiderJack
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As this is the only full-length movie of one of the smartest comedy ensembles ever, this is indeed a classic already and worth every second. It is amazing the wealth of characters The Kids in the Hall are capable of drawing upon which further fuels a very well-written satire on society's eagerness to address and cure any and every thing via a pill - notwithstanding the side effects. To be sure, some of the routines may be uncomfortable, especially because they end up being so funny (most notably Cancer Boy) but sometimes this is the only way - either confront a particular societal flaw with a harsh unfunny reality or, in this case, make them laugh so hard they are bound to see the absurdity in a given situation and thus be able to move toward rectifying it. For KITH fans, this is a must; for those of you who enjoy cutting edge comedy, you will not be disappointed!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sub-amateurish, non-talented and puerile
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aristides-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A 1 because there's no way I can rate this a minus 10. Though alive I was figuratively turning over in my grave every time someone likened this 'thing' to a Monty Python show or movie. The Python writers/performers were all brilliant and could skewer society and culture either with a broadsword or a stiletto. These dopes, less talented than Moe, Larry and Curly, can be summed up with one word and that word is "unsubtle". If there was a god of comedy, bolts of lighting would fry the people for uttering the heresy of comparing them to Python. Anything this amateurish and unfunny makes me either reach for my pistol, walk rapidly to the exit or push the off button on the remote in an excessively heavy manner. (Actually I disliked this movie so much I wanted to do all three things simultaneously.) 'Kids' is the absolute bottom of the comedic barrel and could be the worst comedy in motion picture history (maybe there is a god after all because some Force has intervened and determined that they will never make another movie and so thank you Jesus, thank you Muhammed, thank you Vishnu, thank you Buddha!).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a HUGE disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was a fan of THE KIDS IN THE HALL. Yeah, sometimes the jokes went a little flat, but so often it was gosh darn funny and always was quick to take a risk or poke fun at nearly anything. Unfortunately, once the series ended, they decided to make a farewell film. In hindsight, they should have just left well-enough alone. Boy, was I disappointed. So often, when TV shows go to the big screen, the basic chemistry and formula that made them great is adulterated--this is truly the case with this film. Instead of being weird and funny, it was only slightly weird and not the least bit funny or entertaining. I would have been much happier if they had just strung together three episodes as the movie, instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Freakin' Awesome!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    foureyeblindman7
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Holy god! Can comedy get any funnier? I am an absolutely enormous Kids in the Hall fan and although at first this movie didn't strike me as a "Kids" masterpiece like their series was I soon came to realize that the reason I was somewhat disappointed was because I didn't get to see appearances from the legendary "Head-Crusher" or "Buddy" but once I kept watching past the first few minutes and got to catch a glimpse at the classic Don character and of course who can forget Bruce McCulloch as Cancer Boy? So if you don't get to see some classic head crushing bits, what do you get to see? Well, I'm going to answer my own question. You get to see Michael McDonald finding the formula for "happy," Bruce McColloch rockin' out to Happiness Pie and giving us an amazing "Whistle if You're Loved" performance, Mark McKinney playing one of my favorite characters (Don), Dave Foley's awkward moment as the New Scientist, and Scott Thompson dressed up as an old lady spinning around in a giant and pointless testing machine. Probably my favorite scene in the entire movie is Chris Cooper's flash back to his depressed father coming home from working and having trouble shooting himself (which he finally does after 2-hours worth of tries). And then of course there is the kiss shared by Michael McDonald and Bruce McCulloch at the end of the movie. But does this mean that the Kids have strayed away from their roots? Of course not! There is still plenty of cross-dressing, jokes about business men, jokes about Scott Thompson's sexuality, and of course, many absurdly random moments (bird flying into Bruce McCulloch's eye). So if you are a Kids in the Hall fan or a patient diagnosed with depression there is no way you can miss this absolutely hilarious, clever, absurd, and well-written performance by our friends from up North. I can safely say this is classic comedy worthy of Groucho Marx Level praise. WATCH IT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my Top 10 Films Of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JD WaySide
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "It'll make you laugh, it'll make you cry, and maybe - just maybe - you'll learn something about yourself..." ...Seriously! This movie just blew me away on so many levels. First level: Being a longtime fan of the Kids and getting to see many familiar characters once again was a gas. Not to mention some of the new ones they cooked up for the film. Second level: As an exercise in the absurd (Cancer Boy, the gay guy coming out in a big neighbourhood production number, the German psychiatrist). Next level: Satire and stereotype (the CEO screaming, "MY... EMPIRE... IS... CRUUUMMMMBLINNGG!", the punk rocker, the talkshow hostess). Yet another level: Makes a HUGE statement about the corporate-media-industrial complex and its usurpation of contemporary culture and mores. And so on, and so on... Finally, the film, while purporting to be a comedy masking itself as a tragedy (or is it the other way round?) and beneath that pretending to send a negative message about the human condition (like the cabbie says, "This is not a happy story"), manages to have a positive message as well. This movie is an enigma. And as such it's basically indescribable: It'll move you in about six different directions at once. And it might even make you think about a few things. If you've never seen it, get out and rent the bloody thing already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious Even WIthout Knowing The Show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rphguy
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The TV show was funny as hell, although it was sometimes hit-and-miss ; but what sketch show isn't. This movie contains a well planned plot executed by a diverse but motley crew of characters. It makes you think that the BBC show League of Gentlemen isn't as original as you thought it was! Also, the impersonation of Lorne Michaels is spot-on, and makes you think the Dr Evil character from Austin Powers isn't as original as you thought either (as they are both spoofing Mr Michaels - who produced both SNL for Myers and Kids in the Hall). Great fun... and try not to laugh out loud at the 'cancer boy' character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Film Is Gay
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KIDS IN THE HALL ? This is a sketch show I remembered being broadcast in the wee small hours in Britain on channel 4 . I didn't think much of it . No strike that - I hated it . It was composed of a bunch of Canadian MONTY PYTHON wannabes who dressed in drag more often than not and made sketches that fell flat . I can remember the " I'm crushing your head " character because of the simple reason it was so unfunny and it's no surprise that Canadians I know much prefer British TV like THE OFFICE and DOCTOR WHO BRAIN CANDY is a feature length film by the KITH troupe and as many people have already pointed out you'll only enjoy this movie if you're already a fan , if you've never heard of these kids you will probably dislike with a vengeance with the humour being either underdeveloped or plain crude like the scene where a NCO orders one of his men into battle: " You see these two men beside the wall ? You run over there and f*ck them while we stay here and masturbate " I also couldn't help thinking that because BRAIN CANDY is a spin off from a sketch show the screenplay lacks cohesion , events and scenes happen without any rhyme nor reason like for example a scene cutting to a music award show where Cancer Boy performs a song only for the action to then cut away to another location with Cancer Boy then absent for the rest of the film I certainly didn't enjoy BRAIN CANDY and unless you're a KIDS IN THE HALL fan or someone who enjoys watching men dress up as woman it's highly likely you'll feel the same way
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very Enjoyable, Quotable Cult Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A group of researchers for a pharmaceutical company release Gleemonex, a drug that brings people's happiest memory to the surface and cures depression. All is right in the world, at least until the drug is discovered to have some side effects down the road. The Kids in the Hall had a great show, and it's no surprise they were able to make a great movie. With a very limited cast, they play dozens of parts and keep the humor rolling from the very beginning. If there's a group that is the spiritual successor to Monty Python, it is probably KITH. Some of the best jokes are just throw-aways: a cop that dreams about sex with toast, a therapist who doesn't speak German, and a scientist who develops a drug that gives ex-girlfriends worms. One of the running jokes throughout the film is a man who is obviously gay but is unable to admit it. He is consistently funny, even after he comes out in the middle of a musical scene. Some people allegedly thought that including Cancer Boy was insensitive and not funny in the slightest. I disagree. If it's okay to make fun of depression and homosexuals, I think cancer should be perfectly acceptable. I may not be easily offended, but I think this was fine. A couple other things made this film great: a great soundtrack with bands like They Might Be Giants and The Odds. One of the earliest film appearances of Selma Blair. Seriously, the only way you would not find this funny is if you had a stick up your butt or you were a flipper baby.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    watch as prescribed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    belair82g
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "i realized that i would never be happy and i am much happier because of it". I remember when I first watched the film many years ago (on VHS) I didn't think much of it and years later I gave it another go because I am a Kids in the Hall fan. It turns out there are many who prefer the movie who have given it a second or more viewings. The movie is silly (which is one thing I love) and also quite brilliant. I have to say it has earned the title of being a cult classic and is up there with the Monty Python movies. Much of the dialogue itself is funny and the characters just add so much humour to the screen. The only real problem I have with the movie is the DVD. The DVD lacks completely of special features (and is now out of print). Where is the trailer? (which is totally worth seeing over and over again). Where are the deleted scenes? (There happens to be several deleted scenes). What about the alternate ending (Which is worth watching). Maybe the movie could have been funnier if some of the removed scenes had made it's way into the movie. But still the movie is fine the way it is but again the DVD should feature the removed content in order to appreciate this movie even more. I've seen the work print of the movie and of course the movie itself and yet the trailer has moments that is in neither. What is that all about? Anyway I think the Kids have done a great job here and this movie is perfect for a good laugh but it makes me sad and depressed to see all the missing content from the DVD. Then again watching this movie is a great cure for depression.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seth-287
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw this movie I had never seen the TV series, so I didn't have any preconceived ideas about what this movie was going to be like. I belong to a group of people who question the pharmaceutical industry and the premise of the movie appealed to me. Every time I see this film I find new funny details. At my house we have shown this movie to our friends and they all seemed to love it. Each actor portrays several characters and they are very distinctive. I also think the message throughout is important and this movie is worth watching! It's too bad some people didn't like this movie. I think since the movie wasn't heavily publicized it didn't reach the potential but it's a cult favorite in my circle of friends. I'm surprised Scientology hasn't promoted this movie because it portrays psych meds in an unfavorable light.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Positively Priceless!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RaiderJack
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As this is the only full-length movie of one of the smartest comedy ensembles ever, this is indeed a classic already and worth every second. It is amazing the wealth of characters The Kids in the Hall are capable of drawing upon which further fuels a very well-written satire on society's eagerness to address and cure any and every thing via a pill - notwithstanding the side effects. To be sure, some of the routines may be uncomfortable, especially because they end up being so funny (most notably Cancer Boy) but sometimes this is the only way - either confront a particular societal flaw with a harsh unfunny reality or, in this case, make them laugh so hard they are bound to see the absurdity in a given situation and thus be able to move toward rectifying it. For KITH fans, this is a must; for those of you who enjoy cutting edge comedy, you will not be disappointed!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sub-amateurish, non-talented and puerile
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aristides-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A 1 because there's no way I can rate this a minus 10. Though alive I was figuratively turning over in my grave every time someone likened this 'thing' to a Monty Python show or movie. The Python writers/performers were all brilliant and could skewer society and culture either with a broadsword or a stiletto. These dopes, less talented than Moe, Larry and Curly, can be summed up with one word and that word is "unsubtle". If there was a god of comedy, bolts of lighting would fry the people for uttering the heresy of comparing them to Python. Anything this amateurish and unfunny makes me either reach for my pistol, walk rapidly to the exit or push the off button on the remote in an excessively heavy manner. (Actually I disliked this movie so much I wanted to do all three things simultaneously.) 'Kids' is the absolute bottom of the comedic barrel and could be the worst comedy in motion picture history (maybe there is a god after all because some Force has intervened and determined that they will never make another movie and so thank you Jesus, thank you Muhammed, thank you Vishnu, thank you Buddha!).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a HUGE disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was a fan of THE KIDS IN THE HALL. Yeah, sometimes the jokes went a little flat, but so often it was gosh darn funny and always was quick to take a risk or poke fun at nearly anything. Unfortunately, once the series ended, they decided to make a farewell film. In hindsight, they should have just left well-enough alone. Boy, was I disappointed. So often, when TV shows go to the big screen, the basic chemistry and formula that made them great is adulterated--this is truly the case with this film. Instead of being weird and funny, it was only slightly weird and not the least bit funny or entertaining. I would have been much happier if they had just strung together three episodes as the movie, instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Freakin' Awesome!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    foureyeblindman7
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Holy god! Can comedy get any funnier? I am an absolutely enormous Kids in the Hall fan and although at first this movie didn't strike me as a "Kids" masterpiece like their series was I soon came to realize that the reason I was somewhat disappointed was because I didn't get to see appearances from the legendary "Head-Crusher" or "Buddy" but once I kept watching past the first few minutes and got to catch a glimpse at the classic Don character and of course who can forget Bruce McCulloch as Cancer Boy? So if you don't get to see some classic head crushing bits, what do you get to see? Well, I'm going to answer my own question. You get to see Michael McDonald finding the formula for "happy," Bruce McColloch rockin' out to Happiness Pie and giving us an amazing "Whistle if You're Loved" performance, Mark McKinney playing one of my favorite characters (Don), Dave Foley's awkward moment as the New Scientist, and Scott Thompson dressed up as an old lady spinning around in a giant and pointless testing machine. Probably my favorite scene in the entire movie is Chris Cooper's flash back to his depressed father coming home from working and having trouble shooting himself (which he finally does after 2-hours worth of tries). And then of course there is the kiss shared by Michael McDonald and Bruce McCulloch at the end of the movie. But does this mean that the Kids have strayed away from their roots? Of course not! There is still plenty of cross-dressing, jokes about business men, jokes about Scott Thompson's sexuality, and of course, many absurdly random moments (bird flying into Bruce McCulloch's eye). So if you are a Kids in the Hall fan or a patient diagnosed with depression there is no way you can miss this absolutely hilarious, clever, absurd, and well-written performance by our friends from up North. I can safely say this is classic comedy worthy of Groucho Marx Level praise. WATCH IT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my Top 10 Films Of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JD WaySide
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "It'll make you laugh, it'll make you cry, and maybe - just maybe - you'll learn something about yourself..." ...Seriously! This movie just blew me away on so many levels. First level: Being a longtime fan of the Kids and getting to see many familiar characters once again was a gas. Not to mention some of the new ones they cooked up for the film. Second level: As an exercise in the absurd (Cancer Boy, the gay guy coming out in a big neighbourhood production number, the German psychiatrist). Next level: Satire and stereotype (the CEO screaming, "MY... EMPIRE... IS... CRUUUMMMMBLINNGG!", the punk rocker, the talkshow hostess). Yet another level: Makes a HUGE statement about the corporate-media-industrial complex and its usurpation of contemporary culture and mores. And so on, and so on... Finally, the film, while purporting to be a comedy masking itself as a tragedy (or is it the other way round?) and beneath that pretending to send a negative message about the human condition (like the cabbie says, "This is not a happy story"), manages to have a positive message as well. This movie is an enigma. And as such it's basically indescribable: It'll move you in about six different directions at once. And it might even make you think about a few things. If you've never seen it, get out and rent the bloody thing already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious Even WIthout Knowing The Show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rphguy
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The TV show was funny as hell, although it was sometimes hit-and-miss ; but what sketch show isn't. This movie contains a well planned plot executed by a diverse but motley crew of characters. It makes you think that the BBC show League of Gentlemen isn't as original as you thought it was! Also, the impersonation of Lorne Michaels is spot-on, and makes you think the Dr Evil character from Austin Powers isn't as original as you thought either (as they are both spoofing Mr Michaels - who produced both SNL for Myers and Kids in the Hall). Great fun... and try not to laugh out loud at the 'cancer boy' character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Film Is Gay
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KIDS IN THE HALL ? This is a sketch show I remembered being broadcast in the wee small hours in Britain on channel 4 . I didn't think much of it . No strike that - I hated it . It was composed of a bunch of Canadian MONTY PYTHON wannabes who dressed in drag more often than not and made sketches that fell flat . I can remember the " I'm crushing your head " character because of the simple reason it was so unfunny and it's no surprise that Canadians I know much prefer British TV like THE OFFICE and DOCTOR WHO BRAIN CANDY is a feature length film by the KITH troupe and as many people have already pointed out you'll only enjoy this movie if you're already a fan , if you've never heard of these kids you will probably dislike with a vengeance with the humour being either underdeveloped or plain crude like the scene where a NCO orders one of his men into battle: " You see these two men beside the wall ? You run over there and f*ck them while we stay here and masturbate " I also couldn't help thinking that because BRAIN CANDY is a spin off from a sketch show the screenplay lacks cohesion , events and scenes happen without any rhyme nor reason like for example a scene cutting to a music award show where Cancer Boy performs a song only for the action to then cut away to another location with Cancer Boy then absent for the rest of the film I certainly didn't enjoy BRAIN CANDY and unless you're a KIDS IN THE HALL fan or someone who enjoys watching men dress up as woman it's highly likely you'll feel the same way
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very Enjoyable, Quotable Cult Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A group of researchers for a pharmaceutical company release Gleemonex, a drug that brings people's happiest memory to the surface and cures depression. All is right in the world, at least until the drug is discovered to have some side effects down the road. The Kids in the Hall had a great show, and it's no surprise they were able to make a great movie. With a very limited cast, they play dozens of parts and keep the humor rolling from the very beginning. If there's a group that is the spiritual successor to Monty Python, it is probably KITH. Some of the best jokes are just throw-aways: a cop that dreams about sex with toast, a therapist who doesn't speak German, and a scientist who develops a drug that gives ex-girlfriends worms. One of the running jokes throughout the film is a man who is obviously gay but is unable to admit it. He is consistently funny, even after he comes out in the middle of a musical scene. Some people allegedly thought that including Cancer Boy was insensitive and not funny in the slightest. I disagree. If it's okay to make fun of depression and homosexuals, I think cancer should be perfectly acceptable. I may not be easily offended, but I think this was fine. A couple other things made this film great: a great soundtrack with bands like They Might Be Giants and The Odds. One of the earliest film appearances of Selma Blair. Seriously, the only way you would not find this funny is if you had a stick up your butt or you were a flipper baby.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    watch as prescribed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    belair82g
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "i realized that i would never be happy and i am much happier because of it". I remember when I first watched the film many years ago (on VHS) I didn't think much of it and years later I gave it another go because I am a Kids in the Hall fan. It turns out there are many who prefer the movie who have given it a second or more viewings. The movie is silly (which is one thing I love) and also quite brilliant. I have to say it has earned the title of being a cult classic and is up there with the Monty Python movies. Much of the dialogue itself is funny and the characters just add so much humour to the screen. The only real problem I have with the movie is the DVD. The DVD lacks completely of special features (and is now out of print). Where is the trailer? (which is totally worth seeing over and over again). Where are the deleted scenes? (There happens to be several deleted scenes). What about the alternate ending (Which is worth watching). Maybe the movie could have been funnier if some of the removed scenes had made it's way into the movie. But still the movie is fine the way it is but again the DVD should feature the removed content in order to appreciate this movie even more. I've seen the work print of the movie and of course the movie itself and yet the trailer has moments that is in neither. What is that all about? Anyway I think the Kids have done a great job here and this movie is perfect for a good laugh but it makes me sad and depressed to see all the missing content from the DVD. Then again watching this movie is a great cure for depression.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seth-287
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw this movie I had never seen the TV series, so I didn't have any preconceived ideas about what this movie was going to be like. I belong to a group of people who question the pharmaceutical industry and the premise of the movie appealed to me. Every time I see this film I find new funny details. At my house we have shown this movie to our friends and they all seemed to love it. Each actor portrays several characters and they are very distinctive. I also think the message throughout is important and this movie is worth watching! It's too bad some people didn't like this movie. I think since the movie wasn't heavily publicized it didn't reach the potential but it's a cult favorite in my circle of friends. I'm surprised Scientology hasn't promoted this movie because it portrays psych meds in an unfavorable light.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Positively Priceless!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RaiderJack
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As this is the only full-length movie of one of the smartest comedy ensembles ever, this is indeed a classic already and worth every second. It is amazing the wealth of characters The Kids in the Hall are capable of drawing upon which further fuels a very well-written satire on society's eagerness to address and cure any and every thing via a pill - notwithstanding the side effects. To be sure, some of the routines may be uncomfortable, especially because they end up being so funny (most notably Cancer Boy) but sometimes this is the only way - either confront a particular societal flaw with a harsh unfunny reality or, in this case, make them laugh so hard they are bound to see the absurdity in a given situation and thus be able to move toward rectifying it. For KITH fans, this is a must; for those of you who enjoy cutting edge comedy, you will not be disappointed!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sub-amateurish, non-talented and puerile
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aristides-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A 1 because there's no way I can rate this a minus 10. Though alive I was figuratively turning over in my grave every time someone likened this 'thing' to a Monty Python show or movie. The Python writers/performers were all brilliant and could skewer society and culture either with a broadsword or a stiletto. These dopes, less talented than Moe, Larry and Curly, can be summed up with one word and that word is "unsubtle". If there was a god of comedy, bolts of lighting would fry the people for uttering the heresy of comparing them to Python. Anything this amateurish and unfunny makes me either reach for my pistol, walk rapidly to the exit or push the off button on the remote in an excessively heavy manner. (Actually I disliked this movie so much I wanted to do all three things simultaneously.) 'Kids' is the absolute bottom of the comedic barrel and could be the worst comedy in motion picture history (maybe there is a god after all because some Force has intervened and determined that they will never make another movie and so thank you Jesus, thank you Muhammed, thank you Vishnu, thank you Buddha!).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a HUGE disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was a fan of THE KIDS IN THE HALL. Yeah, sometimes the jokes went a little flat, but so often it was gosh darn funny and always was quick to take a risk or poke fun at nearly anything. Unfortunately, once the series ended, they decided to make a farewell film. In hindsight, they should have just left well-enough alone. Boy, was I disappointed. So often, when TV shows go to the big screen, the basic chemistry and formula that made them great is adulterated--this is truly the case with this film. Instead of being weird and funny, it was only slightly weird and not the least bit funny or entertaining. I would have been much happier if they had just strung together three episodes as the movie, instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Freakin' Awesome!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    foureyeblindman7
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Holy god! Can comedy get any funnier? I am an absolutely enormous Kids in the Hall fan and although at first this movie didn't strike me as a "Kids" masterpiece like their series was I soon came to realize that the reason I was somewhat disappointed was because I didn't get to see appearances from the legendary "Head-Crusher" or "Buddy" but once I kept watching past the first few minutes and got to catch a glimpse at the classic Don character and of course who can forget Bruce McCulloch as Cancer Boy? So if you don't get to see some classic head crushing bits, what do you get to see? Well, I'm going to answer my own question. You get to see Michael McDonald finding the formula for "happy," Bruce McColloch rockin' out to Happiness Pie and giving us an amazing "Whistle if You're Loved" performance, Mark McKinney playing one of my favorite characters (Don), Dave Foley's awkward moment as the New Scientist, and Scott Thompson dressed up as an old lady spinning around in a giant and pointless testing machine. Probably my favorite scene in the entire movie is Chris Cooper's flash back to his depressed father coming home from working and having trouble shooting himself (which he finally does after 2-hours worth of tries). And then of course there is the kiss shared by Michael McDonald and Bruce McCulloch at the end of the movie. But does this mean that the Kids have strayed away from their roots? Of course not! There is still plenty of cross-dressing, jokes about business men, jokes about Scott Thompson's sexuality, and of course, many absurdly random moments (bird flying into Bruce McCulloch's eye). So if you are a Kids in the Hall fan or a patient diagnosed with depression there is no way you can miss this absolutely hilarious, clever, absurd, and well-written performance by our friends from up North. I can safely say this is classic comedy worthy of Groucho Marx Level praise. WATCH IT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my Top 10 Films Of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JD WaySide
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "It'll make you laugh, it'll make you cry, and maybe - just maybe - you'll learn something about yourself..." ...Seriously! This movie just blew me away on so many levels. First level: Being a longtime fan of the Kids and getting to see many familiar characters once again was a gas. Not to mention some of the new ones they cooked up for the film. Second level: As an exercise in the absurd (Cancer Boy, the gay guy coming out in a big neighbourhood production number, the German psychiatrist). Next level: Satire and stereotype (the CEO screaming, "MY... EMPIRE... IS... CRUUUMMMMBLINNGG!", the punk rocker, the talkshow hostess). Yet another level: Makes a HUGE statement about the corporate-media-industrial complex and its usurpation of contemporary culture and mores. And so on, and so on... Finally, the film, while purporting to be a comedy masking itself as a tragedy (or is it the other way round?) and beneath that pretending to send a negative message about the human condition (like the cabbie says, "This is not a happy story"), manages to have a positive message as well. This movie is an enigma. And as such it's basically indescribable: It'll move you in about six different directions at once. And it might even make you think about a few things. If you've never seen it, get out and rent the bloody thing already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious Even WIthout Knowing The Show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rphguy
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The TV show was funny as hell, although it was sometimes hit-and-miss ; but what sketch show isn't. This movie contains a well planned plot executed by a diverse but motley crew of characters. It makes you think that the BBC show League of Gentlemen isn't as original as you thought it was! Also, the impersonation of Lorne Michaels is spot-on, and makes you think the Dr Evil character from Austin Powers isn't as original as you thought either (as they are both spoofing Mr Michaels - who produced both SNL for Myers and Kids in the Hall). Great fun... and try not to laugh out loud at the 'cancer boy' character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Film Is Gay
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KIDS IN THE HALL ? This is a sketch show I remembered being broadcast in the wee small hours in Britain on channel 4 . I didn't think much of it . No strike that - I hated it . It was composed of a bunch of Canadian MONTY PYTHON wannabes who dressed in drag more often than not and made sketches that fell flat . I can remember the " I'm crushing your head " character because of the simple reason it was so unfunny and it's no surprise that Canadians I know much prefer British TV like THE OFFICE and DOCTOR WHO BRAIN CANDY is a feature length film by the KITH troupe and as many people have already pointed out you'll only enjoy this movie if you're already a fan , if you've never heard of these kids you will probably dislike with a vengeance with the humour being either underdeveloped or plain crude like the scene where a NCO orders one of his men into battle: " You see these two men beside the wall ? You run over there and f*ck them while we stay here and masturbate " I also couldn't help thinking that because BRAIN CANDY is a spin off from a sketch show the screenplay lacks cohesion , events and scenes happen without any rhyme nor reason like for example a scene cutting to a music award show where Cancer Boy performs a song only for the action to then cut away to another location with Cancer Boy then absent for the rest of the film I certainly didn't enjoy BRAIN CANDY and unless you're a KIDS IN THE HALL fan or someone who enjoys watching men dress up as woman it's highly likely you'll feel the same way
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very Enjoyable, Quotable Cult Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A group of researchers for a pharmaceutical company release Gleemonex, a drug that brings people's happiest memory to the surface and cures depression. All is right in the world, at least until the drug is discovered to have some side effects down the road. The Kids in the Hall had a great show, and it's no surprise they were able to make a great movie. With a very limited cast, they play dozens of parts and keep the humor rolling from the very beginning. If there's a group that is the spiritual successor to Monty Python, it is probably KITH. Some of the best jokes are just throw-aways: a cop that dreams about sex with toast, a therapist who doesn't speak German, and a scientist who develops a drug that gives ex-girlfriends worms. One of the running jokes throughout the film is a man who is obviously gay but is unable to admit it. He is consistently funny, even after he comes out in the middle of a musical scene. Some people allegedly thought that including Cancer Boy was insensitive and not funny in the slightest. I disagree. If it's okay to make fun of depression and homosexuals, I think cancer should be perfectly acceptable. I may not be easily offended, but I think this was fine. A couple other things made this film great: a great soundtrack with bands like They Might Be Giants and The Odds. One of the earliest film appearances of Selma Blair. Seriously, the only way you would not find this funny is if you had a stick up your butt or you were a flipper baby.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    watch as prescribed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    belair82g
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "i realized that i would never be happy and i am much happier because of it". I remember when I first watched the film many years ago (on VHS) I didn't think much of it and years later I gave it another go because I am a Kids in the Hall fan. It turns out there are many who prefer the movie who have given it a second or more viewings. The movie is silly (which is one thing I love) and also quite brilliant. I have to say it has earned the title of being a cult classic and is up there with the Monty Python movies. Much of the dialogue itself is funny and the characters just add so much humour to the screen. The only real problem I have with the movie is the DVD. The DVD lacks completely of special features (and is now out of print). Where is the trailer? (which is totally worth seeing over and over again). Where are the deleted scenes? (There happens to be several deleted scenes). What about the alternate ending (Which is worth watching). Maybe the movie could have been funnier if some of the removed scenes had made it's way into the movie. But still the movie is fine the way it is but again the DVD should feature the removed content in order to appreciate this movie even more. I've seen the work print of the movie and of course the movie itself and yet the trailer has moments that is in neither. What is that all about? Anyway I think the Kids have done a great job here and this movie is perfect for a good laugh but it makes me sad and depressed to see all the missing content from the DVD. Then again watching this movie is a great cure for depression.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seth-287
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw this movie I had never seen the TV series, so I didn't have any preconceived ideas about what this movie was going to be like. I belong to a group of people who question the pharmaceutical industry and the premise of the movie appealed to me. Every time I see this film I find new funny details. At my house we have shown this movie to our friends and they all seemed to love it. Each actor portrays several characters and they are very distinctive. I also think the message throughout is important and this movie is worth watching! It's too bad some people didn't like this movie. I think since the movie wasn't heavily publicized it didn't reach the potential but it's a cult favorite in my circle of friends. I'm surprised Scientology hasn't promoted this movie because it portrays psych meds in an unfavorable light.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Positively Priceless!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RaiderJack
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As this is the only full-length movie of one of the smartest comedy ensembles ever, this is indeed a classic already and worth every second. It is amazing the wealth of characters The Kids in the Hall are capable of drawing upon which further fuels a very well-written satire on society's eagerness to address and cure any and every thing via a pill - notwithstanding the side effects. To be sure, some of the routines may be uncomfortable, especially because they end up being so funny (most notably Cancer Boy) but sometimes this is the only way - either confront a particular societal flaw with a harsh unfunny reality or, in this case, make them laugh so hard they are bound to see the absurdity in a given situation and thus be able to move toward rectifying it. For KITH fans, this is a must; for those of you who enjoy cutting edge comedy, you will not be disappointed!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sub-amateurish, non-talented and puerile
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aristides-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A 1 because there's no way I can rate this a minus 10. Though alive I was figuratively turning over in my grave every time someone likened this 'thing' to a Monty Python show or movie. The Python writers/performers were all brilliant and could skewer society and culture either with a broadsword or a stiletto. These dopes, less talented than Moe, Larry and Curly, can be summed up with one word and that word is "unsubtle". If there was a god of comedy, bolts of lighting would fry the people for uttering the heresy of comparing them to Python. Anything this amateurish and unfunny makes me either reach for my pistol, walk rapidly to the exit or push the off button on the remote in an excessively heavy manner. (Actually I disliked this movie so much I wanted to do all three things simultaneously.) 'Kids' is the absolute bottom of the comedic barrel and could be the worst comedy in motion picture history (maybe there is a god after all because some Force has intervened and determined that they will never make another movie and so thank you Jesus, thank you Muhammed, thank you Vishnu, thank you Buddha!).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a HUGE disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was a fan of THE KIDS IN THE HALL. Yeah, sometimes the jokes went a little flat, but so often it was gosh darn funny and always was quick to take a risk or poke fun at nearly anything. Unfortunately, once the series ended, they decided to make a farewell film. In hindsight, they should have just left well-enough alone. Boy, was I disappointed. So often, when TV shows go to the big screen, the basic chemistry and formula that made them great is adulterated--this is truly the case with this film. Instead of being weird and funny, it was only slightly weird and not the least bit funny or entertaining. I would have been much happier if they had just strung together three episodes as the movie, instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Freakin' Awesome!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    foureyeblindman7
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Holy god! Can comedy get any funnier? I am an absolutely enormous Kids in the Hall fan and although at first this movie didn't strike me as a "Kids" masterpiece like their series was I soon came to realize that the reason I was somewhat disappointed was because I didn't get to see appearances from the legendary "Head-Crusher" or "Buddy" but once I kept watching past the first few minutes and got to catch a glimpse at the classic Don character and of course who can forget Bruce McCulloch as Cancer Boy? So if you don't get to see some classic head crushing bits, what do you get to see? Well, I'm going to answer my own question. You get to see Michael McDonald finding the formula for "happy," Bruce McColloch rockin' out to Happiness Pie and giving us an amazing "Whistle if You're Loved" performance, Mark McKinney playing one of my favorite characters (Don), Dave Foley's awkward moment as the New Scientist, and Scott Thompson dressed up as an old lady spinning around in a giant and pointless testing machine. Probably my favorite scene in the entire movie is Chris Cooper's flash back to his depressed father coming home from working and having trouble shooting himself (which he finally does after 2-hours worth of tries). And then of course there is the kiss shared by Michael McDonald and Bruce McCulloch at the end of the movie. But does this mean that the Kids have strayed away from their roots? Of course not! There is still plenty of cross-dressing, jokes about business men, jokes about Scott Thompson's sexuality, and of course, many absurdly random moments (bird flying into Bruce McCulloch's eye). So if you are a Kids in the Hall fan or a patient diagnosed with depression there is no way you can miss this absolutely hilarious, clever, absurd, and well-written performance by our friends from up North. I can safely say this is classic comedy worthy of Groucho Marx Level praise. WATCH IT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my Top 10 Films Of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JD WaySide
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "It'll make you laugh, it'll make you cry, and maybe - just maybe - you'll learn something about yourself..." ...Seriously! This movie just blew me away on so many levels. First level: Being a longtime fan of the Kids and getting to see many familiar characters once again was a gas. Not to mention some of the new ones they cooked up for the film. Second level: As an exercise in the absurd (Cancer Boy, the gay guy coming out in a big neighbourhood production number, the German psychiatrist). Next level: Satire and stereotype (the CEO screaming, "MY... EMPIRE... IS... CRUUUMMMMBLINNGG!", the punk rocker, the talkshow hostess). Yet another level: Makes a HUGE statement about the corporate-media-industrial complex and its usurpation of contemporary culture and mores. And so on, and so on... Finally, the film, while purporting to be a comedy masking itself as a tragedy (or is it the other way round?) and beneath that pretending to send a negative message about the human condition (like the cabbie says, "This is not a happy story"), manages to have a positive message as well. This movie is an enigma. And as such it's basically indescribable: It'll move you in about six different directions at once. And it might even make you think about a few things. If you've never seen it, get out and rent the bloody thing already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious Even WIthout Knowing The Show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rphguy
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The TV show was funny as hell, although it was sometimes hit-and-miss ; but what sketch show isn't. This movie contains a well planned plot executed by a diverse but motley crew of characters. It makes you think that the BBC show League of Gentlemen isn't as original as you thought it was! Also, the impersonation of Lorne Michaels is spot-on, and makes you think the Dr Evil character from Austin Powers isn't as original as you thought either (as they are both spoofing Mr Michaels - who produced both SNL for Myers and Kids in the Hall). Great fun... and try not to laugh out loud at the 'cancer boy' character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Film Is Gay
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KIDS IN THE HALL ? This is a sketch show I remembered being broadcast in the wee small hours in Britain on channel 4 . I didn't think much of it . No strike that - I hated it . It was composed of a bunch of Canadian MONTY PYTHON wannabes who dressed in drag more often than not and made sketches that fell flat . I can remember the " I'm crushing your head " character because of the simple reason it was so unfunny and it's no surprise that Canadians I know much prefer British TV like THE OFFICE and DOCTOR WHO BRAIN CANDY is a feature length film by the KITH troupe and as many people have already pointed out you'll only enjoy this movie if you're already a fan , if you've never heard of these kids you will probably dislike with a vengeance with the humour being either underdeveloped or plain crude like the scene where a NCO orders one of his men into battle: " You see these two men beside the wall ? You run over there and f*ck them while we stay here and masturbate " I also couldn't help thinking that because BRAIN CANDY is a spin off from a sketch show the screenplay lacks cohesion , events and scenes happen without any rhyme nor reason like for example a scene cutting to a music award show where Cancer Boy performs a song only for the action to then cut away to another location with Cancer Boy then absent for the rest of the film I certainly didn't enjoy BRAIN CANDY and unless you're a KIDS IN THE HALL fan or someone who enjoys watching men dress up as woman it's highly likely you'll feel the same way
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very Enjoyable, Quotable Cult Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A group of researchers for a pharmaceutical company release Gleemonex, a drug that brings people's happiest memory to the surface and cures depression. All is right in the world, at least until the drug is discovered to have some side effects down the road. The Kids in the Hall had a great show, and it's no surprise they were able to make a great movie. With a very limited cast, they play dozens of parts and keep the humor rolling from the very beginning. If there's a group that is the spiritual successor to Monty Python, it is probably KITH. Some of the best jokes are just throw-aways: a cop that dreams about sex with toast, a therapist who doesn't speak German, and a scientist who develops a drug that gives ex-girlfriends worms. One of the running jokes throughout the film is a man who is obviously gay but is unable to admit it. He is consistently funny, even after he comes out in the middle of a musical scene. Some people allegedly thought that including Cancer Boy was insensitive and not funny in the slightest. I disagree. If it's okay to make fun of depression and homosexuals, I think cancer should be perfectly acceptable. I may not be easily offended, but I think this was fine. A couple other things made this film great: a great soundtrack with bands like They Might Be Giants and The Odds. One of the earliest film appearances of Selma Blair. Seriously, the only way you would not find this funny is if you had a stick up your butt or you were a flipper baby.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    watch as prescribed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    belair82g
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "i realized that i would never be happy and i am much happier because of it". I remember when I first watched the film many years ago (on VHS) I didn't think much of it and years later I gave it another go because I am a Kids in the Hall fan. It turns out there are many who prefer the movie who have given it a second or more viewings. The movie is silly (which is one thing I love) and also quite brilliant. I have to say it has earned the title of being a cult classic and is up there with the Monty Python movies. Much of the dialogue itself is funny and the characters just add so much humour to the screen. The only real problem I have with the movie is the DVD. The DVD lacks completely of special features (and is now out of print). Where is the trailer? (which is totally worth seeing over and over again). Where are the deleted scenes? (There happens to be several deleted scenes). What about the alternate ending (Which is worth watching). Maybe the movie could have been funnier if some of the removed scenes had made it's way into the movie. But still the movie is fine the way it is but again the DVD should feature the removed content in order to appreciate this movie even more. I've seen the work print of the movie and of course the movie itself and yet the trailer has moments that is in neither. What is that all about? Anyway I think the Kids have done a great job here and this movie is perfect for a good laugh but it makes me sad and depressed to see all the missing content from the DVD. Then again watching this movie is a great cure for depression.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seth-287
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw this movie I had never seen the TV series, so I didn't have any preconceived ideas about what this movie was going to be like. I belong to a group of people who question the pharmaceutical industry and the premise of the movie appealed to me. Every time I see this film I find new funny details. At my house we have shown this movie to our friends and they all seemed to love it. Each actor portrays several characters and they are very distinctive. I also think the message throughout is important and this movie is worth watching! It's too bad some people didn't like this movie. I think since the movie wasn't heavily publicized it didn't reach the potential but it's a cult favorite in my circle of friends. I'm surprised Scientology hasn't promoted this movie because it portrays psych meds in an unfavorable light.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Positively Priceless!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RaiderJack
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As this is the only full-length movie of one of the smartest comedy ensembles ever, this is indeed a classic already and worth every second. It is amazing the wealth of characters The Kids in the Hall are capable of drawing upon which further fuels a very well-written satire on society's eagerness to address and cure any and every thing via a pill - notwithstanding the side effects. To be sure, some of the routines may be uncomfortable, especially because they end up being so funny (most notably Cancer Boy) but sometimes this is the only way - either confront a particular societal flaw with a harsh unfunny reality or, in this case, make them laugh so hard they are bound to see the absurdity in a given situation and thus be able to move toward rectifying it. For KITH fans, this is a must; for those of you who enjoy cutting edge comedy, you will not be disappointed!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sub-amateurish, non-talented and puerile
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aristides-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A 1 because there's no way I can rate this a minus 10. Though alive I was figuratively turning over in my grave every time someone likened this 'thing' to a Monty Python show or movie. The Python writers/performers were all brilliant and could skewer society and culture either with a broadsword or a stiletto. These dopes, less talented than Moe, Larry and Curly, can be summed up with one word and that word is "unsubtle". If there was a god of comedy, bolts of lighting would fry the people for uttering the heresy of comparing them to Python. Anything this amateurish and unfunny makes me either reach for my pistol, walk rapidly to the exit or push the off button on the remote in an excessively heavy manner. (Actually I disliked this movie so much I wanted to do all three things simultaneously.) 'Kids' is the absolute bottom of the comedic barrel and could be the worst comedy in motion picture history (maybe there is a god after all because some Force has intervened and determined that they will never make another movie and so thank you Jesus, thank you Muhammed, thank you Vishnu, thank you Buddha!).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a HUGE disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was a fan of THE KIDS IN THE HALL. Yeah, sometimes the jokes went a little flat, but so often it was gosh darn funny and always was quick to take a risk or poke fun at nearly anything. Unfortunately, once the series ended, they decided to make a farewell film. In hindsight, they should have just left well-enough alone. Boy, was I disappointed. So often, when TV shows go to the big screen, the basic chemistry and formula that made them great is adulterated--this is truly the case with this film. Instead of being weird and funny, it was only slightly weird and not the least bit funny or entertaining. I would have been much happier if they had just strung together three episodes as the movie, instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Freakin' Awesome!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    foureyeblindman7
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Holy god! Can comedy get any funnier? I am an absolutely enormous Kids in the Hall fan and although at first this movie didn't strike me as a "Kids" masterpiece like their series was I soon came to realize that the reason I was somewhat disappointed was because I didn't get to see appearances from the legendary "Head-Crusher" or "Buddy" but once I kept watching past the first few minutes and got to catch a glimpse at the classic Don character and of course who can forget Bruce McCulloch as Cancer Boy? So if you don't get to see some classic head crushing bits, what do you get to see? Well, I'm going to answer my own question. You get to see Michael McDonald finding the formula for "happy," Bruce McColloch rockin' out to Happiness Pie and giving us an amazing "Whistle if You're Loved" performance, Mark McKinney playing one of my favorite characters (Don), Dave Foley's awkward moment as the New Scientist, and Scott Thompson dressed up as an old lady spinning around in a giant and pointless testing machine. Probably my favorite scene in the entire movie is Chris Cooper's flash back to his depressed father coming home from working and having trouble shooting himself (which he finally does after 2-hours worth of tries). And then of course there is the kiss shared by Michael McDonald and Bruce McCulloch at the end of the movie. But does this mean that the Kids have strayed away from their roots? Of course not! There is still plenty of cross-dressing, jokes about business men, jokes about Scott Thompson's sexuality, and of course, many absurdly random moments (bird flying into Bruce McCulloch's eye). So if you are a Kids in the Hall fan or a patient diagnosed with depression there is no way you can miss this absolutely hilarious, clever, absurd, and well-written performance by our friends from up North. I can safely say this is classic comedy worthy of Groucho Marx Level praise. WATCH IT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my Top 10 Films Of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JD WaySide
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "It'll make you laugh, it'll make you cry, and maybe - just maybe - you'll learn something about yourself..." ...Seriously! This movie just blew me away on so many levels. First level: Being a longtime fan of the Kids and getting to see many familiar characters once again was a gas. Not to mention some of the new ones they cooked up for the film. Second level: As an exercise in the absurd (Cancer Boy, the gay guy coming out in a big neighbourhood production number, the German psychiatrist). Next level: Satire and stereotype (the CEO screaming, "MY... EMPIRE... IS... CRUUUMMMMBLINNGG!", the punk rocker, the talkshow hostess). Yet another level: Makes a HUGE statement about the corporate-media-industrial complex and its usurpation of contemporary culture and mores. And so on, and so on... Finally, the film, while purporting to be a comedy masking itself as a tragedy (or is it the other way round?) and beneath that pretending to send a negative message about the human condition (like the cabbie says, "This is not a happy story"), manages to have a positive message as well. This movie is an enigma. And as such it's basically indescribable: It'll move you in about six different directions at once. And it might even make you think about a few things. If you've never seen it, get out and rent the bloody thing already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious Even WIthout Knowing The Show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rphguy
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The TV show was funny as hell, although it was sometimes hit-and-miss ; but what sketch show isn't. This movie contains a well planned plot executed by a diverse but motley crew of characters. It makes you think that the BBC show League of Gentlemen isn't as original as you thought it was! Also, the impersonation of Lorne Michaels is spot-on, and makes you think the Dr Evil character from Austin Powers isn't as original as you thought either (as they are both spoofing Mr Michaels - who produced both SNL for Myers and Kids in the Hall). Great fun... and try not to laugh out loud at the 'cancer boy' character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Film Is Gay
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KIDS IN THE HALL ? This is a sketch show I remembered being broadcast in the wee small hours in Britain on channel 4 . I didn't think much of it . No strike that - I hated it . It was composed of a bunch of Canadian MONTY PYTHON wannabes who dressed in drag more often than not and made sketches that fell flat . I can remember the " I'm crushing your head " character because of the simple reason it was so unfunny and it's no surprise that Canadians I know much prefer British TV like THE OFFICE and DOCTOR WHO BRAIN CANDY is a feature length film by the KITH troupe and as many people have already pointed out you'll only enjoy this movie if you're already a fan , if you've never heard of these kids you will probably dislike with a vengeance with the humour being either underdeveloped or plain crude like the scene where a NCO orders one of his men into battle: " You see these two men beside the wall ? You run over there and f*ck them while we stay here and masturbate " I also couldn't help thinking that because BRAIN CANDY is a spin off from a sketch show the screenplay lacks cohesion , events and scenes happen without any rhyme nor reason like for example a scene cutting to a music award show where Cancer Boy performs a song only for the action to then cut away to another location with Cancer Boy then absent for the rest of the film I certainly didn't enjoy BRAIN CANDY and unless you're a KIDS IN THE HALL fan or someone who enjoys watching men dress up as woman it's highly likely you'll feel the same way
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very Enjoyable, Quotable Cult Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A group of researchers for a pharmaceutical company release Gleemonex, a drug that brings people's happiest memory to the surface and cures depression. All is right in the world, at least until the drug is discovered to have some side effects down the road. The Kids in the Hall had a great show, and it's no surprise they were able to make a great movie. With a very limited cast, they play dozens of parts and keep the humor rolling from the very beginning. If there's a group that is the spiritual successor to Monty Python, it is probably KITH. Some of the best jokes are just throw-aways: a cop that dreams about sex with toast, a therapist who doesn't speak German, and a scientist who develops a drug that gives ex-girlfriends worms. One of the running jokes throughout the film is a man who is obviously gay but is unable to admit it. He is consistently funny, even after he comes out in the middle of a musical scene. Some people allegedly thought that including Cancer Boy was insensitive and not funny in the slightest. I disagree. If it's okay to make fun of depression and homosexuals, I think cancer should be perfectly acceptable. I may not be easily offended, but I think this was fine. A couple other things made this film great: a great soundtrack with bands like They Might Be Giants and The Odds. One of the earliest film appearances of Selma Blair. Seriously, the only way you would not find this funny is if you had a stick up your butt or you were a flipper baby.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    watch as prescribed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    belair82g
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "i realized that i would never be happy and i am much happier because of it". I remember when I first watched the film many years ago (on VHS) I didn't think much of it and years later I gave it another go because I am a Kids in the Hall fan. It turns out there are many who prefer the movie who have given it a second or more viewings. The movie is silly (which is one thing I love) and also quite brilliant. I have to say it has earned the title of being a cult classic and is up there with the Monty Python movies. Much of the dialogue itself is funny and the characters just add so much humour to the screen. The only real problem I have with the movie is the DVD. The DVD lacks completely of special features (and is now out of print). Where is the trailer? (which is totally worth seeing over and over again). Where are the deleted scenes? (There happens to be several deleted scenes). What about the alternate ending (Which is worth watching). Maybe the movie could have been funnier if some of the removed scenes had made it's way into the movie. But still the movie is fine the way it is but again the DVD should feature the removed content in order to appreciate this movie even more. I've seen the work print of the movie and of course the movie itself and yet the trailer has moments that is in neither. What is that all about? Anyway I think the Kids have done a great job here and this movie is perfect for a good laugh but it makes me sad and depressed to see all the missing content from the DVD. Then again watching this movie is a great cure for depression.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seth-287
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw this movie I had never seen the TV series, so I didn't have any preconceived ideas about what this movie was going to be like. I belong to a group of people who question the pharmaceutical industry and the premise of the movie appealed to me. Every time I see this film I find new funny details. At my house we have shown this movie to our friends and they all seemed to love it. Each actor portrays several characters and they are very distinctive. I also think the message throughout is important and this movie is worth watching! It's too bad some people didn't like this movie. I think since the movie wasn't heavily publicized it didn't reach the potential but it's a cult favorite in my circle of friends. I'm surprised Scientology hasn't promoted this movie because it portrays psych meds in an unfavorable light.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Positively Priceless!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RaiderJack
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As this is the only full-length movie of one of the smartest comedy ensembles ever, this is indeed a classic already and worth every second. It is amazing the wealth of characters The Kids in the Hall are capable of drawing upon which further fuels a very well-written satire on society's eagerness to address and cure any and every thing via a pill - notwithstanding the side effects. To be sure, some of the routines may be uncomfortable, especially because they end up being so funny (most notably Cancer Boy) but sometimes this is the only way - either confront a particular societal flaw with a harsh unfunny reality or, in this case, make them laugh so hard they are bound to see the absurdity in a given situation and thus be able to move toward rectifying it. For KITH fans, this is a must; for those of you who enjoy cutting edge comedy, you will not be disappointed!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sub-amateurish, non-talented and puerile
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aristides-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A 1 because there's no way I can rate this a minus 10. Though alive I was figuratively turning over in my grave every time someone likened this 'thing' to a Monty Python show or movie. The Python writers/performers were all brilliant and could skewer society and culture either with a broadsword or a stiletto. These dopes, less talented than Moe, Larry and Curly, can be summed up with one word and that word is "unsubtle". If there was a god of comedy, bolts of lighting would fry the people for uttering the heresy of comparing them to Python. Anything this amateurish and unfunny makes me either reach for my pistol, walk rapidly to the exit or push the off button on the remote in an excessively heavy manner. (Actually I disliked this movie so much I wanted to do all three things simultaneously.) 'Kids' is the absolute bottom of the comedic barrel and could be the worst comedy in motion picture history (maybe there is a god after all because some Force has intervened and determined that they will never make another movie and so thank you Jesus, thank you Muhammed, thank you Vishnu, thank you Buddha!).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a HUGE disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was a fan of THE KIDS IN THE HALL. Yeah, sometimes the jokes went a little flat, but so often it was gosh darn funny and always was quick to take a risk or poke fun at nearly anything. Unfortunately, once the series ended, they decided to make a farewell film. In hindsight, they should have just left well-enough alone. Boy, was I disappointed. So often, when TV shows go to the big screen, the basic chemistry and formula that made them great is adulterated--this is truly the case with this film. Instead of being weird and funny, it was only slightly weird and not the least bit funny or entertaining. I would have been much happier if they had just strung together three episodes as the movie, instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Freakin' Awesome!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    foureyeblindman7
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Holy god! Can comedy get any funnier? I am an absolutely enormous Kids in the Hall fan and although at first this movie didn't strike me as a "Kids" masterpiece like their series was I soon came to realize that the reason I was somewhat disappointed was because I didn't get to see appearances from the legendary "Head-Crusher" or "Buddy" but once I kept watching past the first few minutes and got to catch a glimpse at the classic Don character and of course who can forget Bruce McCulloch as Cancer Boy? So if you don't get to see some classic head crushing bits, what do you get to see? Well, I'm going to answer my own question. You get to see Michael McDonald finding the formula for "happy," Bruce McColloch rockin' out to Happiness Pie and giving us an amazing "Whistle if You're Loved" performance, Mark McKinney playing one of my favorite characters (Don), Dave Foley's awkward moment as the New Scientist, and Scott Thompson dressed up as an old lady spinning around in a giant and pointless testing machine. Probably my favorite scene in the entire movie is Chris Cooper's flash back to his depressed father coming home from working and having trouble shooting himself (which he finally does after 2-hours worth of tries). And then of course there is the kiss shared by Michael McDonald and Bruce McCulloch at the end of the movie. But does this mean that the Kids have strayed away from their roots? Of course not! There is still plenty of cross-dressing, jokes about business men, jokes about Scott Thompson's sexuality, and of course, many absurdly random moments (bird flying into Bruce McCulloch's eye). So if you are a Kids in the Hall fan or a patient diagnosed with depression there is no way you can miss this absolutely hilarious, clever, absurd, and well-written performance by our friends from up North. I can safely say this is classic comedy worthy of Groucho Marx Level praise. WATCH IT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my Top 10 Films Of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JD WaySide
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "It'll make you laugh, it'll make you cry, and maybe - just maybe - you'll learn something about yourself..." ...Seriously! This movie just blew me away on so many levels. First level: Being a longtime fan of the Kids and getting to see many familiar characters once again was a gas. Not to mention some of the new ones they cooked up for the film. Second level: As an exercise in the absurd (Cancer Boy, the gay guy coming out in a big neighbourhood production number, the German psychiatrist). Next level: Satire and stereotype (the CEO screaming, "MY... EMPIRE... IS... CRUUUMMMMBLINNGG!", the punk rocker, the talkshow hostess). Yet another level: Makes a HUGE statement about the corporate-media-industrial complex and its usurpation of contemporary culture and mores. And so on, and so on... Finally, the film, while purporting to be a comedy masking itself as a tragedy (or is it the other way round?) and beneath that pretending to send a negative message about the human condition (like the cabbie says, "This is not a happy story"), manages to have a positive message as well. This movie is an enigma. And as such it's basically indescribable: It'll move you in about six different directions at once. And it might even make you think about a few things. If you've never seen it, get out and rent the bloody thing already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious Even WIthout Knowing The Show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rphguy
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The TV show was funny as hell, although it was sometimes hit-and-miss ; but what sketch show isn't. This movie contains a well planned plot executed by a diverse but motley crew of characters. It makes you think that the BBC show League of Gentlemen isn't as original as you thought it was! Also, the impersonation of Lorne Michaels is spot-on, and makes you think the Dr Evil character from Austin Powers isn't as original as you thought either (as they are both spoofing Mr Michaels - who produced both SNL for Myers and Kids in the Hall). Great fun... and try not to laugh out loud at the 'cancer boy' character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Film Is Gay
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KIDS IN THE HALL ? This is a sketch show I remembered being broadcast in the wee small hours in Britain on channel 4 . I didn't think much of it . No strike that - I hated it . It was composed of a bunch of Canadian MONTY PYTHON wannabes who dressed in drag more often than not and made sketches that fell flat . I can remember the " I'm crushing your head " character because of the simple reason it was so unfunny and it's no surprise that Canadians I know much prefer British TV like THE OFFICE and DOCTOR WHO BRAIN CANDY is a feature length film by the KITH troupe and as many people have already pointed out you'll only enjoy this movie if you're already a fan , if you've never heard of these kids you will probably dislike with a vengeance with the humour being either underdeveloped or plain crude like the scene where a NCO orders one of his men into battle: " You see these two men beside the wall ? You run over there and f*ck them while we stay here and masturbate " I also couldn't help thinking that because BRAIN CANDY is a spin off from a sketch show the screenplay lacks cohesion , events and scenes happen without any rhyme nor reason like for example a scene cutting to a music award show where Cancer Boy performs a song only for the action to then cut away to another location with Cancer Boy then absent for the rest of the film I certainly didn't enjoy BRAIN CANDY and unless you're a KIDS IN THE HALL fan or someone who enjoys watching men dress up as woman it's highly likely you'll feel the same way
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
