<filme>
 <id>
  1081
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0115994
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Eles Matam e N&oacute;s Limpamos
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Gabriella, a Colombian immigrant, is obsessed with understanding violent crime. The current string of murders by "The Blue Blood Killer" of affluent Miami socialites provides her with ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Gabriella, a Colombian immigrant, is obsessed with understanding violent crime. The current string of murders by "The Blue Blood Killer" of affluent Miami socialites provides her with fodder for her scrapbook of death. She lands a job with a post-murder cleaning service and during a Blue-Blood clean-up job, discovers evidence that police have overlooked.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   murder
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   blood
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   scrapbook
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   post murder cleaning service
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   death
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Reb Braddock
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Reb Braddock
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   John Maass
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   William Baldwin
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Angela Jones
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Bruce Ramsay
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stylish, Dark and a must-see for fans of black comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stuntman Mike
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film does everything that it wants to do right, and it does it in a time frame that fits. Unlike most Tarantino flicks this movie has a less than 90 minute run-time, which could leave a certain fan unfulfilled and unsatisfied by the end. That being said, the film is fantastic in the time it's given, it's full of details, style and a soundtrack that honestly made me stand up and dance. The main character is a young Columbian woman, Gabriella, who has an obsession for gore and a serial killer "The Blue Blood Killer" who specializes in murdering and cutting off the heads of rich women, clean cut with a Tanto. Gabriella begins working for a forensic clean up crew, but finds more interest with the scene of the crime than the cleaning. The ending may come a bit sooner than you would think, but it feels very similar to the ending of Inglorious Basterds, and will leave you smiling and satisfied if you see the film for what it is and is trying to be. A solid 8 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I think they talk. They could tell you something.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ReasonlsOutToLunch
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This always quirky, sometimes funny, sometimes dark, and sometimes misses film isn't a masterpiece. But, certain scenes make it worth watching. The exchange between Baldwin and Jones is one of those scenes. Gabriela is obsessed with violent crime. When she sees an ad on TV from a crime scene cleaning company she quickly contacts them to get a job with them. She is reluctantly hired and quits her other job. It gets somewhat slow at this point, but a key scene is when her partner complains about Gabriela's childlike behavior. The juxtaposition of Gabriela's demeanor, the crime scene, and her happy salsa music is a strange combination indeed. It sometimes works and it is sometimes grating. William Baldwin as Paul Guell is actually quite brilliant and doesn't get enough credit. You have no idea how much it pains me to write that. But, anyway here it is. He has a very difficult job to do here and he pulls it off and makes it look easy. He has to be a menacing serial killer, check he is very creepy. He has to manage to make it funny somehow as well, check. As mentioned before his exchange with Jones, was well worth watching the movie. He also manages to show some sensitivity, we can almost see into the pit of his dark soul, what motivates him to kill. It does't all work however, there are parts that are so illogical. Aside from the fact that the childlike main character is obsessed with violent crime. Things that would never ever happen in real life. I will have to leave it at that, if you watch the film you will spot at least one glaring example at near the end of the film. The ending will leave you with more questions than this film can answer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very black and bloody horror comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Indyrod
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This very black and bloody horror comedy is a real favorite of mine, ever since I first saw it on cable several years ago. Tarantino saw the original short film while promoting his Reservior Dogs at an Italian film festival, and suggested the filmmakers to expand it to a feature film, and he would produce it. They did of course, and to me, this is a work of art, with a film score that fits about as perfect to the scenes as any I have seen. Angela Jones plays Gabriela, a Columbian beauty that has moved to Miami, and has an obsession with bloody crime scenes. She gets a job with a company that cleans up crime scenes, and she starts following the news accounts of a serial killer played by William Baldwin. After his recent murder, she gets assigned the job of cleaning up the bloody mess, and doesn't know it, but the killer is locked in the wine closet because he left a clue to his identity. Soon, there is the grand finale, which is a danse macabre between the two, with an ending that knocked me out of my chair when I first saw it. This is black comedy at it's darkest and most fun, and the DVD is loaded with features including an intro and outro by Tarantino. It also contains the original 30 minute short version of the movie. I absolutely love this movie, and recommend it very highly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A young woman fascinated with murders gets a job cleaning up murder sites.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ltlacey
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a total surprise. It's fast-paced and will hold your interest the entire time. As a girl, Gabriela witnesses, so to speak, the murder of a man. From then on out she becomes totally fascinated by murder and keeps a scrapbook full of drawings and clippings. As an adult she lives in Miami and ends up working at a place that cleans up after murders (suicides). Cleaners, as they are called. During this time a serial killer is on the loose and Gabriela is hooked. What makes this movie so great is Jones, who plays the young woman, and her somewhat warped sense of killings. The scene where she's dancing with the knife, re-living the latest murder is perfect. Though there's a lot of blood, and the near final scene is audibly graphic (you do not see anything), it's also one of the funniest, for those of us who appreciate a very warped sense of humor. In the Special Features Quentin Tarantino explains why this actress was so perfect for the part, and he's spot on, as even while watching her (prior to watching the SF) you could just tell. He talks about a sparkle in her eye. Her entire body lights up in this part. Everyone else, even Baldwin (as the killer), does not come close, though he did a fairly good job, especially in their scene where they are together dancing. And you know who the killer is from the beginning, so I'm not spoiling an ending here. Find this gem and watch it over and over again. Each time you will catch something new that Jones does. She's a very physical actress and I hope to see more of her, and soon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why Short Shouldn't Go Long...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bolesroor
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quentin Tarantino, aglow with the buzz-borne light from the soon-to-be-released "Pulp Fiction," was sitting in a darkened theater with his producer/pal Lawrence Bender, enjoying a short-film festival. The short being screened was called "Curdled," and it was about a Latin woman working for a housekeeping service that specialized in cleaning up crime scenes for murderers and killers. I picture our hydro-cephalic hero QT laughing so loud he annoyed everyone in the theater, including the film's writer/director Reb Braddock. But Braddock needn't have worried. Our fat-headed pop-culture savant got up from his seat when the short was over, sought out Reb and declared, full of his own ego and I can only guess Goobers, "Listen to me, Mr. Braddock, alriiiiiiiight? We're gonna take your short film and make it into a feature, okaaaaaaaaay? You'll write/direct and I'll produce, alriiiiiiiiiiight?" And so the feature-length version of "Curdled" was born. I'm scarcely exaggerating this story because it is the version told by Quentin himself in the film's bonus material. Could any aspiring director refuse the offer of a then white-hot Tarantino? Could you? Unfortunately for us the feature is nothing more than the 10 min. short stretched out over an hour and a half. Which strangely feels like three hours. Thrill as Nothing happens in slow motion. Watch the immediately-attractive Angela Jones (Butch's cabbie in Pulp Fiction) become less and less adorable as sheer boredom numbs your senses. Laugh at a one-joke black comedy that manages to kill the joke after twenty minutes. Rock to a movie so bad its writer/director Reb Braddock never wrote/directed anything ever again. At all. What did we learn today? We learned that short films don't necessarily translate into feature-length. We learned that even Latin women need good story lines to hold onto our attention. And most importantly: If Quentin Tarantino ever approaches you in a theater with greazy fingers and a shlt-eating grin you need to evacuate the premises as soon as possible. That's what Fire Exits are for. GRADE: D-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cool And Quirky Horror/Dark-Comedy/Thriller....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    EVOL666
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I picked this one up at the recommendation of a few people that I "trust" - and though it is not the typical sleaze/gore/trash that I pump into my brain at a record-pace - it is a truly funny, well-made and entertaining little number. Although there is some blood, don't expect a bloodbath, and there's no nudity (which DOES suck...) but this one is good on it's own merits as a fun and pretty original film... Gabriella is a sweet young girl, who has been obsessed with murder and death since an early age. To satisfy this obsession, she takes a job with a cleaning agency that specializes in cleaning up murder/accident scenes. When the opportunity arises to clean the house where one of a string of the "Blueblood" serial-killer murders occurred - Gabriella jumps at the chance. Unfortunately - her enthusiasm may bring her just a bit closer to the murders than she really wants to be...or does she??? CURDLED truly is an enjoyable and original film. More than anything - the performances carry the film. Angela Jones as Gabriella is both naive and adorable, but also strangely sexy and intense. There are a ton of people you'll "recognize" in this one, in both large and small roles - William Baldwin, Kelly Preston, Daisy Fuentes, a quick shot of Clooney and Tarantino from DUSK TIL DAWN on a "crime-show", and the guy that plays Gabriella's boss (I forget his name, but he's been in a ton of stuff too - he was the one big "boss" in WAR GAMES...) - and all the performances are pretty top-notch. The directing is also confident and well done, and the music direction adds to the overall "quirkiness" of the whole film. If you dig strange black-comedies, you'll probably dig this one. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forgettable and familiar horror yarn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Void
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From it's uninspiring title to the flat acting performances, Curdled is very much an unremarkable film throughout. The film has gained some fans by way of the fact that Quentin Tarantino's name is attached to it, and the silly and out of place nod to the Rodriguez/Tarantino flick 'From Dusk till Dawn'. These things do not make a great movie, however, and this is more than evident all the way through 'Curdled'. The film suffers from an all too obvious lack of ideas, and it tries to mask this with murders that are meant to be stylish and events that are supposed to be disturbing. The Mexican music score that accompanies many of the sequences in the film is obviously meant to be cool, but it's becomes annoying very quickly; especially as aside from the fact that the lead character is Mexican, it doesn't fit with the tone of the movie. The film's plot is typically offbeat and it follows a gorehound who, because of her obsession with grisly murders, takes a job with a firm that cleans up murder scenes. It sounds boring and it is. William Baldwin is the only 'name' on the cast list, and even he doesn't make an impression. He hasn't been given anything to do in the movie and aside from talking to his victims and standing around trying to look menacing, he's pretty much wasted. Angela Jones, or rather; the taxi driver from Pulp Fiction, takes the lead role as the murder obsessed young woman, and it is always clear that it's her involvement with Pulp Fiction that won her this role, not her acting ability. She may have been good enough in her small role in Tarantino's masterpiece, but she doesn't have the talent to lead a film by herself. She looks lost and out of place for the majority of the film, and if it weren't for her Latino accent; she wouldn't convince the audience that she's a weirdo on any level. Curdled is a one hundred percent-proof piece of forgettable trash. Films like this often win themselves praise for invention or black comedic antics; but this one fails on all levels. Whether you're a Tarantino fan, William Baldwin fan, horror fan or just a movie buff; this is one to miss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Curdled cheese...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cwatts-2 (cwatts@hypd.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is definitely unique in that it's original. Quentin Tarantino produced this film and put it under his now failed Rolling Thunder Pictures. The film in its essence had a lot of potential and really had a great leading actress, but it had its share of problems. If your a fan of Tarantino like I am you prob. will rent this no matter what anyone says, but I would recommend this movie with caution because it just a mediocre middle of the year release that Miramax quickly buried under its large pile of flops. The special features of this film are the best part. With the thesis student film attached to the DVD along with an intro and outro by Quentin himself. Overall not much here but you may find some qualities that can be enjoyed by all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The heads...do they talk?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ThrownMuse
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion, this is one of the most underrated movies of the 90s, featuring one of my all-time favorite performances by the enchanting Angela Jones. It is based on a short made in 1991, about a childlike murder-obsessed Colombian-American who takes a job as a maid...who cleans up after violent murders. Apparently, Tarantino liked the short so much that he cast Jones in Pulp Fiction and produced a full length version of "Curdled" with Jones and William Baldwin (who is surprisingly great.) This is one of my favorite black comedies and easily the funniest serial killer thriller ever. Angela Jones lights up the screen with her animated facial expressions (think Audrey Tautou) and quirky delivery. Oh, and this movie features one of the best dance sequences in a movie (yes, even better than Britt Ekland's in "The Wicker Man"). The recently released DVD is a blessing and surprisingly chockful of extras (including the original short film) for a movie that is apparently so reviled. The worst thing I can say about "Curdled" is that Braddock didn't go on to make another film and Jones went on to do a freakin "Children of the Corn" sequel. Recommend to all fans of serial killer movies and dark comedies. My rating: 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my All-Time Fav Movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gothgate
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Darkly funny. I love this movie and can watch it again and again. William Baldwin & Angela Jones are perfect in their roles as a serial killer and a woman who cleans up in his victim's homes after the police have gone. Gabriella, the cleaner, is a great character. She epitomizes the people who are fascinated by serial killers. In some ways this movie reminds me of CSI and Forensic Files and shows like that. Lots of good law-abiding people watch them and not just to imagine themselves on the cops' side, but to fantasize about being criminals and toy with their dark side. The best part is her salsa "dance with the devil" as she reinacts one of the killer's crimes for him. I don't know why this movie got such a bum rap. I think it's great!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stylish, Dark and a must-see for fans of black comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stuntman Mike
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film does everything that it wants to do right, and it does it in a time frame that fits. Unlike most Tarantino flicks this movie has a less than 90 minute run-time, which could leave a certain fan unfulfilled and unsatisfied by the end. That being said, the film is fantastic in the time it's given, it's full of details, style and a soundtrack that honestly made me stand up and dance. The main character is a young Columbian woman, Gabriella, who has an obsession for gore and a serial killer "The Blue Blood Killer" who specializes in murdering and cutting off the heads of rich women, clean cut with a Tanto. Gabriella begins working for a forensic clean up crew, but finds more interest with the scene of the crime than the cleaning. The ending may come a bit sooner than you would think, but it feels very similar to the ending of Inglorious Basterds, and will leave you smiling and satisfied if you see the film for what it is and is trying to be. A solid 8 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I think they talk. They could tell you something.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ReasonlsOutToLunch
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This always quirky, sometimes funny, sometimes dark, and sometimes misses film isn't a masterpiece. But, certain scenes make it worth watching. The exchange between Baldwin and Jones is one of those scenes. Gabriela is obsessed with violent crime. When she sees an ad on TV from a crime scene cleaning company she quickly contacts them to get a job with them. She is reluctantly hired and quits her other job. It gets somewhat slow at this point, but a key scene is when her partner complains about Gabriela's childlike behavior. The juxtaposition of Gabriela's demeanor, the crime scene, and her happy salsa music is a strange combination indeed. It sometimes works and it is sometimes grating. William Baldwin as Paul Guell is actually quite brilliant and doesn't get enough credit. You have no idea how much it pains me to write that. But, anyway here it is. He has a very difficult job to do here and he pulls it off and makes it look easy. He has to be a menacing serial killer, check he is very creepy. He has to manage to make it funny somehow as well, check. As mentioned before his exchange with Jones, was well worth watching the movie. He also manages to show some sensitivity, we can almost see into the pit of his dark soul, what motivates him to kill. It does't all work however, there are parts that are so illogical. Aside from the fact that the childlike main character is obsessed with violent crime. Things that would never ever happen in real life. I will have to leave it at that, if you watch the film you will spot at least one glaring example at near the end of the film. The ending will leave you with more questions than this film can answer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very black and bloody horror comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Indyrod
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This very black and bloody horror comedy is a real favorite of mine, ever since I first saw it on cable several years ago. Tarantino saw the original short film while promoting his Reservior Dogs at an Italian film festival, and suggested the filmmakers to expand it to a feature film, and he would produce it. They did of course, and to me, this is a work of art, with a film score that fits about as perfect to the scenes as any I have seen. Angela Jones plays Gabriela, a Columbian beauty that has moved to Miami, and has an obsession with bloody crime scenes. She gets a job with a company that cleans up crime scenes, and she starts following the news accounts of a serial killer played by William Baldwin. After his recent murder, she gets assigned the job of cleaning up the bloody mess, and doesn't know it, but the killer is locked in the wine closet because he left a clue to his identity. Soon, there is the grand finale, which is a danse macabre between the two, with an ending that knocked me out of my chair when I first saw it. This is black comedy at it's darkest and most fun, and the DVD is loaded with features including an intro and outro by Tarantino. It also contains the original 30 minute short version of the movie. I absolutely love this movie, and recommend it very highly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A young woman fascinated with murders gets a job cleaning up murder sites.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ltlacey
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a total surprise. It's fast-paced and will hold your interest the entire time. As a girl, Gabriela witnesses, so to speak, the murder of a man. From then on out she becomes totally fascinated by murder and keeps a scrapbook full of drawings and clippings. As an adult she lives in Miami and ends up working at a place that cleans up after murders (suicides). Cleaners, as they are called. During this time a serial killer is on the loose and Gabriela is hooked. What makes this movie so great is Jones, who plays the young woman, and her somewhat warped sense of killings. The scene where she's dancing with the knife, re-living the latest murder is perfect. Though there's a lot of blood, and the near final scene is audibly graphic (you do not see anything), it's also one of the funniest, for those of us who appreciate a very warped sense of humor. In the Special Features Quentin Tarantino explains why this actress was so perfect for the part, and he's spot on, as even while watching her (prior to watching the SF) you could just tell. He talks about a sparkle in her eye. Her entire body lights up in this part. Everyone else, even Baldwin (as the killer), does not come close, though he did a fairly good job, especially in their scene where they are together dancing. And you know who the killer is from the beginning, so I'm not spoiling an ending here. Find this gem and watch it over and over again. Each time you will catch something new that Jones does. She's a very physical actress and I hope to see more of her, and soon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why Short Shouldn't Go Long...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bolesroor
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quentin Tarantino, aglow with the buzz-borne light from the soon-to-be-released "Pulp Fiction," was sitting in a darkened theater with his producer/pal Lawrence Bender, enjoying a short-film festival. The short being screened was called "Curdled," and it was about a Latin woman working for a housekeeping service that specialized in cleaning up crime scenes for murderers and killers. I picture our hydro-cephalic hero QT laughing so loud he annoyed everyone in the theater, including the film's writer/director Reb Braddock. But Braddock needn't have worried. Our fat-headed pop-culture savant got up from his seat when the short was over, sought out Reb and declared, full of his own ego and I can only guess Goobers, "Listen to me, Mr. Braddock, alriiiiiiiight? We're gonna take your short film and make it into a feature, okaaaaaaaaay? You'll write/direct and I'll produce, alriiiiiiiiiiight?" And so the feature-length version of "Curdled" was born. I'm scarcely exaggerating this story because it is the version told by Quentin himself in the film's bonus material. Could any aspiring director refuse the offer of a then white-hot Tarantino? Could you? Unfortunately for us the feature is nothing more than the 10 min. short stretched out over an hour and a half. Which strangely feels like three hours. Thrill as Nothing happens in slow motion. Watch the immediately-attractive Angela Jones (Butch's cabbie in Pulp Fiction) become less and less adorable as sheer boredom numbs your senses. Laugh at a one-joke black comedy that manages to kill the joke after twenty minutes. Rock to a movie so bad its writer/director Reb Braddock never wrote/directed anything ever again. At all. What did we learn today? We learned that short films don't necessarily translate into feature-length. We learned that even Latin women need good story lines to hold onto our attention. And most importantly: If Quentin Tarantino ever approaches you in a theater with greazy fingers and a shlt-eating grin you need to evacuate the premises as soon as possible. That's what Fire Exits are for. GRADE: D-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cool And Quirky Horror/Dark-Comedy/Thriller....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    EVOL666
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I picked this one up at the recommendation of a few people that I "trust" - and though it is not the typical sleaze/gore/trash that I pump into my brain at a record-pace - it is a truly funny, well-made and entertaining little number. Although there is some blood, don't expect a bloodbath, and there's no nudity (which DOES suck...) but this one is good on it's own merits as a fun and pretty original film... Gabriella is a sweet young girl, who has been obsessed with murder and death since an early age. To satisfy this obsession, she takes a job with a cleaning agency that specializes in cleaning up murder/accident scenes. When the opportunity arises to clean the house where one of a string of the "Blueblood" serial-killer murders occurred - Gabriella jumps at the chance. Unfortunately - her enthusiasm may bring her just a bit closer to the murders than she really wants to be...or does she??? CURDLED truly is an enjoyable and original film. More than anything - the performances carry the film. Angela Jones as Gabriella is both naive and adorable, but also strangely sexy and intense. There are a ton of people you'll "recognize" in this one, in both large and small roles - William Baldwin, Kelly Preston, Daisy Fuentes, a quick shot of Clooney and Tarantino from DUSK TIL DAWN on a "crime-show", and the guy that plays Gabriella's boss (I forget his name, but he's been in a ton of stuff too - he was the one big "boss" in WAR GAMES...) - and all the performances are pretty top-notch. The directing is also confident and well done, and the music direction adds to the overall "quirkiness" of the whole film. If you dig strange black-comedies, you'll probably dig this one. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forgettable and familiar horror yarn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Void
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From it's uninspiring title to the flat acting performances, Curdled is very much an unremarkable film throughout. The film has gained some fans by way of the fact that Quentin Tarantino's name is attached to it, and the silly and out of place nod to the Rodriguez/Tarantino flick 'From Dusk till Dawn'. These things do not make a great movie, however, and this is more than evident all the way through 'Curdled'. The film suffers from an all too obvious lack of ideas, and it tries to mask this with murders that are meant to be stylish and events that are supposed to be disturbing. The Mexican music score that accompanies many of the sequences in the film is obviously meant to be cool, but it's becomes annoying very quickly; especially as aside from the fact that the lead character is Mexican, it doesn't fit with the tone of the movie. The film's plot is typically offbeat and it follows a gorehound who, because of her obsession with grisly murders, takes a job with a firm that cleans up murder scenes. It sounds boring and it is. William Baldwin is the only 'name' on the cast list, and even he doesn't make an impression. He hasn't been given anything to do in the movie and aside from talking to his victims and standing around trying to look menacing, he's pretty much wasted. Angela Jones, or rather; the taxi driver from Pulp Fiction, takes the lead role as the murder obsessed young woman, and it is always clear that it's her involvement with Pulp Fiction that won her this role, not her acting ability. She may have been good enough in her small role in Tarantino's masterpiece, but she doesn't have the talent to lead a film by herself. She looks lost and out of place for the majority of the film, and if it weren't for her Latino accent; she wouldn't convince the audience that she's a weirdo on any level. Curdled is a one hundred percent-proof piece of forgettable trash. Films like this often win themselves praise for invention or black comedic antics; but this one fails on all levels. Whether you're a Tarantino fan, William Baldwin fan, horror fan or just a movie buff; this is one to miss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Curdled cheese...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cwatts-2 (cwatts@hypd.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is definitely unique in that it's original. Quentin Tarantino produced this film and put it under his now failed Rolling Thunder Pictures. The film in its essence had a lot of potential and really had a great leading actress, but it had its share of problems. If your a fan of Tarantino like I am you prob. will rent this no matter what anyone says, but I would recommend this movie with caution because it just a mediocre middle of the year release that Miramax quickly buried under its large pile of flops. The special features of this film are the best part. With the thesis student film attached to the DVD along with an intro and outro by Quentin himself. Overall not much here but you may find some qualities that can be enjoyed by all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The heads...do they talk?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ThrownMuse
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion, this is one of the most underrated movies of the 90s, featuring one of my all-time favorite performances by the enchanting Angela Jones. It is based on a short made in 1991, about a childlike murder-obsessed Colombian-American who takes a job as a maid...who cleans up after violent murders. Apparently, Tarantino liked the short so much that he cast Jones in Pulp Fiction and produced a full length version of "Curdled" with Jones and William Baldwin (who is surprisingly great.) This is one of my favorite black comedies and easily the funniest serial killer thriller ever. Angela Jones lights up the screen with her animated facial expressions (think Audrey Tautou) and quirky delivery. Oh, and this movie features one of the best dance sequences in a movie (yes, even better than Britt Ekland's in "The Wicker Man"). The recently released DVD is a blessing and surprisingly chockful of extras (including the original short film) for a movie that is apparently so reviled. The worst thing I can say about "Curdled" is that Braddock didn't go on to make another film and Jones went on to do a freakin "Children of the Corn" sequel. Recommend to all fans of serial killer movies and dark comedies. My rating: 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my All-Time Fav Movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gothgate
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Darkly funny. I love this movie and can watch it again and again. William Baldwin & Angela Jones are perfect in their roles as a serial killer and a woman who cleans up in his victim's homes after the police have gone. Gabriella, the cleaner, is a great character. She epitomizes the people who are fascinated by serial killers. In some ways this movie reminds me of CSI and Forensic Files and shows like that. Lots of good law-abiding people watch them and not just to imagine themselves on the cops' side, but to fantasize about being criminals and toy with their dark side. The best part is her salsa "dance with the devil" as she reinacts one of the killer's crimes for him. I don't know why this movie got such a bum rap. I think it's great!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stylish, Dark and a must-see for fans of black comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stuntman Mike
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film does everything that it wants to do right, and it does it in a time frame that fits. Unlike most Tarantino flicks this movie has a less than 90 minute run-time, which could leave a certain fan unfulfilled and unsatisfied by the end. That being said, the film is fantastic in the time it's given, it's full of details, style and a soundtrack that honestly made me stand up and dance. The main character is a young Columbian woman, Gabriella, who has an obsession for gore and a serial killer "The Blue Blood Killer" who specializes in murdering and cutting off the heads of rich women, clean cut with a Tanto. Gabriella begins working for a forensic clean up crew, but finds more interest with the scene of the crime than the cleaning. The ending may come a bit sooner than you would think, but it feels very similar to the ending of Inglorious Basterds, and will leave you smiling and satisfied if you see the film for what it is and is trying to be. A solid 8 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I think they talk. They could tell you something.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ReasonlsOutToLunch
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This always quirky, sometimes funny, sometimes dark, and sometimes misses film isn't a masterpiece. But, certain scenes make it worth watching. The exchange between Baldwin and Jones is one of those scenes. Gabriela is obsessed with violent crime. When she sees an ad on TV from a crime scene cleaning company she quickly contacts them to get a job with them. She is reluctantly hired and quits her other job. It gets somewhat slow at this point, but a key scene is when her partner complains about Gabriela's childlike behavior. The juxtaposition of Gabriela's demeanor, the crime scene, and her happy salsa music is a strange combination indeed. It sometimes works and it is sometimes grating. William Baldwin as Paul Guell is actually quite brilliant and doesn't get enough credit. You have no idea how much it pains me to write that. But, anyway here it is. He has a very difficult job to do here and he pulls it off and makes it look easy. He has to be a menacing serial killer, check he is very creepy. He has to manage to make it funny somehow as well, check. As mentioned before his exchange with Jones, was well worth watching the movie. He also manages to show some sensitivity, we can almost see into the pit of his dark soul, what motivates him to kill. It does't all work however, there are parts that are so illogical. Aside from the fact that the childlike main character is obsessed with violent crime. Things that would never ever happen in real life. I will have to leave it at that, if you watch the film you will spot at least one glaring example at near the end of the film. The ending will leave you with more questions than this film can answer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very black and bloody horror comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Indyrod
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This very black and bloody horror comedy is a real favorite of mine, ever since I first saw it on cable several years ago. Tarantino saw the original short film while promoting his Reservior Dogs at an Italian film festival, and suggested the filmmakers to expand it to a feature film, and he would produce it. They did of course, and to me, this is a work of art, with a film score that fits about as perfect to the scenes as any I have seen. Angela Jones plays Gabriela, a Columbian beauty that has moved to Miami, and has an obsession with bloody crime scenes. She gets a job with a company that cleans up crime scenes, and she starts following the news accounts of a serial killer played by William Baldwin. After his recent murder, she gets assigned the job of cleaning up the bloody mess, and doesn't know it, but the killer is locked in the wine closet because he left a clue to his identity. Soon, there is the grand finale, which is a danse macabre between the two, with an ending that knocked me out of my chair when I first saw it. This is black comedy at it's darkest and most fun, and the DVD is loaded with features including an intro and outro by Tarantino. It also contains the original 30 minute short version of the movie. I absolutely love this movie, and recommend it very highly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A young woman fascinated with murders gets a job cleaning up murder sites.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ltlacey
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a total surprise. It's fast-paced and will hold your interest the entire time. As a girl, Gabriela witnesses, so to speak, the murder of a man. From then on out she becomes totally fascinated by murder and keeps a scrapbook full of drawings and clippings. As an adult she lives in Miami and ends up working at a place that cleans up after murders (suicides). Cleaners, as they are called. During this time a serial killer is on the loose and Gabriela is hooked. What makes this movie so great is Jones, who plays the young woman, and her somewhat warped sense of killings. The scene where she's dancing with the knife, re-living the latest murder is perfect. Though there's a lot of blood, and the near final scene is audibly graphic (you do not see anything), it's also one of the funniest, for those of us who appreciate a very warped sense of humor. In the Special Features Quentin Tarantino explains why this actress was so perfect for the part, and he's spot on, as even while watching her (prior to watching the SF) you could just tell. He talks about a sparkle in her eye. Her entire body lights up in this part. Everyone else, even Baldwin (as the killer), does not come close, though he did a fairly good job, especially in their scene where they are together dancing. And you know who the killer is from the beginning, so I'm not spoiling an ending here. Find this gem and watch it over and over again. Each time you will catch something new that Jones does. She's a very physical actress and I hope to see more of her, and soon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why Short Shouldn't Go Long...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bolesroor
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quentin Tarantino, aglow with the buzz-borne light from the soon-to-be-released "Pulp Fiction," was sitting in a darkened theater with his producer/pal Lawrence Bender, enjoying a short-film festival. The short being screened was called "Curdled," and it was about a Latin woman working for a housekeeping service that specialized in cleaning up crime scenes for murderers and killers. I picture our hydro-cephalic hero QT laughing so loud he annoyed everyone in the theater, including the film's writer/director Reb Braddock. But Braddock needn't have worried. Our fat-headed pop-culture savant got up from his seat when the short was over, sought out Reb and declared, full of his own ego and I can only guess Goobers, "Listen to me, Mr. Braddock, alriiiiiiiight? We're gonna take your short film and make it into a feature, okaaaaaaaaay? You'll write/direct and I'll produce, alriiiiiiiiiiight?" And so the feature-length version of "Curdled" was born. I'm scarcely exaggerating this story because it is the version told by Quentin himself in the film's bonus material. Could any aspiring director refuse the offer of a then white-hot Tarantino? Could you? Unfortunately for us the feature is nothing more than the 10 min. short stretched out over an hour and a half. Which strangely feels like three hours. Thrill as Nothing happens in slow motion. Watch the immediately-attractive Angela Jones (Butch's cabbie in Pulp Fiction) become less and less adorable as sheer boredom numbs your senses. Laugh at a one-joke black comedy that manages to kill the joke after twenty minutes. Rock to a movie so bad its writer/director Reb Braddock never wrote/directed anything ever again. At all. What did we learn today? We learned that short films don't necessarily translate into feature-length. We learned that even Latin women need good story lines to hold onto our attention. And most importantly: If Quentin Tarantino ever approaches you in a theater with greazy fingers and a shlt-eating grin you need to evacuate the premises as soon as possible. That's what Fire Exits are for. GRADE: D-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cool And Quirky Horror/Dark-Comedy/Thriller....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    EVOL666
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I picked this one up at the recommendation of a few people that I "trust" - and though it is not the typical sleaze/gore/trash that I pump into my brain at a record-pace - it is a truly funny, well-made and entertaining little number. Although there is some blood, don't expect a bloodbath, and there's no nudity (which DOES suck...) but this one is good on it's own merits as a fun and pretty original film... Gabriella is a sweet young girl, who has been obsessed with murder and death since an early age. To satisfy this obsession, she takes a job with a cleaning agency that specializes in cleaning up murder/accident scenes. When the opportunity arises to clean the house where one of a string of the "Blueblood" serial-killer murders occurred - Gabriella jumps at the chance. Unfortunately - her enthusiasm may bring her just a bit closer to the murders than she really wants to be...or does she??? CURDLED truly is an enjoyable and original film. More than anything - the performances carry the film. Angela Jones as Gabriella is both naive and adorable, but also strangely sexy and intense. There are a ton of people you'll "recognize" in this one, in both large and small roles - William Baldwin, Kelly Preston, Daisy Fuentes, a quick shot of Clooney and Tarantino from DUSK TIL DAWN on a "crime-show", and the guy that plays Gabriella's boss (I forget his name, but he's been in a ton of stuff too - he was the one big "boss" in WAR GAMES...) - and all the performances are pretty top-notch. The directing is also confident and well done, and the music direction adds to the overall "quirkiness" of the whole film. If you dig strange black-comedies, you'll probably dig this one. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forgettable and familiar horror yarn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Void
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From it's uninspiring title to the flat acting performances, Curdled is very much an unremarkable film throughout. The film has gained some fans by way of the fact that Quentin Tarantino's name is attached to it, and the silly and out of place nod to the Rodriguez/Tarantino flick 'From Dusk till Dawn'. These things do not make a great movie, however, and this is more than evident all the way through 'Curdled'. The film suffers from an all too obvious lack of ideas, and it tries to mask this with murders that are meant to be stylish and events that are supposed to be disturbing. The Mexican music score that accompanies many of the sequences in the film is obviously meant to be cool, but it's becomes annoying very quickly; especially as aside from the fact that the lead character is Mexican, it doesn't fit with the tone of the movie. The film's plot is typically offbeat and it follows a gorehound who, because of her obsession with grisly murders, takes a job with a firm that cleans up murder scenes. It sounds boring and it is. William Baldwin is the only 'name' on the cast list, and even he doesn't make an impression. He hasn't been given anything to do in the movie and aside from talking to his victims and standing around trying to look menacing, he's pretty much wasted. Angela Jones, or rather; the taxi driver from Pulp Fiction, takes the lead role as the murder obsessed young woman, and it is always clear that it's her involvement with Pulp Fiction that won her this role, not her acting ability. She may have been good enough in her small role in Tarantino's masterpiece, but she doesn't have the talent to lead a film by herself. She looks lost and out of place for the majority of the film, and if it weren't for her Latino accent; she wouldn't convince the audience that she's a weirdo on any level. Curdled is a one hundred percent-proof piece of forgettable trash. Films like this often win themselves praise for invention or black comedic antics; but this one fails on all levels. Whether you're a Tarantino fan, William Baldwin fan, horror fan or just a movie buff; this is one to miss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Curdled cheese...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cwatts-2 (cwatts@hypd.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is definitely unique in that it's original. Quentin Tarantino produced this film and put it under his now failed Rolling Thunder Pictures. The film in its essence had a lot of potential and really had a great leading actress, but it had its share of problems. If your a fan of Tarantino like I am you prob. will rent this no matter what anyone says, but I would recommend this movie with caution because it just a mediocre middle of the year release that Miramax quickly buried under its large pile of flops. The special features of this film are the best part. With the thesis student film attached to the DVD along with an intro and outro by Quentin himself. Overall not much here but you may find some qualities that can be enjoyed by all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The heads...do they talk?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ThrownMuse
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion, this is one of the most underrated movies of the 90s, featuring one of my all-time favorite performances by the enchanting Angela Jones. It is based on a short made in 1991, about a childlike murder-obsessed Colombian-American who takes a job as a maid...who cleans up after violent murders. Apparently, Tarantino liked the short so much that he cast Jones in Pulp Fiction and produced a full length version of "Curdled" with Jones and William Baldwin (who is surprisingly great.) This is one of my favorite black comedies and easily the funniest serial killer thriller ever. Angela Jones lights up the screen with her animated facial expressions (think Audrey Tautou) and quirky delivery. Oh, and this movie features one of the best dance sequences in a movie (yes, even better than Britt Ekland's in "The Wicker Man"). The recently released DVD is a blessing and surprisingly chockful of extras (including the original short film) for a movie that is apparently so reviled. The worst thing I can say about "Curdled" is that Braddock didn't go on to make another film and Jones went on to do a freakin "Children of the Corn" sequel. Recommend to all fans of serial killer movies and dark comedies. My rating: 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my All-Time Fav Movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gothgate
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Darkly funny. I love this movie and can watch it again and again. William Baldwin & Angela Jones are perfect in their roles as a serial killer and a woman who cleans up in his victim's homes after the police have gone. Gabriella, the cleaner, is a great character. She epitomizes the people who are fascinated by serial killers. In some ways this movie reminds me of CSI and Forensic Files and shows like that. Lots of good law-abiding people watch them and not just to imagine themselves on the cops' side, but to fantasize about being criminals and toy with their dark side. The best part is her salsa "dance with the devil" as she reinacts one of the killer's crimes for him. I don't know why this movie got such a bum rap. I think it's great!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stylish, Dark and a must-see for fans of black comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stuntman Mike
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film does everything that it wants to do right, and it does it in a time frame that fits. Unlike most Tarantino flicks this movie has a less than 90 minute run-time, which could leave a certain fan unfulfilled and unsatisfied by the end. That being said, the film is fantastic in the time it's given, it's full of details, style and a soundtrack that honestly made me stand up and dance. The main character is a young Columbian woman, Gabriella, who has an obsession for gore and a serial killer "The Blue Blood Killer" who specializes in murdering and cutting off the heads of rich women, clean cut with a Tanto. Gabriella begins working for a forensic clean up crew, but finds more interest with the scene of the crime than the cleaning. The ending may come a bit sooner than you would think, but it feels very similar to the ending of Inglorious Basterds, and will leave you smiling and satisfied if you see the film for what it is and is trying to be. A solid 8 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I think they talk. They could tell you something.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ReasonlsOutToLunch
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This always quirky, sometimes funny, sometimes dark, and sometimes misses film isn't a masterpiece. But, certain scenes make it worth watching. The exchange between Baldwin and Jones is one of those scenes. Gabriela is obsessed with violent crime. When she sees an ad on TV from a crime scene cleaning company she quickly contacts them to get a job with them. She is reluctantly hired and quits her other job. It gets somewhat slow at this point, but a key scene is when her partner complains about Gabriela's childlike behavior. The juxtaposition of Gabriela's demeanor, the crime scene, and her happy salsa music is a strange combination indeed. It sometimes works and it is sometimes grating. William Baldwin as Paul Guell is actually quite brilliant and doesn't get enough credit. You have no idea how much it pains me to write that. But, anyway here it is. He has a very difficult job to do here and he pulls it off and makes it look easy. He has to be a menacing serial killer, check he is very creepy. He has to manage to make it funny somehow as well, check. As mentioned before his exchange with Jones, was well worth watching the movie. He also manages to show some sensitivity, we can almost see into the pit of his dark soul, what motivates him to kill. It does't all work however, there are parts that are so illogical. Aside from the fact that the childlike main character is obsessed with violent crime. Things that would never ever happen in real life. I will have to leave it at that, if you watch the film you will spot at least one glaring example at near the end of the film. The ending will leave you with more questions than this film can answer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very black and bloody horror comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Indyrod
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This very black and bloody horror comedy is a real favorite of mine, ever since I first saw it on cable several years ago. Tarantino saw the original short film while promoting his Reservior Dogs at an Italian film festival, and suggested the filmmakers to expand it to a feature film, and he would produce it. They did of course, and to me, this is a work of art, with a film score that fits about as perfect to the scenes as any I have seen. Angela Jones plays Gabriela, a Columbian beauty that has moved to Miami, and has an obsession with bloody crime scenes. She gets a job with a company that cleans up crime scenes, and she starts following the news accounts of a serial killer played by William Baldwin. After his recent murder, she gets assigned the job of cleaning up the bloody mess, and doesn't know it, but the killer is locked in the wine closet because he left a clue to his identity. Soon, there is the grand finale, which is a danse macabre between the two, with an ending that knocked me out of my chair when I first saw it. This is black comedy at it's darkest and most fun, and the DVD is loaded with features including an intro and outro by Tarantino. It also contains the original 30 minute short version of the movie. I absolutely love this movie, and recommend it very highly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A young woman fascinated with murders gets a job cleaning up murder sites.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ltlacey
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a total surprise. It's fast-paced and will hold your interest the entire time. As a girl, Gabriela witnesses, so to speak, the murder of a man. From then on out she becomes totally fascinated by murder and keeps a scrapbook full of drawings and clippings. As an adult she lives in Miami and ends up working at a place that cleans up after murders (suicides). Cleaners, as they are called. During this time a serial killer is on the loose and Gabriela is hooked. What makes this movie so great is Jones, who plays the young woman, and her somewhat warped sense of killings. The scene where she's dancing with the knife, re-living the latest murder is perfect. Though there's a lot of blood, and the near final scene is audibly graphic (you do not see anything), it's also one of the funniest, for those of us who appreciate a very warped sense of humor. In the Special Features Quentin Tarantino explains why this actress was so perfect for the part, and he's spot on, as even while watching her (prior to watching the SF) you could just tell. He talks about a sparkle in her eye. Her entire body lights up in this part. Everyone else, even Baldwin (as the killer), does not come close, though he did a fairly good job, especially in their scene where they are together dancing. And you know who the killer is from the beginning, so I'm not spoiling an ending here. Find this gem and watch it over and over again. Each time you will catch something new that Jones does. She's a very physical actress and I hope to see more of her, and soon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why Short Shouldn't Go Long...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bolesroor
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quentin Tarantino, aglow with the buzz-borne light from the soon-to-be-released "Pulp Fiction," was sitting in a darkened theater with his producer/pal Lawrence Bender, enjoying a short-film festival. The short being screened was called "Curdled," and it was about a Latin woman working for a housekeeping service that specialized in cleaning up crime scenes for murderers and killers. I picture our hydro-cephalic hero QT laughing so loud he annoyed everyone in the theater, including the film's writer/director Reb Braddock. But Braddock needn't have worried. Our fat-headed pop-culture savant got up from his seat when the short was over, sought out Reb and declared, full of his own ego and I can only guess Goobers, "Listen to me, Mr. Braddock, alriiiiiiiight? We're gonna take your short film and make it into a feature, okaaaaaaaaay? You'll write/direct and I'll produce, alriiiiiiiiiiight?" And so the feature-length version of "Curdled" was born. I'm scarcely exaggerating this story because it is the version told by Quentin himself in the film's bonus material. Could any aspiring director refuse the offer of a then white-hot Tarantino? Could you? Unfortunately for us the feature is nothing more than the 10 min. short stretched out over an hour and a half. Which strangely feels like three hours. Thrill as Nothing happens in slow motion. Watch the immediately-attractive Angela Jones (Butch's cabbie in Pulp Fiction) become less and less adorable as sheer boredom numbs your senses. Laugh at a one-joke black comedy that manages to kill the joke after twenty minutes. Rock to a movie so bad its writer/director Reb Braddock never wrote/directed anything ever again. At all. What did we learn today? We learned that short films don't necessarily translate into feature-length. We learned that even Latin women need good story lines to hold onto our attention. And most importantly: If Quentin Tarantino ever approaches you in a theater with greazy fingers and a shlt-eating grin you need to evacuate the premises as soon as possible. That's what Fire Exits are for. GRADE: D-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cool And Quirky Horror/Dark-Comedy/Thriller....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    EVOL666
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I picked this one up at the recommendation of a few people that I "trust" - and though it is not the typical sleaze/gore/trash that I pump into my brain at a record-pace - it is a truly funny, well-made and entertaining little number. Although there is some blood, don't expect a bloodbath, and there's no nudity (which DOES suck...) but this one is good on it's own merits as a fun and pretty original film... Gabriella is a sweet young girl, who has been obsessed with murder and death since an early age. To satisfy this obsession, she takes a job with a cleaning agency that specializes in cleaning up murder/accident scenes. When the opportunity arises to clean the house where one of a string of the "Blueblood" serial-killer murders occurred - Gabriella jumps at the chance. Unfortunately - her enthusiasm may bring her just a bit closer to the murders than she really wants to be...or does she??? CURDLED truly is an enjoyable and original film. More than anything - the performances carry the film. Angela Jones as Gabriella is both naive and adorable, but also strangely sexy and intense. There are a ton of people you'll "recognize" in this one, in both large and small roles - William Baldwin, Kelly Preston, Daisy Fuentes, a quick shot of Clooney and Tarantino from DUSK TIL DAWN on a "crime-show", and the guy that plays Gabriella's boss (I forget his name, but he's been in a ton of stuff too - he was the one big "boss" in WAR GAMES...) - and all the performances are pretty top-notch. The directing is also confident and well done, and the music direction adds to the overall "quirkiness" of the whole film. If you dig strange black-comedies, you'll probably dig this one. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forgettable and familiar horror yarn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Void
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From it's uninspiring title to the flat acting performances, Curdled is very much an unremarkable film throughout. The film has gained some fans by way of the fact that Quentin Tarantino's name is attached to it, and the silly and out of place nod to the Rodriguez/Tarantino flick 'From Dusk till Dawn'. These things do not make a great movie, however, and this is more than evident all the way through 'Curdled'. The film suffers from an all too obvious lack of ideas, and it tries to mask this with murders that are meant to be stylish and events that are supposed to be disturbing. The Mexican music score that accompanies many of the sequences in the film is obviously meant to be cool, but it's becomes annoying very quickly; especially as aside from the fact that the lead character is Mexican, it doesn't fit with the tone of the movie. The film's plot is typically offbeat and it follows a gorehound who, because of her obsession with grisly murders, takes a job with a firm that cleans up murder scenes. It sounds boring and it is. William Baldwin is the only 'name' on the cast list, and even he doesn't make an impression. He hasn't been given anything to do in the movie and aside from talking to his victims and standing around trying to look menacing, he's pretty much wasted. Angela Jones, or rather; the taxi driver from Pulp Fiction, takes the lead role as the murder obsessed young woman, and it is always clear that it's her involvement with Pulp Fiction that won her this role, not her acting ability. She may have been good enough in her small role in Tarantino's masterpiece, but she doesn't have the talent to lead a film by herself. She looks lost and out of place for the majority of the film, and if it weren't for her Latino accent; she wouldn't convince the audience that she's a weirdo on any level. Curdled is a one hundred percent-proof piece of forgettable trash. Films like this often win themselves praise for invention or black comedic antics; but this one fails on all levels. Whether you're a Tarantino fan, William Baldwin fan, horror fan or just a movie buff; this is one to miss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Curdled cheese...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cwatts-2 (cwatts@hypd.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is definitely unique in that it's original. Quentin Tarantino produced this film and put it under his now failed Rolling Thunder Pictures. The film in its essence had a lot of potential and really had a great leading actress, but it had its share of problems. If your a fan of Tarantino like I am you prob. will rent this no matter what anyone says, but I would recommend this movie with caution because it just a mediocre middle of the year release that Miramax quickly buried under its large pile of flops. The special features of this film are the best part. With the thesis student film attached to the DVD along with an intro and outro by Quentin himself. Overall not much here but you may find some qualities that can be enjoyed by all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The heads...do they talk?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ThrownMuse
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion, this is one of the most underrated movies of the 90s, featuring one of my all-time favorite performances by the enchanting Angela Jones. It is based on a short made in 1991, about a childlike murder-obsessed Colombian-American who takes a job as a maid...who cleans up after violent murders. Apparently, Tarantino liked the short so much that he cast Jones in Pulp Fiction and produced a full length version of "Curdled" with Jones and William Baldwin (who is surprisingly great.) This is one of my favorite black comedies and easily the funniest serial killer thriller ever. Angela Jones lights up the screen with her animated facial expressions (think Audrey Tautou) and quirky delivery. Oh, and this movie features one of the best dance sequences in a movie (yes, even better than Britt Ekland's in "The Wicker Man"). The recently released DVD is a blessing and surprisingly chockful of extras (including the original short film) for a movie that is apparently so reviled. The worst thing I can say about "Curdled" is that Braddock didn't go on to make another film and Jones went on to do a freakin "Children of the Corn" sequel. Recommend to all fans of serial killer movies and dark comedies. My rating: 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my All-Time Fav Movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gothgate
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Darkly funny. I love this movie and can watch it again and again. William Baldwin & Angela Jones are perfect in their roles as a serial killer and a woman who cleans up in his victim's homes after the police have gone. Gabriella, the cleaner, is a great character. She epitomizes the people who are fascinated by serial killers. In some ways this movie reminds me of CSI and Forensic Files and shows like that. Lots of good law-abiding people watch them and not just to imagine themselves on the cops' side, but to fantasize about being criminals and toy with their dark side. The best part is her salsa "dance with the devil" as she reinacts one of the killer's crimes for him. I don't know why this movie got such a bum rap. I think it's great!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
