<filme>
 <id>
  1083
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0115495
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Ciladas da Sorte
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  While escaping from a foiled robbery attempt, three thieves find themselves surrounded by police at a New Orleans bar--only they're not the people the police are searching for.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Three petty thieves who the police believe to be major criminals are chased into a basement bar where they take five hostages including all the bar employees. The rest of the movie deals with the cops lurking outside the bar while the trio try to get hold of the situation inside.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   bar
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   police
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hostage
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   animal in title
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   brother brother relationship
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Kevin Spacey
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Christian Forte
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Matt Dillon
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Faye Dunaway
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Gary Sinise
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watering Hold Up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When a New Orleans robbery turns into a deadly pursuit, three crooks take refuge in a spacious basement bar and hold those inside hostage. The "Dino's" bar invaders are: handsome bad-boy Matt Dillon (as Dova), muscular psychotic William Fichtner (as Law) and quietly wounded Gary Sinise (as Milo). Of those unlucky enough to be in the bar on this eventful night, the biggest parts go to mouthy barmaid Faye Dunaway (as Janet), secretive businessman Viggo Mortensen (as Guy) and cute pool player Skeet Ulrich (as Danny). The drama was written by Christian Forte (son of 1950s "teen" celebrity Fabian) and directed by Kevin Spacey (the highly accomplished actor)... The term "Albino Alligator" is explained in the story and has some character parallels. This is an enjoyable directorial debut for Mr. Spacey. However, the actors appear to bounce around a lot, and a hidden rifle could have been handled better. Three big "secrets" are revealed - the most important could have been "introduced" along with the opening robbery, for maximum tension; let's anticipate that explosive confrontation. Of the other character relationships, one is a surprise and the other is not; neither adds anything by being held back. Also, the "hero" we're left with at the end would probably be unmasked in real life. But, this is the movies, and the story is engaging. ****** Albino Alligator (9/9/96) Kevin Spacey ~ Matt Dillon, Faye Dunaway, William Fichtner, Viggo Mortensen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tense and engrossing thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Woodyanders (Woodyanders@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A trio of small-time crooks -- dim-witted Dova (a sound performance by Matt Dillon), his more smart and sensible brother Milo (the always excellent Gary Sinise), and volatile psycho Law (William Fichtner in peak creepy and intense form) -- are forced to seek refuge in a bar and take everyone inside hostage after they botch a robbery. Director Kevin Spacey, working from a tight and gripping script by Christian Forte, relates the riveting story at a smooth pace, milks plenty of nerve-rattling claustrophobic tension from the premise, maintains a tough no-nonsense tone throughout, delivers several startling moments of abrupt'n'brutal violence (a car crash that sends a man flying out of a windshield at the start stands out as an especially impressive set piece), and pulls off a fairly surprising ending. The sturdy acting from the fine cast keeps the whole thing humming: Faye Dunaway brings her redoubtable A game to the role of sassy and cynical barmaid Janet Boudreaux, Viggo Mortensen likewise excels as the quiet and mysterious Guy Foucard, Skeet Ulrich is solid and likable as the naive Danny, Joe Mantegna huffs and puffs with rip-snorting &eacute;lan as the hard-nosed Agent G.D. Browning, and M. Emmet Walsh is a total rascally treat in his regrettably smallish part as crusty old bar owner Dino. Mark Plummer's handsome widescreen cinematography makes fluid use of a gliding camera and boasts one doozy of an overhead tracking shot. An enjoyable nail-biter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Blu-Ray version of this is 1.77, not 2.35 to 1 aspect ratio
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chuckju-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A number of new movies out recently in Blu Ray, this one, and many others, are in much smaller aspect ratio than original theatrical release! Next of Kin is another example. This should be protested and not allowed to continue. Normally I expect a Blu-Ray to be a duplicate of the original release. HOWEVER, I BELIEVE THIS IS SIMPLY AN ERROR IN AMAZON'S PRODUCT DESCRIPTION. I CHECKED "OUTLAND" AND THOUGH LISTED AS 1.77 TO 1, IT WAS THE CORRECT 2.3 OR SO TO 1 THAT IT SHOULD BE. This is a rip off of the customer. I bought a very good Blu-Ray of "Cellular" a few weeks ago, but it's in 16 X 9 aspect ratio. Now the new version of "Cellular" in Blu-Ray is the correct 2.35 to 1 aspect ratio. The Cellular BluRay at 16 X 9 was excellent but for the aspect ratio. I don't know if this is a ruse to force cinephiles to pony up for another Blu Ray later or not. But I do hate it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flat hostage drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wizard-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the past I have enjoyed a number of movies involving hostage taking, from "Dog Day Afternoon" to "The Negotiator". So I was pretty sure I would enjoy "Albino Alligator". While the movie is not without merit, overall I felt let down. I will say the movie is well made for a low budget, there is some good acting, and some humor in the movie is funny. But there are a number of problems. For one thing, none of the characters - hostage takers, the chief ATF agent, nor the hostages - are made to be colorful or compelling enough. And I found the central story to be surprisingly dull. There is little tension, the movie moves VERY slowly, and the movie resorts to using clich&eacute;s found in other hostage movies instead of trying to put a new spin on things. While this isn't an awful movie, it is pretty flat, and you'd be better off instead rewatching those movies I mentioned in the first sentence of this review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He's not a hero...None of us are.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ***MAJOR SPOILER ALERT*** Tense filled hostage drama that takes place in Dino's Last Chance Bar in New Orleans with a trio of petty crooks hold up there not knowing what exactly the surrounding police are accusing them of! As it later turned out it's one of the hostages whom the cops want for gun smuggling that the FBI set up a sting to catch him. It's in all the confusion that resulted in a deadly car chase where three cops & FBI Agents were killed that the gun smuggler found his way to Dino's Bar! That was just minutes before it was raided by the trio of petty crooks that the police were chasing thinking that their part of the gun smuggling operation. That trio consisted of the brothers Dova & Milo, Matt Dillon & Gary Sinise, and their partner the psychotic Law & Disorder or just plain Law for short, William Fichtner. With Dova Milo & Law not knowing exactly what their wanted for and with the cops and FBI Agents not realizing whom those in the bar are, hostages and hostage takers, the tense stand off lasts for hours into the morning. That's when the police under the command of FBI Agent G.D Browning, Joe Mantegna, plan to raid the place at exactly 7:00 AM with the help of a SWAT team. As the minutes tick away the usual level headed Dova starts to lose it who against his brother Milo's, who was badly injured during the car chase, sound advice plans not to off the hostages plans to blow them all away if the cops make a move on the besieged bar. As for bar owner Dino, Emmet Walsh,who tried to be a hero and take on the trio of bandits he sadly ended up getting killed with his head bashed in, by Law, for his efforts. ***SPOILERS*** It's hostage Janet Boudreaux, Faye Dunaway,the waitress at Dino's Bar who does her best to keep the tension from boiling over and becoming deadly. That's by her advising the leader of the trio Dova that she and the rest of the hostages in the bar won't point him and his motley crew out after the police raid the joint! By her telling the police that the hostage takers escaped thus,in mistaking them as hostages, giving the three a free ride home. What Janet kept from Dova up until the very last moment is that her son like the person whom the police and FBI are really after is one of the hostages! Kevin Spacey directed film that comes across much like the Humphrey Bogart & Bette Davis 1936 crime classic "The Petrified Forest" with a lot more meat or story to it. With a totally unexpected and heart dropping ending that would not have been possible back then in 1936 due to the prudish and "My way or the highway" moral constraints of the then powerful Hollywood Hayes Commission.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring chit chat hostage movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arlis Fuson
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three guys running from the police hide out in a bar and hold the handful of people inside hostage. One of the men is badly injured and they talk and talk and talk about what they are going to do then near the end you find out one of the hostages inside is actually a bigger outlaw than they are. Some get out and some don't. By the end of the film you will more than likely find you don't care about any of these boring characters. I have seen this a few times and never have enjoyed it. It is so extremely slow that it's hard to set through. Kevin Spacey behind the camera offered nothing. The acting was good, but with such a boring movie it didn't matter. Faye Dunaway, M. Emmet Walsh, William Fitchner, John Spencer, Viggo Mortensen, Skeet Ulrich, Joe Mantegna and Gary Sinise all did good, Matt Dillon is a horrible actor and should not be in anything. The music was horrible and made this bad film even worse. This movie is pure drama, 95 percent of the film is spent in the bar with the three idiot bad guys trying to figure out what to do next, it's a hard film to watch because it is so slow.2/10 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Will the Bar Flies Get Swatted?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Papadopoulos
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gather that this neat little movie was loosely based on Humphrey Bogart's The Petrified Forest (1936), which I have never seen in its entirety. An oblique tribute to Bogart is made as the bar in which most of the movie takes place has an old Bogart cinema poster on its wall which features Key Largo (not The Petrified Forest). If there is any similarity between the two movies separated by sixty years it is mostly at the beginning and the bar-hostage situation which occupies about four-fifths of the film. However, Albino Alligator is not a remake of The Petrified Forest. In the Bogart film escaped convicts end up in a bar and terrorise its denizens. In Albino Alligator (referring to a type of pool shot derived from a legend about the alleged habit of alligators to sacrifice weaker members of their own group in order to trap and destroy their rivals) three men are running from the police after a botched warehouse burglary and end up in a basement dive in a pre-Diluvium New Orleans named Dino's Last Chance Bar; a one time basement speak easy which is just about to close for the night. They terrorise the barman , the middle-aged waitress-come do-it-all and the three customers though it is fairly apparent that they are amateur villains but for the one dangerous self-acknowledged sociopath. The Petrified Forest was criticised for being a bit too theatrical, not surprising as it was taken from a stage production. And that may also be true of Albino Alligator but one could say the same of the highly acclaimed Bus Stop starring Marilyn Monroe, in which all the action takes place at a Bus Stop-Coffee bar in Montana. The first ten minutes or so of Albino Alligator -where the burglary is botched in the most amateur way by setting of the warehouse alarms and the escape from the chasing police cars takes place - are basically irrelevant accept to explain why the men are forced to find refuge in the bar. The movie is mainly about the interaction among the burglars and between them and the bar denizens and outside between the local police chief , the FBI and an investigative woman TV reporter. Every character has a vital part to play in the unravelling tale. Nobody is quite what they seem at first sight. There are a few twists, quite well done, and it would be unfair to reveal them. Inevitably the cops arrive as unnoticed the barman has pressed a below counter alarm. But it is never explained how the cops knew exactly who they were seeking in the bar- the film's only flaw. Some of the best film actors alive today comprise the cast and perform wonderfully. The film has been criticised for its profuse use of foul language and violence by those who would prefer to watch Walt Disney movies but such criticism is laughable. This is the sort of film you either detest or love. I loved it. It was never destined to be a blockbuster. It seems the producer and actors didn't expect it to be one. It is the kind of movie actors love to be in and producers die to make but this what those brought up on Hollywood mush don't seem to understand. Some admiring American reviewers would describe it as a "European" style film .But few European films ever get this good. The whole setting and characters are purely American proving that America can make really good movies if the desire is there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Out of control negotiations.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Joe Mantegna definitely has the best scene in "Albino Alligator". It is a humorous infusion into a movie that at times borders on being terminal. Starts out fast with three petty criminals, Dillon, Sinese, and Fichtner, fleeing a botched robbery. Unfortunately once they take refuge in a basement bar, their endless posturing and planning, grinds on the film. There is nothing wrong with the acting, including a great supporting effort from M. Emmet Walsh. Other than the above mentioned scene, Mantegna is somewhat wasted in a one dimensional role. Faye Dunaway is interesting, and William Fichtner is in menacing psycho mode. Marginally recommended. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spacey is not a director
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (tottenhamtillidie@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the face of it, this should be a great film, a great cast, a plot with many possibilities and one of Hollywood's finest behind the camera for the first time. However, its clear why it was another 8 years before spacey decided to try directing a movie again. This movie fails on so many levels. In a film where there is not much action and most of the scenes are shot in a couple of locations, it is imperative that suspense and continuity are provided by the director. Not so here, the great cast is horribly under-used, none more so than the great, late John Spencer, the plot is so run of the mill and nothing you haven't seen in a hundred other TV movies. There is so little character development you end up not caring for any of the protagonists. At least we know spacey has a lot of mates and clout in Hollywood studios to get away with a poor flick like this
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jez88-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film, the character Law played by William Fichtner was sinister but very funny. There is violence but not on a huge scale. The story of the Albino Alligator is brilliantly linked in the film. As the viewer you do start to feel sorry for the three petty criminals who are just there by accident. Each character has a heart but the quiet character of Mortensen is chilling because you don't know anything about him and he's far too calm for the situation. In this film you never know whats going to happen next because the characters are very unpredictable. Overall the film is fantastic and a definite recommendation to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watering Hold Up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When a New Orleans robbery turns into a deadly pursuit, three crooks take refuge in a spacious basement bar and hold those inside hostage. The "Dino's" bar invaders are: handsome bad-boy Matt Dillon (as Dova), muscular psychotic William Fichtner (as Law) and quietly wounded Gary Sinise (as Milo). Of those unlucky enough to be in the bar on this eventful night, the biggest parts go to mouthy barmaid Faye Dunaway (as Janet), secretive businessman Viggo Mortensen (as Guy) and cute pool player Skeet Ulrich (as Danny). The drama was written by Christian Forte (son of 1950s "teen" celebrity Fabian) and directed by Kevin Spacey (the highly accomplished actor)... The term "Albino Alligator" is explained in the story and has some character parallels. This is an enjoyable directorial debut for Mr. Spacey. However, the actors appear to bounce around a lot, and a hidden rifle could have been handled better. Three big "secrets" are revealed - the most important could have been "introduced" along with the opening robbery, for maximum tension; let's anticipate that explosive confrontation. Of the other character relationships, one is a surprise and the other is not; neither adds anything by being held back. Also, the "hero" we're left with at the end would probably be unmasked in real life. But, this is the movies, and the story is engaging. ****** Albino Alligator (9/9/96) Kevin Spacey ~ Matt Dillon, Faye Dunaway, William Fichtner, Viggo Mortensen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tense and engrossing thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Woodyanders (Woodyanders@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A trio of small-time crooks -- dim-witted Dova (a sound performance by Matt Dillon), his more smart and sensible brother Milo (the always excellent Gary Sinise), and volatile psycho Law (William Fichtner in peak creepy and intense form) -- are forced to seek refuge in a bar and take everyone inside hostage after they botch a robbery. Director Kevin Spacey, working from a tight and gripping script by Christian Forte, relates the riveting story at a smooth pace, milks plenty of nerve-rattling claustrophobic tension from the premise, maintains a tough no-nonsense tone throughout, delivers several startling moments of abrupt'n'brutal violence (a car crash that sends a man flying out of a windshield at the start stands out as an especially impressive set piece), and pulls off a fairly surprising ending. The sturdy acting from the fine cast keeps the whole thing humming: Faye Dunaway brings her redoubtable A game to the role of sassy and cynical barmaid Janet Boudreaux, Viggo Mortensen likewise excels as the quiet and mysterious Guy Foucard, Skeet Ulrich is solid and likable as the naive Danny, Joe Mantegna huffs and puffs with rip-snorting &eacute;lan as the hard-nosed Agent G.D. Browning, and M. Emmet Walsh is a total rascally treat in his regrettably smallish part as crusty old bar owner Dino. Mark Plummer's handsome widescreen cinematography makes fluid use of a gliding camera and boasts one doozy of an overhead tracking shot. An enjoyable nail-biter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Blu-Ray version of this is 1.77, not 2.35 to 1 aspect ratio
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chuckju-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A number of new movies out recently in Blu Ray, this one, and many others, are in much smaller aspect ratio than original theatrical release! Next of Kin is another example. This should be protested and not allowed to continue. Normally I expect a Blu-Ray to be a duplicate of the original release. HOWEVER, I BELIEVE THIS IS SIMPLY AN ERROR IN AMAZON'S PRODUCT DESCRIPTION. I CHECKED "OUTLAND" AND THOUGH LISTED AS 1.77 TO 1, IT WAS THE CORRECT 2.3 OR SO TO 1 THAT IT SHOULD BE. This is a rip off of the customer. I bought a very good Blu-Ray of "Cellular" a few weeks ago, but it's in 16 X 9 aspect ratio. Now the new version of "Cellular" in Blu-Ray is the correct 2.35 to 1 aspect ratio. The Cellular BluRay at 16 X 9 was excellent but for the aspect ratio. I don't know if this is a ruse to force cinephiles to pony up for another Blu Ray later or not. But I do hate it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flat hostage drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wizard-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the past I have enjoyed a number of movies involving hostage taking, from "Dog Day Afternoon" to "The Negotiator". So I was pretty sure I would enjoy "Albino Alligator". While the movie is not without merit, overall I felt let down. I will say the movie is well made for a low budget, there is some good acting, and some humor in the movie is funny. But there are a number of problems. For one thing, none of the characters - hostage takers, the chief ATF agent, nor the hostages - are made to be colorful or compelling enough. And I found the central story to be surprisingly dull. There is little tension, the movie moves VERY slowly, and the movie resorts to using clich&eacute;s found in other hostage movies instead of trying to put a new spin on things. While this isn't an awful movie, it is pretty flat, and you'd be better off instead rewatching those movies I mentioned in the first sentence of this review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He's not a hero...None of us are.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ***MAJOR SPOILER ALERT*** Tense filled hostage drama that takes place in Dino's Last Chance Bar in New Orleans with a trio of petty crooks hold up there not knowing what exactly the surrounding police are accusing them of! As it later turned out it's one of the hostages whom the cops want for gun smuggling that the FBI set up a sting to catch him. It's in all the confusion that resulted in a deadly car chase where three cops & FBI Agents were killed that the gun smuggler found his way to Dino's Bar! That was just minutes before it was raided by the trio of petty crooks that the police were chasing thinking that their part of the gun smuggling operation. That trio consisted of the brothers Dova & Milo, Matt Dillon & Gary Sinise, and their partner the psychotic Law & Disorder or just plain Law for short, William Fichtner. With Dova Milo & Law not knowing exactly what their wanted for and with the cops and FBI Agents not realizing whom those in the bar are, hostages and hostage takers, the tense stand off lasts for hours into the morning. That's when the police under the command of FBI Agent G.D Browning, Joe Mantegna, plan to raid the place at exactly 7:00 AM with the help of a SWAT team. As the minutes tick away the usual level headed Dova starts to lose it who against his brother Milo's, who was badly injured during the car chase, sound advice plans not to off the hostages plans to blow them all away if the cops make a move on the besieged bar. As for bar owner Dino, Emmet Walsh,who tried to be a hero and take on the trio of bandits he sadly ended up getting killed with his head bashed in, by Law, for his efforts. ***SPOILERS*** It's hostage Janet Boudreaux, Faye Dunaway,the waitress at Dino's Bar who does her best to keep the tension from boiling over and becoming deadly. That's by her advising the leader of the trio Dova that she and the rest of the hostages in the bar won't point him and his motley crew out after the police raid the joint! By her telling the police that the hostage takers escaped thus,in mistaking them as hostages, giving the three a free ride home. What Janet kept from Dova up until the very last moment is that her son like the person whom the police and FBI are really after is one of the hostages! Kevin Spacey directed film that comes across much like the Humphrey Bogart & Bette Davis 1936 crime classic "The Petrified Forest" with a lot more meat or story to it. With a totally unexpected and heart dropping ending that would not have been possible back then in 1936 due to the prudish and "My way or the highway" moral constraints of the then powerful Hollywood Hayes Commission.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring chit chat hostage movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arlis Fuson
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three guys running from the police hide out in a bar and hold the handful of people inside hostage. One of the men is badly injured and they talk and talk and talk about what they are going to do then near the end you find out one of the hostages inside is actually a bigger outlaw than they are. Some get out and some don't. By the end of the film you will more than likely find you don't care about any of these boring characters. I have seen this a few times and never have enjoyed it. It is so extremely slow that it's hard to set through. Kevin Spacey behind the camera offered nothing. The acting was good, but with such a boring movie it didn't matter. Faye Dunaway, M. Emmet Walsh, William Fitchner, John Spencer, Viggo Mortensen, Skeet Ulrich, Joe Mantegna and Gary Sinise all did good, Matt Dillon is a horrible actor and should not be in anything. The music was horrible and made this bad film even worse. This movie is pure drama, 95 percent of the film is spent in the bar with the three idiot bad guys trying to figure out what to do next, it's a hard film to watch because it is so slow.2/10 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Will the Bar Flies Get Swatted?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Papadopoulos
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gather that this neat little movie was loosely based on Humphrey Bogart's The Petrified Forest (1936), which I have never seen in its entirety. An oblique tribute to Bogart is made as the bar in which most of the movie takes place has an old Bogart cinema poster on its wall which features Key Largo (not The Petrified Forest). If there is any similarity between the two movies separated by sixty years it is mostly at the beginning and the bar-hostage situation which occupies about four-fifths of the film. However, Albino Alligator is not a remake of The Petrified Forest. In the Bogart film escaped convicts end up in a bar and terrorise its denizens. In Albino Alligator (referring to a type of pool shot derived from a legend about the alleged habit of alligators to sacrifice weaker members of their own group in order to trap and destroy their rivals) three men are running from the police after a botched warehouse burglary and end up in a basement dive in a pre-Diluvium New Orleans named Dino's Last Chance Bar; a one time basement speak easy which is just about to close for the night. They terrorise the barman , the middle-aged waitress-come do-it-all and the three customers though it is fairly apparent that they are amateur villains but for the one dangerous self-acknowledged sociopath. The Petrified Forest was criticised for being a bit too theatrical, not surprising as it was taken from a stage production. And that may also be true of Albino Alligator but one could say the same of the highly acclaimed Bus Stop starring Marilyn Monroe, in which all the action takes place at a Bus Stop-Coffee bar in Montana. The first ten minutes or so of Albino Alligator -where the burglary is botched in the most amateur way by setting of the warehouse alarms and the escape from the chasing police cars takes place - are basically irrelevant accept to explain why the men are forced to find refuge in the bar. The movie is mainly about the interaction among the burglars and between them and the bar denizens and outside between the local police chief , the FBI and an investigative woman TV reporter. Every character has a vital part to play in the unravelling tale. Nobody is quite what they seem at first sight. There are a few twists, quite well done, and it would be unfair to reveal them. Inevitably the cops arrive as unnoticed the barman has pressed a below counter alarm. But it is never explained how the cops knew exactly who they were seeking in the bar- the film's only flaw. Some of the best film actors alive today comprise the cast and perform wonderfully. The film has been criticised for its profuse use of foul language and violence by those who would prefer to watch Walt Disney movies but such criticism is laughable. This is the sort of film you either detest or love. I loved it. It was never destined to be a blockbuster. It seems the producer and actors didn't expect it to be one. It is the kind of movie actors love to be in and producers die to make but this what those brought up on Hollywood mush don't seem to understand. Some admiring American reviewers would describe it as a "European" style film .But few European films ever get this good. The whole setting and characters are purely American proving that America can make really good movies if the desire is there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Out of control negotiations.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Joe Mantegna definitely has the best scene in "Albino Alligator". It is a humorous infusion into a movie that at times borders on being terminal. Starts out fast with three petty criminals, Dillon, Sinese, and Fichtner, fleeing a botched robbery. Unfortunately once they take refuge in a basement bar, their endless posturing and planning, grinds on the film. There is nothing wrong with the acting, including a great supporting effort from M. Emmet Walsh. Other than the above mentioned scene, Mantegna is somewhat wasted in a one dimensional role. Faye Dunaway is interesting, and William Fichtner is in menacing psycho mode. Marginally recommended. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spacey is not a director
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (tottenhamtillidie@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the face of it, this should be a great film, a great cast, a plot with many possibilities and one of Hollywood's finest behind the camera for the first time. However, its clear why it was another 8 years before spacey decided to try directing a movie again. This movie fails on so many levels. In a film where there is not much action and most of the scenes are shot in a couple of locations, it is imperative that suspense and continuity are provided by the director. Not so here, the great cast is horribly under-used, none more so than the great, late John Spencer, the plot is so run of the mill and nothing you haven't seen in a hundred other TV movies. There is so little character development you end up not caring for any of the protagonists. At least we know spacey has a lot of mates and clout in Hollywood studios to get away with a poor flick like this
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jez88-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film, the character Law played by William Fichtner was sinister but very funny. There is violence but not on a huge scale. The story of the Albino Alligator is brilliantly linked in the film. As the viewer you do start to feel sorry for the three petty criminals who are just there by accident. Each character has a heart but the quiet character of Mortensen is chilling because you don't know anything about him and he's far too calm for the situation. In this film you never know whats going to happen next because the characters are very unpredictable. Overall the film is fantastic and a definite recommendation to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watering Hold Up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When a New Orleans robbery turns into a deadly pursuit, three crooks take refuge in a spacious basement bar and hold those inside hostage. The "Dino's" bar invaders are: handsome bad-boy Matt Dillon (as Dova), muscular psychotic William Fichtner (as Law) and quietly wounded Gary Sinise (as Milo). Of those unlucky enough to be in the bar on this eventful night, the biggest parts go to mouthy barmaid Faye Dunaway (as Janet), secretive businessman Viggo Mortensen (as Guy) and cute pool player Skeet Ulrich (as Danny). The drama was written by Christian Forte (son of 1950s "teen" celebrity Fabian) and directed by Kevin Spacey (the highly accomplished actor)... The term "Albino Alligator" is explained in the story and has some character parallels. This is an enjoyable directorial debut for Mr. Spacey. However, the actors appear to bounce around a lot, and a hidden rifle could have been handled better. Three big "secrets" are revealed - the most important could have been "introduced" along with the opening robbery, for maximum tension; let's anticipate that explosive confrontation. Of the other character relationships, one is a surprise and the other is not; neither adds anything by being held back. Also, the "hero" we're left with at the end would probably be unmasked in real life. But, this is the movies, and the story is engaging. ****** Albino Alligator (9/9/96) Kevin Spacey ~ Matt Dillon, Faye Dunaway, William Fichtner, Viggo Mortensen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tense and engrossing thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Woodyanders (Woodyanders@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A trio of small-time crooks -- dim-witted Dova (a sound performance by Matt Dillon), his more smart and sensible brother Milo (the always excellent Gary Sinise), and volatile psycho Law (William Fichtner in peak creepy and intense form) -- are forced to seek refuge in a bar and take everyone inside hostage after they botch a robbery. Director Kevin Spacey, working from a tight and gripping script by Christian Forte, relates the riveting story at a smooth pace, milks plenty of nerve-rattling claustrophobic tension from the premise, maintains a tough no-nonsense tone throughout, delivers several startling moments of abrupt'n'brutal violence (a car crash that sends a man flying out of a windshield at the start stands out as an especially impressive set piece), and pulls off a fairly surprising ending. The sturdy acting from the fine cast keeps the whole thing humming: Faye Dunaway brings her redoubtable A game to the role of sassy and cynical barmaid Janet Boudreaux, Viggo Mortensen likewise excels as the quiet and mysterious Guy Foucard, Skeet Ulrich is solid and likable as the naive Danny, Joe Mantegna huffs and puffs with rip-snorting &eacute;lan as the hard-nosed Agent G.D. Browning, and M. Emmet Walsh is a total rascally treat in his regrettably smallish part as crusty old bar owner Dino. Mark Plummer's handsome widescreen cinematography makes fluid use of a gliding camera and boasts one doozy of an overhead tracking shot. An enjoyable nail-biter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Blu-Ray version of this is 1.77, not 2.35 to 1 aspect ratio
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chuckju-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A number of new movies out recently in Blu Ray, this one, and many others, are in much smaller aspect ratio than original theatrical release! Next of Kin is another example. This should be protested and not allowed to continue. Normally I expect a Blu-Ray to be a duplicate of the original release. HOWEVER, I BELIEVE THIS IS SIMPLY AN ERROR IN AMAZON'S PRODUCT DESCRIPTION. I CHECKED "OUTLAND" AND THOUGH LISTED AS 1.77 TO 1, IT WAS THE CORRECT 2.3 OR SO TO 1 THAT IT SHOULD BE. This is a rip off of the customer. I bought a very good Blu-Ray of "Cellular" a few weeks ago, but it's in 16 X 9 aspect ratio. Now the new version of "Cellular" in Blu-Ray is the correct 2.35 to 1 aspect ratio. The Cellular BluRay at 16 X 9 was excellent but for the aspect ratio. I don't know if this is a ruse to force cinephiles to pony up for another Blu Ray later or not. But I do hate it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flat hostage drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wizard-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the past I have enjoyed a number of movies involving hostage taking, from "Dog Day Afternoon" to "The Negotiator". So I was pretty sure I would enjoy "Albino Alligator". While the movie is not without merit, overall I felt let down. I will say the movie is well made for a low budget, there is some good acting, and some humor in the movie is funny. But there are a number of problems. For one thing, none of the characters - hostage takers, the chief ATF agent, nor the hostages - are made to be colorful or compelling enough. And I found the central story to be surprisingly dull. There is little tension, the movie moves VERY slowly, and the movie resorts to using clich&eacute;s found in other hostage movies instead of trying to put a new spin on things. While this isn't an awful movie, it is pretty flat, and you'd be better off instead rewatching those movies I mentioned in the first sentence of this review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He's not a hero...None of us are.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ***MAJOR SPOILER ALERT*** Tense filled hostage drama that takes place in Dino's Last Chance Bar in New Orleans with a trio of petty crooks hold up there not knowing what exactly the surrounding police are accusing them of! As it later turned out it's one of the hostages whom the cops want for gun smuggling that the FBI set up a sting to catch him. It's in all the confusion that resulted in a deadly car chase where three cops & FBI Agents were killed that the gun smuggler found his way to Dino's Bar! That was just minutes before it was raided by the trio of petty crooks that the police were chasing thinking that their part of the gun smuggling operation. That trio consisted of the brothers Dova & Milo, Matt Dillon & Gary Sinise, and their partner the psychotic Law & Disorder or just plain Law for short, William Fichtner. With Dova Milo & Law not knowing exactly what their wanted for and with the cops and FBI Agents not realizing whom those in the bar are, hostages and hostage takers, the tense stand off lasts for hours into the morning. That's when the police under the command of FBI Agent G.D Browning, Joe Mantegna, plan to raid the place at exactly 7:00 AM with the help of a SWAT team. As the minutes tick away the usual level headed Dova starts to lose it who against his brother Milo's, who was badly injured during the car chase, sound advice plans not to off the hostages plans to blow them all away if the cops make a move on the besieged bar. As for bar owner Dino, Emmet Walsh,who tried to be a hero and take on the trio of bandits he sadly ended up getting killed with his head bashed in, by Law, for his efforts. ***SPOILERS*** It's hostage Janet Boudreaux, Faye Dunaway,the waitress at Dino's Bar who does her best to keep the tension from boiling over and becoming deadly. That's by her advising the leader of the trio Dova that she and the rest of the hostages in the bar won't point him and his motley crew out after the police raid the joint! By her telling the police that the hostage takers escaped thus,in mistaking them as hostages, giving the three a free ride home. What Janet kept from Dova up until the very last moment is that her son like the person whom the police and FBI are really after is one of the hostages! Kevin Spacey directed film that comes across much like the Humphrey Bogart & Bette Davis 1936 crime classic "The Petrified Forest" with a lot more meat or story to it. With a totally unexpected and heart dropping ending that would not have been possible back then in 1936 due to the prudish and "My way or the highway" moral constraints of the then powerful Hollywood Hayes Commission.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring chit chat hostage movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arlis Fuson
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three guys running from the police hide out in a bar and hold the handful of people inside hostage. One of the men is badly injured and they talk and talk and talk about what they are going to do then near the end you find out one of the hostages inside is actually a bigger outlaw than they are. Some get out and some don't. By the end of the film you will more than likely find you don't care about any of these boring characters. I have seen this a few times and never have enjoyed it. It is so extremely slow that it's hard to set through. Kevin Spacey behind the camera offered nothing. The acting was good, but with such a boring movie it didn't matter. Faye Dunaway, M. Emmet Walsh, William Fitchner, John Spencer, Viggo Mortensen, Skeet Ulrich, Joe Mantegna and Gary Sinise all did good, Matt Dillon is a horrible actor and should not be in anything. The music was horrible and made this bad film even worse. This movie is pure drama, 95 percent of the film is spent in the bar with the three idiot bad guys trying to figure out what to do next, it's a hard film to watch because it is so slow.2/10 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Will the Bar Flies Get Swatted?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Papadopoulos
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gather that this neat little movie was loosely based on Humphrey Bogart's The Petrified Forest (1936), which I have never seen in its entirety. An oblique tribute to Bogart is made as the bar in which most of the movie takes place has an old Bogart cinema poster on its wall which features Key Largo (not The Petrified Forest). If there is any similarity between the two movies separated by sixty years it is mostly at the beginning and the bar-hostage situation which occupies about four-fifths of the film. However, Albino Alligator is not a remake of The Petrified Forest. In the Bogart film escaped convicts end up in a bar and terrorise its denizens. In Albino Alligator (referring to a type of pool shot derived from a legend about the alleged habit of alligators to sacrifice weaker members of their own group in order to trap and destroy their rivals) three men are running from the police after a botched warehouse burglary and end up in a basement dive in a pre-Diluvium New Orleans named Dino's Last Chance Bar; a one time basement speak easy which is just about to close for the night. They terrorise the barman , the middle-aged waitress-come do-it-all and the three customers though it is fairly apparent that they are amateur villains but for the one dangerous self-acknowledged sociopath. The Petrified Forest was criticised for being a bit too theatrical, not surprising as it was taken from a stage production. And that may also be true of Albino Alligator but one could say the same of the highly acclaimed Bus Stop starring Marilyn Monroe, in which all the action takes place at a Bus Stop-Coffee bar in Montana. The first ten minutes or so of Albino Alligator -where the burglary is botched in the most amateur way by setting of the warehouse alarms and the escape from the chasing police cars takes place - are basically irrelevant accept to explain why the men are forced to find refuge in the bar. The movie is mainly about the interaction among the burglars and between them and the bar denizens and outside between the local police chief , the FBI and an investigative woman TV reporter. Every character has a vital part to play in the unravelling tale. Nobody is quite what they seem at first sight. There are a few twists, quite well done, and it would be unfair to reveal them. Inevitably the cops arrive as unnoticed the barman has pressed a below counter alarm. But it is never explained how the cops knew exactly who they were seeking in the bar- the film's only flaw. Some of the best film actors alive today comprise the cast and perform wonderfully. The film has been criticised for its profuse use of foul language and violence by those who would prefer to watch Walt Disney movies but such criticism is laughable. This is the sort of film you either detest or love. I loved it. It was never destined to be a blockbuster. It seems the producer and actors didn't expect it to be one. It is the kind of movie actors love to be in and producers die to make but this what those brought up on Hollywood mush don't seem to understand. Some admiring American reviewers would describe it as a "European" style film .But few European films ever get this good. The whole setting and characters are purely American proving that America can make really good movies if the desire is there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Out of control negotiations.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Joe Mantegna definitely has the best scene in "Albino Alligator". It is a humorous infusion into a movie that at times borders on being terminal. Starts out fast with three petty criminals, Dillon, Sinese, and Fichtner, fleeing a botched robbery. Unfortunately once they take refuge in a basement bar, their endless posturing and planning, grinds on the film. There is nothing wrong with the acting, including a great supporting effort from M. Emmet Walsh. Other than the above mentioned scene, Mantegna is somewhat wasted in a one dimensional role. Faye Dunaway is interesting, and William Fichtner is in menacing psycho mode. Marginally recommended. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spacey is not a director
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (tottenhamtillidie@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the face of it, this should be a great film, a great cast, a plot with many possibilities and one of Hollywood's finest behind the camera for the first time. However, its clear why it was another 8 years before spacey decided to try directing a movie again. This movie fails on so many levels. In a film where there is not much action and most of the scenes are shot in a couple of locations, it is imperative that suspense and continuity are provided by the director. Not so here, the great cast is horribly under-used, none more so than the great, late John Spencer, the plot is so run of the mill and nothing you haven't seen in a hundred other TV movies. There is so little character development you end up not caring for any of the protagonists. At least we know spacey has a lot of mates and clout in Hollywood studios to get away with a poor flick like this
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jez88-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film, the character Law played by William Fichtner was sinister but very funny. There is violence but not on a huge scale. The story of the Albino Alligator is brilliantly linked in the film. As the viewer you do start to feel sorry for the three petty criminals who are just there by accident. Each character has a heart but the quiet character of Mortensen is chilling because you don't know anything about him and he's far too calm for the situation. In this film you never know whats going to happen next because the characters are very unpredictable. Overall the film is fantastic and a definite recommendation to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watering Hold Up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When a New Orleans robbery turns into a deadly pursuit, three crooks take refuge in a spacious basement bar and hold those inside hostage. The "Dino's" bar invaders are: handsome bad-boy Matt Dillon (as Dova), muscular psychotic William Fichtner (as Law) and quietly wounded Gary Sinise (as Milo). Of those unlucky enough to be in the bar on this eventful night, the biggest parts go to mouthy barmaid Faye Dunaway (as Janet), secretive businessman Viggo Mortensen (as Guy) and cute pool player Skeet Ulrich (as Danny). The drama was written by Christian Forte (son of 1950s "teen" celebrity Fabian) and directed by Kevin Spacey (the highly accomplished actor)... The term "Albino Alligator" is explained in the story and has some character parallels. This is an enjoyable directorial debut for Mr. Spacey. However, the actors appear to bounce around a lot, and a hidden rifle could have been handled better. Three big "secrets" are revealed - the most important could have been "introduced" along with the opening robbery, for maximum tension; let's anticipate that explosive confrontation. Of the other character relationships, one is a surprise and the other is not; neither adds anything by being held back. Also, the "hero" we're left with at the end would probably be unmasked in real life. But, this is the movies, and the story is engaging. ****** Albino Alligator (9/9/96) Kevin Spacey ~ Matt Dillon, Faye Dunaway, William Fichtner, Viggo Mortensen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tense and engrossing thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Woodyanders (Woodyanders@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A trio of small-time crooks -- dim-witted Dova (a sound performance by Matt Dillon), his more smart and sensible brother Milo (the always excellent Gary Sinise), and volatile psycho Law (William Fichtner in peak creepy and intense form) -- are forced to seek refuge in a bar and take everyone inside hostage after they botch a robbery. Director Kevin Spacey, working from a tight and gripping script by Christian Forte, relates the riveting story at a smooth pace, milks plenty of nerve-rattling claustrophobic tension from the premise, maintains a tough no-nonsense tone throughout, delivers several startling moments of abrupt'n'brutal violence (a car crash that sends a man flying out of a windshield at the start stands out as an especially impressive set piece), and pulls off a fairly surprising ending. The sturdy acting from the fine cast keeps the whole thing humming: Faye Dunaway brings her redoubtable A game to the role of sassy and cynical barmaid Janet Boudreaux, Viggo Mortensen likewise excels as the quiet and mysterious Guy Foucard, Skeet Ulrich is solid and likable as the naive Danny, Joe Mantegna huffs and puffs with rip-snorting &eacute;lan as the hard-nosed Agent G.D. Browning, and M. Emmet Walsh is a total rascally treat in his regrettably smallish part as crusty old bar owner Dino. Mark Plummer's handsome widescreen cinematography makes fluid use of a gliding camera and boasts one doozy of an overhead tracking shot. An enjoyable nail-biter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Blu-Ray version of this is 1.77, not 2.35 to 1 aspect ratio
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chuckju-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A number of new movies out recently in Blu Ray, this one, and many others, are in much smaller aspect ratio than original theatrical release! Next of Kin is another example. This should be protested and not allowed to continue. Normally I expect a Blu-Ray to be a duplicate of the original release. HOWEVER, I BELIEVE THIS IS SIMPLY AN ERROR IN AMAZON'S PRODUCT DESCRIPTION. I CHECKED "OUTLAND" AND THOUGH LISTED AS 1.77 TO 1, IT WAS THE CORRECT 2.3 OR SO TO 1 THAT IT SHOULD BE. This is a rip off of the customer. I bought a very good Blu-Ray of "Cellular" a few weeks ago, but it's in 16 X 9 aspect ratio. Now the new version of "Cellular" in Blu-Ray is the correct 2.35 to 1 aspect ratio. The Cellular BluRay at 16 X 9 was excellent but for the aspect ratio. I don't know if this is a ruse to force cinephiles to pony up for another Blu Ray later or not. But I do hate it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flat hostage drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wizard-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the past I have enjoyed a number of movies involving hostage taking, from "Dog Day Afternoon" to "The Negotiator". So I was pretty sure I would enjoy "Albino Alligator". While the movie is not without merit, overall I felt let down. I will say the movie is well made for a low budget, there is some good acting, and some humor in the movie is funny. But there are a number of problems. For one thing, none of the characters - hostage takers, the chief ATF agent, nor the hostages - are made to be colorful or compelling enough. And I found the central story to be surprisingly dull. There is little tension, the movie moves VERY slowly, and the movie resorts to using clich&eacute;s found in other hostage movies instead of trying to put a new spin on things. While this isn't an awful movie, it is pretty flat, and you'd be better off instead rewatching those movies I mentioned in the first sentence of this review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He's not a hero...None of us are.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ***MAJOR SPOILER ALERT*** Tense filled hostage drama that takes place in Dino's Last Chance Bar in New Orleans with a trio of petty crooks hold up there not knowing what exactly the surrounding police are accusing them of! As it later turned out it's one of the hostages whom the cops want for gun smuggling that the FBI set up a sting to catch him. It's in all the confusion that resulted in a deadly car chase where three cops & FBI Agents were killed that the gun smuggler found his way to Dino's Bar! That was just minutes before it was raided by the trio of petty crooks that the police were chasing thinking that their part of the gun smuggling operation. That trio consisted of the brothers Dova & Milo, Matt Dillon & Gary Sinise, and their partner the psychotic Law & Disorder or just plain Law for short, William Fichtner. With Dova Milo & Law not knowing exactly what their wanted for and with the cops and FBI Agents not realizing whom those in the bar are, hostages and hostage takers, the tense stand off lasts for hours into the morning. That's when the police under the command of FBI Agent G.D Browning, Joe Mantegna, plan to raid the place at exactly 7:00 AM with the help of a SWAT team. As the minutes tick away the usual level headed Dova starts to lose it who against his brother Milo's, who was badly injured during the car chase, sound advice plans not to off the hostages plans to blow them all away if the cops make a move on the besieged bar. As for bar owner Dino, Emmet Walsh,who tried to be a hero and take on the trio of bandits he sadly ended up getting killed with his head bashed in, by Law, for his efforts. ***SPOILERS*** It's hostage Janet Boudreaux, Faye Dunaway,the waitress at Dino's Bar who does her best to keep the tension from boiling over and becoming deadly. That's by her advising the leader of the trio Dova that she and the rest of the hostages in the bar won't point him and his motley crew out after the police raid the joint! By her telling the police that the hostage takers escaped thus,in mistaking them as hostages, giving the three a free ride home. What Janet kept from Dova up until the very last moment is that her son like the person whom the police and FBI are really after is one of the hostages! Kevin Spacey directed film that comes across much like the Humphrey Bogart & Bette Davis 1936 crime classic "The Petrified Forest" with a lot more meat or story to it. With a totally unexpected and heart dropping ending that would not have been possible back then in 1936 due to the prudish and "My way or the highway" moral constraints of the then powerful Hollywood Hayes Commission.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring chit chat hostage movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arlis Fuson
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three guys running from the police hide out in a bar and hold the handful of people inside hostage. One of the men is badly injured and they talk and talk and talk about what they are going to do then near the end you find out one of the hostages inside is actually a bigger outlaw than they are. Some get out and some don't. By the end of the film you will more than likely find you don't care about any of these boring characters. I have seen this a few times and never have enjoyed it. It is so extremely slow that it's hard to set through. Kevin Spacey behind the camera offered nothing. The acting was good, but with such a boring movie it didn't matter. Faye Dunaway, M. Emmet Walsh, William Fitchner, John Spencer, Viggo Mortensen, Skeet Ulrich, Joe Mantegna and Gary Sinise all did good, Matt Dillon is a horrible actor and should not be in anything. The music was horrible and made this bad film even worse. This movie is pure drama, 95 percent of the film is spent in the bar with the three idiot bad guys trying to figure out what to do next, it's a hard film to watch because it is so slow.2/10 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Will the Bar Flies Get Swatted?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Papadopoulos
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gather that this neat little movie was loosely based on Humphrey Bogart's The Petrified Forest (1936), which I have never seen in its entirety. An oblique tribute to Bogart is made as the bar in which most of the movie takes place has an old Bogart cinema poster on its wall which features Key Largo (not The Petrified Forest). If there is any similarity between the two movies separated by sixty years it is mostly at the beginning and the bar-hostage situation which occupies about four-fifths of the film. However, Albino Alligator is not a remake of The Petrified Forest. In the Bogart film escaped convicts end up in a bar and terrorise its denizens. In Albino Alligator (referring to a type of pool shot derived from a legend about the alleged habit of alligators to sacrifice weaker members of their own group in order to trap and destroy their rivals) three men are running from the police after a botched warehouse burglary and end up in a basement dive in a pre-Diluvium New Orleans named Dino's Last Chance Bar; a one time basement speak easy which is just about to close for the night. They terrorise the barman , the middle-aged waitress-come do-it-all and the three customers though it is fairly apparent that they are amateur villains but for the one dangerous self-acknowledged sociopath. The Petrified Forest was criticised for being a bit too theatrical, not surprising as it was taken from a stage production. And that may also be true of Albino Alligator but one could say the same of the highly acclaimed Bus Stop starring Marilyn Monroe, in which all the action takes place at a Bus Stop-Coffee bar in Montana. The first ten minutes or so of Albino Alligator -where the burglary is botched in the most amateur way by setting of the warehouse alarms and the escape from the chasing police cars takes place - are basically irrelevant accept to explain why the men are forced to find refuge in the bar. The movie is mainly about the interaction among the burglars and between them and the bar denizens and outside between the local police chief , the FBI and an investigative woman TV reporter. Every character has a vital part to play in the unravelling tale. Nobody is quite what they seem at first sight. There are a few twists, quite well done, and it would be unfair to reveal them. Inevitably the cops arrive as unnoticed the barman has pressed a below counter alarm. But it is never explained how the cops knew exactly who they were seeking in the bar- the film's only flaw. Some of the best film actors alive today comprise the cast and perform wonderfully. The film has been criticised for its profuse use of foul language and violence by those who would prefer to watch Walt Disney movies but such criticism is laughable. This is the sort of film you either detest or love. I loved it. It was never destined to be a blockbuster. It seems the producer and actors didn't expect it to be one. It is the kind of movie actors love to be in and producers die to make but this what those brought up on Hollywood mush don't seem to understand. Some admiring American reviewers would describe it as a "European" style film .But few European films ever get this good. The whole setting and characters are purely American proving that America can make really good movies if the desire is there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Out of control negotiations.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Joe Mantegna definitely has the best scene in "Albino Alligator". It is a humorous infusion into a movie that at times borders on being terminal. Starts out fast with three petty criminals, Dillon, Sinese, and Fichtner, fleeing a botched robbery. Unfortunately once they take refuge in a basement bar, their endless posturing and planning, grinds on the film. There is nothing wrong with the acting, including a great supporting effort from M. Emmet Walsh. Other than the above mentioned scene, Mantegna is somewhat wasted in a one dimensional role. Faye Dunaway is interesting, and William Fichtner is in menacing psycho mode. Marginally recommended. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spacey is not a director
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (tottenhamtillidie@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the face of it, this should be a great film, a great cast, a plot with many possibilities and one of Hollywood's finest behind the camera for the first time. However, its clear why it was another 8 years before spacey decided to try directing a movie again. This movie fails on so many levels. In a film where there is not much action and most of the scenes are shot in a couple of locations, it is imperative that suspense and continuity are provided by the director. Not so here, the great cast is horribly under-used, none more so than the great, late John Spencer, the plot is so run of the mill and nothing you haven't seen in a hundred other TV movies. There is so little character development you end up not caring for any of the protagonists. At least we know spacey has a lot of mates and clout in Hollywood studios to get away with a poor flick like this
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jez88-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film, the character Law played by William Fichtner was sinister but very funny. There is violence but not on a huge scale. The story of the Albino Alligator is brilliantly linked in the film. As the viewer you do start to feel sorry for the three petty criminals who are just there by accident. Each character has a heart but the quiet character of Mortensen is chilling because you don't know anything about him and he's far too calm for the situation. In this film you never know whats going to happen next because the characters are very unpredictable. Overall the film is fantastic and a definite recommendation to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watering Hold Up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When a New Orleans robbery turns into a deadly pursuit, three crooks take refuge in a spacious basement bar and hold those inside hostage. The "Dino's" bar invaders are: handsome bad-boy Matt Dillon (as Dova), muscular psychotic William Fichtner (as Law) and quietly wounded Gary Sinise (as Milo). Of those unlucky enough to be in the bar on this eventful night, the biggest parts go to mouthy barmaid Faye Dunaway (as Janet), secretive businessman Viggo Mortensen (as Guy) and cute pool player Skeet Ulrich (as Danny). The drama was written by Christian Forte (son of 1950s "teen" celebrity Fabian) and directed by Kevin Spacey (the highly accomplished actor)... The term "Albino Alligator" is explained in the story and has some character parallels. This is an enjoyable directorial debut for Mr. Spacey. However, the actors appear to bounce around a lot, and a hidden rifle could have been handled better. Three big "secrets" are revealed - the most important could have been "introduced" along with the opening robbery, for maximum tension; let's anticipate that explosive confrontation. Of the other character relationships, one is a surprise and the other is not; neither adds anything by being held back. Also, the "hero" we're left with at the end would probably be unmasked in real life. But, this is the movies, and the story is engaging. ****** Albino Alligator (9/9/96) Kevin Spacey ~ Matt Dillon, Faye Dunaway, William Fichtner, Viggo Mortensen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tense and engrossing thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Woodyanders (Woodyanders@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A trio of small-time crooks -- dim-witted Dova (a sound performance by Matt Dillon), his more smart and sensible brother Milo (the always excellent Gary Sinise), and volatile psycho Law (William Fichtner in peak creepy and intense form) -- are forced to seek refuge in a bar and take everyone inside hostage after they botch a robbery. Director Kevin Spacey, working from a tight and gripping script by Christian Forte, relates the riveting story at a smooth pace, milks plenty of nerve-rattling claustrophobic tension from the premise, maintains a tough no-nonsense tone throughout, delivers several startling moments of abrupt'n'brutal violence (a car crash that sends a man flying out of a windshield at the start stands out as an especially impressive set piece), and pulls off a fairly surprising ending. The sturdy acting from the fine cast keeps the whole thing humming: Faye Dunaway brings her redoubtable A game to the role of sassy and cynical barmaid Janet Boudreaux, Viggo Mortensen likewise excels as the quiet and mysterious Guy Foucard, Skeet Ulrich is solid and likable as the naive Danny, Joe Mantegna huffs and puffs with rip-snorting &eacute;lan as the hard-nosed Agent G.D. Browning, and M. Emmet Walsh is a total rascally treat in his regrettably smallish part as crusty old bar owner Dino. Mark Plummer's handsome widescreen cinematography makes fluid use of a gliding camera and boasts one doozy of an overhead tracking shot. An enjoyable nail-biter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Blu-Ray version of this is 1.77, not 2.35 to 1 aspect ratio
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chuckju-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A number of new movies out recently in Blu Ray, this one, and many others, are in much smaller aspect ratio than original theatrical release! Next of Kin is another example. This should be protested and not allowed to continue. Normally I expect a Blu-Ray to be a duplicate of the original release. HOWEVER, I BELIEVE THIS IS SIMPLY AN ERROR IN AMAZON'S PRODUCT DESCRIPTION. I CHECKED "OUTLAND" AND THOUGH LISTED AS 1.77 TO 1, IT WAS THE CORRECT 2.3 OR SO TO 1 THAT IT SHOULD BE. This is a rip off of the customer. I bought a very good Blu-Ray of "Cellular" a few weeks ago, but it's in 16 X 9 aspect ratio. Now the new version of "Cellular" in Blu-Ray is the correct 2.35 to 1 aspect ratio. The Cellular BluRay at 16 X 9 was excellent but for the aspect ratio. I don't know if this is a ruse to force cinephiles to pony up for another Blu Ray later or not. But I do hate it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flat hostage drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wizard-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the past I have enjoyed a number of movies involving hostage taking, from "Dog Day Afternoon" to "The Negotiator". So I was pretty sure I would enjoy "Albino Alligator". While the movie is not without merit, overall I felt let down. I will say the movie is well made for a low budget, there is some good acting, and some humor in the movie is funny. But there are a number of problems. For one thing, none of the characters - hostage takers, the chief ATF agent, nor the hostages - are made to be colorful or compelling enough. And I found the central story to be surprisingly dull. There is little tension, the movie moves VERY slowly, and the movie resorts to using clich&eacute;s found in other hostage movies instead of trying to put a new spin on things. While this isn't an awful movie, it is pretty flat, and you'd be better off instead rewatching those movies I mentioned in the first sentence of this review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He's not a hero...None of us are.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ***MAJOR SPOILER ALERT*** Tense filled hostage drama that takes place in Dino's Last Chance Bar in New Orleans with a trio of petty crooks hold up there not knowing what exactly the surrounding police are accusing them of! As it later turned out it's one of the hostages whom the cops want for gun smuggling that the FBI set up a sting to catch him. It's in all the confusion that resulted in a deadly car chase where three cops & FBI Agents were killed that the gun smuggler found his way to Dino's Bar! That was just minutes before it was raided by the trio of petty crooks that the police were chasing thinking that their part of the gun smuggling operation. That trio consisted of the brothers Dova & Milo, Matt Dillon & Gary Sinise, and their partner the psychotic Law & Disorder or just plain Law for short, William Fichtner. With Dova Milo & Law not knowing exactly what their wanted for and with the cops and FBI Agents not realizing whom those in the bar are, hostages and hostage takers, the tense stand off lasts for hours into the morning. That's when the police under the command of FBI Agent G.D Browning, Joe Mantegna, plan to raid the place at exactly 7:00 AM with the help of a SWAT team. As the minutes tick away the usual level headed Dova starts to lose it who against his brother Milo's, who was badly injured during the car chase, sound advice plans not to off the hostages plans to blow them all away if the cops make a move on the besieged bar. As for bar owner Dino, Emmet Walsh,who tried to be a hero and take on the trio of bandits he sadly ended up getting killed with his head bashed in, by Law, for his efforts. ***SPOILERS*** It's hostage Janet Boudreaux, Faye Dunaway,the waitress at Dino's Bar who does her best to keep the tension from boiling over and becoming deadly. That's by her advising the leader of the trio Dova that she and the rest of the hostages in the bar won't point him and his motley crew out after the police raid the joint! By her telling the police that the hostage takers escaped thus,in mistaking them as hostages, giving the three a free ride home. What Janet kept from Dova up until the very last moment is that her son like the person whom the police and FBI are really after is one of the hostages! Kevin Spacey directed film that comes across much like the Humphrey Bogart & Bette Davis 1936 crime classic "The Petrified Forest" with a lot more meat or story to it. With a totally unexpected and heart dropping ending that would not have been possible back then in 1936 due to the prudish and "My way or the highway" moral constraints of the then powerful Hollywood Hayes Commission.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring chit chat hostage movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arlis Fuson
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three guys running from the police hide out in a bar and hold the handful of people inside hostage. One of the men is badly injured and they talk and talk and talk about what they are going to do then near the end you find out one of the hostages inside is actually a bigger outlaw than they are. Some get out and some don't. By the end of the film you will more than likely find you don't care about any of these boring characters. I have seen this a few times and never have enjoyed it. It is so extremely slow that it's hard to set through. Kevin Spacey behind the camera offered nothing. The acting was good, but with such a boring movie it didn't matter. Faye Dunaway, M. Emmet Walsh, William Fitchner, John Spencer, Viggo Mortensen, Skeet Ulrich, Joe Mantegna and Gary Sinise all did good, Matt Dillon is a horrible actor and should not be in anything. The music was horrible and made this bad film even worse. This movie is pure drama, 95 percent of the film is spent in the bar with the three idiot bad guys trying to figure out what to do next, it's a hard film to watch because it is so slow.2/10 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Will the Bar Flies Get Swatted?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Papadopoulos
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gather that this neat little movie was loosely based on Humphrey Bogart's The Petrified Forest (1936), which I have never seen in its entirety. An oblique tribute to Bogart is made as the bar in which most of the movie takes place has an old Bogart cinema poster on its wall which features Key Largo (not The Petrified Forest). If there is any similarity between the two movies separated by sixty years it is mostly at the beginning and the bar-hostage situation which occupies about four-fifths of the film. However, Albino Alligator is not a remake of The Petrified Forest. In the Bogart film escaped convicts end up in a bar and terrorise its denizens. In Albino Alligator (referring to a type of pool shot derived from a legend about the alleged habit of alligators to sacrifice weaker members of their own group in order to trap and destroy their rivals) three men are running from the police after a botched warehouse burglary and end up in a basement dive in a pre-Diluvium New Orleans named Dino's Last Chance Bar; a one time basement speak easy which is just about to close for the night. They terrorise the barman , the middle-aged waitress-come do-it-all and the three customers though it is fairly apparent that they are amateur villains but for the one dangerous self-acknowledged sociopath. The Petrified Forest was criticised for being a bit too theatrical, not surprising as it was taken from a stage production. And that may also be true of Albino Alligator but one could say the same of the highly acclaimed Bus Stop starring Marilyn Monroe, in which all the action takes place at a Bus Stop-Coffee bar in Montana. The first ten minutes or so of Albino Alligator -where the burglary is botched in the most amateur way by setting of the warehouse alarms and the escape from the chasing police cars takes place - are basically irrelevant accept to explain why the men are forced to find refuge in the bar. The movie is mainly about the interaction among the burglars and between them and the bar denizens and outside between the local police chief , the FBI and an investigative woman TV reporter. Every character has a vital part to play in the unravelling tale. Nobody is quite what they seem at first sight. There are a few twists, quite well done, and it would be unfair to reveal them. Inevitably the cops arrive as unnoticed the barman has pressed a below counter alarm. But it is never explained how the cops knew exactly who they were seeking in the bar- the film's only flaw. Some of the best film actors alive today comprise the cast and perform wonderfully. The film has been criticised for its profuse use of foul language and violence by those who would prefer to watch Walt Disney movies but such criticism is laughable. This is the sort of film you either detest or love. I loved it. It was never destined to be a blockbuster. It seems the producer and actors didn't expect it to be one. It is the kind of movie actors love to be in and producers die to make but this what those brought up on Hollywood mush don't seem to understand. Some admiring American reviewers would describe it as a "European" style film .But few European films ever get this good. The whole setting and characters are purely American proving that America can make really good movies if the desire is there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Out of control negotiations.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Joe Mantegna definitely has the best scene in "Albino Alligator". It is a humorous infusion into a movie that at times borders on being terminal. Starts out fast with three petty criminals, Dillon, Sinese, and Fichtner, fleeing a botched robbery. Unfortunately once they take refuge in a basement bar, their endless posturing and planning, grinds on the film. There is nothing wrong with the acting, including a great supporting effort from M. Emmet Walsh. Other than the above mentioned scene, Mantegna is somewhat wasted in a one dimensional role. Faye Dunaway is interesting, and William Fichtner is in menacing psycho mode. Marginally recommended. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spacey is not a director
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (tottenhamtillidie@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the face of it, this should be a great film, a great cast, a plot with many possibilities and one of Hollywood's finest behind the camera for the first time. However, its clear why it was another 8 years before spacey decided to try directing a movie again. This movie fails on so many levels. In a film where there is not much action and most of the scenes are shot in a couple of locations, it is imperative that suspense and continuity are provided by the director. Not so here, the great cast is horribly under-used, none more so than the great, late John Spencer, the plot is so run of the mill and nothing you haven't seen in a hundred other TV movies. There is so little character development you end up not caring for any of the protagonists. At least we know spacey has a lot of mates and clout in Hollywood studios to get away with a poor flick like this
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jez88-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film, the character Law played by William Fichtner was sinister but very funny. There is violence but not on a huge scale. The story of the Albino Alligator is brilliantly linked in the film. As the viewer you do start to feel sorry for the three petty criminals who are just there by accident. Each character has a heart but the quiet character of Mortensen is chilling because you don't know anything about him and he's far too calm for the situation. In this film you never know whats going to happen next because the characters are very unpredictable. Overall the film is fantastic and a definite recommendation to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watering Hold Up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When a New Orleans robbery turns into a deadly pursuit, three crooks take refuge in a spacious basement bar and hold those inside hostage. The "Dino's" bar invaders are: handsome bad-boy Matt Dillon (as Dova), muscular psychotic William Fichtner (as Law) and quietly wounded Gary Sinise (as Milo). Of those unlucky enough to be in the bar on this eventful night, the biggest parts go to mouthy barmaid Faye Dunaway (as Janet), secretive businessman Viggo Mortensen (as Guy) and cute pool player Skeet Ulrich (as Danny). The drama was written by Christian Forte (son of 1950s "teen" celebrity Fabian) and directed by Kevin Spacey (the highly accomplished actor)... The term "Albino Alligator" is explained in the story and has some character parallels. This is an enjoyable directorial debut for Mr. Spacey. However, the actors appear to bounce around a lot, and a hidden rifle could have been handled better. Three big "secrets" are revealed - the most important could have been "introduced" along with the opening robbery, for maximum tension; let's anticipate that explosive confrontation. Of the other character relationships, one is a surprise and the other is not; neither adds anything by being held back. Also, the "hero" we're left with at the end would probably be unmasked in real life. But, this is the movies, and the story is engaging. ****** Albino Alligator (9/9/96) Kevin Spacey ~ Matt Dillon, Faye Dunaway, William Fichtner, Viggo Mortensen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tense and engrossing thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Woodyanders (Woodyanders@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A trio of small-time crooks -- dim-witted Dova (a sound performance by Matt Dillon), his more smart and sensible brother Milo (the always excellent Gary Sinise), and volatile psycho Law (William Fichtner in peak creepy and intense form) -- are forced to seek refuge in a bar and take everyone inside hostage after they botch a robbery. Director Kevin Spacey, working from a tight and gripping script by Christian Forte, relates the riveting story at a smooth pace, milks plenty of nerve-rattling claustrophobic tension from the premise, maintains a tough no-nonsense tone throughout, delivers several startling moments of abrupt'n'brutal violence (a car crash that sends a man flying out of a windshield at the start stands out as an especially impressive set piece), and pulls off a fairly surprising ending. The sturdy acting from the fine cast keeps the whole thing humming: Faye Dunaway brings her redoubtable A game to the role of sassy and cynical barmaid Janet Boudreaux, Viggo Mortensen likewise excels as the quiet and mysterious Guy Foucard, Skeet Ulrich is solid and likable as the naive Danny, Joe Mantegna huffs and puffs with rip-snorting &eacute;lan as the hard-nosed Agent G.D. Browning, and M. Emmet Walsh is a total rascally treat in his regrettably smallish part as crusty old bar owner Dino. Mark Plummer's handsome widescreen cinematography makes fluid use of a gliding camera and boasts one doozy of an overhead tracking shot. An enjoyable nail-biter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Blu-Ray version of this is 1.77, not 2.35 to 1 aspect ratio
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chuckju-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A number of new movies out recently in Blu Ray, this one, and many others, are in much smaller aspect ratio than original theatrical release! Next of Kin is another example. This should be protested and not allowed to continue. Normally I expect a Blu-Ray to be a duplicate of the original release. HOWEVER, I BELIEVE THIS IS SIMPLY AN ERROR IN AMAZON'S PRODUCT DESCRIPTION. I CHECKED "OUTLAND" AND THOUGH LISTED AS 1.77 TO 1, IT WAS THE CORRECT 2.3 OR SO TO 1 THAT IT SHOULD BE. This is a rip off of the customer. I bought a very good Blu-Ray of "Cellular" a few weeks ago, but it's in 16 X 9 aspect ratio. Now the new version of "Cellular" in Blu-Ray is the correct 2.35 to 1 aspect ratio. The Cellular BluRay at 16 X 9 was excellent but for the aspect ratio. I don't know if this is a ruse to force cinephiles to pony up for another Blu Ray later or not. But I do hate it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flat hostage drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wizard-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the past I have enjoyed a number of movies involving hostage taking, from "Dog Day Afternoon" to "The Negotiator". So I was pretty sure I would enjoy "Albino Alligator". While the movie is not without merit, overall I felt let down. I will say the movie is well made for a low budget, there is some good acting, and some humor in the movie is funny. But there are a number of problems. For one thing, none of the characters - hostage takers, the chief ATF agent, nor the hostages - are made to be colorful or compelling enough. And I found the central story to be surprisingly dull. There is little tension, the movie moves VERY slowly, and the movie resorts to using clich&eacute;s found in other hostage movies instead of trying to put a new spin on things. While this isn't an awful movie, it is pretty flat, and you'd be better off instead rewatching those movies I mentioned in the first sentence of this review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He's not a hero...None of us are.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ***MAJOR SPOILER ALERT*** Tense filled hostage drama that takes place in Dino's Last Chance Bar in New Orleans with a trio of petty crooks hold up there not knowing what exactly the surrounding police are accusing them of! As it later turned out it's one of the hostages whom the cops want for gun smuggling that the FBI set up a sting to catch him. It's in all the confusion that resulted in a deadly car chase where three cops & FBI Agents were killed that the gun smuggler found his way to Dino's Bar! That was just minutes before it was raided by the trio of petty crooks that the police were chasing thinking that their part of the gun smuggling operation. That trio consisted of the brothers Dova & Milo, Matt Dillon & Gary Sinise, and their partner the psychotic Law & Disorder or just plain Law for short, William Fichtner. With Dova Milo & Law not knowing exactly what their wanted for and with the cops and FBI Agents not realizing whom those in the bar are, hostages and hostage takers, the tense stand off lasts for hours into the morning. That's when the police under the command of FBI Agent G.D Browning, Joe Mantegna, plan to raid the place at exactly 7:00 AM with the help of a SWAT team. As the minutes tick away the usual level headed Dova starts to lose it who against his brother Milo's, who was badly injured during the car chase, sound advice plans not to off the hostages plans to blow them all away if the cops make a move on the besieged bar. As for bar owner Dino, Emmet Walsh,who tried to be a hero and take on the trio of bandits he sadly ended up getting killed with his head bashed in, by Law, for his efforts. ***SPOILERS*** It's hostage Janet Boudreaux, Faye Dunaway,the waitress at Dino's Bar who does her best to keep the tension from boiling over and becoming deadly. That's by her advising the leader of the trio Dova that she and the rest of the hostages in the bar won't point him and his motley crew out after the police raid the joint! By her telling the police that the hostage takers escaped thus,in mistaking them as hostages, giving the three a free ride home. What Janet kept from Dova up until the very last moment is that her son like the person whom the police and FBI are really after is one of the hostages! Kevin Spacey directed film that comes across much like the Humphrey Bogart & Bette Davis 1936 crime classic "The Petrified Forest" with a lot more meat or story to it. With a totally unexpected and heart dropping ending that would not have been possible back then in 1936 due to the prudish and "My way or the highway" moral constraints of the then powerful Hollywood Hayes Commission.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring chit chat hostage movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arlis Fuson
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three guys running from the police hide out in a bar and hold the handful of people inside hostage. One of the men is badly injured and they talk and talk and talk about what they are going to do then near the end you find out one of the hostages inside is actually a bigger outlaw than they are. Some get out and some don't. By the end of the film you will more than likely find you don't care about any of these boring characters. I have seen this a few times and never have enjoyed it. It is so extremely slow that it's hard to set through. Kevin Spacey behind the camera offered nothing. The acting was good, but with such a boring movie it didn't matter. Faye Dunaway, M. Emmet Walsh, William Fitchner, John Spencer, Viggo Mortensen, Skeet Ulrich, Joe Mantegna and Gary Sinise all did good, Matt Dillon is a horrible actor and should not be in anything. The music was horrible and made this bad film even worse. This movie is pure drama, 95 percent of the film is spent in the bar with the three idiot bad guys trying to figure out what to do next, it's a hard film to watch because it is so slow.2/10 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Will the Bar Flies Get Swatted?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Papadopoulos
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gather that this neat little movie was loosely based on Humphrey Bogart's The Petrified Forest (1936), which I have never seen in its entirety. An oblique tribute to Bogart is made as the bar in which most of the movie takes place has an old Bogart cinema poster on its wall which features Key Largo (not The Petrified Forest). If there is any similarity between the two movies separated by sixty years it is mostly at the beginning and the bar-hostage situation which occupies about four-fifths of the film. However, Albino Alligator is not a remake of The Petrified Forest. In the Bogart film escaped convicts end up in a bar and terrorise its denizens. In Albino Alligator (referring to a type of pool shot derived from a legend about the alleged habit of alligators to sacrifice weaker members of their own group in order to trap and destroy their rivals) three men are running from the police after a botched warehouse burglary and end up in a basement dive in a pre-Diluvium New Orleans named Dino's Last Chance Bar; a one time basement speak easy which is just about to close for the night. They terrorise the barman , the middle-aged waitress-come do-it-all and the three customers though it is fairly apparent that they are amateur villains but for the one dangerous self-acknowledged sociopath. The Petrified Forest was criticised for being a bit too theatrical, not surprising as it was taken from a stage production. And that may also be true of Albino Alligator but one could say the same of the highly acclaimed Bus Stop starring Marilyn Monroe, in which all the action takes place at a Bus Stop-Coffee bar in Montana. The first ten minutes or so of Albino Alligator -where the burglary is botched in the most amateur way by setting of the warehouse alarms and the escape from the chasing police cars takes place - are basically irrelevant accept to explain why the men are forced to find refuge in the bar. The movie is mainly about the interaction among the burglars and between them and the bar denizens and outside between the local police chief , the FBI and an investigative woman TV reporter. Every character has a vital part to play in the unravelling tale. Nobody is quite what they seem at first sight. There are a few twists, quite well done, and it would be unfair to reveal them. Inevitably the cops arrive as unnoticed the barman has pressed a below counter alarm. But it is never explained how the cops knew exactly who they were seeking in the bar- the film's only flaw. Some of the best film actors alive today comprise the cast and perform wonderfully. The film has been criticised for its profuse use of foul language and violence by those who would prefer to watch Walt Disney movies but such criticism is laughable. This is the sort of film you either detest or love. I loved it. It was never destined to be a blockbuster. It seems the producer and actors didn't expect it to be one. It is the kind of movie actors love to be in and producers die to make but this what those brought up on Hollywood mush don't seem to understand. Some admiring American reviewers would describe it as a "European" style film .But few European films ever get this good. The whole setting and characters are purely American proving that America can make really good movies if the desire is there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Out of control negotiations.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Joe Mantegna definitely has the best scene in "Albino Alligator". It is a humorous infusion into a movie that at times borders on being terminal. Starts out fast with three petty criminals, Dillon, Sinese, and Fichtner, fleeing a botched robbery. Unfortunately once they take refuge in a basement bar, their endless posturing and planning, grinds on the film. There is nothing wrong with the acting, including a great supporting effort from M. Emmet Walsh. Other than the above mentioned scene, Mantegna is somewhat wasted in a one dimensional role. Faye Dunaway is interesting, and William Fichtner is in menacing psycho mode. Marginally recommended. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spacey is not a director
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (tottenhamtillidie@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the face of it, this should be a great film, a great cast, a plot with many possibilities and one of Hollywood's finest behind the camera for the first time. However, its clear why it was another 8 years before spacey decided to try directing a movie again. This movie fails on so many levels. In a film where there is not much action and most of the scenes are shot in a couple of locations, it is imperative that suspense and continuity are provided by the director. Not so here, the great cast is horribly under-used, none more so than the great, late John Spencer, the plot is so run of the mill and nothing you haven't seen in a hundred other TV movies. There is so little character development you end up not caring for any of the protagonists. At least we know spacey has a lot of mates and clout in Hollywood studios to get away with a poor flick like this
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jez88-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film, the character Law played by William Fichtner was sinister but very funny. There is violence but not on a huge scale. The story of the Albino Alligator is brilliantly linked in the film. As the viewer you do start to feel sorry for the three petty criminals who are just there by accident. Each character has a heart but the quiet character of Mortensen is chilling because you don't know anything about him and he's far too calm for the situation. In this film you never know whats going to happen next because the characters are very unpredictable. Overall the film is fantastic and a definite recommendation to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watering Hold Up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When a New Orleans robbery turns into a deadly pursuit, three crooks take refuge in a spacious basement bar and hold those inside hostage. The "Dino's" bar invaders are: handsome bad-boy Matt Dillon (as Dova), muscular psychotic William Fichtner (as Law) and quietly wounded Gary Sinise (as Milo). Of those unlucky enough to be in the bar on this eventful night, the biggest parts go to mouthy barmaid Faye Dunaway (as Janet), secretive businessman Viggo Mortensen (as Guy) and cute pool player Skeet Ulrich (as Danny). The drama was written by Christian Forte (son of 1950s "teen" celebrity Fabian) and directed by Kevin Spacey (the highly accomplished actor)... The term "Albino Alligator" is explained in the story and has some character parallels. This is an enjoyable directorial debut for Mr. Spacey. However, the actors appear to bounce around a lot, and a hidden rifle could have been handled better. Three big "secrets" are revealed - the most important could have been "introduced" along with the opening robbery, for maximum tension; let's anticipate that explosive confrontation. Of the other character relationships, one is a surprise and the other is not; neither adds anything by being held back. Also, the "hero" we're left with at the end would probably be unmasked in real life. But, this is the movies, and the story is engaging. ****** Albino Alligator (9/9/96) Kevin Spacey ~ Matt Dillon, Faye Dunaway, William Fichtner, Viggo Mortensen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tense and engrossing thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Woodyanders (Woodyanders@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A trio of small-time crooks -- dim-witted Dova (a sound performance by Matt Dillon), his more smart and sensible brother Milo (the always excellent Gary Sinise), and volatile psycho Law (William Fichtner in peak creepy and intense form) -- are forced to seek refuge in a bar and take everyone inside hostage after they botch a robbery. Director Kevin Spacey, working from a tight and gripping script by Christian Forte, relates the riveting story at a smooth pace, milks plenty of nerve-rattling claustrophobic tension from the premise, maintains a tough no-nonsense tone throughout, delivers several startling moments of abrupt'n'brutal violence (a car crash that sends a man flying out of a windshield at the start stands out as an especially impressive set piece), and pulls off a fairly surprising ending. The sturdy acting from the fine cast keeps the whole thing humming: Faye Dunaway brings her redoubtable A game to the role of sassy and cynical barmaid Janet Boudreaux, Viggo Mortensen likewise excels as the quiet and mysterious Guy Foucard, Skeet Ulrich is solid and likable as the naive Danny, Joe Mantegna huffs and puffs with rip-snorting &eacute;lan as the hard-nosed Agent G.D. Browning, and M. Emmet Walsh is a total rascally treat in his regrettably smallish part as crusty old bar owner Dino. Mark Plummer's handsome widescreen cinematography makes fluid use of a gliding camera and boasts one doozy of an overhead tracking shot. An enjoyable nail-biter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Blu-Ray version of this is 1.77, not 2.35 to 1 aspect ratio
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chuckju-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A number of new movies out recently in Blu Ray, this one, and many others, are in much smaller aspect ratio than original theatrical release! Next of Kin is another example. This should be protested and not allowed to continue. Normally I expect a Blu-Ray to be a duplicate of the original release. HOWEVER, I BELIEVE THIS IS SIMPLY AN ERROR IN AMAZON'S PRODUCT DESCRIPTION. I CHECKED "OUTLAND" AND THOUGH LISTED AS 1.77 TO 1, IT WAS THE CORRECT 2.3 OR SO TO 1 THAT IT SHOULD BE. This is a rip off of the customer. I bought a very good Blu-Ray of "Cellular" a few weeks ago, but it's in 16 X 9 aspect ratio. Now the new version of "Cellular" in Blu-Ray is the correct 2.35 to 1 aspect ratio. The Cellular BluRay at 16 X 9 was excellent but for the aspect ratio. I don't know if this is a ruse to force cinephiles to pony up for another Blu Ray later or not. But I do hate it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flat hostage drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wizard-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the past I have enjoyed a number of movies involving hostage taking, from "Dog Day Afternoon" to "The Negotiator". So I was pretty sure I would enjoy "Albino Alligator". While the movie is not without merit, overall I felt let down. I will say the movie is well made for a low budget, there is some good acting, and some humor in the movie is funny. But there are a number of problems. For one thing, none of the characters - hostage takers, the chief ATF agent, nor the hostages - are made to be colorful or compelling enough. And I found the central story to be surprisingly dull. There is little tension, the movie moves VERY slowly, and the movie resorts to using clich&eacute;s found in other hostage movies instead of trying to put a new spin on things. While this isn't an awful movie, it is pretty flat, and you'd be better off instead rewatching those movies I mentioned in the first sentence of this review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He's not a hero...None of us are.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ***MAJOR SPOILER ALERT*** Tense filled hostage drama that takes place in Dino's Last Chance Bar in New Orleans with a trio of petty crooks hold up there not knowing what exactly the surrounding police are accusing them of! As it later turned out it's one of the hostages whom the cops want for gun smuggling that the FBI set up a sting to catch him. It's in all the confusion that resulted in a deadly car chase where three cops & FBI Agents were killed that the gun smuggler found his way to Dino's Bar! That was just minutes before it was raided by the trio of petty crooks that the police were chasing thinking that their part of the gun smuggling operation. That trio consisted of the brothers Dova & Milo, Matt Dillon & Gary Sinise, and their partner the psychotic Law & Disorder or just plain Law for short, William Fichtner. With Dova Milo & Law not knowing exactly what their wanted for and with the cops and FBI Agents not realizing whom those in the bar are, hostages and hostage takers, the tense stand off lasts for hours into the morning. That's when the police under the command of FBI Agent G.D Browning, Joe Mantegna, plan to raid the place at exactly 7:00 AM with the help of a SWAT team. As the minutes tick away the usual level headed Dova starts to lose it who against his brother Milo's, who was badly injured during the car chase, sound advice plans not to off the hostages plans to blow them all away if the cops make a move on the besieged bar. As for bar owner Dino, Emmet Walsh,who tried to be a hero and take on the trio of bandits he sadly ended up getting killed with his head bashed in, by Law, for his efforts. ***SPOILERS*** It's hostage Janet Boudreaux, Faye Dunaway,the waitress at Dino's Bar who does her best to keep the tension from boiling over and becoming deadly. That's by her advising the leader of the trio Dova that she and the rest of the hostages in the bar won't point him and his motley crew out after the police raid the joint! By her telling the police that the hostage takers escaped thus,in mistaking them as hostages, giving the three a free ride home. What Janet kept from Dova up until the very last moment is that her son like the person whom the police and FBI are really after is one of the hostages! Kevin Spacey directed film that comes across much like the Humphrey Bogart & Bette Davis 1936 crime classic "The Petrified Forest" with a lot more meat or story to it. With a totally unexpected and heart dropping ending that would not have been possible back then in 1936 due to the prudish and "My way or the highway" moral constraints of the then powerful Hollywood Hayes Commission.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring chit chat hostage movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arlis Fuson
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three guys running from the police hide out in a bar and hold the handful of people inside hostage. One of the men is badly injured and they talk and talk and talk about what they are going to do then near the end you find out one of the hostages inside is actually a bigger outlaw than they are. Some get out and some don't. By the end of the film you will more than likely find you don't care about any of these boring characters. I have seen this a few times and never have enjoyed it. It is so extremely slow that it's hard to set through. Kevin Spacey behind the camera offered nothing. The acting was good, but with such a boring movie it didn't matter. Faye Dunaway, M. Emmet Walsh, William Fitchner, John Spencer, Viggo Mortensen, Skeet Ulrich, Joe Mantegna and Gary Sinise all did good, Matt Dillon is a horrible actor and should not be in anything. The music was horrible and made this bad film even worse. This movie is pure drama, 95 percent of the film is spent in the bar with the three idiot bad guys trying to figure out what to do next, it's a hard film to watch because it is so slow.2/10 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Will the Bar Flies Get Swatted?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Papadopoulos
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gather that this neat little movie was loosely based on Humphrey Bogart's The Petrified Forest (1936), which I have never seen in its entirety. An oblique tribute to Bogart is made as the bar in which most of the movie takes place has an old Bogart cinema poster on its wall which features Key Largo (not The Petrified Forest). If there is any similarity between the two movies separated by sixty years it is mostly at the beginning and the bar-hostage situation which occupies about four-fifths of the film. However, Albino Alligator is not a remake of The Petrified Forest. In the Bogart film escaped convicts end up in a bar and terrorise its denizens. In Albino Alligator (referring to a type of pool shot derived from a legend about the alleged habit of alligators to sacrifice weaker members of their own group in order to trap and destroy their rivals) three men are running from the police after a botched warehouse burglary and end up in a basement dive in a pre-Diluvium New Orleans named Dino's Last Chance Bar; a one time basement speak easy which is just about to close for the night. They terrorise the barman , the middle-aged waitress-come do-it-all and the three customers though it is fairly apparent that they are amateur villains but for the one dangerous self-acknowledged sociopath. The Petrified Forest was criticised for being a bit too theatrical, not surprising as it was taken from a stage production. And that may also be true of Albino Alligator but one could say the same of the highly acclaimed Bus Stop starring Marilyn Monroe, in which all the action takes place at a Bus Stop-Coffee bar in Montana. The first ten minutes or so of Albino Alligator -where the burglary is botched in the most amateur way by setting of the warehouse alarms and the escape from the chasing police cars takes place - are basically irrelevant accept to explain why the men are forced to find refuge in the bar. The movie is mainly about the interaction among the burglars and between them and the bar denizens and outside between the local police chief , the FBI and an investigative woman TV reporter. Every character has a vital part to play in the unravelling tale. Nobody is quite what they seem at first sight. There are a few twists, quite well done, and it would be unfair to reveal them. Inevitably the cops arrive as unnoticed the barman has pressed a below counter alarm. But it is never explained how the cops knew exactly who they were seeking in the bar- the film's only flaw. Some of the best film actors alive today comprise the cast and perform wonderfully. The film has been criticised for its profuse use of foul language and violence by those who would prefer to watch Walt Disney movies but such criticism is laughable. This is the sort of film you either detest or love. I loved it. It was never destined to be a blockbuster. It seems the producer and actors didn't expect it to be one. It is the kind of movie actors love to be in and producers die to make but this what those brought up on Hollywood mush don't seem to understand. Some admiring American reviewers would describe it as a "European" style film .But few European films ever get this good. The whole setting and characters are purely American proving that America can make really good movies if the desire is there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Out of control negotiations.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Joe Mantegna definitely has the best scene in "Albino Alligator". It is a humorous infusion into a movie that at times borders on being terminal. Starts out fast with three petty criminals, Dillon, Sinese, and Fichtner, fleeing a botched robbery. Unfortunately once they take refuge in a basement bar, their endless posturing and planning, grinds on the film. There is nothing wrong with the acting, including a great supporting effort from M. Emmet Walsh. Other than the above mentioned scene, Mantegna is somewhat wasted in a one dimensional role. Faye Dunaway is interesting, and William Fichtner is in menacing psycho mode. Marginally recommended. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spacey is not a director
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (tottenhamtillidie@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the face of it, this should be a great film, a great cast, a plot with many possibilities and one of Hollywood's finest behind the camera for the first time. However, its clear why it was another 8 years before spacey decided to try directing a movie again. This movie fails on so many levels. In a film where there is not much action and most of the scenes are shot in a couple of locations, it is imperative that suspense and continuity are provided by the director. Not so here, the great cast is horribly under-used, none more so than the great, late John Spencer, the plot is so run of the mill and nothing you haven't seen in a hundred other TV movies. There is so little character development you end up not caring for any of the protagonists. At least we know spacey has a lot of mates and clout in Hollywood studios to get away with a poor flick like this
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jez88-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film, the character Law played by William Fichtner was sinister but very funny. There is violence but not on a huge scale. The story of the Albino Alligator is brilliantly linked in the film. As the viewer you do start to feel sorry for the three petty criminals who are just there by accident. Each character has a heart but the quiet character of Mortensen is chilling because you don't know anything about him and he's far too calm for the situation. In this film you never know whats going to happen next because the characters are very unpredictable. Overall the film is fantastic and a definite recommendation to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
