<filme>
 <id>
  1089
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120179
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Velocidade M&aacute;xima 2
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  3.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A computer hacker breaks into the computer system of the Seabourn Legend cruise liner and sets it speeding on a collision course into a gigantic oil tanker.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Annie and her policeman boyfriend Alex decide to take a romantic ocean cruise together. Once at sea, however, one of the passengers, a disgruntled computer genius named Giger, disables the ship. Alex must now foil Giger's plans and bring everyone back safely to shore, but how can he outwit a man who can control the entire ship from his keyboard?
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   computer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   cruise
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   diamond
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   police
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   revenge
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Jan de Bont
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Graham Yost
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Jan de Bont
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Sandra Bullock
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jason Patric
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Willem Dafoe
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need Sequel Control...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sandra Bullock returns as Annie Porter, who, along with her fianc&eacute;e officer Alex Shaw(Jason Patric) are on a romantic cruise liner which is (of course) hijacked by a deranged computer programmer(Willem Dafoe) out for revenge against his company, and wants to use the SeaBourn Legend as the instrument of revenge. Can Annie and Alex stop him? Unbelievably awful film is one of the most inferior sequels ever made. Idiotic plot, poor editing and direction(Jan De Bont) and a bizarrely different portrayal of Annie that is most unappealing(What went wrong between her and Jack Traven I wonder?) Jason Patric tries, but dreadful film is a sinking ship that he can't save. A total disaster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speed?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This sequel to an overrated original is a voyage to the bottom of the barrel, with Sandra Bullock and bland Jason Patric going for a nice cruise only for computer nut Willem Dafoe and his leeches to hijack the ship. Erk! The witless screenplay consists of characters explaining what's just happened, the title is a misnomer because the pace is so slow and Bullock is bloody annoying, although to be fair she has nothing to do besides whine a lot while looking good. The film's saving graces are Mark Mancina's score (great credits music) and Dafoe, who recognises this for the rubbish it is and hams it up like a right mad bastard.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most redundant sequel ever made?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandcooler
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know sequels are usually a lucrative business, and I know that you can keep pretty much any story going if you push hard enough, but honestly, what the hell can you add to the original "Speed"? "Speed" was about as done as a story can get, it had the most Hollywood ending in the history of Hollywood endings. The delightfully entertaining bad guy gets what was coming to him, a bunch of stuff explodes, the world is safe again and Keanu Reeves kisses a still hot Sandra Bullock, we got on with our lives. Then all of a sudden you get this follow-up, which is not only unnecessary but also seems to have an undying grudge against the original. It just takes everything that was cool about the first one and throws it straight out of the window. Why even call it "Speed" if the entire thing is set on a boat that goes about 5 mph? Exciting times. Why even call it "Speed" if you're just going to replace Keanu Reeves (he hated the script, what a rascal) with some D-lister who looks about as athletic as a bag of sawdust? Does the name "Speed" really sell that many extra tickets? Apparently not. I've got to say though, there's one scene in the movie that's almost good: the part where the out-of-control ship just ploughs straight through a village. But even that's kinda ruined by the obvious scale models, so just forget I said that. Horrid in every single way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked it but Don't get why she disrespected Jack from the last one,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jody mitch
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was awesome! I am not really a movie critic as much as a movie lover, and it takes a really really bad movie to make me complain BUT, i entirely see where everyones disappointment is coming from. It was more of a money-maker than a real movie, it had no real point at all lol, and the coincidences were just beyond unimaginable. What i really didn't get is why she was bashing jack (Keanu Reeves) so much,, in the beginning she explains why she left him explaining that he was too insane and i didn't understand that, they had such a happy ending, should've never done that; was that the directors way of getting back at Reeves for not accepting the cast? Lol.. Anyways yeaz unless you like everything you watch, don't watch this!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crap Alarm! (Spoiler Alert)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soerheim91
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well i did like this movie as a child, but today i just wanted to cry! I work on a large ship so i did find so much of the stuff in the movie to be the biggest crap ever! 1. Why do the ship get flooded when they open the ballast tanks? To enter a ballast tank off a ship you have to enter a man-hole that is sealed with a hatch and many bolts... It's not open like a big door... Btw, you can't just sink a ship with filling the ballast tanks. 2. I have never seen a wheel on the thruster that you can turn and make the propeller turn. Most thrusters are electric so i find this hard to believe... correct me if i am wrong. 3. At the end of the movie when they are hitting other vessels they slow down by 1knot every time while the main engine is still running at full. Even if the engine was off the ship would not have lost that much speed of a small impact like that. The ship weight is 9,961 GT so it would take much more to slow a ship like that. 4. Yes you can lower the lifeboats when the ship is moving. All in all it's just to stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flashes of potential, but too many flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw SPEED 2: CRUISE CONTROL at the cinema. I was at the tender age of 16, and I thought it was great: action-packed, with great effects and a fun, DIE HARD-style storyline. Well, it still has all those things, but time has not been kind to SPEED 2, and watching as an adult I can see just how poor it is. The problem with the film is the infantile nature of the script, which sounds as if it's been deliberately written for children. Jason Patric's clunky leading man I can forgive, but the supporting characters and their lame comedy are excruciating. The porter and the Scottish guy are bad enough, but Sandra Bullock takes the biscuit with her repetitive attempts at light humour. If ever a film made you despise someone, it's Bullock in this. Otherwise, the story suffers from a little bloating and an ending that goes on way too long, but it does have some stuff to recommend it. The low rent action-man hijinks are a hoot, and Willem Dafoe is fantastic as the over-the-top villain, all teeth and hair and as crazy as he was in WILD AT HEART. The effects hold up pretty well, too. A shame, then, about the child-friendly nature of the production; had this been a proper, adult-focused outing along the lines of UNDER SIEGE it could have been a damn sight better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's out of control and as bad as it gets.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Olsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thing is beyond lame. The entire cast is about as unlikable and impersonal as can be, and the plot is as thin as the news on CNN. It's a huge problem for any movie, if the characters become annoying from the outset of the movie. This is partly due to bad acting and bad casting. The male lead (Jason Patric) is as believable as an action cop, as it would be to watch a 2 year old fly the Concorde. Sandra Bulldog is annoying beyond hope, due to the characters exaggerated amount of stupidity. The rest of the cast, is just bland and as memorable as a rainy Monday. The only two members of the cast that I find the slightest bit interesting are Christine Firkins and Susan Barnes. The plot, well, it's a ship out of control. The main problem with this is, that the director and producer did not take the time to make it believable. There are so many technical errors in this, it's ridiculous. They did not take the time to find out, how a cruise liner works and that way could have eliminated the ways of stopping the ship in a believable fashion. These technical plot holes just go on and on through the entire movie and ends with the biggest blunder ever. If you have any nautical knowledge and knowledge of ships, you'll find yourself covering your eyes due to sheer embarrassment on the behalf of the writer, director and producer. Ship wreck does not even begin to explain what this movie is, a nuclear blast is less of a disaster than this movie is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speed 2: Cruisin' for a Bruisin'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    horacep
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Speed 2 is an action film that kept my interest and wasn't nearly as bad as some reviewers have described. Sandra Bullock stars so that alone lead me to watch this move, and while this clearly isn't her best work she does a good job. I would have liked to have seen a little more humor in her role, although the early scenes with Tim Conway were funny. She and her boyfriend, an LA SWAT team member, are taking a cruise to get away from it all. In this sequel she once again picks a doomed vehicle to travel in. Willem Dafoe is a disgruntled former cruise line employee determined for revenge with his golf clubs and balls hiding bomb materials, something I've not seen before. There is plenty of action and some fine special effects. My wife and I both thought this move was well worth viewing if you like Sandra Bullock and you like action films without all the cursing that seems to come along with the newer films. All in all it is an interesting movie with a spectacular special effects finish. I rate it above average.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheap Thrills.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Willem Dafoe is a computer genius and madman with long greasy locks who takes over a huge cruise ship at sea, causes numerous crises, steals jewels from the ship's vault, and tries to run the ship up on the rocks. This is the kind of movie about a vehicle in jeopardy that, as the discerning viewer already knows, must have a sick child aboard. After the original helpless boy, in "The High and the Mighty," the child must be a girl. Girls are more pitiful. She needs a kidney transplant or the transfusion of some rare blood type to save her life. Obviously there are going to be problems fitting this stereotypical sick child aboard a cruise ship. After all, if you're going to rush your kid someplace, you don't ordinarily put her aboard a cruise ship full of rich drunks, gamblers, and leisurely honeymooners like Sandra Bullock and Jason Patric. So this pretty little girl is made mute, deaf, and speechless, and she's trapped in the elevator on board a ship that appears to be on fire and sinking. That's the best the writers could come up with. I feel like apologizing for them. However, on the plus side, every other single action movie clich&eacute; that you can think of is on reckless display in this piece of dumbed-down and mentally dangerous garbage. Just take the sound track. There is an alarm bell constantly ringing in the background, overwhelming speech, even though everyone is shouting hysterically. (Except the mute little girl, of course, who must use sign language.) The music thumps and stomps most of the screams into oblivion. The camerman wobbles all over the place, probably drunk on excitement. During the first major crisis -- a lifeboat is hung up on the davits -- the editing is so lightning-fast -- a shot of a spinning winch, a terrified face, a cable snapping thread by thread, a body falling into the sea, arms waving, hands grasping for something just out of reach, an explosion of flashing lights, computer screens turning into a fireworks display, the director dashing momentarily in front of the camera and giving the audience the finger -- that you can't follow events. Each shot lasts for one blink of one eye, dashing past like muscae volitantes on speed, until they blend into one another and form a stupefying collage of abandoned movement. I rather liked the original "Speed," which was thoroughly mindless enjoyment. This is bigger, faster, more expensive, stupider. You still want to watch it? Take some Dramamine and a good book along.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Head for the lifeboats, people - this one's going down fast! 42%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As much as I'm a fan of US film critic and all-round nice guy Roger Ebert, there are plenty of times when I disagree with him. I never have and never will call myself a critic - I remain, first and foremost, an audience goer, regardless of whether I'm watching a film at home or at the cinema. Therefore, I regard all films on how entertaining they are rather than the likelihood of winning anything during award season. Despite my resolutely low-brow approach, I do disagree with Ebert on this turgid sequel to one of the best action movies of the Nineties. Ebert's positive praise for this movie was the only good review anywhere to be found of this film and to be frank, I can't really see where he's coming from. Sandra Bullock returns as Annie, the goofy heroine from the first movie who is now seeing fellow LA officer Alex (Jason Patric) - unaware that Alex is just as reckless a daredevil as her ex Jack (Keanu Reeves, who was smarter enough to avoid this). After going away for a romantic cruise in the Caribbean, Annie and Alex find themselves caught up in the explosive schemes of crazed bomber Geiger (Willem Dafoe, in full-on psycho mode). With the ship beyond the control of the crew, Geiger sets a course for collision with an oil tanker - leaving Alex, Annie and a handful of terrified passengers to try and save the ship as well as stop Geiger from making off with loads of diamonds stolen from the ship's vault. What made "Speed" so good was that despite the stupid plot, it remained a genuinely thrilling ride with a suitably OTT villain in the shape of Dennis Hopper, Bullock's flustered performance as the reluctant heroine and the occasionally tongue-in-cheek moment to lighten the mood. So naturally, "Speed 2: Cruise Control" (and can you see what they did there with the title?) offers more of the same except this time, they blew it. Dafoe couldn't be any more insane if he rocked on his knees in the corner of the room reciting nursery rhymes and is actually a pretty weak baddie - at times, I almost felt sorry for him as he appeared to be suffering from some sort of mental illness. Bullock this time is largely relegated to the damsel-in-distress role, leaving Patric to carry the film which, sadly, is beyond him - he is as vacant as an waitress's smile. But the film's attempt at subtle humour badly backfires - take Dante (Royale Watkins), for example, and his insistence on taking photos of everything at any time, even when he's up to his neck in water on a sinking sink. The passengers are mostly anonymous apart from a trapped deaf girl (Christine Ferkins) who provides a side mission and a sweaty fat guy with a moustache (Mike Hagerty) - the rest all seem to be screaming fat women, for some reason. What sort of cruise is this? There are some things to commend, however. The action, when it does arrive, is performed in vast amounts of gushing cold water which can't be pleasant and I must give a nod to Temuera Morrison as the first officer because he is, by far and away, the most convincing actor on screen. He certainly better than the annoying Scot (Brian McCardie) who simply must count down loud the speed of the crashing ship in knots whilst looking like he's being buggered. But "Speed 2: Cruise Control" is that kinda film - even Geiger's Fiber Optic Converter has a big sticky label on it so we can all see what it is! This is an insultingly stupid summer action blockbuster that, in truth, has nothing whatsoever to do with the original and if that's what you want then fine. But for everyone involved, this is am embarrassing outing that sadly ruined the reputation of "Speed" which is unfair because that is a real blast. This is barely a fizzle. Maybe Ebert has a soft spot for Ms Bullock but the question I posed was is this an entertaining film. Only if you get your kicks from exchanges like "It's an earthquake!" "It can't be - we're at sea!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need Sequel Control...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sandra Bullock returns as Annie Porter, who, along with her fianc&eacute;e officer Alex Shaw(Jason Patric) are on a romantic cruise liner which is (of course) hijacked by a deranged computer programmer(Willem Dafoe) out for revenge against his company, and wants to use the SeaBourn Legend as the instrument of revenge. Can Annie and Alex stop him? Unbelievably awful film is one of the most inferior sequels ever made. Idiotic plot, poor editing and direction(Jan De Bont) and a bizarrely different portrayal of Annie that is most unappealing(What went wrong between her and Jack Traven I wonder?) Jason Patric tries, but dreadful film is a sinking ship that he can't save. A total disaster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speed?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This sequel to an overrated original is a voyage to the bottom of the barrel, with Sandra Bullock and bland Jason Patric going for a nice cruise only for computer nut Willem Dafoe and his leeches to hijack the ship. Erk! The witless screenplay consists of characters explaining what's just happened, the title is a misnomer because the pace is so slow and Bullock is bloody annoying, although to be fair she has nothing to do besides whine a lot while looking good. The film's saving graces are Mark Mancina's score (great credits music) and Dafoe, who recognises this for the rubbish it is and hams it up like a right mad bastard.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most redundant sequel ever made?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandcooler
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know sequels are usually a lucrative business, and I know that you can keep pretty much any story going if you push hard enough, but honestly, what the hell can you add to the original "Speed"? "Speed" was about as done as a story can get, it had the most Hollywood ending in the history of Hollywood endings. The delightfully entertaining bad guy gets what was coming to him, a bunch of stuff explodes, the world is safe again and Keanu Reeves kisses a still hot Sandra Bullock, we got on with our lives. Then all of a sudden you get this follow-up, which is not only unnecessary but also seems to have an undying grudge against the original. It just takes everything that was cool about the first one and throws it straight out of the window. Why even call it "Speed" if the entire thing is set on a boat that goes about 5 mph? Exciting times. Why even call it "Speed" if you're just going to replace Keanu Reeves (he hated the script, what a rascal) with some D-lister who looks about as athletic as a bag of sawdust? Does the name "Speed" really sell that many extra tickets? Apparently not. I've got to say though, there's one scene in the movie that's almost good: the part where the out-of-control ship just ploughs straight through a village. But even that's kinda ruined by the obvious scale models, so just forget I said that. Horrid in every single way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked it but Don't get why she disrespected Jack from the last one,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jody mitch
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was awesome! I am not really a movie critic as much as a movie lover, and it takes a really really bad movie to make me complain BUT, i entirely see where everyones disappointment is coming from. It was more of a money-maker than a real movie, it had no real point at all lol, and the coincidences were just beyond unimaginable. What i really didn't get is why she was bashing jack (Keanu Reeves) so much,, in the beginning she explains why she left him explaining that he was too insane and i didn't understand that, they had such a happy ending, should've never done that; was that the directors way of getting back at Reeves for not accepting the cast? Lol.. Anyways yeaz unless you like everything you watch, don't watch this!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crap Alarm! (Spoiler Alert)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soerheim91
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well i did like this movie as a child, but today i just wanted to cry! I work on a large ship so i did find so much of the stuff in the movie to be the biggest crap ever! 1. Why do the ship get flooded when they open the ballast tanks? To enter a ballast tank off a ship you have to enter a man-hole that is sealed with a hatch and many bolts... It's not open like a big door... Btw, you can't just sink a ship with filling the ballast tanks. 2. I have never seen a wheel on the thruster that you can turn and make the propeller turn. Most thrusters are electric so i find this hard to believe... correct me if i am wrong. 3. At the end of the movie when they are hitting other vessels they slow down by 1knot every time while the main engine is still running at full. Even if the engine was off the ship would not have lost that much speed of a small impact like that. The ship weight is 9,961 GT so it would take much more to slow a ship like that. 4. Yes you can lower the lifeboats when the ship is moving. All in all it's just to stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flashes of potential, but too many flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw SPEED 2: CRUISE CONTROL at the cinema. I was at the tender age of 16, and I thought it was great: action-packed, with great effects and a fun, DIE HARD-style storyline. Well, it still has all those things, but time has not been kind to SPEED 2, and watching as an adult I can see just how poor it is. The problem with the film is the infantile nature of the script, which sounds as if it's been deliberately written for children. Jason Patric's clunky leading man I can forgive, but the supporting characters and their lame comedy are excruciating. The porter and the Scottish guy are bad enough, but Sandra Bullock takes the biscuit with her repetitive attempts at light humour. If ever a film made you despise someone, it's Bullock in this. Otherwise, the story suffers from a little bloating and an ending that goes on way too long, but it does have some stuff to recommend it. The low rent action-man hijinks are a hoot, and Willem Dafoe is fantastic as the over-the-top villain, all teeth and hair and as crazy as he was in WILD AT HEART. The effects hold up pretty well, too. A shame, then, about the child-friendly nature of the production; had this been a proper, adult-focused outing along the lines of UNDER SIEGE it could have been a damn sight better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's out of control and as bad as it gets.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Olsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thing is beyond lame. The entire cast is about as unlikable and impersonal as can be, and the plot is as thin as the news on CNN. It's a huge problem for any movie, if the characters become annoying from the outset of the movie. This is partly due to bad acting and bad casting. The male lead (Jason Patric) is as believable as an action cop, as it would be to watch a 2 year old fly the Concorde. Sandra Bulldog is annoying beyond hope, due to the characters exaggerated amount of stupidity. The rest of the cast, is just bland and as memorable as a rainy Monday. The only two members of the cast that I find the slightest bit interesting are Christine Firkins and Susan Barnes. The plot, well, it's a ship out of control. The main problem with this is, that the director and producer did not take the time to make it believable. There are so many technical errors in this, it's ridiculous. They did not take the time to find out, how a cruise liner works and that way could have eliminated the ways of stopping the ship in a believable fashion. These technical plot holes just go on and on through the entire movie and ends with the biggest blunder ever. If you have any nautical knowledge and knowledge of ships, you'll find yourself covering your eyes due to sheer embarrassment on the behalf of the writer, director and producer. Ship wreck does not even begin to explain what this movie is, a nuclear blast is less of a disaster than this movie is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speed 2: Cruisin' for a Bruisin'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    horacep
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Speed 2 is an action film that kept my interest and wasn't nearly as bad as some reviewers have described. Sandra Bullock stars so that alone lead me to watch this move, and while this clearly isn't her best work she does a good job. I would have liked to have seen a little more humor in her role, although the early scenes with Tim Conway were funny. She and her boyfriend, an LA SWAT team member, are taking a cruise to get away from it all. In this sequel she once again picks a doomed vehicle to travel in. Willem Dafoe is a disgruntled former cruise line employee determined for revenge with his golf clubs and balls hiding bomb materials, something I've not seen before. There is plenty of action and some fine special effects. My wife and I both thought this move was well worth viewing if you like Sandra Bullock and you like action films without all the cursing that seems to come along with the newer films. All in all it is an interesting movie with a spectacular special effects finish. I rate it above average.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheap Thrills.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Willem Dafoe is a computer genius and madman with long greasy locks who takes over a huge cruise ship at sea, causes numerous crises, steals jewels from the ship's vault, and tries to run the ship up on the rocks. This is the kind of movie about a vehicle in jeopardy that, as the discerning viewer already knows, must have a sick child aboard. After the original helpless boy, in "The High and the Mighty," the child must be a girl. Girls are more pitiful. She needs a kidney transplant or the transfusion of some rare blood type to save her life. Obviously there are going to be problems fitting this stereotypical sick child aboard a cruise ship. After all, if you're going to rush your kid someplace, you don't ordinarily put her aboard a cruise ship full of rich drunks, gamblers, and leisurely honeymooners like Sandra Bullock and Jason Patric. So this pretty little girl is made mute, deaf, and speechless, and she's trapped in the elevator on board a ship that appears to be on fire and sinking. That's the best the writers could come up with. I feel like apologizing for them. However, on the plus side, every other single action movie clich&eacute; that you can think of is on reckless display in this piece of dumbed-down and mentally dangerous garbage. Just take the sound track. There is an alarm bell constantly ringing in the background, overwhelming speech, even though everyone is shouting hysterically. (Except the mute little girl, of course, who must use sign language.) The music thumps and stomps most of the screams into oblivion. The camerman wobbles all over the place, probably drunk on excitement. During the first major crisis -- a lifeboat is hung up on the davits -- the editing is so lightning-fast -- a shot of a spinning winch, a terrified face, a cable snapping thread by thread, a body falling into the sea, arms waving, hands grasping for something just out of reach, an explosion of flashing lights, computer screens turning into a fireworks display, the director dashing momentarily in front of the camera and giving the audience the finger -- that you can't follow events. Each shot lasts for one blink of one eye, dashing past like muscae volitantes on speed, until they blend into one another and form a stupefying collage of abandoned movement. I rather liked the original "Speed," which was thoroughly mindless enjoyment. This is bigger, faster, more expensive, stupider. You still want to watch it? Take some Dramamine and a good book along.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Head for the lifeboats, people - this one's going down fast! 42%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As much as I'm a fan of US film critic and all-round nice guy Roger Ebert, there are plenty of times when I disagree with him. I never have and never will call myself a critic - I remain, first and foremost, an audience goer, regardless of whether I'm watching a film at home or at the cinema. Therefore, I regard all films on how entertaining they are rather than the likelihood of winning anything during award season. Despite my resolutely low-brow approach, I do disagree with Ebert on this turgid sequel to one of the best action movies of the Nineties. Ebert's positive praise for this movie was the only good review anywhere to be found of this film and to be frank, I can't really see where he's coming from. Sandra Bullock returns as Annie, the goofy heroine from the first movie who is now seeing fellow LA officer Alex (Jason Patric) - unaware that Alex is just as reckless a daredevil as her ex Jack (Keanu Reeves, who was smarter enough to avoid this). After going away for a romantic cruise in the Caribbean, Annie and Alex find themselves caught up in the explosive schemes of crazed bomber Geiger (Willem Dafoe, in full-on psycho mode). With the ship beyond the control of the crew, Geiger sets a course for collision with an oil tanker - leaving Alex, Annie and a handful of terrified passengers to try and save the ship as well as stop Geiger from making off with loads of diamonds stolen from the ship's vault. What made "Speed" so good was that despite the stupid plot, it remained a genuinely thrilling ride with a suitably OTT villain in the shape of Dennis Hopper, Bullock's flustered performance as the reluctant heroine and the occasionally tongue-in-cheek moment to lighten the mood. So naturally, "Speed 2: Cruise Control" (and can you see what they did there with the title?) offers more of the same except this time, they blew it. Dafoe couldn't be any more insane if he rocked on his knees in the corner of the room reciting nursery rhymes and is actually a pretty weak baddie - at times, I almost felt sorry for him as he appeared to be suffering from some sort of mental illness. Bullock this time is largely relegated to the damsel-in-distress role, leaving Patric to carry the film which, sadly, is beyond him - he is as vacant as an waitress's smile. But the film's attempt at subtle humour badly backfires - take Dante (Royale Watkins), for example, and his insistence on taking photos of everything at any time, even when he's up to his neck in water on a sinking sink. The passengers are mostly anonymous apart from a trapped deaf girl (Christine Ferkins) who provides a side mission and a sweaty fat guy with a moustache (Mike Hagerty) - the rest all seem to be screaming fat women, for some reason. What sort of cruise is this? There are some things to commend, however. The action, when it does arrive, is performed in vast amounts of gushing cold water which can't be pleasant and I must give a nod to Temuera Morrison as the first officer because he is, by far and away, the most convincing actor on screen. He certainly better than the annoying Scot (Brian McCardie) who simply must count down loud the speed of the crashing ship in knots whilst looking like he's being buggered. But "Speed 2: Cruise Control" is that kinda film - even Geiger's Fiber Optic Converter has a big sticky label on it so we can all see what it is! This is an insultingly stupid summer action blockbuster that, in truth, has nothing whatsoever to do with the original and if that's what you want then fine. But for everyone involved, this is am embarrassing outing that sadly ruined the reputation of "Speed" which is unfair because that is a real blast. This is barely a fizzle. Maybe Ebert has a soft spot for Ms Bullock but the question I posed was is this an entertaining film. Only if you get your kicks from exchanges like "It's an earthquake!" "It can't be - we're at sea!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need Sequel Control...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sandra Bullock returns as Annie Porter, who, along with her fianc&eacute;e officer Alex Shaw(Jason Patric) are on a romantic cruise liner which is (of course) hijacked by a deranged computer programmer(Willem Dafoe) out for revenge against his company, and wants to use the SeaBourn Legend as the instrument of revenge. Can Annie and Alex stop him? Unbelievably awful film is one of the most inferior sequels ever made. Idiotic plot, poor editing and direction(Jan De Bont) and a bizarrely different portrayal of Annie that is most unappealing(What went wrong between her and Jack Traven I wonder?) Jason Patric tries, but dreadful film is a sinking ship that he can't save. A total disaster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speed?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This sequel to an overrated original is a voyage to the bottom of the barrel, with Sandra Bullock and bland Jason Patric going for a nice cruise only for computer nut Willem Dafoe and his leeches to hijack the ship. Erk! The witless screenplay consists of characters explaining what's just happened, the title is a misnomer because the pace is so slow and Bullock is bloody annoying, although to be fair she has nothing to do besides whine a lot while looking good. The film's saving graces are Mark Mancina's score (great credits music) and Dafoe, who recognises this for the rubbish it is and hams it up like a right mad bastard.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most redundant sequel ever made?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandcooler
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know sequels are usually a lucrative business, and I know that you can keep pretty much any story going if you push hard enough, but honestly, what the hell can you add to the original "Speed"? "Speed" was about as done as a story can get, it had the most Hollywood ending in the history of Hollywood endings. The delightfully entertaining bad guy gets what was coming to him, a bunch of stuff explodes, the world is safe again and Keanu Reeves kisses a still hot Sandra Bullock, we got on with our lives. Then all of a sudden you get this follow-up, which is not only unnecessary but also seems to have an undying grudge against the original. It just takes everything that was cool about the first one and throws it straight out of the window. Why even call it "Speed" if the entire thing is set on a boat that goes about 5 mph? Exciting times. Why even call it "Speed" if you're just going to replace Keanu Reeves (he hated the script, what a rascal) with some D-lister who looks about as athletic as a bag of sawdust? Does the name "Speed" really sell that many extra tickets? Apparently not. I've got to say though, there's one scene in the movie that's almost good: the part where the out-of-control ship just ploughs straight through a village. But even that's kinda ruined by the obvious scale models, so just forget I said that. Horrid in every single way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked it but Don't get why she disrespected Jack from the last one,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jody mitch
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was awesome! I am not really a movie critic as much as a movie lover, and it takes a really really bad movie to make me complain BUT, i entirely see where everyones disappointment is coming from. It was more of a money-maker than a real movie, it had no real point at all lol, and the coincidences were just beyond unimaginable. What i really didn't get is why she was bashing jack (Keanu Reeves) so much,, in the beginning she explains why she left him explaining that he was too insane and i didn't understand that, they had such a happy ending, should've never done that; was that the directors way of getting back at Reeves for not accepting the cast? Lol.. Anyways yeaz unless you like everything you watch, don't watch this!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crap Alarm! (Spoiler Alert)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soerheim91
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well i did like this movie as a child, but today i just wanted to cry! I work on a large ship so i did find so much of the stuff in the movie to be the biggest crap ever! 1. Why do the ship get flooded when they open the ballast tanks? To enter a ballast tank off a ship you have to enter a man-hole that is sealed with a hatch and many bolts... It's not open like a big door... Btw, you can't just sink a ship with filling the ballast tanks. 2. I have never seen a wheel on the thruster that you can turn and make the propeller turn. Most thrusters are electric so i find this hard to believe... correct me if i am wrong. 3. At the end of the movie when they are hitting other vessels they slow down by 1knot every time while the main engine is still running at full. Even if the engine was off the ship would not have lost that much speed of a small impact like that. The ship weight is 9,961 GT so it would take much more to slow a ship like that. 4. Yes you can lower the lifeboats when the ship is moving. All in all it's just to stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flashes of potential, but too many flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw SPEED 2: CRUISE CONTROL at the cinema. I was at the tender age of 16, and I thought it was great: action-packed, with great effects and a fun, DIE HARD-style storyline. Well, it still has all those things, but time has not been kind to SPEED 2, and watching as an adult I can see just how poor it is. The problem with the film is the infantile nature of the script, which sounds as if it's been deliberately written for children. Jason Patric's clunky leading man I can forgive, but the supporting characters and their lame comedy are excruciating. The porter and the Scottish guy are bad enough, but Sandra Bullock takes the biscuit with her repetitive attempts at light humour. If ever a film made you despise someone, it's Bullock in this. Otherwise, the story suffers from a little bloating and an ending that goes on way too long, but it does have some stuff to recommend it. The low rent action-man hijinks are a hoot, and Willem Dafoe is fantastic as the over-the-top villain, all teeth and hair and as crazy as he was in WILD AT HEART. The effects hold up pretty well, too. A shame, then, about the child-friendly nature of the production; had this been a proper, adult-focused outing along the lines of UNDER SIEGE it could have been a damn sight better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's out of control and as bad as it gets.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Olsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thing is beyond lame. The entire cast is about as unlikable and impersonal as can be, and the plot is as thin as the news on CNN. It's a huge problem for any movie, if the characters become annoying from the outset of the movie. This is partly due to bad acting and bad casting. The male lead (Jason Patric) is as believable as an action cop, as it would be to watch a 2 year old fly the Concorde. Sandra Bulldog is annoying beyond hope, due to the characters exaggerated amount of stupidity. The rest of the cast, is just bland and as memorable as a rainy Monday. The only two members of the cast that I find the slightest bit interesting are Christine Firkins and Susan Barnes. The plot, well, it's a ship out of control. The main problem with this is, that the director and producer did not take the time to make it believable. There are so many technical errors in this, it's ridiculous. They did not take the time to find out, how a cruise liner works and that way could have eliminated the ways of stopping the ship in a believable fashion. These technical plot holes just go on and on through the entire movie and ends with the biggest blunder ever. If you have any nautical knowledge and knowledge of ships, you'll find yourself covering your eyes due to sheer embarrassment on the behalf of the writer, director and producer. Ship wreck does not even begin to explain what this movie is, a nuclear blast is less of a disaster than this movie is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speed 2: Cruisin' for a Bruisin'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    horacep
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Speed 2 is an action film that kept my interest and wasn't nearly as bad as some reviewers have described. Sandra Bullock stars so that alone lead me to watch this move, and while this clearly isn't her best work she does a good job. I would have liked to have seen a little more humor in her role, although the early scenes with Tim Conway were funny. She and her boyfriend, an LA SWAT team member, are taking a cruise to get away from it all. In this sequel she once again picks a doomed vehicle to travel in. Willem Dafoe is a disgruntled former cruise line employee determined for revenge with his golf clubs and balls hiding bomb materials, something I've not seen before. There is plenty of action and some fine special effects. My wife and I both thought this move was well worth viewing if you like Sandra Bullock and you like action films without all the cursing that seems to come along with the newer films. All in all it is an interesting movie with a spectacular special effects finish. I rate it above average.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheap Thrills.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Willem Dafoe is a computer genius and madman with long greasy locks who takes over a huge cruise ship at sea, causes numerous crises, steals jewels from the ship's vault, and tries to run the ship up on the rocks. This is the kind of movie about a vehicle in jeopardy that, as the discerning viewer already knows, must have a sick child aboard. After the original helpless boy, in "The High and the Mighty," the child must be a girl. Girls are more pitiful. She needs a kidney transplant or the transfusion of some rare blood type to save her life. Obviously there are going to be problems fitting this stereotypical sick child aboard a cruise ship. After all, if you're going to rush your kid someplace, you don't ordinarily put her aboard a cruise ship full of rich drunks, gamblers, and leisurely honeymooners like Sandra Bullock and Jason Patric. So this pretty little girl is made mute, deaf, and speechless, and she's trapped in the elevator on board a ship that appears to be on fire and sinking. That's the best the writers could come up with. I feel like apologizing for them. However, on the plus side, every other single action movie clich&eacute; that you can think of is on reckless display in this piece of dumbed-down and mentally dangerous garbage. Just take the sound track. There is an alarm bell constantly ringing in the background, overwhelming speech, even though everyone is shouting hysterically. (Except the mute little girl, of course, who must use sign language.) The music thumps and stomps most of the screams into oblivion. The camerman wobbles all over the place, probably drunk on excitement. During the first major crisis -- a lifeboat is hung up on the davits -- the editing is so lightning-fast -- a shot of a spinning winch, a terrified face, a cable snapping thread by thread, a body falling into the sea, arms waving, hands grasping for something just out of reach, an explosion of flashing lights, computer screens turning into a fireworks display, the director dashing momentarily in front of the camera and giving the audience the finger -- that you can't follow events. Each shot lasts for one blink of one eye, dashing past like muscae volitantes on speed, until they blend into one another and form a stupefying collage of abandoned movement. I rather liked the original "Speed," which was thoroughly mindless enjoyment. This is bigger, faster, more expensive, stupider. You still want to watch it? Take some Dramamine and a good book along.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Head for the lifeboats, people - this one's going down fast! 42%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As much as I'm a fan of US film critic and all-round nice guy Roger Ebert, there are plenty of times when I disagree with him. I never have and never will call myself a critic - I remain, first and foremost, an audience goer, regardless of whether I'm watching a film at home or at the cinema. Therefore, I regard all films on how entertaining they are rather than the likelihood of winning anything during award season. Despite my resolutely low-brow approach, I do disagree with Ebert on this turgid sequel to one of the best action movies of the Nineties. Ebert's positive praise for this movie was the only good review anywhere to be found of this film and to be frank, I can't really see where he's coming from. Sandra Bullock returns as Annie, the goofy heroine from the first movie who is now seeing fellow LA officer Alex (Jason Patric) - unaware that Alex is just as reckless a daredevil as her ex Jack (Keanu Reeves, who was smarter enough to avoid this). After going away for a romantic cruise in the Caribbean, Annie and Alex find themselves caught up in the explosive schemes of crazed bomber Geiger (Willem Dafoe, in full-on psycho mode). With the ship beyond the control of the crew, Geiger sets a course for collision with an oil tanker - leaving Alex, Annie and a handful of terrified passengers to try and save the ship as well as stop Geiger from making off with loads of diamonds stolen from the ship's vault. What made "Speed" so good was that despite the stupid plot, it remained a genuinely thrilling ride with a suitably OTT villain in the shape of Dennis Hopper, Bullock's flustered performance as the reluctant heroine and the occasionally tongue-in-cheek moment to lighten the mood. So naturally, "Speed 2: Cruise Control" (and can you see what they did there with the title?) offers more of the same except this time, they blew it. Dafoe couldn't be any more insane if he rocked on his knees in the corner of the room reciting nursery rhymes and is actually a pretty weak baddie - at times, I almost felt sorry for him as he appeared to be suffering from some sort of mental illness. Bullock this time is largely relegated to the damsel-in-distress role, leaving Patric to carry the film which, sadly, is beyond him - he is as vacant as an waitress's smile. But the film's attempt at subtle humour badly backfires - take Dante (Royale Watkins), for example, and his insistence on taking photos of everything at any time, even when he's up to his neck in water on a sinking sink. The passengers are mostly anonymous apart from a trapped deaf girl (Christine Ferkins) who provides a side mission and a sweaty fat guy with a moustache (Mike Hagerty) - the rest all seem to be screaming fat women, for some reason. What sort of cruise is this? There are some things to commend, however. The action, when it does arrive, is performed in vast amounts of gushing cold water which can't be pleasant and I must give a nod to Temuera Morrison as the first officer because he is, by far and away, the most convincing actor on screen. He certainly better than the annoying Scot (Brian McCardie) who simply must count down loud the speed of the crashing ship in knots whilst looking like he's being buggered. But "Speed 2: Cruise Control" is that kinda film - even Geiger's Fiber Optic Converter has a big sticky label on it so we can all see what it is! This is an insultingly stupid summer action blockbuster that, in truth, has nothing whatsoever to do with the original and if that's what you want then fine. But for everyone involved, this is am embarrassing outing that sadly ruined the reputation of "Speed" which is unfair because that is a real blast. This is barely a fizzle. Maybe Ebert has a soft spot for Ms Bullock but the question I posed was is this an entertaining film. Only if you get your kicks from exchanges like "It's an earthquake!" "It can't be - we're at sea!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need Sequel Control...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sandra Bullock returns as Annie Porter, who, along with her fianc&eacute;e officer Alex Shaw(Jason Patric) are on a romantic cruise liner which is (of course) hijacked by a deranged computer programmer(Willem Dafoe) out for revenge against his company, and wants to use the SeaBourn Legend as the instrument of revenge. Can Annie and Alex stop him? Unbelievably awful film is one of the most inferior sequels ever made. Idiotic plot, poor editing and direction(Jan De Bont) and a bizarrely different portrayal of Annie that is most unappealing(What went wrong between her and Jack Traven I wonder?) Jason Patric tries, but dreadful film is a sinking ship that he can't save. A total disaster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speed?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This sequel to an overrated original is a voyage to the bottom of the barrel, with Sandra Bullock and bland Jason Patric going for a nice cruise only for computer nut Willem Dafoe and his leeches to hijack the ship. Erk! The witless screenplay consists of characters explaining what's just happened, the title is a misnomer because the pace is so slow and Bullock is bloody annoying, although to be fair she has nothing to do besides whine a lot while looking good. The film's saving graces are Mark Mancina's score (great credits music) and Dafoe, who recognises this for the rubbish it is and hams it up like a right mad bastard.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most redundant sequel ever made?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandcooler
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know sequels are usually a lucrative business, and I know that you can keep pretty much any story going if you push hard enough, but honestly, what the hell can you add to the original "Speed"? "Speed" was about as done as a story can get, it had the most Hollywood ending in the history of Hollywood endings. The delightfully entertaining bad guy gets what was coming to him, a bunch of stuff explodes, the world is safe again and Keanu Reeves kisses a still hot Sandra Bullock, we got on with our lives. Then all of a sudden you get this follow-up, which is not only unnecessary but also seems to have an undying grudge against the original. It just takes everything that was cool about the first one and throws it straight out of the window. Why even call it "Speed" if the entire thing is set on a boat that goes about 5 mph? Exciting times. Why even call it "Speed" if you're just going to replace Keanu Reeves (he hated the script, what a rascal) with some D-lister who looks about as athletic as a bag of sawdust? Does the name "Speed" really sell that many extra tickets? Apparently not. I've got to say though, there's one scene in the movie that's almost good: the part where the out-of-control ship just ploughs straight through a village. But even that's kinda ruined by the obvious scale models, so just forget I said that. Horrid in every single way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked it but Don't get why she disrespected Jack from the last one,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jody mitch
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was awesome! I am not really a movie critic as much as a movie lover, and it takes a really really bad movie to make me complain BUT, i entirely see where everyones disappointment is coming from. It was more of a money-maker than a real movie, it had no real point at all lol, and the coincidences were just beyond unimaginable. What i really didn't get is why she was bashing jack (Keanu Reeves) so much,, in the beginning she explains why she left him explaining that he was too insane and i didn't understand that, they had such a happy ending, should've never done that; was that the directors way of getting back at Reeves for not accepting the cast? Lol.. Anyways yeaz unless you like everything you watch, don't watch this!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crap Alarm! (Spoiler Alert)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soerheim91
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well i did like this movie as a child, but today i just wanted to cry! I work on a large ship so i did find so much of the stuff in the movie to be the biggest crap ever! 1. Why do the ship get flooded when they open the ballast tanks? To enter a ballast tank off a ship you have to enter a man-hole that is sealed with a hatch and many bolts... It's not open like a big door... Btw, you can't just sink a ship with filling the ballast tanks. 2. I have never seen a wheel on the thruster that you can turn and make the propeller turn. Most thrusters are electric so i find this hard to believe... correct me if i am wrong. 3. At the end of the movie when they are hitting other vessels they slow down by 1knot every time while the main engine is still running at full. Even if the engine was off the ship would not have lost that much speed of a small impact like that. The ship weight is 9,961 GT so it would take much more to slow a ship like that. 4. Yes you can lower the lifeboats when the ship is moving. All in all it's just to stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flashes of potential, but too many flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw SPEED 2: CRUISE CONTROL at the cinema. I was at the tender age of 16, and I thought it was great: action-packed, with great effects and a fun, DIE HARD-style storyline. Well, it still has all those things, but time has not been kind to SPEED 2, and watching as an adult I can see just how poor it is. The problem with the film is the infantile nature of the script, which sounds as if it's been deliberately written for children. Jason Patric's clunky leading man I can forgive, but the supporting characters and their lame comedy are excruciating. The porter and the Scottish guy are bad enough, but Sandra Bullock takes the biscuit with her repetitive attempts at light humour. If ever a film made you despise someone, it's Bullock in this. Otherwise, the story suffers from a little bloating and an ending that goes on way too long, but it does have some stuff to recommend it. The low rent action-man hijinks are a hoot, and Willem Dafoe is fantastic as the over-the-top villain, all teeth and hair and as crazy as he was in WILD AT HEART. The effects hold up pretty well, too. A shame, then, about the child-friendly nature of the production; had this been a proper, adult-focused outing along the lines of UNDER SIEGE it could have been a damn sight better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's out of control and as bad as it gets.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Olsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thing is beyond lame. The entire cast is about as unlikable and impersonal as can be, and the plot is as thin as the news on CNN. It's a huge problem for any movie, if the characters become annoying from the outset of the movie. This is partly due to bad acting and bad casting. The male lead (Jason Patric) is as believable as an action cop, as it would be to watch a 2 year old fly the Concorde. Sandra Bulldog is annoying beyond hope, due to the characters exaggerated amount of stupidity. The rest of the cast, is just bland and as memorable as a rainy Monday. The only two members of the cast that I find the slightest bit interesting are Christine Firkins and Susan Barnes. The plot, well, it's a ship out of control. The main problem with this is, that the director and producer did not take the time to make it believable. There are so many technical errors in this, it's ridiculous. They did not take the time to find out, how a cruise liner works and that way could have eliminated the ways of stopping the ship in a believable fashion. These technical plot holes just go on and on through the entire movie and ends with the biggest blunder ever. If you have any nautical knowledge and knowledge of ships, you'll find yourself covering your eyes due to sheer embarrassment on the behalf of the writer, director and producer. Ship wreck does not even begin to explain what this movie is, a nuclear blast is less of a disaster than this movie is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speed 2: Cruisin' for a Bruisin'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    horacep
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Speed 2 is an action film that kept my interest and wasn't nearly as bad as some reviewers have described. Sandra Bullock stars so that alone lead me to watch this move, and while this clearly isn't her best work she does a good job. I would have liked to have seen a little more humor in her role, although the early scenes with Tim Conway were funny. She and her boyfriend, an LA SWAT team member, are taking a cruise to get away from it all. In this sequel she once again picks a doomed vehicle to travel in. Willem Dafoe is a disgruntled former cruise line employee determined for revenge with his golf clubs and balls hiding bomb materials, something I've not seen before. There is plenty of action and some fine special effects. My wife and I both thought this move was well worth viewing if you like Sandra Bullock and you like action films without all the cursing that seems to come along with the newer films. All in all it is an interesting movie with a spectacular special effects finish. I rate it above average.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheap Thrills.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Willem Dafoe is a computer genius and madman with long greasy locks who takes over a huge cruise ship at sea, causes numerous crises, steals jewels from the ship's vault, and tries to run the ship up on the rocks. This is the kind of movie about a vehicle in jeopardy that, as the discerning viewer already knows, must have a sick child aboard. After the original helpless boy, in "The High and the Mighty," the child must be a girl. Girls are more pitiful. She needs a kidney transplant or the transfusion of some rare blood type to save her life. Obviously there are going to be problems fitting this stereotypical sick child aboard a cruise ship. After all, if you're going to rush your kid someplace, you don't ordinarily put her aboard a cruise ship full of rich drunks, gamblers, and leisurely honeymooners like Sandra Bullock and Jason Patric. So this pretty little girl is made mute, deaf, and speechless, and she's trapped in the elevator on board a ship that appears to be on fire and sinking. That's the best the writers could come up with. I feel like apologizing for them. However, on the plus side, every other single action movie clich&eacute; that you can think of is on reckless display in this piece of dumbed-down and mentally dangerous garbage. Just take the sound track. There is an alarm bell constantly ringing in the background, overwhelming speech, even though everyone is shouting hysterically. (Except the mute little girl, of course, who must use sign language.) The music thumps and stomps most of the screams into oblivion. The camerman wobbles all over the place, probably drunk on excitement. During the first major crisis -- a lifeboat is hung up on the davits -- the editing is so lightning-fast -- a shot of a spinning winch, a terrified face, a cable snapping thread by thread, a body falling into the sea, arms waving, hands grasping for something just out of reach, an explosion of flashing lights, computer screens turning into a fireworks display, the director dashing momentarily in front of the camera and giving the audience the finger -- that you can't follow events. Each shot lasts for one blink of one eye, dashing past like muscae volitantes on speed, until they blend into one another and form a stupefying collage of abandoned movement. I rather liked the original "Speed," which was thoroughly mindless enjoyment. This is bigger, faster, more expensive, stupider. You still want to watch it? Take some Dramamine and a good book along.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Head for the lifeboats, people - this one's going down fast! 42%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As much as I'm a fan of US film critic and all-round nice guy Roger Ebert, there are plenty of times when I disagree with him. I never have and never will call myself a critic - I remain, first and foremost, an audience goer, regardless of whether I'm watching a film at home or at the cinema. Therefore, I regard all films on how entertaining they are rather than the likelihood of winning anything during award season. Despite my resolutely low-brow approach, I do disagree with Ebert on this turgid sequel to one of the best action movies of the Nineties. Ebert's positive praise for this movie was the only good review anywhere to be found of this film and to be frank, I can't really see where he's coming from. Sandra Bullock returns as Annie, the goofy heroine from the first movie who is now seeing fellow LA officer Alex (Jason Patric) - unaware that Alex is just as reckless a daredevil as her ex Jack (Keanu Reeves, who was smarter enough to avoid this). After going away for a romantic cruise in the Caribbean, Annie and Alex find themselves caught up in the explosive schemes of crazed bomber Geiger (Willem Dafoe, in full-on psycho mode). With the ship beyond the control of the crew, Geiger sets a course for collision with an oil tanker - leaving Alex, Annie and a handful of terrified passengers to try and save the ship as well as stop Geiger from making off with loads of diamonds stolen from the ship's vault. What made "Speed" so good was that despite the stupid plot, it remained a genuinely thrilling ride with a suitably OTT villain in the shape of Dennis Hopper, Bullock's flustered performance as the reluctant heroine and the occasionally tongue-in-cheek moment to lighten the mood. So naturally, "Speed 2: Cruise Control" (and can you see what they did there with the title?) offers more of the same except this time, they blew it. Dafoe couldn't be any more insane if he rocked on his knees in the corner of the room reciting nursery rhymes and is actually a pretty weak baddie - at times, I almost felt sorry for him as he appeared to be suffering from some sort of mental illness. Bullock this time is largely relegated to the damsel-in-distress role, leaving Patric to carry the film which, sadly, is beyond him - he is as vacant as an waitress's smile. But the film's attempt at subtle humour badly backfires - take Dante (Royale Watkins), for example, and his insistence on taking photos of everything at any time, even when he's up to his neck in water on a sinking sink. The passengers are mostly anonymous apart from a trapped deaf girl (Christine Ferkins) who provides a side mission and a sweaty fat guy with a moustache (Mike Hagerty) - the rest all seem to be screaming fat women, for some reason. What sort of cruise is this? There are some things to commend, however. The action, when it does arrive, is performed in vast amounts of gushing cold water which can't be pleasant and I must give a nod to Temuera Morrison as the first officer because he is, by far and away, the most convincing actor on screen. He certainly better than the annoying Scot (Brian McCardie) who simply must count down loud the speed of the crashing ship in knots whilst looking like he's being buggered. But "Speed 2: Cruise Control" is that kinda film - even Geiger's Fiber Optic Converter has a big sticky label on it so we can all see what it is! This is an insultingly stupid summer action blockbuster that, in truth, has nothing whatsoever to do with the original and if that's what you want then fine. But for everyone involved, this is am embarrassing outing that sadly ruined the reputation of "Speed" which is unfair because that is a real blast. This is barely a fizzle. Maybe Ebert has a soft spot for Ms Bullock but the question I posed was is this an entertaining film. Only if you get your kicks from exchanges like "It's an earthquake!" "It can't be - we're at sea!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need Sequel Control...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sandra Bullock returns as Annie Porter, who, along with her fianc&eacute;e officer Alex Shaw(Jason Patric) are on a romantic cruise liner which is (of course) hijacked by a deranged computer programmer(Willem Dafoe) out for revenge against his company, and wants to use the SeaBourn Legend as the instrument of revenge. Can Annie and Alex stop him? Unbelievably awful film is one of the most inferior sequels ever made. Idiotic plot, poor editing and direction(Jan De Bont) and a bizarrely different portrayal of Annie that is most unappealing(What went wrong between her and Jack Traven I wonder?) Jason Patric tries, but dreadful film is a sinking ship that he can't save. A total disaster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speed?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This sequel to an overrated original is a voyage to the bottom of the barrel, with Sandra Bullock and bland Jason Patric going for a nice cruise only for computer nut Willem Dafoe and his leeches to hijack the ship. Erk! The witless screenplay consists of characters explaining what's just happened, the title is a misnomer because the pace is so slow and Bullock is bloody annoying, although to be fair she has nothing to do besides whine a lot while looking good. The film's saving graces are Mark Mancina's score (great credits music) and Dafoe, who recognises this for the rubbish it is and hams it up like a right mad bastard.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most redundant sequel ever made?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandcooler
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know sequels are usually a lucrative business, and I know that you can keep pretty much any story going if you push hard enough, but honestly, what the hell can you add to the original "Speed"? "Speed" was about as done as a story can get, it had the most Hollywood ending in the history of Hollywood endings. The delightfully entertaining bad guy gets what was coming to him, a bunch of stuff explodes, the world is safe again and Keanu Reeves kisses a still hot Sandra Bullock, we got on with our lives. Then all of a sudden you get this follow-up, which is not only unnecessary but also seems to have an undying grudge against the original. It just takes everything that was cool about the first one and throws it straight out of the window. Why even call it "Speed" if the entire thing is set on a boat that goes about 5 mph? Exciting times. Why even call it "Speed" if you're just going to replace Keanu Reeves (he hated the script, what a rascal) with some D-lister who looks about as athletic as a bag of sawdust? Does the name "Speed" really sell that many extra tickets? Apparently not. I've got to say though, there's one scene in the movie that's almost good: the part where the out-of-control ship just ploughs straight through a village. But even that's kinda ruined by the obvious scale models, so just forget I said that. Horrid in every single way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked it but Don't get why she disrespected Jack from the last one,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jody mitch
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was awesome! I am not really a movie critic as much as a movie lover, and it takes a really really bad movie to make me complain BUT, i entirely see where everyones disappointment is coming from. It was more of a money-maker than a real movie, it had no real point at all lol, and the coincidences were just beyond unimaginable. What i really didn't get is why she was bashing jack (Keanu Reeves) so much,, in the beginning she explains why she left him explaining that he was too insane and i didn't understand that, they had such a happy ending, should've never done that; was that the directors way of getting back at Reeves for not accepting the cast? Lol.. Anyways yeaz unless you like everything you watch, don't watch this!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crap Alarm! (Spoiler Alert)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soerheim91
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well i did like this movie as a child, but today i just wanted to cry! I work on a large ship so i did find so much of the stuff in the movie to be the biggest crap ever! 1. Why do the ship get flooded when they open the ballast tanks? To enter a ballast tank off a ship you have to enter a man-hole that is sealed with a hatch and many bolts... It's not open like a big door... Btw, you can't just sink a ship with filling the ballast tanks. 2. I have never seen a wheel on the thruster that you can turn and make the propeller turn. Most thrusters are electric so i find this hard to believe... correct me if i am wrong. 3. At the end of the movie when they are hitting other vessels they slow down by 1knot every time while the main engine is still running at full. Even if the engine was off the ship would not have lost that much speed of a small impact like that. The ship weight is 9,961 GT so it would take much more to slow a ship like that. 4. Yes you can lower the lifeboats when the ship is moving. All in all it's just to stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flashes of potential, but too many flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw SPEED 2: CRUISE CONTROL at the cinema. I was at the tender age of 16, and I thought it was great: action-packed, with great effects and a fun, DIE HARD-style storyline. Well, it still has all those things, but time has not been kind to SPEED 2, and watching as an adult I can see just how poor it is. The problem with the film is the infantile nature of the script, which sounds as if it's been deliberately written for children. Jason Patric's clunky leading man I can forgive, but the supporting characters and their lame comedy are excruciating. The porter and the Scottish guy are bad enough, but Sandra Bullock takes the biscuit with her repetitive attempts at light humour. If ever a film made you despise someone, it's Bullock in this. Otherwise, the story suffers from a little bloating and an ending that goes on way too long, but it does have some stuff to recommend it. The low rent action-man hijinks are a hoot, and Willem Dafoe is fantastic as the over-the-top villain, all teeth and hair and as crazy as he was in WILD AT HEART. The effects hold up pretty well, too. A shame, then, about the child-friendly nature of the production; had this been a proper, adult-focused outing along the lines of UNDER SIEGE it could have been a damn sight better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's out of control and as bad as it gets.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Olsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thing is beyond lame. The entire cast is about as unlikable and impersonal as can be, and the plot is as thin as the news on CNN. It's a huge problem for any movie, if the characters become annoying from the outset of the movie. This is partly due to bad acting and bad casting. The male lead (Jason Patric) is as believable as an action cop, as it would be to watch a 2 year old fly the Concorde. Sandra Bulldog is annoying beyond hope, due to the characters exaggerated amount of stupidity. The rest of the cast, is just bland and as memorable as a rainy Monday. The only two members of the cast that I find the slightest bit interesting are Christine Firkins and Susan Barnes. The plot, well, it's a ship out of control. The main problem with this is, that the director and producer did not take the time to make it believable. There are so many technical errors in this, it's ridiculous. They did not take the time to find out, how a cruise liner works and that way could have eliminated the ways of stopping the ship in a believable fashion. These technical plot holes just go on and on through the entire movie and ends with the biggest blunder ever. If you have any nautical knowledge and knowledge of ships, you'll find yourself covering your eyes due to sheer embarrassment on the behalf of the writer, director and producer. Ship wreck does not even begin to explain what this movie is, a nuclear blast is less of a disaster than this movie is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speed 2: Cruisin' for a Bruisin'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    horacep
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Speed 2 is an action film that kept my interest and wasn't nearly as bad as some reviewers have described. Sandra Bullock stars so that alone lead me to watch this move, and while this clearly isn't her best work she does a good job. I would have liked to have seen a little more humor in her role, although the early scenes with Tim Conway were funny. She and her boyfriend, an LA SWAT team member, are taking a cruise to get away from it all. In this sequel she once again picks a doomed vehicle to travel in. Willem Dafoe is a disgruntled former cruise line employee determined for revenge with his golf clubs and balls hiding bomb materials, something I've not seen before. There is plenty of action and some fine special effects. My wife and I both thought this move was well worth viewing if you like Sandra Bullock and you like action films without all the cursing that seems to come along with the newer films. All in all it is an interesting movie with a spectacular special effects finish. I rate it above average.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheap Thrills.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Willem Dafoe is a computer genius and madman with long greasy locks who takes over a huge cruise ship at sea, causes numerous crises, steals jewels from the ship's vault, and tries to run the ship up on the rocks. This is the kind of movie about a vehicle in jeopardy that, as the discerning viewer already knows, must have a sick child aboard. After the original helpless boy, in "The High and the Mighty," the child must be a girl. Girls are more pitiful. She needs a kidney transplant or the transfusion of some rare blood type to save her life. Obviously there are going to be problems fitting this stereotypical sick child aboard a cruise ship. After all, if you're going to rush your kid someplace, you don't ordinarily put her aboard a cruise ship full of rich drunks, gamblers, and leisurely honeymooners like Sandra Bullock and Jason Patric. So this pretty little girl is made mute, deaf, and speechless, and she's trapped in the elevator on board a ship that appears to be on fire and sinking. That's the best the writers could come up with. I feel like apologizing for them. However, on the plus side, every other single action movie clich&eacute; that you can think of is on reckless display in this piece of dumbed-down and mentally dangerous garbage. Just take the sound track. There is an alarm bell constantly ringing in the background, overwhelming speech, even though everyone is shouting hysterically. (Except the mute little girl, of course, who must use sign language.) The music thumps and stomps most of the screams into oblivion. The camerman wobbles all over the place, probably drunk on excitement. During the first major crisis -- a lifeboat is hung up on the davits -- the editing is so lightning-fast -- a shot of a spinning winch, a terrified face, a cable snapping thread by thread, a body falling into the sea, arms waving, hands grasping for something just out of reach, an explosion of flashing lights, computer screens turning into a fireworks display, the director dashing momentarily in front of the camera and giving the audience the finger -- that you can't follow events. Each shot lasts for one blink of one eye, dashing past like muscae volitantes on speed, until they blend into one another and form a stupefying collage of abandoned movement. I rather liked the original "Speed," which was thoroughly mindless enjoyment. This is bigger, faster, more expensive, stupider. You still want to watch it? Take some Dramamine and a good book along.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Head for the lifeboats, people - this one's going down fast! 42%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As much as I'm a fan of US film critic and all-round nice guy Roger Ebert, there are plenty of times when I disagree with him. I never have and never will call myself a critic - I remain, first and foremost, an audience goer, regardless of whether I'm watching a film at home or at the cinema. Therefore, I regard all films on how entertaining they are rather than the likelihood of winning anything during award season. Despite my resolutely low-brow approach, I do disagree with Ebert on this turgid sequel to one of the best action movies of the Nineties. Ebert's positive praise for this movie was the only good review anywhere to be found of this film and to be frank, I can't really see where he's coming from. Sandra Bullock returns as Annie, the goofy heroine from the first movie who is now seeing fellow LA officer Alex (Jason Patric) - unaware that Alex is just as reckless a daredevil as her ex Jack (Keanu Reeves, who was smarter enough to avoid this). After going away for a romantic cruise in the Caribbean, Annie and Alex find themselves caught up in the explosive schemes of crazed bomber Geiger (Willem Dafoe, in full-on psycho mode). With the ship beyond the control of the crew, Geiger sets a course for collision with an oil tanker - leaving Alex, Annie and a handful of terrified passengers to try and save the ship as well as stop Geiger from making off with loads of diamonds stolen from the ship's vault. What made "Speed" so good was that despite the stupid plot, it remained a genuinely thrilling ride with a suitably OTT villain in the shape of Dennis Hopper, Bullock's flustered performance as the reluctant heroine and the occasionally tongue-in-cheek moment to lighten the mood. So naturally, "Speed 2: Cruise Control" (and can you see what they did there with the title?) offers more of the same except this time, they blew it. Dafoe couldn't be any more insane if he rocked on his knees in the corner of the room reciting nursery rhymes and is actually a pretty weak baddie - at times, I almost felt sorry for him as he appeared to be suffering from some sort of mental illness. Bullock this time is largely relegated to the damsel-in-distress role, leaving Patric to carry the film which, sadly, is beyond him - he is as vacant as an waitress's smile. But the film's attempt at subtle humour badly backfires - take Dante (Royale Watkins), for example, and his insistence on taking photos of everything at any time, even when he's up to his neck in water on a sinking sink. The passengers are mostly anonymous apart from a trapped deaf girl (Christine Ferkins) who provides a side mission and a sweaty fat guy with a moustache (Mike Hagerty) - the rest all seem to be screaming fat women, for some reason. What sort of cruise is this? There are some things to commend, however. The action, when it does arrive, is performed in vast amounts of gushing cold water which can't be pleasant and I must give a nod to Temuera Morrison as the first officer because he is, by far and away, the most convincing actor on screen. He certainly better than the annoying Scot (Brian McCardie) who simply must count down loud the speed of the crashing ship in knots whilst looking like he's being buggered. But "Speed 2: Cruise Control" is that kinda film - even Geiger's Fiber Optic Converter has a big sticky label on it so we can all see what it is! This is an insultingly stupid summer action blockbuster that, in truth, has nothing whatsoever to do with the original and if that's what you want then fine. But for everyone involved, this is am embarrassing outing that sadly ruined the reputation of "Speed" which is unfair because that is a real blast. This is barely a fizzle. Maybe Ebert has a soft spot for Ms Bullock but the question I posed was is this an entertaining film. Only if you get your kicks from exchanges like "It's an earthquake!" "It can't be - we're at sea!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need Sequel Control...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sandra Bullock returns as Annie Porter, who, along with her fianc&eacute;e officer Alex Shaw(Jason Patric) are on a romantic cruise liner which is (of course) hijacked by a deranged computer programmer(Willem Dafoe) out for revenge against his company, and wants to use the SeaBourn Legend as the instrument of revenge. Can Annie and Alex stop him? Unbelievably awful film is one of the most inferior sequels ever made. Idiotic plot, poor editing and direction(Jan De Bont) and a bizarrely different portrayal of Annie that is most unappealing(What went wrong between her and Jack Traven I wonder?) Jason Patric tries, but dreadful film is a sinking ship that he can't save. A total disaster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speed?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This sequel to an overrated original is a voyage to the bottom of the barrel, with Sandra Bullock and bland Jason Patric going for a nice cruise only for computer nut Willem Dafoe and his leeches to hijack the ship. Erk! The witless screenplay consists of characters explaining what's just happened, the title is a misnomer because the pace is so slow and Bullock is bloody annoying, although to be fair she has nothing to do besides whine a lot while looking good. The film's saving graces are Mark Mancina's score (great credits music) and Dafoe, who recognises this for the rubbish it is and hams it up like a right mad bastard.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most redundant sequel ever made?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandcooler
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know sequels are usually a lucrative business, and I know that you can keep pretty much any story going if you push hard enough, but honestly, what the hell can you add to the original "Speed"? "Speed" was about as done as a story can get, it had the most Hollywood ending in the history of Hollywood endings. The delightfully entertaining bad guy gets what was coming to him, a bunch of stuff explodes, the world is safe again and Keanu Reeves kisses a still hot Sandra Bullock, we got on with our lives. Then all of a sudden you get this follow-up, which is not only unnecessary but also seems to have an undying grudge against the original. It just takes everything that was cool about the first one and throws it straight out of the window. Why even call it "Speed" if the entire thing is set on a boat that goes about 5 mph? Exciting times. Why even call it "Speed" if you're just going to replace Keanu Reeves (he hated the script, what a rascal) with some D-lister who looks about as athletic as a bag of sawdust? Does the name "Speed" really sell that many extra tickets? Apparently not. I've got to say though, there's one scene in the movie that's almost good: the part where the out-of-control ship just ploughs straight through a village. But even that's kinda ruined by the obvious scale models, so just forget I said that. Horrid in every single way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked it but Don't get why she disrespected Jack from the last one,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jody mitch
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was awesome! I am not really a movie critic as much as a movie lover, and it takes a really really bad movie to make me complain BUT, i entirely see where everyones disappointment is coming from. It was more of a money-maker than a real movie, it had no real point at all lol, and the coincidences were just beyond unimaginable. What i really didn't get is why she was bashing jack (Keanu Reeves) so much,, in the beginning she explains why she left him explaining that he was too insane and i didn't understand that, they had such a happy ending, should've never done that; was that the directors way of getting back at Reeves for not accepting the cast? Lol.. Anyways yeaz unless you like everything you watch, don't watch this!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crap Alarm! (Spoiler Alert)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soerheim91
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well i did like this movie as a child, but today i just wanted to cry! I work on a large ship so i did find so much of the stuff in the movie to be the biggest crap ever! 1. Why do the ship get flooded when they open the ballast tanks? To enter a ballast tank off a ship you have to enter a man-hole that is sealed with a hatch and many bolts... It's not open like a big door... Btw, you can't just sink a ship with filling the ballast tanks. 2. I have never seen a wheel on the thruster that you can turn and make the propeller turn. Most thrusters are electric so i find this hard to believe... correct me if i am wrong. 3. At the end of the movie when they are hitting other vessels they slow down by 1knot every time while the main engine is still running at full. Even if the engine was off the ship would not have lost that much speed of a small impact like that. The ship weight is 9,961 GT so it would take much more to slow a ship like that. 4. Yes you can lower the lifeboats when the ship is moving. All in all it's just to stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flashes of potential, but too many flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw SPEED 2: CRUISE CONTROL at the cinema. I was at the tender age of 16, and I thought it was great: action-packed, with great effects and a fun, DIE HARD-style storyline. Well, it still has all those things, but time has not been kind to SPEED 2, and watching as an adult I can see just how poor it is. The problem with the film is the infantile nature of the script, which sounds as if it's been deliberately written for children. Jason Patric's clunky leading man I can forgive, but the supporting characters and their lame comedy are excruciating. The porter and the Scottish guy are bad enough, but Sandra Bullock takes the biscuit with her repetitive attempts at light humour. If ever a film made you despise someone, it's Bullock in this. Otherwise, the story suffers from a little bloating and an ending that goes on way too long, but it does have some stuff to recommend it. The low rent action-man hijinks are a hoot, and Willem Dafoe is fantastic as the over-the-top villain, all teeth and hair and as crazy as he was in WILD AT HEART. The effects hold up pretty well, too. A shame, then, about the child-friendly nature of the production; had this been a proper, adult-focused outing along the lines of UNDER SIEGE it could have been a damn sight better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's out of control and as bad as it gets.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Olsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thing is beyond lame. The entire cast is about as unlikable and impersonal as can be, and the plot is as thin as the news on CNN. It's a huge problem for any movie, if the characters become annoying from the outset of the movie. This is partly due to bad acting and bad casting. The male lead (Jason Patric) is as believable as an action cop, as it would be to watch a 2 year old fly the Concorde. Sandra Bulldog is annoying beyond hope, due to the characters exaggerated amount of stupidity. The rest of the cast, is just bland and as memorable as a rainy Monday. The only two members of the cast that I find the slightest bit interesting are Christine Firkins and Susan Barnes. The plot, well, it's a ship out of control. The main problem with this is, that the director and producer did not take the time to make it believable. There are so many technical errors in this, it's ridiculous. They did not take the time to find out, how a cruise liner works and that way could have eliminated the ways of stopping the ship in a believable fashion. These technical plot holes just go on and on through the entire movie and ends with the biggest blunder ever. If you have any nautical knowledge and knowledge of ships, you'll find yourself covering your eyes due to sheer embarrassment on the behalf of the writer, director and producer. Ship wreck does not even begin to explain what this movie is, a nuclear blast is less of a disaster than this movie is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speed 2: Cruisin' for a Bruisin'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    horacep
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Speed 2 is an action film that kept my interest and wasn't nearly as bad as some reviewers have described. Sandra Bullock stars so that alone lead me to watch this move, and while this clearly isn't her best work she does a good job. I would have liked to have seen a little more humor in her role, although the early scenes with Tim Conway were funny. She and her boyfriend, an LA SWAT team member, are taking a cruise to get away from it all. In this sequel she once again picks a doomed vehicle to travel in. Willem Dafoe is a disgruntled former cruise line employee determined for revenge with his golf clubs and balls hiding bomb materials, something I've not seen before. There is plenty of action and some fine special effects. My wife and I both thought this move was well worth viewing if you like Sandra Bullock and you like action films without all the cursing that seems to come along with the newer films. All in all it is an interesting movie with a spectacular special effects finish. I rate it above average.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheap Thrills.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Willem Dafoe is a computer genius and madman with long greasy locks who takes over a huge cruise ship at sea, causes numerous crises, steals jewels from the ship's vault, and tries to run the ship up on the rocks. This is the kind of movie about a vehicle in jeopardy that, as the discerning viewer already knows, must have a sick child aboard. After the original helpless boy, in "The High and the Mighty," the child must be a girl. Girls are more pitiful. She needs a kidney transplant or the transfusion of some rare blood type to save her life. Obviously there are going to be problems fitting this stereotypical sick child aboard a cruise ship. After all, if you're going to rush your kid someplace, you don't ordinarily put her aboard a cruise ship full of rich drunks, gamblers, and leisurely honeymooners like Sandra Bullock and Jason Patric. So this pretty little girl is made mute, deaf, and speechless, and she's trapped in the elevator on board a ship that appears to be on fire and sinking. That's the best the writers could come up with. I feel like apologizing for them. However, on the plus side, every other single action movie clich&eacute; that you can think of is on reckless display in this piece of dumbed-down and mentally dangerous garbage. Just take the sound track. There is an alarm bell constantly ringing in the background, overwhelming speech, even though everyone is shouting hysterically. (Except the mute little girl, of course, who must use sign language.) The music thumps and stomps most of the screams into oblivion. The camerman wobbles all over the place, probably drunk on excitement. During the first major crisis -- a lifeboat is hung up on the davits -- the editing is so lightning-fast -- a shot of a spinning winch, a terrified face, a cable snapping thread by thread, a body falling into the sea, arms waving, hands grasping for something just out of reach, an explosion of flashing lights, computer screens turning into a fireworks display, the director dashing momentarily in front of the camera and giving the audience the finger -- that you can't follow events. Each shot lasts for one blink of one eye, dashing past like muscae volitantes on speed, until they blend into one another and form a stupefying collage of abandoned movement. I rather liked the original "Speed," which was thoroughly mindless enjoyment. This is bigger, faster, more expensive, stupider. You still want to watch it? Take some Dramamine and a good book along.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Head for the lifeboats, people - this one's going down fast! 42%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As much as I'm a fan of US film critic and all-round nice guy Roger Ebert, there are plenty of times when I disagree with him. I never have and never will call myself a critic - I remain, first and foremost, an audience goer, regardless of whether I'm watching a film at home or at the cinema. Therefore, I regard all films on how entertaining they are rather than the likelihood of winning anything during award season. Despite my resolutely low-brow approach, I do disagree with Ebert on this turgid sequel to one of the best action movies of the Nineties. Ebert's positive praise for this movie was the only good review anywhere to be found of this film and to be frank, I can't really see where he's coming from. Sandra Bullock returns as Annie, the goofy heroine from the first movie who is now seeing fellow LA officer Alex (Jason Patric) - unaware that Alex is just as reckless a daredevil as her ex Jack (Keanu Reeves, who was smarter enough to avoid this). After going away for a romantic cruise in the Caribbean, Annie and Alex find themselves caught up in the explosive schemes of crazed bomber Geiger (Willem Dafoe, in full-on psycho mode). With the ship beyond the control of the crew, Geiger sets a course for collision with an oil tanker - leaving Alex, Annie and a handful of terrified passengers to try and save the ship as well as stop Geiger from making off with loads of diamonds stolen from the ship's vault. What made "Speed" so good was that despite the stupid plot, it remained a genuinely thrilling ride with a suitably OTT villain in the shape of Dennis Hopper, Bullock's flustered performance as the reluctant heroine and the occasionally tongue-in-cheek moment to lighten the mood. So naturally, "Speed 2: Cruise Control" (and can you see what they did there with the title?) offers more of the same except this time, they blew it. Dafoe couldn't be any more insane if he rocked on his knees in the corner of the room reciting nursery rhymes and is actually a pretty weak baddie - at times, I almost felt sorry for him as he appeared to be suffering from some sort of mental illness. Bullock this time is largely relegated to the damsel-in-distress role, leaving Patric to carry the film which, sadly, is beyond him - he is as vacant as an waitress's smile. But the film's attempt at subtle humour badly backfires - take Dante (Royale Watkins), for example, and his insistence on taking photos of everything at any time, even when he's up to his neck in water on a sinking sink. The passengers are mostly anonymous apart from a trapped deaf girl (Christine Ferkins) who provides a side mission and a sweaty fat guy with a moustache (Mike Hagerty) - the rest all seem to be screaming fat women, for some reason. What sort of cruise is this? There are some things to commend, however. The action, when it does arrive, is performed in vast amounts of gushing cold water which can't be pleasant and I must give a nod to Temuera Morrison as the first officer because he is, by far and away, the most convincing actor on screen. He certainly better than the annoying Scot (Brian McCardie) who simply must count down loud the speed of the crashing ship in knots whilst looking like he's being buggered. But "Speed 2: Cruise Control" is that kinda film - even Geiger's Fiber Optic Converter has a big sticky label on it so we can all see what it is! This is an insultingly stupid summer action blockbuster that, in truth, has nothing whatsoever to do with the original and if that's what you want then fine. But for everyone involved, this is am embarrassing outing that sadly ruined the reputation of "Speed" which is unfair because that is a real blast. This is barely a fizzle. Maybe Ebert has a soft spot for Ms Bullock but the question I posed was is this an entertaining film. Only if you get your kicks from exchanges like "It's an earthquake!" "It can't be - we're at sea!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need Sequel Control...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sandra Bullock returns as Annie Porter, who, along with her fianc&eacute;e officer Alex Shaw(Jason Patric) are on a romantic cruise liner which is (of course) hijacked by a deranged computer programmer(Willem Dafoe) out for revenge against his company, and wants to use the SeaBourn Legend as the instrument of revenge. Can Annie and Alex stop him? Unbelievably awful film is one of the most inferior sequels ever made. Idiotic plot, poor editing and direction(Jan De Bont) and a bizarrely different portrayal of Annie that is most unappealing(What went wrong between her and Jack Traven I wonder?) Jason Patric tries, but dreadful film is a sinking ship that he can't save. A total disaster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speed?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This sequel to an overrated original is a voyage to the bottom of the barrel, with Sandra Bullock and bland Jason Patric going for a nice cruise only for computer nut Willem Dafoe and his leeches to hijack the ship. Erk! The witless screenplay consists of characters explaining what's just happened, the title is a misnomer because the pace is so slow and Bullock is bloody annoying, although to be fair she has nothing to do besides whine a lot while looking good. The film's saving graces are Mark Mancina's score (great credits music) and Dafoe, who recognises this for the rubbish it is and hams it up like a right mad bastard.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most redundant sequel ever made?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandcooler
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know sequels are usually a lucrative business, and I know that you can keep pretty much any story going if you push hard enough, but honestly, what the hell can you add to the original "Speed"? "Speed" was about as done as a story can get, it had the most Hollywood ending in the history of Hollywood endings. The delightfully entertaining bad guy gets what was coming to him, a bunch of stuff explodes, the world is safe again and Keanu Reeves kisses a still hot Sandra Bullock, we got on with our lives. Then all of a sudden you get this follow-up, which is not only unnecessary but also seems to have an undying grudge against the original. It just takes everything that was cool about the first one and throws it straight out of the window. Why even call it "Speed" if the entire thing is set on a boat that goes about 5 mph? Exciting times. Why even call it "Speed" if you're just going to replace Keanu Reeves (he hated the script, what a rascal) with some D-lister who looks about as athletic as a bag of sawdust? Does the name "Speed" really sell that many extra tickets? Apparently not. I've got to say though, there's one scene in the movie that's almost good: the part where the out-of-control ship just ploughs straight through a village. But even that's kinda ruined by the obvious scale models, so just forget I said that. Horrid in every single way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked it but Don't get why she disrespected Jack from the last one,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jody mitch
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was awesome! I am not really a movie critic as much as a movie lover, and it takes a really really bad movie to make me complain BUT, i entirely see where everyones disappointment is coming from. It was more of a money-maker than a real movie, it had no real point at all lol, and the coincidences were just beyond unimaginable. What i really didn't get is why she was bashing jack (Keanu Reeves) so much,, in the beginning she explains why she left him explaining that he was too insane and i didn't understand that, they had such a happy ending, should've never done that; was that the directors way of getting back at Reeves for not accepting the cast? Lol.. Anyways yeaz unless you like everything you watch, don't watch this!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crap Alarm! (Spoiler Alert)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soerheim91
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well i did like this movie as a child, but today i just wanted to cry! I work on a large ship so i did find so much of the stuff in the movie to be the biggest crap ever! 1. Why do the ship get flooded when they open the ballast tanks? To enter a ballast tank off a ship you have to enter a man-hole that is sealed with a hatch and many bolts... It's not open like a big door... Btw, you can't just sink a ship with filling the ballast tanks. 2. I have never seen a wheel on the thruster that you can turn and make the propeller turn. Most thrusters are electric so i find this hard to believe... correct me if i am wrong. 3. At the end of the movie when they are hitting other vessels they slow down by 1knot every time while the main engine is still running at full. Even if the engine was off the ship would not have lost that much speed of a small impact like that. The ship weight is 9,961 GT so it would take much more to slow a ship like that. 4. Yes you can lower the lifeboats when the ship is moving. All in all it's just to stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flashes of potential, but too many flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw SPEED 2: CRUISE CONTROL at the cinema. I was at the tender age of 16, and I thought it was great: action-packed, with great effects and a fun, DIE HARD-style storyline. Well, it still has all those things, but time has not been kind to SPEED 2, and watching as an adult I can see just how poor it is. The problem with the film is the infantile nature of the script, which sounds as if it's been deliberately written for children. Jason Patric's clunky leading man I can forgive, but the supporting characters and their lame comedy are excruciating. The porter and the Scottish guy are bad enough, but Sandra Bullock takes the biscuit with her repetitive attempts at light humour. If ever a film made you despise someone, it's Bullock in this. Otherwise, the story suffers from a little bloating and an ending that goes on way too long, but it does have some stuff to recommend it. The low rent action-man hijinks are a hoot, and Willem Dafoe is fantastic as the over-the-top villain, all teeth and hair and as crazy as he was in WILD AT HEART. The effects hold up pretty well, too. A shame, then, about the child-friendly nature of the production; had this been a proper, adult-focused outing along the lines of UNDER SIEGE it could have been a damn sight better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's out of control and as bad as it gets.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Olsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thing is beyond lame. The entire cast is about as unlikable and impersonal as can be, and the plot is as thin as the news on CNN. It's a huge problem for any movie, if the characters become annoying from the outset of the movie. This is partly due to bad acting and bad casting. The male lead (Jason Patric) is as believable as an action cop, as it would be to watch a 2 year old fly the Concorde. Sandra Bulldog is annoying beyond hope, due to the characters exaggerated amount of stupidity. The rest of the cast, is just bland and as memorable as a rainy Monday. The only two members of the cast that I find the slightest bit interesting are Christine Firkins and Susan Barnes. The plot, well, it's a ship out of control. The main problem with this is, that the director and producer did not take the time to make it believable. There are so many technical errors in this, it's ridiculous. They did not take the time to find out, how a cruise liner works and that way could have eliminated the ways of stopping the ship in a believable fashion. These technical plot holes just go on and on through the entire movie and ends with the biggest blunder ever. If you have any nautical knowledge and knowledge of ships, you'll find yourself covering your eyes due to sheer embarrassment on the behalf of the writer, director and producer. Ship wreck does not even begin to explain what this movie is, a nuclear blast is less of a disaster than this movie is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speed 2: Cruisin' for a Bruisin'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    horacep
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Speed 2 is an action film that kept my interest and wasn't nearly as bad as some reviewers have described. Sandra Bullock stars so that alone lead me to watch this move, and while this clearly isn't her best work she does a good job. I would have liked to have seen a little more humor in her role, although the early scenes with Tim Conway were funny. She and her boyfriend, an LA SWAT team member, are taking a cruise to get away from it all. In this sequel she once again picks a doomed vehicle to travel in. Willem Dafoe is a disgruntled former cruise line employee determined for revenge with his golf clubs and balls hiding bomb materials, something I've not seen before. There is plenty of action and some fine special effects. My wife and I both thought this move was well worth viewing if you like Sandra Bullock and you like action films without all the cursing that seems to come along with the newer films. All in all it is an interesting movie with a spectacular special effects finish. I rate it above average.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheap Thrills.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Willem Dafoe is a computer genius and madman with long greasy locks who takes over a huge cruise ship at sea, causes numerous crises, steals jewels from the ship's vault, and tries to run the ship up on the rocks. This is the kind of movie about a vehicle in jeopardy that, as the discerning viewer already knows, must have a sick child aboard. After the original helpless boy, in "The High and the Mighty," the child must be a girl. Girls are more pitiful. She needs a kidney transplant or the transfusion of some rare blood type to save her life. Obviously there are going to be problems fitting this stereotypical sick child aboard a cruise ship. After all, if you're going to rush your kid someplace, you don't ordinarily put her aboard a cruise ship full of rich drunks, gamblers, and leisurely honeymooners like Sandra Bullock and Jason Patric. So this pretty little girl is made mute, deaf, and speechless, and she's trapped in the elevator on board a ship that appears to be on fire and sinking. That's the best the writers could come up with. I feel like apologizing for them. However, on the plus side, every other single action movie clich&eacute; that you can think of is on reckless display in this piece of dumbed-down and mentally dangerous garbage. Just take the sound track. There is an alarm bell constantly ringing in the background, overwhelming speech, even though everyone is shouting hysterically. (Except the mute little girl, of course, who must use sign language.) The music thumps and stomps most of the screams into oblivion. The camerman wobbles all over the place, probably drunk on excitement. During the first major crisis -- a lifeboat is hung up on the davits -- the editing is so lightning-fast -- a shot of a spinning winch, a terrified face, a cable snapping thread by thread, a body falling into the sea, arms waving, hands grasping for something just out of reach, an explosion of flashing lights, computer screens turning into a fireworks display, the director dashing momentarily in front of the camera and giving the audience the finger -- that you can't follow events. Each shot lasts for one blink of one eye, dashing past like muscae volitantes on speed, until they blend into one another and form a stupefying collage of abandoned movement. I rather liked the original "Speed," which was thoroughly mindless enjoyment. This is bigger, faster, more expensive, stupider. You still want to watch it? Take some Dramamine and a good book along.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Head for the lifeboats, people - this one's going down fast! 42%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As much as I'm a fan of US film critic and all-round nice guy Roger Ebert, there are plenty of times when I disagree with him. I never have and never will call myself a critic - I remain, first and foremost, an audience goer, regardless of whether I'm watching a film at home or at the cinema. Therefore, I regard all films on how entertaining they are rather than the likelihood of winning anything during award season. Despite my resolutely low-brow approach, I do disagree with Ebert on this turgid sequel to one of the best action movies of the Nineties. Ebert's positive praise for this movie was the only good review anywhere to be found of this film and to be frank, I can't really see where he's coming from. Sandra Bullock returns as Annie, the goofy heroine from the first movie who is now seeing fellow LA officer Alex (Jason Patric) - unaware that Alex is just as reckless a daredevil as her ex Jack (Keanu Reeves, who was smarter enough to avoid this). After going away for a romantic cruise in the Caribbean, Annie and Alex find themselves caught up in the explosive schemes of crazed bomber Geiger (Willem Dafoe, in full-on psycho mode). With the ship beyond the control of the crew, Geiger sets a course for collision with an oil tanker - leaving Alex, Annie and a handful of terrified passengers to try and save the ship as well as stop Geiger from making off with loads of diamonds stolen from the ship's vault. What made "Speed" so good was that despite the stupid plot, it remained a genuinely thrilling ride with a suitably OTT villain in the shape of Dennis Hopper, Bullock's flustered performance as the reluctant heroine and the occasionally tongue-in-cheek moment to lighten the mood. So naturally, "Speed 2: Cruise Control" (and can you see what they did there with the title?) offers more of the same except this time, they blew it. Dafoe couldn't be any more insane if he rocked on his knees in the corner of the room reciting nursery rhymes and is actually a pretty weak baddie - at times, I almost felt sorry for him as he appeared to be suffering from some sort of mental illness. Bullock this time is largely relegated to the damsel-in-distress role, leaving Patric to carry the film which, sadly, is beyond him - he is as vacant as an waitress's smile. But the film's attempt at subtle humour badly backfires - take Dante (Royale Watkins), for example, and his insistence on taking photos of everything at any time, even when he's up to his neck in water on a sinking sink. The passengers are mostly anonymous apart from a trapped deaf girl (Christine Ferkins) who provides a side mission and a sweaty fat guy with a moustache (Mike Hagerty) - the rest all seem to be screaming fat women, for some reason. What sort of cruise is this? There are some things to commend, however. The action, when it does arrive, is performed in vast amounts of gushing cold water which can't be pleasant and I must give a nod to Temuera Morrison as the first officer because he is, by far and away, the most convincing actor on screen. He certainly better than the annoying Scot (Brian McCardie) who simply must count down loud the speed of the crashing ship in knots whilst looking like he's being buggered. But "Speed 2: Cruise Control" is that kinda film - even Geiger's Fiber Optic Converter has a big sticky label on it so we can all see what it is! This is an insultingly stupid summer action blockbuster that, in truth, has nothing whatsoever to do with the original and if that's what you want then fine. But for everyone involved, this is am embarrassing outing that sadly ruined the reputation of "Speed" which is unfair because that is a real blast. This is barely a fizzle. Maybe Ebert has a soft spot for Ms Bullock but the question I posed was is this an entertaining film. Only if you get your kicks from exchanges like "It's an earthquake!" "It can't be - we're at sea!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need Sequel Control...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sandra Bullock returns as Annie Porter, who, along with her fianc&eacute;e officer Alex Shaw(Jason Patric) are on a romantic cruise liner which is (of course) hijacked by a deranged computer programmer(Willem Dafoe) out for revenge against his company, and wants to use the SeaBourn Legend as the instrument of revenge. Can Annie and Alex stop him? Unbelievably awful film is one of the most inferior sequels ever made. Idiotic plot, poor editing and direction(Jan De Bont) and a bizarrely different portrayal of Annie that is most unappealing(What went wrong between her and Jack Traven I wonder?) Jason Patric tries, but dreadful film is a sinking ship that he can't save. A total disaster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speed?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This sequel to an overrated original is a voyage to the bottom of the barrel, with Sandra Bullock and bland Jason Patric going for a nice cruise only for computer nut Willem Dafoe and his leeches to hijack the ship. Erk! The witless screenplay consists of characters explaining what's just happened, the title is a misnomer because the pace is so slow and Bullock is bloody annoying, although to be fair she has nothing to do besides whine a lot while looking good. The film's saving graces are Mark Mancina's score (great credits music) and Dafoe, who recognises this for the rubbish it is and hams it up like a right mad bastard.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most redundant sequel ever made?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandcooler
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know sequels are usually a lucrative business, and I know that you can keep pretty much any story going if you push hard enough, but honestly, what the hell can you add to the original "Speed"? "Speed" was about as done as a story can get, it had the most Hollywood ending in the history of Hollywood endings. The delightfully entertaining bad guy gets what was coming to him, a bunch of stuff explodes, the world is safe again and Keanu Reeves kisses a still hot Sandra Bullock, we got on with our lives. Then all of a sudden you get this follow-up, which is not only unnecessary but also seems to have an undying grudge against the original. It just takes everything that was cool about the first one and throws it straight out of the window. Why even call it "Speed" if the entire thing is set on a boat that goes about 5 mph? Exciting times. Why even call it "Speed" if you're just going to replace Keanu Reeves (he hated the script, what a rascal) with some D-lister who looks about as athletic as a bag of sawdust? Does the name "Speed" really sell that many extra tickets? Apparently not. I've got to say though, there's one scene in the movie that's almost good: the part where the out-of-control ship just ploughs straight through a village. But even that's kinda ruined by the obvious scale models, so just forget I said that. Horrid in every single way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked it but Don't get why she disrespected Jack from the last one,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jody mitch
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was awesome! I am not really a movie critic as much as a movie lover, and it takes a really really bad movie to make me complain BUT, i entirely see where everyones disappointment is coming from. It was more of a money-maker than a real movie, it had no real point at all lol, and the coincidences were just beyond unimaginable. What i really didn't get is why she was bashing jack (Keanu Reeves) so much,, in the beginning she explains why she left him explaining that he was too insane and i didn't understand that, they had such a happy ending, should've never done that; was that the directors way of getting back at Reeves for not accepting the cast? Lol.. Anyways yeaz unless you like everything you watch, don't watch this!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crap Alarm! (Spoiler Alert)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soerheim91
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well i did like this movie as a child, but today i just wanted to cry! I work on a large ship so i did find so much of the stuff in the movie to be the biggest crap ever! 1. Why do the ship get flooded when they open the ballast tanks? To enter a ballast tank off a ship you have to enter a man-hole that is sealed with a hatch and many bolts... It's not open like a big door... Btw, you can't just sink a ship with filling the ballast tanks. 2. I have never seen a wheel on the thruster that you can turn and make the propeller turn. Most thrusters are electric so i find this hard to believe... correct me if i am wrong. 3. At the end of the movie when they are hitting other vessels they slow down by 1knot every time while the main engine is still running at full. Even if the engine was off the ship would not have lost that much speed of a small impact like that. The ship weight is 9,961 GT so it would take much more to slow a ship like that. 4. Yes you can lower the lifeboats when the ship is moving. All in all it's just to stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flashes of potential, but too many flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw SPEED 2: CRUISE CONTROL at the cinema. I was at the tender age of 16, and I thought it was great: action-packed, with great effects and a fun, DIE HARD-style storyline. Well, it still has all those things, but time has not been kind to SPEED 2, and watching as an adult I can see just how poor it is. The problem with the film is the infantile nature of the script, which sounds as if it's been deliberately written for children. Jason Patric's clunky leading man I can forgive, but the supporting characters and their lame comedy are excruciating. The porter and the Scottish guy are bad enough, but Sandra Bullock takes the biscuit with her repetitive attempts at light humour. If ever a film made you despise someone, it's Bullock in this. Otherwise, the story suffers from a little bloating and an ending that goes on way too long, but it does have some stuff to recommend it. The low rent action-man hijinks are a hoot, and Willem Dafoe is fantastic as the over-the-top villain, all teeth and hair and as crazy as he was in WILD AT HEART. The effects hold up pretty well, too. A shame, then, about the child-friendly nature of the production; had this been a proper, adult-focused outing along the lines of UNDER SIEGE it could have been a damn sight better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's out of control and as bad as it gets.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Olsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thing is beyond lame. The entire cast is about as unlikable and impersonal as can be, and the plot is as thin as the news on CNN. It's a huge problem for any movie, if the characters become annoying from the outset of the movie. This is partly due to bad acting and bad casting. The male lead (Jason Patric) is as believable as an action cop, as it would be to watch a 2 year old fly the Concorde. Sandra Bulldog is annoying beyond hope, due to the characters exaggerated amount of stupidity. The rest of the cast, is just bland and as memorable as a rainy Monday. The only two members of the cast that I find the slightest bit interesting are Christine Firkins and Susan Barnes. The plot, well, it's a ship out of control. The main problem with this is, that the director and producer did not take the time to make it believable. There are so many technical errors in this, it's ridiculous. They did not take the time to find out, how a cruise liner works and that way could have eliminated the ways of stopping the ship in a believable fashion. These technical plot holes just go on and on through the entire movie and ends with the biggest blunder ever. If you have any nautical knowledge and knowledge of ships, you'll find yourself covering your eyes due to sheer embarrassment on the behalf of the writer, director and producer. Ship wreck does not even begin to explain what this movie is, a nuclear blast is less of a disaster than this movie is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speed 2: Cruisin' for a Bruisin'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    horacep
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Speed 2 is an action film that kept my interest and wasn't nearly as bad as some reviewers have described. Sandra Bullock stars so that alone lead me to watch this move, and while this clearly isn't her best work she does a good job. I would have liked to have seen a little more humor in her role, although the early scenes with Tim Conway were funny. She and her boyfriend, an LA SWAT team member, are taking a cruise to get away from it all. In this sequel she once again picks a doomed vehicle to travel in. Willem Dafoe is a disgruntled former cruise line employee determined for revenge with his golf clubs and balls hiding bomb materials, something I've not seen before. There is plenty of action and some fine special effects. My wife and I both thought this move was well worth viewing if you like Sandra Bullock and you like action films without all the cursing that seems to come along with the newer films. All in all it is an interesting movie with a spectacular special effects finish. I rate it above average.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheap Thrills.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Willem Dafoe is a computer genius and madman with long greasy locks who takes over a huge cruise ship at sea, causes numerous crises, steals jewels from the ship's vault, and tries to run the ship up on the rocks. This is the kind of movie about a vehicle in jeopardy that, as the discerning viewer already knows, must have a sick child aboard. After the original helpless boy, in "The High and the Mighty," the child must be a girl. Girls are more pitiful. She needs a kidney transplant or the transfusion of some rare blood type to save her life. Obviously there are going to be problems fitting this stereotypical sick child aboard a cruise ship. After all, if you're going to rush your kid someplace, you don't ordinarily put her aboard a cruise ship full of rich drunks, gamblers, and leisurely honeymooners like Sandra Bullock and Jason Patric. So this pretty little girl is made mute, deaf, and speechless, and she's trapped in the elevator on board a ship that appears to be on fire and sinking. That's the best the writers could come up with. I feel like apologizing for them. However, on the plus side, every other single action movie clich&eacute; that you can think of is on reckless display in this piece of dumbed-down and mentally dangerous garbage. Just take the sound track. There is an alarm bell constantly ringing in the background, overwhelming speech, even though everyone is shouting hysterically. (Except the mute little girl, of course, who must use sign language.) The music thumps and stomps most of the screams into oblivion. The camerman wobbles all over the place, probably drunk on excitement. During the first major crisis -- a lifeboat is hung up on the davits -- the editing is so lightning-fast -- a shot of a spinning winch, a terrified face, a cable snapping thread by thread, a body falling into the sea, arms waving, hands grasping for something just out of reach, an explosion of flashing lights, computer screens turning into a fireworks display, the director dashing momentarily in front of the camera and giving the audience the finger -- that you can't follow events. Each shot lasts for one blink of one eye, dashing past like muscae volitantes on speed, until they blend into one another and form a stupefying collage of abandoned movement. I rather liked the original "Speed," which was thoroughly mindless enjoyment. This is bigger, faster, more expensive, stupider. You still want to watch it? Take some Dramamine and a good book along.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Head for the lifeboats, people - this one's going down fast! 42%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As much as I'm a fan of US film critic and all-round nice guy Roger Ebert, there are plenty of times when I disagree with him. I never have and never will call myself a critic - I remain, first and foremost, an audience goer, regardless of whether I'm watching a film at home or at the cinema. Therefore, I regard all films on how entertaining they are rather than the likelihood of winning anything during award season. Despite my resolutely low-brow approach, I do disagree with Ebert on this turgid sequel to one of the best action movies of the Nineties. Ebert's positive praise for this movie was the only good review anywhere to be found of this film and to be frank, I can't really see where he's coming from. Sandra Bullock returns as Annie, the goofy heroine from the first movie who is now seeing fellow LA officer Alex (Jason Patric) - unaware that Alex is just as reckless a daredevil as her ex Jack (Keanu Reeves, who was smarter enough to avoid this). After going away for a romantic cruise in the Caribbean, Annie and Alex find themselves caught up in the explosive schemes of crazed bomber Geiger (Willem Dafoe, in full-on psycho mode). With the ship beyond the control of the crew, Geiger sets a course for collision with an oil tanker - leaving Alex, Annie and a handful of terrified passengers to try and save the ship as well as stop Geiger from making off with loads of diamonds stolen from the ship's vault. What made "Speed" so good was that despite the stupid plot, it remained a genuinely thrilling ride with a suitably OTT villain in the shape of Dennis Hopper, Bullock's flustered performance as the reluctant heroine and the occasionally tongue-in-cheek moment to lighten the mood. So naturally, "Speed 2: Cruise Control" (and can you see what they did there with the title?) offers more of the same except this time, they blew it. Dafoe couldn't be any more insane if he rocked on his knees in the corner of the room reciting nursery rhymes and is actually a pretty weak baddie - at times, I almost felt sorry for him as he appeared to be suffering from some sort of mental illness. Bullock this time is largely relegated to the damsel-in-distress role, leaving Patric to carry the film which, sadly, is beyond him - he is as vacant as an waitress's smile. But the film's attempt at subtle humour badly backfires - take Dante (Royale Watkins), for example, and his insistence on taking photos of everything at any time, even when he's up to his neck in water on a sinking sink. The passengers are mostly anonymous apart from a trapped deaf girl (Christine Ferkins) who provides a side mission and a sweaty fat guy with a moustache (Mike Hagerty) - the rest all seem to be screaming fat women, for some reason. What sort of cruise is this? There are some things to commend, however. The action, when it does arrive, is performed in vast amounts of gushing cold water which can't be pleasant and I must give a nod to Temuera Morrison as the first officer because he is, by far and away, the most convincing actor on screen. He certainly better than the annoying Scot (Brian McCardie) who simply must count down loud the speed of the crashing ship in knots whilst looking like he's being buggered. But "Speed 2: Cruise Control" is that kinda film - even Geiger's Fiber Optic Converter has a big sticky label on it so we can all see what it is! This is an insultingly stupid summer action blockbuster that, in truth, has nothing whatsoever to do with the original and if that's what you want then fine. But for everyone involved, this is am embarrassing outing that sadly ruined the reputation of "Speed" which is unfair because that is a real blast. This is barely a fizzle. Maybe Ebert has a soft spot for Ms Bullock but the question I posed was is this an entertaining film. Only if you get your kicks from exchanges like "It's an earthquake!" "It can't be - we're at sea!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need Sequel Control...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sandra Bullock returns as Annie Porter, who, along with her fianc&eacute;e officer Alex Shaw(Jason Patric) are on a romantic cruise liner which is (of course) hijacked by a deranged computer programmer(Willem Dafoe) out for revenge against his company, and wants to use the SeaBourn Legend as the instrument of revenge. Can Annie and Alex stop him? Unbelievably awful film is one of the most inferior sequels ever made. Idiotic plot, poor editing and direction(Jan De Bont) and a bizarrely different portrayal of Annie that is most unappealing(What went wrong between her and Jack Traven I wonder?) Jason Patric tries, but dreadful film is a sinking ship that he can't save. A total disaster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speed?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This sequel to an overrated original is a voyage to the bottom of the barrel, with Sandra Bullock and bland Jason Patric going for a nice cruise only for computer nut Willem Dafoe and his leeches to hijack the ship. Erk! The witless screenplay consists of characters explaining what's just happened, the title is a misnomer because the pace is so slow and Bullock is bloody annoying, although to be fair she has nothing to do besides whine a lot while looking good. The film's saving graces are Mark Mancina's score (great credits music) and Dafoe, who recognises this for the rubbish it is and hams it up like a right mad bastard.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most redundant sequel ever made?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandcooler
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know sequels are usually a lucrative business, and I know that you can keep pretty much any story going if you push hard enough, but honestly, what the hell can you add to the original "Speed"? "Speed" was about as done as a story can get, it had the most Hollywood ending in the history of Hollywood endings. The delightfully entertaining bad guy gets what was coming to him, a bunch of stuff explodes, the world is safe again and Keanu Reeves kisses a still hot Sandra Bullock, we got on with our lives. Then all of a sudden you get this follow-up, which is not only unnecessary but also seems to have an undying grudge against the original. It just takes everything that was cool about the first one and throws it straight out of the window. Why even call it "Speed" if the entire thing is set on a boat that goes about 5 mph? Exciting times. Why even call it "Speed" if you're just going to replace Keanu Reeves (he hated the script, what a rascal) with some D-lister who looks about as athletic as a bag of sawdust? Does the name "Speed" really sell that many extra tickets? Apparently not. I've got to say though, there's one scene in the movie that's almost good: the part where the out-of-control ship just ploughs straight through a village. But even that's kinda ruined by the obvious scale models, so just forget I said that. Horrid in every single way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked it but Don't get why she disrespected Jack from the last one,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jody mitch
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was awesome! I am not really a movie critic as much as a movie lover, and it takes a really really bad movie to make me complain BUT, i entirely see where everyones disappointment is coming from. It was more of a money-maker than a real movie, it had no real point at all lol, and the coincidences were just beyond unimaginable. What i really didn't get is why she was bashing jack (Keanu Reeves) so much,, in the beginning she explains why she left him explaining that he was too insane and i didn't understand that, they had such a happy ending, should've never done that; was that the directors way of getting back at Reeves for not accepting the cast? Lol.. Anyways yeaz unless you like everything you watch, don't watch this!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crap Alarm! (Spoiler Alert)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soerheim91
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well i did like this movie as a child, but today i just wanted to cry! I work on a large ship so i did find so much of the stuff in the movie to be the biggest crap ever! 1. Why do the ship get flooded when they open the ballast tanks? To enter a ballast tank off a ship you have to enter a man-hole that is sealed with a hatch and many bolts... It's not open like a big door... Btw, you can't just sink a ship with filling the ballast tanks. 2. I have never seen a wheel on the thruster that you can turn and make the propeller turn. Most thrusters are electric so i find this hard to believe... correct me if i am wrong. 3. At the end of the movie when they are hitting other vessels they slow down by 1knot every time while the main engine is still running at full. Even if the engine was off the ship would not have lost that much speed of a small impact like that. The ship weight is 9,961 GT so it would take much more to slow a ship like that. 4. Yes you can lower the lifeboats when the ship is moving. All in all it's just to stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flashes of potential, but too many flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw SPEED 2: CRUISE CONTROL at the cinema. I was at the tender age of 16, and I thought it was great: action-packed, with great effects and a fun, DIE HARD-style storyline. Well, it still has all those things, but time has not been kind to SPEED 2, and watching as an adult I can see just how poor it is. The problem with the film is the infantile nature of the script, which sounds as if it's been deliberately written for children. Jason Patric's clunky leading man I can forgive, but the supporting characters and their lame comedy are excruciating. The porter and the Scottish guy are bad enough, but Sandra Bullock takes the biscuit with her repetitive attempts at light humour. If ever a film made you despise someone, it's Bullock in this. Otherwise, the story suffers from a little bloating and an ending that goes on way too long, but it does have some stuff to recommend it. The low rent action-man hijinks are a hoot, and Willem Dafoe is fantastic as the over-the-top villain, all teeth and hair and as crazy as he was in WILD AT HEART. The effects hold up pretty well, too. A shame, then, about the child-friendly nature of the production; had this been a proper, adult-focused outing along the lines of UNDER SIEGE it could have been a damn sight better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's out of control and as bad as it gets.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Olsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thing is beyond lame. The entire cast is about as unlikable and impersonal as can be, and the plot is as thin as the news on CNN. It's a huge problem for any movie, if the characters become annoying from the outset of the movie. This is partly due to bad acting and bad casting. The male lead (Jason Patric) is as believable as an action cop, as it would be to watch a 2 year old fly the Concorde. Sandra Bulldog is annoying beyond hope, due to the characters exaggerated amount of stupidity. The rest of the cast, is just bland and as memorable as a rainy Monday. The only two members of the cast that I find the slightest bit interesting are Christine Firkins and Susan Barnes. The plot, well, it's a ship out of control. The main problem with this is, that the director and producer did not take the time to make it believable. There are so many technical errors in this, it's ridiculous. They did not take the time to find out, how a cruise liner works and that way could have eliminated the ways of stopping the ship in a believable fashion. These technical plot holes just go on and on through the entire movie and ends with the biggest blunder ever. If you have any nautical knowledge and knowledge of ships, you'll find yourself covering your eyes due to sheer embarrassment on the behalf of the writer, director and producer. Ship wreck does not even begin to explain what this movie is, a nuclear blast is less of a disaster than this movie is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speed 2: Cruisin' for a Bruisin'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    horacep
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Speed 2 is an action film that kept my interest and wasn't nearly as bad as some reviewers have described. Sandra Bullock stars so that alone lead me to watch this move, and while this clearly isn't her best work she does a good job. I would have liked to have seen a little more humor in her role, although the early scenes with Tim Conway were funny. She and her boyfriend, an LA SWAT team member, are taking a cruise to get away from it all. In this sequel she once again picks a doomed vehicle to travel in. Willem Dafoe is a disgruntled former cruise line employee determined for revenge with his golf clubs and balls hiding bomb materials, something I've not seen before. There is plenty of action and some fine special effects. My wife and I both thought this move was well worth viewing if you like Sandra Bullock and you like action films without all the cursing that seems to come along with the newer films. All in all it is an interesting movie with a spectacular special effects finish. I rate it above average.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheap Thrills.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Willem Dafoe is a computer genius and madman with long greasy locks who takes over a huge cruise ship at sea, causes numerous crises, steals jewels from the ship's vault, and tries to run the ship up on the rocks. This is the kind of movie about a vehicle in jeopardy that, as the discerning viewer already knows, must have a sick child aboard. After the original helpless boy, in "The High and the Mighty," the child must be a girl. Girls are more pitiful. She needs a kidney transplant or the transfusion of some rare blood type to save her life. Obviously there are going to be problems fitting this stereotypical sick child aboard a cruise ship. After all, if you're going to rush your kid someplace, you don't ordinarily put her aboard a cruise ship full of rich drunks, gamblers, and leisurely honeymooners like Sandra Bullock and Jason Patric. So this pretty little girl is made mute, deaf, and speechless, and she's trapped in the elevator on board a ship that appears to be on fire and sinking. That's the best the writers could come up with. I feel like apologizing for them. However, on the plus side, every other single action movie clich&eacute; that you can think of is on reckless display in this piece of dumbed-down and mentally dangerous garbage. Just take the sound track. There is an alarm bell constantly ringing in the background, overwhelming speech, even though everyone is shouting hysterically. (Except the mute little girl, of course, who must use sign language.) The music thumps and stomps most of the screams into oblivion. The camerman wobbles all over the place, probably drunk on excitement. During the first major crisis -- a lifeboat is hung up on the davits -- the editing is so lightning-fast -- a shot of a spinning winch, a terrified face, a cable snapping thread by thread, a body falling into the sea, arms waving, hands grasping for something just out of reach, an explosion of flashing lights, computer screens turning into a fireworks display, the director dashing momentarily in front of the camera and giving the audience the finger -- that you can't follow events. Each shot lasts for one blink of one eye, dashing past like muscae volitantes on speed, until they blend into one another and form a stupefying collage of abandoned movement. I rather liked the original "Speed," which was thoroughly mindless enjoyment. This is bigger, faster, more expensive, stupider. You still want to watch it? Take some Dramamine and a good book along.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Head for the lifeboats, people - this one's going down fast! 42%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As much as I'm a fan of US film critic and all-round nice guy Roger Ebert, there are plenty of times when I disagree with him. I never have and never will call myself a critic - I remain, first and foremost, an audience goer, regardless of whether I'm watching a film at home or at the cinema. Therefore, I regard all films on how entertaining they are rather than the likelihood of winning anything during award season. Despite my resolutely low-brow approach, I do disagree with Ebert on this turgid sequel to one of the best action movies of the Nineties. Ebert's positive praise for this movie was the only good review anywhere to be found of this film and to be frank, I can't really see where he's coming from. Sandra Bullock returns as Annie, the goofy heroine from the first movie who is now seeing fellow LA officer Alex (Jason Patric) - unaware that Alex is just as reckless a daredevil as her ex Jack (Keanu Reeves, who was smarter enough to avoid this). After going away for a romantic cruise in the Caribbean, Annie and Alex find themselves caught up in the explosive schemes of crazed bomber Geiger (Willem Dafoe, in full-on psycho mode). With the ship beyond the control of the crew, Geiger sets a course for collision with an oil tanker - leaving Alex, Annie and a handful of terrified passengers to try and save the ship as well as stop Geiger from making off with loads of diamonds stolen from the ship's vault. What made "Speed" so good was that despite the stupid plot, it remained a genuinely thrilling ride with a suitably OTT villain in the shape of Dennis Hopper, Bullock's flustered performance as the reluctant heroine and the occasionally tongue-in-cheek moment to lighten the mood. So naturally, "Speed 2: Cruise Control" (and can you see what they did there with the title?) offers more of the same except this time, they blew it. Dafoe couldn't be any more insane if he rocked on his knees in the corner of the room reciting nursery rhymes and is actually a pretty weak baddie - at times, I almost felt sorry for him as he appeared to be suffering from some sort of mental illness. Bullock this time is largely relegated to the damsel-in-distress role, leaving Patric to carry the film which, sadly, is beyond him - he is as vacant as an waitress's smile. But the film's attempt at subtle humour badly backfires - take Dante (Royale Watkins), for example, and his insistence on taking photos of everything at any time, even when he's up to his neck in water on a sinking sink. The passengers are mostly anonymous apart from a trapped deaf girl (Christine Ferkins) who provides a side mission and a sweaty fat guy with a moustache (Mike Hagerty) - the rest all seem to be screaming fat women, for some reason. What sort of cruise is this? There are some things to commend, however. The action, when it does arrive, is performed in vast amounts of gushing cold water which can't be pleasant and I must give a nod to Temuera Morrison as the first officer because he is, by far and away, the most convincing actor on screen. He certainly better than the annoying Scot (Brian McCardie) who simply must count down loud the speed of the crashing ship in knots whilst looking like he's being buggered. But "Speed 2: Cruise Control" is that kinda film - even Geiger's Fiber Optic Converter has a big sticky label on it so we can all see what it is! This is an insultingly stupid summer action blockbuster that, in truth, has nothing whatsoever to do with the original and if that's what you want then fine. But for everyone involved, this is am embarrassing outing that sadly ruined the reputation of "Speed" which is unfair because that is a real blast. This is barely a fizzle. Maybe Ebert has a soft spot for Ms Bullock but the question I posed was is this an entertaining film. Only if you get your kicks from exchanges like "It's an earthquake!" "It can't be - we're at sea!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need Sequel Control...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sandra Bullock returns as Annie Porter, who, along with her fianc&eacute;e officer Alex Shaw(Jason Patric) are on a romantic cruise liner which is (of course) hijacked by a deranged computer programmer(Willem Dafoe) out for revenge against his company, and wants to use the SeaBourn Legend as the instrument of revenge. Can Annie and Alex stop him? Unbelievably awful film is one of the most inferior sequels ever made. Idiotic plot, poor editing and direction(Jan De Bont) and a bizarrely different portrayal of Annie that is most unappealing(What went wrong between her and Jack Traven I wonder?) Jason Patric tries, but dreadful film is a sinking ship that he can't save. A total disaster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speed?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This sequel to an overrated original is a voyage to the bottom of the barrel, with Sandra Bullock and bland Jason Patric going for a nice cruise only for computer nut Willem Dafoe and his leeches to hijack the ship. Erk! The witless screenplay consists of characters explaining what's just happened, the title is a misnomer because the pace is so slow and Bullock is bloody annoying, although to be fair she has nothing to do besides whine a lot while looking good. The film's saving graces are Mark Mancina's score (great credits music) and Dafoe, who recognises this for the rubbish it is and hams it up like a right mad bastard.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most redundant sequel ever made?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandcooler
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know sequels are usually a lucrative business, and I know that you can keep pretty much any story going if you push hard enough, but honestly, what the hell can you add to the original "Speed"? "Speed" was about as done as a story can get, it had the most Hollywood ending in the history of Hollywood endings. The delightfully entertaining bad guy gets what was coming to him, a bunch of stuff explodes, the world is safe again and Keanu Reeves kisses a still hot Sandra Bullock, we got on with our lives. Then all of a sudden you get this follow-up, which is not only unnecessary but also seems to have an undying grudge against the original. It just takes everything that was cool about the first one and throws it straight out of the window. Why even call it "Speed" if the entire thing is set on a boat that goes about 5 mph? Exciting times. Why even call it "Speed" if you're just going to replace Keanu Reeves (he hated the script, what a rascal) with some D-lister who looks about as athletic as a bag of sawdust? Does the name "Speed" really sell that many extra tickets? Apparently not. I've got to say though, there's one scene in the movie that's almost good: the part where the out-of-control ship just ploughs straight through a village. But even that's kinda ruined by the obvious scale models, so just forget I said that. Horrid in every single way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked it but Don't get why she disrespected Jack from the last one,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jody mitch
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was awesome! I am not really a movie critic as much as a movie lover, and it takes a really really bad movie to make me complain BUT, i entirely see where everyones disappointment is coming from. It was more of a money-maker than a real movie, it had no real point at all lol, and the coincidences were just beyond unimaginable. What i really didn't get is why she was bashing jack (Keanu Reeves) so much,, in the beginning she explains why she left him explaining that he was too insane and i didn't understand that, they had such a happy ending, should've never done that; was that the directors way of getting back at Reeves for not accepting the cast? Lol.. Anyways yeaz unless you like everything you watch, don't watch this!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crap Alarm! (Spoiler Alert)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soerheim91
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well i did like this movie as a child, but today i just wanted to cry! I work on a large ship so i did find so much of the stuff in the movie to be the biggest crap ever! 1. Why do the ship get flooded when they open the ballast tanks? To enter a ballast tank off a ship you have to enter a man-hole that is sealed with a hatch and many bolts... It's not open like a big door... Btw, you can't just sink a ship with filling the ballast tanks. 2. I have never seen a wheel on the thruster that you can turn and make the propeller turn. Most thrusters are electric so i find this hard to believe... correct me if i am wrong. 3. At the end of the movie when they are hitting other vessels they slow down by 1knot every time while the main engine is still running at full. Even if the engine was off the ship would not have lost that much speed of a small impact like that. The ship weight is 9,961 GT so it would take much more to slow a ship like that. 4. Yes you can lower the lifeboats when the ship is moving. All in all it's just to stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flashes of potential, but too many flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw SPEED 2: CRUISE CONTROL at the cinema. I was at the tender age of 16, and I thought it was great: action-packed, with great effects and a fun, DIE HARD-style storyline. Well, it still has all those things, but time has not been kind to SPEED 2, and watching as an adult I can see just how poor it is. The problem with the film is the infantile nature of the script, which sounds as if it's been deliberately written for children. Jason Patric's clunky leading man I can forgive, but the supporting characters and their lame comedy are excruciating. The porter and the Scottish guy are bad enough, but Sandra Bullock takes the biscuit with her repetitive attempts at light humour. If ever a film made you despise someone, it's Bullock in this. Otherwise, the story suffers from a little bloating and an ending that goes on way too long, but it does have some stuff to recommend it. The low rent action-man hijinks are a hoot, and Willem Dafoe is fantastic as the over-the-top villain, all teeth and hair and as crazy as he was in WILD AT HEART. The effects hold up pretty well, too. A shame, then, about the child-friendly nature of the production; had this been a proper, adult-focused outing along the lines of UNDER SIEGE it could have been a damn sight better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's out of control and as bad as it gets.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Olsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thing is beyond lame. The entire cast is about as unlikable and impersonal as can be, and the plot is as thin as the news on CNN. It's a huge problem for any movie, if the characters become annoying from the outset of the movie. This is partly due to bad acting and bad casting. The male lead (Jason Patric) is as believable as an action cop, as it would be to watch a 2 year old fly the Concorde. Sandra Bulldog is annoying beyond hope, due to the characters exaggerated amount of stupidity. The rest of the cast, is just bland and as memorable as a rainy Monday. The only two members of the cast that I find the slightest bit interesting are Christine Firkins and Susan Barnes. The plot, well, it's a ship out of control. The main problem with this is, that the director and producer did not take the time to make it believable. There are so many technical errors in this, it's ridiculous. They did not take the time to find out, how a cruise liner works and that way could have eliminated the ways of stopping the ship in a believable fashion. These technical plot holes just go on and on through the entire movie and ends with the biggest blunder ever. If you have any nautical knowledge and knowledge of ships, you'll find yourself covering your eyes due to sheer embarrassment on the behalf of the writer, director and producer. Ship wreck does not even begin to explain what this movie is, a nuclear blast is less of a disaster than this movie is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speed 2: Cruisin' for a Bruisin'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    horacep
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Speed 2 is an action film that kept my interest and wasn't nearly as bad as some reviewers have described. Sandra Bullock stars so that alone lead me to watch this move, and while this clearly isn't her best work she does a good job. I would have liked to have seen a little more humor in her role, although the early scenes with Tim Conway were funny. She and her boyfriend, an LA SWAT team member, are taking a cruise to get away from it all. In this sequel she once again picks a doomed vehicle to travel in. Willem Dafoe is a disgruntled former cruise line employee determined for revenge with his golf clubs and balls hiding bomb materials, something I've not seen before. There is plenty of action and some fine special effects. My wife and I both thought this move was well worth viewing if you like Sandra Bullock and you like action films without all the cursing that seems to come along with the newer films. All in all it is an interesting movie with a spectacular special effects finish. I rate it above average.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheap Thrills.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Willem Dafoe is a computer genius and madman with long greasy locks who takes over a huge cruise ship at sea, causes numerous crises, steals jewels from the ship's vault, and tries to run the ship up on the rocks. This is the kind of movie about a vehicle in jeopardy that, as the discerning viewer already knows, must have a sick child aboard. After the original helpless boy, in "The High and the Mighty," the child must be a girl. Girls are more pitiful. She needs a kidney transplant or the transfusion of some rare blood type to save her life. Obviously there are going to be problems fitting this stereotypical sick child aboard a cruise ship. After all, if you're going to rush your kid someplace, you don't ordinarily put her aboard a cruise ship full of rich drunks, gamblers, and leisurely honeymooners like Sandra Bullock and Jason Patric. So this pretty little girl is made mute, deaf, and speechless, and she's trapped in the elevator on board a ship that appears to be on fire and sinking. That's the best the writers could come up with. I feel like apologizing for them. However, on the plus side, every other single action movie clich&eacute; that you can think of is on reckless display in this piece of dumbed-down and mentally dangerous garbage. Just take the sound track. There is an alarm bell constantly ringing in the background, overwhelming speech, even though everyone is shouting hysterically. (Except the mute little girl, of course, who must use sign language.) The music thumps and stomps most of the screams into oblivion. The camerman wobbles all over the place, probably drunk on excitement. During the first major crisis -- a lifeboat is hung up on the davits -- the editing is so lightning-fast -- a shot of a spinning winch, a terrified face, a cable snapping thread by thread, a body falling into the sea, arms waving, hands grasping for something just out of reach, an explosion of flashing lights, computer screens turning into a fireworks display, the director dashing momentarily in front of the camera and giving the audience the finger -- that you can't follow events. Each shot lasts for one blink of one eye, dashing past like muscae volitantes on speed, until they blend into one another and form a stupefying collage of abandoned movement. I rather liked the original "Speed," which was thoroughly mindless enjoyment. This is bigger, faster, more expensive, stupider. You still want to watch it? Take some Dramamine and a good book along.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Head for the lifeboats, people - this one's going down fast! 42%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As much as I'm a fan of US film critic and all-round nice guy Roger Ebert, there are plenty of times when I disagree with him. I never have and never will call myself a critic - I remain, first and foremost, an audience goer, regardless of whether I'm watching a film at home or at the cinema. Therefore, I regard all films on how entertaining they are rather than the likelihood of winning anything during award season. Despite my resolutely low-brow approach, I do disagree with Ebert on this turgid sequel to one of the best action movies of the Nineties. Ebert's positive praise for this movie was the only good review anywhere to be found of this film and to be frank, I can't really see where he's coming from. Sandra Bullock returns as Annie, the goofy heroine from the first movie who is now seeing fellow LA officer Alex (Jason Patric) - unaware that Alex is just as reckless a daredevil as her ex Jack (Keanu Reeves, who was smarter enough to avoid this). After going away for a romantic cruise in the Caribbean, Annie and Alex find themselves caught up in the explosive schemes of crazed bomber Geiger (Willem Dafoe, in full-on psycho mode). With the ship beyond the control of the crew, Geiger sets a course for collision with an oil tanker - leaving Alex, Annie and a handful of terrified passengers to try and save the ship as well as stop Geiger from making off with loads of diamonds stolen from the ship's vault. What made "Speed" so good was that despite the stupid plot, it remained a genuinely thrilling ride with a suitably OTT villain in the shape of Dennis Hopper, Bullock's flustered performance as the reluctant heroine and the occasionally tongue-in-cheek moment to lighten the mood. So naturally, "Speed 2: Cruise Control" (and can you see what they did there with the title?) offers more of the same except this time, they blew it. Dafoe couldn't be any more insane if he rocked on his knees in the corner of the room reciting nursery rhymes and is actually a pretty weak baddie - at times, I almost felt sorry for him as he appeared to be suffering from some sort of mental illness. Bullock this time is largely relegated to the damsel-in-distress role, leaving Patric to carry the film which, sadly, is beyond him - he is as vacant as an waitress's smile. But the film's attempt at subtle humour badly backfires - take Dante (Royale Watkins), for example, and his insistence on taking photos of everything at any time, even when he's up to his neck in water on a sinking sink. The passengers are mostly anonymous apart from a trapped deaf girl (Christine Ferkins) who provides a side mission and a sweaty fat guy with a moustache (Mike Hagerty) - the rest all seem to be screaming fat women, for some reason. What sort of cruise is this? There are some things to commend, however. The action, when it does arrive, is performed in vast amounts of gushing cold water which can't be pleasant and I must give a nod to Temuera Morrison as the first officer because he is, by far and away, the most convincing actor on screen. He certainly better than the annoying Scot (Brian McCardie) who simply must count down loud the speed of the crashing ship in knots whilst looking like he's being buggered. But "Speed 2: Cruise Control" is that kinda film - even Geiger's Fiber Optic Converter has a big sticky label on it so we can all see what it is! This is an insultingly stupid summer action blockbuster that, in truth, has nothing whatsoever to do with the original and if that's what you want then fine. But for everyone involved, this is am embarrassing outing that sadly ruined the reputation of "Speed" which is unfair because that is a real blast. This is barely a fizzle. Maybe Ebert has a soft spot for Ms Bullock but the question I posed was is this an entertaining film. Only if you get your kicks from exchanges like "It's an earthquake!" "It can't be - we're at sea!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
