<filme>
 <id>
  109
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0117128
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Filme Mais Idiota do Mundo
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Mike Nelson and his robot companions watch and give their comments about "This Island Earth".
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  The mad and evil scientist, Dr. Clayton Forrester, has created an evil little scheme that is bound to give him world global domination but first thing's first. He plans to torment Mike Nelson and the robots by sending them a real stinker of a film to watch called, "This Island Earth." He is convinced that this movie will drive them insane. And since the guys cannot control when the movie begins or ends, they are forced to witness the true horror that is this awful movie that has a lobster creature dressed in slacks. But will this be the ultimate cheese that breaks the boys' spirits? It's up to one test subject's quick wit, sharp sense of humor, and utter intolerance for cinematic garbage to foil the plans of the scientist and to save the Earth.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   robot
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   scientist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   pick axe
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   poking fun at movie
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   gay innuendo
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Jim Mallon
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Joel Hodgson
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Michael J. Nelson
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Trace Beaulieu
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Michael J. Nelson
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jim Mallon
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you liked the TV show, you can't go wrong with this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joshua kit
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is just a two hour episode of the TV show, and that's why it works. It won't make you cry, but it will make you laugh. I enjoyed the TV show and found the movie had everything I enjoyed about it. The movie they watch is the much-maligned, iconic 50s sci-fi B-movie, "This Island Earth". (Which, for what it's worth, is not a terrible movie. It's silly, but compared to many of it's contemporary films, is somewhat watchable.) If you've never seen it, then this is a good way to watch it. Not a whole lot else to say. This movie won't win an Oscar, but it's a fine pastime for a Friday night at home with a few beers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Several Good Laughs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mystery Science Theatre 3000: The Movie (1996) *** (out of 4) The cult TV show made it to the big screen this one time and features Mike and his two robots being held by an evil scientist who forces them to watch THIS ISLAND EARTH. This is meant to torture the trio but the three turn the tables with their comments. I will admit right up front that I'm not one of the die hard fans who love this show more than anything else. I'm very hit and miss on it and I often find myself on message boards talking against the show because I'm one who can enjoy these bad movies without the added comments. However, every time I argue against the show it hits me that when I do watch one I find it funny and there's no question that there's talent behind the comments. Now, I will say that I found it strange that they selected THIS ISLAND EARTH for their first movie because, to be honest, it's really not a bad movie. I think had they selected a worse movie it might have led to more and better jokes but what's here is still pretty good. I thought the best moments happened whenever the trio went on with continued dialogue. One would pretend to be the voice of a character and then they would just go back and forth. I thought this is when the best jokes came out and especially the stuff dealing with the alien leader's ultra big head. Another funny jokes happens at the start when the plane is about to crash but the alien's help land it with a green flashing light. The jokes that are around this are very good. As with any comedy, there are jokes that don't work but I think for the most part the majority of them hit their target and deliver laughs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pitiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Green_Saturn
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It doesn't matter that this movie is based off a successful T.V. show. It still is painful to watch. After a confusing and messy opening monologue by some creepy professor, for whatever reason the audience discovers that this movie takes place in space. And the spaceship our "heroes" are in looks suspiciously like male genitalia. I never quite understood whether that was intentional or not. The only thing sadder than the plot of this movie is the robots. Seriously, its like whoever designed them died half way through the process. I don't know if they're from the T.V. show or something (NO, I have never seen the show), but they are just utterly awful. One is something that I think resembles a crow, and the other is just a talking gumball machine. It creeped me out. What was the point of even having the robots, or the random guy who is friends with them? (By the way, was Trace Beaulieu blackmailed into playing Mike Nelson?) The comments made about the movie these characters are watching are juvenile and distracting. At one point, one of the robots makes a sound like a car engine when a car pans on screen. Where is the humor? What am I not getting? Halfway through the movie (that the characters are watching), the filmmakers decided to spare the audience by having the film reel break. While we wait for the creepy scientist guy to fix this, our useless heroes break the Hubble telescope. This is, in fact, their biggest accomplishment of the entire movie. The movie the creepy scientist makes them watch isn't that bad. It's actually pretty interesting, if a little cheesy. You'd think if the whole point of the movie was to make fun of another movie, whoever made this would've at least picked a bad movie to make fun of. The worst part is the ending. Usually, in the last ten minutes of a movie, loose ends are tied up. Nope. Not in this. Nothing happens. One star, because at least this movie was SHORT.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I never understood why they made this movie, but it was still rather good.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aaron1375
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film features the gang of the Satellite of Love like you have never seen them before! Being told what to do by movie producers, being passed over for ad revenue in favor of Barb Wire and riffing a film that is 94 minutes long and longer than this entire film. Still, the riffing was good and the film overall funny, just not as good as some of the stuff one saw in the regular show. In this film the Satellite of Love looks like it is in space, other than that it seems there was very little need to make this movie as the producers seemed to want to make this film short as all get out, it would of been better off simply being an episode of the show. The film being parodied is "This Island Earth", a film I have not seen other than what is presented here. Usually I feel comfortable reviewing films the gang have done, but this one is so obviously cut short I will not review this one as this one is so chopped up a lot of the plot is too. I am not sure what is happening in places so until I see the full movie I will not review it. I can review this though and like I said, it is good, but I would rather they had stayed on television as this movie is shorter than anything they did on the show on Comedy Central or the Sci-Fi channel. The host segments were not as funny as the host segments on the regular show either as they seemed to want to scream at the audience, "This is a movie!" So overall, funny, just kind of pointless. Though it is one film I can watch the closing credits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its a mystery why this film was ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ryan-Pollard
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'MST3K - The Movie', I came to the conclusion that it deserved to be on 'MST3K - The Television Series' far more than 'Danger Diabolik', 'Squirm' or 'Phase 4'. Bad script, ham acting, lame jokes, poor special effects - it had the lot. It also managed to insult one of the finest science fiction films of the '50's - 'This Island Earth'. Why that particular movie? Could they not find something more suitable, such as 'Plan 9 From Outer Space'? The sad thing is that its audience will never know how good a film 'This Island Earth' is because all they have seen of it is a silly send-up. The funniest line in the whole 90 minutes was "I've farted!" and that tells you all you need to know. The 'MST3K' brigade do not seem to be aware that any idiot can laugh at an old movie, especially if it is of its time. It takes real intelligence to be able to look at 'This Island Earth' and see it for what it is, an imaginative and exciting sci-fi picture. 'MST3K' bombed on its release, and the show itself was cancelled a few years later, so one good thing came out of it at least.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In space . . . . . . . . . . . everyone can hear your screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, just wow. The popularity of this movie (and, by logical extension, I would have to say the TV show) astounds me. The concept? There is a man in space who is being tested by being shown the worst movies ever made and so he sits through them with a couple of robot buddies and makes fun of them. That's it, and to some people that's all well and good and makes for some of the funniest stuff that they've ever sat through. For me, this ends up being one of the very worst experiences I have ever had to endure in my whole life of movie-watching (and I've watched a LOT of crap, believe me). My main issue with the thing is that, to me anyway, the comments from the folk on screen are just annoying and unfunny. Okay, okay, I smirked on about two occasions but that's not a very good average for something that's supposed to be a comedy. There will be those thinking I am just a massive fan of This Island Earth (the movie being watched within the movie) and feeling all defensive about it being so insulted. Well, this was the first time I had seen This Island Earth in any form and there's no denying that it was a risible movie but the fact remains that many of my own thoughts while watching the movie would be/were funnier than those mentioned by the Mystery Science Theatregoers (who are, essentially, the annoying people sitting in the row in front of you in a cinema, thinking they are smart-assed greatness with their constant nattering and stream of lowest common denominator consciousness). Pretty much all of those involved (director Jim Mallon, stars Trace Beaulieu and Michael J. Nelson, etc) had a hand in writing this nonsense and so can all share the blame. Unfunny, irritating and just absolutely awful. It was like spending just over an hour listening to nails on a chalk board while I tried to "enjoy" a bad 50s sci-fi flick. I never ever want to see this again. Ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny as if Richard Basehart ran naked through Washington yelling "I'm Richard Basehart!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (udragon2010)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As always, the guys at MST3K make a bad movie watchable. I giggled and guffawed from the minute it started. The guys are forced to watch "This Island Earth" and riff on its stupidness. The bots are just as nutty as they are in the show and good old Mike Nelson is the glue that keeps the zaniness from getting too much. This is a great jumping on point for those who have not yet been blessed by the goodness that is Mystery Science Theater 3000. People who have complained about this movie riffing on a classic movie should repeat to themselves "its just a movie and I should really just relax." It's great for the kids, family and the dog, but not for grandpa and grandma. Watch this flick and you'll wish for movie sign for the rest of your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious even When You Watch for the Second Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The evil scientist Dr. Clayton Forrester (Trace Beaulieu) locks Mike Nelson (Michael J. Nelson) and two robots in a spacecraft to watch terrible low-budget movies as part of his scheme to conquer the world. He projects 1954 "This Island Earth" (Title (Brazil): "Guerra Entre Planetas") with the intention of driving them crazy. However, the trio laughs and makes funny comments in every scene and dialogs, having good-time instead, and Dr. Forrester's ambitious plan does not work. The first time I saw "Mystery Science Theater 3000: The Movie" on 01 February 2000 I loved it a lot and I gave a nine. I had watched the cheese "This Island Earth" a few months ago and the comments of Mike Nelson and the two robots made me laugh a lot. Today I have just watched this film again and it is still hilarious, but my rating is lower this time. "Mystery Science Theater 3000: The Movie" was released in Brazil on VHS by CIC-Universal Distributor. My vote is seven. Title (Brazil): "O Filme Mais Idiota do Mundo" ("The Most Idiot Movie of the World")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Keanu Reeves In My Own Private Airfield"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Possible Spoilers But I Can't See Any. This Is The First Time I Ever Saw A Mystery Science Theater...Well Anything. Its Where Dr. Forrester Subjects Their Last Movie On Them. "THIS ISLAND EARTH" & This Island Earth Is A Horrible Movie With Animation Techniques That'll Make A 5 Year Old Get Worried. THIS Movie On The Other Hand Is Stupid & Downright Hilarious. I Am Interested In The Series Because They Look Funny. All In All A Great Comedy Sci-Fi. The Plot To This Island Earth Is That Dr. Meacham is chosen along with others by the inhabitants of the planet Metaluna to do research that will help save their dying planet. However, an evil scheme is uncovered by the suspecting Dr. Meacham when he discovers the Metalunan's plan to take over Earth. Dr. Meacham then escapes an exploding Metalunan built Earth lab along with Dr. Adams only to be kidnapped while flying away in a small plane. A flying saucer whisks both the scientists off to Metaluna where they are held accountable for blowing up the Metalunan Earth lab during their escape. They later escape there with the help of Exeter the friendly Metalunan. Metaluna then self destructs and the Doctors make it safely back to Earth, which is saved from Metalunan invasion. Now Do You See Why I Call THIS ISLAND EARTH Horrible
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Very Funny Film, Though Only Makes Me Miss the Show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Nelson and his robot buddies are still trapped on the Satellite of Love, forced to watch bad movies for some sort of bizarre experiment to drive Nelson mad. This time, the film is "This Island Earth". This film is very funny, but there is really nothing I have to say about it. If you like the show, you will like the movie, because there is really no difference whatsoever. The budget is slightly greater, so the lobby jokes are nicer looking, but they are so minor that it hardly matters. The picture quality also seems slightly crisper. The bulk of the film has them in the theater, which would look the same no matter what. Sadly, the film does little more than make me miss the show. According to some unknown source, "The TV show's usual density of gags was reduced for theatrical audiences, so that a larger number of people laughing wouldn't cause too much dialogue to be missed." That makes sense, except when you are watching it sixteen years later on DVD. You do not need that much silence -- it then becomes almost like really watching "This Island Earth". Even more mysterious, the film comes in at a short 73 minutes, even shorter than the average episode of 90 minutes. So the movie is shorter than the TV show! And the disc has no special features (besides French language track), so the DVD is not that special -- you would be better off buying a DVD of them watching "Manos" or something, unless you really enjoyed this particular film. A good film, some funny gags, and a short run time for quick viewing... but really nothing worth making a movie about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you liked the TV show, you can't go wrong with this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joshua kit
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is just a two hour episode of the TV show, and that's why it works. It won't make you cry, but it will make you laugh. I enjoyed the TV show and found the movie had everything I enjoyed about it. The movie they watch is the much-maligned, iconic 50s sci-fi B-movie, "This Island Earth". (Which, for what it's worth, is not a terrible movie. It's silly, but compared to many of it's contemporary films, is somewhat watchable.) If you've never seen it, then this is a good way to watch it. Not a whole lot else to say. This movie won't win an Oscar, but it's a fine pastime for a Friday night at home with a few beers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Several Good Laughs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mystery Science Theatre 3000: The Movie (1996) *** (out of 4) The cult TV show made it to the big screen this one time and features Mike and his two robots being held by an evil scientist who forces them to watch THIS ISLAND EARTH. This is meant to torture the trio but the three turn the tables with their comments. I will admit right up front that I'm not one of the die hard fans who love this show more than anything else. I'm very hit and miss on it and I often find myself on message boards talking against the show because I'm one who can enjoy these bad movies without the added comments. However, every time I argue against the show it hits me that when I do watch one I find it funny and there's no question that there's talent behind the comments. Now, I will say that I found it strange that they selected THIS ISLAND EARTH for their first movie because, to be honest, it's really not a bad movie. I think had they selected a worse movie it might have led to more and better jokes but what's here is still pretty good. I thought the best moments happened whenever the trio went on with continued dialogue. One would pretend to be the voice of a character and then they would just go back and forth. I thought this is when the best jokes came out and especially the stuff dealing with the alien leader's ultra big head. Another funny jokes happens at the start when the plane is about to crash but the alien's help land it with a green flashing light. The jokes that are around this are very good. As with any comedy, there are jokes that don't work but I think for the most part the majority of them hit their target and deliver laughs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pitiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Green_Saturn
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It doesn't matter that this movie is based off a successful T.V. show. It still is painful to watch. After a confusing and messy opening monologue by some creepy professor, for whatever reason the audience discovers that this movie takes place in space. And the spaceship our "heroes" are in looks suspiciously like male genitalia. I never quite understood whether that was intentional or not. The only thing sadder than the plot of this movie is the robots. Seriously, its like whoever designed them died half way through the process. I don't know if they're from the T.V. show or something (NO, I have never seen the show), but they are just utterly awful. One is something that I think resembles a crow, and the other is just a talking gumball machine. It creeped me out. What was the point of even having the robots, or the random guy who is friends with them? (By the way, was Trace Beaulieu blackmailed into playing Mike Nelson?) The comments made about the movie these characters are watching are juvenile and distracting. At one point, one of the robots makes a sound like a car engine when a car pans on screen. Where is the humor? What am I not getting? Halfway through the movie (that the characters are watching), the filmmakers decided to spare the audience by having the film reel break. While we wait for the creepy scientist guy to fix this, our useless heroes break the Hubble telescope. This is, in fact, their biggest accomplishment of the entire movie. The movie the creepy scientist makes them watch isn't that bad. It's actually pretty interesting, if a little cheesy. You'd think if the whole point of the movie was to make fun of another movie, whoever made this would've at least picked a bad movie to make fun of. The worst part is the ending. Usually, in the last ten minutes of a movie, loose ends are tied up. Nope. Not in this. Nothing happens. One star, because at least this movie was SHORT.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I never understood why they made this movie, but it was still rather good.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aaron1375
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film features the gang of the Satellite of Love like you have never seen them before! Being told what to do by movie producers, being passed over for ad revenue in favor of Barb Wire and riffing a film that is 94 minutes long and longer than this entire film. Still, the riffing was good and the film overall funny, just not as good as some of the stuff one saw in the regular show. In this film the Satellite of Love looks like it is in space, other than that it seems there was very little need to make this movie as the producers seemed to want to make this film short as all get out, it would of been better off simply being an episode of the show. The film being parodied is "This Island Earth", a film I have not seen other than what is presented here. Usually I feel comfortable reviewing films the gang have done, but this one is so obviously cut short I will not review this one as this one is so chopped up a lot of the plot is too. I am not sure what is happening in places so until I see the full movie I will not review it. I can review this though and like I said, it is good, but I would rather they had stayed on television as this movie is shorter than anything they did on the show on Comedy Central or the Sci-Fi channel. The host segments were not as funny as the host segments on the regular show either as they seemed to want to scream at the audience, "This is a movie!" So overall, funny, just kind of pointless. Though it is one film I can watch the closing credits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its a mystery why this film was ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ryan-Pollard
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'MST3K - The Movie', I came to the conclusion that it deserved to be on 'MST3K - The Television Series' far more than 'Danger Diabolik', 'Squirm' or 'Phase 4'. Bad script, ham acting, lame jokes, poor special effects - it had the lot. It also managed to insult one of the finest science fiction films of the '50's - 'This Island Earth'. Why that particular movie? Could they not find something more suitable, such as 'Plan 9 From Outer Space'? The sad thing is that its audience will never know how good a film 'This Island Earth' is because all they have seen of it is a silly send-up. The funniest line in the whole 90 minutes was "I've farted!" and that tells you all you need to know. The 'MST3K' brigade do not seem to be aware that any idiot can laugh at an old movie, especially if it is of its time. It takes real intelligence to be able to look at 'This Island Earth' and see it for what it is, an imaginative and exciting sci-fi picture. 'MST3K' bombed on its release, and the show itself was cancelled a few years later, so one good thing came out of it at least.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In space . . . . . . . . . . . everyone can hear your screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, just wow. The popularity of this movie (and, by logical extension, I would have to say the TV show) astounds me. The concept? There is a man in space who is being tested by being shown the worst movies ever made and so he sits through them with a couple of robot buddies and makes fun of them. That's it, and to some people that's all well and good and makes for some of the funniest stuff that they've ever sat through. For me, this ends up being one of the very worst experiences I have ever had to endure in my whole life of movie-watching (and I've watched a LOT of crap, believe me). My main issue with the thing is that, to me anyway, the comments from the folk on screen are just annoying and unfunny. Okay, okay, I smirked on about two occasions but that's not a very good average for something that's supposed to be a comedy. There will be those thinking I am just a massive fan of This Island Earth (the movie being watched within the movie) and feeling all defensive about it being so insulted. Well, this was the first time I had seen This Island Earth in any form and there's no denying that it was a risible movie but the fact remains that many of my own thoughts while watching the movie would be/were funnier than those mentioned by the Mystery Science Theatregoers (who are, essentially, the annoying people sitting in the row in front of you in a cinema, thinking they are smart-assed greatness with their constant nattering and stream of lowest common denominator consciousness). Pretty much all of those involved (director Jim Mallon, stars Trace Beaulieu and Michael J. Nelson, etc) had a hand in writing this nonsense and so can all share the blame. Unfunny, irritating and just absolutely awful. It was like spending just over an hour listening to nails on a chalk board while I tried to "enjoy" a bad 50s sci-fi flick. I never ever want to see this again. Ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny as if Richard Basehart ran naked through Washington yelling "I'm Richard Basehart!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (udragon2010)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As always, the guys at MST3K make a bad movie watchable. I giggled and guffawed from the minute it started. The guys are forced to watch "This Island Earth" and riff on its stupidness. The bots are just as nutty as they are in the show and good old Mike Nelson is the glue that keeps the zaniness from getting too much. This is a great jumping on point for those who have not yet been blessed by the goodness that is Mystery Science Theater 3000. People who have complained about this movie riffing on a classic movie should repeat to themselves "its just a movie and I should really just relax." It's great for the kids, family and the dog, but not for grandpa and grandma. Watch this flick and you'll wish for movie sign for the rest of your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious even When You Watch for the Second Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The evil scientist Dr. Clayton Forrester (Trace Beaulieu) locks Mike Nelson (Michael J. Nelson) and two robots in a spacecraft to watch terrible low-budget movies as part of his scheme to conquer the world. He projects 1954 "This Island Earth" (Title (Brazil): "Guerra Entre Planetas") with the intention of driving them crazy. However, the trio laughs and makes funny comments in every scene and dialogs, having good-time instead, and Dr. Forrester's ambitious plan does not work. The first time I saw "Mystery Science Theater 3000: The Movie" on 01 February 2000 I loved it a lot and I gave a nine. I had watched the cheese "This Island Earth" a few months ago and the comments of Mike Nelson and the two robots made me laugh a lot. Today I have just watched this film again and it is still hilarious, but my rating is lower this time. "Mystery Science Theater 3000: The Movie" was released in Brazil on VHS by CIC-Universal Distributor. My vote is seven. Title (Brazil): "O Filme Mais Idiota do Mundo" ("The Most Idiot Movie of the World")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Keanu Reeves In My Own Private Airfield"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Possible Spoilers But I Can't See Any. This Is The First Time I Ever Saw A Mystery Science Theater...Well Anything. Its Where Dr. Forrester Subjects Their Last Movie On Them. "THIS ISLAND EARTH" & This Island Earth Is A Horrible Movie With Animation Techniques That'll Make A 5 Year Old Get Worried. THIS Movie On The Other Hand Is Stupid & Downright Hilarious. I Am Interested In The Series Because They Look Funny. All In All A Great Comedy Sci-Fi. The Plot To This Island Earth Is That Dr. Meacham is chosen along with others by the inhabitants of the planet Metaluna to do research that will help save their dying planet. However, an evil scheme is uncovered by the suspecting Dr. Meacham when he discovers the Metalunan's plan to take over Earth. Dr. Meacham then escapes an exploding Metalunan built Earth lab along with Dr. Adams only to be kidnapped while flying away in a small plane. A flying saucer whisks both the scientists off to Metaluna where they are held accountable for blowing up the Metalunan Earth lab during their escape. They later escape there with the help of Exeter the friendly Metalunan. Metaluna then self destructs and the Doctors make it safely back to Earth, which is saved from Metalunan invasion. Now Do You See Why I Call THIS ISLAND EARTH Horrible
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Very Funny Film, Though Only Makes Me Miss the Show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Nelson and his robot buddies are still trapped on the Satellite of Love, forced to watch bad movies for some sort of bizarre experiment to drive Nelson mad. This time, the film is "This Island Earth". This film is very funny, but there is really nothing I have to say about it. If you like the show, you will like the movie, because there is really no difference whatsoever. The budget is slightly greater, so the lobby jokes are nicer looking, but they are so minor that it hardly matters. The picture quality also seems slightly crisper. The bulk of the film has them in the theater, which would look the same no matter what. Sadly, the film does little more than make me miss the show. According to some unknown source, "The TV show's usual density of gags was reduced for theatrical audiences, so that a larger number of people laughing wouldn't cause too much dialogue to be missed." That makes sense, except when you are watching it sixteen years later on DVD. You do not need that much silence -- it then becomes almost like really watching "This Island Earth". Even more mysterious, the film comes in at a short 73 minutes, even shorter than the average episode of 90 minutes. So the movie is shorter than the TV show! And the disc has no special features (besides French language track), so the DVD is not that special -- you would be better off buying a DVD of them watching "Manos" or something, unless you really enjoyed this particular film. A good film, some funny gags, and a short run time for quick viewing... but really nothing worth making a movie about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you liked the TV show, you can't go wrong with this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joshua kit
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is just a two hour episode of the TV show, and that's why it works. It won't make you cry, but it will make you laugh. I enjoyed the TV show and found the movie had everything I enjoyed about it. The movie they watch is the much-maligned, iconic 50s sci-fi B-movie, "This Island Earth". (Which, for what it's worth, is not a terrible movie. It's silly, but compared to many of it's contemporary films, is somewhat watchable.) If you've never seen it, then this is a good way to watch it. Not a whole lot else to say. This movie won't win an Oscar, but it's a fine pastime for a Friday night at home with a few beers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Several Good Laughs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mystery Science Theatre 3000: The Movie (1996) *** (out of 4) The cult TV show made it to the big screen this one time and features Mike and his two robots being held by an evil scientist who forces them to watch THIS ISLAND EARTH. This is meant to torture the trio but the three turn the tables with their comments. I will admit right up front that I'm not one of the die hard fans who love this show more than anything else. I'm very hit and miss on it and I often find myself on message boards talking against the show because I'm one who can enjoy these bad movies without the added comments. However, every time I argue against the show it hits me that when I do watch one I find it funny and there's no question that there's talent behind the comments. Now, I will say that I found it strange that they selected THIS ISLAND EARTH for their first movie because, to be honest, it's really not a bad movie. I think had they selected a worse movie it might have led to more and better jokes but what's here is still pretty good. I thought the best moments happened whenever the trio went on with continued dialogue. One would pretend to be the voice of a character and then they would just go back and forth. I thought this is when the best jokes came out and especially the stuff dealing with the alien leader's ultra big head. Another funny jokes happens at the start when the plane is about to crash but the alien's help land it with a green flashing light. The jokes that are around this are very good. As with any comedy, there are jokes that don't work but I think for the most part the majority of them hit their target and deliver laughs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pitiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Green_Saturn
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It doesn't matter that this movie is based off a successful T.V. show. It still is painful to watch. After a confusing and messy opening monologue by some creepy professor, for whatever reason the audience discovers that this movie takes place in space. And the spaceship our "heroes" are in looks suspiciously like male genitalia. I never quite understood whether that was intentional or not. The only thing sadder than the plot of this movie is the robots. Seriously, its like whoever designed them died half way through the process. I don't know if they're from the T.V. show or something (NO, I have never seen the show), but they are just utterly awful. One is something that I think resembles a crow, and the other is just a talking gumball machine. It creeped me out. What was the point of even having the robots, or the random guy who is friends with them? (By the way, was Trace Beaulieu blackmailed into playing Mike Nelson?) The comments made about the movie these characters are watching are juvenile and distracting. At one point, one of the robots makes a sound like a car engine when a car pans on screen. Where is the humor? What am I not getting? Halfway through the movie (that the characters are watching), the filmmakers decided to spare the audience by having the film reel break. While we wait for the creepy scientist guy to fix this, our useless heroes break the Hubble telescope. This is, in fact, their biggest accomplishment of the entire movie. The movie the creepy scientist makes them watch isn't that bad. It's actually pretty interesting, if a little cheesy. You'd think if the whole point of the movie was to make fun of another movie, whoever made this would've at least picked a bad movie to make fun of. The worst part is the ending. Usually, in the last ten minutes of a movie, loose ends are tied up. Nope. Not in this. Nothing happens. One star, because at least this movie was SHORT.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I never understood why they made this movie, but it was still rather good.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aaron1375
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film features the gang of the Satellite of Love like you have never seen them before! Being told what to do by movie producers, being passed over for ad revenue in favor of Barb Wire and riffing a film that is 94 minutes long and longer than this entire film. Still, the riffing was good and the film overall funny, just not as good as some of the stuff one saw in the regular show. In this film the Satellite of Love looks like it is in space, other than that it seems there was very little need to make this movie as the producers seemed to want to make this film short as all get out, it would of been better off simply being an episode of the show. The film being parodied is "This Island Earth", a film I have not seen other than what is presented here. Usually I feel comfortable reviewing films the gang have done, but this one is so obviously cut short I will not review this one as this one is so chopped up a lot of the plot is too. I am not sure what is happening in places so until I see the full movie I will not review it. I can review this though and like I said, it is good, but I would rather they had stayed on television as this movie is shorter than anything they did on the show on Comedy Central or the Sci-Fi channel. The host segments were not as funny as the host segments on the regular show either as they seemed to want to scream at the audience, "This is a movie!" So overall, funny, just kind of pointless. Though it is one film I can watch the closing credits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its a mystery why this film was ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ryan-Pollard
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'MST3K - The Movie', I came to the conclusion that it deserved to be on 'MST3K - The Television Series' far more than 'Danger Diabolik', 'Squirm' or 'Phase 4'. Bad script, ham acting, lame jokes, poor special effects - it had the lot. It also managed to insult one of the finest science fiction films of the '50's - 'This Island Earth'. Why that particular movie? Could they not find something more suitable, such as 'Plan 9 From Outer Space'? The sad thing is that its audience will never know how good a film 'This Island Earth' is because all they have seen of it is a silly send-up. The funniest line in the whole 90 minutes was "I've farted!" and that tells you all you need to know. The 'MST3K' brigade do not seem to be aware that any idiot can laugh at an old movie, especially if it is of its time. It takes real intelligence to be able to look at 'This Island Earth' and see it for what it is, an imaginative and exciting sci-fi picture. 'MST3K' bombed on its release, and the show itself was cancelled a few years later, so one good thing came out of it at least.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In space . . . . . . . . . . . everyone can hear your screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, just wow. The popularity of this movie (and, by logical extension, I would have to say the TV show) astounds me. The concept? There is a man in space who is being tested by being shown the worst movies ever made and so he sits through them with a couple of robot buddies and makes fun of them. That's it, and to some people that's all well and good and makes for some of the funniest stuff that they've ever sat through. For me, this ends up being one of the very worst experiences I have ever had to endure in my whole life of movie-watching (and I've watched a LOT of crap, believe me). My main issue with the thing is that, to me anyway, the comments from the folk on screen are just annoying and unfunny. Okay, okay, I smirked on about two occasions but that's not a very good average for something that's supposed to be a comedy. There will be those thinking I am just a massive fan of This Island Earth (the movie being watched within the movie) and feeling all defensive about it being so insulted. Well, this was the first time I had seen This Island Earth in any form and there's no denying that it was a risible movie but the fact remains that many of my own thoughts while watching the movie would be/were funnier than those mentioned by the Mystery Science Theatregoers (who are, essentially, the annoying people sitting in the row in front of you in a cinema, thinking they are smart-assed greatness with their constant nattering and stream of lowest common denominator consciousness). Pretty much all of those involved (director Jim Mallon, stars Trace Beaulieu and Michael J. Nelson, etc) had a hand in writing this nonsense and so can all share the blame. Unfunny, irritating and just absolutely awful. It was like spending just over an hour listening to nails on a chalk board while I tried to "enjoy" a bad 50s sci-fi flick. I never ever want to see this again. Ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny as if Richard Basehart ran naked through Washington yelling "I'm Richard Basehart!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (udragon2010)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As always, the guys at MST3K make a bad movie watchable. I giggled and guffawed from the minute it started. The guys are forced to watch "This Island Earth" and riff on its stupidness. The bots are just as nutty as they are in the show and good old Mike Nelson is the glue that keeps the zaniness from getting too much. This is a great jumping on point for those who have not yet been blessed by the goodness that is Mystery Science Theater 3000. People who have complained about this movie riffing on a classic movie should repeat to themselves "its just a movie and I should really just relax." It's great for the kids, family and the dog, but not for grandpa and grandma. Watch this flick and you'll wish for movie sign for the rest of your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious even When You Watch for the Second Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The evil scientist Dr. Clayton Forrester (Trace Beaulieu) locks Mike Nelson (Michael J. Nelson) and two robots in a spacecraft to watch terrible low-budget movies as part of his scheme to conquer the world. He projects 1954 "This Island Earth" (Title (Brazil): "Guerra Entre Planetas") with the intention of driving them crazy. However, the trio laughs and makes funny comments in every scene and dialogs, having good-time instead, and Dr. Forrester's ambitious plan does not work. The first time I saw "Mystery Science Theater 3000: The Movie" on 01 February 2000 I loved it a lot and I gave a nine. I had watched the cheese "This Island Earth" a few months ago and the comments of Mike Nelson and the two robots made me laugh a lot. Today I have just watched this film again and it is still hilarious, but my rating is lower this time. "Mystery Science Theater 3000: The Movie" was released in Brazil on VHS by CIC-Universal Distributor. My vote is seven. Title (Brazil): "O Filme Mais Idiota do Mundo" ("The Most Idiot Movie of the World")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Keanu Reeves In My Own Private Airfield"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Possible Spoilers But I Can't See Any. This Is The First Time I Ever Saw A Mystery Science Theater...Well Anything. Its Where Dr. Forrester Subjects Their Last Movie On Them. "THIS ISLAND EARTH" & This Island Earth Is A Horrible Movie With Animation Techniques That'll Make A 5 Year Old Get Worried. THIS Movie On The Other Hand Is Stupid & Downright Hilarious. I Am Interested In The Series Because They Look Funny. All In All A Great Comedy Sci-Fi. The Plot To This Island Earth Is That Dr. Meacham is chosen along with others by the inhabitants of the planet Metaluna to do research that will help save their dying planet. However, an evil scheme is uncovered by the suspecting Dr. Meacham when he discovers the Metalunan's plan to take over Earth. Dr. Meacham then escapes an exploding Metalunan built Earth lab along with Dr. Adams only to be kidnapped while flying away in a small plane. A flying saucer whisks both the scientists off to Metaluna where they are held accountable for blowing up the Metalunan Earth lab during their escape. They later escape there with the help of Exeter the friendly Metalunan. Metaluna then self destructs and the Doctors make it safely back to Earth, which is saved from Metalunan invasion. Now Do You See Why I Call THIS ISLAND EARTH Horrible
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Very Funny Film, Though Only Makes Me Miss the Show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Nelson and his robot buddies are still trapped on the Satellite of Love, forced to watch bad movies for some sort of bizarre experiment to drive Nelson mad. This time, the film is "This Island Earth". This film is very funny, but there is really nothing I have to say about it. If you like the show, you will like the movie, because there is really no difference whatsoever. The budget is slightly greater, so the lobby jokes are nicer looking, but they are so minor that it hardly matters. The picture quality also seems slightly crisper. The bulk of the film has them in the theater, which would look the same no matter what. Sadly, the film does little more than make me miss the show. According to some unknown source, "The TV show's usual density of gags was reduced for theatrical audiences, so that a larger number of people laughing wouldn't cause too much dialogue to be missed." That makes sense, except when you are watching it sixteen years later on DVD. You do not need that much silence -- it then becomes almost like really watching "This Island Earth". Even more mysterious, the film comes in at a short 73 minutes, even shorter than the average episode of 90 minutes. So the movie is shorter than the TV show! And the disc has no special features (besides French language track), so the DVD is not that special -- you would be better off buying a DVD of them watching "Manos" or something, unless you really enjoyed this particular film. A good film, some funny gags, and a short run time for quick viewing... but really nothing worth making a movie about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you liked the TV show, you can't go wrong with this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joshua kit
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is just a two hour episode of the TV show, and that's why it works. It won't make you cry, but it will make you laugh. I enjoyed the TV show and found the movie had everything I enjoyed about it. The movie they watch is the much-maligned, iconic 50s sci-fi B-movie, "This Island Earth". (Which, for what it's worth, is not a terrible movie. It's silly, but compared to many of it's contemporary films, is somewhat watchable.) If you've never seen it, then this is a good way to watch it. Not a whole lot else to say. This movie won't win an Oscar, but it's a fine pastime for a Friday night at home with a few beers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Several Good Laughs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mystery Science Theatre 3000: The Movie (1996) *** (out of 4) The cult TV show made it to the big screen this one time and features Mike and his two robots being held by an evil scientist who forces them to watch THIS ISLAND EARTH. This is meant to torture the trio but the three turn the tables with their comments. I will admit right up front that I'm not one of the die hard fans who love this show more than anything else. I'm very hit and miss on it and I often find myself on message boards talking against the show because I'm one who can enjoy these bad movies without the added comments. However, every time I argue against the show it hits me that when I do watch one I find it funny and there's no question that there's talent behind the comments. Now, I will say that I found it strange that they selected THIS ISLAND EARTH for their first movie because, to be honest, it's really not a bad movie. I think had they selected a worse movie it might have led to more and better jokes but what's here is still pretty good. I thought the best moments happened whenever the trio went on with continued dialogue. One would pretend to be the voice of a character and then they would just go back and forth. I thought this is when the best jokes came out and especially the stuff dealing with the alien leader's ultra big head. Another funny jokes happens at the start when the plane is about to crash but the alien's help land it with a green flashing light. The jokes that are around this are very good. As with any comedy, there are jokes that don't work but I think for the most part the majority of them hit their target and deliver laughs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pitiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Green_Saturn
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It doesn't matter that this movie is based off a successful T.V. show. It still is painful to watch. After a confusing and messy opening monologue by some creepy professor, for whatever reason the audience discovers that this movie takes place in space. And the spaceship our "heroes" are in looks suspiciously like male genitalia. I never quite understood whether that was intentional or not. The only thing sadder than the plot of this movie is the robots. Seriously, its like whoever designed them died half way through the process. I don't know if they're from the T.V. show or something (NO, I have never seen the show), but they are just utterly awful. One is something that I think resembles a crow, and the other is just a talking gumball machine. It creeped me out. What was the point of even having the robots, or the random guy who is friends with them? (By the way, was Trace Beaulieu blackmailed into playing Mike Nelson?) The comments made about the movie these characters are watching are juvenile and distracting. At one point, one of the robots makes a sound like a car engine when a car pans on screen. Where is the humor? What am I not getting? Halfway through the movie (that the characters are watching), the filmmakers decided to spare the audience by having the film reel break. While we wait for the creepy scientist guy to fix this, our useless heroes break the Hubble telescope. This is, in fact, their biggest accomplishment of the entire movie. The movie the creepy scientist makes them watch isn't that bad. It's actually pretty interesting, if a little cheesy. You'd think if the whole point of the movie was to make fun of another movie, whoever made this would've at least picked a bad movie to make fun of. The worst part is the ending. Usually, in the last ten minutes of a movie, loose ends are tied up. Nope. Not in this. Nothing happens. One star, because at least this movie was SHORT.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I never understood why they made this movie, but it was still rather good.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aaron1375
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film features the gang of the Satellite of Love like you have never seen them before! Being told what to do by movie producers, being passed over for ad revenue in favor of Barb Wire and riffing a film that is 94 minutes long and longer than this entire film. Still, the riffing was good and the film overall funny, just not as good as some of the stuff one saw in the regular show. In this film the Satellite of Love looks like it is in space, other than that it seems there was very little need to make this movie as the producers seemed to want to make this film short as all get out, it would of been better off simply being an episode of the show. The film being parodied is "This Island Earth", a film I have not seen other than what is presented here. Usually I feel comfortable reviewing films the gang have done, but this one is so obviously cut short I will not review this one as this one is so chopped up a lot of the plot is too. I am not sure what is happening in places so until I see the full movie I will not review it. I can review this though and like I said, it is good, but I would rather they had stayed on television as this movie is shorter than anything they did on the show on Comedy Central or the Sci-Fi channel. The host segments were not as funny as the host segments on the regular show either as they seemed to want to scream at the audience, "This is a movie!" So overall, funny, just kind of pointless. Though it is one film I can watch the closing credits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its a mystery why this film was ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ryan-Pollard
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'MST3K - The Movie', I came to the conclusion that it deserved to be on 'MST3K - The Television Series' far more than 'Danger Diabolik', 'Squirm' or 'Phase 4'. Bad script, ham acting, lame jokes, poor special effects - it had the lot. It also managed to insult one of the finest science fiction films of the '50's - 'This Island Earth'. Why that particular movie? Could they not find something more suitable, such as 'Plan 9 From Outer Space'? The sad thing is that its audience will never know how good a film 'This Island Earth' is because all they have seen of it is a silly send-up. The funniest line in the whole 90 minutes was "I've farted!" and that tells you all you need to know. The 'MST3K' brigade do not seem to be aware that any idiot can laugh at an old movie, especially if it is of its time. It takes real intelligence to be able to look at 'This Island Earth' and see it for what it is, an imaginative and exciting sci-fi picture. 'MST3K' bombed on its release, and the show itself was cancelled a few years later, so one good thing came out of it at least.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In space . . . . . . . . . . . everyone can hear your screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, just wow. The popularity of this movie (and, by logical extension, I would have to say the TV show) astounds me. The concept? There is a man in space who is being tested by being shown the worst movies ever made and so he sits through them with a couple of robot buddies and makes fun of them. That's it, and to some people that's all well and good and makes for some of the funniest stuff that they've ever sat through. For me, this ends up being one of the very worst experiences I have ever had to endure in my whole life of movie-watching (and I've watched a LOT of crap, believe me). My main issue with the thing is that, to me anyway, the comments from the folk on screen are just annoying and unfunny. Okay, okay, I smirked on about two occasions but that's not a very good average for something that's supposed to be a comedy. There will be those thinking I am just a massive fan of This Island Earth (the movie being watched within the movie) and feeling all defensive about it being so insulted. Well, this was the first time I had seen This Island Earth in any form and there's no denying that it was a risible movie but the fact remains that many of my own thoughts while watching the movie would be/were funnier than those mentioned by the Mystery Science Theatregoers (who are, essentially, the annoying people sitting in the row in front of you in a cinema, thinking they are smart-assed greatness with their constant nattering and stream of lowest common denominator consciousness). Pretty much all of those involved (director Jim Mallon, stars Trace Beaulieu and Michael J. Nelson, etc) had a hand in writing this nonsense and so can all share the blame. Unfunny, irritating and just absolutely awful. It was like spending just over an hour listening to nails on a chalk board while I tried to "enjoy" a bad 50s sci-fi flick. I never ever want to see this again. Ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny as if Richard Basehart ran naked through Washington yelling "I'm Richard Basehart!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (udragon2010)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As always, the guys at MST3K make a bad movie watchable. I giggled and guffawed from the minute it started. The guys are forced to watch "This Island Earth" and riff on its stupidness. The bots are just as nutty as they are in the show and good old Mike Nelson is the glue that keeps the zaniness from getting too much. This is a great jumping on point for those who have not yet been blessed by the goodness that is Mystery Science Theater 3000. People who have complained about this movie riffing on a classic movie should repeat to themselves "its just a movie and I should really just relax." It's great for the kids, family and the dog, but not for grandpa and grandma. Watch this flick and you'll wish for movie sign for the rest of your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious even When You Watch for the Second Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The evil scientist Dr. Clayton Forrester (Trace Beaulieu) locks Mike Nelson (Michael J. Nelson) and two robots in a spacecraft to watch terrible low-budget movies as part of his scheme to conquer the world. He projects 1954 "This Island Earth" (Title (Brazil): "Guerra Entre Planetas") with the intention of driving them crazy. However, the trio laughs and makes funny comments in every scene and dialogs, having good-time instead, and Dr. Forrester's ambitious plan does not work. The first time I saw "Mystery Science Theater 3000: The Movie" on 01 February 2000 I loved it a lot and I gave a nine. I had watched the cheese "This Island Earth" a few months ago and the comments of Mike Nelson and the two robots made me laugh a lot. Today I have just watched this film again and it is still hilarious, but my rating is lower this time. "Mystery Science Theater 3000: The Movie" was released in Brazil on VHS by CIC-Universal Distributor. My vote is seven. Title (Brazil): "O Filme Mais Idiota do Mundo" ("The Most Idiot Movie of the World")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Keanu Reeves In My Own Private Airfield"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Possible Spoilers But I Can't See Any. This Is The First Time I Ever Saw A Mystery Science Theater...Well Anything. Its Where Dr. Forrester Subjects Their Last Movie On Them. "THIS ISLAND EARTH" & This Island Earth Is A Horrible Movie With Animation Techniques That'll Make A 5 Year Old Get Worried. THIS Movie On The Other Hand Is Stupid & Downright Hilarious. I Am Interested In The Series Because They Look Funny. All In All A Great Comedy Sci-Fi. The Plot To This Island Earth Is That Dr. Meacham is chosen along with others by the inhabitants of the planet Metaluna to do research that will help save their dying planet. However, an evil scheme is uncovered by the suspecting Dr. Meacham when he discovers the Metalunan's plan to take over Earth. Dr. Meacham then escapes an exploding Metalunan built Earth lab along with Dr. Adams only to be kidnapped while flying away in a small plane. A flying saucer whisks both the scientists off to Metaluna where they are held accountable for blowing up the Metalunan Earth lab during their escape. They later escape there with the help of Exeter the friendly Metalunan. Metaluna then self destructs and the Doctors make it safely back to Earth, which is saved from Metalunan invasion. Now Do You See Why I Call THIS ISLAND EARTH Horrible
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Very Funny Film, Though Only Makes Me Miss the Show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Nelson and his robot buddies are still trapped on the Satellite of Love, forced to watch bad movies for some sort of bizarre experiment to drive Nelson mad. This time, the film is "This Island Earth". This film is very funny, but there is really nothing I have to say about it. If you like the show, you will like the movie, because there is really no difference whatsoever. The budget is slightly greater, so the lobby jokes are nicer looking, but they are so minor that it hardly matters. The picture quality also seems slightly crisper. The bulk of the film has them in the theater, which would look the same no matter what. Sadly, the film does little more than make me miss the show. According to some unknown source, "The TV show's usual density of gags was reduced for theatrical audiences, so that a larger number of people laughing wouldn't cause too much dialogue to be missed." That makes sense, except when you are watching it sixteen years later on DVD. You do not need that much silence -- it then becomes almost like really watching "This Island Earth". Even more mysterious, the film comes in at a short 73 minutes, even shorter than the average episode of 90 minutes. So the movie is shorter than the TV show! And the disc has no special features (besides French language track), so the DVD is not that special -- you would be better off buying a DVD of them watching "Manos" or something, unless you really enjoyed this particular film. A good film, some funny gags, and a short run time for quick viewing... but really nothing worth making a movie about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you liked the TV show, you can't go wrong with this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joshua kit
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is just a two hour episode of the TV show, and that's why it works. It won't make you cry, but it will make you laugh. I enjoyed the TV show and found the movie had everything I enjoyed about it. The movie they watch is the much-maligned, iconic 50s sci-fi B-movie, "This Island Earth". (Which, for what it's worth, is not a terrible movie. It's silly, but compared to many of it's contemporary films, is somewhat watchable.) If you've never seen it, then this is a good way to watch it. Not a whole lot else to say. This movie won't win an Oscar, but it's a fine pastime for a Friday night at home with a few beers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Several Good Laughs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mystery Science Theatre 3000: The Movie (1996) *** (out of 4) The cult TV show made it to the big screen this one time and features Mike and his two robots being held by an evil scientist who forces them to watch THIS ISLAND EARTH. This is meant to torture the trio but the three turn the tables with their comments. I will admit right up front that I'm not one of the die hard fans who love this show more than anything else. I'm very hit and miss on it and I often find myself on message boards talking against the show because I'm one who can enjoy these bad movies without the added comments. However, every time I argue against the show it hits me that when I do watch one I find it funny and there's no question that there's talent behind the comments. Now, I will say that I found it strange that they selected THIS ISLAND EARTH for their first movie because, to be honest, it's really not a bad movie. I think had they selected a worse movie it might have led to more and better jokes but what's here is still pretty good. I thought the best moments happened whenever the trio went on with continued dialogue. One would pretend to be the voice of a character and then they would just go back and forth. I thought this is when the best jokes came out and especially the stuff dealing with the alien leader's ultra big head. Another funny jokes happens at the start when the plane is about to crash but the alien's help land it with a green flashing light. The jokes that are around this are very good. As with any comedy, there are jokes that don't work but I think for the most part the majority of them hit their target and deliver laughs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pitiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Green_Saturn
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It doesn't matter that this movie is based off a successful T.V. show. It still is painful to watch. After a confusing and messy opening monologue by some creepy professor, for whatever reason the audience discovers that this movie takes place in space. And the spaceship our "heroes" are in looks suspiciously like male genitalia. I never quite understood whether that was intentional or not. The only thing sadder than the plot of this movie is the robots. Seriously, its like whoever designed them died half way through the process. I don't know if they're from the T.V. show or something (NO, I have never seen the show), but they are just utterly awful. One is something that I think resembles a crow, and the other is just a talking gumball machine. It creeped me out. What was the point of even having the robots, or the random guy who is friends with them? (By the way, was Trace Beaulieu blackmailed into playing Mike Nelson?) The comments made about the movie these characters are watching are juvenile and distracting. At one point, one of the robots makes a sound like a car engine when a car pans on screen. Where is the humor? What am I not getting? Halfway through the movie (that the characters are watching), the filmmakers decided to spare the audience by having the film reel break. While we wait for the creepy scientist guy to fix this, our useless heroes break the Hubble telescope. This is, in fact, their biggest accomplishment of the entire movie. The movie the creepy scientist makes them watch isn't that bad. It's actually pretty interesting, if a little cheesy. You'd think if the whole point of the movie was to make fun of another movie, whoever made this would've at least picked a bad movie to make fun of. The worst part is the ending. Usually, in the last ten minutes of a movie, loose ends are tied up. Nope. Not in this. Nothing happens. One star, because at least this movie was SHORT.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I never understood why they made this movie, but it was still rather good.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aaron1375
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film features the gang of the Satellite of Love like you have never seen them before! Being told what to do by movie producers, being passed over for ad revenue in favor of Barb Wire and riffing a film that is 94 minutes long and longer than this entire film. Still, the riffing was good and the film overall funny, just not as good as some of the stuff one saw in the regular show. In this film the Satellite of Love looks like it is in space, other than that it seems there was very little need to make this movie as the producers seemed to want to make this film short as all get out, it would of been better off simply being an episode of the show. The film being parodied is "This Island Earth", a film I have not seen other than what is presented here. Usually I feel comfortable reviewing films the gang have done, but this one is so obviously cut short I will not review this one as this one is so chopped up a lot of the plot is too. I am not sure what is happening in places so until I see the full movie I will not review it. I can review this though and like I said, it is good, but I would rather they had stayed on television as this movie is shorter than anything they did on the show on Comedy Central or the Sci-Fi channel. The host segments were not as funny as the host segments on the regular show either as they seemed to want to scream at the audience, "This is a movie!" So overall, funny, just kind of pointless. Though it is one film I can watch the closing credits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its a mystery why this film was ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ryan-Pollard
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'MST3K - The Movie', I came to the conclusion that it deserved to be on 'MST3K - The Television Series' far more than 'Danger Diabolik', 'Squirm' or 'Phase 4'. Bad script, ham acting, lame jokes, poor special effects - it had the lot. It also managed to insult one of the finest science fiction films of the '50's - 'This Island Earth'. Why that particular movie? Could they not find something more suitable, such as 'Plan 9 From Outer Space'? The sad thing is that its audience will never know how good a film 'This Island Earth' is because all they have seen of it is a silly send-up. The funniest line in the whole 90 minutes was "I've farted!" and that tells you all you need to know. The 'MST3K' brigade do not seem to be aware that any idiot can laugh at an old movie, especially if it is of its time. It takes real intelligence to be able to look at 'This Island Earth' and see it for what it is, an imaginative and exciting sci-fi picture. 'MST3K' bombed on its release, and the show itself was cancelled a few years later, so one good thing came out of it at least.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In space . . . . . . . . . . . everyone can hear your screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, just wow. The popularity of this movie (and, by logical extension, I would have to say the TV show) astounds me. The concept? There is a man in space who is being tested by being shown the worst movies ever made and so he sits through them with a couple of robot buddies and makes fun of them. That's it, and to some people that's all well and good and makes for some of the funniest stuff that they've ever sat through. For me, this ends up being one of the very worst experiences I have ever had to endure in my whole life of movie-watching (and I've watched a LOT of crap, believe me). My main issue with the thing is that, to me anyway, the comments from the folk on screen are just annoying and unfunny. Okay, okay, I smirked on about two occasions but that's not a very good average for something that's supposed to be a comedy. There will be those thinking I am just a massive fan of This Island Earth (the movie being watched within the movie) and feeling all defensive about it being so insulted. Well, this was the first time I had seen This Island Earth in any form and there's no denying that it was a risible movie but the fact remains that many of my own thoughts while watching the movie would be/were funnier than those mentioned by the Mystery Science Theatregoers (who are, essentially, the annoying people sitting in the row in front of you in a cinema, thinking they are smart-assed greatness with their constant nattering and stream of lowest common denominator consciousness). Pretty much all of those involved (director Jim Mallon, stars Trace Beaulieu and Michael J. Nelson, etc) had a hand in writing this nonsense and so can all share the blame. Unfunny, irritating and just absolutely awful. It was like spending just over an hour listening to nails on a chalk board while I tried to "enjoy" a bad 50s sci-fi flick. I never ever want to see this again. Ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny as if Richard Basehart ran naked through Washington yelling "I'm Richard Basehart!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (udragon2010)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As always, the guys at MST3K make a bad movie watchable. I giggled and guffawed from the minute it started. The guys are forced to watch "This Island Earth" and riff on its stupidness. The bots are just as nutty as they are in the show and good old Mike Nelson is the glue that keeps the zaniness from getting too much. This is a great jumping on point for those who have not yet been blessed by the goodness that is Mystery Science Theater 3000. People who have complained about this movie riffing on a classic movie should repeat to themselves "its just a movie and I should really just relax." It's great for the kids, family and the dog, but not for grandpa and grandma. Watch this flick and you'll wish for movie sign for the rest of your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious even When You Watch for the Second Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The evil scientist Dr. Clayton Forrester (Trace Beaulieu) locks Mike Nelson (Michael J. Nelson) and two robots in a spacecraft to watch terrible low-budget movies as part of his scheme to conquer the world. He projects 1954 "This Island Earth" (Title (Brazil): "Guerra Entre Planetas") with the intention of driving them crazy. However, the trio laughs and makes funny comments in every scene and dialogs, having good-time instead, and Dr. Forrester's ambitious plan does not work. The first time I saw "Mystery Science Theater 3000: The Movie" on 01 February 2000 I loved it a lot and I gave a nine. I had watched the cheese "This Island Earth" a few months ago and the comments of Mike Nelson and the two robots made me laugh a lot. Today I have just watched this film again and it is still hilarious, but my rating is lower this time. "Mystery Science Theater 3000: The Movie" was released in Brazil on VHS by CIC-Universal Distributor. My vote is seven. Title (Brazil): "O Filme Mais Idiota do Mundo" ("The Most Idiot Movie of the World")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Keanu Reeves In My Own Private Airfield"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Possible Spoilers But I Can't See Any. This Is The First Time I Ever Saw A Mystery Science Theater...Well Anything. Its Where Dr. Forrester Subjects Their Last Movie On Them. "THIS ISLAND EARTH" & This Island Earth Is A Horrible Movie With Animation Techniques That'll Make A 5 Year Old Get Worried. THIS Movie On The Other Hand Is Stupid & Downright Hilarious. I Am Interested In The Series Because They Look Funny. All In All A Great Comedy Sci-Fi. The Plot To This Island Earth Is That Dr. Meacham is chosen along with others by the inhabitants of the planet Metaluna to do research that will help save their dying planet. However, an evil scheme is uncovered by the suspecting Dr. Meacham when he discovers the Metalunan's plan to take over Earth. Dr. Meacham then escapes an exploding Metalunan built Earth lab along with Dr. Adams only to be kidnapped while flying away in a small plane. A flying saucer whisks both the scientists off to Metaluna where they are held accountable for blowing up the Metalunan Earth lab during their escape. They later escape there with the help of Exeter the friendly Metalunan. Metaluna then self destructs and the Doctors make it safely back to Earth, which is saved from Metalunan invasion. Now Do You See Why I Call THIS ISLAND EARTH Horrible
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Very Funny Film, Though Only Makes Me Miss the Show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Nelson and his robot buddies are still trapped on the Satellite of Love, forced to watch bad movies for some sort of bizarre experiment to drive Nelson mad. This time, the film is "This Island Earth". This film is very funny, but there is really nothing I have to say about it. If you like the show, you will like the movie, because there is really no difference whatsoever. The budget is slightly greater, so the lobby jokes are nicer looking, but they are so minor that it hardly matters. The picture quality also seems slightly crisper. The bulk of the film has them in the theater, which would look the same no matter what. Sadly, the film does little more than make me miss the show. According to some unknown source, "The TV show's usual density of gags was reduced for theatrical audiences, so that a larger number of people laughing wouldn't cause too much dialogue to be missed." That makes sense, except when you are watching it sixteen years later on DVD. You do not need that much silence -- it then becomes almost like really watching "This Island Earth". Even more mysterious, the film comes in at a short 73 minutes, even shorter than the average episode of 90 minutes. So the movie is shorter than the TV show! And the disc has no special features (besides French language track), so the DVD is not that special -- you would be better off buying a DVD of them watching "Manos" or something, unless you really enjoyed this particular film. A good film, some funny gags, and a short run time for quick viewing... but really nothing worth making a movie about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you liked the TV show, you can't go wrong with this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joshua kit
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is just a two hour episode of the TV show, and that's why it works. It won't make you cry, but it will make you laugh. I enjoyed the TV show and found the movie had everything I enjoyed about it. The movie they watch is the much-maligned, iconic 50s sci-fi B-movie, "This Island Earth". (Which, for what it's worth, is not a terrible movie. It's silly, but compared to many of it's contemporary films, is somewhat watchable.) If you've never seen it, then this is a good way to watch it. Not a whole lot else to say. This movie won't win an Oscar, but it's a fine pastime for a Friday night at home with a few beers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Several Good Laughs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mystery Science Theatre 3000: The Movie (1996) *** (out of 4) The cult TV show made it to the big screen this one time and features Mike and his two robots being held by an evil scientist who forces them to watch THIS ISLAND EARTH. This is meant to torture the trio but the three turn the tables with their comments. I will admit right up front that I'm not one of the die hard fans who love this show more than anything else. I'm very hit and miss on it and I often find myself on message boards talking against the show because I'm one who can enjoy these bad movies without the added comments. However, every time I argue against the show it hits me that when I do watch one I find it funny and there's no question that there's talent behind the comments. Now, I will say that I found it strange that they selected THIS ISLAND EARTH for their first movie because, to be honest, it's really not a bad movie. I think had they selected a worse movie it might have led to more and better jokes but what's here is still pretty good. I thought the best moments happened whenever the trio went on with continued dialogue. One would pretend to be the voice of a character and then they would just go back and forth. I thought this is when the best jokes came out and especially the stuff dealing with the alien leader's ultra big head. Another funny jokes happens at the start when the plane is about to crash but the alien's help land it with a green flashing light. The jokes that are around this are very good. As with any comedy, there are jokes that don't work but I think for the most part the majority of them hit their target and deliver laughs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pitiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Green_Saturn
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It doesn't matter that this movie is based off a successful T.V. show. It still is painful to watch. After a confusing and messy opening monologue by some creepy professor, for whatever reason the audience discovers that this movie takes place in space. And the spaceship our "heroes" are in looks suspiciously like male genitalia. I never quite understood whether that was intentional or not. The only thing sadder than the plot of this movie is the robots. Seriously, its like whoever designed them died half way through the process. I don't know if they're from the T.V. show or something (NO, I have never seen the show), but they are just utterly awful. One is something that I think resembles a crow, and the other is just a talking gumball machine. It creeped me out. What was the point of even having the robots, or the random guy who is friends with them? (By the way, was Trace Beaulieu blackmailed into playing Mike Nelson?) The comments made about the movie these characters are watching are juvenile and distracting. At one point, one of the robots makes a sound like a car engine when a car pans on screen. Where is the humor? What am I not getting? Halfway through the movie (that the characters are watching), the filmmakers decided to spare the audience by having the film reel break. While we wait for the creepy scientist guy to fix this, our useless heroes break the Hubble telescope. This is, in fact, their biggest accomplishment of the entire movie. The movie the creepy scientist makes them watch isn't that bad. It's actually pretty interesting, if a little cheesy. You'd think if the whole point of the movie was to make fun of another movie, whoever made this would've at least picked a bad movie to make fun of. The worst part is the ending. Usually, in the last ten minutes of a movie, loose ends are tied up. Nope. Not in this. Nothing happens. One star, because at least this movie was SHORT.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I never understood why they made this movie, but it was still rather good.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aaron1375
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film features the gang of the Satellite of Love like you have never seen them before! Being told what to do by movie producers, being passed over for ad revenue in favor of Barb Wire and riffing a film that is 94 minutes long and longer than this entire film. Still, the riffing was good and the film overall funny, just not as good as some of the stuff one saw in the regular show. In this film the Satellite of Love looks like it is in space, other than that it seems there was very little need to make this movie as the producers seemed to want to make this film short as all get out, it would of been better off simply being an episode of the show. The film being parodied is "This Island Earth", a film I have not seen other than what is presented here. Usually I feel comfortable reviewing films the gang have done, but this one is so obviously cut short I will not review this one as this one is so chopped up a lot of the plot is too. I am not sure what is happening in places so until I see the full movie I will not review it. I can review this though and like I said, it is good, but I would rather they had stayed on television as this movie is shorter than anything they did on the show on Comedy Central or the Sci-Fi channel. The host segments were not as funny as the host segments on the regular show either as they seemed to want to scream at the audience, "This is a movie!" So overall, funny, just kind of pointless. Though it is one film I can watch the closing credits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its a mystery why this film was ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ryan-Pollard
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'MST3K - The Movie', I came to the conclusion that it deserved to be on 'MST3K - The Television Series' far more than 'Danger Diabolik', 'Squirm' or 'Phase 4'. Bad script, ham acting, lame jokes, poor special effects - it had the lot. It also managed to insult one of the finest science fiction films of the '50's - 'This Island Earth'. Why that particular movie? Could they not find something more suitable, such as 'Plan 9 From Outer Space'? The sad thing is that its audience will never know how good a film 'This Island Earth' is because all they have seen of it is a silly send-up. The funniest line in the whole 90 minutes was "I've farted!" and that tells you all you need to know. The 'MST3K' brigade do not seem to be aware that any idiot can laugh at an old movie, especially if it is of its time. It takes real intelligence to be able to look at 'This Island Earth' and see it for what it is, an imaginative and exciting sci-fi picture. 'MST3K' bombed on its release, and the show itself was cancelled a few years later, so one good thing came out of it at least.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In space . . . . . . . . . . . everyone can hear your screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, just wow. The popularity of this movie (and, by logical extension, I would have to say the TV show) astounds me. The concept? There is a man in space who is being tested by being shown the worst movies ever made and so he sits through them with a couple of robot buddies and makes fun of them. That's it, and to some people that's all well and good and makes for some of the funniest stuff that they've ever sat through. For me, this ends up being one of the very worst experiences I have ever had to endure in my whole life of movie-watching (and I've watched a LOT of crap, believe me). My main issue with the thing is that, to me anyway, the comments from the folk on screen are just annoying and unfunny. Okay, okay, I smirked on about two occasions but that's not a very good average for something that's supposed to be a comedy. There will be those thinking I am just a massive fan of This Island Earth (the movie being watched within the movie) and feeling all defensive about it being so insulted. Well, this was the first time I had seen This Island Earth in any form and there's no denying that it was a risible movie but the fact remains that many of my own thoughts while watching the movie would be/were funnier than those mentioned by the Mystery Science Theatregoers (who are, essentially, the annoying people sitting in the row in front of you in a cinema, thinking they are smart-assed greatness with their constant nattering and stream of lowest common denominator consciousness). Pretty much all of those involved (director Jim Mallon, stars Trace Beaulieu and Michael J. Nelson, etc) had a hand in writing this nonsense and so can all share the blame. Unfunny, irritating and just absolutely awful. It was like spending just over an hour listening to nails on a chalk board while I tried to "enjoy" a bad 50s sci-fi flick. I never ever want to see this again. Ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny as if Richard Basehart ran naked through Washington yelling "I'm Richard Basehart!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (udragon2010)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As always, the guys at MST3K make a bad movie watchable. I giggled and guffawed from the minute it started. The guys are forced to watch "This Island Earth" and riff on its stupidness. The bots are just as nutty as they are in the show and good old Mike Nelson is the glue that keeps the zaniness from getting too much. This is a great jumping on point for those who have not yet been blessed by the goodness that is Mystery Science Theater 3000. People who have complained about this movie riffing on a classic movie should repeat to themselves "its just a movie and I should really just relax." It's great for the kids, family and the dog, but not for grandpa and grandma. Watch this flick and you'll wish for movie sign for the rest of your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious even When You Watch for the Second Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The evil scientist Dr. Clayton Forrester (Trace Beaulieu) locks Mike Nelson (Michael J. Nelson) and two robots in a spacecraft to watch terrible low-budget movies as part of his scheme to conquer the world. He projects 1954 "This Island Earth" (Title (Brazil): "Guerra Entre Planetas") with the intention of driving them crazy. However, the trio laughs and makes funny comments in every scene and dialogs, having good-time instead, and Dr. Forrester's ambitious plan does not work. The first time I saw "Mystery Science Theater 3000: The Movie" on 01 February 2000 I loved it a lot and I gave a nine. I had watched the cheese "This Island Earth" a few months ago and the comments of Mike Nelson and the two robots made me laugh a lot. Today I have just watched this film again and it is still hilarious, but my rating is lower this time. "Mystery Science Theater 3000: The Movie" was released in Brazil on VHS by CIC-Universal Distributor. My vote is seven. Title (Brazil): "O Filme Mais Idiota do Mundo" ("The Most Idiot Movie of the World")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Keanu Reeves In My Own Private Airfield"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Possible Spoilers But I Can't See Any. This Is The First Time I Ever Saw A Mystery Science Theater...Well Anything. Its Where Dr. Forrester Subjects Their Last Movie On Them. "THIS ISLAND EARTH" & This Island Earth Is A Horrible Movie With Animation Techniques That'll Make A 5 Year Old Get Worried. THIS Movie On The Other Hand Is Stupid & Downright Hilarious. I Am Interested In The Series Because They Look Funny. All In All A Great Comedy Sci-Fi. The Plot To This Island Earth Is That Dr. Meacham is chosen along with others by the inhabitants of the planet Metaluna to do research that will help save their dying planet. However, an evil scheme is uncovered by the suspecting Dr. Meacham when he discovers the Metalunan's plan to take over Earth. Dr. Meacham then escapes an exploding Metalunan built Earth lab along with Dr. Adams only to be kidnapped while flying away in a small plane. A flying saucer whisks both the scientists off to Metaluna where they are held accountable for blowing up the Metalunan Earth lab during their escape. They later escape there with the help of Exeter the friendly Metalunan. Metaluna then self destructs and the Doctors make it safely back to Earth, which is saved from Metalunan invasion. Now Do You See Why I Call THIS ISLAND EARTH Horrible
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Very Funny Film, Though Only Makes Me Miss the Show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Nelson and his robot buddies are still trapped on the Satellite of Love, forced to watch bad movies for some sort of bizarre experiment to drive Nelson mad. This time, the film is "This Island Earth". This film is very funny, but there is really nothing I have to say about it. If you like the show, you will like the movie, because there is really no difference whatsoever. The budget is slightly greater, so the lobby jokes are nicer looking, but they are so minor that it hardly matters. The picture quality also seems slightly crisper. The bulk of the film has them in the theater, which would look the same no matter what. Sadly, the film does little more than make me miss the show. According to some unknown source, "The TV show's usual density of gags was reduced for theatrical audiences, so that a larger number of people laughing wouldn't cause too much dialogue to be missed." That makes sense, except when you are watching it sixteen years later on DVD. You do not need that much silence -- it then becomes almost like really watching "This Island Earth". Even more mysterious, the film comes in at a short 73 minutes, even shorter than the average episode of 90 minutes. So the movie is shorter than the TV show! And the disc has no special features (besides French language track), so the DVD is not that special -- you would be better off buying a DVD of them watching "Manos" or something, unless you really enjoyed this particular film. A good film, some funny gags, and a short run time for quick viewing... but really nothing worth making a movie about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you liked the TV show, you can't go wrong with this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joshua kit
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is just a two hour episode of the TV show, and that's why it works. It won't make you cry, but it will make you laugh. I enjoyed the TV show and found the movie had everything I enjoyed about it. The movie they watch is the much-maligned, iconic 50s sci-fi B-movie, "This Island Earth". (Which, for what it's worth, is not a terrible movie. It's silly, but compared to many of it's contemporary films, is somewhat watchable.) If you've never seen it, then this is a good way to watch it. Not a whole lot else to say. This movie won't win an Oscar, but it's a fine pastime for a Friday night at home with a few beers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Several Good Laughs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mystery Science Theatre 3000: The Movie (1996) *** (out of 4) The cult TV show made it to the big screen this one time and features Mike and his two robots being held by an evil scientist who forces them to watch THIS ISLAND EARTH. This is meant to torture the trio but the three turn the tables with their comments. I will admit right up front that I'm not one of the die hard fans who love this show more than anything else. I'm very hit and miss on it and I often find myself on message boards talking against the show because I'm one who can enjoy these bad movies without the added comments. However, every time I argue against the show it hits me that when I do watch one I find it funny and there's no question that there's talent behind the comments. Now, I will say that I found it strange that they selected THIS ISLAND EARTH for their first movie because, to be honest, it's really not a bad movie. I think had they selected a worse movie it might have led to more and better jokes but what's here is still pretty good. I thought the best moments happened whenever the trio went on with continued dialogue. One would pretend to be the voice of a character and then they would just go back and forth. I thought this is when the best jokes came out and especially the stuff dealing with the alien leader's ultra big head. Another funny jokes happens at the start when the plane is about to crash but the alien's help land it with a green flashing light. The jokes that are around this are very good. As with any comedy, there are jokes that don't work but I think for the most part the majority of them hit their target and deliver laughs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pitiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Green_Saturn
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It doesn't matter that this movie is based off a successful T.V. show. It still is painful to watch. After a confusing and messy opening monologue by some creepy professor, for whatever reason the audience discovers that this movie takes place in space. And the spaceship our "heroes" are in looks suspiciously like male genitalia. I never quite understood whether that was intentional or not. The only thing sadder than the plot of this movie is the robots. Seriously, its like whoever designed them died half way through the process. I don't know if they're from the T.V. show or something (NO, I have never seen the show), but they are just utterly awful. One is something that I think resembles a crow, and the other is just a talking gumball machine. It creeped me out. What was the point of even having the robots, or the random guy who is friends with them? (By the way, was Trace Beaulieu blackmailed into playing Mike Nelson?) The comments made about the movie these characters are watching are juvenile and distracting. At one point, one of the robots makes a sound like a car engine when a car pans on screen. Where is the humor? What am I not getting? Halfway through the movie (that the characters are watching), the filmmakers decided to spare the audience by having the film reel break. While we wait for the creepy scientist guy to fix this, our useless heroes break the Hubble telescope. This is, in fact, their biggest accomplishment of the entire movie. The movie the creepy scientist makes them watch isn't that bad. It's actually pretty interesting, if a little cheesy. You'd think if the whole point of the movie was to make fun of another movie, whoever made this would've at least picked a bad movie to make fun of. The worst part is the ending. Usually, in the last ten minutes of a movie, loose ends are tied up. Nope. Not in this. Nothing happens. One star, because at least this movie was SHORT.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I never understood why they made this movie, but it was still rather good.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aaron1375
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film features the gang of the Satellite of Love like you have never seen them before! Being told what to do by movie producers, being passed over for ad revenue in favor of Barb Wire and riffing a film that is 94 minutes long and longer than this entire film. Still, the riffing was good and the film overall funny, just not as good as some of the stuff one saw in the regular show. In this film the Satellite of Love looks like it is in space, other than that it seems there was very little need to make this movie as the producers seemed to want to make this film short as all get out, it would of been better off simply being an episode of the show. The film being parodied is "This Island Earth", a film I have not seen other than what is presented here. Usually I feel comfortable reviewing films the gang have done, but this one is so obviously cut short I will not review this one as this one is so chopped up a lot of the plot is too. I am not sure what is happening in places so until I see the full movie I will not review it. I can review this though and like I said, it is good, but I would rather they had stayed on television as this movie is shorter than anything they did on the show on Comedy Central or the Sci-Fi channel. The host segments were not as funny as the host segments on the regular show either as they seemed to want to scream at the audience, "This is a movie!" So overall, funny, just kind of pointless. Though it is one film I can watch the closing credits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its a mystery why this film was ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ryan-Pollard
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'MST3K - The Movie', I came to the conclusion that it deserved to be on 'MST3K - The Television Series' far more than 'Danger Diabolik', 'Squirm' or 'Phase 4'. Bad script, ham acting, lame jokes, poor special effects - it had the lot. It also managed to insult one of the finest science fiction films of the '50's - 'This Island Earth'. Why that particular movie? Could they not find something more suitable, such as 'Plan 9 From Outer Space'? The sad thing is that its audience will never know how good a film 'This Island Earth' is because all they have seen of it is a silly send-up. The funniest line in the whole 90 minutes was "I've farted!" and that tells you all you need to know. The 'MST3K' brigade do not seem to be aware that any idiot can laugh at an old movie, especially if it is of its time. It takes real intelligence to be able to look at 'This Island Earth' and see it for what it is, an imaginative and exciting sci-fi picture. 'MST3K' bombed on its release, and the show itself was cancelled a few years later, so one good thing came out of it at least.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In space . . . . . . . . . . . everyone can hear your screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, just wow. The popularity of this movie (and, by logical extension, I would have to say the TV show) astounds me. The concept? There is a man in space who is being tested by being shown the worst movies ever made and so he sits through them with a couple of robot buddies and makes fun of them. That's it, and to some people that's all well and good and makes for some of the funniest stuff that they've ever sat through. For me, this ends up being one of the very worst experiences I have ever had to endure in my whole life of movie-watching (and I've watched a LOT of crap, believe me). My main issue with the thing is that, to me anyway, the comments from the folk on screen are just annoying and unfunny. Okay, okay, I smirked on about two occasions but that's not a very good average for something that's supposed to be a comedy. There will be those thinking I am just a massive fan of This Island Earth (the movie being watched within the movie) and feeling all defensive about it being so insulted. Well, this was the first time I had seen This Island Earth in any form and there's no denying that it was a risible movie but the fact remains that many of my own thoughts while watching the movie would be/were funnier than those mentioned by the Mystery Science Theatregoers (who are, essentially, the annoying people sitting in the row in front of you in a cinema, thinking they are smart-assed greatness with their constant nattering and stream of lowest common denominator consciousness). Pretty much all of those involved (director Jim Mallon, stars Trace Beaulieu and Michael J. Nelson, etc) had a hand in writing this nonsense and so can all share the blame. Unfunny, irritating and just absolutely awful. It was like spending just over an hour listening to nails on a chalk board while I tried to "enjoy" a bad 50s sci-fi flick. I never ever want to see this again. Ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny as if Richard Basehart ran naked through Washington yelling "I'm Richard Basehart!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (udragon2010)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As always, the guys at MST3K make a bad movie watchable. I giggled and guffawed from the minute it started. The guys are forced to watch "This Island Earth" and riff on its stupidness. The bots are just as nutty as they are in the show and good old Mike Nelson is the glue that keeps the zaniness from getting too much. This is a great jumping on point for those who have not yet been blessed by the goodness that is Mystery Science Theater 3000. People who have complained about this movie riffing on a classic movie should repeat to themselves "its just a movie and I should really just relax." It's great for the kids, family and the dog, but not for grandpa and grandma. Watch this flick and you'll wish for movie sign for the rest of your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious even When You Watch for the Second Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The evil scientist Dr. Clayton Forrester (Trace Beaulieu) locks Mike Nelson (Michael J. Nelson) and two robots in a spacecraft to watch terrible low-budget movies as part of his scheme to conquer the world. He projects 1954 "This Island Earth" (Title (Brazil): "Guerra Entre Planetas") with the intention of driving them crazy. However, the trio laughs and makes funny comments in every scene and dialogs, having good-time instead, and Dr. Forrester's ambitious plan does not work. The first time I saw "Mystery Science Theater 3000: The Movie" on 01 February 2000 I loved it a lot and I gave a nine. I had watched the cheese "This Island Earth" a few months ago and the comments of Mike Nelson and the two robots made me laugh a lot. Today I have just watched this film again and it is still hilarious, but my rating is lower this time. "Mystery Science Theater 3000: The Movie" was released in Brazil on VHS by CIC-Universal Distributor. My vote is seven. Title (Brazil): "O Filme Mais Idiota do Mundo" ("The Most Idiot Movie of the World")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Keanu Reeves In My Own Private Airfield"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Possible Spoilers But I Can't See Any. This Is The First Time I Ever Saw A Mystery Science Theater...Well Anything. Its Where Dr. Forrester Subjects Their Last Movie On Them. "THIS ISLAND EARTH" & This Island Earth Is A Horrible Movie With Animation Techniques That'll Make A 5 Year Old Get Worried. THIS Movie On The Other Hand Is Stupid & Downright Hilarious. I Am Interested In The Series Because They Look Funny. All In All A Great Comedy Sci-Fi. The Plot To This Island Earth Is That Dr. Meacham is chosen along with others by the inhabitants of the planet Metaluna to do research that will help save their dying planet. However, an evil scheme is uncovered by the suspecting Dr. Meacham when he discovers the Metalunan's plan to take over Earth. Dr. Meacham then escapes an exploding Metalunan built Earth lab along with Dr. Adams only to be kidnapped while flying away in a small plane. A flying saucer whisks both the scientists off to Metaluna where they are held accountable for blowing up the Metalunan Earth lab during their escape. They later escape there with the help of Exeter the friendly Metalunan. Metaluna then self destructs and the Doctors make it safely back to Earth, which is saved from Metalunan invasion. Now Do You See Why I Call THIS ISLAND EARTH Horrible
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Very Funny Film, Though Only Makes Me Miss the Show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Nelson and his robot buddies are still trapped on the Satellite of Love, forced to watch bad movies for some sort of bizarre experiment to drive Nelson mad. This time, the film is "This Island Earth". This film is very funny, but there is really nothing I have to say about it. If you like the show, you will like the movie, because there is really no difference whatsoever. The budget is slightly greater, so the lobby jokes are nicer looking, but they are so minor that it hardly matters. The picture quality also seems slightly crisper. The bulk of the film has them in the theater, which would look the same no matter what. Sadly, the film does little more than make me miss the show. According to some unknown source, "The TV show's usual density of gags was reduced for theatrical audiences, so that a larger number of people laughing wouldn't cause too much dialogue to be missed." That makes sense, except when you are watching it sixteen years later on DVD. You do not need that much silence -- it then becomes almost like really watching "This Island Earth". Even more mysterious, the film comes in at a short 73 minutes, even shorter than the average episode of 90 minutes. So the movie is shorter than the TV show! And the disc has no special features (besides French language track), so the DVD is not that special -- you would be better off buying a DVD of them watching "Manos" or something, unless you really enjoyed this particular film. A good film, some funny gags, and a short run time for quick viewing... but really nothing worth making a movie about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you liked the TV show, you can't go wrong with this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joshua kit
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is just a two hour episode of the TV show, and that's why it works. It won't make you cry, but it will make you laugh. I enjoyed the TV show and found the movie had everything I enjoyed about it. The movie they watch is the much-maligned, iconic 50s sci-fi B-movie, "This Island Earth". (Which, for what it's worth, is not a terrible movie. It's silly, but compared to many of it's contemporary films, is somewhat watchable.) If you've never seen it, then this is a good way to watch it. Not a whole lot else to say. This movie won't win an Oscar, but it's a fine pastime for a Friday night at home with a few beers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Several Good Laughs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mystery Science Theatre 3000: The Movie (1996) *** (out of 4) The cult TV show made it to the big screen this one time and features Mike and his two robots being held by an evil scientist who forces them to watch THIS ISLAND EARTH. This is meant to torture the trio but the three turn the tables with their comments. I will admit right up front that I'm not one of the die hard fans who love this show more than anything else. I'm very hit and miss on it and I often find myself on message boards talking against the show because I'm one who can enjoy these bad movies without the added comments. However, every time I argue against the show it hits me that when I do watch one I find it funny and there's no question that there's talent behind the comments. Now, I will say that I found it strange that they selected THIS ISLAND EARTH for their first movie because, to be honest, it's really not a bad movie. I think had they selected a worse movie it might have led to more and better jokes but what's here is still pretty good. I thought the best moments happened whenever the trio went on with continued dialogue. One would pretend to be the voice of a character and then they would just go back and forth. I thought this is when the best jokes came out and especially the stuff dealing with the alien leader's ultra big head. Another funny jokes happens at the start when the plane is about to crash but the alien's help land it with a green flashing light. The jokes that are around this are very good. As with any comedy, there are jokes that don't work but I think for the most part the majority of them hit their target and deliver laughs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pitiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Green_Saturn
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It doesn't matter that this movie is based off a successful T.V. show. It still is painful to watch. After a confusing and messy opening monologue by some creepy professor, for whatever reason the audience discovers that this movie takes place in space. And the spaceship our "heroes" are in looks suspiciously like male genitalia. I never quite understood whether that was intentional or not. The only thing sadder than the plot of this movie is the robots. Seriously, its like whoever designed them died half way through the process. I don't know if they're from the T.V. show or something (NO, I have never seen the show), but they are just utterly awful. One is something that I think resembles a crow, and the other is just a talking gumball machine. It creeped me out. What was the point of even having the robots, or the random guy who is friends with them? (By the way, was Trace Beaulieu blackmailed into playing Mike Nelson?) The comments made about the movie these characters are watching are juvenile and distracting. At one point, one of the robots makes a sound like a car engine when a car pans on screen. Where is the humor? What am I not getting? Halfway through the movie (that the characters are watching), the filmmakers decided to spare the audience by having the film reel break. While we wait for the creepy scientist guy to fix this, our useless heroes break the Hubble telescope. This is, in fact, their biggest accomplishment of the entire movie. The movie the creepy scientist makes them watch isn't that bad. It's actually pretty interesting, if a little cheesy. You'd think if the whole point of the movie was to make fun of another movie, whoever made this would've at least picked a bad movie to make fun of. The worst part is the ending. Usually, in the last ten minutes of a movie, loose ends are tied up. Nope. Not in this. Nothing happens. One star, because at least this movie was SHORT.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I never understood why they made this movie, but it was still rather good.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aaron1375
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film features the gang of the Satellite of Love like you have never seen them before! Being told what to do by movie producers, being passed over for ad revenue in favor of Barb Wire and riffing a film that is 94 minutes long and longer than this entire film. Still, the riffing was good and the film overall funny, just not as good as some of the stuff one saw in the regular show. In this film the Satellite of Love looks like it is in space, other than that it seems there was very little need to make this movie as the producers seemed to want to make this film short as all get out, it would of been better off simply being an episode of the show. The film being parodied is "This Island Earth", a film I have not seen other than what is presented here. Usually I feel comfortable reviewing films the gang have done, but this one is so obviously cut short I will not review this one as this one is so chopped up a lot of the plot is too. I am not sure what is happening in places so until I see the full movie I will not review it. I can review this though and like I said, it is good, but I would rather they had stayed on television as this movie is shorter than anything they did on the show on Comedy Central or the Sci-Fi channel. The host segments were not as funny as the host segments on the regular show either as they seemed to want to scream at the audience, "This is a movie!" So overall, funny, just kind of pointless. Though it is one film I can watch the closing credits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its a mystery why this film was ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ryan-Pollard
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'MST3K - The Movie', I came to the conclusion that it deserved to be on 'MST3K - The Television Series' far more than 'Danger Diabolik', 'Squirm' or 'Phase 4'. Bad script, ham acting, lame jokes, poor special effects - it had the lot. It also managed to insult one of the finest science fiction films of the '50's - 'This Island Earth'. Why that particular movie? Could they not find something more suitable, such as 'Plan 9 From Outer Space'? The sad thing is that its audience will never know how good a film 'This Island Earth' is because all they have seen of it is a silly send-up. The funniest line in the whole 90 minutes was "I've farted!" and that tells you all you need to know. The 'MST3K' brigade do not seem to be aware that any idiot can laugh at an old movie, especially if it is of its time. It takes real intelligence to be able to look at 'This Island Earth' and see it for what it is, an imaginative and exciting sci-fi picture. 'MST3K' bombed on its release, and the show itself was cancelled a few years later, so one good thing came out of it at least.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In space . . . . . . . . . . . everyone can hear your screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, just wow. The popularity of this movie (and, by logical extension, I would have to say the TV show) astounds me. The concept? There is a man in space who is being tested by being shown the worst movies ever made and so he sits through them with a couple of robot buddies and makes fun of them. That's it, and to some people that's all well and good and makes for some of the funniest stuff that they've ever sat through. For me, this ends up being one of the very worst experiences I have ever had to endure in my whole life of movie-watching (and I've watched a LOT of crap, believe me). My main issue with the thing is that, to me anyway, the comments from the folk on screen are just annoying and unfunny. Okay, okay, I smirked on about two occasions but that's not a very good average for something that's supposed to be a comedy. There will be those thinking I am just a massive fan of This Island Earth (the movie being watched within the movie) and feeling all defensive about it being so insulted. Well, this was the first time I had seen This Island Earth in any form and there's no denying that it was a risible movie but the fact remains that many of my own thoughts while watching the movie would be/were funnier than those mentioned by the Mystery Science Theatregoers (who are, essentially, the annoying people sitting in the row in front of you in a cinema, thinking they are smart-assed greatness with their constant nattering and stream of lowest common denominator consciousness). Pretty much all of those involved (director Jim Mallon, stars Trace Beaulieu and Michael J. Nelson, etc) had a hand in writing this nonsense and so can all share the blame. Unfunny, irritating and just absolutely awful. It was like spending just over an hour listening to nails on a chalk board while I tried to "enjoy" a bad 50s sci-fi flick. I never ever want to see this again. Ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny as if Richard Basehart ran naked through Washington yelling "I'm Richard Basehart!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (udragon2010)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As always, the guys at MST3K make a bad movie watchable. I giggled and guffawed from the minute it started. The guys are forced to watch "This Island Earth" and riff on its stupidness. The bots are just as nutty as they are in the show and good old Mike Nelson is the glue that keeps the zaniness from getting too much. This is a great jumping on point for those who have not yet been blessed by the goodness that is Mystery Science Theater 3000. People who have complained about this movie riffing on a classic movie should repeat to themselves "its just a movie and I should really just relax." It's great for the kids, family and the dog, but not for grandpa and grandma. Watch this flick and you'll wish for movie sign for the rest of your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious even When You Watch for the Second Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The evil scientist Dr. Clayton Forrester (Trace Beaulieu) locks Mike Nelson (Michael J. Nelson) and two robots in a spacecraft to watch terrible low-budget movies as part of his scheme to conquer the world. He projects 1954 "This Island Earth" (Title (Brazil): "Guerra Entre Planetas") with the intention of driving them crazy. However, the trio laughs and makes funny comments in every scene and dialogs, having good-time instead, and Dr. Forrester's ambitious plan does not work. The first time I saw "Mystery Science Theater 3000: The Movie" on 01 February 2000 I loved it a lot and I gave a nine. I had watched the cheese "This Island Earth" a few months ago and the comments of Mike Nelson and the two robots made me laugh a lot. Today I have just watched this film again and it is still hilarious, but my rating is lower this time. "Mystery Science Theater 3000: The Movie" was released in Brazil on VHS by CIC-Universal Distributor. My vote is seven. Title (Brazil): "O Filme Mais Idiota do Mundo" ("The Most Idiot Movie of the World")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Keanu Reeves In My Own Private Airfield"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Possible Spoilers But I Can't See Any. This Is The First Time I Ever Saw A Mystery Science Theater...Well Anything. Its Where Dr. Forrester Subjects Their Last Movie On Them. "THIS ISLAND EARTH" & This Island Earth Is A Horrible Movie With Animation Techniques That'll Make A 5 Year Old Get Worried. THIS Movie On The Other Hand Is Stupid & Downright Hilarious. I Am Interested In The Series Because They Look Funny. All In All A Great Comedy Sci-Fi. The Plot To This Island Earth Is That Dr. Meacham is chosen along with others by the inhabitants of the planet Metaluna to do research that will help save their dying planet. However, an evil scheme is uncovered by the suspecting Dr. Meacham when he discovers the Metalunan's plan to take over Earth. Dr. Meacham then escapes an exploding Metalunan built Earth lab along with Dr. Adams only to be kidnapped while flying away in a small plane. A flying saucer whisks both the scientists off to Metaluna where they are held accountable for blowing up the Metalunan Earth lab during their escape. They later escape there with the help of Exeter the friendly Metalunan. Metaluna then self destructs and the Doctors make it safely back to Earth, which is saved from Metalunan invasion. Now Do You See Why I Call THIS ISLAND EARTH Horrible
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Very Funny Film, Though Only Makes Me Miss the Show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Nelson and his robot buddies are still trapped on the Satellite of Love, forced to watch bad movies for some sort of bizarre experiment to drive Nelson mad. This time, the film is "This Island Earth". This film is very funny, but there is really nothing I have to say about it. If you like the show, you will like the movie, because there is really no difference whatsoever. The budget is slightly greater, so the lobby jokes are nicer looking, but they are so minor that it hardly matters. The picture quality also seems slightly crisper. The bulk of the film has them in the theater, which would look the same no matter what. Sadly, the film does little more than make me miss the show. According to some unknown source, "The TV show's usual density of gags was reduced for theatrical audiences, so that a larger number of people laughing wouldn't cause too much dialogue to be missed." That makes sense, except when you are watching it sixteen years later on DVD. You do not need that much silence -- it then becomes almost like really watching "This Island Earth". Even more mysterious, the film comes in at a short 73 minutes, even shorter than the average episode of 90 minutes. So the movie is shorter than the TV show! And the disc has no special features (besides French language track), so the DVD is not that special -- you would be better off buying a DVD of them watching "Manos" or something, unless you really enjoyed this particular film. A good film, some funny gags, and a short run time for quick viewing... but really nothing worth making a movie about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you liked the TV show, you can't go wrong with this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joshua kit
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is just a two hour episode of the TV show, and that's why it works. It won't make you cry, but it will make you laugh. I enjoyed the TV show and found the movie had everything I enjoyed about it. The movie they watch is the much-maligned, iconic 50s sci-fi B-movie, "This Island Earth". (Which, for what it's worth, is not a terrible movie. It's silly, but compared to many of it's contemporary films, is somewhat watchable.) If you've never seen it, then this is a good way to watch it. Not a whole lot else to say. This movie won't win an Oscar, but it's a fine pastime for a Friday night at home with a few beers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Several Good Laughs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mystery Science Theatre 3000: The Movie (1996) *** (out of 4) The cult TV show made it to the big screen this one time and features Mike and his two robots being held by an evil scientist who forces them to watch THIS ISLAND EARTH. This is meant to torture the trio but the three turn the tables with their comments. I will admit right up front that I'm not one of the die hard fans who love this show more than anything else. I'm very hit and miss on it and I often find myself on message boards talking against the show because I'm one who can enjoy these bad movies without the added comments. However, every time I argue against the show it hits me that when I do watch one I find it funny and there's no question that there's talent behind the comments. Now, I will say that I found it strange that they selected THIS ISLAND EARTH for their first movie because, to be honest, it's really not a bad movie. I think had they selected a worse movie it might have led to more and better jokes but what's here is still pretty good. I thought the best moments happened whenever the trio went on with continued dialogue. One would pretend to be the voice of a character and then they would just go back and forth. I thought this is when the best jokes came out and especially the stuff dealing with the alien leader's ultra big head. Another funny jokes happens at the start when the plane is about to crash but the alien's help land it with a green flashing light. The jokes that are around this are very good. As with any comedy, there are jokes that don't work but I think for the most part the majority of them hit their target and deliver laughs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pitiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Green_Saturn
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It doesn't matter that this movie is based off a successful T.V. show. It still is painful to watch. After a confusing and messy opening monologue by some creepy professor, for whatever reason the audience discovers that this movie takes place in space. And the spaceship our "heroes" are in looks suspiciously like male genitalia. I never quite understood whether that was intentional or not. The only thing sadder than the plot of this movie is the robots. Seriously, its like whoever designed them died half way through the process. I don't know if they're from the T.V. show or something (NO, I have never seen the show), but they are just utterly awful. One is something that I think resembles a crow, and the other is just a talking gumball machine. It creeped me out. What was the point of even having the robots, or the random guy who is friends with them? (By the way, was Trace Beaulieu blackmailed into playing Mike Nelson?) The comments made about the movie these characters are watching are juvenile and distracting. At one point, one of the robots makes a sound like a car engine when a car pans on screen. Where is the humor? What am I not getting? Halfway through the movie (that the characters are watching), the filmmakers decided to spare the audience by having the film reel break. While we wait for the creepy scientist guy to fix this, our useless heroes break the Hubble telescope. This is, in fact, their biggest accomplishment of the entire movie. The movie the creepy scientist makes them watch isn't that bad. It's actually pretty interesting, if a little cheesy. You'd think if the whole point of the movie was to make fun of another movie, whoever made this would've at least picked a bad movie to make fun of. The worst part is the ending. Usually, in the last ten minutes of a movie, loose ends are tied up. Nope. Not in this. Nothing happens. One star, because at least this movie was SHORT.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I never understood why they made this movie, but it was still rather good.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aaron1375
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film features the gang of the Satellite of Love like you have never seen them before! Being told what to do by movie producers, being passed over for ad revenue in favor of Barb Wire and riffing a film that is 94 minutes long and longer than this entire film. Still, the riffing was good and the film overall funny, just not as good as some of the stuff one saw in the regular show. In this film the Satellite of Love looks like it is in space, other than that it seems there was very little need to make this movie as the producers seemed to want to make this film short as all get out, it would of been better off simply being an episode of the show. The film being parodied is "This Island Earth", a film I have not seen other than what is presented here. Usually I feel comfortable reviewing films the gang have done, but this one is so obviously cut short I will not review this one as this one is so chopped up a lot of the plot is too. I am not sure what is happening in places so until I see the full movie I will not review it. I can review this though and like I said, it is good, but I would rather they had stayed on television as this movie is shorter than anything they did on the show on Comedy Central or the Sci-Fi channel. The host segments were not as funny as the host segments on the regular show either as they seemed to want to scream at the audience, "This is a movie!" So overall, funny, just kind of pointless. Though it is one film I can watch the closing credits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its a mystery why this film was ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ryan-Pollard
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'MST3K - The Movie', I came to the conclusion that it deserved to be on 'MST3K - The Television Series' far more than 'Danger Diabolik', 'Squirm' or 'Phase 4'. Bad script, ham acting, lame jokes, poor special effects - it had the lot. It also managed to insult one of the finest science fiction films of the '50's - 'This Island Earth'. Why that particular movie? Could they not find something more suitable, such as 'Plan 9 From Outer Space'? The sad thing is that its audience will never know how good a film 'This Island Earth' is because all they have seen of it is a silly send-up. The funniest line in the whole 90 minutes was "I've farted!" and that tells you all you need to know. The 'MST3K' brigade do not seem to be aware that any idiot can laugh at an old movie, especially if it is of its time. It takes real intelligence to be able to look at 'This Island Earth' and see it for what it is, an imaginative and exciting sci-fi picture. 'MST3K' bombed on its release, and the show itself was cancelled a few years later, so one good thing came out of it at least.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In space . . . . . . . . . . . everyone can hear your screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, just wow. The popularity of this movie (and, by logical extension, I would have to say the TV show) astounds me. The concept? There is a man in space who is being tested by being shown the worst movies ever made and so he sits through them with a couple of robot buddies and makes fun of them. That's it, and to some people that's all well and good and makes for some of the funniest stuff that they've ever sat through. For me, this ends up being one of the very worst experiences I have ever had to endure in my whole life of movie-watching (and I've watched a LOT of crap, believe me). My main issue with the thing is that, to me anyway, the comments from the folk on screen are just annoying and unfunny. Okay, okay, I smirked on about two occasions but that's not a very good average for something that's supposed to be a comedy. There will be those thinking I am just a massive fan of This Island Earth (the movie being watched within the movie) and feeling all defensive about it being so insulted. Well, this was the first time I had seen This Island Earth in any form and there's no denying that it was a risible movie but the fact remains that many of my own thoughts while watching the movie would be/were funnier than those mentioned by the Mystery Science Theatregoers (who are, essentially, the annoying people sitting in the row in front of you in a cinema, thinking they are smart-assed greatness with their constant nattering and stream of lowest common denominator consciousness). Pretty much all of those involved (director Jim Mallon, stars Trace Beaulieu and Michael J. Nelson, etc) had a hand in writing this nonsense and so can all share the blame. Unfunny, irritating and just absolutely awful. It was like spending just over an hour listening to nails on a chalk board while I tried to "enjoy" a bad 50s sci-fi flick. I never ever want to see this again. Ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny as if Richard Basehart ran naked through Washington yelling "I'm Richard Basehart!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (udragon2010)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As always, the guys at MST3K make a bad movie watchable. I giggled and guffawed from the minute it started. The guys are forced to watch "This Island Earth" and riff on its stupidness. The bots are just as nutty as they are in the show and good old Mike Nelson is the glue that keeps the zaniness from getting too much. This is a great jumping on point for those who have not yet been blessed by the goodness that is Mystery Science Theater 3000. People who have complained about this movie riffing on a classic movie should repeat to themselves "its just a movie and I should really just relax." It's great for the kids, family and the dog, but not for grandpa and grandma. Watch this flick and you'll wish for movie sign for the rest of your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious even When You Watch for the Second Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The evil scientist Dr. Clayton Forrester (Trace Beaulieu) locks Mike Nelson (Michael J. Nelson) and two robots in a spacecraft to watch terrible low-budget movies as part of his scheme to conquer the world. He projects 1954 "This Island Earth" (Title (Brazil): "Guerra Entre Planetas") with the intention of driving them crazy. However, the trio laughs and makes funny comments in every scene and dialogs, having good-time instead, and Dr. Forrester's ambitious plan does not work. The first time I saw "Mystery Science Theater 3000: The Movie" on 01 February 2000 I loved it a lot and I gave a nine. I had watched the cheese "This Island Earth" a few months ago and the comments of Mike Nelson and the two robots made me laugh a lot. Today I have just watched this film again and it is still hilarious, but my rating is lower this time. "Mystery Science Theater 3000: The Movie" was released in Brazil on VHS by CIC-Universal Distributor. My vote is seven. Title (Brazil): "O Filme Mais Idiota do Mundo" ("The Most Idiot Movie of the World")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Keanu Reeves In My Own Private Airfield"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Possible Spoilers But I Can't See Any. This Is The First Time I Ever Saw A Mystery Science Theater...Well Anything. Its Where Dr. Forrester Subjects Their Last Movie On Them. "THIS ISLAND EARTH" & This Island Earth Is A Horrible Movie With Animation Techniques That'll Make A 5 Year Old Get Worried. THIS Movie On The Other Hand Is Stupid & Downright Hilarious. I Am Interested In The Series Because They Look Funny. All In All A Great Comedy Sci-Fi. The Plot To This Island Earth Is That Dr. Meacham is chosen along with others by the inhabitants of the planet Metaluna to do research that will help save their dying planet. However, an evil scheme is uncovered by the suspecting Dr. Meacham when he discovers the Metalunan's plan to take over Earth. Dr. Meacham then escapes an exploding Metalunan built Earth lab along with Dr. Adams only to be kidnapped while flying away in a small plane. A flying saucer whisks both the scientists off to Metaluna where they are held accountable for blowing up the Metalunan Earth lab during their escape. They later escape there with the help of Exeter the friendly Metalunan. Metaluna then self destructs and the Doctors make it safely back to Earth, which is saved from Metalunan invasion. Now Do You See Why I Call THIS ISLAND EARTH Horrible
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Very Funny Film, Though Only Makes Me Miss the Show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Nelson and his robot buddies are still trapped on the Satellite of Love, forced to watch bad movies for some sort of bizarre experiment to drive Nelson mad. This time, the film is "This Island Earth". This film is very funny, but there is really nothing I have to say about it. If you like the show, you will like the movie, because there is really no difference whatsoever. The budget is slightly greater, so the lobby jokes are nicer looking, but they are so minor that it hardly matters. The picture quality also seems slightly crisper. The bulk of the film has them in the theater, which would look the same no matter what. Sadly, the film does little more than make me miss the show. According to some unknown source, "The TV show's usual density of gags was reduced for theatrical audiences, so that a larger number of people laughing wouldn't cause too much dialogue to be missed." That makes sense, except when you are watching it sixteen years later on DVD. You do not need that much silence -- it then becomes almost like really watching "This Island Earth". Even more mysterious, the film comes in at a short 73 minutes, even shorter than the average episode of 90 minutes. So the movie is shorter than the TV show! And the disc has no special features (besides French language track), so the DVD is not that special -- you would be better off buying a DVD of them watching "Manos" or something, unless you really enjoyed this particular film. A good film, some funny gags, and a short run time for quick viewing... but really nothing worth making a movie about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you liked the TV show, you can't go wrong with this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joshua kit
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is just a two hour episode of the TV show, and that's why it works. It won't make you cry, but it will make you laugh. I enjoyed the TV show and found the movie had everything I enjoyed about it. The movie they watch is the much-maligned, iconic 50s sci-fi B-movie, "This Island Earth". (Which, for what it's worth, is not a terrible movie. It's silly, but compared to many of it's contemporary films, is somewhat watchable.) If you've never seen it, then this is a good way to watch it. Not a whole lot else to say. This movie won't win an Oscar, but it's a fine pastime for a Friday night at home with a few beers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Several Good Laughs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mystery Science Theatre 3000: The Movie (1996) *** (out of 4) The cult TV show made it to the big screen this one time and features Mike and his two robots being held by an evil scientist who forces them to watch THIS ISLAND EARTH. This is meant to torture the trio but the three turn the tables with their comments. I will admit right up front that I'm not one of the die hard fans who love this show more than anything else. I'm very hit and miss on it and I often find myself on message boards talking against the show because I'm one who can enjoy these bad movies without the added comments. However, every time I argue against the show it hits me that when I do watch one I find it funny and there's no question that there's talent behind the comments. Now, I will say that I found it strange that they selected THIS ISLAND EARTH for their first movie because, to be honest, it's really not a bad movie. I think had they selected a worse movie it might have led to more and better jokes but what's here is still pretty good. I thought the best moments happened whenever the trio went on with continued dialogue. One would pretend to be the voice of a character and then they would just go back and forth. I thought this is when the best jokes came out and especially the stuff dealing with the alien leader's ultra big head. Another funny jokes happens at the start when the plane is about to crash but the alien's help land it with a green flashing light. The jokes that are around this are very good. As with any comedy, there are jokes that don't work but I think for the most part the majority of them hit their target and deliver laughs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pitiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Green_Saturn
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It doesn't matter that this movie is based off a successful T.V. show. It still is painful to watch. After a confusing and messy opening monologue by some creepy professor, for whatever reason the audience discovers that this movie takes place in space. And the spaceship our "heroes" are in looks suspiciously like male genitalia. I never quite understood whether that was intentional or not. The only thing sadder than the plot of this movie is the robots. Seriously, its like whoever designed them died half way through the process. I don't know if they're from the T.V. show or something (NO, I have never seen the show), but they are just utterly awful. One is something that I think resembles a crow, and the other is just a talking gumball machine. It creeped me out. What was the point of even having the robots, or the random guy who is friends with them? (By the way, was Trace Beaulieu blackmailed into playing Mike Nelson?) The comments made about the movie these characters are watching are juvenile and distracting. At one point, one of the robots makes a sound like a car engine when a car pans on screen. Where is the humor? What am I not getting? Halfway through the movie (that the characters are watching), the filmmakers decided to spare the audience by having the film reel break. While we wait for the creepy scientist guy to fix this, our useless heroes break the Hubble telescope. This is, in fact, their biggest accomplishment of the entire movie. The movie the creepy scientist makes them watch isn't that bad. It's actually pretty interesting, if a little cheesy. You'd think if the whole point of the movie was to make fun of another movie, whoever made this would've at least picked a bad movie to make fun of. The worst part is the ending. Usually, in the last ten minutes of a movie, loose ends are tied up. Nope. Not in this. Nothing happens. One star, because at least this movie was SHORT.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I never understood why they made this movie, but it was still rather good.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aaron1375
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film features the gang of the Satellite of Love like you have never seen them before! Being told what to do by movie producers, being passed over for ad revenue in favor of Barb Wire and riffing a film that is 94 minutes long and longer than this entire film. Still, the riffing was good and the film overall funny, just not as good as some of the stuff one saw in the regular show. In this film the Satellite of Love looks like it is in space, other than that it seems there was very little need to make this movie as the producers seemed to want to make this film short as all get out, it would of been better off simply being an episode of the show. The film being parodied is "This Island Earth", a film I have not seen other than what is presented here. Usually I feel comfortable reviewing films the gang have done, but this one is so obviously cut short I will not review this one as this one is so chopped up a lot of the plot is too. I am not sure what is happening in places so until I see the full movie I will not review it. I can review this though and like I said, it is good, but I would rather they had stayed on television as this movie is shorter than anything they did on the show on Comedy Central or the Sci-Fi channel. The host segments were not as funny as the host segments on the regular show either as they seemed to want to scream at the audience, "This is a movie!" So overall, funny, just kind of pointless. Though it is one film I can watch the closing credits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its a mystery why this film was ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ryan-Pollard
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'MST3K - The Movie', I came to the conclusion that it deserved to be on 'MST3K - The Television Series' far more than 'Danger Diabolik', 'Squirm' or 'Phase 4'. Bad script, ham acting, lame jokes, poor special effects - it had the lot. It also managed to insult one of the finest science fiction films of the '50's - 'This Island Earth'. Why that particular movie? Could they not find something more suitable, such as 'Plan 9 From Outer Space'? The sad thing is that its audience will never know how good a film 'This Island Earth' is because all they have seen of it is a silly send-up. The funniest line in the whole 90 minutes was "I've farted!" and that tells you all you need to know. The 'MST3K' brigade do not seem to be aware that any idiot can laugh at an old movie, especially if it is of its time. It takes real intelligence to be able to look at 'This Island Earth' and see it for what it is, an imaginative and exciting sci-fi picture. 'MST3K' bombed on its release, and the show itself was cancelled a few years later, so one good thing came out of it at least.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In space . . . . . . . . . . . everyone can hear your screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, just wow. The popularity of this movie (and, by logical extension, I would have to say the TV show) astounds me. The concept? There is a man in space who is being tested by being shown the worst movies ever made and so he sits through them with a couple of robot buddies and makes fun of them. That's it, and to some people that's all well and good and makes for some of the funniest stuff that they've ever sat through. For me, this ends up being one of the very worst experiences I have ever had to endure in my whole life of movie-watching (and I've watched a LOT of crap, believe me). My main issue with the thing is that, to me anyway, the comments from the folk on screen are just annoying and unfunny. Okay, okay, I smirked on about two occasions but that's not a very good average for something that's supposed to be a comedy. There will be those thinking I am just a massive fan of This Island Earth (the movie being watched within the movie) and feeling all defensive about it being so insulted. Well, this was the first time I had seen This Island Earth in any form and there's no denying that it was a risible movie but the fact remains that many of my own thoughts while watching the movie would be/were funnier than those mentioned by the Mystery Science Theatregoers (who are, essentially, the annoying people sitting in the row in front of you in a cinema, thinking they are smart-assed greatness with their constant nattering and stream of lowest common denominator consciousness). Pretty much all of those involved (director Jim Mallon, stars Trace Beaulieu and Michael J. Nelson, etc) had a hand in writing this nonsense and so can all share the blame. Unfunny, irritating and just absolutely awful. It was like spending just over an hour listening to nails on a chalk board while I tried to "enjoy" a bad 50s sci-fi flick. I never ever want to see this again. Ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny as if Richard Basehart ran naked through Washington yelling "I'm Richard Basehart!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (udragon2010)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As always, the guys at MST3K make a bad movie watchable. I giggled and guffawed from the minute it started. The guys are forced to watch "This Island Earth" and riff on its stupidness. The bots are just as nutty as they are in the show and good old Mike Nelson is the glue that keeps the zaniness from getting too much. This is a great jumping on point for those who have not yet been blessed by the goodness that is Mystery Science Theater 3000. People who have complained about this movie riffing on a classic movie should repeat to themselves "its just a movie and I should really just relax." It's great for the kids, family and the dog, but not for grandpa and grandma. Watch this flick and you'll wish for movie sign for the rest of your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious even When You Watch for the Second Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The evil scientist Dr. Clayton Forrester (Trace Beaulieu) locks Mike Nelson (Michael J. Nelson) and two robots in a spacecraft to watch terrible low-budget movies as part of his scheme to conquer the world. He projects 1954 "This Island Earth" (Title (Brazil): "Guerra Entre Planetas") with the intention of driving them crazy. However, the trio laughs and makes funny comments in every scene and dialogs, having good-time instead, and Dr. Forrester's ambitious plan does not work. The first time I saw "Mystery Science Theater 3000: The Movie" on 01 February 2000 I loved it a lot and I gave a nine. I had watched the cheese "This Island Earth" a few months ago and the comments of Mike Nelson and the two robots made me laugh a lot. Today I have just watched this film again and it is still hilarious, but my rating is lower this time. "Mystery Science Theater 3000: The Movie" was released in Brazil on VHS by CIC-Universal Distributor. My vote is seven. Title (Brazil): "O Filme Mais Idiota do Mundo" ("The Most Idiot Movie of the World")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Keanu Reeves In My Own Private Airfield"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Possible Spoilers But I Can't See Any. This Is The First Time I Ever Saw A Mystery Science Theater...Well Anything. Its Where Dr. Forrester Subjects Their Last Movie On Them. "THIS ISLAND EARTH" & This Island Earth Is A Horrible Movie With Animation Techniques That'll Make A 5 Year Old Get Worried. THIS Movie On The Other Hand Is Stupid & Downright Hilarious. I Am Interested In The Series Because They Look Funny. All In All A Great Comedy Sci-Fi. The Plot To This Island Earth Is That Dr. Meacham is chosen along with others by the inhabitants of the planet Metaluna to do research that will help save their dying planet. However, an evil scheme is uncovered by the suspecting Dr. Meacham when he discovers the Metalunan's plan to take over Earth. Dr. Meacham then escapes an exploding Metalunan built Earth lab along with Dr. Adams only to be kidnapped while flying away in a small plane. A flying saucer whisks both the scientists off to Metaluna where they are held accountable for blowing up the Metalunan Earth lab during their escape. They later escape there with the help of Exeter the friendly Metalunan. Metaluna then self destructs and the Doctors make it safely back to Earth, which is saved from Metalunan invasion. Now Do You See Why I Call THIS ISLAND EARTH Horrible
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Very Funny Film, Though Only Makes Me Miss the Show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Nelson and his robot buddies are still trapped on the Satellite of Love, forced to watch bad movies for some sort of bizarre experiment to drive Nelson mad. This time, the film is "This Island Earth". This film is very funny, but there is really nothing I have to say about it. If you like the show, you will like the movie, because there is really no difference whatsoever. The budget is slightly greater, so the lobby jokes are nicer looking, but they are so minor that it hardly matters. The picture quality also seems slightly crisper. The bulk of the film has them in the theater, which would look the same no matter what. Sadly, the film does little more than make me miss the show. According to some unknown source, "The TV show's usual density of gags was reduced for theatrical audiences, so that a larger number of people laughing wouldn't cause too much dialogue to be missed." That makes sense, except when you are watching it sixteen years later on DVD. You do not need that much silence -- it then becomes almost like really watching "This Island Earth". Even more mysterious, the film comes in at a short 73 minutes, even shorter than the average episode of 90 minutes. So the movie is shorter than the TV show! And the disc has no special features (besides French language track), so the DVD is not that special -- you would be better off buying a DVD of them watching "Manos" or something, unless you really enjoyed this particular film. A good film, some funny gags, and a short run time for quick viewing... but really nothing worth making a movie about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
