<filme>
 <id>
  1103
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0103130
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1990
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Confian&ccedil;a
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  When high school dropout Maria Coughlin announces her pregnancy to her parents, her father drops dead on the floor. Her mother kicks her out of the house and her boyfriend dumps her, so ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  When high school dropout Maria Coughlin announces her pregnancy to her parents, her father drops dead on the floor. Her mother kicks her out of the house and her boyfriend dumps her, so Maria is left alone and homeless. This is when she meets Matthew Slaughter. Matthew is an educated high school graduate with a great talent for fixing electronic devices, but he can't hang on to a job because of his principled attitude towards quality. When Maria accepts Matthew's offer to help her, they begin to form a relationship with each other in which both of them begin to change.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   pregnancy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   dropout
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   high school dropout
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   rebellion
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   protective male
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Hal Hartley
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Hal Hartley
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Adrienne Shelly
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Martin Donovan
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Rebecca Nelson
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful funny thing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ethanstraffin
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This remains one of my favorite films of all time. Hal Hartley's second feature is built around the same deliciously weird sense of humor as his debut "The Unbelievable Truth" -- but Adrienne Shelly (RIP) is even better in this one than she was in that one, and now we also get Martin Donovan as one of the more intense, flawed, and ultimately lovable romantic leads you'll ever see on film. (I almost put quotes around "romantic," because this is not a love story in the traditional "does the guy get the girl" sense. It's more interesting than that.) Between the characters and the dialogue, Hartley and his cast created something here that is wonderfully unique, humorous, and poignant. Think _Sex, Lies and Videotape_, sort of: there's that same sense of wondering whether these two messed-up people are ever going to get their acts together, and cheering them on either way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You can feel a new talent emerge
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From the first sequence of Hal Hartley's Trust a viewer knows he's in for a dark, obscure ride. It opens with the shot of a young teen named Maria (Adrienne Shelly), smoking while being scolded by her parents on what a punk deviant she is after being kicked out of school. She informs them that she is pregnant and the consumption of shock and shame leads to her father's on-spot heart attack and death. This should give you an inkling on what kind of film you're in for. Maria winds up running away from home to inform her jock-boyfriend she is pregnant. He, of course, couldn't care less, as he wants to focus on sports with little distraction. Now, Maria is alone until she meets Matthew (Martin Donovan), a man whose life keeps intercepting the focus of the film up until this point. Matthew lives with his abusive father, who looks on to his son with a condescending eye. He regards him as an irrelevant failure with no ability to hold down a job. This puts Matthew in a suicidal position, barely holding on as a whole. When both of them meet, we truly see that misery loves company. The relationship Maria and Matthew have in the film is talky and quiet, with Matthew bringing detached realism into the life of Maria's, which is already dominated by teenage naivety. Hartley paints both characters as flawed people that do not magically become repaired by each other, but find a more stable sense of life and trust in their opposites. Shelley captures the reckless spirit of Maria well, and Donovan is superb at giving his sadsack character Matthew a face and a soul. Their chemistry is the driving force behind Trust's success. There's a constant use of bright, vibrant color in the film that really amplifies the overall look and tone of the picture. In the opening shot is where this can be viewed as being most prominent. As stated, Shelley remains in close-up and the colors of her makeup and lip gloss remain eye-popping and totally "in your face." The remainder of the movie can occasionally turn up as grim, with a gray palette, but often does Hartley gather up the brightest, most visually attractive colors to see on-screen. But where Trust really excels is in its dialog. Smooth, fluent, and often subversively philosophical in terms of direct contact, he establishes a relationship between two unlikely characters that we can see grow and build as time goes on. They expand from the one-dimensional caricatures we initially view them as to complete humans we can recognize and sympathize with. Trust is the second film from Hal Hartley, who has made a career out of making comedy-dramas with an emphasis on character and monologues. He establishes himself quaintly here, assuring his independent status, and carefully makes use of such neglected things as mood and tone to set a nice standard in this drama. It's the kind of feeling that I see many going for. We walk in unsure, but emerge with the mindset that we've seen a new filmmaking talent in the works. God, do I love that feeling. Starring: Adrienne Shelly and Martin Donovan. Directed by: Hal Hartley.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a very fine film with no inherent gaps or mislead characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    italys
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most popular films delineate their stories in a rather comical and insipid way: the dialogue is often exchanged between characters as if it were bounced off a Spartan gladiator - and, in some cases very little to short-of-nothing is penetrable in the film. "Trust" is a film that inverses that idea - and does so with wit, charm, and most importantly: astute cleverness. The story begins with careful sequencing that portrays each character a new journey of life. We see an antisocial protagonist, a pregnant girl who recently dropped out of high school, and a motherly type whose apathy is cunning and partially insane. "Trust" is a love story that defies any clich&eacute; of filmmaking. The lead character pours his organism into the film and invokes integrity of personality without apprehension or any constipation (who can forget that wit from Mr Slaughter??) The film is about what happens when we take chances, and don't take chances. In short: it's about being and what happens when we share our being with others. The film's sequencing is what I loved most of all. It's weaved into a fabric that reminded me of early avant-garde films (the envelope of the story is reminiscent of Kubricks's older film "The Killing") and perhaps more-or-less surprising is the protagonist(played by Martin Donovan) exchanges silence; those rare moments in the film that can't help to be compared to the work of Godard. Momentarily, it shines solicitude and violence (the symbolism is slightly ironic and very insincere.) My favorite moments are about jeering characters who feel unwanted. A definite must-watch. I recommend it to anyone, everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a gifted filmmaker, treading water
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Long Island filmmaker Hal Hartley fights the sophomore jinx in the follow-up to his disarming debut feature 'The Unbelievable Truth' (1989). His second film is an overwritten satire drawn around the usual clich&eacute;s of modern suburban culture (television, dysfunctional families, etc.) and filtered through the director's trademark cast of quirky characters, none of whom resemble anyone raised in a genuine suburb. It lacks the offbeat appeal of his earlier effort, presenting a darker, more emotionally violent story about a pregnant high school dropout and her unlikely friendship with an alienated electronics whiz-kid, who carries a hand grenade "just in case". The odd, choreographed rhythm of Hartley's dialogue is still enjoyable, but this time his characters have nothing amusing to say, and the impression is left of a gifted talent trying too hard to overcome a creative block.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Inventive film experiment..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When student Maria tells her parents that she is pregnant it leads to her father dying of an heart-attack and herself being thrown out of the house. Coincidentally she meets electro-genius Matthew that lives with his despot of a father, and a peculiar romance arises. Hal Hartley's second feature film after his directorial debut "The Unbelievable Truth" (1989), is a surreal independent film about two loners from the working-class who are entangled in a whimsical though adorable romance without knowing that they are destined for each other. Compounded by witty and overlapping dialog, paradox situations and archetype characters, Hal Hartley creates a colorful and fabulous universe that describes life's irony, fragility, triviality, ambiguity and harmony in a comical, sophisticated and enriching way, and composes his minimalistic style with finely structured narrative, stylish photography, good music, costumes of great contrasts, innovating cinematography and rare moods. Hal Hartley's individualistic film style is characterized by fertile acting, detailed depictions of milieu, frequent close-ups, alternate perspectives and short takes, that in interaction with the talkative scripts fast dialog increases the films progression. "Trust" is an inventive film experiment about tricky family relations and people's need to be seen, heard and believed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comforting like a good sad balled...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Probably one of the least seen films that I have discussed over the last 6 months, this was a movie that I remember vividly as a teen, though in more glowing terms than I now see it. Trust was made by indie filmmaker Hal Hartley, who was renowned for his dialogue heavy films exploring regular people going about their lives. Now that I revisit this some 20 years later I think that perhaps his work also merits the dreaded "quirky" tag. The film starts with a domestic between a young girl and her Dad, the scene culminates with the Dad keeling over dead of a heart attack. The girl is one of two leads, her name is Maria, she is apparently high school age, is pregnant to the quarterback who she now wants nothing to do with, and not wanted at home as her mother blames her for the death of her dad. She also looks a lot like a duck. The other lead is Matthew, played by Martin Donovan in deadpan mode. He is a marginally psychotic TV repairman who is bullied by his single Dad and carries a grenade around with him. Real people dealing with real issues. There is much more of a plot than Maria and Matthew meet, share their problems and decide to make a go of things together, the action occurs as they progress through and come into contact with the various other characters in the film. No-one seems to get along, Maria's mum hates her, and later Matthew. Matthew's dad hates him, and everyone else it seems. Matthew is an angry loner who hates everyone and everyone hates, which leaves Maria and her unborn child as the victim of a tug of war. Everyone in the film seems to be 5% off-normal, not quite enough to be a caricature, but more than enough that they could all aptly be described as weird (at least) by normal people. In this vein Hartley is like Kevin Smith (really), he puts people that you might almost convince yourself that could exist, and in fact you might know someone who really reminds of one of them, only he fills every role with these one-in-a-million characters, so you have a town full of people that would ordinarily be the nut-job. The dialogue is scripted down to the nth degree, which unfortunately leads to conversations that alternate between snappy and robotic, at times in the same scene. At times it is almost like the characters are starting their response before the other sentence is finished. This film is most notable to me as being the first film I can remember seeing that had a character say the C-word, and a female character at that. If this sounds juvenile it is because when I watched the film I was, so it was a genuine surprise to me to see such a taboo word bandied about in an art house film. Even now that I watch this movie and see that I perhaps was looking at my memories with rose coloured glasses, there are moments that are both calculated that still have an impact, you know that the director is trying to scream "this is important" and want to ignore it but it still works. Like a good sad ballad, you know it is simply trying to manipulate your emotions, but turn off the lights and crank it loud and you can't help but caught up in it. Only Trust is a 90+ minute movie, it's hard to be "swept along" for that long when everything is so mechanical. Final Rating - 6.5 - 10. As I said at times it works, there are just too many dead spots in between those times. If you liked this review (or even if you didn't) check out oneguyrambling.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite Movie Of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (david-a-goddard)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this film in 1990 while I was in college and I loved it. I watched it over and over on VHS. I told everyone that this was my favorite movie of all time and watched every Hal Hartley movie I could find. Last night I stumbled across Trust on Netflix Instant and I thought I'd check it out to see if this film that I was so passionate about when I was 20 years old held up over time or if the 40 year old me would find it silly or dated. To my surprise I was blown away all over again by how ridiculously great it is. The smart stylized dialog, the music, the starkness, the silences, the camera framing, all of the whacked out but fully human characters, Martin Donovan and Adrienne Shelly so young and beautiful. As the final, simple, beautiful, frame of the film disappeared and credits rolled I was left sitting on the couch in a state of shocked amazement at the effect this film still has on me. Hands down my favorite movie of all time!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Top 100 of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    randallhurlbut
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hal Hartley's film TRUST is one of the top 100 achievements in the history of cinema. Hal, if you ever visit this site and see this statement I hope it makes you feel good. A d-girl in LA (development person in Hollywood) at a party once showed me a bookshelf at her home that contained her 10 or 15 favorite screenplays of all time... KANE, CHINATOWN, ... and one of my old screenplays (!)(she didn't know I was the author) and yeah... that makes you feel pretty damn good. So why does TRUST work so well? Maybe it's alchemy... getting sorta the right combination in the right quantities of abstraction, hyper-realism, irony, and distance. Hartley plays with archetypes and yet makes them singular. (That ain't easy.) It's like reading Theodore Dreyer filtered by Bertolt Brecht, or running into a Long Island Godard, but the fun version of Godard before he became too p-ssed off at the world. Hartley will stage a scene that you've seen a thousand times before, almost as genre commentary or put-on, then morph it into something you have NEVER seen before. Come to think of it, although Hartley is often thought of as the American Godard, at times he could almost be the American Bunuel (sorry Mr. Lynch). It would be easy to hate some of the characters in Hartley's TRUST, but Hartley doesn't. He may hate the situations, the contexts, the environments... but he certainly has no hatred for the people. It's a great love story and a quasi-homage to PIERROT LE FOU. It contains multitudes. It is a great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll marry you if you admit that respect, admiration and trust equal love."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paddy Jamieson (imdbpaddy@hotmail.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust (1990) - 10/10 As a filmmaker, Hal Hartley will forever divide audiences due to his unique story-telling style, dead-pan humour and tendency to favour words over action. His themes are often subtle and can take more than one viewing to fully understand or appreciate. Something which, understandably, can put off many. But whether you adore his style or think it to be moronic, no-one can deny that he is and always will be an inspired writer and director. A director who has influenced many and will continue to do so, I am sure, for years to come. Now I fall into the category of adoration and I believe 'Trust' to be his finest work. 'Trust' focuses on the coming together of two characters. Maria Coughlin, a pregnant high-school dropout who has just been the cause of her fathers fatal heart attack, and Matthew Slaughter, an intellectual loner who still lives with his sadistic father. Sound like a standard, if a bit over the top, romance? You couldn't be more wrong. What makes Hartley's films so special, and 'Trust' is no exception, are the characters he manages to create. Though the situations they get into and the characters around them are nothing short of surreal, the way the react to each situation and deal with very serious issues could not be more realistic. A huge reason for this is his dialogue. Reminiscent of early Richard Linklater or Godard, his flowing, straight to the point script has you hooked from the word go. Fantastically direct delivery from both Shelley and Donovan allow this dialogue to shine and have you believe you these characters are friends you have known for years. In 'Trust' I believe Hartley has created one of the most earnest romances ever to be filmed. Utterly believable and almost heartbreakingly beautiful, this is certainly not a film to be missed. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unusual characters brilliantly portrayed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    timmy_501
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust opens with a stereotypical ignorant high school girl named Maria making petty demands of her parents and deliberately scandalizing them by explaining her future plans which involve marrying her jock boyfriend. She explains that he'll have to because she's pregnant and then leaves before she has a chance to realize that the news has caused her father to have a heart attack. Since she does leave we have a while longer to become familiar with her before her perfect world begins to crumble around her. She carelessly goes clothes shopping during the day and only stops by the school she is supposed to be attending to talk to her boyfriend. He's more worried about the upcoming football game than anything she can tell him; news of her pregnancy only angers him and he makes it clear that he won't take care of the child. Things get progressively worse for her as she's kicked out of her house, has a conversation with an insane woman, and is nearly raped before retreating to a quiet street where she attempts to drown her sorrow in a six pack. At this point Maria happens to meet Matthew, a gifted machinist who is so unsatisfied with his foolish employers and demanding father that he has developed a nasty violent streak. This initially seems to be an excellent match as the newly disillusioned Maria has become just as averse to nonsense as Matthew. The two slowly get to know each other and each one realizes that the other satisfies an innate desire that has previously gone unmet. Unfortunately circumstances keep arising to drive them apart and Matthew puts his trust in the wrong people. Writer/director Hal Hartley infuses this film with a uniquely cynical wit that meshes perfectly with the material to create a work that is at once funny and emotionally engaging. The film also is thematically satisfying in that it explores the attitudes of the characters and how those attitudes have been developed. Specifically, we see how the trust characters place in other people, particularly family members, is abused and subverted and how this has shaped various characters over time. Trust is one of those rare films that not only encapsulates a certain time and place but also presents some genuine truths about human behavior and offers a consistently engaging viewing experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful funny thing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ethanstraffin
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This remains one of my favorite films of all time. Hal Hartley's second feature is built around the same deliciously weird sense of humor as his debut "The Unbelievable Truth" -- but Adrienne Shelly (RIP) is even better in this one than she was in that one, and now we also get Martin Donovan as one of the more intense, flawed, and ultimately lovable romantic leads you'll ever see on film. (I almost put quotes around "romantic," because this is not a love story in the traditional "does the guy get the girl" sense. It's more interesting than that.) Between the characters and the dialogue, Hartley and his cast created something here that is wonderfully unique, humorous, and poignant. Think _Sex, Lies and Videotape_, sort of: there's that same sense of wondering whether these two messed-up people are ever going to get their acts together, and cheering them on either way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You can feel a new talent emerge
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From the first sequence of Hal Hartley's Trust a viewer knows he's in for a dark, obscure ride. It opens with the shot of a young teen named Maria (Adrienne Shelly), smoking while being scolded by her parents on what a punk deviant she is after being kicked out of school. She informs them that she is pregnant and the consumption of shock and shame leads to her father's on-spot heart attack and death. This should give you an inkling on what kind of film you're in for. Maria winds up running away from home to inform her jock-boyfriend she is pregnant. He, of course, couldn't care less, as he wants to focus on sports with little distraction. Now, Maria is alone until she meets Matthew (Martin Donovan), a man whose life keeps intercepting the focus of the film up until this point. Matthew lives with his abusive father, who looks on to his son with a condescending eye. He regards him as an irrelevant failure with no ability to hold down a job. This puts Matthew in a suicidal position, barely holding on as a whole. When both of them meet, we truly see that misery loves company. The relationship Maria and Matthew have in the film is talky and quiet, with Matthew bringing detached realism into the life of Maria's, which is already dominated by teenage naivety. Hartley paints both characters as flawed people that do not magically become repaired by each other, but find a more stable sense of life and trust in their opposites. Shelley captures the reckless spirit of Maria well, and Donovan is superb at giving his sadsack character Matthew a face and a soul. Their chemistry is the driving force behind Trust's success. There's a constant use of bright, vibrant color in the film that really amplifies the overall look and tone of the picture. In the opening shot is where this can be viewed as being most prominent. As stated, Shelley remains in close-up and the colors of her makeup and lip gloss remain eye-popping and totally "in your face." The remainder of the movie can occasionally turn up as grim, with a gray palette, but often does Hartley gather up the brightest, most visually attractive colors to see on-screen. But where Trust really excels is in its dialog. Smooth, fluent, and often subversively philosophical in terms of direct contact, he establishes a relationship between two unlikely characters that we can see grow and build as time goes on. They expand from the one-dimensional caricatures we initially view them as to complete humans we can recognize and sympathize with. Trust is the second film from Hal Hartley, who has made a career out of making comedy-dramas with an emphasis on character and monologues. He establishes himself quaintly here, assuring his independent status, and carefully makes use of such neglected things as mood and tone to set a nice standard in this drama. It's the kind of feeling that I see many going for. We walk in unsure, but emerge with the mindset that we've seen a new filmmaking talent in the works. God, do I love that feeling. Starring: Adrienne Shelly and Martin Donovan. Directed by: Hal Hartley.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a very fine film with no inherent gaps or mislead characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    italys
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most popular films delineate their stories in a rather comical and insipid way: the dialogue is often exchanged between characters as if it were bounced off a Spartan gladiator - and, in some cases very little to short-of-nothing is penetrable in the film. "Trust" is a film that inverses that idea - and does so with wit, charm, and most importantly: astute cleverness. The story begins with careful sequencing that portrays each character a new journey of life. We see an antisocial protagonist, a pregnant girl who recently dropped out of high school, and a motherly type whose apathy is cunning and partially insane. "Trust" is a love story that defies any clich&eacute; of filmmaking. The lead character pours his organism into the film and invokes integrity of personality without apprehension or any constipation (who can forget that wit from Mr Slaughter??) The film is about what happens when we take chances, and don't take chances. In short: it's about being and what happens when we share our being with others. The film's sequencing is what I loved most of all. It's weaved into a fabric that reminded me of early avant-garde films (the envelope of the story is reminiscent of Kubricks's older film "The Killing") and perhaps more-or-less surprising is the protagonist(played by Martin Donovan) exchanges silence; those rare moments in the film that can't help to be compared to the work of Godard. Momentarily, it shines solicitude and violence (the symbolism is slightly ironic and very insincere.) My favorite moments are about jeering characters who feel unwanted. A definite must-watch. I recommend it to anyone, everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a gifted filmmaker, treading water
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Long Island filmmaker Hal Hartley fights the sophomore jinx in the follow-up to his disarming debut feature 'The Unbelievable Truth' (1989). His second film is an overwritten satire drawn around the usual clich&eacute;s of modern suburban culture (television, dysfunctional families, etc.) and filtered through the director's trademark cast of quirky characters, none of whom resemble anyone raised in a genuine suburb. It lacks the offbeat appeal of his earlier effort, presenting a darker, more emotionally violent story about a pregnant high school dropout and her unlikely friendship with an alienated electronics whiz-kid, who carries a hand grenade "just in case". The odd, choreographed rhythm of Hartley's dialogue is still enjoyable, but this time his characters have nothing amusing to say, and the impression is left of a gifted talent trying too hard to overcome a creative block.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Inventive film experiment..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When student Maria tells her parents that she is pregnant it leads to her father dying of an heart-attack and herself being thrown out of the house. Coincidentally she meets electro-genius Matthew that lives with his despot of a father, and a peculiar romance arises. Hal Hartley's second feature film after his directorial debut "The Unbelievable Truth" (1989), is a surreal independent film about two loners from the working-class who are entangled in a whimsical though adorable romance without knowing that they are destined for each other. Compounded by witty and overlapping dialog, paradox situations and archetype characters, Hal Hartley creates a colorful and fabulous universe that describes life's irony, fragility, triviality, ambiguity and harmony in a comical, sophisticated and enriching way, and composes his minimalistic style with finely structured narrative, stylish photography, good music, costumes of great contrasts, innovating cinematography and rare moods. Hal Hartley's individualistic film style is characterized by fertile acting, detailed depictions of milieu, frequent close-ups, alternate perspectives and short takes, that in interaction with the talkative scripts fast dialog increases the films progression. "Trust" is an inventive film experiment about tricky family relations and people's need to be seen, heard and believed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comforting like a good sad balled...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Probably one of the least seen films that I have discussed over the last 6 months, this was a movie that I remember vividly as a teen, though in more glowing terms than I now see it. Trust was made by indie filmmaker Hal Hartley, who was renowned for his dialogue heavy films exploring regular people going about their lives. Now that I revisit this some 20 years later I think that perhaps his work also merits the dreaded "quirky" tag. The film starts with a domestic between a young girl and her Dad, the scene culminates with the Dad keeling over dead of a heart attack. The girl is one of two leads, her name is Maria, she is apparently high school age, is pregnant to the quarterback who she now wants nothing to do with, and not wanted at home as her mother blames her for the death of her dad. She also looks a lot like a duck. The other lead is Matthew, played by Martin Donovan in deadpan mode. He is a marginally psychotic TV repairman who is bullied by his single Dad and carries a grenade around with him. Real people dealing with real issues. There is much more of a plot than Maria and Matthew meet, share their problems and decide to make a go of things together, the action occurs as they progress through and come into contact with the various other characters in the film. No-one seems to get along, Maria's mum hates her, and later Matthew. Matthew's dad hates him, and everyone else it seems. Matthew is an angry loner who hates everyone and everyone hates, which leaves Maria and her unborn child as the victim of a tug of war. Everyone in the film seems to be 5% off-normal, not quite enough to be a caricature, but more than enough that they could all aptly be described as weird (at least) by normal people. In this vein Hartley is like Kevin Smith (really), he puts people that you might almost convince yourself that could exist, and in fact you might know someone who really reminds of one of them, only he fills every role with these one-in-a-million characters, so you have a town full of people that would ordinarily be the nut-job. The dialogue is scripted down to the nth degree, which unfortunately leads to conversations that alternate between snappy and robotic, at times in the same scene. At times it is almost like the characters are starting their response before the other sentence is finished. This film is most notable to me as being the first film I can remember seeing that had a character say the C-word, and a female character at that. If this sounds juvenile it is because when I watched the film I was, so it was a genuine surprise to me to see such a taboo word bandied about in an art house film. Even now that I watch this movie and see that I perhaps was looking at my memories with rose coloured glasses, there are moments that are both calculated that still have an impact, you know that the director is trying to scream "this is important" and want to ignore it but it still works. Like a good sad ballad, you know it is simply trying to manipulate your emotions, but turn off the lights and crank it loud and you can't help but caught up in it. Only Trust is a 90+ minute movie, it's hard to be "swept along" for that long when everything is so mechanical. Final Rating - 6.5 - 10. As I said at times it works, there are just too many dead spots in between those times. If you liked this review (or even if you didn't) check out oneguyrambling.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite Movie Of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (david-a-goddard)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this film in 1990 while I was in college and I loved it. I watched it over and over on VHS. I told everyone that this was my favorite movie of all time and watched every Hal Hartley movie I could find. Last night I stumbled across Trust on Netflix Instant and I thought I'd check it out to see if this film that I was so passionate about when I was 20 years old held up over time or if the 40 year old me would find it silly or dated. To my surprise I was blown away all over again by how ridiculously great it is. The smart stylized dialog, the music, the starkness, the silences, the camera framing, all of the whacked out but fully human characters, Martin Donovan and Adrienne Shelly so young and beautiful. As the final, simple, beautiful, frame of the film disappeared and credits rolled I was left sitting on the couch in a state of shocked amazement at the effect this film still has on me. Hands down my favorite movie of all time!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Top 100 of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    randallhurlbut
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hal Hartley's film TRUST is one of the top 100 achievements in the history of cinema. Hal, if you ever visit this site and see this statement I hope it makes you feel good. A d-girl in LA (development person in Hollywood) at a party once showed me a bookshelf at her home that contained her 10 or 15 favorite screenplays of all time... KANE, CHINATOWN, ... and one of my old screenplays (!)(she didn't know I was the author) and yeah... that makes you feel pretty damn good. So why does TRUST work so well? Maybe it's alchemy... getting sorta the right combination in the right quantities of abstraction, hyper-realism, irony, and distance. Hartley plays with archetypes and yet makes them singular. (That ain't easy.) It's like reading Theodore Dreyer filtered by Bertolt Brecht, or running into a Long Island Godard, but the fun version of Godard before he became too p-ssed off at the world. Hartley will stage a scene that you've seen a thousand times before, almost as genre commentary or put-on, then morph it into something you have NEVER seen before. Come to think of it, although Hartley is often thought of as the American Godard, at times he could almost be the American Bunuel (sorry Mr. Lynch). It would be easy to hate some of the characters in Hartley's TRUST, but Hartley doesn't. He may hate the situations, the contexts, the environments... but he certainly has no hatred for the people. It's a great love story and a quasi-homage to PIERROT LE FOU. It contains multitudes. It is a great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll marry you if you admit that respect, admiration and trust equal love."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paddy Jamieson (imdbpaddy@hotmail.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust (1990) - 10/10 As a filmmaker, Hal Hartley will forever divide audiences due to his unique story-telling style, dead-pan humour and tendency to favour words over action. His themes are often subtle and can take more than one viewing to fully understand or appreciate. Something which, understandably, can put off many. But whether you adore his style or think it to be moronic, no-one can deny that he is and always will be an inspired writer and director. A director who has influenced many and will continue to do so, I am sure, for years to come. Now I fall into the category of adoration and I believe 'Trust' to be his finest work. 'Trust' focuses on the coming together of two characters. Maria Coughlin, a pregnant high-school dropout who has just been the cause of her fathers fatal heart attack, and Matthew Slaughter, an intellectual loner who still lives with his sadistic father. Sound like a standard, if a bit over the top, romance? You couldn't be more wrong. What makes Hartley's films so special, and 'Trust' is no exception, are the characters he manages to create. Though the situations they get into and the characters around them are nothing short of surreal, the way the react to each situation and deal with very serious issues could not be more realistic. A huge reason for this is his dialogue. Reminiscent of early Richard Linklater or Godard, his flowing, straight to the point script has you hooked from the word go. Fantastically direct delivery from both Shelley and Donovan allow this dialogue to shine and have you believe you these characters are friends you have known for years. In 'Trust' I believe Hartley has created one of the most earnest romances ever to be filmed. Utterly believable and almost heartbreakingly beautiful, this is certainly not a film to be missed. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unusual characters brilliantly portrayed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    timmy_501
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust opens with a stereotypical ignorant high school girl named Maria making petty demands of her parents and deliberately scandalizing them by explaining her future plans which involve marrying her jock boyfriend. She explains that he'll have to because she's pregnant and then leaves before she has a chance to realize that the news has caused her father to have a heart attack. Since she does leave we have a while longer to become familiar with her before her perfect world begins to crumble around her. She carelessly goes clothes shopping during the day and only stops by the school she is supposed to be attending to talk to her boyfriend. He's more worried about the upcoming football game than anything she can tell him; news of her pregnancy only angers him and he makes it clear that he won't take care of the child. Things get progressively worse for her as she's kicked out of her house, has a conversation with an insane woman, and is nearly raped before retreating to a quiet street where she attempts to drown her sorrow in a six pack. At this point Maria happens to meet Matthew, a gifted machinist who is so unsatisfied with his foolish employers and demanding father that he has developed a nasty violent streak. This initially seems to be an excellent match as the newly disillusioned Maria has become just as averse to nonsense as Matthew. The two slowly get to know each other and each one realizes that the other satisfies an innate desire that has previously gone unmet. Unfortunately circumstances keep arising to drive them apart and Matthew puts his trust in the wrong people. Writer/director Hal Hartley infuses this film with a uniquely cynical wit that meshes perfectly with the material to create a work that is at once funny and emotionally engaging. The film also is thematically satisfying in that it explores the attitudes of the characters and how those attitudes have been developed. Specifically, we see how the trust characters place in other people, particularly family members, is abused and subverted and how this has shaped various characters over time. Trust is one of those rare films that not only encapsulates a certain time and place but also presents some genuine truths about human behavior and offers a consistently engaging viewing experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful funny thing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ethanstraffin
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This remains one of my favorite films of all time. Hal Hartley's second feature is built around the same deliciously weird sense of humor as his debut "The Unbelievable Truth" -- but Adrienne Shelly (RIP) is even better in this one than she was in that one, and now we also get Martin Donovan as one of the more intense, flawed, and ultimately lovable romantic leads you'll ever see on film. (I almost put quotes around "romantic," because this is not a love story in the traditional "does the guy get the girl" sense. It's more interesting than that.) Between the characters and the dialogue, Hartley and his cast created something here that is wonderfully unique, humorous, and poignant. Think _Sex, Lies and Videotape_, sort of: there's that same sense of wondering whether these two messed-up people are ever going to get their acts together, and cheering them on either way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You can feel a new talent emerge
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From the first sequence of Hal Hartley's Trust a viewer knows he's in for a dark, obscure ride. It opens with the shot of a young teen named Maria (Adrienne Shelly), smoking while being scolded by her parents on what a punk deviant she is after being kicked out of school. She informs them that she is pregnant and the consumption of shock and shame leads to her father's on-spot heart attack and death. This should give you an inkling on what kind of film you're in for. Maria winds up running away from home to inform her jock-boyfriend she is pregnant. He, of course, couldn't care less, as he wants to focus on sports with little distraction. Now, Maria is alone until she meets Matthew (Martin Donovan), a man whose life keeps intercepting the focus of the film up until this point. Matthew lives with his abusive father, who looks on to his son with a condescending eye. He regards him as an irrelevant failure with no ability to hold down a job. This puts Matthew in a suicidal position, barely holding on as a whole. When both of them meet, we truly see that misery loves company. The relationship Maria and Matthew have in the film is talky and quiet, with Matthew bringing detached realism into the life of Maria's, which is already dominated by teenage naivety. Hartley paints both characters as flawed people that do not magically become repaired by each other, but find a more stable sense of life and trust in their opposites. Shelley captures the reckless spirit of Maria well, and Donovan is superb at giving his sadsack character Matthew a face and a soul. Their chemistry is the driving force behind Trust's success. There's a constant use of bright, vibrant color in the film that really amplifies the overall look and tone of the picture. In the opening shot is where this can be viewed as being most prominent. As stated, Shelley remains in close-up and the colors of her makeup and lip gloss remain eye-popping and totally "in your face." The remainder of the movie can occasionally turn up as grim, with a gray palette, but often does Hartley gather up the brightest, most visually attractive colors to see on-screen. But where Trust really excels is in its dialog. Smooth, fluent, and often subversively philosophical in terms of direct contact, he establishes a relationship between two unlikely characters that we can see grow and build as time goes on. They expand from the one-dimensional caricatures we initially view them as to complete humans we can recognize and sympathize with. Trust is the second film from Hal Hartley, who has made a career out of making comedy-dramas with an emphasis on character and monologues. He establishes himself quaintly here, assuring his independent status, and carefully makes use of such neglected things as mood and tone to set a nice standard in this drama. It's the kind of feeling that I see many going for. We walk in unsure, but emerge with the mindset that we've seen a new filmmaking talent in the works. God, do I love that feeling. Starring: Adrienne Shelly and Martin Donovan. Directed by: Hal Hartley.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a very fine film with no inherent gaps or mislead characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    italys
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most popular films delineate their stories in a rather comical and insipid way: the dialogue is often exchanged between characters as if it were bounced off a Spartan gladiator - and, in some cases very little to short-of-nothing is penetrable in the film. "Trust" is a film that inverses that idea - and does so with wit, charm, and most importantly: astute cleverness. The story begins with careful sequencing that portrays each character a new journey of life. We see an antisocial protagonist, a pregnant girl who recently dropped out of high school, and a motherly type whose apathy is cunning and partially insane. "Trust" is a love story that defies any clich&eacute; of filmmaking. The lead character pours his organism into the film and invokes integrity of personality without apprehension or any constipation (who can forget that wit from Mr Slaughter??) The film is about what happens when we take chances, and don't take chances. In short: it's about being and what happens when we share our being with others. The film's sequencing is what I loved most of all. It's weaved into a fabric that reminded me of early avant-garde films (the envelope of the story is reminiscent of Kubricks's older film "The Killing") and perhaps more-or-less surprising is the protagonist(played by Martin Donovan) exchanges silence; those rare moments in the film that can't help to be compared to the work of Godard. Momentarily, it shines solicitude and violence (the symbolism is slightly ironic and very insincere.) My favorite moments are about jeering characters who feel unwanted. A definite must-watch. I recommend it to anyone, everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a gifted filmmaker, treading water
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Long Island filmmaker Hal Hartley fights the sophomore jinx in the follow-up to his disarming debut feature 'The Unbelievable Truth' (1989). His second film is an overwritten satire drawn around the usual clich&eacute;s of modern suburban culture (television, dysfunctional families, etc.) and filtered through the director's trademark cast of quirky characters, none of whom resemble anyone raised in a genuine suburb. It lacks the offbeat appeal of his earlier effort, presenting a darker, more emotionally violent story about a pregnant high school dropout and her unlikely friendship with an alienated electronics whiz-kid, who carries a hand grenade "just in case". The odd, choreographed rhythm of Hartley's dialogue is still enjoyable, but this time his characters have nothing amusing to say, and the impression is left of a gifted talent trying too hard to overcome a creative block.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Inventive film experiment..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When student Maria tells her parents that she is pregnant it leads to her father dying of an heart-attack and herself being thrown out of the house. Coincidentally she meets electro-genius Matthew that lives with his despot of a father, and a peculiar romance arises. Hal Hartley's second feature film after his directorial debut "The Unbelievable Truth" (1989), is a surreal independent film about two loners from the working-class who are entangled in a whimsical though adorable romance without knowing that they are destined for each other. Compounded by witty and overlapping dialog, paradox situations and archetype characters, Hal Hartley creates a colorful and fabulous universe that describes life's irony, fragility, triviality, ambiguity and harmony in a comical, sophisticated and enriching way, and composes his minimalistic style with finely structured narrative, stylish photography, good music, costumes of great contrasts, innovating cinematography and rare moods. Hal Hartley's individualistic film style is characterized by fertile acting, detailed depictions of milieu, frequent close-ups, alternate perspectives and short takes, that in interaction with the talkative scripts fast dialog increases the films progression. "Trust" is an inventive film experiment about tricky family relations and people's need to be seen, heard and believed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comforting like a good sad balled...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Probably one of the least seen films that I have discussed over the last 6 months, this was a movie that I remember vividly as a teen, though in more glowing terms than I now see it. Trust was made by indie filmmaker Hal Hartley, who was renowned for his dialogue heavy films exploring regular people going about their lives. Now that I revisit this some 20 years later I think that perhaps his work also merits the dreaded "quirky" tag. The film starts with a domestic between a young girl and her Dad, the scene culminates with the Dad keeling over dead of a heart attack. The girl is one of two leads, her name is Maria, she is apparently high school age, is pregnant to the quarterback who she now wants nothing to do with, and not wanted at home as her mother blames her for the death of her dad. She also looks a lot like a duck. The other lead is Matthew, played by Martin Donovan in deadpan mode. He is a marginally psychotic TV repairman who is bullied by his single Dad and carries a grenade around with him. Real people dealing with real issues. There is much more of a plot than Maria and Matthew meet, share their problems and decide to make a go of things together, the action occurs as they progress through and come into contact with the various other characters in the film. No-one seems to get along, Maria's mum hates her, and later Matthew. Matthew's dad hates him, and everyone else it seems. Matthew is an angry loner who hates everyone and everyone hates, which leaves Maria and her unborn child as the victim of a tug of war. Everyone in the film seems to be 5% off-normal, not quite enough to be a caricature, but more than enough that they could all aptly be described as weird (at least) by normal people. In this vein Hartley is like Kevin Smith (really), he puts people that you might almost convince yourself that could exist, and in fact you might know someone who really reminds of one of them, only he fills every role with these one-in-a-million characters, so you have a town full of people that would ordinarily be the nut-job. The dialogue is scripted down to the nth degree, which unfortunately leads to conversations that alternate between snappy and robotic, at times in the same scene. At times it is almost like the characters are starting their response before the other sentence is finished. This film is most notable to me as being the first film I can remember seeing that had a character say the C-word, and a female character at that. If this sounds juvenile it is because when I watched the film I was, so it was a genuine surprise to me to see such a taboo word bandied about in an art house film. Even now that I watch this movie and see that I perhaps was looking at my memories with rose coloured glasses, there are moments that are both calculated that still have an impact, you know that the director is trying to scream "this is important" and want to ignore it but it still works. Like a good sad ballad, you know it is simply trying to manipulate your emotions, but turn off the lights and crank it loud and you can't help but caught up in it. Only Trust is a 90+ minute movie, it's hard to be "swept along" for that long when everything is so mechanical. Final Rating - 6.5 - 10. As I said at times it works, there are just too many dead spots in between those times. If you liked this review (or even if you didn't) check out oneguyrambling.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite Movie Of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (david-a-goddard)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this film in 1990 while I was in college and I loved it. I watched it over and over on VHS. I told everyone that this was my favorite movie of all time and watched every Hal Hartley movie I could find. Last night I stumbled across Trust on Netflix Instant and I thought I'd check it out to see if this film that I was so passionate about when I was 20 years old held up over time or if the 40 year old me would find it silly or dated. To my surprise I was blown away all over again by how ridiculously great it is. The smart stylized dialog, the music, the starkness, the silences, the camera framing, all of the whacked out but fully human characters, Martin Donovan and Adrienne Shelly so young and beautiful. As the final, simple, beautiful, frame of the film disappeared and credits rolled I was left sitting on the couch in a state of shocked amazement at the effect this film still has on me. Hands down my favorite movie of all time!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Top 100 of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    randallhurlbut
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hal Hartley's film TRUST is one of the top 100 achievements in the history of cinema. Hal, if you ever visit this site and see this statement I hope it makes you feel good. A d-girl in LA (development person in Hollywood) at a party once showed me a bookshelf at her home that contained her 10 or 15 favorite screenplays of all time... KANE, CHINATOWN, ... and one of my old screenplays (!)(she didn't know I was the author) and yeah... that makes you feel pretty damn good. So why does TRUST work so well? Maybe it's alchemy... getting sorta the right combination in the right quantities of abstraction, hyper-realism, irony, and distance. Hartley plays with archetypes and yet makes them singular. (That ain't easy.) It's like reading Theodore Dreyer filtered by Bertolt Brecht, or running into a Long Island Godard, but the fun version of Godard before he became too p-ssed off at the world. Hartley will stage a scene that you've seen a thousand times before, almost as genre commentary or put-on, then morph it into something you have NEVER seen before. Come to think of it, although Hartley is often thought of as the American Godard, at times he could almost be the American Bunuel (sorry Mr. Lynch). It would be easy to hate some of the characters in Hartley's TRUST, but Hartley doesn't. He may hate the situations, the contexts, the environments... but he certainly has no hatred for the people. It's a great love story and a quasi-homage to PIERROT LE FOU. It contains multitudes. It is a great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll marry you if you admit that respect, admiration and trust equal love."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paddy Jamieson (imdbpaddy@hotmail.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust (1990) - 10/10 As a filmmaker, Hal Hartley will forever divide audiences due to his unique story-telling style, dead-pan humour and tendency to favour words over action. His themes are often subtle and can take more than one viewing to fully understand or appreciate. Something which, understandably, can put off many. But whether you adore his style or think it to be moronic, no-one can deny that he is and always will be an inspired writer and director. A director who has influenced many and will continue to do so, I am sure, for years to come. Now I fall into the category of adoration and I believe 'Trust' to be his finest work. 'Trust' focuses on the coming together of two characters. Maria Coughlin, a pregnant high-school dropout who has just been the cause of her fathers fatal heart attack, and Matthew Slaughter, an intellectual loner who still lives with his sadistic father. Sound like a standard, if a bit over the top, romance? You couldn't be more wrong. What makes Hartley's films so special, and 'Trust' is no exception, are the characters he manages to create. Though the situations they get into and the characters around them are nothing short of surreal, the way the react to each situation and deal with very serious issues could not be more realistic. A huge reason for this is his dialogue. Reminiscent of early Richard Linklater or Godard, his flowing, straight to the point script has you hooked from the word go. Fantastically direct delivery from both Shelley and Donovan allow this dialogue to shine and have you believe you these characters are friends you have known for years. In 'Trust' I believe Hartley has created one of the most earnest romances ever to be filmed. Utterly believable and almost heartbreakingly beautiful, this is certainly not a film to be missed. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unusual characters brilliantly portrayed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    timmy_501
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust opens with a stereotypical ignorant high school girl named Maria making petty demands of her parents and deliberately scandalizing them by explaining her future plans which involve marrying her jock boyfriend. She explains that he'll have to because she's pregnant and then leaves before she has a chance to realize that the news has caused her father to have a heart attack. Since she does leave we have a while longer to become familiar with her before her perfect world begins to crumble around her. She carelessly goes clothes shopping during the day and only stops by the school she is supposed to be attending to talk to her boyfriend. He's more worried about the upcoming football game than anything she can tell him; news of her pregnancy only angers him and he makes it clear that he won't take care of the child. Things get progressively worse for her as she's kicked out of her house, has a conversation with an insane woman, and is nearly raped before retreating to a quiet street where she attempts to drown her sorrow in a six pack. At this point Maria happens to meet Matthew, a gifted machinist who is so unsatisfied with his foolish employers and demanding father that he has developed a nasty violent streak. This initially seems to be an excellent match as the newly disillusioned Maria has become just as averse to nonsense as Matthew. The two slowly get to know each other and each one realizes that the other satisfies an innate desire that has previously gone unmet. Unfortunately circumstances keep arising to drive them apart and Matthew puts his trust in the wrong people. Writer/director Hal Hartley infuses this film with a uniquely cynical wit that meshes perfectly with the material to create a work that is at once funny and emotionally engaging. The film also is thematically satisfying in that it explores the attitudes of the characters and how those attitudes have been developed. Specifically, we see how the trust characters place in other people, particularly family members, is abused and subverted and how this has shaped various characters over time. Trust is one of those rare films that not only encapsulates a certain time and place but also presents some genuine truths about human behavior and offers a consistently engaging viewing experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful funny thing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ethanstraffin
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This remains one of my favorite films of all time. Hal Hartley's second feature is built around the same deliciously weird sense of humor as his debut "The Unbelievable Truth" -- but Adrienne Shelly (RIP) is even better in this one than she was in that one, and now we also get Martin Donovan as one of the more intense, flawed, and ultimately lovable romantic leads you'll ever see on film. (I almost put quotes around "romantic," because this is not a love story in the traditional "does the guy get the girl" sense. It's more interesting than that.) Between the characters and the dialogue, Hartley and his cast created something here that is wonderfully unique, humorous, and poignant. Think _Sex, Lies and Videotape_, sort of: there's that same sense of wondering whether these two messed-up people are ever going to get their acts together, and cheering them on either way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You can feel a new talent emerge
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From the first sequence of Hal Hartley's Trust a viewer knows he's in for a dark, obscure ride. It opens with the shot of a young teen named Maria (Adrienne Shelly), smoking while being scolded by her parents on what a punk deviant she is after being kicked out of school. She informs them that she is pregnant and the consumption of shock and shame leads to her father's on-spot heart attack and death. This should give you an inkling on what kind of film you're in for. Maria winds up running away from home to inform her jock-boyfriend she is pregnant. He, of course, couldn't care less, as he wants to focus on sports with little distraction. Now, Maria is alone until she meets Matthew (Martin Donovan), a man whose life keeps intercepting the focus of the film up until this point. Matthew lives with his abusive father, who looks on to his son with a condescending eye. He regards him as an irrelevant failure with no ability to hold down a job. This puts Matthew in a suicidal position, barely holding on as a whole. When both of them meet, we truly see that misery loves company. The relationship Maria and Matthew have in the film is talky and quiet, with Matthew bringing detached realism into the life of Maria's, which is already dominated by teenage naivety. Hartley paints both characters as flawed people that do not magically become repaired by each other, but find a more stable sense of life and trust in their opposites. Shelley captures the reckless spirit of Maria well, and Donovan is superb at giving his sadsack character Matthew a face and a soul. Their chemistry is the driving force behind Trust's success. There's a constant use of bright, vibrant color in the film that really amplifies the overall look and tone of the picture. In the opening shot is where this can be viewed as being most prominent. As stated, Shelley remains in close-up and the colors of her makeup and lip gloss remain eye-popping and totally "in your face." The remainder of the movie can occasionally turn up as grim, with a gray palette, but often does Hartley gather up the brightest, most visually attractive colors to see on-screen. But where Trust really excels is in its dialog. Smooth, fluent, and often subversively philosophical in terms of direct contact, he establishes a relationship between two unlikely characters that we can see grow and build as time goes on. They expand from the one-dimensional caricatures we initially view them as to complete humans we can recognize and sympathize with. Trust is the second film from Hal Hartley, who has made a career out of making comedy-dramas with an emphasis on character and monologues. He establishes himself quaintly here, assuring his independent status, and carefully makes use of such neglected things as mood and tone to set a nice standard in this drama. It's the kind of feeling that I see many going for. We walk in unsure, but emerge with the mindset that we've seen a new filmmaking talent in the works. God, do I love that feeling. Starring: Adrienne Shelly and Martin Donovan. Directed by: Hal Hartley.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a very fine film with no inherent gaps or mislead characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    italys
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most popular films delineate their stories in a rather comical and insipid way: the dialogue is often exchanged between characters as if it were bounced off a Spartan gladiator - and, in some cases very little to short-of-nothing is penetrable in the film. "Trust" is a film that inverses that idea - and does so with wit, charm, and most importantly: astute cleverness. The story begins with careful sequencing that portrays each character a new journey of life. We see an antisocial protagonist, a pregnant girl who recently dropped out of high school, and a motherly type whose apathy is cunning and partially insane. "Trust" is a love story that defies any clich&eacute; of filmmaking. The lead character pours his organism into the film and invokes integrity of personality without apprehension or any constipation (who can forget that wit from Mr Slaughter??) The film is about what happens when we take chances, and don't take chances. In short: it's about being and what happens when we share our being with others. The film's sequencing is what I loved most of all. It's weaved into a fabric that reminded me of early avant-garde films (the envelope of the story is reminiscent of Kubricks's older film "The Killing") and perhaps more-or-less surprising is the protagonist(played by Martin Donovan) exchanges silence; those rare moments in the film that can't help to be compared to the work of Godard. Momentarily, it shines solicitude and violence (the symbolism is slightly ironic and very insincere.) My favorite moments are about jeering characters who feel unwanted. A definite must-watch. I recommend it to anyone, everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a gifted filmmaker, treading water
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Long Island filmmaker Hal Hartley fights the sophomore jinx in the follow-up to his disarming debut feature 'The Unbelievable Truth' (1989). His second film is an overwritten satire drawn around the usual clich&eacute;s of modern suburban culture (television, dysfunctional families, etc.) and filtered through the director's trademark cast of quirky characters, none of whom resemble anyone raised in a genuine suburb. It lacks the offbeat appeal of his earlier effort, presenting a darker, more emotionally violent story about a pregnant high school dropout and her unlikely friendship with an alienated electronics whiz-kid, who carries a hand grenade "just in case". The odd, choreographed rhythm of Hartley's dialogue is still enjoyable, but this time his characters have nothing amusing to say, and the impression is left of a gifted talent trying too hard to overcome a creative block.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Inventive film experiment..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When student Maria tells her parents that she is pregnant it leads to her father dying of an heart-attack and herself being thrown out of the house. Coincidentally she meets electro-genius Matthew that lives with his despot of a father, and a peculiar romance arises. Hal Hartley's second feature film after his directorial debut "The Unbelievable Truth" (1989), is a surreal independent film about two loners from the working-class who are entangled in a whimsical though adorable romance without knowing that they are destined for each other. Compounded by witty and overlapping dialog, paradox situations and archetype characters, Hal Hartley creates a colorful and fabulous universe that describes life's irony, fragility, triviality, ambiguity and harmony in a comical, sophisticated and enriching way, and composes his minimalistic style with finely structured narrative, stylish photography, good music, costumes of great contrasts, innovating cinematography and rare moods. Hal Hartley's individualistic film style is characterized by fertile acting, detailed depictions of milieu, frequent close-ups, alternate perspectives and short takes, that in interaction with the talkative scripts fast dialog increases the films progression. "Trust" is an inventive film experiment about tricky family relations and people's need to be seen, heard and believed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comforting like a good sad balled...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Probably one of the least seen films that I have discussed over the last 6 months, this was a movie that I remember vividly as a teen, though in more glowing terms than I now see it. Trust was made by indie filmmaker Hal Hartley, who was renowned for his dialogue heavy films exploring regular people going about their lives. Now that I revisit this some 20 years later I think that perhaps his work also merits the dreaded "quirky" tag. The film starts with a domestic between a young girl and her Dad, the scene culminates with the Dad keeling over dead of a heart attack. The girl is one of two leads, her name is Maria, she is apparently high school age, is pregnant to the quarterback who she now wants nothing to do with, and not wanted at home as her mother blames her for the death of her dad. She also looks a lot like a duck. The other lead is Matthew, played by Martin Donovan in deadpan mode. He is a marginally psychotic TV repairman who is bullied by his single Dad and carries a grenade around with him. Real people dealing with real issues. There is much more of a plot than Maria and Matthew meet, share their problems and decide to make a go of things together, the action occurs as they progress through and come into contact with the various other characters in the film. No-one seems to get along, Maria's mum hates her, and later Matthew. Matthew's dad hates him, and everyone else it seems. Matthew is an angry loner who hates everyone and everyone hates, which leaves Maria and her unborn child as the victim of a tug of war. Everyone in the film seems to be 5% off-normal, not quite enough to be a caricature, but more than enough that they could all aptly be described as weird (at least) by normal people. In this vein Hartley is like Kevin Smith (really), he puts people that you might almost convince yourself that could exist, and in fact you might know someone who really reminds of one of them, only he fills every role with these one-in-a-million characters, so you have a town full of people that would ordinarily be the nut-job. The dialogue is scripted down to the nth degree, which unfortunately leads to conversations that alternate between snappy and robotic, at times in the same scene. At times it is almost like the characters are starting their response before the other sentence is finished. This film is most notable to me as being the first film I can remember seeing that had a character say the C-word, and a female character at that. If this sounds juvenile it is because when I watched the film I was, so it was a genuine surprise to me to see such a taboo word bandied about in an art house film. Even now that I watch this movie and see that I perhaps was looking at my memories with rose coloured glasses, there are moments that are both calculated that still have an impact, you know that the director is trying to scream "this is important" and want to ignore it but it still works. Like a good sad ballad, you know it is simply trying to manipulate your emotions, but turn off the lights and crank it loud and you can't help but caught up in it. Only Trust is a 90+ minute movie, it's hard to be "swept along" for that long when everything is so mechanical. Final Rating - 6.5 - 10. As I said at times it works, there are just too many dead spots in between those times. If you liked this review (or even if you didn't) check out oneguyrambling.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite Movie Of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (david-a-goddard)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this film in 1990 while I was in college and I loved it. I watched it over and over on VHS. I told everyone that this was my favorite movie of all time and watched every Hal Hartley movie I could find. Last night I stumbled across Trust on Netflix Instant and I thought I'd check it out to see if this film that I was so passionate about when I was 20 years old held up over time or if the 40 year old me would find it silly or dated. To my surprise I was blown away all over again by how ridiculously great it is. The smart stylized dialog, the music, the starkness, the silences, the camera framing, all of the whacked out but fully human characters, Martin Donovan and Adrienne Shelly so young and beautiful. As the final, simple, beautiful, frame of the film disappeared and credits rolled I was left sitting on the couch in a state of shocked amazement at the effect this film still has on me. Hands down my favorite movie of all time!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Top 100 of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    randallhurlbut
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hal Hartley's film TRUST is one of the top 100 achievements in the history of cinema. Hal, if you ever visit this site and see this statement I hope it makes you feel good. A d-girl in LA (development person in Hollywood) at a party once showed me a bookshelf at her home that contained her 10 or 15 favorite screenplays of all time... KANE, CHINATOWN, ... and one of my old screenplays (!)(she didn't know I was the author) and yeah... that makes you feel pretty damn good. So why does TRUST work so well? Maybe it's alchemy... getting sorta the right combination in the right quantities of abstraction, hyper-realism, irony, and distance. Hartley plays with archetypes and yet makes them singular. (That ain't easy.) It's like reading Theodore Dreyer filtered by Bertolt Brecht, or running into a Long Island Godard, but the fun version of Godard before he became too p-ssed off at the world. Hartley will stage a scene that you've seen a thousand times before, almost as genre commentary or put-on, then morph it into something you have NEVER seen before. Come to think of it, although Hartley is often thought of as the American Godard, at times he could almost be the American Bunuel (sorry Mr. Lynch). It would be easy to hate some of the characters in Hartley's TRUST, but Hartley doesn't. He may hate the situations, the contexts, the environments... but he certainly has no hatred for the people. It's a great love story and a quasi-homage to PIERROT LE FOU. It contains multitudes. It is a great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll marry you if you admit that respect, admiration and trust equal love."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paddy Jamieson (imdbpaddy@hotmail.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust (1990) - 10/10 As a filmmaker, Hal Hartley will forever divide audiences due to his unique story-telling style, dead-pan humour and tendency to favour words over action. His themes are often subtle and can take more than one viewing to fully understand or appreciate. Something which, understandably, can put off many. But whether you adore his style or think it to be moronic, no-one can deny that he is and always will be an inspired writer and director. A director who has influenced many and will continue to do so, I am sure, for years to come. Now I fall into the category of adoration and I believe 'Trust' to be his finest work. 'Trust' focuses on the coming together of two characters. Maria Coughlin, a pregnant high-school dropout who has just been the cause of her fathers fatal heart attack, and Matthew Slaughter, an intellectual loner who still lives with his sadistic father. Sound like a standard, if a bit over the top, romance? You couldn't be more wrong. What makes Hartley's films so special, and 'Trust' is no exception, are the characters he manages to create. Though the situations they get into and the characters around them are nothing short of surreal, the way the react to each situation and deal with very serious issues could not be more realistic. A huge reason for this is his dialogue. Reminiscent of early Richard Linklater or Godard, his flowing, straight to the point script has you hooked from the word go. Fantastically direct delivery from both Shelley and Donovan allow this dialogue to shine and have you believe you these characters are friends you have known for years. In 'Trust' I believe Hartley has created one of the most earnest romances ever to be filmed. Utterly believable and almost heartbreakingly beautiful, this is certainly not a film to be missed. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unusual characters brilliantly portrayed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    timmy_501
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust opens with a stereotypical ignorant high school girl named Maria making petty demands of her parents and deliberately scandalizing them by explaining her future plans which involve marrying her jock boyfriend. She explains that he'll have to because she's pregnant and then leaves before she has a chance to realize that the news has caused her father to have a heart attack. Since she does leave we have a while longer to become familiar with her before her perfect world begins to crumble around her. She carelessly goes clothes shopping during the day and only stops by the school she is supposed to be attending to talk to her boyfriend. He's more worried about the upcoming football game than anything she can tell him; news of her pregnancy only angers him and he makes it clear that he won't take care of the child. Things get progressively worse for her as she's kicked out of her house, has a conversation with an insane woman, and is nearly raped before retreating to a quiet street where she attempts to drown her sorrow in a six pack. At this point Maria happens to meet Matthew, a gifted machinist who is so unsatisfied with his foolish employers and demanding father that he has developed a nasty violent streak. This initially seems to be an excellent match as the newly disillusioned Maria has become just as averse to nonsense as Matthew. The two slowly get to know each other and each one realizes that the other satisfies an innate desire that has previously gone unmet. Unfortunately circumstances keep arising to drive them apart and Matthew puts his trust in the wrong people. Writer/director Hal Hartley infuses this film with a uniquely cynical wit that meshes perfectly with the material to create a work that is at once funny and emotionally engaging. The film also is thematically satisfying in that it explores the attitudes of the characters and how those attitudes have been developed. Specifically, we see how the trust characters place in other people, particularly family members, is abused and subverted and how this has shaped various characters over time. Trust is one of those rare films that not only encapsulates a certain time and place but also presents some genuine truths about human behavior and offers a consistently engaging viewing experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful funny thing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ethanstraffin
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This remains one of my favorite films of all time. Hal Hartley's second feature is built around the same deliciously weird sense of humor as his debut "The Unbelievable Truth" -- but Adrienne Shelly (RIP) is even better in this one than she was in that one, and now we also get Martin Donovan as one of the more intense, flawed, and ultimately lovable romantic leads you'll ever see on film. (I almost put quotes around "romantic," because this is not a love story in the traditional "does the guy get the girl" sense. It's more interesting than that.) Between the characters and the dialogue, Hartley and his cast created something here that is wonderfully unique, humorous, and poignant. Think _Sex, Lies and Videotape_, sort of: there's that same sense of wondering whether these two messed-up people are ever going to get their acts together, and cheering them on either way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You can feel a new talent emerge
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From the first sequence of Hal Hartley's Trust a viewer knows he's in for a dark, obscure ride. It opens with the shot of a young teen named Maria (Adrienne Shelly), smoking while being scolded by her parents on what a punk deviant she is after being kicked out of school. She informs them that she is pregnant and the consumption of shock and shame leads to her father's on-spot heart attack and death. This should give you an inkling on what kind of film you're in for. Maria winds up running away from home to inform her jock-boyfriend she is pregnant. He, of course, couldn't care less, as he wants to focus on sports with little distraction. Now, Maria is alone until she meets Matthew (Martin Donovan), a man whose life keeps intercepting the focus of the film up until this point. Matthew lives with his abusive father, who looks on to his son with a condescending eye. He regards him as an irrelevant failure with no ability to hold down a job. This puts Matthew in a suicidal position, barely holding on as a whole. When both of them meet, we truly see that misery loves company. The relationship Maria and Matthew have in the film is talky and quiet, with Matthew bringing detached realism into the life of Maria's, which is already dominated by teenage naivety. Hartley paints both characters as flawed people that do not magically become repaired by each other, but find a more stable sense of life and trust in their opposites. Shelley captures the reckless spirit of Maria well, and Donovan is superb at giving his sadsack character Matthew a face and a soul. Their chemistry is the driving force behind Trust's success. There's a constant use of bright, vibrant color in the film that really amplifies the overall look and tone of the picture. In the opening shot is where this can be viewed as being most prominent. As stated, Shelley remains in close-up and the colors of her makeup and lip gloss remain eye-popping and totally "in your face." The remainder of the movie can occasionally turn up as grim, with a gray palette, but often does Hartley gather up the brightest, most visually attractive colors to see on-screen. But where Trust really excels is in its dialog. Smooth, fluent, and often subversively philosophical in terms of direct contact, he establishes a relationship between two unlikely characters that we can see grow and build as time goes on. They expand from the one-dimensional caricatures we initially view them as to complete humans we can recognize and sympathize with. Trust is the second film from Hal Hartley, who has made a career out of making comedy-dramas with an emphasis on character and monologues. He establishes himself quaintly here, assuring his independent status, and carefully makes use of such neglected things as mood and tone to set a nice standard in this drama. It's the kind of feeling that I see many going for. We walk in unsure, but emerge with the mindset that we've seen a new filmmaking talent in the works. God, do I love that feeling. Starring: Adrienne Shelly and Martin Donovan. Directed by: Hal Hartley.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a very fine film with no inherent gaps or mislead characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    italys
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most popular films delineate their stories in a rather comical and insipid way: the dialogue is often exchanged between characters as if it were bounced off a Spartan gladiator - and, in some cases very little to short-of-nothing is penetrable in the film. "Trust" is a film that inverses that idea - and does so with wit, charm, and most importantly: astute cleverness. The story begins with careful sequencing that portrays each character a new journey of life. We see an antisocial protagonist, a pregnant girl who recently dropped out of high school, and a motherly type whose apathy is cunning and partially insane. "Trust" is a love story that defies any clich&eacute; of filmmaking. The lead character pours his organism into the film and invokes integrity of personality without apprehension or any constipation (who can forget that wit from Mr Slaughter??) The film is about what happens when we take chances, and don't take chances. In short: it's about being and what happens when we share our being with others. The film's sequencing is what I loved most of all. It's weaved into a fabric that reminded me of early avant-garde films (the envelope of the story is reminiscent of Kubricks's older film "The Killing") and perhaps more-or-less surprising is the protagonist(played by Martin Donovan) exchanges silence; those rare moments in the film that can't help to be compared to the work of Godard. Momentarily, it shines solicitude and violence (the symbolism is slightly ironic and very insincere.) My favorite moments are about jeering characters who feel unwanted. A definite must-watch. I recommend it to anyone, everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a gifted filmmaker, treading water
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Long Island filmmaker Hal Hartley fights the sophomore jinx in the follow-up to his disarming debut feature 'The Unbelievable Truth' (1989). His second film is an overwritten satire drawn around the usual clich&eacute;s of modern suburban culture (television, dysfunctional families, etc.) and filtered through the director's trademark cast of quirky characters, none of whom resemble anyone raised in a genuine suburb. It lacks the offbeat appeal of his earlier effort, presenting a darker, more emotionally violent story about a pregnant high school dropout and her unlikely friendship with an alienated electronics whiz-kid, who carries a hand grenade "just in case". The odd, choreographed rhythm of Hartley's dialogue is still enjoyable, but this time his characters have nothing amusing to say, and the impression is left of a gifted talent trying too hard to overcome a creative block.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Inventive film experiment..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When student Maria tells her parents that she is pregnant it leads to her father dying of an heart-attack and herself being thrown out of the house. Coincidentally she meets electro-genius Matthew that lives with his despot of a father, and a peculiar romance arises. Hal Hartley's second feature film after his directorial debut "The Unbelievable Truth" (1989), is a surreal independent film about two loners from the working-class who are entangled in a whimsical though adorable romance without knowing that they are destined for each other. Compounded by witty and overlapping dialog, paradox situations and archetype characters, Hal Hartley creates a colorful and fabulous universe that describes life's irony, fragility, triviality, ambiguity and harmony in a comical, sophisticated and enriching way, and composes his minimalistic style with finely structured narrative, stylish photography, good music, costumes of great contrasts, innovating cinematography and rare moods. Hal Hartley's individualistic film style is characterized by fertile acting, detailed depictions of milieu, frequent close-ups, alternate perspectives and short takes, that in interaction with the talkative scripts fast dialog increases the films progression. "Trust" is an inventive film experiment about tricky family relations and people's need to be seen, heard and believed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comforting like a good sad balled...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Probably one of the least seen films that I have discussed over the last 6 months, this was a movie that I remember vividly as a teen, though in more glowing terms than I now see it. Trust was made by indie filmmaker Hal Hartley, who was renowned for his dialogue heavy films exploring regular people going about their lives. Now that I revisit this some 20 years later I think that perhaps his work also merits the dreaded "quirky" tag. The film starts with a domestic between a young girl and her Dad, the scene culminates with the Dad keeling over dead of a heart attack. The girl is one of two leads, her name is Maria, she is apparently high school age, is pregnant to the quarterback who she now wants nothing to do with, and not wanted at home as her mother blames her for the death of her dad. She also looks a lot like a duck. The other lead is Matthew, played by Martin Donovan in deadpan mode. He is a marginally psychotic TV repairman who is bullied by his single Dad and carries a grenade around with him. Real people dealing with real issues. There is much more of a plot than Maria and Matthew meet, share their problems and decide to make a go of things together, the action occurs as they progress through and come into contact with the various other characters in the film. No-one seems to get along, Maria's mum hates her, and later Matthew. Matthew's dad hates him, and everyone else it seems. Matthew is an angry loner who hates everyone and everyone hates, which leaves Maria and her unborn child as the victim of a tug of war. Everyone in the film seems to be 5% off-normal, not quite enough to be a caricature, but more than enough that they could all aptly be described as weird (at least) by normal people. In this vein Hartley is like Kevin Smith (really), he puts people that you might almost convince yourself that could exist, and in fact you might know someone who really reminds of one of them, only he fills every role with these one-in-a-million characters, so you have a town full of people that would ordinarily be the nut-job. The dialogue is scripted down to the nth degree, which unfortunately leads to conversations that alternate between snappy and robotic, at times in the same scene. At times it is almost like the characters are starting their response before the other sentence is finished. This film is most notable to me as being the first film I can remember seeing that had a character say the C-word, and a female character at that. If this sounds juvenile it is because when I watched the film I was, so it was a genuine surprise to me to see such a taboo word bandied about in an art house film. Even now that I watch this movie and see that I perhaps was looking at my memories with rose coloured glasses, there are moments that are both calculated that still have an impact, you know that the director is trying to scream "this is important" and want to ignore it but it still works. Like a good sad ballad, you know it is simply trying to manipulate your emotions, but turn off the lights and crank it loud and you can't help but caught up in it. Only Trust is a 90+ minute movie, it's hard to be "swept along" for that long when everything is so mechanical. Final Rating - 6.5 - 10. As I said at times it works, there are just too many dead spots in between those times. If you liked this review (or even if you didn't) check out oneguyrambling.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite Movie Of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (david-a-goddard)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this film in 1990 while I was in college and I loved it. I watched it over and over on VHS. I told everyone that this was my favorite movie of all time and watched every Hal Hartley movie I could find. Last night I stumbled across Trust on Netflix Instant and I thought I'd check it out to see if this film that I was so passionate about when I was 20 years old held up over time or if the 40 year old me would find it silly or dated. To my surprise I was blown away all over again by how ridiculously great it is. The smart stylized dialog, the music, the starkness, the silences, the camera framing, all of the whacked out but fully human characters, Martin Donovan and Adrienne Shelly so young and beautiful. As the final, simple, beautiful, frame of the film disappeared and credits rolled I was left sitting on the couch in a state of shocked amazement at the effect this film still has on me. Hands down my favorite movie of all time!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Top 100 of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    randallhurlbut
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hal Hartley's film TRUST is one of the top 100 achievements in the history of cinema. Hal, if you ever visit this site and see this statement I hope it makes you feel good. A d-girl in LA (development person in Hollywood) at a party once showed me a bookshelf at her home that contained her 10 or 15 favorite screenplays of all time... KANE, CHINATOWN, ... and one of my old screenplays (!)(she didn't know I was the author) and yeah... that makes you feel pretty damn good. So why does TRUST work so well? Maybe it's alchemy... getting sorta the right combination in the right quantities of abstraction, hyper-realism, irony, and distance. Hartley plays with archetypes and yet makes them singular. (That ain't easy.) It's like reading Theodore Dreyer filtered by Bertolt Brecht, or running into a Long Island Godard, but the fun version of Godard before he became too p-ssed off at the world. Hartley will stage a scene that you've seen a thousand times before, almost as genre commentary or put-on, then morph it into something you have NEVER seen before. Come to think of it, although Hartley is often thought of as the American Godard, at times he could almost be the American Bunuel (sorry Mr. Lynch). It would be easy to hate some of the characters in Hartley's TRUST, but Hartley doesn't. He may hate the situations, the contexts, the environments... but he certainly has no hatred for the people. It's a great love story and a quasi-homage to PIERROT LE FOU. It contains multitudes. It is a great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll marry you if you admit that respect, admiration and trust equal love."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paddy Jamieson (imdbpaddy@hotmail.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust (1990) - 10/10 As a filmmaker, Hal Hartley will forever divide audiences due to his unique story-telling style, dead-pan humour and tendency to favour words over action. His themes are often subtle and can take more than one viewing to fully understand or appreciate. Something which, understandably, can put off many. But whether you adore his style or think it to be moronic, no-one can deny that he is and always will be an inspired writer and director. A director who has influenced many and will continue to do so, I am sure, for years to come. Now I fall into the category of adoration and I believe 'Trust' to be his finest work. 'Trust' focuses on the coming together of two characters. Maria Coughlin, a pregnant high-school dropout who has just been the cause of her fathers fatal heart attack, and Matthew Slaughter, an intellectual loner who still lives with his sadistic father. Sound like a standard, if a bit over the top, romance? You couldn't be more wrong. What makes Hartley's films so special, and 'Trust' is no exception, are the characters he manages to create. Though the situations they get into and the characters around them are nothing short of surreal, the way the react to each situation and deal with very serious issues could not be more realistic. A huge reason for this is his dialogue. Reminiscent of early Richard Linklater or Godard, his flowing, straight to the point script has you hooked from the word go. Fantastically direct delivery from both Shelley and Donovan allow this dialogue to shine and have you believe you these characters are friends you have known for years. In 'Trust' I believe Hartley has created one of the most earnest romances ever to be filmed. Utterly believable and almost heartbreakingly beautiful, this is certainly not a film to be missed. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unusual characters brilliantly portrayed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    timmy_501
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust opens with a stereotypical ignorant high school girl named Maria making petty demands of her parents and deliberately scandalizing them by explaining her future plans which involve marrying her jock boyfriend. She explains that he'll have to because she's pregnant and then leaves before she has a chance to realize that the news has caused her father to have a heart attack. Since she does leave we have a while longer to become familiar with her before her perfect world begins to crumble around her. She carelessly goes clothes shopping during the day and only stops by the school she is supposed to be attending to talk to her boyfriend. He's more worried about the upcoming football game than anything she can tell him; news of her pregnancy only angers him and he makes it clear that he won't take care of the child. Things get progressively worse for her as she's kicked out of her house, has a conversation with an insane woman, and is nearly raped before retreating to a quiet street where she attempts to drown her sorrow in a six pack. At this point Maria happens to meet Matthew, a gifted machinist who is so unsatisfied with his foolish employers and demanding father that he has developed a nasty violent streak. This initially seems to be an excellent match as the newly disillusioned Maria has become just as averse to nonsense as Matthew. The two slowly get to know each other and each one realizes that the other satisfies an innate desire that has previously gone unmet. Unfortunately circumstances keep arising to drive them apart and Matthew puts his trust in the wrong people. Writer/director Hal Hartley infuses this film with a uniquely cynical wit that meshes perfectly with the material to create a work that is at once funny and emotionally engaging. The film also is thematically satisfying in that it explores the attitudes of the characters and how those attitudes have been developed. Specifically, we see how the trust characters place in other people, particularly family members, is abused and subverted and how this has shaped various characters over time. Trust is one of those rare films that not only encapsulates a certain time and place but also presents some genuine truths about human behavior and offers a consistently engaging viewing experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
