<filme>
 <id>
  1105
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120670
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1998
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Tormenta de Fogo
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  4.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Firefighter Jesse Graves has to save ornithologist Jennifer and other people caught in a forest fire, which was set up by the lawyer of convicted killer Earl Shaye, who escaped from the ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Firefighter Jesse Graves has to save ornithologist Jennifer and other people caught in a forest fire, which was set up by the lawyer of convicted killer Earl Shaye, who escaped from the prison with several of his inmates posing as firefighters to recover $37,000,000 in stashed loot.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   fire
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   jail break
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   forest fire
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   criminal
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   prison
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Dean Semler
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Chris Soth
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Howie Long
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Scott Glenn
  </ator>
  <ator>
   William Forsythe
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Movie brings fear of fires into focus
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sharon
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Firestorm is a movie that people who are 15 and older might enjoy to watch. The acting in the movie truly gives the film its cohesiveness. There is no outstanding actor/actress. They all work together to make the film work. Firestorm is not the best nor the worst film ever. It is a good solid action (crime) drama. Firestorm is a movie which helps to humanize firefighters. The criminal elements in the film are truly ruthless and deserve no sympathy. We are all afraid of fire burning down our homes, consuming our life's memories, and burning alive. This movie brings these fears into focus. Firestorm also reminds us all as to why every community needs firefighters. For it short duration of about an hour and one half, Firestorm will keep you occupied. Grab the popcorn, soda, and some extra water (just in case). I give it four thumbs up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Light Entertainment With A Soft R Rating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Standard, innocuous, and incendiary this rather enjoyable Action Movie is light entertainment with a soft R rating. Pretty tame as these things go, it has some death defying dumb stunts and the whole thing is a notch above a TV Movie and can be quite enjoyable in a humdrum sort of way. If you don't expect your leading Actor to act or can tolerate a script that is dampened by a standard re-write of a glutted genre, then settle in for a Movie that doesn't ask much and is a jump into a not so hot Movie, but it doesn't leave you cold either. William Forsythe (has he ever disappointed) once again is a force to be reckoned on screen and steals the show with his Evil stare and detached dementia. This bad guy and the raging inferno are the reasons to catch this when you are in the mood for some pizza and beer or cheese and wine, but keep an eye on the hearth or the fondue.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You're a bird watcher?!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lost-in-limbo
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Toasty, by-the-numbers b-grade natural disaster action joint which has a stout-hearted Howie Long playing a smoke-jumper that has to tackle firestorms and William Forsythe's gleefully hammy bad guy persona. Forsythe is great and you know you can always expect a show whenever his on screen, as he simply knows how to play devious tyrants. Also along for the heatwave are Scott Glenn and Barry Pepper. Simple-minded writing makes sure that the bubblegum action flows with the blatant heroics coming to the forefront, which is led by Long and Glenn. Hammy dialogues (I can't remember the last time I heard someone be called a butt-munch) are filtered in and the stunt-work can get hot and heavy. Too bad some of the computer effects come off rather lousy, especially during the final climatic scenes. Director Dean Semler (who was cinematographer for such films as "Mad Max 2" and "Razorback") keeps it rugged and heightens it with some stylish shots of the woodland terrain. Disposable, but crackling entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good for what it was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MargoC
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen worse and of course I've seen better. I enjoyed Backdraft, and I figured this was just Backdraft in the woods. It was just what I expected, a cheesy action movie, with "witty" lines and a totally off the wall villain. William Forsythe is one of my favorite "villain" actors, and he does not disappoint. There's something about him that's really creepy. Favorite line? "Heeeeeeeeeeeeey smokejumpah! You still alive?" If you're looking for a B movie that has pretty good action scenes and bad dialogue, this is the one for you. The fire scenes were actually quite good too. Great improbable stunts too. Too bad Howie didn't take his shirt off, I would have given it another star.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Firestorm" Blows Smoke
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You cannot see the trees for the testosterone in director Dean Semler's synthetic outdoors action saga "Firestorm," starring sportscaster Howie Long as a stalwart smoke jumper who parachutes into raging Wyoming forest fires to rescue little gals and grown-up gals from getting cremated. Any sparks that Howie ignited as an actor in John Woo's "Broken Arrow" sputter in "Firestorm" with Long's pulp diction performance. Chris Soth's one-dimensional script doesn't help Howie much as escaped convicts and flaming infernos challenge his physical prowess. There is nothing compelling about Howie's character and his charisma cannot compensate for this monolithic hero. Leanly plotted as a sapling but predictable as a plunging redwood, "Firestorm" kindles minimal excitement with its prefabricated plot and Howie's Styrofoam heroics. Of course, juvenile-minded audiences who don't demand much from their cinematic exercises may find this half-toasted tale tolerable. What modicum of merit the movie musters lies in its premise. Ultraviolent villain Randy Earl Shaye (William Forsythe of "Once Upon A Time in America") cons his shyster lawyer (Terry Kelly of "Christina") into committing wildfire arson. Shaye wants out of the Wyoming State Penitentiary to get his $20-million. It seems that the prison dispatches short-time convicts to help extinguish forest fires. Shaye plans to use the forest fire as a cover for his escape. Stabbing a friendly prisoner on the fire detail, Shaye disguises himself as the dead man, and then sneaks out of the joint. Soth asks us to believe that a man could escape from prison based largely on a tattoo worn behind the ear. As villains go, Shaye shows early promise as a worthy adversary, until the filmmakers contrive obvious flaws in his character that assure his mortality. Veteran heavy William Forsythe supplies appropriate plug-ugly menace as Randy Earl Shaye. When we initially see Shaye, he resembles Sean Connery from the "The Rock," with a beard and blond messianic coiffure. The filmmakers emphasize Shaye's villainy by showing not only the character of Shaye but also Forsythe's sneering face together in the same shot with the man that he kills. Driving the point home, director Dean Semler wants audiences to realize that Shaye is clearly an unrepentant sadist. Sadly, the events of the plot turn more on Shaye's sadism than on his criminal ingenuity. Shaye's comeuppance is horribly graphic but richly deserved for his murderous demeanor. "Firestorm" follows clench-jawed Jesse Graves (ex-Raiders football star Howie Long) as he thwarts Shaye's escape. The Spartan Chris Soth screenplay tosses in a woman to liven things up. "Titanic" supporting player Suzy Amis appears here as Jennifer, an ornithologist who finds herself trapped by the wildfire blaze. Fleeing from the fire, she runs smack into Randy Earl and his armed and stupid henchmen masquerading as Canadian firefighters. You must have stupid henchmen in "Firestorm" so that they can brag about their means of escape. When Jennifer finally gets away, Shaye cannot afford to let her live because she knows his plans. Meanwhile, when Jesse learns about the forest fire, he skydives into it singlehandedly. He stumbles into Shaye, Jennifer and Shaye's other henchmen. In other words, "Firestorm" constantly moves ahead in terms of storytelling, but with little efficiency, plausibility, or imagination. When Shaye tries his bogus Canadian firefighters story out, Jesse is neither impressed nor convinced. Matching fists and wits with Shaye's motley crew, our brawny firefighter hero sneaks off with Jennifer and they evade Randy Earl until a climactic fight on a lake about to be engulfed in a withering blaze. "Firestorm" derives its title from the phenomenon which occurs when two fires collide and suck all of the oxygen out of the air, creating one of Mother Nature's nasty nuclear-style blasts which destroys everything in it. Soth's script contains those suitable elements that any decent he-man actioneer should boast. The effect, however, is less than incendiary. The problem with Soth along with uncredited scenarist Graham Yost of "Speed" and "Hard Target" is that their characters are a poorly developed bundle of stick figures with neither depth nor complexity. Randy Earl Shaye is supposed to be a homicidal genius who goes so far as to impersonate a prisoner (brutally killing the convict by stabbing him in the neck), but doesn't know squat about forest fires. Jennifer claims to be the offspring of a third generation Marine. Boasting that she can field strip automatic weapons like an AK-47, she fails to notice that the auto-pistol that she swiped from a sex offender isn't loaded. "Firestorm" does other things wrong, too. A neat gimmick--ping-pong balls that explode to start firesis lamely utilized. The first time that they use it as a trick during a ping-pong game, and the second time, Howie uses it to start a backfire to divert oxygen from the first fire. But the ping-pong balls disappear afterward, never to be used again. There is a running joke about axes that the filmmakers bungle, too. At one point in the plot, Jesse and Jennifer lay a trap for Shaye and his sex-predator henchmen that goes afoul because it is so ineptly planned with half-baked results! The only surprises in "Firestorm" are provided by rugged Scott Glenn as battle-weary smoke jumper Wynt Perkins who is crippled while rescuing a dog from a burning house. Revealing more about his role and character would cut down on what little energy "Firestorm" contrives. Sentimentality drips off the script at points, especially at the end when Jennifer learns that she has been incubating two bird eggs during this maelstrom of action. "Dances with Wolves" Oscar-winning photographer Dean Semler makes his less than inflammatory directorial debut with "Firestorm." When he takes his cameras up for aerial shots of British Columbia, you find your breath catching in your throat. Sadly, Semler doesn't breath the same magic into the thin, adolescent storyline. The special effects of the firestorm aren't that imaginative. You feel like you're trapped by expensive looking computer graphics instead of a real wildfire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It burns, it burns!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BroadswordCallinDannyBoy
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A cunning criminal sets a fire to cover his escape from prison. He takes a hostage and promises fellow cohorts a share of a large stash that he hid sometime ago. It is up to smokejumper Jesse Graves to save the hostage and stop the villain. The premise is unbelievably hokey, but it still manages to fall short of the plots hokeyness. The movie is just some loosely connected action scenes that are made with unimpressive staging and mediocre special effects. From the first super cheesy scene the acting is virtually non-existent, except for William Forysthe who manages to entertain with his super-evil and calculating villain persona. But still, he can't make something out of nothing. Nothing is an apt way to put it since this is really a film about just that. There is little mention of plot, little mention of the smokejumpers' techniques, little mention of the science of fire, but there is lots of fire. LOTS AND LOTS OF FIRE. But fire is just fire. It can't make a movie by itself. Re-watch Twister for a relatively plot-less disaster/action movie done right. Or if fire is your thing Backdraft or Ladder 49 will do. Just avoid this. --- 2/10 Rated R for violence
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    William Forsythe rocks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ghostman16
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    firestorm is a cliffhanger type thriller starring Howie Long as Jesse Graves a heroic fire fighter who is up against a group of escaped convicts led by the Psycotic Randell who has kidnapped a bird watcher played by Suzi Amis and has caused a giant fire that is turning into a firestorm.now Jesse must now save the hostage stop the fire and take care of Randell. firestorm is quite a fun little thriller Howie Long was quite a good hero shame he didn't make anymore action films after this.William Forsythe was absolutely brilliant as the main bad guy Randell William normally plays decent bad guys anyway like in out for justice and stone cold.even Scott Glenn is in it. to end the review firestorm is a well made action thriller a bit clich&eacute;d but still cool 7 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even a real movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Candice Boyle (SalamanderGirl)
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although nowhere as infamous as John Travolta's Battlefield Earth or Warren Beatty's Ishtar or George Lucas's Howard the Duck, this sorry excuse for a movie is equal in unintentional humor. Some of the worst computer graphics ever seen, a "performance" so wooden from Howie Long it makes Stallone look like Ben Kingsley, and scenes that are so unrealistic Ed Wood would not have filmed them. One scene, the "Fire Storm" scene, shows raging computer graphic flames rushing over mountains like a gigantic burning tornado, covering hundreds of square miles in three seconds flat. Everyone in the theater was laughing, except maybe for the smart ones who had already walked out. The director went on to make one of the more forgettable Steven Seagal straight-to-video movies, and the writer was never heard from again. And poor Suzi Amis; You'd think James Cameron might have helped his gal get better movie roles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Than Anticipated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is kind of a Class B action film and it stars an ex-pro football player (Howie Long) making his debut in the movies. Because of that, I didn't expect much. I was surprised. It's actually a good adventure story and Long was capable in his acting. He was aided by three fine actors who usually are interesting in whatever roles they play: Scott Glenn, Suzy Amis and William Forstyhe. Glenn is the best-known of the three but had the least lines in here. Forsythe was good at playing what he does best: the nasty villain. This movie was also well-filmed with some nice closeup and camera angles. The only complaints were some dopey dialog in spots and a little too much profanity in spots. Otherwise, for a no-name movie starring a rookie actor it was better than I anticipated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow. That's all I can say. Or is it?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dragonreborn008
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Holy Crap. Howie Long should be promoted to Master Actor. He is so good at expressing his emotions. He should teach a class about emotions at a major college. A major college about human emotions. He is a vortex, that drags all of his surrounding actors and co-workers into his world. The drama in this movie is incredible as well. The whole "firestorm" element pulls you to the edge of your seat and then drops you on your face. I wish I could throw an axe like Howie Long. When the escaped convicts pretended to be Canadian, I wasn't sure whether they were Canadian or American. And when the Bird watcher stated how she had Marine training, I could see how perfect a match those two little love birds were. I really love how the whole plot was summarized in about 10 minutes during the entire feature, this allowed for more Howie Long content. This was an incredible movie. I would recommend it to anyone. Except to pregnant women. This movie has a few side effects such as premature birth, diarrhea, and drilling your eyes out with a jackhammer. I would also recommend Fire Down Below (Steven Seagal). If I could make one wish for anything in the whole world, it would be for Howie Long to restart(or start) his film career.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Movie brings fear of fires into focus
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sharon
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Firestorm is a movie that people who are 15 and older might enjoy to watch. The acting in the movie truly gives the film its cohesiveness. There is no outstanding actor/actress. They all work together to make the film work. Firestorm is not the best nor the worst film ever. It is a good solid action (crime) drama. Firestorm is a movie which helps to humanize firefighters. The criminal elements in the film are truly ruthless and deserve no sympathy. We are all afraid of fire burning down our homes, consuming our life's memories, and burning alive. This movie brings these fears into focus. Firestorm also reminds us all as to why every community needs firefighters. For it short duration of about an hour and one half, Firestorm will keep you occupied. Grab the popcorn, soda, and some extra water (just in case). I give it four thumbs up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Light Entertainment With A Soft R Rating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Standard, innocuous, and incendiary this rather enjoyable Action Movie is light entertainment with a soft R rating. Pretty tame as these things go, it has some death defying dumb stunts and the whole thing is a notch above a TV Movie and can be quite enjoyable in a humdrum sort of way. If you don't expect your leading Actor to act or can tolerate a script that is dampened by a standard re-write of a glutted genre, then settle in for a Movie that doesn't ask much and is a jump into a not so hot Movie, but it doesn't leave you cold either. William Forsythe (has he ever disappointed) once again is a force to be reckoned on screen and steals the show with his Evil stare and detached dementia. This bad guy and the raging inferno are the reasons to catch this when you are in the mood for some pizza and beer or cheese and wine, but keep an eye on the hearth or the fondue.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You're a bird watcher?!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lost-in-limbo
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Toasty, by-the-numbers b-grade natural disaster action joint which has a stout-hearted Howie Long playing a smoke-jumper that has to tackle firestorms and William Forsythe's gleefully hammy bad guy persona. Forsythe is great and you know you can always expect a show whenever his on screen, as he simply knows how to play devious tyrants. Also along for the heatwave are Scott Glenn and Barry Pepper. Simple-minded writing makes sure that the bubblegum action flows with the blatant heroics coming to the forefront, which is led by Long and Glenn. Hammy dialogues (I can't remember the last time I heard someone be called a butt-munch) are filtered in and the stunt-work can get hot and heavy. Too bad some of the computer effects come off rather lousy, especially during the final climatic scenes. Director Dean Semler (who was cinematographer for such films as "Mad Max 2" and "Razorback") keeps it rugged and heightens it with some stylish shots of the woodland terrain. Disposable, but crackling entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good for what it was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MargoC
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen worse and of course I've seen better. I enjoyed Backdraft, and I figured this was just Backdraft in the woods. It was just what I expected, a cheesy action movie, with "witty" lines and a totally off the wall villain. William Forsythe is one of my favorite "villain" actors, and he does not disappoint. There's something about him that's really creepy. Favorite line? "Heeeeeeeeeeeeey smokejumpah! You still alive?" If you're looking for a B movie that has pretty good action scenes and bad dialogue, this is the one for you. The fire scenes were actually quite good too. Great improbable stunts too. Too bad Howie didn't take his shirt off, I would have given it another star.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Firestorm" Blows Smoke
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You cannot see the trees for the testosterone in director Dean Semler's synthetic outdoors action saga "Firestorm," starring sportscaster Howie Long as a stalwart smoke jumper who parachutes into raging Wyoming forest fires to rescue little gals and grown-up gals from getting cremated. Any sparks that Howie ignited as an actor in John Woo's "Broken Arrow" sputter in "Firestorm" with Long's pulp diction performance. Chris Soth's one-dimensional script doesn't help Howie much as escaped convicts and flaming infernos challenge his physical prowess. There is nothing compelling about Howie's character and his charisma cannot compensate for this monolithic hero. Leanly plotted as a sapling but predictable as a plunging redwood, "Firestorm" kindles minimal excitement with its prefabricated plot and Howie's Styrofoam heroics. Of course, juvenile-minded audiences who don't demand much from their cinematic exercises may find this half-toasted tale tolerable. What modicum of merit the movie musters lies in its premise. Ultraviolent villain Randy Earl Shaye (William Forsythe of "Once Upon A Time in America") cons his shyster lawyer (Terry Kelly of "Christina") into committing wildfire arson. Shaye wants out of the Wyoming State Penitentiary to get his $20-million. It seems that the prison dispatches short-time convicts to help extinguish forest fires. Shaye plans to use the forest fire as a cover for his escape. Stabbing a friendly prisoner on the fire detail, Shaye disguises himself as the dead man, and then sneaks out of the joint. Soth asks us to believe that a man could escape from prison based largely on a tattoo worn behind the ear. As villains go, Shaye shows early promise as a worthy adversary, until the filmmakers contrive obvious flaws in his character that assure his mortality. Veteran heavy William Forsythe supplies appropriate plug-ugly menace as Randy Earl Shaye. When we initially see Shaye, he resembles Sean Connery from the "The Rock," with a beard and blond messianic coiffure. The filmmakers emphasize Shaye's villainy by showing not only the character of Shaye but also Forsythe's sneering face together in the same shot with the man that he kills. Driving the point home, director Dean Semler wants audiences to realize that Shaye is clearly an unrepentant sadist. Sadly, the events of the plot turn more on Shaye's sadism than on his criminal ingenuity. Shaye's comeuppance is horribly graphic but richly deserved for his murderous demeanor. "Firestorm" follows clench-jawed Jesse Graves (ex-Raiders football star Howie Long) as he thwarts Shaye's escape. The Spartan Chris Soth screenplay tosses in a woman to liven things up. "Titanic" supporting player Suzy Amis appears here as Jennifer, an ornithologist who finds herself trapped by the wildfire blaze. Fleeing from the fire, she runs smack into Randy Earl and his armed and stupid henchmen masquerading as Canadian firefighters. You must have stupid henchmen in "Firestorm" so that they can brag about their means of escape. When Jennifer finally gets away, Shaye cannot afford to let her live because she knows his plans. Meanwhile, when Jesse learns about the forest fire, he skydives into it singlehandedly. He stumbles into Shaye, Jennifer and Shaye's other henchmen. In other words, "Firestorm" constantly moves ahead in terms of storytelling, but with little efficiency, plausibility, or imagination. When Shaye tries his bogus Canadian firefighters story out, Jesse is neither impressed nor convinced. Matching fists and wits with Shaye's motley crew, our brawny firefighter hero sneaks off with Jennifer and they evade Randy Earl until a climactic fight on a lake about to be engulfed in a withering blaze. "Firestorm" derives its title from the phenomenon which occurs when two fires collide and suck all of the oxygen out of the air, creating one of Mother Nature's nasty nuclear-style blasts which destroys everything in it. Soth's script contains those suitable elements that any decent he-man actioneer should boast. The effect, however, is less than incendiary. The problem with Soth along with uncredited scenarist Graham Yost of "Speed" and "Hard Target" is that their characters are a poorly developed bundle of stick figures with neither depth nor complexity. Randy Earl Shaye is supposed to be a homicidal genius who goes so far as to impersonate a prisoner (brutally killing the convict by stabbing him in the neck), but doesn't know squat about forest fires. Jennifer claims to be the offspring of a third generation Marine. Boasting that she can field strip automatic weapons like an AK-47, she fails to notice that the auto-pistol that she swiped from a sex offender isn't loaded. "Firestorm" does other things wrong, too. A neat gimmick--ping-pong balls that explode to start firesis lamely utilized. The first time that they use it as a trick during a ping-pong game, and the second time, Howie uses it to start a backfire to divert oxygen from the first fire. But the ping-pong balls disappear afterward, never to be used again. There is a running joke about axes that the filmmakers bungle, too. At one point in the plot, Jesse and Jennifer lay a trap for Shaye and his sex-predator henchmen that goes afoul because it is so ineptly planned with half-baked results! The only surprises in "Firestorm" are provided by rugged Scott Glenn as battle-weary smoke jumper Wynt Perkins who is crippled while rescuing a dog from a burning house. Revealing more about his role and character would cut down on what little energy "Firestorm" contrives. Sentimentality drips off the script at points, especially at the end when Jennifer learns that she has been incubating two bird eggs during this maelstrom of action. "Dances with Wolves" Oscar-winning photographer Dean Semler makes his less than inflammatory directorial debut with "Firestorm." When he takes his cameras up for aerial shots of British Columbia, you find your breath catching in your throat. Sadly, Semler doesn't breath the same magic into the thin, adolescent storyline. The special effects of the firestorm aren't that imaginative. You feel like you're trapped by expensive looking computer graphics instead of a real wildfire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It burns, it burns!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BroadswordCallinDannyBoy
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A cunning criminal sets a fire to cover his escape from prison. He takes a hostage and promises fellow cohorts a share of a large stash that he hid sometime ago. It is up to smokejumper Jesse Graves to save the hostage and stop the villain. The premise is unbelievably hokey, but it still manages to fall short of the plots hokeyness. The movie is just some loosely connected action scenes that are made with unimpressive staging and mediocre special effects. From the first super cheesy scene the acting is virtually non-existent, except for William Forysthe who manages to entertain with his super-evil and calculating villain persona. But still, he can't make something out of nothing. Nothing is an apt way to put it since this is really a film about just that. There is little mention of plot, little mention of the smokejumpers' techniques, little mention of the science of fire, but there is lots of fire. LOTS AND LOTS OF FIRE. But fire is just fire. It can't make a movie by itself. Re-watch Twister for a relatively plot-less disaster/action movie done right. Or if fire is your thing Backdraft or Ladder 49 will do. Just avoid this. --- 2/10 Rated R for violence
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    William Forsythe rocks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ghostman16
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    firestorm is a cliffhanger type thriller starring Howie Long as Jesse Graves a heroic fire fighter who is up against a group of escaped convicts led by the Psycotic Randell who has kidnapped a bird watcher played by Suzi Amis and has caused a giant fire that is turning into a firestorm.now Jesse must now save the hostage stop the fire and take care of Randell. firestorm is quite a fun little thriller Howie Long was quite a good hero shame he didn't make anymore action films after this.William Forsythe was absolutely brilliant as the main bad guy Randell William normally plays decent bad guys anyway like in out for justice and stone cold.even Scott Glenn is in it. to end the review firestorm is a well made action thriller a bit clich&eacute;d but still cool 7 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even a real movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Candice Boyle (SalamanderGirl)
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although nowhere as infamous as John Travolta's Battlefield Earth or Warren Beatty's Ishtar or George Lucas's Howard the Duck, this sorry excuse for a movie is equal in unintentional humor. Some of the worst computer graphics ever seen, a "performance" so wooden from Howie Long it makes Stallone look like Ben Kingsley, and scenes that are so unrealistic Ed Wood would not have filmed them. One scene, the "Fire Storm" scene, shows raging computer graphic flames rushing over mountains like a gigantic burning tornado, covering hundreds of square miles in three seconds flat. Everyone in the theater was laughing, except maybe for the smart ones who had already walked out. The director went on to make one of the more forgettable Steven Seagal straight-to-video movies, and the writer was never heard from again. And poor Suzi Amis; You'd think James Cameron might have helped his gal get better movie roles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Than Anticipated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is kind of a Class B action film and it stars an ex-pro football player (Howie Long) making his debut in the movies. Because of that, I didn't expect much. I was surprised. It's actually a good adventure story and Long was capable in his acting. He was aided by three fine actors who usually are interesting in whatever roles they play: Scott Glenn, Suzy Amis and William Forstyhe. Glenn is the best-known of the three but had the least lines in here. Forsythe was good at playing what he does best: the nasty villain. This movie was also well-filmed with some nice closeup and camera angles. The only complaints were some dopey dialog in spots and a little too much profanity in spots. Otherwise, for a no-name movie starring a rookie actor it was better than I anticipated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow. That's all I can say. Or is it?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dragonreborn008
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Holy Crap. Howie Long should be promoted to Master Actor. He is so good at expressing his emotions. He should teach a class about emotions at a major college. A major college about human emotions. He is a vortex, that drags all of his surrounding actors and co-workers into his world. The drama in this movie is incredible as well. The whole "firestorm" element pulls you to the edge of your seat and then drops you on your face. I wish I could throw an axe like Howie Long. When the escaped convicts pretended to be Canadian, I wasn't sure whether they were Canadian or American. And when the Bird watcher stated how she had Marine training, I could see how perfect a match those two little love birds were. I really love how the whole plot was summarized in about 10 minutes during the entire feature, this allowed for more Howie Long content. This was an incredible movie. I would recommend it to anyone. Except to pregnant women. This movie has a few side effects such as premature birth, diarrhea, and drilling your eyes out with a jackhammer. I would also recommend Fire Down Below (Steven Seagal). If I could make one wish for anything in the whole world, it would be for Howie Long to restart(or start) his film career.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Movie brings fear of fires into focus
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sharon
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Firestorm is a movie that people who are 15 and older might enjoy to watch. The acting in the movie truly gives the film its cohesiveness. There is no outstanding actor/actress. They all work together to make the film work. Firestorm is not the best nor the worst film ever. It is a good solid action (crime) drama. Firestorm is a movie which helps to humanize firefighters. The criminal elements in the film are truly ruthless and deserve no sympathy. We are all afraid of fire burning down our homes, consuming our life's memories, and burning alive. This movie brings these fears into focus. Firestorm also reminds us all as to why every community needs firefighters. For it short duration of about an hour and one half, Firestorm will keep you occupied. Grab the popcorn, soda, and some extra water (just in case). I give it four thumbs up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Light Entertainment With A Soft R Rating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Standard, innocuous, and incendiary this rather enjoyable Action Movie is light entertainment with a soft R rating. Pretty tame as these things go, it has some death defying dumb stunts and the whole thing is a notch above a TV Movie and can be quite enjoyable in a humdrum sort of way. If you don't expect your leading Actor to act or can tolerate a script that is dampened by a standard re-write of a glutted genre, then settle in for a Movie that doesn't ask much and is a jump into a not so hot Movie, but it doesn't leave you cold either. William Forsythe (has he ever disappointed) once again is a force to be reckoned on screen and steals the show with his Evil stare and detached dementia. This bad guy and the raging inferno are the reasons to catch this when you are in the mood for some pizza and beer or cheese and wine, but keep an eye on the hearth or the fondue.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You're a bird watcher?!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lost-in-limbo
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Toasty, by-the-numbers b-grade natural disaster action joint which has a stout-hearted Howie Long playing a smoke-jumper that has to tackle firestorms and William Forsythe's gleefully hammy bad guy persona. Forsythe is great and you know you can always expect a show whenever his on screen, as he simply knows how to play devious tyrants. Also along for the heatwave are Scott Glenn and Barry Pepper. Simple-minded writing makes sure that the bubblegum action flows with the blatant heroics coming to the forefront, which is led by Long and Glenn. Hammy dialogues (I can't remember the last time I heard someone be called a butt-munch) are filtered in and the stunt-work can get hot and heavy. Too bad some of the computer effects come off rather lousy, especially during the final climatic scenes. Director Dean Semler (who was cinematographer for such films as "Mad Max 2" and "Razorback") keeps it rugged and heightens it with some stylish shots of the woodland terrain. Disposable, but crackling entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good for what it was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MargoC
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen worse and of course I've seen better. I enjoyed Backdraft, and I figured this was just Backdraft in the woods. It was just what I expected, a cheesy action movie, with "witty" lines and a totally off the wall villain. William Forsythe is one of my favorite "villain" actors, and he does not disappoint. There's something about him that's really creepy. Favorite line? "Heeeeeeeeeeeeey smokejumpah! You still alive?" If you're looking for a B movie that has pretty good action scenes and bad dialogue, this is the one for you. The fire scenes were actually quite good too. Great improbable stunts too. Too bad Howie didn't take his shirt off, I would have given it another star.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Firestorm" Blows Smoke
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You cannot see the trees for the testosterone in director Dean Semler's synthetic outdoors action saga "Firestorm," starring sportscaster Howie Long as a stalwart smoke jumper who parachutes into raging Wyoming forest fires to rescue little gals and grown-up gals from getting cremated. Any sparks that Howie ignited as an actor in John Woo's "Broken Arrow" sputter in "Firestorm" with Long's pulp diction performance. Chris Soth's one-dimensional script doesn't help Howie much as escaped convicts and flaming infernos challenge his physical prowess. There is nothing compelling about Howie's character and his charisma cannot compensate for this monolithic hero. Leanly plotted as a sapling but predictable as a plunging redwood, "Firestorm" kindles minimal excitement with its prefabricated plot and Howie's Styrofoam heroics. Of course, juvenile-minded audiences who don't demand much from their cinematic exercises may find this half-toasted tale tolerable. What modicum of merit the movie musters lies in its premise. Ultraviolent villain Randy Earl Shaye (William Forsythe of "Once Upon A Time in America") cons his shyster lawyer (Terry Kelly of "Christina") into committing wildfire arson. Shaye wants out of the Wyoming State Penitentiary to get his $20-million. It seems that the prison dispatches short-time convicts to help extinguish forest fires. Shaye plans to use the forest fire as a cover for his escape. Stabbing a friendly prisoner on the fire detail, Shaye disguises himself as the dead man, and then sneaks out of the joint. Soth asks us to believe that a man could escape from prison based largely on a tattoo worn behind the ear. As villains go, Shaye shows early promise as a worthy adversary, until the filmmakers contrive obvious flaws in his character that assure his mortality. Veteran heavy William Forsythe supplies appropriate plug-ugly menace as Randy Earl Shaye. When we initially see Shaye, he resembles Sean Connery from the "The Rock," with a beard and blond messianic coiffure. The filmmakers emphasize Shaye's villainy by showing not only the character of Shaye but also Forsythe's sneering face together in the same shot with the man that he kills. Driving the point home, director Dean Semler wants audiences to realize that Shaye is clearly an unrepentant sadist. Sadly, the events of the plot turn more on Shaye's sadism than on his criminal ingenuity. Shaye's comeuppance is horribly graphic but richly deserved for his murderous demeanor. "Firestorm" follows clench-jawed Jesse Graves (ex-Raiders football star Howie Long) as he thwarts Shaye's escape. The Spartan Chris Soth screenplay tosses in a woman to liven things up. "Titanic" supporting player Suzy Amis appears here as Jennifer, an ornithologist who finds herself trapped by the wildfire blaze. Fleeing from the fire, she runs smack into Randy Earl and his armed and stupid henchmen masquerading as Canadian firefighters. You must have stupid henchmen in "Firestorm" so that they can brag about their means of escape. When Jennifer finally gets away, Shaye cannot afford to let her live because she knows his plans. Meanwhile, when Jesse learns about the forest fire, he skydives into it singlehandedly. He stumbles into Shaye, Jennifer and Shaye's other henchmen. In other words, "Firestorm" constantly moves ahead in terms of storytelling, but with little efficiency, plausibility, or imagination. When Shaye tries his bogus Canadian firefighters story out, Jesse is neither impressed nor convinced. Matching fists and wits with Shaye's motley crew, our brawny firefighter hero sneaks off with Jennifer and they evade Randy Earl until a climactic fight on a lake about to be engulfed in a withering blaze. "Firestorm" derives its title from the phenomenon which occurs when two fires collide and suck all of the oxygen out of the air, creating one of Mother Nature's nasty nuclear-style blasts which destroys everything in it. Soth's script contains those suitable elements that any decent he-man actioneer should boast. The effect, however, is less than incendiary. The problem with Soth along with uncredited scenarist Graham Yost of "Speed" and "Hard Target" is that their characters are a poorly developed bundle of stick figures with neither depth nor complexity. Randy Earl Shaye is supposed to be a homicidal genius who goes so far as to impersonate a prisoner (brutally killing the convict by stabbing him in the neck), but doesn't know squat about forest fires. Jennifer claims to be the offspring of a third generation Marine. Boasting that she can field strip automatic weapons like an AK-47, she fails to notice that the auto-pistol that she swiped from a sex offender isn't loaded. "Firestorm" does other things wrong, too. A neat gimmick--ping-pong balls that explode to start firesis lamely utilized. The first time that they use it as a trick during a ping-pong game, and the second time, Howie uses it to start a backfire to divert oxygen from the first fire. But the ping-pong balls disappear afterward, never to be used again. There is a running joke about axes that the filmmakers bungle, too. At one point in the plot, Jesse and Jennifer lay a trap for Shaye and his sex-predator henchmen that goes afoul because it is so ineptly planned with half-baked results! The only surprises in "Firestorm" are provided by rugged Scott Glenn as battle-weary smoke jumper Wynt Perkins who is crippled while rescuing a dog from a burning house. Revealing more about his role and character would cut down on what little energy "Firestorm" contrives. Sentimentality drips off the script at points, especially at the end when Jennifer learns that she has been incubating two bird eggs during this maelstrom of action. "Dances with Wolves" Oscar-winning photographer Dean Semler makes his less than inflammatory directorial debut with "Firestorm." When he takes his cameras up for aerial shots of British Columbia, you find your breath catching in your throat. Sadly, Semler doesn't breath the same magic into the thin, adolescent storyline. The special effects of the firestorm aren't that imaginative. You feel like you're trapped by expensive looking computer graphics instead of a real wildfire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It burns, it burns!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BroadswordCallinDannyBoy
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A cunning criminal sets a fire to cover his escape from prison. He takes a hostage and promises fellow cohorts a share of a large stash that he hid sometime ago. It is up to smokejumper Jesse Graves to save the hostage and stop the villain. The premise is unbelievably hokey, but it still manages to fall short of the plots hokeyness. The movie is just some loosely connected action scenes that are made with unimpressive staging and mediocre special effects. From the first super cheesy scene the acting is virtually non-existent, except for William Forysthe who manages to entertain with his super-evil and calculating villain persona. But still, he can't make something out of nothing. Nothing is an apt way to put it since this is really a film about just that. There is little mention of plot, little mention of the smokejumpers' techniques, little mention of the science of fire, but there is lots of fire. LOTS AND LOTS OF FIRE. But fire is just fire. It can't make a movie by itself. Re-watch Twister for a relatively plot-less disaster/action movie done right. Or if fire is your thing Backdraft or Ladder 49 will do. Just avoid this. --- 2/10 Rated R for violence
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    William Forsythe rocks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ghostman16
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    firestorm is a cliffhanger type thriller starring Howie Long as Jesse Graves a heroic fire fighter who is up against a group of escaped convicts led by the Psycotic Randell who has kidnapped a bird watcher played by Suzi Amis and has caused a giant fire that is turning into a firestorm.now Jesse must now save the hostage stop the fire and take care of Randell. firestorm is quite a fun little thriller Howie Long was quite a good hero shame he didn't make anymore action films after this.William Forsythe was absolutely brilliant as the main bad guy Randell William normally plays decent bad guys anyway like in out for justice and stone cold.even Scott Glenn is in it. to end the review firestorm is a well made action thriller a bit clich&eacute;d but still cool 7 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even a real movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Candice Boyle (SalamanderGirl)
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although nowhere as infamous as John Travolta's Battlefield Earth or Warren Beatty's Ishtar or George Lucas's Howard the Duck, this sorry excuse for a movie is equal in unintentional humor. Some of the worst computer graphics ever seen, a "performance" so wooden from Howie Long it makes Stallone look like Ben Kingsley, and scenes that are so unrealistic Ed Wood would not have filmed them. One scene, the "Fire Storm" scene, shows raging computer graphic flames rushing over mountains like a gigantic burning tornado, covering hundreds of square miles in three seconds flat. Everyone in the theater was laughing, except maybe for the smart ones who had already walked out. The director went on to make one of the more forgettable Steven Seagal straight-to-video movies, and the writer was never heard from again. And poor Suzi Amis; You'd think James Cameron might have helped his gal get better movie roles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Than Anticipated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is kind of a Class B action film and it stars an ex-pro football player (Howie Long) making his debut in the movies. Because of that, I didn't expect much. I was surprised. It's actually a good adventure story and Long was capable in his acting. He was aided by three fine actors who usually are interesting in whatever roles they play: Scott Glenn, Suzy Amis and William Forstyhe. Glenn is the best-known of the three but had the least lines in here. Forsythe was good at playing what he does best: the nasty villain. This movie was also well-filmed with some nice closeup and camera angles. The only complaints were some dopey dialog in spots and a little too much profanity in spots. Otherwise, for a no-name movie starring a rookie actor it was better than I anticipated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow. That's all I can say. Or is it?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dragonreborn008
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Holy Crap. Howie Long should be promoted to Master Actor. He is so good at expressing his emotions. He should teach a class about emotions at a major college. A major college about human emotions. He is a vortex, that drags all of his surrounding actors and co-workers into his world. The drama in this movie is incredible as well. The whole "firestorm" element pulls you to the edge of your seat and then drops you on your face. I wish I could throw an axe like Howie Long. When the escaped convicts pretended to be Canadian, I wasn't sure whether they were Canadian or American. And when the Bird watcher stated how she had Marine training, I could see how perfect a match those two little love birds were. I really love how the whole plot was summarized in about 10 minutes during the entire feature, this allowed for more Howie Long content. This was an incredible movie. I would recommend it to anyone. Except to pregnant women. This movie has a few side effects such as premature birth, diarrhea, and drilling your eyes out with a jackhammer. I would also recommend Fire Down Below (Steven Seagal). If I could make one wish for anything in the whole world, it would be for Howie Long to restart(or start) his film career.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Movie brings fear of fires into focus
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sharon
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Firestorm is a movie that people who are 15 and older might enjoy to watch. The acting in the movie truly gives the film its cohesiveness. There is no outstanding actor/actress. They all work together to make the film work. Firestorm is not the best nor the worst film ever. It is a good solid action (crime) drama. Firestorm is a movie which helps to humanize firefighters. The criminal elements in the film are truly ruthless and deserve no sympathy. We are all afraid of fire burning down our homes, consuming our life's memories, and burning alive. This movie brings these fears into focus. Firestorm also reminds us all as to why every community needs firefighters. For it short duration of about an hour and one half, Firestorm will keep you occupied. Grab the popcorn, soda, and some extra water (just in case). I give it four thumbs up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Light Entertainment With A Soft R Rating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Standard, innocuous, and incendiary this rather enjoyable Action Movie is light entertainment with a soft R rating. Pretty tame as these things go, it has some death defying dumb stunts and the whole thing is a notch above a TV Movie and can be quite enjoyable in a humdrum sort of way. If you don't expect your leading Actor to act or can tolerate a script that is dampened by a standard re-write of a glutted genre, then settle in for a Movie that doesn't ask much and is a jump into a not so hot Movie, but it doesn't leave you cold either. William Forsythe (has he ever disappointed) once again is a force to be reckoned on screen and steals the show with his Evil stare and detached dementia. This bad guy and the raging inferno are the reasons to catch this when you are in the mood for some pizza and beer or cheese and wine, but keep an eye on the hearth or the fondue.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You're a bird watcher?!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lost-in-limbo
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Toasty, by-the-numbers b-grade natural disaster action joint which has a stout-hearted Howie Long playing a smoke-jumper that has to tackle firestorms and William Forsythe's gleefully hammy bad guy persona. Forsythe is great and you know you can always expect a show whenever his on screen, as he simply knows how to play devious tyrants. Also along for the heatwave are Scott Glenn and Barry Pepper. Simple-minded writing makes sure that the bubblegum action flows with the blatant heroics coming to the forefront, which is led by Long and Glenn. Hammy dialogues (I can't remember the last time I heard someone be called a butt-munch) are filtered in and the stunt-work can get hot and heavy. Too bad some of the computer effects come off rather lousy, especially during the final climatic scenes. Director Dean Semler (who was cinematographer for such films as "Mad Max 2" and "Razorback") keeps it rugged and heightens it with some stylish shots of the woodland terrain. Disposable, but crackling entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good for what it was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MargoC
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen worse and of course I've seen better. I enjoyed Backdraft, and I figured this was just Backdraft in the woods. It was just what I expected, a cheesy action movie, with "witty" lines and a totally off the wall villain. William Forsythe is one of my favorite "villain" actors, and he does not disappoint. There's something about him that's really creepy. Favorite line? "Heeeeeeeeeeeeey smokejumpah! You still alive?" If you're looking for a B movie that has pretty good action scenes and bad dialogue, this is the one for you. The fire scenes were actually quite good too. Great improbable stunts too. Too bad Howie didn't take his shirt off, I would have given it another star.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Firestorm" Blows Smoke
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You cannot see the trees for the testosterone in director Dean Semler's synthetic outdoors action saga "Firestorm," starring sportscaster Howie Long as a stalwart smoke jumper who parachutes into raging Wyoming forest fires to rescue little gals and grown-up gals from getting cremated. Any sparks that Howie ignited as an actor in John Woo's "Broken Arrow" sputter in "Firestorm" with Long's pulp diction performance. Chris Soth's one-dimensional script doesn't help Howie much as escaped convicts and flaming infernos challenge his physical prowess. There is nothing compelling about Howie's character and his charisma cannot compensate for this monolithic hero. Leanly plotted as a sapling but predictable as a plunging redwood, "Firestorm" kindles minimal excitement with its prefabricated plot and Howie's Styrofoam heroics. Of course, juvenile-minded audiences who don't demand much from their cinematic exercises may find this half-toasted tale tolerable. What modicum of merit the movie musters lies in its premise. Ultraviolent villain Randy Earl Shaye (William Forsythe of "Once Upon A Time in America") cons his shyster lawyer (Terry Kelly of "Christina") into committing wildfire arson. Shaye wants out of the Wyoming State Penitentiary to get his $20-million. It seems that the prison dispatches short-time convicts to help extinguish forest fires. Shaye plans to use the forest fire as a cover for his escape. Stabbing a friendly prisoner on the fire detail, Shaye disguises himself as the dead man, and then sneaks out of the joint. Soth asks us to believe that a man could escape from prison based largely on a tattoo worn behind the ear. As villains go, Shaye shows early promise as a worthy adversary, until the filmmakers contrive obvious flaws in his character that assure his mortality. Veteran heavy William Forsythe supplies appropriate plug-ugly menace as Randy Earl Shaye. When we initially see Shaye, he resembles Sean Connery from the "The Rock," with a beard and blond messianic coiffure. The filmmakers emphasize Shaye's villainy by showing not only the character of Shaye but also Forsythe's sneering face together in the same shot with the man that he kills. Driving the point home, director Dean Semler wants audiences to realize that Shaye is clearly an unrepentant sadist. Sadly, the events of the plot turn more on Shaye's sadism than on his criminal ingenuity. Shaye's comeuppance is horribly graphic but richly deserved for his murderous demeanor. "Firestorm" follows clench-jawed Jesse Graves (ex-Raiders football star Howie Long) as he thwarts Shaye's escape. The Spartan Chris Soth screenplay tosses in a woman to liven things up. "Titanic" supporting player Suzy Amis appears here as Jennifer, an ornithologist who finds herself trapped by the wildfire blaze. Fleeing from the fire, she runs smack into Randy Earl and his armed and stupid henchmen masquerading as Canadian firefighters. You must have stupid henchmen in "Firestorm" so that they can brag about their means of escape. When Jennifer finally gets away, Shaye cannot afford to let her live because she knows his plans. Meanwhile, when Jesse learns about the forest fire, he skydives into it singlehandedly. He stumbles into Shaye, Jennifer and Shaye's other henchmen. In other words, "Firestorm" constantly moves ahead in terms of storytelling, but with little efficiency, plausibility, or imagination. When Shaye tries his bogus Canadian firefighters story out, Jesse is neither impressed nor convinced. Matching fists and wits with Shaye's motley crew, our brawny firefighter hero sneaks off with Jennifer and they evade Randy Earl until a climactic fight on a lake about to be engulfed in a withering blaze. "Firestorm" derives its title from the phenomenon which occurs when two fires collide and suck all of the oxygen out of the air, creating one of Mother Nature's nasty nuclear-style blasts which destroys everything in it. Soth's script contains those suitable elements that any decent he-man actioneer should boast. The effect, however, is less than incendiary. The problem with Soth along with uncredited scenarist Graham Yost of "Speed" and "Hard Target" is that their characters are a poorly developed bundle of stick figures with neither depth nor complexity. Randy Earl Shaye is supposed to be a homicidal genius who goes so far as to impersonate a prisoner (brutally killing the convict by stabbing him in the neck), but doesn't know squat about forest fires. Jennifer claims to be the offspring of a third generation Marine. Boasting that she can field strip automatic weapons like an AK-47, she fails to notice that the auto-pistol that she swiped from a sex offender isn't loaded. "Firestorm" does other things wrong, too. A neat gimmick--ping-pong balls that explode to start firesis lamely utilized. The first time that they use it as a trick during a ping-pong game, and the second time, Howie uses it to start a backfire to divert oxygen from the first fire. But the ping-pong balls disappear afterward, never to be used again. There is a running joke about axes that the filmmakers bungle, too. At one point in the plot, Jesse and Jennifer lay a trap for Shaye and his sex-predator henchmen that goes afoul because it is so ineptly planned with half-baked results! The only surprises in "Firestorm" are provided by rugged Scott Glenn as battle-weary smoke jumper Wynt Perkins who is crippled while rescuing a dog from a burning house. Revealing more about his role and character would cut down on what little energy "Firestorm" contrives. Sentimentality drips off the script at points, especially at the end when Jennifer learns that she has been incubating two bird eggs during this maelstrom of action. "Dances with Wolves" Oscar-winning photographer Dean Semler makes his less than inflammatory directorial debut with "Firestorm." When he takes his cameras up for aerial shots of British Columbia, you find your breath catching in your throat. Sadly, Semler doesn't breath the same magic into the thin, adolescent storyline. The special effects of the firestorm aren't that imaginative. You feel like you're trapped by expensive looking computer graphics instead of a real wildfire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It burns, it burns!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BroadswordCallinDannyBoy
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A cunning criminal sets a fire to cover his escape from prison. He takes a hostage and promises fellow cohorts a share of a large stash that he hid sometime ago. It is up to smokejumper Jesse Graves to save the hostage and stop the villain. The premise is unbelievably hokey, but it still manages to fall short of the plots hokeyness. The movie is just some loosely connected action scenes that are made with unimpressive staging and mediocre special effects. From the first super cheesy scene the acting is virtually non-existent, except for William Forysthe who manages to entertain with his super-evil and calculating villain persona. But still, he can't make something out of nothing. Nothing is an apt way to put it since this is really a film about just that. There is little mention of plot, little mention of the smokejumpers' techniques, little mention of the science of fire, but there is lots of fire. LOTS AND LOTS OF FIRE. But fire is just fire. It can't make a movie by itself. Re-watch Twister for a relatively plot-less disaster/action movie done right. Or if fire is your thing Backdraft or Ladder 49 will do. Just avoid this. --- 2/10 Rated R for violence
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    William Forsythe rocks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ghostman16
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    firestorm is a cliffhanger type thriller starring Howie Long as Jesse Graves a heroic fire fighter who is up against a group of escaped convicts led by the Psycotic Randell who has kidnapped a bird watcher played by Suzi Amis and has caused a giant fire that is turning into a firestorm.now Jesse must now save the hostage stop the fire and take care of Randell. firestorm is quite a fun little thriller Howie Long was quite a good hero shame he didn't make anymore action films after this.William Forsythe was absolutely brilliant as the main bad guy Randell William normally plays decent bad guys anyway like in out for justice and stone cold.even Scott Glenn is in it. to end the review firestorm is a well made action thriller a bit clich&eacute;d but still cool 7 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even a real movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Candice Boyle (SalamanderGirl)
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although nowhere as infamous as John Travolta's Battlefield Earth or Warren Beatty's Ishtar or George Lucas's Howard the Duck, this sorry excuse for a movie is equal in unintentional humor. Some of the worst computer graphics ever seen, a "performance" so wooden from Howie Long it makes Stallone look like Ben Kingsley, and scenes that are so unrealistic Ed Wood would not have filmed them. One scene, the "Fire Storm" scene, shows raging computer graphic flames rushing over mountains like a gigantic burning tornado, covering hundreds of square miles in three seconds flat. Everyone in the theater was laughing, except maybe for the smart ones who had already walked out. The director went on to make one of the more forgettable Steven Seagal straight-to-video movies, and the writer was never heard from again. And poor Suzi Amis; You'd think James Cameron might have helped his gal get better movie roles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Than Anticipated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is kind of a Class B action film and it stars an ex-pro football player (Howie Long) making his debut in the movies. Because of that, I didn't expect much. I was surprised. It's actually a good adventure story and Long was capable in his acting. He was aided by three fine actors who usually are interesting in whatever roles they play: Scott Glenn, Suzy Amis and William Forstyhe. Glenn is the best-known of the three but had the least lines in here. Forsythe was good at playing what he does best: the nasty villain. This movie was also well-filmed with some nice closeup and camera angles. The only complaints were some dopey dialog in spots and a little too much profanity in spots. Otherwise, for a no-name movie starring a rookie actor it was better than I anticipated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow. That's all I can say. Or is it?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dragonreborn008
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Holy Crap. Howie Long should be promoted to Master Actor. He is so good at expressing his emotions. He should teach a class about emotions at a major college. A major college about human emotions. He is a vortex, that drags all of his surrounding actors and co-workers into his world. The drama in this movie is incredible as well. The whole "firestorm" element pulls you to the edge of your seat and then drops you on your face. I wish I could throw an axe like Howie Long. When the escaped convicts pretended to be Canadian, I wasn't sure whether they were Canadian or American. And when the Bird watcher stated how she had Marine training, I could see how perfect a match those two little love birds were. I really love how the whole plot was summarized in about 10 minutes during the entire feature, this allowed for more Howie Long content. This was an incredible movie. I would recommend it to anyone. Except to pregnant women. This movie has a few side effects such as premature birth, diarrhea, and drilling your eyes out with a jackhammer. I would also recommend Fire Down Below (Steven Seagal). If I could make one wish for anything in the whole world, it would be for Howie Long to restart(or start) his film career.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Movie brings fear of fires into focus
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sharon
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Firestorm is a movie that people who are 15 and older might enjoy to watch. The acting in the movie truly gives the film its cohesiveness. There is no outstanding actor/actress. They all work together to make the film work. Firestorm is not the best nor the worst film ever. It is a good solid action (crime) drama. Firestorm is a movie which helps to humanize firefighters. The criminal elements in the film are truly ruthless and deserve no sympathy. We are all afraid of fire burning down our homes, consuming our life's memories, and burning alive. This movie brings these fears into focus. Firestorm also reminds us all as to why every community needs firefighters. For it short duration of about an hour and one half, Firestorm will keep you occupied. Grab the popcorn, soda, and some extra water (just in case). I give it four thumbs up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Light Entertainment With A Soft R Rating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Standard, innocuous, and incendiary this rather enjoyable Action Movie is light entertainment with a soft R rating. Pretty tame as these things go, it has some death defying dumb stunts and the whole thing is a notch above a TV Movie and can be quite enjoyable in a humdrum sort of way. If you don't expect your leading Actor to act or can tolerate a script that is dampened by a standard re-write of a glutted genre, then settle in for a Movie that doesn't ask much and is a jump into a not so hot Movie, but it doesn't leave you cold either. William Forsythe (has he ever disappointed) once again is a force to be reckoned on screen and steals the show with his Evil stare and detached dementia. This bad guy and the raging inferno are the reasons to catch this when you are in the mood for some pizza and beer or cheese and wine, but keep an eye on the hearth or the fondue.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You're a bird watcher?!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lost-in-limbo
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Toasty, by-the-numbers b-grade natural disaster action joint which has a stout-hearted Howie Long playing a smoke-jumper that has to tackle firestorms and William Forsythe's gleefully hammy bad guy persona. Forsythe is great and you know you can always expect a show whenever his on screen, as he simply knows how to play devious tyrants. Also along for the heatwave are Scott Glenn and Barry Pepper. Simple-minded writing makes sure that the bubblegum action flows with the blatant heroics coming to the forefront, which is led by Long and Glenn. Hammy dialogues (I can't remember the last time I heard someone be called a butt-munch) are filtered in and the stunt-work can get hot and heavy. Too bad some of the computer effects come off rather lousy, especially during the final climatic scenes. Director Dean Semler (who was cinematographer for such films as "Mad Max 2" and "Razorback") keeps it rugged and heightens it with some stylish shots of the woodland terrain. Disposable, but crackling entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good for what it was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MargoC
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen worse and of course I've seen better. I enjoyed Backdraft, and I figured this was just Backdraft in the woods. It was just what I expected, a cheesy action movie, with "witty" lines and a totally off the wall villain. William Forsythe is one of my favorite "villain" actors, and he does not disappoint. There's something about him that's really creepy. Favorite line? "Heeeeeeeeeeeeey smokejumpah! You still alive?" If you're looking for a B movie that has pretty good action scenes and bad dialogue, this is the one for you. The fire scenes were actually quite good too. Great improbable stunts too. Too bad Howie didn't take his shirt off, I would have given it another star.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Firestorm" Blows Smoke
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You cannot see the trees for the testosterone in director Dean Semler's synthetic outdoors action saga "Firestorm," starring sportscaster Howie Long as a stalwart smoke jumper who parachutes into raging Wyoming forest fires to rescue little gals and grown-up gals from getting cremated. Any sparks that Howie ignited as an actor in John Woo's "Broken Arrow" sputter in "Firestorm" with Long's pulp diction performance. Chris Soth's one-dimensional script doesn't help Howie much as escaped convicts and flaming infernos challenge his physical prowess. There is nothing compelling about Howie's character and his charisma cannot compensate for this monolithic hero. Leanly plotted as a sapling but predictable as a plunging redwood, "Firestorm" kindles minimal excitement with its prefabricated plot and Howie's Styrofoam heroics. Of course, juvenile-minded audiences who don't demand much from their cinematic exercises may find this half-toasted tale tolerable. What modicum of merit the movie musters lies in its premise. Ultraviolent villain Randy Earl Shaye (William Forsythe of "Once Upon A Time in America") cons his shyster lawyer (Terry Kelly of "Christina") into committing wildfire arson. Shaye wants out of the Wyoming State Penitentiary to get his $20-million. It seems that the prison dispatches short-time convicts to help extinguish forest fires. Shaye plans to use the forest fire as a cover for his escape. Stabbing a friendly prisoner on the fire detail, Shaye disguises himself as the dead man, and then sneaks out of the joint. Soth asks us to believe that a man could escape from prison based largely on a tattoo worn behind the ear. As villains go, Shaye shows early promise as a worthy adversary, until the filmmakers contrive obvious flaws in his character that assure his mortality. Veteran heavy William Forsythe supplies appropriate plug-ugly menace as Randy Earl Shaye. When we initially see Shaye, he resembles Sean Connery from the "The Rock," with a beard and blond messianic coiffure. The filmmakers emphasize Shaye's villainy by showing not only the character of Shaye but also Forsythe's sneering face together in the same shot with the man that he kills. Driving the point home, director Dean Semler wants audiences to realize that Shaye is clearly an unrepentant sadist. Sadly, the events of the plot turn more on Shaye's sadism than on his criminal ingenuity. Shaye's comeuppance is horribly graphic but richly deserved for his murderous demeanor. "Firestorm" follows clench-jawed Jesse Graves (ex-Raiders football star Howie Long) as he thwarts Shaye's escape. The Spartan Chris Soth screenplay tosses in a woman to liven things up. "Titanic" supporting player Suzy Amis appears here as Jennifer, an ornithologist who finds herself trapped by the wildfire blaze. Fleeing from the fire, she runs smack into Randy Earl and his armed and stupid henchmen masquerading as Canadian firefighters. You must have stupid henchmen in "Firestorm" so that they can brag about their means of escape. When Jennifer finally gets away, Shaye cannot afford to let her live because she knows his plans. Meanwhile, when Jesse learns about the forest fire, he skydives into it singlehandedly. He stumbles into Shaye, Jennifer and Shaye's other henchmen. In other words, "Firestorm" constantly moves ahead in terms of storytelling, but with little efficiency, plausibility, or imagination. When Shaye tries his bogus Canadian firefighters story out, Jesse is neither impressed nor convinced. Matching fists and wits with Shaye's motley crew, our brawny firefighter hero sneaks off with Jennifer and they evade Randy Earl until a climactic fight on a lake about to be engulfed in a withering blaze. "Firestorm" derives its title from the phenomenon which occurs when two fires collide and suck all of the oxygen out of the air, creating one of Mother Nature's nasty nuclear-style blasts which destroys everything in it. Soth's script contains those suitable elements that any decent he-man actioneer should boast. The effect, however, is less than incendiary. The problem with Soth along with uncredited scenarist Graham Yost of "Speed" and "Hard Target" is that their characters are a poorly developed bundle of stick figures with neither depth nor complexity. Randy Earl Shaye is supposed to be a homicidal genius who goes so far as to impersonate a prisoner (brutally killing the convict by stabbing him in the neck), but doesn't know squat about forest fires. Jennifer claims to be the offspring of a third generation Marine. Boasting that she can field strip automatic weapons like an AK-47, she fails to notice that the auto-pistol that she swiped from a sex offender isn't loaded. "Firestorm" does other things wrong, too. A neat gimmick--ping-pong balls that explode to start firesis lamely utilized. The first time that they use it as a trick during a ping-pong game, and the second time, Howie uses it to start a backfire to divert oxygen from the first fire. But the ping-pong balls disappear afterward, never to be used again. There is a running joke about axes that the filmmakers bungle, too. At one point in the plot, Jesse and Jennifer lay a trap for Shaye and his sex-predator henchmen that goes afoul because it is so ineptly planned with half-baked results! The only surprises in "Firestorm" are provided by rugged Scott Glenn as battle-weary smoke jumper Wynt Perkins who is crippled while rescuing a dog from a burning house. Revealing more about his role and character would cut down on what little energy "Firestorm" contrives. Sentimentality drips off the script at points, especially at the end when Jennifer learns that she has been incubating two bird eggs during this maelstrom of action. "Dances with Wolves" Oscar-winning photographer Dean Semler makes his less than inflammatory directorial debut with "Firestorm." When he takes his cameras up for aerial shots of British Columbia, you find your breath catching in your throat. Sadly, Semler doesn't breath the same magic into the thin, adolescent storyline. The special effects of the firestorm aren't that imaginative. You feel like you're trapped by expensive looking computer graphics instead of a real wildfire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It burns, it burns!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BroadswordCallinDannyBoy
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A cunning criminal sets a fire to cover his escape from prison. He takes a hostage and promises fellow cohorts a share of a large stash that he hid sometime ago. It is up to smokejumper Jesse Graves to save the hostage and stop the villain. The premise is unbelievably hokey, but it still manages to fall short of the plots hokeyness. The movie is just some loosely connected action scenes that are made with unimpressive staging and mediocre special effects. From the first super cheesy scene the acting is virtually non-existent, except for William Forysthe who manages to entertain with his super-evil and calculating villain persona. But still, he can't make something out of nothing. Nothing is an apt way to put it since this is really a film about just that. There is little mention of plot, little mention of the smokejumpers' techniques, little mention of the science of fire, but there is lots of fire. LOTS AND LOTS OF FIRE. But fire is just fire. It can't make a movie by itself. Re-watch Twister for a relatively plot-less disaster/action movie done right. Or if fire is your thing Backdraft or Ladder 49 will do. Just avoid this. --- 2/10 Rated R for violence
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    William Forsythe rocks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ghostman16
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    firestorm is a cliffhanger type thriller starring Howie Long as Jesse Graves a heroic fire fighter who is up against a group of escaped convicts led by the Psycotic Randell who has kidnapped a bird watcher played by Suzi Amis and has caused a giant fire that is turning into a firestorm.now Jesse must now save the hostage stop the fire and take care of Randell. firestorm is quite a fun little thriller Howie Long was quite a good hero shame he didn't make anymore action films after this.William Forsythe was absolutely brilliant as the main bad guy Randell William normally plays decent bad guys anyway like in out for justice and stone cold.even Scott Glenn is in it. to end the review firestorm is a well made action thriller a bit clich&eacute;d but still cool 7 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even a real movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Candice Boyle (SalamanderGirl)
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although nowhere as infamous as John Travolta's Battlefield Earth or Warren Beatty's Ishtar or George Lucas's Howard the Duck, this sorry excuse for a movie is equal in unintentional humor. Some of the worst computer graphics ever seen, a "performance" so wooden from Howie Long it makes Stallone look like Ben Kingsley, and scenes that are so unrealistic Ed Wood would not have filmed them. One scene, the "Fire Storm" scene, shows raging computer graphic flames rushing over mountains like a gigantic burning tornado, covering hundreds of square miles in three seconds flat. Everyone in the theater was laughing, except maybe for the smart ones who had already walked out. The director went on to make one of the more forgettable Steven Seagal straight-to-video movies, and the writer was never heard from again. And poor Suzi Amis; You'd think James Cameron might have helped his gal get better movie roles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Than Anticipated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is kind of a Class B action film and it stars an ex-pro football player (Howie Long) making his debut in the movies. Because of that, I didn't expect much. I was surprised. It's actually a good adventure story and Long was capable in his acting. He was aided by three fine actors who usually are interesting in whatever roles they play: Scott Glenn, Suzy Amis and William Forstyhe. Glenn is the best-known of the three but had the least lines in here. Forsythe was good at playing what he does best: the nasty villain. This movie was also well-filmed with some nice closeup and camera angles. The only complaints were some dopey dialog in spots and a little too much profanity in spots. Otherwise, for a no-name movie starring a rookie actor it was better than I anticipated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow. That's all I can say. Or is it?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dragonreborn008
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Holy Crap. Howie Long should be promoted to Master Actor. He is so good at expressing his emotions. He should teach a class about emotions at a major college. A major college about human emotions. He is a vortex, that drags all of his surrounding actors and co-workers into his world. The drama in this movie is incredible as well. The whole "firestorm" element pulls you to the edge of your seat and then drops you on your face. I wish I could throw an axe like Howie Long. When the escaped convicts pretended to be Canadian, I wasn't sure whether they were Canadian or American. And when the Bird watcher stated how she had Marine training, I could see how perfect a match those two little love birds were. I really love how the whole plot was summarized in about 10 minutes during the entire feature, this allowed for more Howie Long content. This was an incredible movie. I would recommend it to anyone. Except to pregnant women. This movie has a few side effects such as premature birth, diarrhea, and drilling your eyes out with a jackhammer. I would also recommend Fire Down Below (Steven Seagal). If I could make one wish for anything in the whole world, it would be for Howie Long to restart(or start) his film career.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
