<filme>
 <id>
  1112
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109450
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Cobb
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A reporter hired to write the 'official' biography of Ty Cobb discovers just how dark the baseball legend's real story is.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Al Stump is a famous sports-writer chosen by Ty Cobb to co-write his official, authorized 'autobiography' before his death. Cobb, widely feared and despised, feels misunderstood and wants to set the record straight about 'the greatest ball-player ever,' in his words. However, when Stump spends time with Cobb, interviewing him and beginning to write, he realizes that the general public opinion is largely correct. In Stump's presence, Cobb is angry, violent, racist, misogynistic, and incorrigibly abusive to everyone around him. Torn between printing the truth by plumbing the depths of Cobb's dark soul and grim childhood, and succumbing to Cobb's pressure for a whitewash of his character and a simple baseball tale of his greatness, Stump writes two different books. One book is for Cobb, the other for the public.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Biography
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sport
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   baseball
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   misanthrope
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   ghost writer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   baseball player
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   baseball movie
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Ron Shelton
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Al Stump
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Ron Shelton
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Tommy Lee Jones
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Robert Wuhl
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Lolita Davidovich
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cobb You would think that in a sport where teams carry around baseball bats that its players wouldn't so blatantly insult each other. However, the outfielder in this biography ran his mouth as much as his feet. Hiring famed sportswriter Al Stump (Robert Wuhl), the cantankerous Ty Cobb (Tommy Lee Jones) hopes to whitewash his blemished baseball reputation with a glowing autobiography. While staying with the 72-year-old alcoholic at his home in Lake Tahoe, Stump, himself, experiences the legendary irritability of the Hall of Famer. Over the many months and miles he spends with Cobb, Stump must decide if he's going to pen a sanitized memoir or his own tell all. Based on Stump's book, Tommy Lee Jones' performance is certainly a homerun, however, the story revels too much in Cobb's senility and deep-seated racism. Furthermore, portraying baseball players as racists is insulting to those players who are just degenerate gamblers. Yellow Light vidiotreviews.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mr. Cobb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just from a purely baseball side of things, this movie was a joy to watch,, all of the historical footage from the early days, makes me wish I could have seen the great Ty Cobb actually play. then you get into his personal life,, and everything wasn't actually roses,, he had a very seedy side to him,, heavy drinker, womanizer, lot's of stuff that today's heroes really aren't made of. but if you take the whole movie and wrap it up into one , I think that the viewer will be mesmerized from start to finish,, I know that I was. i'm a big Tommy Lee Jones fan and I hit he definitely hit a four bagger with his performance. even if you're not a baseball fan this movie is well worth watching , and if you are a baseball fan , then this is truly the movie for you to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cobb great ballplayer, not a great guy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ty Cobb is considered by most to be the best baseball player of all time or at least in the discussion for that honor. With holding almost all of the hitting records prior to Pete Rose. But as great of a player as he was he was a mean spirited, wife beater and racist by the account of a lot of times and spending any extended time with him was considered impossible. We see Cobb in this movie at the end of his life alongside Al Stump a famous sportswriter in the process of writing his autobiography with occasional flashbacks to Cobb's playing career. The movie is directed by Ron Shelton who's most known for making Bull Durham.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The humanization of the inhuman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tommy Lee Jones may not look much like the infamous ballplayer Ty Cobb, but he sure does embody his spirit, hatred, and consistent belligerence wonderfully. To play a person of his magnitude certainly requires ambition and drive but also talent and diversity. Jones tackles the player with the hatred and evilness that many archived articles and reports have claimed he proudly wore with piercing accuracy. Today, in 2012, baseball players are often viewed as "heroes," "role models," and sometimes even people who provide us with more motivation and passion than those we know in real life. Players like Starlin Castro, Alfonso Soriano, and Jim Thome have etched themselves into the hearts of many. Cobb would've etched himself in the dark side of someone's heart. He was a racist, sexist, selfish, mean-spirited, cocky, gun-toting ignoramus who hated everyone except himself. He thought of himself as "the sport of baseball," completely shunning teamwork and thoroughly enjoyed being hated by literally everyone in the audience. He thought the fact that they showed up to the stadium to throw food and garbage on him was the highest compliment someone could pay. The film centers around not his baseball career, but how a famed sportswriter had the questionably fortunate opportunity to dig into Cobb as a real person in 1959. That man was Al Stump (Robert Wuhl), who was hired to act as a ghostwriter for Cobb's autobiography. Initially, Stump is incredibly honored and thrilled to be given such a job, being able to spend days and nights with "the best baseball player of all time." But when Stump arrives, he is immediately greeted with loud rants from a writer who walks on him and we eventually see Cobb, as he lies in bed, frail and uninspired, verbally assaulting the poor man as he tries to simply reason with him and remain civil. Cobb suggests that him and Stump drive down to Reno to have sex with random women - an act he hopes to accomplish before he dies. He insists on driving recklessly through a terrible blizzard and, as he slips and slides down the road, Cobb briefly illustrates his baseball history for Al. You'd believe the film was told entirely in flashback, but the flashback ceases only after a few minutes and we are back in the present with Al and Cobb, and that's where we remain for the remainder of the picture. It is widely known that Stump published a book shortly after spending days on end with Cobb, but that was the fabricated version he was conned into writing for the man, which the film heavily explores. Al secretly kept a real recollection of his treatment and relationship with the man, but resorted to scribbling notes on cocktail napkins, small pieces of paper, etc. He then released a book detailing the true accounts of the man years after his death - accounts that are depicted in this film. Ron Shelton's Cobb is far from a perfect biopic. It's a little choppy, somewhat dry in sequences, and may run twenty minutes too long, but the fact that it humanizes an unbelievably despicable character, is written with little tongue in cheek innuendos, and the fact that it showcases many honorable performances makes it one that proves its existence nicely. Starring: Tommy Lee Jones, Robert Wuhl, and Lolita Davidovich. Directed by: Ron Shelton.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting but needed more baseball.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    willeagle23
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie on New Year's Eve while I was having a movie marathon to help me stay awake till midnight. I found the movie to be interesting but I felt it could have used more baseball scenes. I understand it was about him telling his story to Al Stump but I was expecting more baseball flashbacks. Tommy Lee Jones is really good in this movie and Robert Wuhl really stands out as well. It was neat to find out where Cobb was from and to see scenes where he was in Cooperstown for a ceremony. This movie did get me interested in checking out more info on Ty Cobb and of course checking out Al Stump's book plus others I may find. If your a baseball fan or Tommy Lee Jones fan this is worth checking out but Cobb's mean attitude does grow old after a while.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who cares?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    policy134
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an awful film. Not because it portrays a man in a not so positive light, nor because it may or may not be true to life. Simply because the story is enormously uninteresting. Tommy Lee Jones gives the pest performance as he can under the circumstances. He fires guns, belts a lot of people and is antagonistic towards just about every character in this atrocity. Character, is the main word here. Not once did I believe that any of the people here were portrayed with a minimum of accuracy. Like the character, Cobb, himself points out: "What is the truth?" I think that there must have been a serious attempt at making a decent biopic but it was probably too boring. So the director thought of an angle. Let's make it as cartoonish as we can possibly get away with. To quote another line from the movie: "He knows greatness", said by the Al Stump character, commenting on why he doesn't get the hell out of writing the bio on Cobb. He will never know greatness from Cobb and neither will we. There is another scene towards the end where Cobb is dying and has discovered that Stump has betrayed him. What does he do? He gives Stump his blessing to write a tell-all bio on him. That is maybe the best scene in the film. He basically says: "Who cares?". Ironically, a lot of people does seem to care, for about a minute, until they find some other gossip that's juicier. The only people who will truly care are the box office profiteers and by the looks of it, they were truly hurt because it was one of the more notorious failures of movies starring Tommy Lee Jones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Brilliant Scene, the Rest Disposable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    russianberserker
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ty Cobb is, by far, the most interesting and belligerently insane athlete to ever live. His baseball career was unparalleled in absurd statistics, brilliant strategy, and pure unadulterated violence. Every game he played in was a spectacle in human ability and cruelty. So of course, the film about him deals with none of that, instead focusing on the writing of his biography by author Al Stump. Now this isn't such a horrible idea in theory, as Cobb himself slid even further into paranoid dementia as years progressed and the stories of his crazed outbursts even as a senior are shocking even by today's desensitized standards. But instead of focusing on these events, which I figure were simply too interesting, the film is a pseudo fictionalized road film with a clich&eacute;d plot that will cause any knowledgeable Cobb fan to cry vinegar tears. Tommy Lee Jones does quite well as a crotchety Cobb, but somehow manages to overplay his cartoon supervillainy. Most stories about Cobb are barely believable, but to make him even crazier seems both impossible and unnecessary. Robert Wuhl, portraying the writer Al Stump, is a dark vortex of non-talent. He sucks the life out of every scene, trying to make this film his own Nagasaki. There is a reason we never see him as a leading man anymore (Arli$$ does not count. It's barely a show). Even the played out, inevitable "role reversal" of Cobb and Stump by the end is made even worse by his pure inability to utter lines that don't sound akin to a bottom shelf book on tape narration voice. For all the awful writing and bland film-making on display, there is one sequence which stands out as so far superior to the rest of this failure that accepting it's from the same film is near impossible. A hyper stylized flashback sequence displaying Cobb's overpowering psychology and brutal athleticism while actually playing the game of baseball is pure brilliance. The camera moves in bizarre fashion and the whole event seems like a dream due to the unique playing style of the monster Cobb. Every slide, hit, and tackle are rendered even more forceful due to enhanced sound, and Tommy Lee Jones OWNS the intensity of the master player. It makes the viewer drool over the possibilities of a true biopic of Cobb in his prime with the same actor. It's worth watching the film for this incredible few minutes alone, just to see what could have been. I may be slightly unfair to this film due to my own knowledge of Ty Cobb and wanting it to be something it isn't, but to make such boring, neutered movie about this maniac is nonsensical. I'm glad Ron Shelton's career has slid ever since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    We shouldn't have to lie about our heroes.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TOMASBBloodhound
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cobb is the supposedly true account of the final days of the great ballplayer Ty Cobb as seen through the eyes of sportswriter Al Stump. Tommy Lee Jones gives an extraordinary performance as the doomed and rambunctious old man. And Robert Wuhl ends up just being along for the Ride as Stump. Though it likely plays a little hard and fast with the truth, Cobb is an engrossing film. The film is told through the perspective of Al Stump who was one of the more prominent sports writers of his day. Early in the film he finds himself summoned to an elaborate yet secluded hunting lodge in the Sierra Mountains. Here he finds the angry old delusional ball player in a state just a few paces ahead of death from various cancers, ailments, and substance abuse. Cobb always seems to be pointing a pistol at those around him and occasionally firing rounds through nearby objects. Cobb knows he's about to die, but wants the complete story of his life to be told... his way! Cobb, as played by Jones is often cartoon-ish, and likely a great exaggeration of the true man. Though he claims to want Stump to only include Cobb's introspection of the game of baseball itself, he often readily offers up lurid details of his past. But then forcefully reminds his biographer, "that's not going in your book, though!" It's almost as if Cobb is using Stump as a man to relate his final confessions to, knowing for sure that many of these details will some day be told about him. If not in the book they are working on at the time. Or it could be that Cobb just needs someone to pour out his soul to in his final days, and lacks friends or close family to do it with. Either way, the film paints Cobb as a monster. And he likely wasn't as bad a guy as the film paints him. But still he was no prince, that is clear from basically every account of the man's life. The film follows Cobb and Stump on several wild escapades inside casinos, seedy motels, and even the Baseball Hall of Fame in Cooperstown, NY. Cobb is played as a violent, impotent, and repugnant junkie. Stump finds himself being more of a caregiver than a biographer by the film's end, and finds himself in a difficult situation. He is the only thing keeping Cobb alive, yet he cannot wait for the old man to die so he can spill all of his secrets in the book. Unfortunately, Stump ends up copping out with the manuscript, and only submitting the good things Cobb wanted the world to hear. He explanation.... he felt he needed Cobb to be a hero, and not the villain he proved to be. The film never really explains why Stump comes to this conclusion. And thus the viewer may feel a little short-changed. In the end, it looks like this film was only made for shock value is showing us what a monster Cobb was. But this makes the Stump character little more than just another audience member like us. Overall, the film is decent enough. Jones is fun to watch, and you'll never forget his performance. Even if it was probably a great exaggeration. The film looks good, and captures the older periods quite well. The script is a foul-mouthed exercise in brutal self-degradation and poor treatment of others, however. There is some brutal violence, and even a sexual assault at gunpoint. For those looking for the cleaner side of the man, a trip to Cooperstown might be a better idea. 7 of 10 stars. The Hound.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I live in his home town.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tyler Goss
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My grandma and her sister were both in the movie. They are in the church at the part that is filmed in Royston, Georgia. I have never seen the movie, that is why I gave it a 5. Royston is a really nice place that you should visit if you have seen the movie. There is a museum about Ty Cobb among other famous people from Royston. You can visit his grave site and places that the movie was filmed. We have a great downtown with shops and a few places to eat. Visit the funeral home and the train depot. It says that the minimum has to be 10 lines for a comment so I am trying to take up as much space as possible and I think that this is a stupid rule. Ty Cobb is one of the greatest baseball players ever and I am proud to live in is home town of Royston, Georgia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The "Georgia Peach" was actually NO peach.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a damn good biopic about baseball legend Ty Cobb. Not much baseball action, but a not-to-miss movie if you are a real baseball fan. Cobb was probably the most hated ballplayer in history; but definitely one of the best...and that for sure is debatable. This movie shows what happens when a biographer discovers that the truth is far less glamorous than the legend. Respected and well liked sportswriter Al Stump(Robert Wuhl)gets assigned and requested by the subject to write the bio of Ty Cobb(Tommy Lee Jones). Stump travels through a major winter storm to Cobb's home in Tahoe. Cobb is dying and wants his story to be told...his way. Cobb mistreats, slanders, belittles and humiliates Stump at every opportunity. Stump has to battle not only his subject by his own values as to either candy-coat his story or present an accurate picture of the disgusting, racist, drunken and bitter Cobb. Most of Cobb's story is mythical and exaggerated. Even Ty would tell you he is a 'damn liar'. He was definitely someone to reckon with on the ball field. With his spaced hand grip was one of the greatest hitters of his era. He was known for sliding into second or third with cleats raised to his opponent's knees. And sliding home would even raise his cleats crotch and stomach high. His nickname was "The Georgia Peach", but he was by all means no peach. He retired in 1928 with over 90 records. In 1936, he was the very first player to be elected to the National Baseball Hall of Fame. Cobb was so disliked by other players, only 4 showed up at his funeral in 1961. Ty Cobb was quoted "When I began playing the game, baseball was about gentlemanly as a kick in the crotch." I've seen this movie several times and urge any sports fan to watch this story of a unique athlete.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cobb You would think that in a sport where teams carry around baseball bats that its players wouldn't so blatantly insult each other. However, the outfielder in this biography ran his mouth as much as his feet. Hiring famed sportswriter Al Stump (Robert Wuhl), the cantankerous Ty Cobb (Tommy Lee Jones) hopes to whitewash his blemished baseball reputation with a glowing autobiography. While staying with the 72-year-old alcoholic at his home in Lake Tahoe, Stump, himself, experiences the legendary irritability of the Hall of Famer. Over the many months and miles he spends with Cobb, Stump must decide if he's going to pen a sanitized memoir or his own tell all. Based on Stump's book, Tommy Lee Jones' performance is certainly a homerun, however, the story revels too much in Cobb's senility and deep-seated racism. Furthermore, portraying baseball players as racists is insulting to those players who are just degenerate gamblers. Yellow Light vidiotreviews.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mr. Cobb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just from a purely baseball side of things, this movie was a joy to watch,, all of the historical footage from the early days, makes me wish I could have seen the great Ty Cobb actually play. then you get into his personal life,, and everything wasn't actually roses,, he had a very seedy side to him,, heavy drinker, womanizer, lot's of stuff that today's heroes really aren't made of. but if you take the whole movie and wrap it up into one , I think that the viewer will be mesmerized from start to finish,, I know that I was. i'm a big Tommy Lee Jones fan and I hit he definitely hit a four bagger with his performance. even if you're not a baseball fan this movie is well worth watching , and if you are a baseball fan , then this is truly the movie for you to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cobb great ballplayer, not a great guy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ty Cobb is considered by most to be the best baseball player of all time or at least in the discussion for that honor. With holding almost all of the hitting records prior to Pete Rose. But as great of a player as he was he was a mean spirited, wife beater and racist by the account of a lot of times and spending any extended time with him was considered impossible. We see Cobb in this movie at the end of his life alongside Al Stump a famous sportswriter in the process of writing his autobiography with occasional flashbacks to Cobb's playing career. The movie is directed by Ron Shelton who's most known for making Bull Durham.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The humanization of the inhuman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tommy Lee Jones may not look much like the infamous ballplayer Ty Cobb, but he sure does embody his spirit, hatred, and consistent belligerence wonderfully. To play a person of his magnitude certainly requires ambition and drive but also talent and diversity. Jones tackles the player with the hatred and evilness that many archived articles and reports have claimed he proudly wore with piercing accuracy. Today, in 2012, baseball players are often viewed as "heroes," "role models," and sometimes even people who provide us with more motivation and passion than those we know in real life. Players like Starlin Castro, Alfonso Soriano, and Jim Thome have etched themselves into the hearts of many. Cobb would've etched himself in the dark side of someone's heart. He was a racist, sexist, selfish, mean-spirited, cocky, gun-toting ignoramus who hated everyone except himself. He thought of himself as "the sport of baseball," completely shunning teamwork and thoroughly enjoyed being hated by literally everyone in the audience. He thought the fact that they showed up to the stadium to throw food and garbage on him was the highest compliment someone could pay. The film centers around not his baseball career, but how a famed sportswriter had the questionably fortunate opportunity to dig into Cobb as a real person in 1959. That man was Al Stump (Robert Wuhl), who was hired to act as a ghostwriter for Cobb's autobiography. Initially, Stump is incredibly honored and thrilled to be given such a job, being able to spend days and nights with "the best baseball player of all time." But when Stump arrives, he is immediately greeted with loud rants from a writer who walks on him and we eventually see Cobb, as he lies in bed, frail and uninspired, verbally assaulting the poor man as he tries to simply reason with him and remain civil. Cobb suggests that him and Stump drive down to Reno to have sex with random women - an act he hopes to accomplish before he dies. He insists on driving recklessly through a terrible blizzard and, as he slips and slides down the road, Cobb briefly illustrates his baseball history for Al. You'd believe the film was told entirely in flashback, but the flashback ceases only after a few minutes and we are back in the present with Al and Cobb, and that's where we remain for the remainder of the picture. It is widely known that Stump published a book shortly after spending days on end with Cobb, but that was the fabricated version he was conned into writing for the man, which the film heavily explores. Al secretly kept a real recollection of his treatment and relationship with the man, but resorted to scribbling notes on cocktail napkins, small pieces of paper, etc. He then released a book detailing the true accounts of the man years after his death - accounts that are depicted in this film. Ron Shelton's Cobb is far from a perfect biopic. It's a little choppy, somewhat dry in sequences, and may run twenty minutes too long, but the fact that it humanizes an unbelievably despicable character, is written with little tongue in cheek innuendos, and the fact that it showcases many honorable performances makes it one that proves its existence nicely. Starring: Tommy Lee Jones, Robert Wuhl, and Lolita Davidovich. Directed by: Ron Shelton.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting but needed more baseball.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    willeagle23
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie on New Year's Eve while I was having a movie marathon to help me stay awake till midnight. I found the movie to be interesting but I felt it could have used more baseball scenes. I understand it was about him telling his story to Al Stump but I was expecting more baseball flashbacks. Tommy Lee Jones is really good in this movie and Robert Wuhl really stands out as well. It was neat to find out where Cobb was from and to see scenes where he was in Cooperstown for a ceremony. This movie did get me interested in checking out more info on Ty Cobb and of course checking out Al Stump's book plus others I may find. If your a baseball fan or Tommy Lee Jones fan this is worth checking out but Cobb's mean attitude does grow old after a while.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who cares?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    policy134
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an awful film. Not because it portrays a man in a not so positive light, nor because it may or may not be true to life. Simply because the story is enormously uninteresting. Tommy Lee Jones gives the pest performance as he can under the circumstances. He fires guns, belts a lot of people and is antagonistic towards just about every character in this atrocity. Character, is the main word here. Not once did I believe that any of the people here were portrayed with a minimum of accuracy. Like the character, Cobb, himself points out: "What is the truth?" I think that there must have been a serious attempt at making a decent biopic but it was probably too boring. So the director thought of an angle. Let's make it as cartoonish as we can possibly get away with. To quote another line from the movie: "He knows greatness", said by the Al Stump character, commenting on why he doesn't get the hell out of writing the bio on Cobb. He will never know greatness from Cobb and neither will we. There is another scene towards the end where Cobb is dying and has discovered that Stump has betrayed him. What does he do? He gives Stump his blessing to write a tell-all bio on him. That is maybe the best scene in the film. He basically says: "Who cares?". Ironically, a lot of people does seem to care, for about a minute, until they find some other gossip that's juicier. The only people who will truly care are the box office profiteers and by the looks of it, they were truly hurt because it was one of the more notorious failures of movies starring Tommy Lee Jones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Brilliant Scene, the Rest Disposable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    russianberserker
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ty Cobb is, by far, the most interesting and belligerently insane athlete to ever live. His baseball career was unparalleled in absurd statistics, brilliant strategy, and pure unadulterated violence. Every game he played in was a spectacle in human ability and cruelty. So of course, the film about him deals with none of that, instead focusing on the writing of his biography by author Al Stump. Now this isn't such a horrible idea in theory, as Cobb himself slid even further into paranoid dementia as years progressed and the stories of his crazed outbursts even as a senior are shocking even by today's desensitized standards. But instead of focusing on these events, which I figure were simply too interesting, the film is a pseudo fictionalized road film with a clich&eacute;d plot that will cause any knowledgeable Cobb fan to cry vinegar tears. Tommy Lee Jones does quite well as a crotchety Cobb, but somehow manages to overplay his cartoon supervillainy. Most stories about Cobb are barely believable, but to make him even crazier seems both impossible and unnecessary. Robert Wuhl, portraying the writer Al Stump, is a dark vortex of non-talent. He sucks the life out of every scene, trying to make this film his own Nagasaki. There is a reason we never see him as a leading man anymore (Arli$$ does not count. It's barely a show). Even the played out, inevitable "role reversal" of Cobb and Stump by the end is made even worse by his pure inability to utter lines that don't sound akin to a bottom shelf book on tape narration voice. For all the awful writing and bland film-making on display, there is one sequence which stands out as so far superior to the rest of this failure that accepting it's from the same film is near impossible. A hyper stylized flashback sequence displaying Cobb's overpowering psychology and brutal athleticism while actually playing the game of baseball is pure brilliance. The camera moves in bizarre fashion and the whole event seems like a dream due to the unique playing style of the monster Cobb. Every slide, hit, and tackle are rendered even more forceful due to enhanced sound, and Tommy Lee Jones OWNS the intensity of the master player. It makes the viewer drool over the possibilities of a true biopic of Cobb in his prime with the same actor. It's worth watching the film for this incredible few minutes alone, just to see what could have been. I may be slightly unfair to this film due to my own knowledge of Ty Cobb and wanting it to be something it isn't, but to make such boring, neutered movie about this maniac is nonsensical. I'm glad Ron Shelton's career has slid ever since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    We shouldn't have to lie about our heroes.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TOMASBBloodhound
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cobb is the supposedly true account of the final days of the great ballplayer Ty Cobb as seen through the eyes of sportswriter Al Stump. Tommy Lee Jones gives an extraordinary performance as the doomed and rambunctious old man. And Robert Wuhl ends up just being along for the Ride as Stump. Though it likely plays a little hard and fast with the truth, Cobb is an engrossing film. The film is told through the perspective of Al Stump who was one of the more prominent sports writers of his day. Early in the film he finds himself summoned to an elaborate yet secluded hunting lodge in the Sierra Mountains. Here he finds the angry old delusional ball player in a state just a few paces ahead of death from various cancers, ailments, and substance abuse. Cobb always seems to be pointing a pistol at those around him and occasionally firing rounds through nearby objects. Cobb knows he's about to die, but wants the complete story of his life to be told... his way! Cobb, as played by Jones is often cartoon-ish, and likely a great exaggeration of the true man. Though he claims to want Stump to only include Cobb's introspection of the game of baseball itself, he often readily offers up lurid details of his past. But then forcefully reminds his biographer, "that's not going in your book, though!" It's almost as if Cobb is using Stump as a man to relate his final confessions to, knowing for sure that many of these details will some day be told about him. If not in the book they are working on at the time. Or it could be that Cobb just needs someone to pour out his soul to in his final days, and lacks friends or close family to do it with. Either way, the film paints Cobb as a monster. And he likely wasn't as bad a guy as the film paints him. But still he was no prince, that is clear from basically every account of the man's life. The film follows Cobb and Stump on several wild escapades inside casinos, seedy motels, and even the Baseball Hall of Fame in Cooperstown, NY. Cobb is played as a violent, impotent, and repugnant junkie. Stump finds himself being more of a caregiver than a biographer by the film's end, and finds himself in a difficult situation. He is the only thing keeping Cobb alive, yet he cannot wait for the old man to die so he can spill all of his secrets in the book. Unfortunately, Stump ends up copping out with the manuscript, and only submitting the good things Cobb wanted the world to hear. He explanation.... he felt he needed Cobb to be a hero, and not the villain he proved to be. The film never really explains why Stump comes to this conclusion. And thus the viewer may feel a little short-changed. In the end, it looks like this film was only made for shock value is showing us what a monster Cobb was. But this makes the Stump character little more than just another audience member like us. Overall, the film is decent enough. Jones is fun to watch, and you'll never forget his performance. Even if it was probably a great exaggeration. The film looks good, and captures the older periods quite well. The script is a foul-mouthed exercise in brutal self-degradation and poor treatment of others, however. There is some brutal violence, and even a sexual assault at gunpoint. For those looking for the cleaner side of the man, a trip to Cooperstown might be a better idea. 7 of 10 stars. The Hound.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I live in his home town.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tyler Goss
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My grandma and her sister were both in the movie. They are in the church at the part that is filmed in Royston, Georgia. I have never seen the movie, that is why I gave it a 5. Royston is a really nice place that you should visit if you have seen the movie. There is a museum about Ty Cobb among other famous people from Royston. You can visit his grave site and places that the movie was filmed. We have a great downtown with shops and a few places to eat. Visit the funeral home and the train depot. It says that the minimum has to be 10 lines for a comment so I am trying to take up as much space as possible and I think that this is a stupid rule. Ty Cobb is one of the greatest baseball players ever and I am proud to live in is home town of Royston, Georgia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The "Georgia Peach" was actually NO peach.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a damn good biopic about baseball legend Ty Cobb. Not much baseball action, but a not-to-miss movie if you are a real baseball fan. Cobb was probably the most hated ballplayer in history; but definitely one of the best...and that for sure is debatable. This movie shows what happens when a biographer discovers that the truth is far less glamorous than the legend. Respected and well liked sportswriter Al Stump(Robert Wuhl)gets assigned and requested by the subject to write the bio of Ty Cobb(Tommy Lee Jones). Stump travels through a major winter storm to Cobb's home in Tahoe. Cobb is dying and wants his story to be told...his way. Cobb mistreats, slanders, belittles and humiliates Stump at every opportunity. Stump has to battle not only his subject by his own values as to either candy-coat his story or present an accurate picture of the disgusting, racist, drunken and bitter Cobb. Most of Cobb's story is mythical and exaggerated. Even Ty would tell you he is a 'damn liar'. He was definitely someone to reckon with on the ball field. With his spaced hand grip was one of the greatest hitters of his era. He was known for sliding into second or third with cleats raised to his opponent's knees. And sliding home would even raise his cleats crotch and stomach high. His nickname was "The Georgia Peach", but he was by all means no peach. He retired in 1928 with over 90 records. In 1936, he was the very first player to be elected to the National Baseball Hall of Fame. Cobb was so disliked by other players, only 4 showed up at his funeral in 1961. Ty Cobb was quoted "When I began playing the game, baseball was about gentlemanly as a kick in the crotch." I've seen this movie several times and urge any sports fan to watch this story of a unique athlete.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cobb You would think that in a sport where teams carry around baseball bats that its players wouldn't so blatantly insult each other. However, the outfielder in this biography ran his mouth as much as his feet. Hiring famed sportswriter Al Stump (Robert Wuhl), the cantankerous Ty Cobb (Tommy Lee Jones) hopes to whitewash his blemished baseball reputation with a glowing autobiography. While staying with the 72-year-old alcoholic at his home in Lake Tahoe, Stump, himself, experiences the legendary irritability of the Hall of Famer. Over the many months and miles he spends with Cobb, Stump must decide if he's going to pen a sanitized memoir or his own tell all. Based on Stump's book, Tommy Lee Jones' performance is certainly a homerun, however, the story revels too much in Cobb's senility and deep-seated racism. Furthermore, portraying baseball players as racists is insulting to those players who are just degenerate gamblers. Yellow Light vidiotreviews.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mr. Cobb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just from a purely baseball side of things, this movie was a joy to watch,, all of the historical footage from the early days, makes me wish I could have seen the great Ty Cobb actually play. then you get into his personal life,, and everything wasn't actually roses,, he had a very seedy side to him,, heavy drinker, womanizer, lot's of stuff that today's heroes really aren't made of. but if you take the whole movie and wrap it up into one , I think that the viewer will be mesmerized from start to finish,, I know that I was. i'm a big Tommy Lee Jones fan and I hit he definitely hit a four bagger with his performance. even if you're not a baseball fan this movie is well worth watching , and if you are a baseball fan , then this is truly the movie for you to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cobb great ballplayer, not a great guy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ty Cobb is considered by most to be the best baseball player of all time or at least in the discussion for that honor. With holding almost all of the hitting records prior to Pete Rose. But as great of a player as he was he was a mean spirited, wife beater and racist by the account of a lot of times and spending any extended time with him was considered impossible. We see Cobb in this movie at the end of his life alongside Al Stump a famous sportswriter in the process of writing his autobiography with occasional flashbacks to Cobb's playing career. The movie is directed by Ron Shelton who's most known for making Bull Durham.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The humanization of the inhuman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tommy Lee Jones may not look much like the infamous ballplayer Ty Cobb, but he sure does embody his spirit, hatred, and consistent belligerence wonderfully. To play a person of his magnitude certainly requires ambition and drive but also talent and diversity. Jones tackles the player with the hatred and evilness that many archived articles and reports have claimed he proudly wore with piercing accuracy. Today, in 2012, baseball players are often viewed as "heroes," "role models," and sometimes even people who provide us with more motivation and passion than those we know in real life. Players like Starlin Castro, Alfonso Soriano, and Jim Thome have etched themselves into the hearts of many. Cobb would've etched himself in the dark side of someone's heart. He was a racist, sexist, selfish, mean-spirited, cocky, gun-toting ignoramus who hated everyone except himself. He thought of himself as "the sport of baseball," completely shunning teamwork and thoroughly enjoyed being hated by literally everyone in the audience. He thought the fact that they showed up to the stadium to throw food and garbage on him was the highest compliment someone could pay. The film centers around not his baseball career, but how a famed sportswriter had the questionably fortunate opportunity to dig into Cobb as a real person in 1959. That man was Al Stump (Robert Wuhl), who was hired to act as a ghostwriter for Cobb's autobiography. Initially, Stump is incredibly honored and thrilled to be given such a job, being able to spend days and nights with "the best baseball player of all time." But when Stump arrives, he is immediately greeted with loud rants from a writer who walks on him and we eventually see Cobb, as he lies in bed, frail and uninspired, verbally assaulting the poor man as he tries to simply reason with him and remain civil. Cobb suggests that him and Stump drive down to Reno to have sex with random women - an act he hopes to accomplish before he dies. He insists on driving recklessly through a terrible blizzard and, as he slips and slides down the road, Cobb briefly illustrates his baseball history for Al. You'd believe the film was told entirely in flashback, but the flashback ceases only after a few minutes and we are back in the present with Al and Cobb, and that's where we remain for the remainder of the picture. It is widely known that Stump published a book shortly after spending days on end with Cobb, but that was the fabricated version he was conned into writing for the man, which the film heavily explores. Al secretly kept a real recollection of his treatment and relationship with the man, but resorted to scribbling notes on cocktail napkins, small pieces of paper, etc. He then released a book detailing the true accounts of the man years after his death - accounts that are depicted in this film. Ron Shelton's Cobb is far from a perfect biopic. It's a little choppy, somewhat dry in sequences, and may run twenty minutes too long, but the fact that it humanizes an unbelievably despicable character, is written with little tongue in cheek innuendos, and the fact that it showcases many honorable performances makes it one that proves its existence nicely. Starring: Tommy Lee Jones, Robert Wuhl, and Lolita Davidovich. Directed by: Ron Shelton.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting but needed more baseball.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    willeagle23
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie on New Year's Eve while I was having a movie marathon to help me stay awake till midnight. I found the movie to be interesting but I felt it could have used more baseball scenes. I understand it was about him telling his story to Al Stump but I was expecting more baseball flashbacks. Tommy Lee Jones is really good in this movie and Robert Wuhl really stands out as well. It was neat to find out where Cobb was from and to see scenes where he was in Cooperstown for a ceremony. This movie did get me interested in checking out more info on Ty Cobb and of course checking out Al Stump's book plus others I may find. If your a baseball fan or Tommy Lee Jones fan this is worth checking out but Cobb's mean attitude does grow old after a while.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who cares?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    policy134
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an awful film. Not because it portrays a man in a not so positive light, nor because it may or may not be true to life. Simply because the story is enormously uninteresting. Tommy Lee Jones gives the pest performance as he can under the circumstances. He fires guns, belts a lot of people and is antagonistic towards just about every character in this atrocity. Character, is the main word here. Not once did I believe that any of the people here were portrayed with a minimum of accuracy. Like the character, Cobb, himself points out: "What is the truth?" I think that there must have been a serious attempt at making a decent biopic but it was probably too boring. So the director thought of an angle. Let's make it as cartoonish as we can possibly get away with. To quote another line from the movie: "He knows greatness", said by the Al Stump character, commenting on why he doesn't get the hell out of writing the bio on Cobb. He will never know greatness from Cobb and neither will we. There is another scene towards the end where Cobb is dying and has discovered that Stump has betrayed him. What does he do? He gives Stump his blessing to write a tell-all bio on him. That is maybe the best scene in the film. He basically says: "Who cares?". Ironically, a lot of people does seem to care, for about a minute, until they find some other gossip that's juicier. The only people who will truly care are the box office profiteers and by the looks of it, they were truly hurt because it was one of the more notorious failures of movies starring Tommy Lee Jones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Brilliant Scene, the Rest Disposable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    russianberserker
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ty Cobb is, by far, the most interesting and belligerently insane athlete to ever live. His baseball career was unparalleled in absurd statistics, brilliant strategy, and pure unadulterated violence. Every game he played in was a spectacle in human ability and cruelty. So of course, the film about him deals with none of that, instead focusing on the writing of his biography by author Al Stump. Now this isn't such a horrible idea in theory, as Cobb himself slid even further into paranoid dementia as years progressed and the stories of his crazed outbursts even as a senior are shocking even by today's desensitized standards. But instead of focusing on these events, which I figure were simply too interesting, the film is a pseudo fictionalized road film with a clich&eacute;d plot that will cause any knowledgeable Cobb fan to cry vinegar tears. Tommy Lee Jones does quite well as a crotchety Cobb, but somehow manages to overplay his cartoon supervillainy. Most stories about Cobb are barely believable, but to make him even crazier seems both impossible and unnecessary. Robert Wuhl, portraying the writer Al Stump, is a dark vortex of non-talent. He sucks the life out of every scene, trying to make this film his own Nagasaki. There is a reason we never see him as a leading man anymore (Arli$$ does not count. It's barely a show). Even the played out, inevitable "role reversal" of Cobb and Stump by the end is made even worse by his pure inability to utter lines that don't sound akin to a bottom shelf book on tape narration voice. For all the awful writing and bland film-making on display, there is one sequence which stands out as so far superior to the rest of this failure that accepting it's from the same film is near impossible. A hyper stylized flashback sequence displaying Cobb's overpowering psychology and brutal athleticism while actually playing the game of baseball is pure brilliance. The camera moves in bizarre fashion and the whole event seems like a dream due to the unique playing style of the monster Cobb. Every slide, hit, and tackle are rendered even more forceful due to enhanced sound, and Tommy Lee Jones OWNS the intensity of the master player. It makes the viewer drool over the possibilities of a true biopic of Cobb in his prime with the same actor. It's worth watching the film for this incredible few minutes alone, just to see what could have been. I may be slightly unfair to this film due to my own knowledge of Ty Cobb and wanting it to be something it isn't, but to make such boring, neutered movie about this maniac is nonsensical. I'm glad Ron Shelton's career has slid ever since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    We shouldn't have to lie about our heroes.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TOMASBBloodhound
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cobb is the supposedly true account of the final days of the great ballplayer Ty Cobb as seen through the eyes of sportswriter Al Stump. Tommy Lee Jones gives an extraordinary performance as the doomed and rambunctious old man. And Robert Wuhl ends up just being along for the Ride as Stump. Though it likely plays a little hard and fast with the truth, Cobb is an engrossing film. The film is told through the perspective of Al Stump who was one of the more prominent sports writers of his day. Early in the film he finds himself summoned to an elaborate yet secluded hunting lodge in the Sierra Mountains. Here he finds the angry old delusional ball player in a state just a few paces ahead of death from various cancers, ailments, and substance abuse. Cobb always seems to be pointing a pistol at those around him and occasionally firing rounds through nearby objects. Cobb knows he's about to die, but wants the complete story of his life to be told... his way! Cobb, as played by Jones is often cartoon-ish, and likely a great exaggeration of the true man. Though he claims to want Stump to only include Cobb's introspection of the game of baseball itself, he often readily offers up lurid details of his past. But then forcefully reminds his biographer, "that's not going in your book, though!" It's almost as if Cobb is using Stump as a man to relate his final confessions to, knowing for sure that many of these details will some day be told about him. If not in the book they are working on at the time. Or it could be that Cobb just needs someone to pour out his soul to in his final days, and lacks friends or close family to do it with. Either way, the film paints Cobb as a monster. And he likely wasn't as bad a guy as the film paints him. But still he was no prince, that is clear from basically every account of the man's life. The film follows Cobb and Stump on several wild escapades inside casinos, seedy motels, and even the Baseball Hall of Fame in Cooperstown, NY. Cobb is played as a violent, impotent, and repugnant junkie. Stump finds himself being more of a caregiver than a biographer by the film's end, and finds himself in a difficult situation. He is the only thing keeping Cobb alive, yet he cannot wait for the old man to die so he can spill all of his secrets in the book. Unfortunately, Stump ends up copping out with the manuscript, and only submitting the good things Cobb wanted the world to hear. He explanation.... he felt he needed Cobb to be a hero, and not the villain he proved to be. The film never really explains why Stump comes to this conclusion. And thus the viewer may feel a little short-changed. In the end, it looks like this film was only made for shock value is showing us what a monster Cobb was. But this makes the Stump character little more than just another audience member like us. Overall, the film is decent enough. Jones is fun to watch, and you'll never forget his performance. Even if it was probably a great exaggeration. The film looks good, and captures the older periods quite well. The script is a foul-mouthed exercise in brutal self-degradation and poor treatment of others, however. There is some brutal violence, and even a sexual assault at gunpoint. For those looking for the cleaner side of the man, a trip to Cooperstown might be a better idea. 7 of 10 stars. The Hound.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I live in his home town.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tyler Goss
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My grandma and her sister were both in the movie. They are in the church at the part that is filmed in Royston, Georgia. I have never seen the movie, that is why I gave it a 5. Royston is a really nice place that you should visit if you have seen the movie. There is a museum about Ty Cobb among other famous people from Royston. You can visit his grave site and places that the movie was filmed. We have a great downtown with shops and a few places to eat. Visit the funeral home and the train depot. It says that the minimum has to be 10 lines for a comment so I am trying to take up as much space as possible and I think that this is a stupid rule. Ty Cobb is one of the greatest baseball players ever and I am proud to live in is home town of Royston, Georgia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The "Georgia Peach" was actually NO peach.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a damn good biopic about baseball legend Ty Cobb. Not much baseball action, but a not-to-miss movie if you are a real baseball fan. Cobb was probably the most hated ballplayer in history; but definitely one of the best...and that for sure is debatable. This movie shows what happens when a biographer discovers that the truth is far less glamorous than the legend. Respected and well liked sportswriter Al Stump(Robert Wuhl)gets assigned and requested by the subject to write the bio of Ty Cobb(Tommy Lee Jones). Stump travels through a major winter storm to Cobb's home in Tahoe. Cobb is dying and wants his story to be told...his way. Cobb mistreats, slanders, belittles and humiliates Stump at every opportunity. Stump has to battle not only his subject by his own values as to either candy-coat his story or present an accurate picture of the disgusting, racist, drunken and bitter Cobb. Most of Cobb's story is mythical and exaggerated. Even Ty would tell you he is a 'damn liar'. He was definitely someone to reckon with on the ball field. With his spaced hand grip was one of the greatest hitters of his era. He was known for sliding into second or third with cleats raised to his opponent's knees. And sliding home would even raise his cleats crotch and stomach high. His nickname was "The Georgia Peach", but he was by all means no peach. He retired in 1928 with over 90 records. In 1936, he was the very first player to be elected to the National Baseball Hall of Fame. Cobb was so disliked by other players, only 4 showed up at his funeral in 1961. Ty Cobb was quoted "When I began playing the game, baseball was about gentlemanly as a kick in the crotch." I've seen this movie several times and urge any sports fan to watch this story of a unique athlete.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cobb You would think that in a sport where teams carry around baseball bats that its players wouldn't so blatantly insult each other. However, the outfielder in this biography ran his mouth as much as his feet. Hiring famed sportswriter Al Stump (Robert Wuhl), the cantankerous Ty Cobb (Tommy Lee Jones) hopes to whitewash his blemished baseball reputation with a glowing autobiography. While staying with the 72-year-old alcoholic at his home in Lake Tahoe, Stump, himself, experiences the legendary irritability of the Hall of Famer. Over the many months and miles he spends with Cobb, Stump must decide if he's going to pen a sanitized memoir or his own tell all. Based on Stump's book, Tommy Lee Jones' performance is certainly a homerun, however, the story revels too much in Cobb's senility and deep-seated racism. Furthermore, portraying baseball players as racists is insulting to those players who are just degenerate gamblers. Yellow Light vidiotreviews.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mr. Cobb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just from a purely baseball side of things, this movie was a joy to watch,, all of the historical footage from the early days, makes me wish I could have seen the great Ty Cobb actually play. then you get into his personal life,, and everything wasn't actually roses,, he had a very seedy side to him,, heavy drinker, womanizer, lot's of stuff that today's heroes really aren't made of. but if you take the whole movie and wrap it up into one , I think that the viewer will be mesmerized from start to finish,, I know that I was. i'm a big Tommy Lee Jones fan and I hit he definitely hit a four bagger with his performance. even if you're not a baseball fan this movie is well worth watching , and if you are a baseball fan , then this is truly the movie for you to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cobb great ballplayer, not a great guy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ty Cobb is considered by most to be the best baseball player of all time or at least in the discussion for that honor. With holding almost all of the hitting records prior to Pete Rose. But as great of a player as he was he was a mean spirited, wife beater and racist by the account of a lot of times and spending any extended time with him was considered impossible. We see Cobb in this movie at the end of his life alongside Al Stump a famous sportswriter in the process of writing his autobiography with occasional flashbacks to Cobb's playing career. The movie is directed by Ron Shelton who's most known for making Bull Durham.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The humanization of the inhuman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tommy Lee Jones may not look much like the infamous ballplayer Ty Cobb, but he sure does embody his spirit, hatred, and consistent belligerence wonderfully. To play a person of his magnitude certainly requires ambition and drive but also talent and diversity. Jones tackles the player with the hatred and evilness that many archived articles and reports have claimed he proudly wore with piercing accuracy. Today, in 2012, baseball players are often viewed as "heroes," "role models," and sometimes even people who provide us with more motivation and passion than those we know in real life. Players like Starlin Castro, Alfonso Soriano, and Jim Thome have etched themselves into the hearts of many. Cobb would've etched himself in the dark side of someone's heart. He was a racist, sexist, selfish, mean-spirited, cocky, gun-toting ignoramus who hated everyone except himself. He thought of himself as "the sport of baseball," completely shunning teamwork and thoroughly enjoyed being hated by literally everyone in the audience. He thought the fact that they showed up to the stadium to throw food and garbage on him was the highest compliment someone could pay. The film centers around not his baseball career, but how a famed sportswriter had the questionably fortunate opportunity to dig into Cobb as a real person in 1959. That man was Al Stump (Robert Wuhl), who was hired to act as a ghostwriter for Cobb's autobiography. Initially, Stump is incredibly honored and thrilled to be given such a job, being able to spend days and nights with "the best baseball player of all time." But when Stump arrives, he is immediately greeted with loud rants from a writer who walks on him and we eventually see Cobb, as he lies in bed, frail and uninspired, verbally assaulting the poor man as he tries to simply reason with him and remain civil. Cobb suggests that him and Stump drive down to Reno to have sex with random women - an act he hopes to accomplish before he dies. He insists on driving recklessly through a terrible blizzard and, as he slips and slides down the road, Cobb briefly illustrates his baseball history for Al. You'd believe the film was told entirely in flashback, but the flashback ceases only after a few minutes and we are back in the present with Al and Cobb, and that's where we remain for the remainder of the picture. It is widely known that Stump published a book shortly after spending days on end with Cobb, but that was the fabricated version he was conned into writing for the man, which the film heavily explores. Al secretly kept a real recollection of his treatment and relationship with the man, but resorted to scribbling notes on cocktail napkins, small pieces of paper, etc. He then released a book detailing the true accounts of the man years after his death - accounts that are depicted in this film. Ron Shelton's Cobb is far from a perfect biopic. It's a little choppy, somewhat dry in sequences, and may run twenty minutes too long, but the fact that it humanizes an unbelievably despicable character, is written with little tongue in cheek innuendos, and the fact that it showcases many honorable performances makes it one that proves its existence nicely. Starring: Tommy Lee Jones, Robert Wuhl, and Lolita Davidovich. Directed by: Ron Shelton.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting but needed more baseball.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    willeagle23
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie on New Year's Eve while I was having a movie marathon to help me stay awake till midnight. I found the movie to be interesting but I felt it could have used more baseball scenes. I understand it was about him telling his story to Al Stump but I was expecting more baseball flashbacks. Tommy Lee Jones is really good in this movie and Robert Wuhl really stands out as well. It was neat to find out where Cobb was from and to see scenes where he was in Cooperstown for a ceremony. This movie did get me interested in checking out more info on Ty Cobb and of course checking out Al Stump's book plus others I may find. If your a baseball fan or Tommy Lee Jones fan this is worth checking out but Cobb's mean attitude does grow old after a while.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who cares?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    policy134
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an awful film. Not because it portrays a man in a not so positive light, nor because it may or may not be true to life. Simply because the story is enormously uninteresting. Tommy Lee Jones gives the pest performance as he can under the circumstances. He fires guns, belts a lot of people and is antagonistic towards just about every character in this atrocity. Character, is the main word here. Not once did I believe that any of the people here were portrayed with a minimum of accuracy. Like the character, Cobb, himself points out: "What is the truth?" I think that there must have been a serious attempt at making a decent biopic but it was probably too boring. So the director thought of an angle. Let's make it as cartoonish as we can possibly get away with. To quote another line from the movie: "He knows greatness", said by the Al Stump character, commenting on why he doesn't get the hell out of writing the bio on Cobb. He will never know greatness from Cobb and neither will we. There is another scene towards the end where Cobb is dying and has discovered that Stump has betrayed him. What does he do? He gives Stump his blessing to write a tell-all bio on him. That is maybe the best scene in the film. He basically says: "Who cares?". Ironically, a lot of people does seem to care, for about a minute, until they find some other gossip that's juicier. The only people who will truly care are the box office profiteers and by the looks of it, they were truly hurt because it was one of the more notorious failures of movies starring Tommy Lee Jones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Brilliant Scene, the Rest Disposable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    russianberserker
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ty Cobb is, by far, the most interesting and belligerently insane athlete to ever live. His baseball career was unparalleled in absurd statistics, brilliant strategy, and pure unadulterated violence. Every game he played in was a spectacle in human ability and cruelty. So of course, the film about him deals with none of that, instead focusing on the writing of his biography by author Al Stump. Now this isn't such a horrible idea in theory, as Cobb himself slid even further into paranoid dementia as years progressed and the stories of his crazed outbursts even as a senior are shocking even by today's desensitized standards. But instead of focusing on these events, which I figure were simply too interesting, the film is a pseudo fictionalized road film with a clich&eacute;d plot that will cause any knowledgeable Cobb fan to cry vinegar tears. Tommy Lee Jones does quite well as a crotchety Cobb, but somehow manages to overplay his cartoon supervillainy. Most stories about Cobb are barely believable, but to make him even crazier seems both impossible and unnecessary. Robert Wuhl, portraying the writer Al Stump, is a dark vortex of non-talent. He sucks the life out of every scene, trying to make this film his own Nagasaki. There is a reason we never see him as a leading man anymore (Arli$$ does not count. It's barely a show). Even the played out, inevitable "role reversal" of Cobb and Stump by the end is made even worse by his pure inability to utter lines that don't sound akin to a bottom shelf book on tape narration voice. For all the awful writing and bland film-making on display, there is one sequence which stands out as so far superior to the rest of this failure that accepting it's from the same film is near impossible. A hyper stylized flashback sequence displaying Cobb's overpowering psychology and brutal athleticism while actually playing the game of baseball is pure brilliance. The camera moves in bizarre fashion and the whole event seems like a dream due to the unique playing style of the monster Cobb. Every slide, hit, and tackle are rendered even more forceful due to enhanced sound, and Tommy Lee Jones OWNS the intensity of the master player. It makes the viewer drool over the possibilities of a true biopic of Cobb in his prime with the same actor. It's worth watching the film for this incredible few minutes alone, just to see what could have been. I may be slightly unfair to this film due to my own knowledge of Ty Cobb and wanting it to be something it isn't, but to make such boring, neutered movie about this maniac is nonsensical. I'm glad Ron Shelton's career has slid ever since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    We shouldn't have to lie about our heroes.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TOMASBBloodhound
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cobb is the supposedly true account of the final days of the great ballplayer Ty Cobb as seen through the eyes of sportswriter Al Stump. Tommy Lee Jones gives an extraordinary performance as the doomed and rambunctious old man. And Robert Wuhl ends up just being along for the Ride as Stump. Though it likely plays a little hard and fast with the truth, Cobb is an engrossing film. The film is told through the perspective of Al Stump who was one of the more prominent sports writers of his day. Early in the film he finds himself summoned to an elaborate yet secluded hunting lodge in the Sierra Mountains. Here he finds the angry old delusional ball player in a state just a few paces ahead of death from various cancers, ailments, and substance abuse. Cobb always seems to be pointing a pistol at those around him and occasionally firing rounds through nearby objects. Cobb knows he's about to die, but wants the complete story of his life to be told... his way! Cobb, as played by Jones is often cartoon-ish, and likely a great exaggeration of the true man. Though he claims to want Stump to only include Cobb's introspection of the game of baseball itself, he often readily offers up lurid details of his past. But then forcefully reminds his biographer, "that's not going in your book, though!" It's almost as if Cobb is using Stump as a man to relate his final confessions to, knowing for sure that many of these details will some day be told about him. If not in the book they are working on at the time. Or it could be that Cobb just needs someone to pour out his soul to in his final days, and lacks friends or close family to do it with. Either way, the film paints Cobb as a monster. And he likely wasn't as bad a guy as the film paints him. But still he was no prince, that is clear from basically every account of the man's life. The film follows Cobb and Stump on several wild escapades inside casinos, seedy motels, and even the Baseball Hall of Fame in Cooperstown, NY. Cobb is played as a violent, impotent, and repugnant junkie. Stump finds himself being more of a caregiver than a biographer by the film's end, and finds himself in a difficult situation. He is the only thing keeping Cobb alive, yet he cannot wait for the old man to die so he can spill all of his secrets in the book. Unfortunately, Stump ends up copping out with the manuscript, and only submitting the good things Cobb wanted the world to hear. He explanation.... he felt he needed Cobb to be a hero, and not the villain he proved to be. The film never really explains why Stump comes to this conclusion. And thus the viewer may feel a little short-changed. In the end, it looks like this film was only made for shock value is showing us what a monster Cobb was. But this makes the Stump character little more than just another audience member like us. Overall, the film is decent enough. Jones is fun to watch, and you'll never forget his performance. Even if it was probably a great exaggeration. The film looks good, and captures the older periods quite well. The script is a foul-mouthed exercise in brutal self-degradation and poor treatment of others, however. There is some brutal violence, and even a sexual assault at gunpoint. For those looking for the cleaner side of the man, a trip to Cooperstown might be a better idea. 7 of 10 stars. The Hound.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I live in his home town.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tyler Goss
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My grandma and her sister were both in the movie. They are in the church at the part that is filmed in Royston, Georgia. I have never seen the movie, that is why I gave it a 5. Royston is a really nice place that you should visit if you have seen the movie. There is a museum about Ty Cobb among other famous people from Royston. You can visit his grave site and places that the movie was filmed. We have a great downtown with shops and a few places to eat. Visit the funeral home and the train depot. It says that the minimum has to be 10 lines for a comment so I am trying to take up as much space as possible and I think that this is a stupid rule. Ty Cobb is one of the greatest baseball players ever and I am proud to live in is home town of Royston, Georgia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The "Georgia Peach" was actually NO peach.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a damn good biopic about baseball legend Ty Cobb. Not much baseball action, but a not-to-miss movie if you are a real baseball fan. Cobb was probably the most hated ballplayer in history; but definitely one of the best...and that for sure is debatable. This movie shows what happens when a biographer discovers that the truth is far less glamorous than the legend. Respected and well liked sportswriter Al Stump(Robert Wuhl)gets assigned and requested by the subject to write the bio of Ty Cobb(Tommy Lee Jones). Stump travels through a major winter storm to Cobb's home in Tahoe. Cobb is dying and wants his story to be told...his way. Cobb mistreats, slanders, belittles and humiliates Stump at every opportunity. Stump has to battle not only his subject by his own values as to either candy-coat his story or present an accurate picture of the disgusting, racist, drunken and bitter Cobb. Most of Cobb's story is mythical and exaggerated. Even Ty would tell you he is a 'damn liar'. He was definitely someone to reckon with on the ball field. With his spaced hand grip was one of the greatest hitters of his era. He was known for sliding into second or third with cleats raised to his opponent's knees. And sliding home would even raise his cleats crotch and stomach high. His nickname was "The Georgia Peach", but he was by all means no peach. He retired in 1928 with over 90 records. In 1936, he was the very first player to be elected to the National Baseball Hall of Fame. Cobb was so disliked by other players, only 4 showed up at his funeral in 1961. Ty Cobb was quoted "When I began playing the game, baseball was about gentlemanly as a kick in the crotch." I've seen this movie several times and urge any sports fan to watch this story of a unique athlete.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cobb You would think that in a sport where teams carry around baseball bats that its players wouldn't so blatantly insult each other. However, the outfielder in this biography ran his mouth as much as his feet. Hiring famed sportswriter Al Stump (Robert Wuhl), the cantankerous Ty Cobb (Tommy Lee Jones) hopes to whitewash his blemished baseball reputation with a glowing autobiography. While staying with the 72-year-old alcoholic at his home in Lake Tahoe, Stump, himself, experiences the legendary irritability of the Hall of Famer. Over the many months and miles he spends with Cobb, Stump must decide if he's going to pen a sanitized memoir or his own tell all. Based on Stump's book, Tommy Lee Jones' performance is certainly a homerun, however, the story revels too much in Cobb's senility and deep-seated racism. Furthermore, portraying baseball players as racists is insulting to those players who are just degenerate gamblers. Yellow Light vidiotreviews.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mr. Cobb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just from a purely baseball side of things, this movie was a joy to watch,, all of the historical footage from the early days, makes me wish I could have seen the great Ty Cobb actually play. then you get into his personal life,, and everything wasn't actually roses,, he had a very seedy side to him,, heavy drinker, womanizer, lot's of stuff that today's heroes really aren't made of. but if you take the whole movie and wrap it up into one , I think that the viewer will be mesmerized from start to finish,, I know that I was. i'm a big Tommy Lee Jones fan and I hit he definitely hit a four bagger with his performance. even if you're not a baseball fan this movie is well worth watching , and if you are a baseball fan , then this is truly the movie for you to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cobb great ballplayer, not a great guy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ty Cobb is considered by most to be the best baseball player of all time or at least in the discussion for that honor. With holding almost all of the hitting records prior to Pete Rose. But as great of a player as he was he was a mean spirited, wife beater and racist by the account of a lot of times and spending any extended time with him was considered impossible. We see Cobb in this movie at the end of his life alongside Al Stump a famous sportswriter in the process of writing his autobiography with occasional flashbacks to Cobb's playing career. The movie is directed by Ron Shelton who's most known for making Bull Durham.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The humanization of the inhuman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tommy Lee Jones may not look much like the infamous ballplayer Ty Cobb, but he sure does embody his spirit, hatred, and consistent belligerence wonderfully. To play a person of his magnitude certainly requires ambition and drive but also talent and diversity. Jones tackles the player with the hatred and evilness that many archived articles and reports have claimed he proudly wore with piercing accuracy. Today, in 2012, baseball players are often viewed as "heroes," "role models," and sometimes even people who provide us with more motivation and passion than those we know in real life. Players like Starlin Castro, Alfonso Soriano, and Jim Thome have etched themselves into the hearts of many. Cobb would've etched himself in the dark side of someone's heart. He was a racist, sexist, selfish, mean-spirited, cocky, gun-toting ignoramus who hated everyone except himself. He thought of himself as "the sport of baseball," completely shunning teamwork and thoroughly enjoyed being hated by literally everyone in the audience. He thought the fact that they showed up to the stadium to throw food and garbage on him was the highest compliment someone could pay. The film centers around not his baseball career, but how a famed sportswriter had the questionably fortunate opportunity to dig into Cobb as a real person in 1959. That man was Al Stump (Robert Wuhl), who was hired to act as a ghostwriter for Cobb's autobiography. Initially, Stump is incredibly honored and thrilled to be given such a job, being able to spend days and nights with "the best baseball player of all time." But when Stump arrives, he is immediately greeted with loud rants from a writer who walks on him and we eventually see Cobb, as he lies in bed, frail and uninspired, verbally assaulting the poor man as he tries to simply reason with him and remain civil. Cobb suggests that him and Stump drive down to Reno to have sex with random women - an act he hopes to accomplish before he dies. He insists on driving recklessly through a terrible blizzard and, as he slips and slides down the road, Cobb briefly illustrates his baseball history for Al. You'd believe the film was told entirely in flashback, but the flashback ceases only after a few minutes and we are back in the present with Al and Cobb, and that's where we remain for the remainder of the picture. It is widely known that Stump published a book shortly after spending days on end with Cobb, but that was the fabricated version he was conned into writing for the man, which the film heavily explores. Al secretly kept a real recollection of his treatment and relationship with the man, but resorted to scribbling notes on cocktail napkins, small pieces of paper, etc. He then released a book detailing the true accounts of the man years after his death - accounts that are depicted in this film. Ron Shelton's Cobb is far from a perfect biopic. It's a little choppy, somewhat dry in sequences, and may run twenty minutes too long, but the fact that it humanizes an unbelievably despicable character, is written with little tongue in cheek innuendos, and the fact that it showcases many honorable performances makes it one that proves its existence nicely. Starring: Tommy Lee Jones, Robert Wuhl, and Lolita Davidovich. Directed by: Ron Shelton.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting but needed more baseball.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    willeagle23
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie on New Year's Eve while I was having a movie marathon to help me stay awake till midnight. I found the movie to be interesting but I felt it could have used more baseball scenes. I understand it was about him telling his story to Al Stump but I was expecting more baseball flashbacks. Tommy Lee Jones is really good in this movie and Robert Wuhl really stands out as well. It was neat to find out where Cobb was from and to see scenes where he was in Cooperstown for a ceremony. This movie did get me interested in checking out more info on Ty Cobb and of course checking out Al Stump's book plus others I may find. If your a baseball fan or Tommy Lee Jones fan this is worth checking out but Cobb's mean attitude does grow old after a while.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who cares?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    policy134
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an awful film. Not because it portrays a man in a not so positive light, nor because it may or may not be true to life. Simply because the story is enormously uninteresting. Tommy Lee Jones gives the pest performance as he can under the circumstances. He fires guns, belts a lot of people and is antagonistic towards just about every character in this atrocity. Character, is the main word here. Not once did I believe that any of the people here were portrayed with a minimum of accuracy. Like the character, Cobb, himself points out: "What is the truth?" I think that there must have been a serious attempt at making a decent biopic but it was probably too boring. So the director thought of an angle. Let's make it as cartoonish as we can possibly get away with. To quote another line from the movie: "He knows greatness", said by the Al Stump character, commenting on why he doesn't get the hell out of writing the bio on Cobb. He will never know greatness from Cobb and neither will we. There is another scene towards the end where Cobb is dying and has discovered that Stump has betrayed him. What does he do? He gives Stump his blessing to write a tell-all bio on him. That is maybe the best scene in the film. He basically says: "Who cares?". Ironically, a lot of people does seem to care, for about a minute, until they find some other gossip that's juicier. The only people who will truly care are the box office profiteers and by the looks of it, they were truly hurt because it was one of the more notorious failures of movies starring Tommy Lee Jones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Brilliant Scene, the Rest Disposable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    russianberserker
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ty Cobb is, by far, the most interesting and belligerently insane athlete to ever live. His baseball career was unparalleled in absurd statistics, brilliant strategy, and pure unadulterated violence. Every game he played in was a spectacle in human ability and cruelty. So of course, the film about him deals with none of that, instead focusing on the writing of his biography by author Al Stump. Now this isn't such a horrible idea in theory, as Cobb himself slid even further into paranoid dementia as years progressed and the stories of his crazed outbursts even as a senior are shocking even by today's desensitized standards. But instead of focusing on these events, which I figure were simply too interesting, the film is a pseudo fictionalized road film with a clich&eacute;d plot that will cause any knowledgeable Cobb fan to cry vinegar tears. Tommy Lee Jones does quite well as a crotchety Cobb, but somehow manages to overplay his cartoon supervillainy. Most stories about Cobb are barely believable, but to make him even crazier seems both impossible and unnecessary. Robert Wuhl, portraying the writer Al Stump, is a dark vortex of non-talent. He sucks the life out of every scene, trying to make this film his own Nagasaki. There is a reason we never see him as a leading man anymore (Arli$$ does not count. It's barely a show). Even the played out, inevitable "role reversal" of Cobb and Stump by the end is made even worse by his pure inability to utter lines that don't sound akin to a bottom shelf book on tape narration voice. For all the awful writing and bland film-making on display, there is one sequence which stands out as so far superior to the rest of this failure that accepting it's from the same film is near impossible. A hyper stylized flashback sequence displaying Cobb's overpowering psychology and brutal athleticism while actually playing the game of baseball is pure brilliance. The camera moves in bizarre fashion and the whole event seems like a dream due to the unique playing style of the monster Cobb. Every slide, hit, and tackle are rendered even more forceful due to enhanced sound, and Tommy Lee Jones OWNS the intensity of the master player. It makes the viewer drool over the possibilities of a true biopic of Cobb in his prime with the same actor. It's worth watching the film for this incredible few minutes alone, just to see what could have been. I may be slightly unfair to this film due to my own knowledge of Ty Cobb and wanting it to be something it isn't, but to make such boring, neutered movie about this maniac is nonsensical. I'm glad Ron Shelton's career has slid ever since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    We shouldn't have to lie about our heroes.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TOMASBBloodhound
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cobb is the supposedly true account of the final days of the great ballplayer Ty Cobb as seen through the eyes of sportswriter Al Stump. Tommy Lee Jones gives an extraordinary performance as the doomed and rambunctious old man. And Robert Wuhl ends up just being along for the Ride as Stump. Though it likely plays a little hard and fast with the truth, Cobb is an engrossing film. The film is told through the perspective of Al Stump who was one of the more prominent sports writers of his day. Early in the film he finds himself summoned to an elaborate yet secluded hunting lodge in the Sierra Mountains. Here he finds the angry old delusional ball player in a state just a few paces ahead of death from various cancers, ailments, and substance abuse. Cobb always seems to be pointing a pistol at those around him and occasionally firing rounds through nearby objects. Cobb knows he's about to die, but wants the complete story of his life to be told... his way! Cobb, as played by Jones is often cartoon-ish, and likely a great exaggeration of the true man. Though he claims to want Stump to only include Cobb's introspection of the game of baseball itself, he often readily offers up lurid details of his past. But then forcefully reminds his biographer, "that's not going in your book, though!" It's almost as if Cobb is using Stump as a man to relate his final confessions to, knowing for sure that many of these details will some day be told about him. If not in the book they are working on at the time. Or it could be that Cobb just needs someone to pour out his soul to in his final days, and lacks friends or close family to do it with. Either way, the film paints Cobb as a monster. And he likely wasn't as bad a guy as the film paints him. But still he was no prince, that is clear from basically every account of the man's life. The film follows Cobb and Stump on several wild escapades inside casinos, seedy motels, and even the Baseball Hall of Fame in Cooperstown, NY. Cobb is played as a violent, impotent, and repugnant junkie. Stump finds himself being more of a caregiver than a biographer by the film's end, and finds himself in a difficult situation. He is the only thing keeping Cobb alive, yet he cannot wait for the old man to die so he can spill all of his secrets in the book. Unfortunately, Stump ends up copping out with the manuscript, and only submitting the good things Cobb wanted the world to hear. He explanation.... he felt he needed Cobb to be a hero, and not the villain he proved to be. The film never really explains why Stump comes to this conclusion. And thus the viewer may feel a little short-changed. In the end, it looks like this film was only made for shock value is showing us what a monster Cobb was. But this makes the Stump character little more than just another audience member like us. Overall, the film is decent enough. Jones is fun to watch, and you'll never forget his performance. Even if it was probably a great exaggeration. The film looks good, and captures the older periods quite well. The script is a foul-mouthed exercise in brutal self-degradation and poor treatment of others, however. There is some brutal violence, and even a sexual assault at gunpoint. For those looking for the cleaner side of the man, a trip to Cooperstown might be a better idea. 7 of 10 stars. The Hound.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I live in his home town.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tyler Goss
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My grandma and her sister were both in the movie. They are in the church at the part that is filmed in Royston, Georgia. I have never seen the movie, that is why I gave it a 5. Royston is a really nice place that you should visit if you have seen the movie. There is a museum about Ty Cobb among other famous people from Royston. You can visit his grave site and places that the movie was filmed. We have a great downtown with shops and a few places to eat. Visit the funeral home and the train depot. It says that the minimum has to be 10 lines for a comment so I am trying to take up as much space as possible and I think that this is a stupid rule. Ty Cobb is one of the greatest baseball players ever and I am proud to live in is home town of Royston, Georgia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The "Georgia Peach" was actually NO peach.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a damn good biopic about baseball legend Ty Cobb. Not much baseball action, but a not-to-miss movie if you are a real baseball fan. Cobb was probably the most hated ballplayer in history; but definitely one of the best...and that for sure is debatable. This movie shows what happens when a biographer discovers that the truth is far less glamorous than the legend. Respected and well liked sportswriter Al Stump(Robert Wuhl)gets assigned and requested by the subject to write the bio of Ty Cobb(Tommy Lee Jones). Stump travels through a major winter storm to Cobb's home in Tahoe. Cobb is dying and wants his story to be told...his way. Cobb mistreats, slanders, belittles and humiliates Stump at every opportunity. Stump has to battle not only his subject by his own values as to either candy-coat his story or present an accurate picture of the disgusting, racist, drunken and bitter Cobb. Most of Cobb's story is mythical and exaggerated. Even Ty would tell you he is a 'damn liar'. He was definitely someone to reckon with on the ball field. With his spaced hand grip was one of the greatest hitters of his era. He was known for sliding into second or third with cleats raised to his opponent's knees. And sliding home would even raise his cleats crotch and stomach high. His nickname was "The Georgia Peach", but he was by all means no peach. He retired in 1928 with over 90 records. In 1936, he was the very first player to be elected to the National Baseball Hall of Fame. Cobb was so disliked by other players, only 4 showed up at his funeral in 1961. Ty Cobb was quoted "When I began playing the game, baseball was about gentlemanly as a kick in the crotch." I've seen this movie several times and urge any sports fan to watch this story of a unique athlete.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
