<filme>
 <id>
  1118
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0078446
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1978
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Queimando Tudo
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Two stoners unknowingly smuggle a van - made entirely of marijuana - from Mexico to L.A., with incompetent Sgt. Stedenko on their trail.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Cheech and Chong meet up by chance on the highway somewhere in California. They go in search of some dope and are accidentally deported to Mexico where in their desperation to get home they agree to drive a van back to the States so they can get back in time for a gig they are due to play. Unaware of the properties from which the van is constructed they make their way back having aquired a couple of female hitch-hikers whilst all the time avoiding the cops whom they are not even aware are following them.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Music
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   van
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   marijuana
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   mexico
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   smuggling
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   dope
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Lou Adler
  </diretor>
  <diretor>
   Tommy Chong
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Tommy Chong
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Cheech Marin
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Cheech Marin
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Tommy Chong
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Strother Martin
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very amiable comedy classic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Legendary comedy duo Cheech & Chong's first and best cinematic outing is a hoot the entire time, just what this reviewer would recommend for those people who just want to turn off their brain for about an hour and a half and relax. One certainly doesn't have to be a stoner themselves in order to appreciate it. There's not much of a story here, mostly a series of easygoing, sometimes hysterical vignettes as Pedro (Cheech) and Anthony (Chong) go on the hunt for "good grass", although Pedro's main ambition is for his band to achieve some fame and fortune, and, recruiting Anthony as a drummer, he and his bandmates get their chance in a battle of the bands for the movie's finish. Great sight gags abound; the fact that Pedro and Anthony end up driving a van that's actually made out of marijuana is priceless. Hot on their trail is flustered narc Stedenko (Stacy Keach), who's stuck with a bunch of incredibly inept detectives. Cheech & Chong are hilarious as always, and incidentally, one can see how Chong's Anthony would get the nickname that he has, MAN. A spirited supporting cast adds to the fun, although I personally would have liked to have seen at least a little more of Strother Martin as Anthony's fed-up father. But Tom Skerritt is great as Pedro's Nam flashback plagued cousin Strawberry (I'd advise you not to look at his neck), Louisa Moritz is in fine bubbly form as luscious cop Gloria, and Zane Buzby is fun as stoner babe Jade East. The cast features such familiar character players and celebrities as Arthur Roberts, Donald Hotton, Ray Vitte, Gary Mule Deer, Mills Watson, Val Avery, and Rodney Bingenheimer, with lovely ladies Cheryl "Rainbeaux" Smith and Wally Ann Wharton adding to the entertainment value. It's just too funny to see, among other things, a group of nuns get detained by the cops, and the cops getting the munchies as they get stoned. The cool soundtrack (including the classic "Low Rider") and the bright, sunny look of the film are big bonuses, and the laughs keep coming at a consistent pace. "Up in Smoke" is good natured in spirit, and is definitely too hard to resist. Eight out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slam-Bong Comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first Cheech & Chong stoner comedy of errors "Up in Smoke" consists of gags lifted from their comedy albums about marijuana usage tacked onto a rolling paper thin plot about smuggling a fortune in pot into the U.S. by two dopers desperate for some weed to puff. The message is that if our heroes get high enough that all their troubles will disappear in a purple haze of smoke. Freshman director Lou Adler learned on the job with this occasionally funny comedy that never advocates the legalization of pot. You won't find anything remotely subversive and "Up in Smoke" doesn't take any chances. Adler and scenarists Tommy Chong and Cheech Marin may have gotten high when they contrived this harmless nonsense, but they have no lofty aims. They ridicule their own clueless characters as well as a cadre of hopelessly inept but zealous narcotics police officers who pursue them. "Up in Smoke" amounts to a stoned version of the Keystone Kops, except that the cops are narcs. Of course, Pedro De Bacas (Cheech Marin) and Anthony Stoner (Tommy Chong) are a pair of misguided stoners who encounter each other after Anthony's intolerant father Arnold (Strother Martin of "The Wild Bunch") threatens to pack him off to military school if he doesn't get a job. Anthony's Volkswagon Beetle conks out on him on the highway and he winds up spending the night in a ditch before Pedro mistakes him for a woman and tries to pick him up. Several mildly amusing scenes follow without apparent much apparent motivation. Everything centers on the efforts of our duo to find some good marijuana. One of the funniest scenes in the first 30 minutes shows them smoking a hilariously huge joint that consists of Maui-wowie strained from the turds of Anthony's Labrador. According to Anthony, he caught man's best friend chowing down on his stash and then followed him around with a baggie. Smoke pours out of their car as Pedros cruises the freeway. Inevitably, the police pull them over and pack them off to court with Anthony the worst for wear. During their arraignment in court, Anthony partakes of water from the judge's carafe. He spews the contents and announces to everybody that the judge has been drinking vodka. Our heroes are released after this alarming incident. Later, they visit one of their friends, Veteran-veteran Strawberry (Tom Skerritt of "M.A.S.H.") who has a huge discolored birthmark looking scar on his face. Before Strawberry can goad Anthony into confessing that he is staring at his skin problem, Pedro gets him to embark on a search for some reefer. They leave Anthony at Strawberry's house and Anthony monkeys around with some Comet so that it appears to be cocaine. Party girls snort it up and raise hell. Strawberry has a Vietnam flashback and dons his combat gear, while Pedro warns Anthony of an impending bust by Sergeant Stedenko. No sooner do our heroes escape from the cops a second time than they are caught in a raid organized by INS agents and bussed back across the border. The catch is that the rest of the Mexicans deliberately informed on themselves so they could get a free ride to the border prior to a wedding. Pedro and Anthony go to an upholstery shop run by an uncle to acquire the means of getting back across the border. Predictably, they enter the wrong shop and find themselves in a massive pot smuggling enterprise. They are given a van to drive back to L.A., but what our protagonists don't realize is that they are driving a van constructed of fiberweed. Meaning, the dope smugglers have converted the THC resin found in marijuana in a fiberglass-like substance. Just when it looks like our heroes will be busted at the border, Anthony thumps a roach into a station wagon full of Catholic sisters. The authorities allows our heroes to pass through, but they bust the sisters. Once they are back in L.A., Pedro and Anthony decide to compete in a battle of rock bands. They dress themselves in outlandish costumes and manage to sing a ridiculous song that turns the entire audience into a raving room of fans. The general idea here to keep our heroes off balance as they look for pot and Alder and company shun any political positions. No, this is not an imaginative comedy, but it marked not only their debut but the biggest depiction of a counter-culture duo that spawned a number of lesser films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Start To Stoner Comedies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cheech and Chong meet up by chance on the highway somewhere in California. They go in search of some dope and are accidentally deported to Mexico where in their desperation to get home they agree to drive a van back to the States so they can get back in time for a gig they are due to play. Unaware of the properties from which the van is constructed they make their way back having acquired a couple of female hitch-hikers whilst all the time avoiding the cops whom they are not even aware are following them. Tonight I Decided To Give The Mother Of All Stoner Comedies A Go. This Is Not Just The Mother Of Stoner Comedies...Its The Father Of Dumb Comedies. I Loved Every Minute Of It...I Was Adimant Not To Turn The TV Off When Cheech & Chong Smoked Dog Crap That Came From A Dog That Ate Chong's Marjuana...I'm Laughing Now As I Type It Up. I Also Have Some Of Their Recordings Like "Dave", "Up In Smoke"(I Was Familiar With The Movie Before Tonight), I Even Had "Earache My Eye" Which Is My Personal Favourite So I Didn't Mind Hearing It In This Film But I Would've Loved It Even More If After The End Credits The Sketch That Goes With Earache My Eye Would Play. I Also Loved The Fact That They Were So Dumb That They Had No Idea The "Hard Hat" Cops Were After Them. Overall If You Like Stoner Comedies In The Same Vein As The Kevin Smith Comedies Of...Well His Entire Career Than This Movie Is Definitely One To Buy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where it all began...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluethunder35 (bluethunder35@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Richard "Cheech" Marin and Tommy Chong debuted their Mary-Jane fueled humor with Up In Smoke. While Reefer Madness was the first notable film to promote weed, it's this film that set the template for stoner films. Not really much of a plot here: Pedro De Pacas (Marin) meets up with rich-kid Anthony "Man" Stoner (Chong) and find out they both like getting high. Their search for pot takes them all over Los Angeles and Tijuana in a wacky road-trip in a car unknowingly made out of grass. On their trip, they have to deal with Sgt. Sedenko (Stacy Keach), an over-zealous police officer trying to clean L.A. of druggies. The movie is filled with crazy situations: drug-filled parties, performances at a punk rock contest and a trip through a upholstery factory that is just a front for drug trafficking. Crazy people, the kind you would expect in a film like this, are everywhere. Both Marin and Chong are very good in the film but Keach steals the show. He is an absolute hoot in this film and he comes off as the most interesting character in the film. It's still very entertaining to this day as a curiosity piece. Check it out. BTW, one of the ladies Pedro and Man picks up looks remarkably like Sharon Snow of NTV.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The First & Best Cheech and Chong Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TBoldOne
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cheech and Chong were already insanely popular with their comedy record albums and were contracted to make a movie. Hoping to make the "big score" they go to Mexico and end up driving a van built entirely of Weed back across the border. Many reviewers have already commented on the classic "stoner" humor, and I won't add to that. If you get this movie get the DVD with the extended commentary. In it you find that they were on the cutting edge of the Punk Rock revolution. The battle of the bands features some of the earliest LA punk rock bands. My favorite gags. 1) Cheech and Chong get in their car, do a U - Turn, park on the other side of the street and get out. 2) The Van Scene - This literally made the phrase "If this vans rocking, don't come a-knocking" part of our popular culture. Whats so amazing about this scene was that it wasn't even in the original script! The actress, who played Chongs girlfriend was telling the story of a roommate who was a "screamer", while they were on lunch break outside of the battle of the bands show. Cheech and Chong said that sounds funny, lets film it. It just goes to show you that sometimes the best comedy can be the spontaneous type. Finally students of film comedy should rent this movie for an unusual reason. Watching this movie in 2010 is like a going into a time warp. This movie could never be made today, and I'm not referring to the drug humor. The pacing of the gags is so slow compared to today. It's weirdly funny when you watch and notice it like I did. Sadly most comedies today don't give their actors time to develop their gags. If you wan't a harmless (except for the drug humor) movie, buy this movie. It is the best of the Cheech and Chong movies
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheech and Chong's Up in Smoke
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first heard of and saw Cheech and Chong featured in the South Park Episode "Cherokee Hair Tampons", and then I heard about this 1001 Movies You See Before You Die recommended film. Basically slackers and getting nowhere musicians Pedro De Pacas (Richard 'Cheech' Marin) and Anthony 'Man' Stoner (Tommy Chong) happen to meet on a Californian highway, and instantly find a connection with their love of marijuana. They are pulled over by the cops, and end up deported to Mexico, but in court they are let off lightly by the Vodka drinking judge, and they start a road trip to go back home, and try to score some drugs along the way. This includes a trip to dealer Strawberry (Alien's Tom Skerritt), a little house party snorting some wash powder as cocaine, and the big hoot of the film, unintentionally steal a van made entirely of hardened weed. Along the way Pedro and Man pick up two women, who convince them that they should enter their band in a Battle of the Bands contest, and the final scene sees them win with a very high audience. Also starring Batman: Mask of the Phantasm's Stacy Keach as Sgt. Stedenko, Strother Martin as Arnold Stoner, Edie Adams as Mrs. Tempest Stoner, Ray Vitte as Bass Player James and Michael Caldwell as Guitar Player Duane. Cheech and Chong with their "man" catchphrase creating smiles and stoned foolishness are a great double act, Keach does make a good deranged cop, and there are some good songs in it. I will say, the film started hilariously, it then loses a tiny bit of steam, then it picks up with the "fiberweed" van, and the last few scenes are quite funny, so overall, it a most watchable cult comedy. Good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    hilarious ! the funniest weed movie i have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yousif el3li
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is the only comedy movie that made me laugh so loud ! i swear i would pay 1 grand only to see Pedro and Anthony again and the way they are acting ! the jokes are so funny man especially when it comes from Anthony i laugh even if he didn't said any funny jokes ! his way in talking is so freaking funny man they just sing well when they get high ! its an incredible movie man i just want to tell you this movie is a life time opportunity Quote from Pedro is so funny when you hear it in the movie : ARE WE SMOKING DOG Sh*t , MAN ? 10\10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Everybody must get stoned"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RainDogJr
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I added to my collection the Double Feature DVD with Up in Smoke and Still Smokin like two months ago but just last night I finally saw the first one so also last night was my very first "encounter" with Cheech and Chong and for sure won't be the last. So here Cheech Marin and Tommy Chong are Pedro and Anthony (his father call him Anthony yet in the credits Tommy Chong is just "man") respectively and basically they will meet just by pure causality. We have the sort of introduction and we see a moment with each one, we see the first funny moment with Pedro pissing and on the other hand we have the classic situation of a guy who at the age of what 30 or something still lives with his parents, certainly the father is just tired of having his lazy son doing about nothing during the entire day. Both Pedro and Anthony are out with cars yet only Pedro will be able to continue driving, to continue looking for a lost babe or maybe babes but he will have only kind of a really big disappointment but after all there he meets who will be his best friend. Certainly these two have a lot in common but mainly two things will keep them together: drugs and rock and roll. Is just amazing and hilarious the first joint they smoke together, Pedro was like "I been smoking since always, I can smoke anything" but the Led Zeppelin is something else, heavy s***, dog s***! And that s*** will give them some troubles and certainly we will laugh and laugh. Up in Smoke is one of those movies that are just so damn enjoyable since the very first second till the very last, essentially Pedro and Anthony are just looking out for some s*** but of course things will happen. The police play here a big role, they will be close to Pedro, Anthony and company and they deliver also a lot of fun. We have the police chief and three of his "sons" (is also a great "show" with this guys, of course the one who will suffer most is the chief, he even loses his dog that was the best cop he ever saw!), they are after those who are transporting a really big quantity of drug from Mexico to the US, they will be after "two hippies with a van". And certainly we know who those hippies are, we know that the van they are driving would be a damn treasure for them but they don't know, actually they don't know a damn thing. Is really funny what Pedro's cousin (not sure is his cousin but sure is a relative) do to get a free ride to Tijuana, very funny and Pedro and Anthony will be in Mexico also and in THE van they will return to the US. At one point we know what will happen with the van if the police finds it, actually is not that different to what will happen with the van if Pedro and Anthony realize about the truth. By this time our dudes have company, finally the company of women and now they have another thing in mind: the battle of the bands at the Roxy. And will be for a moment like a little Monterey or Woodstock, every single soul in the place was connected! Those like me who saw first the great Coen brothers film The Big Lebowski (that is my second favourite Coen bros film) certainly will remember it. Terrific fun with these two DUDES!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The original stoner flick(I think)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gangstahippie
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Throughout film history, there have been plenty of films involving the use or talk of marijuana.Because of marijuana, there have been plenty of hilarious films such as Harold & Kumar showing the misadventures of people who smoke it.I believe that Cheech and Chong's Up In Smoke, was the first film to portray the positive use of marijuana.There have been other movies beforehand such as the 1936 "Reefer Madness".This is the first of a series of films which continued on into the 1980's.Before this film, they were comedians/musicians.Anyway, this movie is about two guys who try to smuggle a van made out of marijuana across the Mexican border while the narc cops led by Sgt Stedeko are hot on their trail.The duo gets into many misadventures during the film, while they must win the battle of the bands contest.Overall this is a great stoner film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic of drug comedies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kurciasbezdalas
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basically all Up in Smoke movies are about watching other people getting high, actually all the drug comedies are about that. It sounds kinda boring, but not when those people are Cheech & Chong. The scene where they were smoking in a car in the beginning is still funny to me, though I watched it many times. This movie is making fun more from the cops and other people who fight drugs, than from the drug addicts who just want to get high. This film shows how ridiculous those fighters against drugs look like, though this is a comedy, in my opinion, there is a lot of truth in this film. Maybe other Up in Smoke movies aren't that good as this one, but as I remember there is always at least few hilarious moments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very amiable comedy classic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Legendary comedy duo Cheech & Chong's first and best cinematic outing is a hoot the entire time, just what this reviewer would recommend for those people who just want to turn off their brain for about an hour and a half and relax. One certainly doesn't have to be a stoner themselves in order to appreciate it. There's not much of a story here, mostly a series of easygoing, sometimes hysterical vignettes as Pedro (Cheech) and Anthony (Chong) go on the hunt for "good grass", although Pedro's main ambition is for his band to achieve some fame and fortune, and, recruiting Anthony as a drummer, he and his bandmates get their chance in a battle of the bands for the movie's finish. Great sight gags abound; the fact that Pedro and Anthony end up driving a van that's actually made out of marijuana is priceless. Hot on their trail is flustered narc Stedenko (Stacy Keach), who's stuck with a bunch of incredibly inept detectives. Cheech & Chong are hilarious as always, and incidentally, one can see how Chong's Anthony would get the nickname that he has, MAN. A spirited supporting cast adds to the fun, although I personally would have liked to have seen at least a little more of Strother Martin as Anthony's fed-up father. But Tom Skerritt is great as Pedro's Nam flashback plagued cousin Strawberry (I'd advise you not to look at his neck), Louisa Moritz is in fine bubbly form as luscious cop Gloria, and Zane Buzby is fun as stoner babe Jade East. The cast features such familiar character players and celebrities as Arthur Roberts, Donald Hotton, Ray Vitte, Gary Mule Deer, Mills Watson, Val Avery, and Rodney Bingenheimer, with lovely ladies Cheryl "Rainbeaux" Smith and Wally Ann Wharton adding to the entertainment value. It's just too funny to see, among other things, a group of nuns get detained by the cops, and the cops getting the munchies as they get stoned. The cool soundtrack (including the classic "Low Rider") and the bright, sunny look of the film are big bonuses, and the laughs keep coming at a consistent pace. "Up in Smoke" is good natured in spirit, and is definitely too hard to resist. Eight out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slam-Bong Comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first Cheech & Chong stoner comedy of errors "Up in Smoke" consists of gags lifted from their comedy albums about marijuana usage tacked onto a rolling paper thin plot about smuggling a fortune in pot into the U.S. by two dopers desperate for some weed to puff. The message is that if our heroes get high enough that all their troubles will disappear in a purple haze of smoke. Freshman director Lou Adler learned on the job with this occasionally funny comedy that never advocates the legalization of pot. You won't find anything remotely subversive and "Up in Smoke" doesn't take any chances. Adler and scenarists Tommy Chong and Cheech Marin may have gotten high when they contrived this harmless nonsense, but they have no lofty aims. They ridicule their own clueless characters as well as a cadre of hopelessly inept but zealous narcotics police officers who pursue them. "Up in Smoke" amounts to a stoned version of the Keystone Kops, except that the cops are narcs. Of course, Pedro De Bacas (Cheech Marin) and Anthony Stoner (Tommy Chong) are a pair of misguided stoners who encounter each other after Anthony's intolerant father Arnold (Strother Martin of "The Wild Bunch") threatens to pack him off to military school if he doesn't get a job. Anthony's Volkswagon Beetle conks out on him on the highway and he winds up spending the night in a ditch before Pedro mistakes him for a woman and tries to pick him up. Several mildly amusing scenes follow without apparent much apparent motivation. Everything centers on the efforts of our duo to find some good marijuana. One of the funniest scenes in the first 30 minutes shows them smoking a hilariously huge joint that consists of Maui-wowie strained from the turds of Anthony's Labrador. According to Anthony, he caught man's best friend chowing down on his stash and then followed him around with a baggie. Smoke pours out of their car as Pedros cruises the freeway. Inevitably, the police pull them over and pack them off to court with Anthony the worst for wear. During their arraignment in court, Anthony partakes of water from the judge's carafe. He spews the contents and announces to everybody that the judge has been drinking vodka. Our heroes are released after this alarming incident. Later, they visit one of their friends, Veteran-veteran Strawberry (Tom Skerritt of "M.A.S.H.") who has a huge discolored birthmark looking scar on his face. Before Strawberry can goad Anthony into confessing that he is staring at his skin problem, Pedro gets him to embark on a search for some reefer. They leave Anthony at Strawberry's house and Anthony monkeys around with some Comet so that it appears to be cocaine. Party girls snort it up and raise hell. Strawberry has a Vietnam flashback and dons his combat gear, while Pedro warns Anthony of an impending bust by Sergeant Stedenko. No sooner do our heroes escape from the cops a second time than they are caught in a raid organized by INS agents and bussed back across the border. The catch is that the rest of the Mexicans deliberately informed on themselves so they could get a free ride to the border prior to a wedding. Pedro and Anthony go to an upholstery shop run by an uncle to acquire the means of getting back across the border. Predictably, they enter the wrong shop and find themselves in a massive pot smuggling enterprise. They are given a van to drive back to L.A., but what our protagonists don't realize is that they are driving a van constructed of fiberweed. Meaning, the dope smugglers have converted the THC resin found in marijuana in a fiberglass-like substance. Just when it looks like our heroes will be busted at the border, Anthony thumps a roach into a station wagon full of Catholic sisters. The authorities allows our heroes to pass through, but they bust the sisters. Once they are back in L.A., Pedro and Anthony decide to compete in a battle of rock bands. They dress themselves in outlandish costumes and manage to sing a ridiculous song that turns the entire audience into a raving room of fans. The general idea here to keep our heroes off balance as they look for pot and Alder and company shun any political positions. No, this is not an imaginative comedy, but it marked not only their debut but the biggest depiction of a counter-culture duo that spawned a number of lesser films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Start To Stoner Comedies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cheech and Chong meet up by chance on the highway somewhere in California. They go in search of some dope and are accidentally deported to Mexico where in their desperation to get home they agree to drive a van back to the States so they can get back in time for a gig they are due to play. Unaware of the properties from which the van is constructed they make their way back having acquired a couple of female hitch-hikers whilst all the time avoiding the cops whom they are not even aware are following them. Tonight I Decided To Give The Mother Of All Stoner Comedies A Go. This Is Not Just The Mother Of Stoner Comedies...Its The Father Of Dumb Comedies. I Loved Every Minute Of It...I Was Adimant Not To Turn The TV Off When Cheech & Chong Smoked Dog Crap That Came From A Dog That Ate Chong's Marjuana...I'm Laughing Now As I Type It Up. I Also Have Some Of Their Recordings Like "Dave", "Up In Smoke"(I Was Familiar With The Movie Before Tonight), I Even Had "Earache My Eye" Which Is My Personal Favourite So I Didn't Mind Hearing It In This Film But I Would've Loved It Even More If After The End Credits The Sketch That Goes With Earache My Eye Would Play. I Also Loved The Fact That They Were So Dumb That They Had No Idea The "Hard Hat" Cops Were After Them. Overall If You Like Stoner Comedies In The Same Vein As The Kevin Smith Comedies Of...Well His Entire Career Than This Movie Is Definitely One To Buy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where it all began...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluethunder35 (bluethunder35@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Richard "Cheech" Marin and Tommy Chong debuted their Mary-Jane fueled humor with Up In Smoke. While Reefer Madness was the first notable film to promote weed, it's this film that set the template for stoner films. Not really much of a plot here: Pedro De Pacas (Marin) meets up with rich-kid Anthony "Man" Stoner (Chong) and find out they both like getting high. Their search for pot takes them all over Los Angeles and Tijuana in a wacky road-trip in a car unknowingly made out of grass. On their trip, they have to deal with Sgt. Sedenko (Stacy Keach), an over-zealous police officer trying to clean L.A. of druggies. The movie is filled with crazy situations: drug-filled parties, performances at a punk rock contest and a trip through a upholstery factory that is just a front for drug trafficking. Crazy people, the kind you would expect in a film like this, are everywhere. Both Marin and Chong are very good in the film but Keach steals the show. He is an absolute hoot in this film and he comes off as the most interesting character in the film. It's still very entertaining to this day as a curiosity piece. Check it out. BTW, one of the ladies Pedro and Man picks up looks remarkably like Sharon Snow of NTV.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The First & Best Cheech and Chong Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TBoldOne
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cheech and Chong were already insanely popular with their comedy record albums and were contracted to make a movie. Hoping to make the "big score" they go to Mexico and end up driving a van built entirely of Weed back across the border. Many reviewers have already commented on the classic "stoner" humor, and I won't add to that. If you get this movie get the DVD with the extended commentary. In it you find that they were on the cutting edge of the Punk Rock revolution. The battle of the bands features some of the earliest LA punk rock bands. My favorite gags. 1) Cheech and Chong get in their car, do a U - Turn, park on the other side of the street and get out. 2) The Van Scene - This literally made the phrase "If this vans rocking, don't come a-knocking" part of our popular culture. Whats so amazing about this scene was that it wasn't even in the original script! The actress, who played Chongs girlfriend was telling the story of a roommate who was a "screamer", while they were on lunch break outside of the battle of the bands show. Cheech and Chong said that sounds funny, lets film it. It just goes to show you that sometimes the best comedy can be the spontaneous type. Finally students of film comedy should rent this movie for an unusual reason. Watching this movie in 2010 is like a going into a time warp. This movie could never be made today, and I'm not referring to the drug humor. The pacing of the gags is so slow compared to today. It's weirdly funny when you watch and notice it like I did. Sadly most comedies today don't give their actors time to develop their gags. If you wan't a harmless (except for the drug humor) movie, buy this movie. It is the best of the Cheech and Chong movies
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheech and Chong's Up in Smoke
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first heard of and saw Cheech and Chong featured in the South Park Episode "Cherokee Hair Tampons", and then I heard about this 1001 Movies You See Before You Die recommended film. Basically slackers and getting nowhere musicians Pedro De Pacas (Richard 'Cheech' Marin) and Anthony 'Man' Stoner (Tommy Chong) happen to meet on a Californian highway, and instantly find a connection with their love of marijuana. They are pulled over by the cops, and end up deported to Mexico, but in court they are let off lightly by the Vodka drinking judge, and they start a road trip to go back home, and try to score some drugs along the way. This includes a trip to dealer Strawberry (Alien's Tom Skerritt), a little house party snorting some wash powder as cocaine, and the big hoot of the film, unintentionally steal a van made entirely of hardened weed. Along the way Pedro and Man pick up two women, who convince them that they should enter their band in a Battle of the Bands contest, and the final scene sees them win with a very high audience. Also starring Batman: Mask of the Phantasm's Stacy Keach as Sgt. Stedenko, Strother Martin as Arnold Stoner, Edie Adams as Mrs. Tempest Stoner, Ray Vitte as Bass Player James and Michael Caldwell as Guitar Player Duane. Cheech and Chong with their "man" catchphrase creating smiles and stoned foolishness are a great double act, Keach does make a good deranged cop, and there are some good songs in it. I will say, the film started hilariously, it then loses a tiny bit of steam, then it picks up with the "fiberweed" van, and the last few scenes are quite funny, so overall, it a most watchable cult comedy. Good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    hilarious ! the funniest weed movie i have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yousif el3li
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is the only comedy movie that made me laugh so loud ! i swear i would pay 1 grand only to see Pedro and Anthony again and the way they are acting ! the jokes are so funny man especially when it comes from Anthony i laugh even if he didn't said any funny jokes ! his way in talking is so freaking funny man they just sing well when they get high ! its an incredible movie man i just want to tell you this movie is a life time opportunity Quote from Pedro is so funny when you hear it in the movie : ARE WE SMOKING DOG Sh*t , MAN ? 10\10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Everybody must get stoned"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RainDogJr
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I added to my collection the Double Feature DVD with Up in Smoke and Still Smokin like two months ago but just last night I finally saw the first one so also last night was my very first "encounter" with Cheech and Chong and for sure won't be the last. So here Cheech Marin and Tommy Chong are Pedro and Anthony (his father call him Anthony yet in the credits Tommy Chong is just "man") respectively and basically they will meet just by pure causality. We have the sort of introduction and we see a moment with each one, we see the first funny moment with Pedro pissing and on the other hand we have the classic situation of a guy who at the age of what 30 or something still lives with his parents, certainly the father is just tired of having his lazy son doing about nothing during the entire day. Both Pedro and Anthony are out with cars yet only Pedro will be able to continue driving, to continue looking for a lost babe or maybe babes but he will have only kind of a really big disappointment but after all there he meets who will be his best friend. Certainly these two have a lot in common but mainly two things will keep them together: drugs and rock and roll. Is just amazing and hilarious the first joint they smoke together, Pedro was like "I been smoking since always, I can smoke anything" but the Led Zeppelin is something else, heavy s***, dog s***! And that s*** will give them some troubles and certainly we will laugh and laugh. Up in Smoke is one of those movies that are just so damn enjoyable since the very first second till the very last, essentially Pedro and Anthony are just looking out for some s*** but of course things will happen. The police play here a big role, they will be close to Pedro, Anthony and company and they deliver also a lot of fun. We have the police chief and three of his "sons" (is also a great "show" with this guys, of course the one who will suffer most is the chief, he even loses his dog that was the best cop he ever saw!), they are after those who are transporting a really big quantity of drug from Mexico to the US, they will be after "two hippies with a van". And certainly we know who those hippies are, we know that the van they are driving would be a damn treasure for them but they don't know, actually they don't know a damn thing. Is really funny what Pedro's cousin (not sure is his cousin but sure is a relative) do to get a free ride to Tijuana, very funny and Pedro and Anthony will be in Mexico also and in THE van they will return to the US. At one point we know what will happen with the van if the police finds it, actually is not that different to what will happen with the van if Pedro and Anthony realize about the truth. By this time our dudes have company, finally the company of women and now they have another thing in mind: the battle of the bands at the Roxy. And will be for a moment like a little Monterey or Woodstock, every single soul in the place was connected! Those like me who saw first the great Coen brothers film The Big Lebowski (that is my second favourite Coen bros film) certainly will remember it. Terrific fun with these two DUDES!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The original stoner flick(I think)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gangstahippie
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Throughout film history, there have been plenty of films involving the use or talk of marijuana.Because of marijuana, there have been plenty of hilarious films such as Harold & Kumar showing the misadventures of people who smoke it.I believe that Cheech and Chong's Up In Smoke, was the first film to portray the positive use of marijuana.There have been other movies beforehand such as the 1936 "Reefer Madness".This is the first of a series of films which continued on into the 1980's.Before this film, they were comedians/musicians.Anyway, this movie is about two guys who try to smuggle a van made out of marijuana across the Mexican border while the narc cops led by Sgt Stedeko are hot on their trail.The duo gets into many misadventures during the film, while they must win the battle of the bands contest.Overall this is a great stoner film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic of drug comedies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kurciasbezdalas
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basically all Up in Smoke movies are about watching other people getting high, actually all the drug comedies are about that. It sounds kinda boring, but not when those people are Cheech & Chong. The scene where they were smoking in a car in the beginning is still funny to me, though I watched it many times. This movie is making fun more from the cops and other people who fight drugs, than from the drug addicts who just want to get high. This film shows how ridiculous those fighters against drugs look like, though this is a comedy, in my opinion, there is a lot of truth in this film. Maybe other Up in Smoke movies aren't that good as this one, but as I remember there is always at least few hilarious moments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very amiable comedy classic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Legendary comedy duo Cheech & Chong's first and best cinematic outing is a hoot the entire time, just what this reviewer would recommend for those people who just want to turn off their brain for about an hour and a half and relax. One certainly doesn't have to be a stoner themselves in order to appreciate it. There's not much of a story here, mostly a series of easygoing, sometimes hysterical vignettes as Pedro (Cheech) and Anthony (Chong) go on the hunt for "good grass", although Pedro's main ambition is for his band to achieve some fame and fortune, and, recruiting Anthony as a drummer, he and his bandmates get their chance in a battle of the bands for the movie's finish. Great sight gags abound; the fact that Pedro and Anthony end up driving a van that's actually made out of marijuana is priceless. Hot on their trail is flustered narc Stedenko (Stacy Keach), who's stuck with a bunch of incredibly inept detectives. Cheech & Chong are hilarious as always, and incidentally, one can see how Chong's Anthony would get the nickname that he has, MAN. A spirited supporting cast adds to the fun, although I personally would have liked to have seen at least a little more of Strother Martin as Anthony's fed-up father. But Tom Skerritt is great as Pedro's Nam flashback plagued cousin Strawberry (I'd advise you not to look at his neck), Louisa Moritz is in fine bubbly form as luscious cop Gloria, and Zane Buzby is fun as stoner babe Jade East. The cast features such familiar character players and celebrities as Arthur Roberts, Donald Hotton, Ray Vitte, Gary Mule Deer, Mills Watson, Val Avery, and Rodney Bingenheimer, with lovely ladies Cheryl "Rainbeaux" Smith and Wally Ann Wharton adding to the entertainment value. It's just too funny to see, among other things, a group of nuns get detained by the cops, and the cops getting the munchies as they get stoned. The cool soundtrack (including the classic "Low Rider") and the bright, sunny look of the film are big bonuses, and the laughs keep coming at a consistent pace. "Up in Smoke" is good natured in spirit, and is definitely too hard to resist. Eight out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slam-Bong Comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first Cheech & Chong stoner comedy of errors "Up in Smoke" consists of gags lifted from their comedy albums about marijuana usage tacked onto a rolling paper thin plot about smuggling a fortune in pot into the U.S. by two dopers desperate for some weed to puff. The message is that if our heroes get high enough that all their troubles will disappear in a purple haze of smoke. Freshman director Lou Adler learned on the job with this occasionally funny comedy that never advocates the legalization of pot. You won't find anything remotely subversive and "Up in Smoke" doesn't take any chances. Adler and scenarists Tommy Chong and Cheech Marin may have gotten high when they contrived this harmless nonsense, but they have no lofty aims. They ridicule their own clueless characters as well as a cadre of hopelessly inept but zealous narcotics police officers who pursue them. "Up in Smoke" amounts to a stoned version of the Keystone Kops, except that the cops are narcs. Of course, Pedro De Bacas (Cheech Marin) and Anthony Stoner (Tommy Chong) are a pair of misguided stoners who encounter each other after Anthony's intolerant father Arnold (Strother Martin of "The Wild Bunch") threatens to pack him off to military school if he doesn't get a job. Anthony's Volkswagon Beetle conks out on him on the highway and he winds up spending the night in a ditch before Pedro mistakes him for a woman and tries to pick him up. Several mildly amusing scenes follow without apparent much apparent motivation. Everything centers on the efforts of our duo to find some good marijuana. One of the funniest scenes in the first 30 minutes shows them smoking a hilariously huge joint that consists of Maui-wowie strained from the turds of Anthony's Labrador. According to Anthony, he caught man's best friend chowing down on his stash and then followed him around with a baggie. Smoke pours out of their car as Pedros cruises the freeway. Inevitably, the police pull them over and pack them off to court with Anthony the worst for wear. During their arraignment in court, Anthony partakes of water from the judge's carafe. He spews the contents and announces to everybody that the judge has been drinking vodka. Our heroes are released after this alarming incident. Later, they visit one of their friends, Veteran-veteran Strawberry (Tom Skerritt of "M.A.S.H.") who has a huge discolored birthmark looking scar on his face. Before Strawberry can goad Anthony into confessing that he is staring at his skin problem, Pedro gets him to embark on a search for some reefer. They leave Anthony at Strawberry's house and Anthony monkeys around with some Comet so that it appears to be cocaine. Party girls snort it up and raise hell. Strawberry has a Vietnam flashback and dons his combat gear, while Pedro warns Anthony of an impending bust by Sergeant Stedenko. No sooner do our heroes escape from the cops a second time than they are caught in a raid organized by INS agents and bussed back across the border. The catch is that the rest of the Mexicans deliberately informed on themselves so they could get a free ride to the border prior to a wedding. Pedro and Anthony go to an upholstery shop run by an uncle to acquire the means of getting back across the border. Predictably, they enter the wrong shop and find themselves in a massive pot smuggling enterprise. They are given a van to drive back to L.A., but what our protagonists don't realize is that they are driving a van constructed of fiberweed. Meaning, the dope smugglers have converted the THC resin found in marijuana in a fiberglass-like substance. Just when it looks like our heroes will be busted at the border, Anthony thumps a roach into a station wagon full of Catholic sisters. The authorities allows our heroes to pass through, but they bust the sisters. Once they are back in L.A., Pedro and Anthony decide to compete in a battle of rock bands. They dress themselves in outlandish costumes and manage to sing a ridiculous song that turns the entire audience into a raving room of fans. The general idea here to keep our heroes off balance as they look for pot and Alder and company shun any political positions. No, this is not an imaginative comedy, but it marked not only their debut but the biggest depiction of a counter-culture duo that spawned a number of lesser films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Start To Stoner Comedies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cheech and Chong meet up by chance on the highway somewhere in California. They go in search of some dope and are accidentally deported to Mexico where in their desperation to get home they agree to drive a van back to the States so they can get back in time for a gig they are due to play. Unaware of the properties from which the van is constructed they make their way back having acquired a couple of female hitch-hikers whilst all the time avoiding the cops whom they are not even aware are following them. Tonight I Decided To Give The Mother Of All Stoner Comedies A Go. This Is Not Just The Mother Of Stoner Comedies...Its The Father Of Dumb Comedies. I Loved Every Minute Of It...I Was Adimant Not To Turn The TV Off When Cheech & Chong Smoked Dog Crap That Came From A Dog That Ate Chong's Marjuana...I'm Laughing Now As I Type It Up. I Also Have Some Of Their Recordings Like "Dave", "Up In Smoke"(I Was Familiar With The Movie Before Tonight), I Even Had "Earache My Eye" Which Is My Personal Favourite So I Didn't Mind Hearing It In This Film But I Would've Loved It Even More If After The End Credits The Sketch That Goes With Earache My Eye Would Play. I Also Loved The Fact That They Were So Dumb That They Had No Idea The "Hard Hat" Cops Were After Them. Overall If You Like Stoner Comedies In The Same Vein As The Kevin Smith Comedies Of...Well His Entire Career Than This Movie Is Definitely One To Buy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where it all began...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluethunder35 (bluethunder35@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Richard "Cheech" Marin and Tommy Chong debuted their Mary-Jane fueled humor with Up In Smoke. While Reefer Madness was the first notable film to promote weed, it's this film that set the template for stoner films. Not really much of a plot here: Pedro De Pacas (Marin) meets up with rich-kid Anthony "Man" Stoner (Chong) and find out they both like getting high. Their search for pot takes them all over Los Angeles and Tijuana in a wacky road-trip in a car unknowingly made out of grass. On their trip, they have to deal with Sgt. Sedenko (Stacy Keach), an over-zealous police officer trying to clean L.A. of druggies. The movie is filled with crazy situations: drug-filled parties, performances at a punk rock contest and a trip through a upholstery factory that is just a front for drug trafficking. Crazy people, the kind you would expect in a film like this, are everywhere. Both Marin and Chong are very good in the film but Keach steals the show. He is an absolute hoot in this film and he comes off as the most interesting character in the film. It's still very entertaining to this day as a curiosity piece. Check it out. BTW, one of the ladies Pedro and Man picks up looks remarkably like Sharon Snow of NTV.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The First & Best Cheech and Chong Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TBoldOne
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cheech and Chong were already insanely popular with their comedy record albums and were contracted to make a movie. Hoping to make the "big score" they go to Mexico and end up driving a van built entirely of Weed back across the border. Many reviewers have already commented on the classic "stoner" humor, and I won't add to that. If you get this movie get the DVD with the extended commentary. In it you find that they were on the cutting edge of the Punk Rock revolution. The battle of the bands features some of the earliest LA punk rock bands. My favorite gags. 1) Cheech and Chong get in their car, do a U - Turn, park on the other side of the street and get out. 2) The Van Scene - This literally made the phrase "If this vans rocking, don't come a-knocking" part of our popular culture. Whats so amazing about this scene was that it wasn't even in the original script! The actress, who played Chongs girlfriend was telling the story of a roommate who was a "screamer", while they were on lunch break outside of the battle of the bands show. Cheech and Chong said that sounds funny, lets film it. It just goes to show you that sometimes the best comedy can be the spontaneous type. Finally students of film comedy should rent this movie for an unusual reason. Watching this movie in 2010 is like a going into a time warp. This movie could never be made today, and I'm not referring to the drug humor. The pacing of the gags is so slow compared to today. It's weirdly funny when you watch and notice it like I did. Sadly most comedies today don't give their actors time to develop their gags. If you wan't a harmless (except for the drug humor) movie, buy this movie. It is the best of the Cheech and Chong movies
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheech and Chong's Up in Smoke
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first heard of and saw Cheech and Chong featured in the South Park Episode "Cherokee Hair Tampons", and then I heard about this 1001 Movies You See Before You Die recommended film. Basically slackers and getting nowhere musicians Pedro De Pacas (Richard 'Cheech' Marin) and Anthony 'Man' Stoner (Tommy Chong) happen to meet on a Californian highway, and instantly find a connection with their love of marijuana. They are pulled over by the cops, and end up deported to Mexico, but in court they are let off lightly by the Vodka drinking judge, and they start a road trip to go back home, and try to score some drugs along the way. This includes a trip to dealer Strawberry (Alien's Tom Skerritt), a little house party snorting some wash powder as cocaine, and the big hoot of the film, unintentionally steal a van made entirely of hardened weed. Along the way Pedro and Man pick up two women, who convince them that they should enter their band in a Battle of the Bands contest, and the final scene sees them win with a very high audience. Also starring Batman: Mask of the Phantasm's Stacy Keach as Sgt. Stedenko, Strother Martin as Arnold Stoner, Edie Adams as Mrs. Tempest Stoner, Ray Vitte as Bass Player James and Michael Caldwell as Guitar Player Duane. Cheech and Chong with their "man" catchphrase creating smiles and stoned foolishness are a great double act, Keach does make a good deranged cop, and there are some good songs in it. I will say, the film started hilariously, it then loses a tiny bit of steam, then it picks up with the "fiberweed" van, and the last few scenes are quite funny, so overall, it a most watchable cult comedy. Good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    hilarious ! the funniest weed movie i have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yousif el3li
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is the only comedy movie that made me laugh so loud ! i swear i would pay 1 grand only to see Pedro and Anthony again and the way they are acting ! the jokes are so funny man especially when it comes from Anthony i laugh even if he didn't said any funny jokes ! his way in talking is so freaking funny man they just sing well when they get high ! its an incredible movie man i just want to tell you this movie is a life time opportunity Quote from Pedro is so funny when you hear it in the movie : ARE WE SMOKING DOG Sh*t , MAN ? 10\10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Everybody must get stoned"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RainDogJr
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I added to my collection the Double Feature DVD with Up in Smoke and Still Smokin like two months ago but just last night I finally saw the first one so also last night was my very first "encounter" with Cheech and Chong and for sure won't be the last. So here Cheech Marin and Tommy Chong are Pedro and Anthony (his father call him Anthony yet in the credits Tommy Chong is just "man") respectively and basically they will meet just by pure causality. We have the sort of introduction and we see a moment with each one, we see the first funny moment with Pedro pissing and on the other hand we have the classic situation of a guy who at the age of what 30 or something still lives with his parents, certainly the father is just tired of having his lazy son doing about nothing during the entire day. Both Pedro and Anthony are out with cars yet only Pedro will be able to continue driving, to continue looking for a lost babe or maybe babes but he will have only kind of a really big disappointment but after all there he meets who will be his best friend. Certainly these two have a lot in common but mainly two things will keep them together: drugs and rock and roll. Is just amazing and hilarious the first joint they smoke together, Pedro was like "I been smoking since always, I can smoke anything" but the Led Zeppelin is something else, heavy s***, dog s***! And that s*** will give them some troubles and certainly we will laugh and laugh. Up in Smoke is one of those movies that are just so damn enjoyable since the very first second till the very last, essentially Pedro and Anthony are just looking out for some s*** but of course things will happen. The police play here a big role, they will be close to Pedro, Anthony and company and they deliver also a lot of fun. We have the police chief and three of his "sons" (is also a great "show" with this guys, of course the one who will suffer most is the chief, he even loses his dog that was the best cop he ever saw!), they are after those who are transporting a really big quantity of drug from Mexico to the US, they will be after "two hippies with a van". And certainly we know who those hippies are, we know that the van they are driving would be a damn treasure for them but they don't know, actually they don't know a damn thing. Is really funny what Pedro's cousin (not sure is his cousin but sure is a relative) do to get a free ride to Tijuana, very funny and Pedro and Anthony will be in Mexico also and in THE van they will return to the US. At one point we know what will happen with the van if the police finds it, actually is not that different to what will happen with the van if Pedro and Anthony realize about the truth. By this time our dudes have company, finally the company of women and now they have another thing in mind: the battle of the bands at the Roxy. And will be for a moment like a little Monterey or Woodstock, every single soul in the place was connected! Those like me who saw first the great Coen brothers film The Big Lebowski (that is my second favourite Coen bros film) certainly will remember it. Terrific fun with these two DUDES!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The original stoner flick(I think)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gangstahippie
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Throughout film history, there have been plenty of films involving the use or talk of marijuana.Because of marijuana, there have been plenty of hilarious films such as Harold & Kumar showing the misadventures of people who smoke it.I believe that Cheech and Chong's Up In Smoke, was the first film to portray the positive use of marijuana.There have been other movies beforehand such as the 1936 "Reefer Madness".This is the first of a series of films which continued on into the 1980's.Before this film, they were comedians/musicians.Anyway, this movie is about two guys who try to smuggle a van made out of marijuana across the Mexican border while the narc cops led by Sgt Stedeko are hot on their trail.The duo gets into many misadventures during the film, while they must win the battle of the bands contest.Overall this is a great stoner film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic of drug comedies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kurciasbezdalas
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basically all Up in Smoke movies are about watching other people getting high, actually all the drug comedies are about that. It sounds kinda boring, but not when those people are Cheech & Chong. The scene where they were smoking in a car in the beginning is still funny to me, though I watched it many times. This movie is making fun more from the cops and other people who fight drugs, than from the drug addicts who just want to get high. This film shows how ridiculous those fighters against drugs look like, though this is a comedy, in my opinion, there is a lot of truth in this film. Maybe other Up in Smoke movies aren't that good as this one, but as I remember there is always at least few hilarious moments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very amiable comedy classic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Legendary comedy duo Cheech & Chong's first and best cinematic outing is a hoot the entire time, just what this reviewer would recommend for those people who just want to turn off their brain for about an hour and a half and relax. One certainly doesn't have to be a stoner themselves in order to appreciate it. There's not much of a story here, mostly a series of easygoing, sometimes hysterical vignettes as Pedro (Cheech) and Anthony (Chong) go on the hunt for "good grass", although Pedro's main ambition is for his band to achieve some fame and fortune, and, recruiting Anthony as a drummer, he and his bandmates get their chance in a battle of the bands for the movie's finish. Great sight gags abound; the fact that Pedro and Anthony end up driving a van that's actually made out of marijuana is priceless. Hot on their trail is flustered narc Stedenko (Stacy Keach), who's stuck with a bunch of incredibly inept detectives. Cheech & Chong are hilarious as always, and incidentally, one can see how Chong's Anthony would get the nickname that he has, MAN. A spirited supporting cast adds to the fun, although I personally would have liked to have seen at least a little more of Strother Martin as Anthony's fed-up father. But Tom Skerritt is great as Pedro's Nam flashback plagued cousin Strawberry (I'd advise you not to look at his neck), Louisa Moritz is in fine bubbly form as luscious cop Gloria, and Zane Buzby is fun as stoner babe Jade East. The cast features such familiar character players and celebrities as Arthur Roberts, Donald Hotton, Ray Vitte, Gary Mule Deer, Mills Watson, Val Avery, and Rodney Bingenheimer, with lovely ladies Cheryl "Rainbeaux" Smith and Wally Ann Wharton adding to the entertainment value. It's just too funny to see, among other things, a group of nuns get detained by the cops, and the cops getting the munchies as they get stoned. The cool soundtrack (including the classic "Low Rider") and the bright, sunny look of the film are big bonuses, and the laughs keep coming at a consistent pace. "Up in Smoke" is good natured in spirit, and is definitely too hard to resist. Eight out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slam-Bong Comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first Cheech & Chong stoner comedy of errors "Up in Smoke" consists of gags lifted from their comedy albums about marijuana usage tacked onto a rolling paper thin plot about smuggling a fortune in pot into the U.S. by two dopers desperate for some weed to puff. The message is that if our heroes get high enough that all their troubles will disappear in a purple haze of smoke. Freshman director Lou Adler learned on the job with this occasionally funny comedy that never advocates the legalization of pot. You won't find anything remotely subversive and "Up in Smoke" doesn't take any chances. Adler and scenarists Tommy Chong and Cheech Marin may have gotten high when they contrived this harmless nonsense, but they have no lofty aims. They ridicule their own clueless characters as well as a cadre of hopelessly inept but zealous narcotics police officers who pursue them. "Up in Smoke" amounts to a stoned version of the Keystone Kops, except that the cops are narcs. Of course, Pedro De Bacas (Cheech Marin) and Anthony Stoner (Tommy Chong) are a pair of misguided stoners who encounter each other after Anthony's intolerant father Arnold (Strother Martin of "The Wild Bunch") threatens to pack him off to military school if he doesn't get a job. Anthony's Volkswagon Beetle conks out on him on the highway and he winds up spending the night in a ditch before Pedro mistakes him for a woman and tries to pick him up. Several mildly amusing scenes follow without apparent much apparent motivation. Everything centers on the efforts of our duo to find some good marijuana. One of the funniest scenes in the first 30 minutes shows them smoking a hilariously huge joint that consists of Maui-wowie strained from the turds of Anthony's Labrador. According to Anthony, he caught man's best friend chowing down on his stash and then followed him around with a baggie. Smoke pours out of their car as Pedros cruises the freeway. Inevitably, the police pull them over and pack them off to court with Anthony the worst for wear. During their arraignment in court, Anthony partakes of water from the judge's carafe. He spews the contents and announces to everybody that the judge has been drinking vodka. Our heroes are released after this alarming incident. Later, they visit one of their friends, Veteran-veteran Strawberry (Tom Skerritt of "M.A.S.H.") who has a huge discolored birthmark looking scar on his face. Before Strawberry can goad Anthony into confessing that he is staring at his skin problem, Pedro gets him to embark on a search for some reefer. They leave Anthony at Strawberry's house and Anthony monkeys around with some Comet so that it appears to be cocaine. Party girls snort it up and raise hell. Strawberry has a Vietnam flashback and dons his combat gear, while Pedro warns Anthony of an impending bust by Sergeant Stedenko. No sooner do our heroes escape from the cops a second time than they are caught in a raid organized by INS agents and bussed back across the border. The catch is that the rest of the Mexicans deliberately informed on themselves so they could get a free ride to the border prior to a wedding. Pedro and Anthony go to an upholstery shop run by an uncle to acquire the means of getting back across the border. Predictably, they enter the wrong shop and find themselves in a massive pot smuggling enterprise. They are given a van to drive back to L.A., but what our protagonists don't realize is that they are driving a van constructed of fiberweed. Meaning, the dope smugglers have converted the THC resin found in marijuana in a fiberglass-like substance. Just when it looks like our heroes will be busted at the border, Anthony thumps a roach into a station wagon full of Catholic sisters. The authorities allows our heroes to pass through, but they bust the sisters. Once they are back in L.A., Pedro and Anthony decide to compete in a battle of rock bands. They dress themselves in outlandish costumes and manage to sing a ridiculous song that turns the entire audience into a raving room of fans. The general idea here to keep our heroes off balance as they look for pot and Alder and company shun any political positions. No, this is not an imaginative comedy, but it marked not only their debut but the biggest depiction of a counter-culture duo that spawned a number of lesser films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Start To Stoner Comedies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cheech and Chong meet up by chance on the highway somewhere in California. They go in search of some dope and are accidentally deported to Mexico where in their desperation to get home they agree to drive a van back to the States so they can get back in time for a gig they are due to play. Unaware of the properties from which the van is constructed they make their way back having acquired a couple of female hitch-hikers whilst all the time avoiding the cops whom they are not even aware are following them. Tonight I Decided To Give The Mother Of All Stoner Comedies A Go. This Is Not Just The Mother Of Stoner Comedies...Its The Father Of Dumb Comedies. I Loved Every Minute Of It...I Was Adimant Not To Turn The TV Off When Cheech & Chong Smoked Dog Crap That Came From A Dog That Ate Chong's Marjuana...I'm Laughing Now As I Type It Up. I Also Have Some Of Their Recordings Like "Dave", "Up In Smoke"(I Was Familiar With The Movie Before Tonight), I Even Had "Earache My Eye" Which Is My Personal Favourite So I Didn't Mind Hearing It In This Film But I Would've Loved It Even More If After The End Credits The Sketch That Goes With Earache My Eye Would Play. I Also Loved The Fact That They Were So Dumb That They Had No Idea The "Hard Hat" Cops Were After Them. Overall If You Like Stoner Comedies In The Same Vein As The Kevin Smith Comedies Of...Well His Entire Career Than This Movie Is Definitely One To Buy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where it all began...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluethunder35 (bluethunder35@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Richard "Cheech" Marin and Tommy Chong debuted their Mary-Jane fueled humor with Up In Smoke. While Reefer Madness was the first notable film to promote weed, it's this film that set the template for stoner films. Not really much of a plot here: Pedro De Pacas (Marin) meets up with rich-kid Anthony "Man" Stoner (Chong) and find out they both like getting high. Their search for pot takes them all over Los Angeles and Tijuana in a wacky road-trip in a car unknowingly made out of grass. On their trip, they have to deal with Sgt. Sedenko (Stacy Keach), an over-zealous police officer trying to clean L.A. of druggies. The movie is filled with crazy situations: drug-filled parties, performances at a punk rock contest and a trip through a upholstery factory that is just a front for drug trafficking. Crazy people, the kind you would expect in a film like this, are everywhere. Both Marin and Chong are very good in the film but Keach steals the show. He is an absolute hoot in this film and he comes off as the most interesting character in the film. It's still very entertaining to this day as a curiosity piece. Check it out. BTW, one of the ladies Pedro and Man picks up looks remarkably like Sharon Snow of NTV.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The First & Best Cheech and Chong Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TBoldOne
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cheech and Chong were already insanely popular with their comedy record albums and were contracted to make a movie. Hoping to make the "big score" they go to Mexico and end up driving a van built entirely of Weed back across the border. Many reviewers have already commented on the classic "stoner" humor, and I won't add to that. If you get this movie get the DVD with the extended commentary. In it you find that they were on the cutting edge of the Punk Rock revolution. The battle of the bands features some of the earliest LA punk rock bands. My favorite gags. 1) Cheech and Chong get in their car, do a U - Turn, park on the other side of the street and get out. 2) The Van Scene - This literally made the phrase "If this vans rocking, don't come a-knocking" part of our popular culture. Whats so amazing about this scene was that it wasn't even in the original script! The actress, who played Chongs girlfriend was telling the story of a roommate who was a "screamer", while they were on lunch break outside of the battle of the bands show. Cheech and Chong said that sounds funny, lets film it. It just goes to show you that sometimes the best comedy can be the spontaneous type. Finally students of film comedy should rent this movie for an unusual reason. Watching this movie in 2010 is like a going into a time warp. This movie could never be made today, and I'm not referring to the drug humor. The pacing of the gags is so slow compared to today. It's weirdly funny when you watch and notice it like I did. Sadly most comedies today don't give their actors time to develop their gags. If you wan't a harmless (except for the drug humor) movie, buy this movie. It is the best of the Cheech and Chong movies
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheech and Chong's Up in Smoke
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first heard of and saw Cheech and Chong featured in the South Park Episode "Cherokee Hair Tampons", and then I heard about this 1001 Movies You See Before You Die recommended film. Basically slackers and getting nowhere musicians Pedro De Pacas (Richard 'Cheech' Marin) and Anthony 'Man' Stoner (Tommy Chong) happen to meet on a Californian highway, and instantly find a connection with their love of marijuana. They are pulled over by the cops, and end up deported to Mexico, but in court they are let off lightly by the Vodka drinking judge, and they start a road trip to go back home, and try to score some drugs along the way. This includes a trip to dealer Strawberry (Alien's Tom Skerritt), a little house party snorting some wash powder as cocaine, and the big hoot of the film, unintentionally steal a van made entirely of hardened weed. Along the way Pedro and Man pick up two women, who convince them that they should enter their band in a Battle of the Bands contest, and the final scene sees them win with a very high audience. Also starring Batman: Mask of the Phantasm's Stacy Keach as Sgt. Stedenko, Strother Martin as Arnold Stoner, Edie Adams as Mrs. Tempest Stoner, Ray Vitte as Bass Player James and Michael Caldwell as Guitar Player Duane. Cheech and Chong with their "man" catchphrase creating smiles and stoned foolishness are a great double act, Keach does make a good deranged cop, and there are some good songs in it. I will say, the film started hilariously, it then loses a tiny bit of steam, then it picks up with the "fiberweed" van, and the last few scenes are quite funny, so overall, it a most watchable cult comedy. Good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    hilarious ! the funniest weed movie i have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yousif el3li
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is the only comedy movie that made me laugh so loud ! i swear i would pay 1 grand only to see Pedro and Anthony again and the way they are acting ! the jokes are so funny man especially when it comes from Anthony i laugh even if he didn't said any funny jokes ! his way in talking is so freaking funny man they just sing well when they get high ! its an incredible movie man i just want to tell you this movie is a life time opportunity Quote from Pedro is so funny when you hear it in the movie : ARE WE SMOKING DOG Sh*t , MAN ? 10\10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Everybody must get stoned"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RainDogJr
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I added to my collection the Double Feature DVD with Up in Smoke and Still Smokin like two months ago but just last night I finally saw the first one so also last night was my very first "encounter" with Cheech and Chong and for sure won't be the last. So here Cheech Marin and Tommy Chong are Pedro and Anthony (his father call him Anthony yet in the credits Tommy Chong is just "man") respectively and basically they will meet just by pure causality. We have the sort of introduction and we see a moment with each one, we see the first funny moment with Pedro pissing and on the other hand we have the classic situation of a guy who at the age of what 30 or something still lives with his parents, certainly the father is just tired of having his lazy son doing about nothing during the entire day. Both Pedro and Anthony are out with cars yet only Pedro will be able to continue driving, to continue looking for a lost babe or maybe babes but he will have only kind of a really big disappointment but after all there he meets who will be his best friend. Certainly these two have a lot in common but mainly two things will keep them together: drugs and rock and roll. Is just amazing and hilarious the first joint they smoke together, Pedro was like "I been smoking since always, I can smoke anything" but the Led Zeppelin is something else, heavy s***, dog s***! And that s*** will give them some troubles and certainly we will laugh and laugh. Up in Smoke is one of those movies that are just so damn enjoyable since the very first second till the very last, essentially Pedro and Anthony are just looking out for some s*** but of course things will happen. The police play here a big role, they will be close to Pedro, Anthony and company and they deliver also a lot of fun. We have the police chief and three of his "sons" (is also a great "show" with this guys, of course the one who will suffer most is the chief, he even loses his dog that was the best cop he ever saw!), they are after those who are transporting a really big quantity of drug from Mexico to the US, they will be after "two hippies with a van". And certainly we know who those hippies are, we know that the van they are driving would be a damn treasure for them but they don't know, actually they don't know a damn thing. Is really funny what Pedro's cousin (not sure is his cousin but sure is a relative) do to get a free ride to Tijuana, very funny and Pedro and Anthony will be in Mexico also and in THE van they will return to the US. At one point we know what will happen with the van if the police finds it, actually is not that different to what will happen with the van if Pedro and Anthony realize about the truth. By this time our dudes have company, finally the company of women and now they have another thing in mind: the battle of the bands at the Roxy. And will be for a moment like a little Monterey or Woodstock, every single soul in the place was connected! Those like me who saw first the great Coen brothers film The Big Lebowski (that is my second favourite Coen bros film) certainly will remember it. Terrific fun with these two DUDES!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The original stoner flick(I think)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gangstahippie
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Throughout film history, there have been plenty of films involving the use or talk of marijuana.Because of marijuana, there have been plenty of hilarious films such as Harold & Kumar showing the misadventures of people who smoke it.I believe that Cheech and Chong's Up In Smoke, was the first film to portray the positive use of marijuana.There have been other movies beforehand such as the 1936 "Reefer Madness".This is the first of a series of films which continued on into the 1980's.Before this film, they were comedians/musicians.Anyway, this movie is about two guys who try to smuggle a van made out of marijuana across the Mexican border while the narc cops led by Sgt Stedeko are hot on their trail.The duo gets into many misadventures during the film, while they must win the battle of the bands contest.Overall this is a great stoner film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic of drug comedies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kurciasbezdalas
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basically all Up in Smoke movies are about watching other people getting high, actually all the drug comedies are about that. It sounds kinda boring, but not when those people are Cheech & Chong. The scene where they were smoking in a car in the beginning is still funny to me, though I watched it many times. This movie is making fun more from the cops and other people who fight drugs, than from the drug addicts who just want to get high. This film shows how ridiculous those fighters against drugs look like, though this is a comedy, in my opinion, there is a lot of truth in this film. Maybe other Up in Smoke movies aren't that good as this one, but as I remember there is always at least few hilarious moments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very amiable comedy classic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Legendary comedy duo Cheech & Chong's first and best cinematic outing is a hoot the entire time, just what this reviewer would recommend for those people who just want to turn off their brain for about an hour and a half and relax. One certainly doesn't have to be a stoner themselves in order to appreciate it. There's not much of a story here, mostly a series of easygoing, sometimes hysterical vignettes as Pedro (Cheech) and Anthony (Chong) go on the hunt for "good grass", although Pedro's main ambition is for his band to achieve some fame and fortune, and, recruiting Anthony as a drummer, he and his bandmates get their chance in a battle of the bands for the movie's finish. Great sight gags abound; the fact that Pedro and Anthony end up driving a van that's actually made out of marijuana is priceless. Hot on their trail is flustered narc Stedenko (Stacy Keach), who's stuck with a bunch of incredibly inept detectives. Cheech & Chong are hilarious as always, and incidentally, one can see how Chong's Anthony would get the nickname that he has, MAN. A spirited supporting cast adds to the fun, although I personally would have liked to have seen at least a little more of Strother Martin as Anthony's fed-up father. But Tom Skerritt is great as Pedro's Nam flashback plagued cousin Strawberry (I'd advise you not to look at his neck), Louisa Moritz is in fine bubbly form as luscious cop Gloria, and Zane Buzby is fun as stoner babe Jade East. The cast features such familiar character players and celebrities as Arthur Roberts, Donald Hotton, Ray Vitte, Gary Mule Deer, Mills Watson, Val Avery, and Rodney Bingenheimer, with lovely ladies Cheryl "Rainbeaux" Smith and Wally Ann Wharton adding to the entertainment value. It's just too funny to see, among other things, a group of nuns get detained by the cops, and the cops getting the munchies as they get stoned. The cool soundtrack (including the classic "Low Rider") and the bright, sunny look of the film are big bonuses, and the laughs keep coming at a consistent pace. "Up in Smoke" is good natured in spirit, and is definitely too hard to resist. Eight out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slam-Bong Comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first Cheech & Chong stoner comedy of errors "Up in Smoke" consists of gags lifted from their comedy albums about marijuana usage tacked onto a rolling paper thin plot about smuggling a fortune in pot into the U.S. by two dopers desperate for some weed to puff. The message is that if our heroes get high enough that all their troubles will disappear in a purple haze of smoke. Freshman director Lou Adler learned on the job with this occasionally funny comedy that never advocates the legalization of pot. You won't find anything remotely subversive and "Up in Smoke" doesn't take any chances. Adler and scenarists Tommy Chong and Cheech Marin may have gotten high when they contrived this harmless nonsense, but they have no lofty aims. They ridicule their own clueless characters as well as a cadre of hopelessly inept but zealous narcotics police officers who pursue them. "Up in Smoke" amounts to a stoned version of the Keystone Kops, except that the cops are narcs. Of course, Pedro De Bacas (Cheech Marin) and Anthony Stoner (Tommy Chong) are a pair of misguided stoners who encounter each other after Anthony's intolerant father Arnold (Strother Martin of "The Wild Bunch") threatens to pack him off to military school if he doesn't get a job. Anthony's Volkswagon Beetle conks out on him on the highway and he winds up spending the night in a ditch before Pedro mistakes him for a woman and tries to pick him up. Several mildly amusing scenes follow without apparent much apparent motivation. Everything centers on the efforts of our duo to find some good marijuana. One of the funniest scenes in the first 30 minutes shows them smoking a hilariously huge joint that consists of Maui-wowie strained from the turds of Anthony's Labrador. According to Anthony, he caught man's best friend chowing down on his stash and then followed him around with a baggie. Smoke pours out of their car as Pedros cruises the freeway. Inevitably, the police pull them over and pack them off to court with Anthony the worst for wear. During their arraignment in court, Anthony partakes of water from the judge's carafe. He spews the contents and announces to everybody that the judge has been drinking vodka. Our heroes are released after this alarming incident. Later, they visit one of their friends, Veteran-veteran Strawberry (Tom Skerritt of "M.A.S.H.") who has a huge discolored birthmark looking scar on his face. Before Strawberry can goad Anthony into confessing that he is staring at his skin problem, Pedro gets him to embark on a search for some reefer. They leave Anthony at Strawberry's house and Anthony monkeys around with some Comet so that it appears to be cocaine. Party girls snort it up and raise hell. Strawberry has a Vietnam flashback and dons his combat gear, while Pedro warns Anthony of an impending bust by Sergeant Stedenko. No sooner do our heroes escape from the cops a second time than they are caught in a raid organized by INS agents and bussed back across the border. The catch is that the rest of the Mexicans deliberately informed on themselves so they could get a free ride to the border prior to a wedding. Pedro and Anthony go to an upholstery shop run by an uncle to acquire the means of getting back across the border. Predictably, they enter the wrong shop and find themselves in a massive pot smuggling enterprise. They are given a van to drive back to L.A., but what our protagonists don't realize is that they are driving a van constructed of fiberweed. Meaning, the dope smugglers have converted the THC resin found in marijuana in a fiberglass-like substance. Just when it looks like our heroes will be busted at the border, Anthony thumps a roach into a station wagon full of Catholic sisters. The authorities allows our heroes to pass through, but they bust the sisters. Once they are back in L.A., Pedro and Anthony decide to compete in a battle of rock bands. They dress themselves in outlandish costumes and manage to sing a ridiculous song that turns the entire audience into a raving room of fans. The general idea here to keep our heroes off balance as they look for pot and Alder and company shun any political positions. No, this is not an imaginative comedy, but it marked not only their debut but the biggest depiction of a counter-culture duo that spawned a number of lesser films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Start To Stoner Comedies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cheech and Chong meet up by chance on the highway somewhere in California. They go in search of some dope and are accidentally deported to Mexico where in their desperation to get home they agree to drive a van back to the States so they can get back in time for a gig they are due to play. Unaware of the properties from which the van is constructed they make their way back having acquired a couple of female hitch-hikers whilst all the time avoiding the cops whom they are not even aware are following them. Tonight I Decided To Give The Mother Of All Stoner Comedies A Go. This Is Not Just The Mother Of Stoner Comedies...Its The Father Of Dumb Comedies. I Loved Every Minute Of It...I Was Adimant Not To Turn The TV Off When Cheech & Chong Smoked Dog Crap That Came From A Dog That Ate Chong's Marjuana...I'm Laughing Now As I Type It Up. I Also Have Some Of Their Recordings Like "Dave", "Up In Smoke"(I Was Familiar With The Movie Before Tonight), I Even Had "Earache My Eye" Which Is My Personal Favourite So I Didn't Mind Hearing It In This Film But I Would've Loved It Even More If After The End Credits The Sketch That Goes With Earache My Eye Would Play. I Also Loved The Fact That They Were So Dumb That They Had No Idea The "Hard Hat" Cops Were After Them. Overall If You Like Stoner Comedies In The Same Vein As The Kevin Smith Comedies Of...Well His Entire Career Than This Movie Is Definitely One To Buy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where it all began...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluethunder35 (bluethunder35@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Richard "Cheech" Marin and Tommy Chong debuted their Mary-Jane fueled humor with Up In Smoke. While Reefer Madness was the first notable film to promote weed, it's this film that set the template for stoner films. Not really much of a plot here: Pedro De Pacas (Marin) meets up with rich-kid Anthony "Man" Stoner (Chong) and find out they both like getting high. Their search for pot takes them all over Los Angeles and Tijuana in a wacky road-trip in a car unknowingly made out of grass. On their trip, they have to deal with Sgt. Sedenko (Stacy Keach), an over-zealous police officer trying to clean L.A. of druggies. The movie is filled with crazy situations: drug-filled parties, performances at a punk rock contest and a trip through a upholstery factory that is just a front for drug trafficking. Crazy people, the kind you would expect in a film like this, are everywhere. Both Marin and Chong are very good in the film but Keach steals the show. He is an absolute hoot in this film and he comes off as the most interesting character in the film. It's still very entertaining to this day as a curiosity piece. Check it out. BTW, one of the ladies Pedro and Man picks up looks remarkably like Sharon Snow of NTV.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The First & Best Cheech and Chong Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TBoldOne
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cheech and Chong were already insanely popular with their comedy record albums and were contracted to make a movie. Hoping to make the "big score" they go to Mexico and end up driving a van built entirely of Weed back across the border. Many reviewers have already commented on the classic "stoner" humor, and I won't add to that. If you get this movie get the DVD with the extended commentary. In it you find that they were on the cutting edge of the Punk Rock revolution. The battle of the bands features some of the earliest LA punk rock bands. My favorite gags. 1) Cheech and Chong get in their car, do a U - Turn, park on the other side of the street and get out. 2) The Van Scene - This literally made the phrase "If this vans rocking, don't come a-knocking" part of our popular culture. Whats so amazing about this scene was that it wasn't even in the original script! The actress, who played Chongs girlfriend was telling the story of a roommate who was a "screamer", while they were on lunch break outside of the battle of the bands show. Cheech and Chong said that sounds funny, lets film it. It just goes to show you that sometimes the best comedy can be the spontaneous type. Finally students of film comedy should rent this movie for an unusual reason. Watching this movie in 2010 is like a going into a time warp. This movie could never be made today, and I'm not referring to the drug humor. The pacing of the gags is so slow compared to today. It's weirdly funny when you watch and notice it like I did. Sadly most comedies today don't give their actors time to develop their gags. If you wan't a harmless (except for the drug humor) movie, buy this movie. It is the best of the Cheech and Chong movies
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheech and Chong's Up in Smoke
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first heard of and saw Cheech and Chong featured in the South Park Episode "Cherokee Hair Tampons", and then I heard about this 1001 Movies You See Before You Die recommended film. Basically slackers and getting nowhere musicians Pedro De Pacas (Richard 'Cheech' Marin) and Anthony 'Man' Stoner (Tommy Chong) happen to meet on a Californian highway, and instantly find a connection with their love of marijuana. They are pulled over by the cops, and end up deported to Mexico, but in court they are let off lightly by the Vodka drinking judge, and they start a road trip to go back home, and try to score some drugs along the way. This includes a trip to dealer Strawberry (Alien's Tom Skerritt), a little house party snorting some wash powder as cocaine, and the big hoot of the film, unintentionally steal a van made entirely of hardened weed. Along the way Pedro and Man pick up two women, who convince them that they should enter their band in a Battle of the Bands contest, and the final scene sees them win with a very high audience. Also starring Batman: Mask of the Phantasm's Stacy Keach as Sgt. Stedenko, Strother Martin as Arnold Stoner, Edie Adams as Mrs. Tempest Stoner, Ray Vitte as Bass Player James and Michael Caldwell as Guitar Player Duane. Cheech and Chong with their "man" catchphrase creating smiles and stoned foolishness are a great double act, Keach does make a good deranged cop, and there are some good songs in it. I will say, the film started hilariously, it then loses a tiny bit of steam, then it picks up with the "fiberweed" van, and the last few scenes are quite funny, so overall, it a most watchable cult comedy. Good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    hilarious ! the funniest weed movie i have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yousif el3li
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is the only comedy movie that made me laugh so loud ! i swear i would pay 1 grand only to see Pedro and Anthony again and the way they are acting ! the jokes are so funny man especially when it comes from Anthony i laugh even if he didn't said any funny jokes ! his way in talking is so freaking funny man they just sing well when they get high ! its an incredible movie man i just want to tell you this movie is a life time opportunity Quote from Pedro is so funny when you hear it in the movie : ARE WE SMOKING DOG Sh*t , MAN ? 10\10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Everybody must get stoned"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RainDogJr
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I added to my collection the Double Feature DVD with Up in Smoke and Still Smokin like two months ago but just last night I finally saw the first one so also last night was my very first "encounter" with Cheech and Chong and for sure won't be the last. So here Cheech Marin and Tommy Chong are Pedro and Anthony (his father call him Anthony yet in the credits Tommy Chong is just "man") respectively and basically they will meet just by pure causality. We have the sort of introduction and we see a moment with each one, we see the first funny moment with Pedro pissing and on the other hand we have the classic situation of a guy who at the age of what 30 or something still lives with his parents, certainly the father is just tired of having his lazy son doing about nothing during the entire day. Both Pedro and Anthony are out with cars yet only Pedro will be able to continue driving, to continue looking for a lost babe or maybe babes but he will have only kind of a really big disappointment but after all there he meets who will be his best friend. Certainly these two have a lot in common but mainly two things will keep them together: drugs and rock and roll. Is just amazing and hilarious the first joint they smoke together, Pedro was like "I been smoking since always, I can smoke anything" but the Led Zeppelin is something else, heavy s***, dog s***! And that s*** will give them some troubles and certainly we will laugh and laugh. Up in Smoke is one of those movies that are just so damn enjoyable since the very first second till the very last, essentially Pedro and Anthony are just looking out for some s*** but of course things will happen. The police play here a big role, they will be close to Pedro, Anthony and company and they deliver also a lot of fun. We have the police chief and three of his "sons" (is also a great "show" with this guys, of course the one who will suffer most is the chief, he even loses his dog that was the best cop he ever saw!), they are after those who are transporting a really big quantity of drug from Mexico to the US, they will be after "two hippies with a van". And certainly we know who those hippies are, we know that the van they are driving would be a damn treasure for them but they don't know, actually they don't know a damn thing. Is really funny what Pedro's cousin (not sure is his cousin but sure is a relative) do to get a free ride to Tijuana, very funny and Pedro and Anthony will be in Mexico also and in THE van they will return to the US. At one point we know what will happen with the van if the police finds it, actually is not that different to what will happen with the van if Pedro and Anthony realize about the truth. By this time our dudes have company, finally the company of women and now they have another thing in mind: the battle of the bands at the Roxy. And will be for a moment like a little Monterey or Woodstock, every single soul in the place was connected! Those like me who saw first the great Coen brothers film The Big Lebowski (that is my second favourite Coen bros film) certainly will remember it. Terrific fun with these two DUDES!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The original stoner flick(I think)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gangstahippie
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Throughout film history, there have been plenty of films involving the use or talk of marijuana.Because of marijuana, there have been plenty of hilarious films such as Harold & Kumar showing the misadventures of people who smoke it.I believe that Cheech and Chong's Up In Smoke, was the first film to portray the positive use of marijuana.There have been other movies beforehand such as the 1936 "Reefer Madness".This is the first of a series of films which continued on into the 1980's.Before this film, they were comedians/musicians.Anyway, this movie is about two guys who try to smuggle a van made out of marijuana across the Mexican border while the narc cops led by Sgt Stedeko are hot on their trail.The duo gets into many misadventures during the film, while they must win the battle of the bands contest.Overall this is a great stoner film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic of drug comedies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kurciasbezdalas
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basically all Up in Smoke movies are about watching other people getting high, actually all the drug comedies are about that. It sounds kinda boring, but not when those people are Cheech & Chong. The scene where they were smoking in a car in the beginning is still funny to me, though I watched it many times. This movie is making fun more from the cops and other people who fight drugs, than from the drug addicts who just want to get high. This film shows how ridiculous those fighters against drugs look like, though this is a comedy, in my opinion, there is a lot of truth in this film. Maybe other Up in Smoke movies aren't that good as this one, but as I remember there is always at least few hilarious moments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very amiable comedy classic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Legendary comedy duo Cheech & Chong's first and best cinematic outing is a hoot the entire time, just what this reviewer would recommend for those people who just want to turn off their brain for about an hour and a half and relax. One certainly doesn't have to be a stoner themselves in order to appreciate it. There's not much of a story here, mostly a series of easygoing, sometimes hysterical vignettes as Pedro (Cheech) and Anthony (Chong) go on the hunt for "good grass", although Pedro's main ambition is for his band to achieve some fame and fortune, and, recruiting Anthony as a drummer, he and his bandmates get their chance in a battle of the bands for the movie's finish. Great sight gags abound; the fact that Pedro and Anthony end up driving a van that's actually made out of marijuana is priceless. Hot on their trail is flustered narc Stedenko (Stacy Keach), who's stuck with a bunch of incredibly inept detectives. Cheech & Chong are hilarious as always, and incidentally, one can see how Chong's Anthony would get the nickname that he has, MAN. A spirited supporting cast adds to the fun, although I personally would have liked to have seen at least a little more of Strother Martin as Anthony's fed-up father. But Tom Skerritt is great as Pedro's Nam flashback plagued cousin Strawberry (I'd advise you not to look at his neck), Louisa Moritz is in fine bubbly form as luscious cop Gloria, and Zane Buzby is fun as stoner babe Jade East. The cast features such familiar character players and celebrities as Arthur Roberts, Donald Hotton, Ray Vitte, Gary Mule Deer, Mills Watson, Val Avery, and Rodney Bingenheimer, with lovely ladies Cheryl "Rainbeaux" Smith and Wally Ann Wharton adding to the entertainment value. It's just too funny to see, among other things, a group of nuns get detained by the cops, and the cops getting the munchies as they get stoned. The cool soundtrack (including the classic "Low Rider") and the bright, sunny look of the film are big bonuses, and the laughs keep coming at a consistent pace. "Up in Smoke" is good natured in spirit, and is definitely too hard to resist. Eight out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slam-Bong Comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first Cheech & Chong stoner comedy of errors "Up in Smoke" consists of gags lifted from their comedy albums about marijuana usage tacked onto a rolling paper thin plot about smuggling a fortune in pot into the U.S. by two dopers desperate for some weed to puff. The message is that if our heroes get high enough that all their troubles will disappear in a purple haze of smoke. Freshman director Lou Adler learned on the job with this occasionally funny comedy that never advocates the legalization of pot. You won't find anything remotely subversive and "Up in Smoke" doesn't take any chances. Adler and scenarists Tommy Chong and Cheech Marin may have gotten high when they contrived this harmless nonsense, but they have no lofty aims. They ridicule their own clueless characters as well as a cadre of hopelessly inept but zealous narcotics police officers who pursue them. "Up in Smoke" amounts to a stoned version of the Keystone Kops, except that the cops are narcs. Of course, Pedro De Bacas (Cheech Marin) and Anthony Stoner (Tommy Chong) are a pair of misguided stoners who encounter each other after Anthony's intolerant father Arnold (Strother Martin of "The Wild Bunch") threatens to pack him off to military school if he doesn't get a job. Anthony's Volkswagon Beetle conks out on him on the highway and he winds up spending the night in a ditch before Pedro mistakes him for a woman and tries to pick him up. Several mildly amusing scenes follow without apparent much apparent motivation. Everything centers on the efforts of our duo to find some good marijuana. One of the funniest scenes in the first 30 minutes shows them smoking a hilariously huge joint that consists of Maui-wowie strained from the turds of Anthony's Labrador. According to Anthony, he caught man's best friend chowing down on his stash and then followed him around with a baggie. Smoke pours out of their car as Pedros cruises the freeway. Inevitably, the police pull them over and pack them off to court with Anthony the worst for wear. During their arraignment in court, Anthony partakes of water from the judge's carafe. He spews the contents and announces to everybody that the judge has been drinking vodka. Our heroes are released after this alarming incident. Later, they visit one of their friends, Veteran-veteran Strawberry (Tom Skerritt of "M.A.S.H.") who has a huge discolored birthmark looking scar on his face. Before Strawberry can goad Anthony into confessing that he is staring at his skin problem, Pedro gets him to embark on a search for some reefer. They leave Anthony at Strawberry's house and Anthony monkeys around with some Comet so that it appears to be cocaine. Party girls snort it up and raise hell. Strawberry has a Vietnam flashback and dons his combat gear, while Pedro warns Anthony of an impending bust by Sergeant Stedenko. No sooner do our heroes escape from the cops a second time than they are caught in a raid organized by INS agents and bussed back across the border. The catch is that the rest of the Mexicans deliberately informed on themselves so they could get a free ride to the border prior to a wedding. Pedro and Anthony go to an upholstery shop run by an uncle to acquire the means of getting back across the border. Predictably, they enter the wrong shop and find themselves in a massive pot smuggling enterprise. They are given a van to drive back to L.A., but what our protagonists don't realize is that they are driving a van constructed of fiberweed. Meaning, the dope smugglers have converted the THC resin found in marijuana in a fiberglass-like substance. Just when it looks like our heroes will be busted at the border, Anthony thumps a roach into a station wagon full of Catholic sisters. The authorities allows our heroes to pass through, but they bust the sisters. Once they are back in L.A., Pedro and Anthony decide to compete in a battle of rock bands. They dress themselves in outlandish costumes and manage to sing a ridiculous song that turns the entire audience into a raving room of fans. The general idea here to keep our heroes off balance as they look for pot and Alder and company shun any political positions. No, this is not an imaginative comedy, but it marked not only their debut but the biggest depiction of a counter-culture duo that spawned a number of lesser films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Start To Stoner Comedies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cheech and Chong meet up by chance on the highway somewhere in California. They go in search of some dope and are accidentally deported to Mexico where in their desperation to get home they agree to drive a van back to the States so they can get back in time for a gig they are due to play. Unaware of the properties from which the van is constructed they make their way back having acquired a couple of female hitch-hikers whilst all the time avoiding the cops whom they are not even aware are following them. Tonight I Decided To Give The Mother Of All Stoner Comedies A Go. This Is Not Just The Mother Of Stoner Comedies...Its The Father Of Dumb Comedies. I Loved Every Minute Of It...I Was Adimant Not To Turn The TV Off When Cheech & Chong Smoked Dog Crap That Came From A Dog That Ate Chong's Marjuana...I'm Laughing Now As I Type It Up. I Also Have Some Of Their Recordings Like "Dave", "Up In Smoke"(I Was Familiar With The Movie Before Tonight), I Even Had "Earache My Eye" Which Is My Personal Favourite So I Didn't Mind Hearing It In This Film But I Would've Loved It Even More If After The End Credits The Sketch That Goes With Earache My Eye Would Play. I Also Loved The Fact That They Were So Dumb That They Had No Idea The "Hard Hat" Cops Were After Them. Overall If You Like Stoner Comedies In The Same Vein As The Kevin Smith Comedies Of...Well His Entire Career Than This Movie Is Definitely One To Buy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where it all began...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluethunder35 (bluethunder35@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Richard "Cheech" Marin and Tommy Chong debuted their Mary-Jane fueled humor with Up In Smoke. While Reefer Madness was the first notable film to promote weed, it's this film that set the template for stoner films. Not really much of a plot here: Pedro De Pacas (Marin) meets up with rich-kid Anthony "Man" Stoner (Chong) and find out they both like getting high. Their search for pot takes them all over Los Angeles and Tijuana in a wacky road-trip in a car unknowingly made out of grass. On their trip, they have to deal with Sgt. Sedenko (Stacy Keach), an over-zealous police officer trying to clean L.A. of druggies. The movie is filled with crazy situations: drug-filled parties, performances at a punk rock contest and a trip through a upholstery factory that is just a front for drug trafficking. Crazy people, the kind you would expect in a film like this, are everywhere. Both Marin and Chong are very good in the film but Keach steals the show. He is an absolute hoot in this film and he comes off as the most interesting character in the film. It's still very entertaining to this day as a curiosity piece. Check it out. BTW, one of the ladies Pedro and Man picks up looks remarkably like Sharon Snow of NTV.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The First & Best Cheech and Chong Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TBoldOne
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cheech and Chong were already insanely popular with their comedy record albums and were contracted to make a movie. Hoping to make the "big score" they go to Mexico and end up driving a van built entirely of Weed back across the border. Many reviewers have already commented on the classic "stoner" humor, and I won't add to that. If you get this movie get the DVD with the extended commentary. In it you find that they were on the cutting edge of the Punk Rock revolution. The battle of the bands features some of the earliest LA punk rock bands. My favorite gags. 1) Cheech and Chong get in their car, do a U - Turn, park on the other side of the street and get out. 2) The Van Scene - This literally made the phrase "If this vans rocking, don't come a-knocking" part of our popular culture. Whats so amazing about this scene was that it wasn't even in the original script! The actress, who played Chongs girlfriend was telling the story of a roommate who was a "screamer", while they were on lunch break outside of the battle of the bands show. Cheech and Chong said that sounds funny, lets film it. It just goes to show you that sometimes the best comedy can be the spontaneous type. Finally students of film comedy should rent this movie for an unusual reason. Watching this movie in 2010 is like a going into a time warp. This movie could never be made today, and I'm not referring to the drug humor. The pacing of the gags is so slow compared to today. It's weirdly funny when you watch and notice it like I did. Sadly most comedies today don't give their actors time to develop their gags. If you wan't a harmless (except for the drug humor) movie, buy this movie. It is the best of the Cheech and Chong movies
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheech and Chong's Up in Smoke
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first heard of and saw Cheech and Chong featured in the South Park Episode "Cherokee Hair Tampons", and then I heard about this 1001 Movies You See Before You Die recommended film. Basically slackers and getting nowhere musicians Pedro De Pacas (Richard 'Cheech' Marin) and Anthony 'Man' Stoner (Tommy Chong) happen to meet on a Californian highway, and instantly find a connection with their love of marijuana. They are pulled over by the cops, and end up deported to Mexico, but in court they are let off lightly by the Vodka drinking judge, and they start a road trip to go back home, and try to score some drugs along the way. This includes a trip to dealer Strawberry (Alien's Tom Skerritt), a little house party snorting some wash powder as cocaine, and the big hoot of the film, unintentionally steal a van made entirely of hardened weed. Along the way Pedro and Man pick up two women, who convince them that they should enter their band in a Battle of the Bands contest, and the final scene sees them win with a very high audience. Also starring Batman: Mask of the Phantasm's Stacy Keach as Sgt. Stedenko, Strother Martin as Arnold Stoner, Edie Adams as Mrs. Tempest Stoner, Ray Vitte as Bass Player James and Michael Caldwell as Guitar Player Duane. Cheech and Chong with their "man" catchphrase creating smiles and stoned foolishness are a great double act, Keach does make a good deranged cop, and there are some good songs in it. I will say, the film started hilariously, it then loses a tiny bit of steam, then it picks up with the "fiberweed" van, and the last few scenes are quite funny, so overall, it a most watchable cult comedy. Good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    hilarious ! the funniest weed movie i have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yousif el3li
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is the only comedy movie that made me laugh so loud ! i swear i would pay 1 grand only to see Pedro and Anthony again and the way they are acting ! the jokes are so funny man especially when it comes from Anthony i laugh even if he didn't said any funny jokes ! his way in talking is so freaking funny man they just sing well when they get high ! its an incredible movie man i just want to tell you this movie is a life time opportunity Quote from Pedro is so funny when you hear it in the movie : ARE WE SMOKING DOG Sh*t , MAN ? 10\10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Everybody must get stoned"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RainDogJr
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I added to my collection the Double Feature DVD with Up in Smoke and Still Smokin like two months ago but just last night I finally saw the first one so also last night was my very first "encounter" with Cheech and Chong and for sure won't be the last. So here Cheech Marin and Tommy Chong are Pedro and Anthony (his father call him Anthony yet in the credits Tommy Chong is just "man") respectively and basically they will meet just by pure causality. We have the sort of introduction and we see a moment with each one, we see the first funny moment with Pedro pissing and on the other hand we have the classic situation of a guy who at the age of what 30 or something still lives with his parents, certainly the father is just tired of having his lazy son doing about nothing during the entire day. Both Pedro and Anthony are out with cars yet only Pedro will be able to continue driving, to continue looking for a lost babe or maybe babes but he will have only kind of a really big disappointment but after all there he meets who will be his best friend. Certainly these two have a lot in common but mainly two things will keep them together: drugs and rock and roll. Is just amazing and hilarious the first joint they smoke together, Pedro was like "I been smoking since always, I can smoke anything" but the Led Zeppelin is something else, heavy s***, dog s***! And that s*** will give them some troubles and certainly we will laugh and laugh. Up in Smoke is one of those movies that are just so damn enjoyable since the very first second till the very last, essentially Pedro and Anthony are just looking out for some s*** but of course things will happen. The police play here a big role, they will be close to Pedro, Anthony and company and they deliver also a lot of fun. We have the police chief and three of his "sons" (is also a great "show" with this guys, of course the one who will suffer most is the chief, he even loses his dog that was the best cop he ever saw!), they are after those who are transporting a really big quantity of drug from Mexico to the US, they will be after "two hippies with a van". And certainly we know who those hippies are, we know that the van they are driving would be a damn treasure for them but they don't know, actually they don't know a damn thing. Is really funny what Pedro's cousin (not sure is his cousin but sure is a relative) do to get a free ride to Tijuana, very funny and Pedro and Anthony will be in Mexico also and in THE van they will return to the US. At one point we know what will happen with the van if the police finds it, actually is not that different to what will happen with the van if Pedro and Anthony realize about the truth. By this time our dudes have company, finally the company of women and now they have another thing in mind: the battle of the bands at the Roxy. And will be for a moment like a little Monterey or Woodstock, every single soul in the place was connected! Those like me who saw first the great Coen brothers film The Big Lebowski (that is my second favourite Coen bros film) certainly will remember it. Terrific fun with these two DUDES!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The original stoner flick(I think)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gangstahippie
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Throughout film history, there have been plenty of films involving the use or talk of marijuana.Because of marijuana, there have been plenty of hilarious films such as Harold & Kumar showing the misadventures of people who smoke it.I believe that Cheech and Chong's Up In Smoke, was the first film to portray the positive use of marijuana.There have been other movies beforehand such as the 1936 "Reefer Madness".This is the first of a series of films which continued on into the 1980's.Before this film, they were comedians/musicians.Anyway, this movie is about two guys who try to smuggle a van made out of marijuana across the Mexican border while the narc cops led by Sgt Stedeko are hot on their trail.The duo gets into many misadventures during the film, while they must win the battle of the bands contest.Overall this is a great stoner film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic of drug comedies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kurciasbezdalas
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basically all Up in Smoke movies are about watching other people getting high, actually all the drug comedies are about that. It sounds kinda boring, but not when those people are Cheech & Chong. The scene where they were smoking in a car in the beginning is still funny to me, though I watched it many times. This movie is making fun more from the cops and other people who fight drugs, than from the drug addicts who just want to get high. This film shows how ridiculous those fighters against drugs look like, though this is a comedy, in my opinion, there is a lot of truth in this film. Maybe other Up in Smoke movies aren't that good as this one, but as I remember there is always at least few hilarious moments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very amiable comedy classic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Legendary comedy duo Cheech & Chong's first and best cinematic outing is a hoot the entire time, just what this reviewer would recommend for those people who just want to turn off their brain for about an hour and a half and relax. One certainly doesn't have to be a stoner themselves in order to appreciate it. There's not much of a story here, mostly a series of easygoing, sometimes hysterical vignettes as Pedro (Cheech) and Anthony (Chong) go on the hunt for "good grass", although Pedro's main ambition is for his band to achieve some fame and fortune, and, recruiting Anthony as a drummer, he and his bandmates get their chance in a battle of the bands for the movie's finish. Great sight gags abound; the fact that Pedro and Anthony end up driving a van that's actually made out of marijuana is priceless. Hot on their trail is flustered narc Stedenko (Stacy Keach), who's stuck with a bunch of incredibly inept detectives. Cheech & Chong are hilarious as always, and incidentally, one can see how Chong's Anthony would get the nickname that he has, MAN. A spirited supporting cast adds to the fun, although I personally would have liked to have seen at least a little more of Strother Martin as Anthony's fed-up father. But Tom Skerritt is great as Pedro's Nam flashback plagued cousin Strawberry (I'd advise you not to look at his neck), Louisa Moritz is in fine bubbly form as luscious cop Gloria, and Zane Buzby is fun as stoner babe Jade East. The cast features such familiar character players and celebrities as Arthur Roberts, Donald Hotton, Ray Vitte, Gary Mule Deer, Mills Watson, Val Avery, and Rodney Bingenheimer, with lovely ladies Cheryl "Rainbeaux" Smith and Wally Ann Wharton adding to the entertainment value. It's just too funny to see, among other things, a group of nuns get detained by the cops, and the cops getting the munchies as they get stoned. The cool soundtrack (including the classic "Low Rider") and the bright, sunny look of the film are big bonuses, and the laughs keep coming at a consistent pace. "Up in Smoke" is good natured in spirit, and is definitely too hard to resist. Eight out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slam-Bong Comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first Cheech & Chong stoner comedy of errors "Up in Smoke" consists of gags lifted from their comedy albums about marijuana usage tacked onto a rolling paper thin plot about smuggling a fortune in pot into the U.S. by two dopers desperate for some weed to puff. The message is that if our heroes get high enough that all their troubles will disappear in a purple haze of smoke. Freshman director Lou Adler learned on the job with this occasionally funny comedy that never advocates the legalization of pot. You won't find anything remotely subversive and "Up in Smoke" doesn't take any chances. Adler and scenarists Tommy Chong and Cheech Marin may have gotten high when they contrived this harmless nonsense, but they have no lofty aims. They ridicule their own clueless characters as well as a cadre of hopelessly inept but zealous narcotics police officers who pursue them. "Up in Smoke" amounts to a stoned version of the Keystone Kops, except that the cops are narcs. Of course, Pedro De Bacas (Cheech Marin) and Anthony Stoner (Tommy Chong) are a pair of misguided stoners who encounter each other after Anthony's intolerant father Arnold (Strother Martin of "The Wild Bunch") threatens to pack him off to military school if he doesn't get a job. Anthony's Volkswagon Beetle conks out on him on the highway and he winds up spending the night in a ditch before Pedro mistakes him for a woman and tries to pick him up. Several mildly amusing scenes follow without apparent much apparent motivation. Everything centers on the efforts of our duo to find some good marijuana. One of the funniest scenes in the first 30 minutes shows them smoking a hilariously huge joint that consists of Maui-wowie strained from the turds of Anthony's Labrador. According to Anthony, he caught man's best friend chowing down on his stash and then followed him around with a baggie. Smoke pours out of their car as Pedros cruises the freeway. Inevitably, the police pull them over and pack them off to court with Anthony the worst for wear. During their arraignment in court, Anthony partakes of water from the judge's carafe. He spews the contents and announces to everybody that the judge has been drinking vodka. Our heroes are released after this alarming incident. Later, they visit one of their friends, Veteran-veteran Strawberry (Tom Skerritt of "M.A.S.H.") who has a huge discolored birthmark looking scar on his face. Before Strawberry can goad Anthony into confessing that he is staring at his skin problem, Pedro gets him to embark on a search for some reefer. They leave Anthony at Strawberry's house and Anthony monkeys around with some Comet so that it appears to be cocaine. Party girls snort it up and raise hell. Strawberry has a Vietnam flashback and dons his combat gear, while Pedro warns Anthony of an impending bust by Sergeant Stedenko. No sooner do our heroes escape from the cops a second time than they are caught in a raid organized by INS agents and bussed back across the border. The catch is that the rest of the Mexicans deliberately informed on themselves so they could get a free ride to the border prior to a wedding. Pedro and Anthony go to an upholstery shop run by an uncle to acquire the means of getting back across the border. Predictably, they enter the wrong shop and find themselves in a massive pot smuggling enterprise. They are given a van to drive back to L.A., but what our protagonists don't realize is that they are driving a van constructed of fiberweed. Meaning, the dope smugglers have converted the THC resin found in marijuana in a fiberglass-like substance. Just when it looks like our heroes will be busted at the border, Anthony thumps a roach into a station wagon full of Catholic sisters. The authorities allows our heroes to pass through, but they bust the sisters. Once they are back in L.A., Pedro and Anthony decide to compete in a battle of rock bands. They dress themselves in outlandish costumes and manage to sing a ridiculous song that turns the entire audience into a raving room of fans. The general idea here to keep our heroes off balance as they look for pot and Alder and company shun any political positions. No, this is not an imaginative comedy, but it marked not only their debut but the biggest depiction of a counter-culture duo that spawned a number of lesser films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Start To Stoner Comedies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cheech and Chong meet up by chance on the highway somewhere in California. They go in search of some dope and are accidentally deported to Mexico where in their desperation to get home they agree to drive a van back to the States so they can get back in time for a gig they are due to play. Unaware of the properties from which the van is constructed they make their way back having acquired a couple of female hitch-hikers whilst all the time avoiding the cops whom they are not even aware are following them. Tonight I Decided To Give The Mother Of All Stoner Comedies A Go. This Is Not Just The Mother Of Stoner Comedies...Its The Father Of Dumb Comedies. I Loved Every Minute Of It...I Was Adimant Not To Turn The TV Off When Cheech & Chong Smoked Dog Crap That Came From A Dog That Ate Chong's Marjuana...I'm Laughing Now As I Type It Up. I Also Have Some Of Their Recordings Like "Dave", "Up In Smoke"(I Was Familiar With The Movie Before Tonight), I Even Had "Earache My Eye" Which Is My Personal Favourite So I Didn't Mind Hearing It In This Film But I Would've Loved It Even More If After The End Credits The Sketch That Goes With Earache My Eye Would Play. I Also Loved The Fact That They Were So Dumb That They Had No Idea The "Hard Hat" Cops Were After Them. Overall If You Like Stoner Comedies In The Same Vein As The Kevin Smith Comedies Of...Well His Entire Career Than This Movie Is Definitely One To Buy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where it all began...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluethunder35 (bluethunder35@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Richard "Cheech" Marin and Tommy Chong debuted their Mary-Jane fueled humor with Up In Smoke. While Reefer Madness was the first notable film to promote weed, it's this film that set the template for stoner films. Not really much of a plot here: Pedro De Pacas (Marin) meets up with rich-kid Anthony "Man" Stoner (Chong) and find out they both like getting high. Their search for pot takes them all over Los Angeles and Tijuana in a wacky road-trip in a car unknowingly made out of grass. On their trip, they have to deal with Sgt. Sedenko (Stacy Keach), an over-zealous police officer trying to clean L.A. of druggies. The movie is filled with crazy situations: drug-filled parties, performances at a punk rock contest and a trip through a upholstery factory that is just a front for drug trafficking. Crazy people, the kind you would expect in a film like this, are everywhere. Both Marin and Chong are very good in the film but Keach steals the show. He is an absolute hoot in this film and he comes off as the most interesting character in the film. It's still very entertaining to this day as a curiosity piece. Check it out. BTW, one of the ladies Pedro and Man picks up looks remarkably like Sharon Snow of NTV.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The First & Best Cheech and Chong Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TBoldOne
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cheech and Chong were already insanely popular with their comedy record albums and were contracted to make a movie. Hoping to make the "big score" they go to Mexico and end up driving a van built entirely of Weed back across the border. Many reviewers have already commented on the classic "stoner" humor, and I won't add to that. If you get this movie get the DVD with the extended commentary. In it you find that they were on the cutting edge of the Punk Rock revolution. The battle of the bands features some of the earliest LA punk rock bands. My favorite gags. 1) Cheech and Chong get in their car, do a U - Turn, park on the other side of the street and get out. 2) The Van Scene - This literally made the phrase "If this vans rocking, don't come a-knocking" part of our popular culture. Whats so amazing about this scene was that it wasn't even in the original script! The actress, who played Chongs girlfriend was telling the story of a roommate who was a "screamer", while they were on lunch break outside of the battle of the bands show. Cheech and Chong said that sounds funny, lets film it. It just goes to show you that sometimes the best comedy can be the spontaneous type. Finally students of film comedy should rent this movie for an unusual reason. Watching this movie in 2010 is like a going into a time warp. This movie could never be made today, and I'm not referring to the drug humor. The pacing of the gags is so slow compared to today. It's weirdly funny when you watch and notice it like I did. Sadly most comedies today don't give their actors time to develop their gags. If you wan't a harmless (except for the drug humor) movie, buy this movie. It is the best of the Cheech and Chong movies
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheech and Chong's Up in Smoke
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first heard of and saw Cheech and Chong featured in the South Park Episode "Cherokee Hair Tampons", and then I heard about this 1001 Movies You See Before You Die recommended film. Basically slackers and getting nowhere musicians Pedro De Pacas (Richard 'Cheech' Marin) and Anthony 'Man' Stoner (Tommy Chong) happen to meet on a Californian highway, and instantly find a connection with their love of marijuana. They are pulled over by the cops, and end up deported to Mexico, but in court they are let off lightly by the Vodka drinking judge, and they start a road trip to go back home, and try to score some drugs along the way. This includes a trip to dealer Strawberry (Alien's Tom Skerritt), a little house party snorting some wash powder as cocaine, and the big hoot of the film, unintentionally steal a van made entirely of hardened weed. Along the way Pedro and Man pick up two women, who convince them that they should enter their band in a Battle of the Bands contest, and the final scene sees them win with a very high audience. Also starring Batman: Mask of the Phantasm's Stacy Keach as Sgt. Stedenko, Strother Martin as Arnold Stoner, Edie Adams as Mrs. Tempest Stoner, Ray Vitte as Bass Player James and Michael Caldwell as Guitar Player Duane. Cheech and Chong with their "man" catchphrase creating smiles and stoned foolishness are a great double act, Keach does make a good deranged cop, and there are some good songs in it. I will say, the film started hilariously, it then loses a tiny bit of steam, then it picks up with the "fiberweed" van, and the last few scenes are quite funny, so overall, it a most watchable cult comedy. Good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    hilarious ! the funniest weed movie i have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yousif el3li
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is the only comedy movie that made me laugh so loud ! i swear i would pay 1 grand only to see Pedro and Anthony again and the way they are acting ! the jokes are so funny man especially when it comes from Anthony i laugh even if he didn't said any funny jokes ! his way in talking is so freaking funny man they just sing well when they get high ! its an incredible movie man i just want to tell you this movie is a life time opportunity Quote from Pedro is so funny when you hear it in the movie : ARE WE SMOKING DOG Sh*t , MAN ? 10\10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Everybody must get stoned"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RainDogJr
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I added to my collection the Double Feature DVD with Up in Smoke and Still Smokin like two months ago but just last night I finally saw the first one so also last night was my very first "encounter" with Cheech and Chong and for sure won't be the last. So here Cheech Marin and Tommy Chong are Pedro and Anthony (his father call him Anthony yet in the credits Tommy Chong is just "man") respectively and basically they will meet just by pure causality. We have the sort of introduction and we see a moment with each one, we see the first funny moment with Pedro pissing and on the other hand we have the classic situation of a guy who at the age of what 30 or something still lives with his parents, certainly the father is just tired of having his lazy son doing about nothing during the entire day. Both Pedro and Anthony are out with cars yet only Pedro will be able to continue driving, to continue looking for a lost babe or maybe babes but he will have only kind of a really big disappointment but after all there he meets who will be his best friend. Certainly these two have a lot in common but mainly two things will keep them together: drugs and rock and roll. Is just amazing and hilarious the first joint they smoke together, Pedro was like "I been smoking since always, I can smoke anything" but the Led Zeppelin is something else, heavy s***, dog s***! And that s*** will give them some troubles and certainly we will laugh and laugh. Up in Smoke is one of those movies that are just so damn enjoyable since the very first second till the very last, essentially Pedro and Anthony are just looking out for some s*** but of course things will happen. The police play here a big role, they will be close to Pedro, Anthony and company and they deliver also a lot of fun. We have the police chief and three of his "sons" (is also a great "show" with this guys, of course the one who will suffer most is the chief, he even loses his dog that was the best cop he ever saw!), they are after those who are transporting a really big quantity of drug from Mexico to the US, they will be after "two hippies with a van". And certainly we know who those hippies are, we know that the van they are driving would be a damn treasure for them but they don't know, actually they don't know a damn thing. Is really funny what Pedro's cousin (not sure is his cousin but sure is a relative) do to get a free ride to Tijuana, very funny and Pedro and Anthony will be in Mexico also and in THE van they will return to the US. At one point we know what will happen with the van if the police finds it, actually is not that different to what will happen with the van if Pedro and Anthony realize about the truth. By this time our dudes have company, finally the company of women and now they have another thing in mind: the battle of the bands at the Roxy. And will be for a moment like a little Monterey or Woodstock, every single soul in the place was connected! Those like me who saw first the great Coen brothers film The Big Lebowski (that is my second favourite Coen bros film) certainly will remember it. Terrific fun with these two DUDES!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The original stoner flick(I think)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gangstahippie
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Throughout film history, there have been plenty of films involving the use or talk of marijuana.Because of marijuana, there have been plenty of hilarious films such as Harold & Kumar showing the misadventures of people who smoke it.I believe that Cheech and Chong's Up In Smoke, was the first film to portray the positive use of marijuana.There have been other movies beforehand such as the 1936 "Reefer Madness".This is the first of a series of films which continued on into the 1980's.Before this film, they were comedians/musicians.Anyway, this movie is about two guys who try to smuggle a van made out of marijuana across the Mexican border while the narc cops led by Sgt Stedeko are hot on their trail.The duo gets into many misadventures during the film, while they must win the battle of the bands contest.Overall this is a great stoner film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic of drug comedies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kurciasbezdalas
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basically all Up in Smoke movies are about watching other people getting high, actually all the drug comedies are about that. It sounds kinda boring, but not when those people are Cheech & Chong. The scene where they were smoking in a car in the beginning is still funny to me, though I watched it many times. This movie is making fun more from the cops and other people who fight drugs, than from the drug addicts who just want to get high. This film shows how ridiculous those fighters against drugs look like, though this is a comedy, in my opinion, there is a lot of truth in this film. Maybe other Up in Smoke movies aren't that good as this one, but as I remember there is always at least few hilarious moments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
