<filme>
 <id>
  1121
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0058450
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1964
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Os Guarda-Chuvas do Amor
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A young girl separated from her lover by war faces a life altering decision.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Genevi&egrave;ve, 17, lives with her widowed mother, who owns an umbrella shop in Cherbourg. She and Guy, a twenty-year-old auto mechanic, are secretly in love and want to marry, but when she reveals this to her mother, her mother objects on the grounds that Genevi&egrave;ve is too young and Guy is not mature or well-established enough, particularly since he has not yet done his required military service. Shortly after this, Guy is drafted to serve in the war in Algeria. Before he leaves, he and Genevi&egrave;ve consummate their love for each other, which results in her becoming pregnant. While Guy is away they drift apart, and Genevi&egrave;ve, strongly encouraged by her mother, accepts a marriage proposal from a well-to-do gem dealer named Roland Cassard, who has fallen in love with her at first sight and has promised to bring up her child as his own. (The character of Cassard is continued from Demy's earlier film .) Guy is wounded and is discharged before his two-year term is up, but when...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Musical
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   aunt
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   military service
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   mechanic
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   umbrella
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Jacques Demy
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Jacques Demy
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Catherine Deneuve
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Nino Castelnuovo
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Anne Vernon
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ageless jazz opera
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film like this makes me think of my own life choices. It starts out like a painting that comes to life, set in the ancient port town of Cherbourg. (I was surprised to read on Wikipedia that a U.S. Civil War battle was fought off its shores.) From the cobblestone streets to the jewel-box storefronts to the grease monkeys at Guy's garage, this film is a joy to behold. And with Michel LeGrand's score, a delight to listen to. As a Francophile, I wish I could find a copy of its script. I enjoyed the crisp simplicity of the entirely sung dialogue. Adding to the satisfying unity of "Parapluies" is its perfect casting. Catherine Deneuve convinces as a rebellious daughter, infatuated teen, and bemused unwed woman with child. Her own mother, played fascinatingly by Anne Vernon, probably experienced the same out-of-wedlock pregnancy as she did. Clearly, Mme. Emery is attracted to M. Cassard, yet her only conscious wish is for the security of her only child. The mother-daughter relationship here is one of almost-total miscomprehension. Cassard (a dapper Marc Michel) is interesting to watch as the wealthy, somewhat bloodless suitor who actually travels with a crown, ready-made to place on his lady love's head! Nino Castelnuovo is superb as Guy, along with Ellen Farner as Madeleine. I enjoyed the range that Castelnuovo demonstrated, going from carefree lover to read-to-serve draftee, to depressed and acting-out Algerian War vet. The conversation between Guy and Madeleine, prior to marriage, is one of stunningly convincing depth, though its words are few. Of course, the final scene of this film unforgettable. I've seen "Parapluies" no fewer than five times and this viewing I cried perhaps more than ever, due to evermore bittersweet experience of my own under my belt. This must be one of those movies that never grows old. Its haunting melodies soothe and inspire me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Umbrellas of Cherbourg
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I read the title for this film in the book of 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die I knew it was a foreign film, from France, but I had no idea it was a musical, so I was most intrigued to watch, from director Jacques Demy (Lola, The Young Girls of Rochefort). Basically seventeen year old Genevi&egrave;ve Emery (Catherine Deneuve) lives in an umbrella shop in Cherbourg with her widowed mother Madame Emery (Anne Vernon), and she is secretly in love with twenty year old auto mechanic Guy Foucher (Nino Castelnuovo), and the two of them want to get married. She reveals this to her mother however, and she objects thinking that her daughter is too young and that he is not mature and well-established enough, and he may be required to do military service, and shortly later he is sent to Algeria after being drafted to serve in the war, but before leaving he and Genevi&egrave;ve consummate their love. Following this Genevi&egrave;ve is pregnant, while he is away he hardly communicates and they have drifted apart, so she listens to her mother's strong encouragement to accept a marriage proposal from Roland Cassard (Marc Michel) (he previously appeared as the same character in the film Lola), the affluent gem dealer who is in love with her and promises to bring her child up as his own. Guy is discharged from service before his two year term is up due to being wounded, he returns home and finds out Genevi&egrave;ve is married with a child and has moved away, and following this he sinks into deep depression and anger, which he struggles to control. But Guy recovers from his state when he falls in love and married young Madeleine (Ellen Farner) who had been caring for his aunt &Eacute;lise (Mireille Perrey), who is now deceased, and she left him an inheritance which he uses to fulfil his ambition to open a service station. Years pass, and Genevi&egrave;ve, who is now discernibly wealthy, has returned home with Fran&ccedil;oise (Rosalie Varda), her and Guy's daughter, and have an accidental meeting at his service station, their short conversation is obviously filled with unuttered fondness and regret, and in the end they finally part ways. Also starring Jean Champion as Aubin and Harald Wolff as Monsieur Dubourg. Deneuve is beautiful and gives a great delicate performance as the young woman longing for love from one man until fate changes everything, Castelnuovo is interesting as the man who is in and out of her life, and Michel is likable as the wealthy man with good intentions. The story is relatively simple, complicated romance, but what makes this musically distinctive is that every scene has singing, from the most mundane conversations to emotionally charging moments every word is spoken and sun in tune, and the picture has good use of vivid colour and design as well, it is a fantastic musical. It was nominated the Oscar for Best Song for "I Will Wait for You", Best Original Music for Michel Legrand and Jacques Demy, Best Music Adaptation or Treatment for Michel Legrand, Best Writing, Story and Screenplay - Written Directly for the Screen for Demy and Best Foreign Language Film, and it was nominated the Golden Globe for Best Foreign-Language Foreign Film. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A musical that compares the expectations of love with the harsh realities. The heart sings and breaks.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Umbrellas of Cherbourg is a unique film experiment. It's a musical where every line is sung. Even the mundane lines which have little to do with the film. While this style could be expected to be under threat of being too sweet, the film avoids this by approaching sentimentality with heart-wrenching reality, which the musical aspect of the film highlights. It's a love story. And the film is aware that it begins as a movie love story, addressed by the fact that the protagonist genuinely expects to die if they are parted. Instead of dying, the film explores one of my favourite deep subjects in art, by comparing the expectations of love brought on by pop culture with the harsh reality without being overdramatic. It's nostalgic and extremely genuine. As expected, the omnipresent music is absolutely wonderful and can speak for the film's emotion even without translation. How they managed to fit in the dialogue so fluently is incredible, let alone perform it. The set decoration and costume design is another highlight as well, with bright and bold colours, which the sweeping camera movement compliments perfectly. Despite the broad story, the film is surprisingly small scale with a limited use of sets, but the colour palette makes the world feel huge. There's some incredible use of match cuts as well. Though this film has a fantastic and charming atmosphere, it's the simple and effective storytelling that makes it, particularly the heartbreaking and subtle end. Bona fide classic. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    115 reviews so far...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Traversa
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... and they condense every possible information and observation one can make about this awesome movie. I will see it again out of an intense curiosity and nostalgia (I saw it many years ago and left me flabbergasted --patidifuso-- with all its fantastic beauty) after having listened the radio program I mention further down. I write these lines not to review one more time the film, but just to comment that I was listening a radio program from France Culture radio and they made a reportage about Cherbourg, where this movie was shot FIFTY YEARS AGO... and they are celebrating that anniversary in Cherbourg pulling out all the stops. It seems that the filming on that location 50 years ago was a big happening for this small and quiet coal town, apparently very dirty and facing away from the waterfront (now they have changed that concept and all new buildings are facing the waters) since then the huge popularity of this movie worldwide was such a ground shaking event for the inhabitants that they became aware of their own ignored potential and started to change everything, renovating shops and cleaning the city, to such an extent that nowadays the place is unrecognizable from its past dreary image. Japanese tourist go there to visit the umbrella shop where part of the action takes place (still looking and functioning like then) and even French people go there to visit the shop and take pictures!! During these fifty years Catherine Deneuve appeared in 117 films, leaving behind an enormous quantity of documentation to her legendary ice blonde beauty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Sweet Film."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manendra-lodhi (manendra.lodhi@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art cannot be for someone who fears. The director's approach fits in this quote. When I learned (before seeing the film) that it was a musical, I expected a rip off of the sound of Music. But when I started watching, everything started to look weird. All the dialogs in the film are in a musical way. You start to feel funny and irritated at the same time. The story is a very general, so do not expect much from it. It is just one normal love story that has a neutral ending with a good message. But what makes the film a must watch is its colorful cinematography. If for the first few minutes you are feeling irritated because of the musical dialogs then just wait some more and you will find yourself completely immersed in the film. After a time the dialogs, with music and everything look so normal that even such a predictable story can make you feel happy. It needed a lot of faith to make a film like this. The director has given a beautiful film which is definitely going to make you feel lighter. The most charming thing of the film is that none of the characters is shown as evil. It is the circumstances that are acting here as the obstacles. The film made me remember the films of Ghibli studios by Hayao Miyazaki. The film won the Palme d or in its time. But this is not the reason why you should be watching this, but that it is very much watchable in its own weird way. MESSAGE: "Life" VERDICT: "A recommended watch."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch it for the music, the colors, the story, and for the diving Ms. Deneuve
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    info-2752
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always associated my favorite musicals with Broadway, apart from this one, which is up there with my top three favorites. Filed as a love story, it also makes my top three. And Catherine Deneuve? She's definitely in my top three most beautiful actresses of all time. Then there's Michel Legrand, my second favorite composer (after Chopin, and if you must know, the third ones would be the Lennon/McCartney collaboration). How does one get so willingly hooked to a movie? Just sample the first five minutes of it, you don't even wait for the first lines of song to realize you're in for a gem of a film. Before you hear any of it, the sets are bound to get you. For the colors, those vibrant, palpable colors are a veritable visual feast. And have I mentioned the divine Catherine Deneuve? If there's anything most likely to distract your attention from the sets, it would be her presence. And last, but not least, for long after you may have forgotten the plot, you will never forget this: that melodious, hummable music, a song most of us associate with having heard from childhood, that beautifully threads the scenes of the story together--and you have the perfect musical. The most poignant love story (reminiscent of Splendor in the Grass, another coming-of-age film with a most genetically- blessed lead actors), with an ending that breaks the heart, but one which I completely approve of!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful--But Where's the Blu-Ray?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    t_k_matthews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most beautiful movies ever made deserves a Blu-Ray release. I first saw "The Umbrellas of Cherbourg" a few years ago on cable with a dinosaur CRT television, and even in that format it glowed. I want to buy the disc, but I'm holding out for Blu-Ray. The movie is stunning in every way. I can imagine a couple of female friends sharing a bottle of wine and a box of Kleenex and having a good, purifying cry. It is everything that a filmed romance should be, an amazing sung story of lost love, with a poignant ending that is--depending on your viewpoint--sweetly happy or deliciously sad. If you haven't seen it yet, don't wait--see it now on DVD. Those of us who have already seen it will patiently await the Blu-Ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Under my umbrella (Ella ella eh eh eh)"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Checking a selection of Euro Art-films which my dad had kindly picked up on Video for me,I was pleased to see that one of the movies starred an actress who I had first her about in connection to a 1977 Giallo called Anima Persa.Taking another look at the case for the Catherine Deneuve movie,something about its title "clicked" with me in an odd way.Searching round on IMDb,I quickly got the answer,when I found that the film had been chosen for the IMDb's Indian Cinema board's next joint viewing,which led me to grabbing my umbrella,and getting ready to come face to face with Deneuve for the first time. The plot: Returning home from a wonderful date with the man of her dreams:Roland Cassard,Genevieve Emery is met with the stern face from her mother,who drains all the joy out of Genevieve's cheeks.Ignoring her mum's (who also works with her daughter in an umbrella shop) extremely vocal disagreement's about her "not knowing what real love is",and also that it is "Far too soon to be talking about marriage", Genevieve continues to have fantastic dates with Cassard.Feeling a deeper sense of intimacy with Roland, Genevieve decides to show the passion and intimacy that has grown between herself and Cassard by going to bed with him.Basking in the glow of the tightening of their bond, Genevieve and Cassard's romance is torn in two,due to Roland being drafted for a 2 year tour of duty in the Algerian War.Shortly after Roland leaves for his tour of duty, Genevieve discovers that she is pregnant with Cassard's child.As the months go by, Genevieve starts to fearfully take her mums words to heart,that Roland may possibly never return to her from his tour of duty. View on the film: Using the opening of the movie to have Roland Cassard take the audience into the film's startling Technicolour world,writer/director Jacques Demy teams up with costume designer Jacquline Moreau to smartly contrast the dark troubles facing Roland and Genevieve's families by aw-ashing the film in dazzling,flowing colours,which along with perfectly matching the detailed costume work of Moreau,also creates a lively atmosphere as the couples relationship increases in passion.Along with the shining colours, Demy also uses expertly stylised constantly moving,long tracking shots to show the life is so exciting and fast moving that Genevieve and Roland don't have a change to notice the changing backgrounds,until freezing the camera,to show the harsh,war light of reality hitting the couple's dream.For the screenplay, (all of which is sung!) Demy shows an impressive restrain of not including any fiddly,overly complicated words,but to instead go for something much more brilliantly simplistic,that allows the viewing to be completely caught,in the pure joy of Genevieve and Cassard's dates.With sharing almost every scene with each other for the first half the film, the beautiful Catherine Deneuve and Marc Michel each give splendid performances that perfectly compliment each other,with Deneuve showing Genevieve to have stars in her eyes every time she looks at Cassard,whilst Michel shows Roland to be someone who desperately wants to see the same stars that Genevieve does,but is sadly unable to get away from the harsh reality taking place around them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danatus-jairus
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1. Coloring, that is absolutely matchless 2. Even the first notes of the main theme make you cry 3. Unique way of singing in a musical 4. One of the most touching love stories 5. Beautiful Catherine Deneuve 6. It's not American 7. Made in the sixties 8. You can watch it over and over again 9. Since you've once seen it.. you must watch it over and over again 10. Esso-scene Ten more or less good reasons why this just might be the one.. the favorite movie of mine. I partly understand people who hate it, the singing is the main reason i think. But the unique way of singing! Not in the traditional way this is a musical, people just happen to sing when they talk. And the music (especially main theme) is so hauntingly beautiful it really does make you want to cry when you hear the first notes. The coloring is like in no other film. The clothing and background have been matched in every single scene of the movie. That's real cinema, that's beautiful! And if that's beautiful already, then what comes when the 20-year old Catherine Deneuve is in the lead role! Just WOW! Once again I don't bother explaining any of the plot, because there's no point really...but one of the saddest scenes in movie history, is the Esso-scene in this one. Watch it! if you're not too busy watching the latest Van-Damme.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie hasn't made me shed tears since A.I. until I watched this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joey Lan
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the credits rolled, I sat there with a tear streak still remaining on my face from a minute passed. I was bewildered. Bewildered by how this movie managed to invoke such strong emotion in me. It isn't a particularly sad movie. I'm not a even French movie buff. I'm not sure if I've even seen a French movie before. The movie is set in the small town of Cherbourg, France from 1957 to 1963. The walls are still all brick and mortar, covered with vibrant colors, hand painted on. Young Genevieve (Catherine Deneuve) lives with her protective mother (Anne Vernon) and together they run a quaint Umbrella shop in Cherbourg, France. Genevieve and Guy (Nino Castelnuovo) , a car mechanic at a local garage, are deeply in love and contemplate marriage but they are forced to put everything on hold as Guy (prounounced Gee in Geese) goes to serve his mandatory two years in the French army. Can their love survive the separation while she is being pushed by her mother to marry a rich jewel merchant by the name of Cassard (Marc Michel) in Guy's absence? It is a quintessential love story. Catherine Deneuve is breathtakingly beautiful. The characters are memorable and their personalities distinct. You might find that their relationship interactions a bit funny by modern standards but remember, this is set in the late 50s. Back when it was normal for ladies to lean on their partner's chest and caress his hands lovingly with their face.....while being pet like a cat. Still it added to the charm of the movie. The daintiness of the Genevieve that is, not the petting. The movie breaks down into four acts. After each act the movie fades to black and you are briefed on the next act. If you went and saw this movie upon its release, you went to the theater to watch......theater. One thing to note is that this is a different form of musical. ALL of the dialogue is sung instead of having musical numbers fitted in between spoken dialogue. The only other movie I've ever seen that has all the dialogue sung is "Repo the Genetic Opera". Imagine a gothicized Paris doing a musical number; Enough said. This one's much better. Back to the movie at hand, Michael Legrand could not have composed a more beautiful and fitting orchestral score. I must mention that the score is continuous throughout the whole movie from beginning to end. And it led to a beautiful song covered many great artists. The definitive and most haunting version by Connie Francis; Titled, "I will wait for you". The cinematography translates the charm of Cherbourg to film, wonderfully. The shots are simple and effective. My favorite shot in the movie is that of a departing train. I have seen my share of train scenes but I don't remember seeing it ever done this way. I recommend this movie, unless you despise theater, can't stand orchestral music and refer to French fries as Freedom Fries. I recommend watching it with your significant other (for maximum effect) and staring into their soul after the movie ends. Then put on some Marvin Gaye and get it on while keeping in mind that tomorrow may never come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ageless jazz opera
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film like this makes me think of my own life choices. It starts out like a painting that comes to life, set in the ancient port town of Cherbourg. (I was surprised to read on Wikipedia that a U.S. Civil War battle was fought off its shores.) From the cobblestone streets to the jewel-box storefronts to the grease monkeys at Guy's garage, this film is a joy to behold. And with Michel LeGrand's score, a delight to listen to. As a Francophile, I wish I could find a copy of its script. I enjoyed the crisp simplicity of the entirely sung dialogue. Adding to the satisfying unity of "Parapluies" is its perfect casting. Catherine Deneuve convinces as a rebellious daughter, infatuated teen, and bemused unwed woman with child. Her own mother, played fascinatingly by Anne Vernon, probably experienced the same out-of-wedlock pregnancy as she did. Clearly, Mme. Emery is attracted to M. Cassard, yet her only conscious wish is for the security of her only child. The mother-daughter relationship here is one of almost-total miscomprehension. Cassard (a dapper Marc Michel) is interesting to watch as the wealthy, somewhat bloodless suitor who actually travels with a crown, ready-made to place on his lady love's head! Nino Castelnuovo is superb as Guy, along with Ellen Farner as Madeleine. I enjoyed the range that Castelnuovo demonstrated, going from carefree lover to read-to-serve draftee, to depressed and acting-out Algerian War vet. The conversation between Guy and Madeleine, prior to marriage, is one of stunningly convincing depth, though its words are few. Of course, the final scene of this film unforgettable. I've seen "Parapluies" no fewer than five times and this viewing I cried perhaps more than ever, due to evermore bittersweet experience of my own under my belt. This must be one of those movies that never grows old. Its haunting melodies soothe and inspire me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Umbrellas of Cherbourg
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I read the title for this film in the book of 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die I knew it was a foreign film, from France, but I had no idea it was a musical, so I was most intrigued to watch, from director Jacques Demy (Lola, The Young Girls of Rochefort). Basically seventeen year old Genevi&egrave;ve Emery (Catherine Deneuve) lives in an umbrella shop in Cherbourg with her widowed mother Madame Emery (Anne Vernon), and she is secretly in love with twenty year old auto mechanic Guy Foucher (Nino Castelnuovo), and the two of them want to get married. She reveals this to her mother however, and she objects thinking that her daughter is too young and that he is not mature and well-established enough, and he may be required to do military service, and shortly later he is sent to Algeria after being drafted to serve in the war, but before leaving he and Genevi&egrave;ve consummate their love. Following this Genevi&egrave;ve is pregnant, while he is away he hardly communicates and they have drifted apart, so she listens to her mother's strong encouragement to accept a marriage proposal from Roland Cassard (Marc Michel) (he previously appeared as the same character in the film Lola), the affluent gem dealer who is in love with her and promises to bring her child up as his own. Guy is discharged from service before his two year term is up due to being wounded, he returns home and finds out Genevi&egrave;ve is married with a child and has moved away, and following this he sinks into deep depression and anger, which he struggles to control. But Guy recovers from his state when he falls in love and married young Madeleine (Ellen Farner) who had been caring for his aunt &Eacute;lise (Mireille Perrey), who is now deceased, and she left him an inheritance which he uses to fulfil his ambition to open a service station. Years pass, and Genevi&egrave;ve, who is now discernibly wealthy, has returned home with Fran&ccedil;oise (Rosalie Varda), her and Guy's daughter, and have an accidental meeting at his service station, their short conversation is obviously filled with unuttered fondness and regret, and in the end they finally part ways. Also starring Jean Champion as Aubin and Harald Wolff as Monsieur Dubourg. Deneuve is beautiful and gives a great delicate performance as the young woman longing for love from one man until fate changes everything, Castelnuovo is interesting as the man who is in and out of her life, and Michel is likable as the wealthy man with good intentions. The story is relatively simple, complicated romance, but what makes this musically distinctive is that every scene has singing, from the most mundane conversations to emotionally charging moments every word is spoken and sun in tune, and the picture has good use of vivid colour and design as well, it is a fantastic musical. It was nominated the Oscar for Best Song for "I Will Wait for You", Best Original Music for Michel Legrand and Jacques Demy, Best Music Adaptation or Treatment for Michel Legrand, Best Writing, Story and Screenplay - Written Directly for the Screen for Demy and Best Foreign Language Film, and it was nominated the Golden Globe for Best Foreign-Language Foreign Film. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A musical that compares the expectations of love with the harsh realities. The heart sings and breaks.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Umbrellas of Cherbourg is a unique film experiment. It's a musical where every line is sung. Even the mundane lines which have little to do with the film. While this style could be expected to be under threat of being too sweet, the film avoids this by approaching sentimentality with heart-wrenching reality, which the musical aspect of the film highlights. It's a love story. And the film is aware that it begins as a movie love story, addressed by the fact that the protagonist genuinely expects to die if they are parted. Instead of dying, the film explores one of my favourite deep subjects in art, by comparing the expectations of love brought on by pop culture with the harsh reality without being overdramatic. It's nostalgic and extremely genuine. As expected, the omnipresent music is absolutely wonderful and can speak for the film's emotion even without translation. How they managed to fit in the dialogue so fluently is incredible, let alone perform it. The set decoration and costume design is another highlight as well, with bright and bold colours, which the sweeping camera movement compliments perfectly. Despite the broad story, the film is surprisingly small scale with a limited use of sets, but the colour palette makes the world feel huge. There's some incredible use of match cuts as well. Though this film has a fantastic and charming atmosphere, it's the simple and effective storytelling that makes it, particularly the heartbreaking and subtle end. Bona fide classic. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    115 reviews so far...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Traversa
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... and they condense every possible information and observation one can make about this awesome movie. I will see it again out of an intense curiosity and nostalgia (I saw it many years ago and left me flabbergasted --patidifuso-- with all its fantastic beauty) after having listened the radio program I mention further down. I write these lines not to review one more time the film, but just to comment that I was listening a radio program from France Culture radio and they made a reportage about Cherbourg, where this movie was shot FIFTY YEARS AGO... and they are celebrating that anniversary in Cherbourg pulling out all the stops. It seems that the filming on that location 50 years ago was a big happening for this small and quiet coal town, apparently very dirty and facing away from the waterfront (now they have changed that concept and all new buildings are facing the waters) since then the huge popularity of this movie worldwide was such a ground shaking event for the inhabitants that they became aware of their own ignored potential and started to change everything, renovating shops and cleaning the city, to such an extent that nowadays the place is unrecognizable from its past dreary image. Japanese tourist go there to visit the umbrella shop where part of the action takes place (still looking and functioning like then) and even French people go there to visit the shop and take pictures!! During these fifty years Catherine Deneuve appeared in 117 films, leaving behind an enormous quantity of documentation to her legendary ice blonde beauty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Sweet Film."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manendra-lodhi (manendra.lodhi@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art cannot be for someone who fears. The director's approach fits in this quote. When I learned (before seeing the film) that it was a musical, I expected a rip off of the sound of Music. But when I started watching, everything started to look weird. All the dialogs in the film are in a musical way. You start to feel funny and irritated at the same time. The story is a very general, so do not expect much from it. It is just one normal love story that has a neutral ending with a good message. But what makes the film a must watch is its colorful cinematography. If for the first few minutes you are feeling irritated because of the musical dialogs then just wait some more and you will find yourself completely immersed in the film. After a time the dialogs, with music and everything look so normal that even such a predictable story can make you feel happy. It needed a lot of faith to make a film like this. The director has given a beautiful film which is definitely going to make you feel lighter. The most charming thing of the film is that none of the characters is shown as evil. It is the circumstances that are acting here as the obstacles. The film made me remember the films of Ghibli studios by Hayao Miyazaki. The film won the Palme d or in its time. But this is not the reason why you should be watching this, but that it is very much watchable in its own weird way. MESSAGE: "Life" VERDICT: "A recommended watch."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch it for the music, the colors, the story, and for the diving Ms. Deneuve
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    info-2752
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always associated my favorite musicals with Broadway, apart from this one, which is up there with my top three favorites. Filed as a love story, it also makes my top three. And Catherine Deneuve? She's definitely in my top three most beautiful actresses of all time. Then there's Michel Legrand, my second favorite composer (after Chopin, and if you must know, the third ones would be the Lennon/McCartney collaboration). How does one get so willingly hooked to a movie? Just sample the first five minutes of it, you don't even wait for the first lines of song to realize you're in for a gem of a film. Before you hear any of it, the sets are bound to get you. For the colors, those vibrant, palpable colors are a veritable visual feast. And have I mentioned the divine Catherine Deneuve? If there's anything most likely to distract your attention from the sets, it would be her presence. And last, but not least, for long after you may have forgotten the plot, you will never forget this: that melodious, hummable music, a song most of us associate with having heard from childhood, that beautifully threads the scenes of the story together--and you have the perfect musical. The most poignant love story (reminiscent of Splendor in the Grass, another coming-of-age film with a most genetically- blessed lead actors), with an ending that breaks the heart, but one which I completely approve of!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful--But Where's the Blu-Ray?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    t_k_matthews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most beautiful movies ever made deserves a Blu-Ray release. I first saw "The Umbrellas of Cherbourg" a few years ago on cable with a dinosaur CRT television, and even in that format it glowed. I want to buy the disc, but I'm holding out for Blu-Ray. The movie is stunning in every way. I can imagine a couple of female friends sharing a bottle of wine and a box of Kleenex and having a good, purifying cry. It is everything that a filmed romance should be, an amazing sung story of lost love, with a poignant ending that is--depending on your viewpoint--sweetly happy or deliciously sad. If you haven't seen it yet, don't wait--see it now on DVD. Those of us who have already seen it will patiently await the Blu-Ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Under my umbrella (Ella ella eh eh eh)"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Checking a selection of Euro Art-films which my dad had kindly picked up on Video for me,I was pleased to see that one of the movies starred an actress who I had first her about in connection to a 1977 Giallo called Anima Persa.Taking another look at the case for the Catherine Deneuve movie,something about its title "clicked" with me in an odd way.Searching round on IMDb,I quickly got the answer,when I found that the film had been chosen for the IMDb's Indian Cinema board's next joint viewing,which led me to grabbing my umbrella,and getting ready to come face to face with Deneuve for the first time. The plot: Returning home from a wonderful date with the man of her dreams:Roland Cassard,Genevieve Emery is met with the stern face from her mother,who drains all the joy out of Genevieve's cheeks.Ignoring her mum's (who also works with her daughter in an umbrella shop) extremely vocal disagreement's about her "not knowing what real love is",and also that it is "Far too soon to be talking about marriage", Genevieve continues to have fantastic dates with Cassard.Feeling a deeper sense of intimacy with Roland, Genevieve decides to show the passion and intimacy that has grown between herself and Cassard by going to bed with him.Basking in the glow of the tightening of their bond, Genevieve and Cassard's romance is torn in two,due to Roland being drafted for a 2 year tour of duty in the Algerian War.Shortly after Roland leaves for his tour of duty, Genevieve discovers that she is pregnant with Cassard's child.As the months go by, Genevieve starts to fearfully take her mums words to heart,that Roland may possibly never return to her from his tour of duty. View on the film: Using the opening of the movie to have Roland Cassard take the audience into the film's startling Technicolour world,writer/director Jacques Demy teams up with costume designer Jacquline Moreau to smartly contrast the dark troubles facing Roland and Genevieve's families by aw-ashing the film in dazzling,flowing colours,which along with perfectly matching the detailed costume work of Moreau,also creates a lively atmosphere as the couples relationship increases in passion.Along with the shining colours, Demy also uses expertly stylised constantly moving,long tracking shots to show the life is so exciting and fast moving that Genevieve and Roland don't have a change to notice the changing backgrounds,until freezing the camera,to show the harsh,war light of reality hitting the couple's dream.For the screenplay, (all of which is sung!) Demy shows an impressive restrain of not including any fiddly,overly complicated words,but to instead go for something much more brilliantly simplistic,that allows the viewing to be completely caught,in the pure joy of Genevieve and Cassard's dates.With sharing almost every scene with each other for the first half the film, the beautiful Catherine Deneuve and Marc Michel each give splendid performances that perfectly compliment each other,with Deneuve showing Genevieve to have stars in her eyes every time she looks at Cassard,whilst Michel shows Roland to be someone who desperately wants to see the same stars that Genevieve does,but is sadly unable to get away from the harsh reality taking place around them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danatus-jairus
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1. Coloring, that is absolutely matchless 2. Even the first notes of the main theme make you cry 3. Unique way of singing in a musical 4. One of the most touching love stories 5. Beautiful Catherine Deneuve 6. It's not American 7. Made in the sixties 8. You can watch it over and over again 9. Since you've once seen it.. you must watch it over and over again 10. Esso-scene Ten more or less good reasons why this just might be the one.. the favorite movie of mine. I partly understand people who hate it, the singing is the main reason i think. But the unique way of singing! Not in the traditional way this is a musical, people just happen to sing when they talk. And the music (especially main theme) is so hauntingly beautiful it really does make you want to cry when you hear the first notes. The coloring is like in no other film. The clothing and background have been matched in every single scene of the movie. That's real cinema, that's beautiful! And if that's beautiful already, then what comes when the 20-year old Catherine Deneuve is in the lead role! Just WOW! Once again I don't bother explaining any of the plot, because there's no point really...but one of the saddest scenes in movie history, is the Esso-scene in this one. Watch it! if you're not too busy watching the latest Van-Damme.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie hasn't made me shed tears since A.I. until I watched this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joey Lan
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the credits rolled, I sat there with a tear streak still remaining on my face from a minute passed. I was bewildered. Bewildered by how this movie managed to invoke such strong emotion in me. It isn't a particularly sad movie. I'm not a even French movie buff. I'm not sure if I've even seen a French movie before. The movie is set in the small town of Cherbourg, France from 1957 to 1963. The walls are still all brick and mortar, covered with vibrant colors, hand painted on. Young Genevieve (Catherine Deneuve) lives with her protective mother (Anne Vernon) and together they run a quaint Umbrella shop in Cherbourg, France. Genevieve and Guy (Nino Castelnuovo) , a car mechanic at a local garage, are deeply in love and contemplate marriage but they are forced to put everything on hold as Guy (prounounced Gee in Geese) goes to serve his mandatory two years in the French army. Can their love survive the separation while she is being pushed by her mother to marry a rich jewel merchant by the name of Cassard (Marc Michel) in Guy's absence? It is a quintessential love story. Catherine Deneuve is breathtakingly beautiful. The characters are memorable and their personalities distinct. You might find that their relationship interactions a bit funny by modern standards but remember, this is set in the late 50s. Back when it was normal for ladies to lean on their partner's chest and caress his hands lovingly with their face.....while being pet like a cat. Still it added to the charm of the movie. The daintiness of the Genevieve that is, not the petting. The movie breaks down into four acts. After each act the movie fades to black and you are briefed on the next act. If you went and saw this movie upon its release, you went to the theater to watch......theater. One thing to note is that this is a different form of musical. ALL of the dialogue is sung instead of having musical numbers fitted in between spoken dialogue. The only other movie I've ever seen that has all the dialogue sung is "Repo the Genetic Opera". Imagine a gothicized Paris doing a musical number; Enough said. This one's much better. Back to the movie at hand, Michael Legrand could not have composed a more beautiful and fitting orchestral score. I must mention that the score is continuous throughout the whole movie from beginning to end. And it led to a beautiful song covered many great artists. The definitive and most haunting version by Connie Francis; Titled, "I will wait for you". The cinematography translates the charm of Cherbourg to film, wonderfully. The shots are simple and effective. My favorite shot in the movie is that of a departing train. I have seen my share of train scenes but I don't remember seeing it ever done this way. I recommend this movie, unless you despise theater, can't stand orchestral music and refer to French fries as Freedom Fries. I recommend watching it with your significant other (for maximum effect) and staring into their soul after the movie ends. Then put on some Marvin Gaye and get it on while keeping in mind that tomorrow may never come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ageless jazz opera
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film like this makes me think of my own life choices. It starts out like a painting that comes to life, set in the ancient port town of Cherbourg. (I was surprised to read on Wikipedia that a U.S. Civil War battle was fought off its shores.) From the cobblestone streets to the jewel-box storefronts to the grease monkeys at Guy's garage, this film is a joy to behold. And with Michel LeGrand's score, a delight to listen to. As a Francophile, I wish I could find a copy of its script. I enjoyed the crisp simplicity of the entirely sung dialogue. Adding to the satisfying unity of "Parapluies" is its perfect casting. Catherine Deneuve convinces as a rebellious daughter, infatuated teen, and bemused unwed woman with child. Her own mother, played fascinatingly by Anne Vernon, probably experienced the same out-of-wedlock pregnancy as she did. Clearly, Mme. Emery is attracted to M. Cassard, yet her only conscious wish is for the security of her only child. The mother-daughter relationship here is one of almost-total miscomprehension. Cassard (a dapper Marc Michel) is interesting to watch as the wealthy, somewhat bloodless suitor who actually travels with a crown, ready-made to place on his lady love's head! Nino Castelnuovo is superb as Guy, along with Ellen Farner as Madeleine. I enjoyed the range that Castelnuovo demonstrated, going from carefree lover to read-to-serve draftee, to depressed and acting-out Algerian War vet. The conversation between Guy and Madeleine, prior to marriage, is one of stunningly convincing depth, though its words are few. Of course, the final scene of this film unforgettable. I've seen "Parapluies" no fewer than five times and this viewing I cried perhaps more than ever, due to evermore bittersweet experience of my own under my belt. This must be one of those movies that never grows old. Its haunting melodies soothe and inspire me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Umbrellas of Cherbourg
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I read the title for this film in the book of 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die I knew it was a foreign film, from France, but I had no idea it was a musical, so I was most intrigued to watch, from director Jacques Demy (Lola, The Young Girls of Rochefort). Basically seventeen year old Genevi&egrave;ve Emery (Catherine Deneuve) lives in an umbrella shop in Cherbourg with her widowed mother Madame Emery (Anne Vernon), and she is secretly in love with twenty year old auto mechanic Guy Foucher (Nino Castelnuovo), and the two of them want to get married. She reveals this to her mother however, and she objects thinking that her daughter is too young and that he is not mature and well-established enough, and he may be required to do military service, and shortly later he is sent to Algeria after being drafted to serve in the war, but before leaving he and Genevi&egrave;ve consummate their love. Following this Genevi&egrave;ve is pregnant, while he is away he hardly communicates and they have drifted apart, so she listens to her mother's strong encouragement to accept a marriage proposal from Roland Cassard (Marc Michel) (he previously appeared as the same character in the film Lola), the affluent gem dealer who is in love with her and promises to bring her child up as his own. Guy is discharged from service before his two year term is up due to being wounded, he returns home and finds out Genevi&egrave;ve is married with a child and has moved away, and following this he sinks into deep depression and anger, which he struggles to control. But Guy recovers from his state when he falls in love and married young Madeleine (Ellen Farner) who had been caring for his aunt &Eacute;lise (Mireille Perrey), who is now deceased, and she left him an inheritance which he uses to fulfil his ambition to open a service station. Years pass, and Genevi&egrave;ve, who is now discernibly wealthy, has returned home with Fran&ccedil;oise (Rosalie Varda), her and Guy's daughter, and have an accidental meeting at his service station, their short conversation is obviously filled with unuttered fondness and regret, and in the end they finally part ways. Also starring Jean Champion as Aubin and Harald Wolff as Monsieur Dubourg. Deneuve is beautiful and gives a great delicate performance as the young woman longing for love from one man until fate changes everything, Castelnuovo is interesting as the man who is in and out of her life, and Michel is likable as the wealthy man with good intentions. The story is relatively simple, complicated romance, but what makes this musically distinctive is that every scene has singing, from the most mundane conversations to emotionally charging moments every word is spoken and sun in tune, and the picture has good use of vivid colour and design as well, it is a fantastic musical. It was nominated the Oscar for Best Song for "I Will Wait for You", Best Original Music for Michel Legrand and Jacques Demy, Best Music Adaptation or Treatment for Michel Legrand, Best Writing, Story and Screenplay - Written Directly for the Screen for Demy and Best Foreign Language Film, and it was nominated the Golden Globe for Best Foreign-Language Foreign Film. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A musical that compares the expectations of love with the harsh realities. The heart sings and breaks.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Umbrellas of Cherbourg is a unique film experiment. It's a musical where every line is sung. Even the mundane lines which have little to do with the film. While this style could be expected to be under threat of being too sweet, the film avoids this by approaching sentimentality with heart-wrenching reality, which the musical aspect of the film highlights. It's a love story. And the film is aware that it begins as a movie love story, addressed by the fact that the protagonist genuinely expects to die if they are parted. Instead of dying, the film explores one of my favourite deep subjects in art, by comparing the expectations of love brought on by pop culture with the harsh reality without being overdramatic. It's nostalgic and extremely genuine. As expected, the omnipresent music is absolutely wonderful and can speak for the film's emotion even without translation. How they managed to fit in the dialogue so fluently is incredible, let alone perform it. The set decoration and costume design is another highlight as well, with bright and bold colours, which the sweeping camera movement compliments perfectly. Despite the broad story, the film is surprisingly small scale with a limited use of sets, but the colour palette makes the world feel huge. There's some incredible use of match cuts as well. Though this film has a fantastic and charming atmosphere, it's the simple and effective storytelling that makes it, particularly the heartbreaking and subtle end. Bona fide classic. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    115 reviews so far...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Traversa
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... and they condense every possible information and observation one can make about this awesome movie. I will see it again out of an intense curiosity and nostalgia (I saw it many years ago and left me flabbergasted --patidifuso-- with all its fantastic beauty) after having listened the radio program I mention further down. I write these lines not to review one more time the film, but just to comment that I was listening a radio program from France Culture radio and they made a reportage about Cherbourg, where this movie was shot FIFTY YEARS AGO... and they are celebrating that anniversary in Cherbourg pulling out all the stops. It seems that the filming on that location 50 years ago was a big happening for this small and quiet coal town, apparently very dirty and facing away from the waterfront (now they have changed that concept and all new buildings are facing the waters) since then the huge popularity of this movie worldwide was such a ground shaking event for the inhabitants that they became aware of their own ignored potential and started to change everything, renovating shops and cleaning the city, to such an extent that nowadays the place is unrecognizable from its past dreary image. Japanese tourist go there to visit the umbrella shop where part of the action takes place (still looking and functioning like then) and even French people go there to visit the shop and take pictures!! During these fifty years Catherine Deneuve appeared in 117 films, leaving behind an enormous quantity of documentation to her legendary ice blonde beauty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Sweet Film."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manendra-lodhi (manendra.lodhi@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art cannot be for someone who fears. The director's approach fits in this quote. When I learned (before seeing the film) that it was a musical, I expected a rip off of the sound of Music. But when I started watching, everything started to look weird. All the dialogs in the film are in a musical way. You start to feel funny and irritated at the same time. The story is a very general, so do not expect much from it. It is just one normal love story that has a neutral ending with a good message. But what makes the film a must watch is its colorful cinematography. If for the first few minutes you are feeling irritated because of the musical dialogs then just wait some more and you will find yourself completely immersed in the film. After a time the dialogs, with music and everything look so normal that even such a predictable story can make you feel happy. It needed a lot of faith to make a film like this. The director has given a beautiful film which is definitely going to make you feel lighter. The most charming thing of the film is that none of the characters is shown as evil. It is the circumstances that are acting here as the obstacles. The film made me remember the films of Ghibli studios by Hayao Miyazaki. The film won the Palme d or in its time. But this is not the reason why you should be watching this, but that it is very much watchable in its own weird way. MESSAGE: "Life" VERDICT: "A recommended watch."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch it for the music, the colors, the story, and for the diving Ms. Deneuve
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    info-2752
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always associated my favorite musicals with Broadway, apart from this one, which is up there with my top three favorites. Filed as a love story, it also makes my top three. And Catherine Deneuve? She's definitely in my top three most beautiful actresses of all time. Then there's Michel Legrand, my second favorite composer (after Chopin, and if you must know, the third ones would be the Lennon/McCartney collaboration). How does one get so willingly hooked to a movie? Just sample the first five minutes of it, you don't even wait for the first lines of song to realize you're in for a gem of a film. Before you hear any of it, the sets are bound to get you. For the colors, those vibrant, palpable colors are a veritable visual feast. And have I mentioned the divine Catherine Deneuve? If there's anything most likely to distract your attention from the sets, it would be her presence. And last, but not least, for long after you may have forgotten the plot, you will never forget this: that melodious, hummable music, a song most of us associate with having heard from childhood, that beautifully threads the scenes of the story together--and you have the perfect musical. The most poignant love story (reminiscent of Splendor in the Grass, another coming-of-age film with a most genetically- blessed lead actors), with an ending that breaks the heart, but one which I completely approve of!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful--But Where's the Blu-Ray?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    t_k_matthews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most beautiful movies ever made deserves a Blu-Ray release. I first saw "The Umbrellas of Cherbourg" a few years ago on cable with a dinosaur CRT television, and even in that format it glowed. I want to buy the disc, but I'm holding out for Blu-Ray. The movie is stunning in every way. I can imagine a couple of female friends sharing a bottle of wine and a box of Kleenex and having a good, purifying cry. It is everything that a filmed romance should be, an amazing sung story of lost love, with a poignant ending that is--depending on your viewpoint--sweetly happy or deliciously sad. If you haven't seen it yet, don't wait--see it now on DVD. Those of us who have already seen it will patiently await the Blu-Ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Under my umbrella (Ella ella eh eh eh)"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Checking a selection of Euro Art-films which my dad had kindly picked up on Video for me,I was pleased to see that one of the movies starred an actress who I had first her about in connection to a 1977 Giallo called Anima Persa.Taking another look at the case for the Catherine Deneuve movie,something about its title "clicked" with me in an odd way.Searching round on IMDb,I quickly got the answer,when I found that the film had been chosen for the IMDb's Indian Cinema board's next joint viewing,which led me to grabbing my umbrella,and getting ready to come face to face with Deneuve for the first time. The plot: Returning home from a wonderful date with the man of her dreams:Roland Cassard,Genevieve Emery is met with the stern face from her mother,who drains all the joy out of Genevieve's cheeks.Ignoring her mum's (who also works with her daughter in an umbrella shop) extremely vocal disagreement's about her "not knowing what real love is",and also that it is "Far too soon to be talking about marriage", Genevieve continues to have fantastic dates with Cassard.Feeling a deeper sense of intimacy with Roland, Genevieve decides to show the passion and intimacy that has grown between herself and Cassard by going to bed with him.Basking in the glow of the tightening of their bond, Genevieve and Cassard's romance is torn in two,due to Roland being drafted for a 2 year tour of duty in the Algerian War.Shortly after Roland leaves for his tour of duty, Genevieve discovers that she is pregnant with Cassard's child.As the months go by, Genevieve starts to fearfully take her mums words to heart,that Roland may possibly never return to her from his tour of duty. View on the film: Using the opening of the movie to have Roland Cassard take the audience into the film's startling Technicolour world,writer/director Jacques Demy teams up with costume designer Jacquline Moreau to smartly contrast the dark troubles facing Roland and Genevieve's families by aw-ashing the film in dazzling,flowing colours,which along with perfectly matching the detailed costume work of Moreau,also creates a lively atmosphere as the couples relationship increases in passion.Along with the shining colours, Demy also uses expertly stylised constantly moving,long tracking shots to show the life is so exciting and fast moving that Genevieve and Roland don't have a change to notice the changing backgrounds,until freezing the camera,to show the harsh,war light of reality hitting the couple's dream.For the screenplay, (all of which is sung!) Demy shows an impressive restrain of not including any fiddly,overly complicated words,but to instead go for something much more brilliantly simplistic,that allows the viewing to be completely caught,in the pure joy of Genevieve and Cassard's dates.With sharing almost every scene with each other for the first half the film, the beautiful Catherine Deneuve and Marc Michel each give splendid performances that perfectly compliment each other,with Deneuve showing Genevieve to have stars in her eyes every time she looks at Cassard,whilst Michel shows Roland to be someone who desperately wants to see the same stars that Genevieve does,but is sadly unable to get away from the harsh reality taking place around them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danatus-jairus
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1. Coloring, that is absolutely matchless 2. Even the first notes of the main theme make you cry 3. Unique way of singing in a musical 4. One of the most touching love stories 5. Beautiful Catherine Deneuve 6. It's not American 7. Made in the sixties 8. You can watch it over and over again 9. Since you've once seen it.. you must watch it over and over again 10. Esso-scene Ten more or less good reasons why this just might be the one.. the favorite movie of mine. I partly understand people who hate it, the singing is the main reason i think. But the unique way of singing! Not in the traditional way this is a musical, people just happen to sing when they talk. And the music (especially main theme) is so hauntingly beautiful it really does make you want to cry when you hear the first notes. The coloring is like in no other film. The clothing and background have been matched in every single scene of the movie. That's real cinema, that's beautiful! And if that's beautiful already, then what comes when the 20-year old Catherine Deneuve is in the lead role! Just WOW! Once again I don't bother explaining any of the plot, because there's no point really...but one of the saddest scenes in movie history, is the Esso-scene in this one. Watch it! if you're not too busy watching the latest Van-Damme.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie hasn't made me shed tears since A.I. until I watched this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joey Lan
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the credits rolled, I sat there with a tear streak still remaining on my face from a minute passed. I was bewildered. Bewildered by how this movie managed to invoke such strong emotion in me. It isn't a particularly sad movie. I'm not a even French movie buff. I'm not sure if I've even seen a French movie before. The movie is set in the small town of Cherbourg, France from 1957 to 1963. The walls are still all brick and mortar, covered with vibrant colors, hand painted on. Young Genevieve (Catherine Deneuve) lives with her protective mother (Anne Vernon) and together they run a quaint Umbrella shop in Cherbourg, France. Genevieve and Guy (Nino Castelnuovo) , a car mechanic at a local garage, are deeply in love and contemplate marriage but they are forced to put everything on hold as Guy (prounounced Gee in Geese) goes to serve his mandatory two years in the French army. Can their love survive the separation while she is being pushed by her mother to marry a rich jewel merchant by the name of Cassard (Marc Michel) in Guy's absence? It is a quintessential love story. Catherine Deneuve is breathtakingly beautiful. The characters are memorable and their personalities distinct. You might find that their relationship interactions a bit funny by modern standards but remember, this is set in the late 50s. Back when it was normal for ladies to lean on their partner's chest and caress his hands lovingly with their face.....while being pet like a cat. Still it added to the charm of the movie. The daintiness of the Genevieve that is, not the petting. The movie breaks down into four acts. After each act the movie fades to black and you are briefed on the next act. If you went and saw this movie upon its release, you went to the theater to watch......theater. One thing to note is that this is a different form of musical. ALL of the dialogue is sung instead of having musical numbers fitted in between spoken dialogue. The only other movie I've ever seen that has all the dialogue sung is "Repo the Genetic Opera". Imagine a gothicized Paris doing a musical number; Enough said. This one's much better. Back to the movie at hand, Michael Legrand could not have composed a more beautiful and fitting orchestral score. I must mention that the score is continuous throughout the whole movie from beginning to end. And it led to a beautiful song covered many great artists. The definitive and most haunting version by Connie Francis; Titled, "I will wait for you". The cinematography translates the charm of Cherbourg to film, wonderfully. The shots are simple and effective. My favorite shot in the movie is that of a departing train. I have seen my share of train scenes but I don't remember seeing it ever done this way. I recommend this movie, unless you despise theater, can't stand orchestral music and refer to French fries as Freedom Fries. I recommend watching it with your significant other (for maximum effect) and staring into their soul after the movie ends. Then put on some Marvin Gaye and get it on while keeping in mind that tomorrow may never come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ageless jazz opera
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film like this makes me think of my own life choices. It starts out like a painting that comes to life, set in the ancient port town of Cherbourg. (I was surprised to read on Wikipedia that a U.S. Civil War battle was fought off its shores.) From the cobblestone streets to the jewel-box storefronts to the grease monkeys at Guy's garage, this film is a joy to behold. And with Michel LeGrand's score, a delight to listen to. As a Francophile, I wish I could find a copy of its script. I enjoyed the crisp simplicity of the entirely sung dialogue. Adding to the satisfying unity of "Parapluies" is its perfect casting. Catherine Deneuve convinces as a rebellious daughter, infatuated teen, and bemused unwed woman with child. Her own mother, played fascinatingly by Anne Vernon, probably experienced the same out-of-wedlock pregnancy as she did. Clearly, Mme. Emery is attracted to M. Cassard, yet her only conscious wish is for the security of her only child. The mother-daughter relationship here is one of almost-total miscomprehension. Cassard (a dapper Marc Michel) is interesting to watch as the wealthy, somewhat bloodless suitor who actually travels with a crown, ready-made to place on his lady love's head! Nino Castelnuovo is superb as Guy, along with Ellen Farner as Madeleine. I enjoyed the range that Castelnuovo demonstrated, going from carefree lover to read-to-serve draftee, to depressed and acting-out Algerian War vet. The conversation between Guy and Madeleine, prior to marriage, is one of stunningly convincing depth, though its words are few. Of course, the final scene of this film unforgettable. I've seen "Parapluies" no fewer than five times and this viewing I cried perhaps more than ever, due to evermore bittersweet experience of my own under my belt. This must be one of those movies that never grows old. Its haunting melodies soothe and inspire me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Umbrellas of Cherbourg
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I read the title for this film in the book of 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die I knew it was a foreign film, from France, but I had no idea it was a musical, so I was most intrigued to watch, from director Jacques Demy (Lola, The Young Girls of Rochefort). Basically seventeen year old Genevi&egrave;ve Emery (Catherine Deneuve) lives in an umbrella shop in Cherbourg with her widowed mother Madame Emery (Anne Vernon), and she is secretly in love with twenty year old auto mechanic Guy Foucher (Nino Castelnuovo), and the two of them want to get married. She reveals this to her mother however, and she objects thinking that her daughter is too young and that he is not mature and well-established enough, and he may be required to do military service, and shortly later he is sent to Algeria after being drafted to serve in the war, but before leaving he and Genevi&egrave;ve consummate their love. Following this Genevi&egrave;ve is pregnant, while he is away he hardly communicates and they have drifted apart, so she listens to her mother's strong encouragement to accept a marriage proposal from Roland Cassard (Marc Michel) (he previously appeared as the same character in the film Lola), the affluent gem dealer who is in love with her and promises to bring her child up as his own. Guy is discharged from service before his two year term is up due to being wounded, he returns home and finds out Genevi&egrave;ve is married with a child and has moved away, and following this he sinks into deep depression and anger, which he struggles to control. But Guy recovers from his state when he falls in love and married young Madeleine (Ellen Farner) who had been caring for his aunt &Eacute;lise (Mireille Perrey), who is now deceased, and she left him an inheritance which he uses to fulfil his ambition to open a service station. Years pass, and Genevi&egrave;ve, who is now discernibly wealthy, has returned home with Fran&ccedil;oise (Rosalie Varda), her and Guy's daughter, and have an accidental meeting at his service station, their short conversation is obviously filled with unuttered fondness and regret, and in the end they finally part ways. Also starring Jean Champion as Aubin and Harald Wolff as Monsieur Dubourg. Deneuve is beautiful and gives a great delicate performance as the young woman longing for love from one man until fate changes everything, Castelnuovo is interesting as the man who is in and out of her life, and Michel is likable as the wealthy man with good intentions. The story is relatively simple, complicated romance, but what makes this musically distinctive is that every scene has singing, from the most mundane conversations to emotionally charging moments every word is spoken and sun in tune, and the picture has good use of vivid colour and design as well, it is a fantastic musical. It was nominated the Oscar for Best Song for "I Will Wait for You", Best Original Music for Michel Legrand and Jacques Demy, Best Music Adaptation or Treatment for Michel Legrand, Best Writing, Story and Screenplay - Written Directly for the Screen for Demy and Best Foreign Language Film, and it was nominated the Golden Globe for Best Foreign-Language Foreign Film. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A musical that compares the expectations of love with the harsh realities. The heart sings and breaks.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Umbrellas of Cherbourg is a unique film experiment. It's a musical where every line is sung. Even the mundane lines which have little to do with the film. While this style could be expected to be under threat of being too sweet, the film avoids this by approaching sentimentality with heart-wrenching reality, which the musical aspect of the film highlights. It's a love story. And the film is aware that it begins as a movie love story, addressed by the fact that the protagonist genuinely expects to die if they are parted. Instead of dying, the film explores one of my favourite deep subjects in art, by comparing the expectations of love brought on by pop culture with the harsh reality without being overdramatic. It's nostalgic and extremely genuine. As expected, the omnipresent music is absolutely wonderful and can speak for the film's emotion even without translation. How they managed to fit in the dialogue so fluently is incredible, let alone perform it. The set decoration and costume design is another highlight as well, with bright and bold colours, which the sweeping camera movement compliments perfectly. Despite the broad story, the film is surprisingly small scale with a limited use of sets, but the colour palette makes the world feel huge. There's some incredible use of match cuts as well. Though this film has a fantastic and charming atmosphere, it's the simple and effective storytelling that makes it, particularly the heartbreaking and subtle end. Bona fide classic. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    115 reviews so far...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Traversa
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... and they condense every possible information and observation one can make about this awesome movie. I will see it again out of an intense curiosity and nostalgia (I saw it many years ago and left me flabbergasted --patidifuso-- with all its fantastic beauty) after having listened the radio program I mention further down. I write these lines not to review one more time the film, but just to comment that I was listening a radio program from France Culture radio and they made a reportage about Cherbourg, where this movie was shot FIFTY YEARS AGO... and they are celebrating that anniversary in Cherbourg pulling out all the stops. It seems that the filming on that location 50 years ago was a big happening for this small and quiet coal town, apparently very dirty and facing away from the waterfront (now they have changed that concept and all new buildings are facing the waters) since then the huge popularity of this movie worldwide was such a ground shaking event for the inhabitants that they became aware of their own ignored potential and started to change everything, renovating shops and cleaning the city, to such an extent that nowadays the place is unrecognizable from its past dreary image. Japanese tourist go there to visit the umbrella shop where part of the action takes place (still looking and functioning like then) and even French people go there to visit the shop and take pictures!! During these fifty years Catherine Deneuve appeared in 117 films, leaving behind an enormous quantity of documentation to her legendary ice blonde beauty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Sweet Film."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manendra-lodhi (manendra.lodhi@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art cannot be for someone who fears. The director's approach fits in this quote. When I learned (before seeing the film) that it was a musical, I expected a rip off of the sound of Music. But when I started watching, everything started to look weird. All the dialogs in the film are in a musical way. You start to feel funny and irritated at the same time. The story is a very general, so do not expect much from it. It is just one normal love story that has a neutral ending with a good message. But what makes the film a must watch is its colorful cinematography. If for the first few minutes you are feeling irritated because of the musical dialogs then just wait some more and you will find yourself completely immersed in the film. After a time the dialogs, with music and everything look so normal that even such a predictable story can make you feel happy. It needed a lot of faith to make a film like this. The director has given a beautiful film which is definitely going to make you feel lighter. The most charming thing of the film is that none of the characters is shown as evil. It is the circumstances that are acting here as the obstacles. The film made me remember the films of Ghibli studios by Hayao Miyazaki. The film won the Palme d or in its time. But this is not the reason why you should be watching this, but that it is very much watchable in its own weird way. MESSAGE: "Life" VERDICT: "A recommended watch."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch it for the music, the colors, the story, and for the diving Ms. Deneuve
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    info-2752
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always associated my favorite musicals with Broadway, apart from this one, which is up there with my top three favorites. Filed as a love story, it also makes my top three. And Catherine Deneuve? She's definitely in my top three most beautiful actresses of all time. Then there's Michel Legrand, my second favorite composer (after Chopin, and if you must know, the third ones would be the Lennon/McCartney collaboration). How does one get so willingly hooked to a movie? Just sample the first five minutes of it, you don't even wait for the first lines of song to realize you're in for a gem of a film. Before you hear any of it, the sets are bound to get you. For the colors, those vibrant, palpable colors are a veritable visual feast. And have I mentioned the divine Catherine Deneuve? If there's anything most likely to distract your attention from the sets, it would be her presence. And last, but not least, for long after you may have forgotten the plot, you will never forget this: that melodious, hummable music, a song most of us associate with having heard from childhood, that beautifully threads the scenes of the story together--and you have the perfect musical. The most poignant love story (reminiscent of Splendor in the Grass, another coming-of-age film with a most genetically- blessed lead actors), with an ending that breaks the heart, but one which I completely approve of!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful--But Where's the Blu-Ray?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    t_k_matthews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most beautiful movies ever made deserves a Blu-Ray release. I first saw "The Umbrellas of Cherbourg" a few years ago on cable with a dinosaur CRT television, and even in that format it glowed. I want to buy the disc, but I'm holding out for Blu-Ray. The movie is stunning in every way. I can imagine a couple of female friends sharing a bottle of wine and a box of Kleenex and having a good, purifying cry. It is everything that a filmed romance should be, an amazing sung story of lost love, with a poignant ending that is--depending on your viewpoint--sweetly happy or deliciously sad. If you haven't seen it yet, don't wait--see it now on DVD. Those of us who have already seen it will patiently await the Blu-Ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Under my umbrella (Ella ella eh eh eh)"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Checking a selection of Euro Art-films which my dad had kindly picked up on Video for me,I was pleased to see that one of the movies starred an actress who I had first her about in connection to a 1977 Giallo called Anima Persa.Taking another look at the case for the Catherine Deneuve movie,something about its title "clicked" with me in an odd way.Searching round on IMDb,I quickly got the answer,when I found that the film had been chosen for the IMDb's Indian Cinema board's next joint viewing,which led me to grabbing my umbrella,and getting ready to come face to face with Deneuve for the first time. The plot: Returning home from a wonderful date with the man of her dreams:Roland Cassard,Genevieve Emery is met with the stern face from her mother,who drains all the joy out of Genevieve's cheeks.Ignoring her mum's (who also works with her daughter in an umbrella shop) extremely vocal disagreement's about her "not knowing what real love is",and also that it is "Far too soon to be talking about marriage", Genevieve continues to have fantastic dates with Cassard.Feeling a deeper sense of intimacy with Roland, Genevieve decides to show the passion and intimacy that has grown between herself and Cassard by going to bed with him.Basking in the glow of the tightening of their bond, Genevieve and Cassard's romance is torn in two,due to Roland being drafted for a 2 year tour of duty in the Algerian War.Shortly after Roland leaves for his tour of duty, Genevieve discovers that she is pregnant with Cassard's child.As the months go by, Genevieve starts to fearfully take her mums words to heart,that Roland may possibly never return to her from his tour of duty. View on the film: Using the opening of the movie to have Roland Cassard take the audience into the film's startling Technicolour world,writer/director Jacques Demy teams up with costume designer Jacquline Moreau to smartly contrast the dark troubles facing Roland and Genevieve's families by aw-ashing the film in dazzling,flowing colours,which along with perfectly matching the detailed costume work of Moreau,also creates a lively atmosphere as the couples relationship increases in passion.Along with the shining colours, Demy also uses expertly stylised constantly moving,long tracking shots to show the life is so exciting and fast moving that Genevieve and Roland don't have a change to notice the changing backgrounds,until freezing the camera,to show the harsh,war light of reality hitting the couple's dream.For the screenplay, (all of which is sung!) Demy shows an impressive restrain of not including any fiddly,overly complicated words,but to instead go for something much more brilliantly simplistic,that allows the viewing to be completely caught,in the pure joy of Genevieve and Cassard's dates.With sharing almost every scene with each other for the first half the film, the beautiful Catherine Deneuve and Marc Michel each give splendid performances that perfectly compliment each other,with Deneuve showing Genevieve to have stars in her eyes every time she looks at Cassard,whilst Michel shows Roland to be someone who desperately wants to see the same stars that Genevieve does,but is sadly unable to get away from the harsh reality taking place around them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danatus-jairus
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1. Coloring, that is absolutely matchless 2. Even the first notes of the main theme make you cry 3. Unique way of singing in a musical 4. One of the most touching love stories 5. Beautiful Catherine Deneuve 6. It's not American 7. Made in the sixties 8. You can watch it over and over again 9. Since you've once seen it.. you must watch it over and over again 10. Esso-scene Ten more or less good reasons why this just might be the one.. the favorite movie of mine. I partly understand people who hate it, the singing is the main reason i think. But the unique way of singing! Not in the traditional way this is a musical, people just happen to sing when they talk. And the music (especially main theme) is so hauntingly beautiful it really does make you want to cry when you hear the first notes. The coloring is like in no other film. The clothing and background have been matched in every single scene of the movie. That's real cinema, that's beautiful! And if that's beautiful already, then what comes when the 20-year old Catherine Deneuve is in the lead role! Just WOW! Once again I don't bother explaining any of the plot, because there's no point really...but one of the saddest scenes in movie history, is the Esso-scene in this one. Watch it! if you're not too busy watching the latest Van-Damme.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie hasn't made me shed tears since A.I. until I watched this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joey Lan
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the credits rolled, I sat there with a tear streak still remaining on my face from a minute passed. I was bewildered. Bewildered by how this movie managed to invoke such strong emotion in me. It isn't a particularly sad movie. I'm not a even French movie buff. I'm not sure if I've even seen a French movie before. The movie is set in the small town of Cherbourg, France from 1957 to 1963. The walls are still all brick and mortar, covered with vibrant colors, hand painted on. Young Genevieve (Catherine Deneuve) lives with her protective mother (Anne Vernon) and together they run a quaint Umbrella shop in Cherbourg, France. Genevieve and Guy (Nino Castelnuovo) , a car mechanic at a local garage, are deeply in love and contemplate marriage but they are forced to put everything on hold as Guy (prounounced Gee in Geese) goes to serve his mandatory two years in the French army. Can their love survive the separation while she is being pushed by her mother to marry a rich jewel merchant by the name of Cassard (Marc Michel) in Guy's absence? It is a quintessential love story. Catherine Deneuve is breathtakingly beautiful. The characters are memorable and their personalities distinct. You might find that their relationship interactions a bit funny by modern standards but remember, this is set in the late 50s. Back when it was normal for ladies to lean on their partner's chest and caress his hands lovingly with their face.....while being pet like a cat. Still it added to the charm of the movie. The daintiness of the Genevieve that is, not the petting. The movie breaks down into four acts. After each act the movie fades to black and you are briefed on the next act. If you went and saw this movie upon its release, you went to the theater to watch......theater. One thing to note is that this is a different form of musical. ALL of the dialogue is sung instead of having musical numbers fitted in between spoken dialogue. The only other movie I've ever seen that has all the dialogue sung is "Repo the Genetic Opera". Imagine a gothicized Paris doing a musical number; Enough said. This one's much better. Back to the movie at hand, Michael Legrand could not have composed a more beautiful and fitting orchestral score. I must mention that the score is continuous throughout the whole movie from beginning to end. And it led to a beautiful song covered many great artists. The definitive and most haunting version by Connie Francis; Titled, "I will wait for you". The cinematography translates the charm of Cherbourg to film, wonderfully. The shots are simple and effective. My favorite shot in the movie is that of a departing train. I have seen my share of train scenes but I don't remember seeing it ever done this way. I recommend this movie, unless you despise theater, can't stand orchestral music and refer to French fries as Freedom Fries. I recommend watching it with your significant other (for maximum effect) and staring into their soul after the movie ends. Then put on some Marvin Gaye and get it on while keeping in mind that tomorrow may never come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ageless jazz opera
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film like this makes me think of my own life choices. It starts out like a painting that comes to life, set in the ancient port town of Cherbourg. (I was surprised to read on Wikipedia that a U.S. Civil War battle was fought off its shores.) From the cobblestone streets to the jewel-box storefronts to the grease monkeys at Guy's garage, this film is a joy to behold. And with Michel LeGrand's score, a delight to listen to. As a Francophile, I wish I could find a copy of its script. I enjoyed the crisp simplicity of the entirely sung dialogue. Adding to the satisfying unity of "Parapluies" is its perfect casting. Catherine Deneuve convinces as a rebellious daughter, infatuated teen, and bemused unwed woman with child. Her own mother, played fascinatingly by Anne Vernon, probably experienced the same out-of-wedlock pregnancy as she did. Clearly, Mme. Emery is attracted to M. Cassard, yet her only conscious wish is for the security of her only child. The mother-daughter relationship here is one of almost-total miscomprehension. Cassard (a dapper Marc Michel) is interesting to watch as the wealthy, somewhat bloodless suitor who actually travels with a crown, ready-made to place on his lady love's head! Nino Castelnuovo is superb as Guy, along with Ellen Farner as Madeleine. I enjoyed the range that Castelnuovo demonstrated, going from carefree lover to read-to-serve draftee, to depressed and acting-out Algerian War vet. The conversation between Guy and Madeleine, prior to marriage, is one of stunningly convincing depth, though its words are few. Of course, the final scene of this film unforgettable. I've seen "Parapluies" no fewer than five times and this viewing I cried perhaps more than ever, due to evermore bittersweet experience of my own under my belt. This must be one of those movies that never grows old. Its haunting melodies soothe and inspire me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Umbrellas of Cherbourg
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I read the title for this film in the book of 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die I knew it was a foreign film, from France, but I had no idea it was a musical, so I was most intrigued to watch, from director Jacques Demy (Lola, The Young Girls of Rochefort). Basically seventeen year old Genevi&egrave;ve Emery (Catherine Deneuve) lives in an umbrella shop in Cherbourg with her widowed mother Madame Emery (Anne Vernon), and she is secretly in love with twenty year old auto mechanic Guy Foucher (Nino Castelnuovo), and the two of them want to get married. She reveals this to her mother however, and she objects thinking that her daughter is too young and that he is not mature and well-established enough, and he may be required to do military service, and shortly later he is sent to Algeria after being drafted to serve in the war, but before leaving he and Genevi&egrave;ve consummate their love. Following this Genevi&egrave;ve is pregnant, while he is away he hardly communicates and they have drifted apart, so she listens to her mother's strong encouragement to accept a marriage proposal from Roland Cassard (Marc Michel) (he previously appeared as the same character in the film Lola), the affluent gem dealer who is in love with her and promises to bring her child up as his own. Guy is discharged from service before his two year term is up due to being wounded, he returns home and finds out Genevi&egrave;ve is married with a child and has moved away, and following this he sinks into deep depression and anger, which he struggles to control. But Guy recovers from his state when he falls in love and married young Madeleine (Ellen Farner) who had been caring for his aunt &Eacute;lise (Mireille Perrey), who is now deceased, and she left him an inheritance which he uses to fulfil his ambition to open a service station. Years pass, and Genevi&egrave;ve, who is now discernibly wealthy, has returned home with Fran&ccedil;oise (Rosalie Varda), her and Guy's daughter, and have an accidental meeting at his service station, their short conversation is obviously filled with unuttered fondness and regret, and in the end they finally part ways. Also starring Jean Champion as Aubin and Harald Wolff as Monsieur Dubourg. Deneuve is beautiful and gives a great delicate performance as the young woman longing for love from one man until fate changes everything, Castelnuovo is interesting as the man who is in and out of her life, and Michel is likable as the wealthy man with good intentions. The story is relatively simple, complicated romance, but what makes this musically distinctive is that every scene has singing, from the most mundane conversations to emotionally charging moments every word is spoken and sun in tune, and the picture has good use of vivid colour and design as well, it is a fantastic musical. It was nominated the Oscar for Best Song for "I Will Wait for You", Best Original Music for Michel Legrand and Jacques Demy, Best Music Adaptation or Treatment for Michel Legrand, Best Writing, Story and Screenplay - Written Directly for the Screen for Demy and Best Foreign Language Film, and it was nominated the Golden Globe for Best Foreign-Language Foreign Film. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A musical that compares the expectations of love with the harsh realities. The heart sings and breaks.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Umbrellas of Cherbourg is a unique film experiment. It's a musical where every line is sung. Even the mundane lines which have little to do with the film. While this style could be expected to be under threat of being too sweet, the film avoids this by approaching sentimentality with heart-wrenching reality, which the musical aspect of the film highlights. It's a love story. And the film is aware that it begins as a movie love story, addressed by the fact that the protagonist genuinely expects to die if they are parted. Instead of dying, the film explores one of my favourite deep subjects in art, by comparing the expectations of love brought on by pop culture with the harsh reality without being overdramatic. It's nostalgic and extremely genuine. As expected, the omnipresent music is absolutely wonderful and can speak for the film's emotion even without translation. How they managed to fit in the dialogue so fluently is incredible, let alone perform it. The set decoration and costume design is another highlight as well, with bright and bold colours, which the sweeping camera movement compliments perfectly. Despite the broad story, the film is surprisingly small scale with a limited use of sets, but the colour palette makes the world feel huge. There's some incredible use of match cuts as well. Though this film has a fantastic and charming atmosphere, it's the simple and effective storytelling that makes it, particularly the heartbreaking and subtle end. Bona fide classic. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    115 reviews so far...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Traversa
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... and they condense every possible information and observation one can make about this awesome movie. I will see it again out of an intense curiosity and nostalgia (I saw it many years ago and left me flabbergasted --patidifuso-- with all its fantastic beauty) after having listened the radio program I mention further down. I write these lines not to review one more time the film, but just to comment that I was listening a radio program from France Culture radio and they made a reportage about Cherbourg, where this movie was shot FIFTY YEARS AGO... and they are celebrating that anniversary in Cherbourg pulling out all the stops. It seems that the filming on that location 50 years ago was a big happening for this small and quiet coal town, apparently very dirty and facing away from the waterfront (now they have changed that concept and all new buildings are facing the waters) since then the huge popularity of this movie worldwide was such a ground shaking event for the inhabitants that they became aware of their own ignored potential and started to change everything, renovating shops and cleaning the city, to such an extent that nowadays the place is unrecognizable from its past dreary image. Japanese tourist go there to visit the umbrella shop where part of the action takes place (still looking and functioning like then) and even French people go there to visit the shop and take pictures!! During these fifty years Catherine Deneuve appeared in 117 films, leaving behind an enormous quantity of documentation to her legendary ice blonde beauty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Sweet Film."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manendra-lodhi (manendra.lodhi@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art cannot be for someone who fears. The director's approach fits in this quote. When I learned (before seeing the film) that it was a musical, I expected a rip off of the sound of Music. But when I started watching, everything started to look weird. All the dialogs in the film are in a musical way. You start to feel funny and irritated at the same time. The story is a very general, so do not expect much from it. It is just one normal love story that has a neutral ending with a good message. But what makes the film a must watch is its colorful cinematography. If for the first few minutes you are feeling irritated because of the musical dialogs then just wait some more and you will find yourself completely immersed in the film. After a time the dialogs, with music and everything look so normal that even such a predictable story can make you feel happy. It needed a lot of faith to make a film like this. The director has given a beautiful film which is definitely going to make you feel lighter. The most charming thing of the film is that none of the characters is shown as evil. It is the circumstances that are acting here as the obstacles. The film made me remember the films of Ghibli studios by Hayao Miyazaki. The film won the Palme d or in its time. But this is not the reason why you should be watching this, but that it is very much watchable in its own weird way. MESSAGE: "Life" VERDICT: "A recommended watch."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch it for the music, the colors, the story, and for the diving Ms. Deneuve
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    info-2752
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always associated my favorite musicals with Broadway, apart from this one, which is up there with my top three favorites. Filed as a love story, it also makes my top three. And Catherine Deneuve? She's definitely in my top three most beautiful actresses of all time. Then there's Michel Legrand, my second favorite composer (after Chopin, and if you must know, the third ones would be the Lennon/McCartney collaboration). How does one get so willingly hooked to a movie? Just sample the first five minutes of it, you don't even wait for the first lines of song to realize you're in for a gem of a film. Before you hear any of it, the sets are bound to get you. For the colors, those vibrant, palpable colors are a veritable visual feast. And have I mentioned the divine Catherine Deneuve? If there's anything most likely to distract your attention from the sets, it would be her presence. And last, but not least, for long after you may have forgotten the plot, you will never forget this: that melodious, hummable music, a song most of us associate with having heard from childhood, that beautifully threads the scenes of the story together--and you have the perfect musical. The most poignant love story (reminiscent of Splendor in the Grass, another coming-of-age film with a most genetically- blessed lead actors), with an ending that breaks the heart, but one which I completely approve of!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful--But Where's the Blu-Ray?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    t_k_matthews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most beautiful movies ever made deserves a Blu-Ray release. I first saw "The Umbrellas of Cherbourg" a few years ago on cable with a dinosaur CRT television, and even in that format it glowed. I want to buy the disc, but I'm holding out for Blu-Ray. The movie is stunning in every way. I can imagine a couple of female friends sharing a bottle of wine and a box of Kleenex and having a good, purifying cry. It is everything that a filmed romance should be, an amazing sung story of lost love, with a poignant ending that is--depending on your viewpoint--sweetly happy or deliciously sad. If you haven't seen it yet, don't wait--see it now on DVD. Those of us who have already seen it will patiently await the Blu-Ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Under my umbrella (Ella ella eh eh eh)"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Checking a selection of Euro Art-films which my dad had kindly picked up on Video for me,I was pleased to see that one of the movies starred an actress who I had first her about in connection to a 1977 Giallo called Anima Persa.Taking another look at the case for the Catherine Deneuve movie,something about its title "clicked" with me in an odd way.Searching round on IMDb,I quickly got the answer,when I found that the film had been chosen for the IMDb's Indian Cinema board's next joint viewing,which led me to grabbing my umbrella,and getting ready to come face to face with Deneuve for the first time. The plot: Returning home from a wonderful date with the man of her dreams:Roland Cassard,Genevieve Emery is met with the stern face from her mother,who drains all the joy out of Genevieve's cheeks.Ignoring her mum's (who also works with her daughter in an umbrella shop) extremely vocal disagreement's about her "not knowing what real love is",and also that it is "Far too soon to be talking about marriage", Genevieve continues to have fantastic dates with Cassard.Feeling a deeper sense of intimacy with Roland, Genevieve decides to show the passion and intimacy that has grown between herself and Cassard by going to bed with him.Basking in the glow of the tightening of their bond, Genevieve and Cassard's romance is torn in two,due to Roland being drafted for a 2 year tour of duty in the Algerian War.Shortly after Roland leaves for his tour of duty, Genevieve discovers that she is pregnant with Cassard's child.As the months go by, Genevieve starts to fearfully take her mums words to heart,that Roland may possibly never return to her from his tour of duty. View on the film: Using the opening of the movie to have Roland Cassard take the audience into the film's startling Technicolour world,writer/director Jacques Demy teams up with costume designer Jacquline Moreau to smartly contrast the dark troubles facing Roland and Genevieve's families by aw-ashing the film in dazzling,flowing colours,which along with perfectly matching the detailed costume work of Moreau,also creates a lively atmosphere as the couples relationship increases in passion.Along with the shining colours, Demy also uses expertly stylised constantly moving,long tracking shots to show the life is so exciting and fast moving that Genevieve and Roland don't have a change to notice the changing backgrounds,until freezing the camera,to show the harsh,war light of reality hitting the couple's dream.For the screenplay, (all of which is sung!) Demy shows an impressive restrain of not including any fiddly,overly complicated words,but to instead go for something much more brilliantly simplistic,that allows the viewing to be completely caught,in the pure joy of Genevieve and Cassard's dates.With sharing almost every scene with each other for the first half the film, the beautiful Catherine Deneuve and Marc Michel each give splendid performances that perfectly compliment each other,with Deneuve showing Genevieve to have stars in her eyes every time she looks at Cassard,whilst Michel shows Roland to be someone who desperately wants to see the same stars that Genevieve does,but is sadly unable to get away from the harsh reality taking place around them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danatus-jairus
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1. Coloring, that is absolutely matchless 2. Even the first notes of the main theme make you cry 3. Unique way of singing in a musical 4. One of the most touching love stories 5. Beautiful Catherine Deneuve 6. It's not American 7. Made in the sixties 8. You can watch it over and over again 9. Since you've once seen it.. you must watch it over and over again 10. Esso-scene Ten more or less good reasons why this just might be the one.. the favorite movie of mine. I partly understand people who hate it, the singing is the main reason i think. But the unique way of singing! Not in the traditional way this is a musical, people just happen to sing when they talk. And the music (especially main theme) is so hauntingly beautiful it really does make you want to cry when you hear the first notes. The coloring is like in no other film. The clothing and background have been matched in every single scene of the movie. That's real cinema, that's beautiful! And if that's beautiful already, then what comes when the 20-year old Catherine Deneuve is in the lead role! Just WOW! Once again I don't bother explaining any of the plot, because there's no point really...but one of the saddest scenes in movie history, is the Esso-scene in this one. Watch it! if you're not too busy watching the latest Van-Damme.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie hasn't made me shed tears since A.I. until I watched this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joey Lan
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the credits rolled, I sat there with a tear streak still remaining on my face from a minute passed. I was bewildered. Bewildered by how this movie managed to invoke such strong emotion in me. It isn't a particularly sad movie. I'm not a even French movie buff. I'm not sure if I've even seen a French movie before. The movie is set in the small town of Cherbourg, France from 1957 to 1963. The walls are still all brick and mortar, covered with vibrant colors, hand painted on. Young Genevieve (Catherine Deneuve) lives with her protective mother (Anne Vernon) and together they run a quaint Umbrella shop in Cherbourg, France. Genevieve and Guy (Nino Castelnuovo) , a car mechanic at a local garage, are deeply in love and contemplate marriage but they are forced to put everything on hold as Guy (prounounced Gee in Geese) goes to serve his mandatory two years in the French army. Can their love survive the separation while she is being pushed by her mother to marry a rich jewel merchant by the name of Cassard (Marc Michel) in Guy's absence? It is a quintessential love story. Catherine Deneuve is breathtakingly beautiful. The characters are memorable and their personalities distinct. You might find that their relationship interactions a bit funny by modern standards but remember, this is set in the late 50s. Back when it was normal for ladies to lean on their partner's chest and caress his hands lovingly with their face.....while being pet like a cat. Still it added to the charm of the movie. The daintiness of the Genevieve that is, not the petting. The movie breaks down into four acts. After each act the movie fades to black and you are briefed on the next act. If you went and saw this movie upon its release, you went to the theater to watch......theater. One thing to note is that this is a different form of musical. ALL of the dialogue is sung instead of having musical numbers fitted in between spoken dialogue. The only other movie I've ever seen that has all the dialogue sung is "Repo the Genetic Opera". Imagine a gothicized Paris doing a musical number; Enough said. This one's much better. Back to the movie at hand, Michael Legrand could not have composed a more beautiful and fitting orchestral score. I must mention that the score is continuous throughout the whole movie from beginning to end. And it led to a beautiful song covered many great artists. The definitive and most haunting version by Connie Francis; Titled, "I will wait for you". The cinematography translates the charm of Cherbourg to film, wonderfully. The shots are simple and effective. My favorite shot in the movie is that of a departing train. I have seen my share of train scenes but I don't remember seeing it ever done this way. I recommend this movie, unless you despise theater, can't stand orchestral music and refer to French fries as Freedom Fries. I recommend watching it with your significant other (for maximum effect) and staring into their soul after the movie ends. Then put on some Marvin Gaye and get it on while keeping in mind that tomorrow may never come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ageless jazz opera
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film like this makes me think of my own life choices. It starts out like a painting that comes to life, set in the ancient port town of Cherbourg. (I was surprised to read on Wikipedia that a U.S. Civil War battle was fought off its shores.) From the cobblestone streets to the jewel-box storefronts to the grease monkeys at Guy's garage, this film is a joy to behold. And with Michel LeGrand's score, a delight to listen to. As a Francophile, I wish I could find a copy of its script. I enjoyed the crisp simplicity of the entirely sung dialogue. Adding to the satisfying unity of "Parapluies" is its perfect casting. Catherine Deneuve convinces as a rebellious daughter, infatuated teen, and bemused unwed woman with child. Her own mother, played fascinatingly by Anne Vernon, probably experienced the same out-of-wedlock pregnancy as she did. Clearly, Mme. Emery is attracted to M. Cassard, yet her only conscious wish is for the security of her only child. The mother-daughter relationship here is one of almost-total miscomprehension. Cassard (a dapper Marc Michel) is interesting to watch as the wealthy, somewhat bloodless suitor who actually travels with a crown, ready-made to place on his lady love's head! Nino Castelnuovo is superb as Guy, along with Ellen Farner as Madeleine. I enjoyed the range that Castelnuovo demonstrated, going from carefree lover to read-to-serve draftee, to depressed and acting-out Algerian War vet. The conversation between Guy and Madeleine, prior to marriage, is one of stunningly convincing depth, though its words are few. Of course, the final scene of this film unforgettable. I've seen "Parapluies" no fewer than five times and this viewing I cried perhaps more than ever, due to evermore bittersweet experience of my own under my belt. This must be one of those movies that never grows old. Its haunting melodies soothe and inspire me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Umbrellas of Cherbourg
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I read the title for this film in the book of 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die I knew it was a foreign film, from France, but I had no idea it was a musical, so I was most intrigued to watch, from director Jacques Demy (Lola, The Young Girls of Rochefort). Basically seventeen year old Genevi&egrave;ve Emery (Catherine Deneuve) lives in an umbrella shop in Cherbourg with her widowed mother Madame Emery (Anne Vernon), and she is secretly in love with twenty year old auto mechanic Guy Foucher (Nino Castelnuovo), and the two of them want to get married. She reveals this to her mother however, and she objects thinking that her daughter is too young and that he is not mature and well-established enough, and he may be required to do military service, and shortly later he is sent to Algeria after being drafted to serve in the war, but before leaving he and Genevi&egrave;ve consummate their love. Following this Genevi&egrave;ve is pregnant, while he is away he hardly communicates and they have drifted apart, so she listens to her mother's strong encouragement to accept a marriage proposal from Roland Cassard (Marc Michel) (he previously appeared as the same character in the film Lola), the affluent gem dealer who is in love with her and promises to bring her child up as his own. Guy is discharged from service before his two year term is up due to being wounded, he returns home and finds out Genevi&egrave;ve is married with a child and has moved away, and following this he sinks into deep depression and anger, which he struggles to control. But Guy recovers from his state when he falls in love and married young Madeleine (Ellen Farner) who had been caring for his aunt &Eacute;lise (Mireille Perrey), who is now deceased, and she left him an inheritance which he uses to fulfil his ambition to open a service station. Years pass, and Genevi&egrave;ve, who is now discernibly wealthy, has returned home with Fran&ccedil;oise (Rosalie Varda), her and Guy's daughter, and have an accidental meeting at his service station, their short conversation is obviously filled with unuttered fondness and regret, and in the end they finally part ways. Also starring Jean Champion as Aubin and Harald Wolff as Monsieur Dubourg. Deneuve is beautiful and gives a great delicate performance as the young woman longing for love from one man until fate changes everything, Castelnuovo is interesting as the man who is in and out of her life, and Michel is likable as the wealthy man with good intentions. The story is relatively simple, complicated romance, but what makes this musically distinctive is that every scene has singing, from the most mundane conversations to emotionally charging moments every word is spoken and sun in tune, and the picture has good use of vivid colour and design as well, it is a fantastic musical. It was nominated the Oscar for Best Song for "I Will Wait for You", Best Original Music for Michel Legrand and Jacques Demy, Best Music Adaptation or Treatment for Michel Legrand, Best Writing, Story and Screenplay - Written Directly for the Screen for Demy and Best Foreign Language Film, and it was nominated the Golden Globe for Best Foreign-Language Foreign Film. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A musical that compares the expectations of love with the harsh realities. The heart sings and breaks.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Umbrellas of Cherbourg is a unique film experiment. It's a musical where every line is sung. Even the mundane lines which have little to do with the film. While this style could be expected to be under threat of being too sweet, the film avoids this by approaching sentimentality with heart-wrenching reality, which the musical aspect of the film highlights. It's a love story. And the film is aware that it begins as a movie love story, addressed by the fact that the protagonist genuinely expects to die if they are parted. Instead of dying, the film explores one of my favourite deep subjects in art, by comparing the expectations of love brought on by pop culture with the harsh reality without being overdramatic. It's nostalgic and extremely genuine. As expected, the omnipresent music is absolutely wonderful and can speak for the film's emotion even without translation. How they managed to fit in the dialogue so fluently is incredible, let alone perform it. The set decoration and costume design is another highlight as well, with bright and bold colours, which the sweeping camera movement compliments perfectly. Despite the broad story, the film is surprisingly small scale with a limited use of sets, but the colour palette makes the world feel huge. There's some incredible use of match cuts as well. Though this film has a fantastic and charming atmosphere, it's the simple and effective storytelling that makes it, particularly the heartbreaking and subtle end. Bona fide classic. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    115 reviews so far...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Traversa
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... and they condense every possible information and observation one can make about this awesome movie. I will see it again out of an intense curiosity and nostalgia (I saw it many years ago and left me flabbergasted --patidifuso-- with all its fantastic beauty) after having listened the radio program I mention further down. I write these lines not to review one more time the film, but just to comment that I was listening a radio program from France Culture radio and they made a reportage about Cherbourg, where this movie was shot FIFTY YEARS AGO... and they are celebrating that anniversary in Cherbourg pulling out all the stops. It seems that the filming on that location 50 years ago was a big happening for this small and quiet coal town, apparently very dirty and facing away from the waterfront (now they have changed that concept and all new buildings are facing the waters) since then the huge popularity of this movie worldwide was such a ground shaking event for the inhabitants that they became aware of their own ignored potential and started to change everything, renovating shops and cleaning the city, to such an extent that nowadays the place is unrecognizable from its past dreary image. Japanese tourist go there to visit the umbrella shop where part of the action takes place (still looking and functioning like then) and even French people go there to visit the shop and take pictures!! During these fifty years Catherine Deneuve appeared in 117 films, leaving behind an enormous quantity of documentation to her legendary ice blonde beauty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Sweet Film."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manendra-lodhi (manendra.lodhi@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art cannot be for someone who fears. The director's approach fits in this quote. When I learned (before seeing the film) that it was a musical, I expected a rip off of the sound of Music. But when I started watching, everything started to look weird. All the dialogs in the film are in a musical way. You start to feel funny and irritated at the same time. The story is a very general, so do not expect much from it. It is just one normal love story that has a neutral ending with a good message. But what makes the film a must watch is its colorful cinematography. If for the first few minutes you are feeling irritated because of the musical dialogs then just wait some more and you will find yourself completely immersed in the film. After a time the dialogs, with music and everything look so normal that even such a predictable story can make you feel happy. It needed a lot of faith to make a film like this. The director has given a beautiful film which is definitely going to make you feel lighter. The most charming thing of the film is that none of the characters is shown as evil. It is the circumstances that are acting here as the obstacles. The film made me remember the films of Ghibli studios by Hayao Miyazaki. The film won the Palme d or in its time. But this is not the reason why you should be watching this, but that it is very much watchable in its own weird way. MESSAGE: "Life" VERDICT: "A recommended watch."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch it for the music, the colors, the story, and for the diving Ms. Deneuve
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    info-2752
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always associated my favorite musicals with Broadway, apart from this one, which is up there with my top three favorites. Filed as a love story, it also makes my top three. And Catherine Deneuve? She's definitely in my top three most beautiful actresses of all time. Then there's Michel Legrand, my second favorite composer (after Chopin, and if you must know, the third ones would be the Lennon/McCartney collaboration). How does one get so willingly hooked to a movie? Just sample the first five minutes of it, you don't even wait for the first lines of song to realize you're in for a gem of a film. Before you hear any of it, the sets are bound to get you. For the colors, those vibrant, palpable colors are a veritable visual feast. And have I mentioned the divine Catherine Deneuve? If there's anything most likely to distract your attention from the sets, it would be her presence. And last, but not least, for long after you may have forgotten the plot, you will never forget this: that melodious, hummable music, a song most of us associate with having heard from childhood, that beautifully threads the scenes of the story together--and you have the perfect musical. The most poignant love story (reminiscent of Splendor in the Grass, another coming-of-age film with a most genetically- blessed lead actors), with an ending that breaks the heart, but one which I completely approve of!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful--But Where's the Blu-Ray?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    t_k_matthews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most beautiful movies ever made deserves a Blu-Ray release. I first saw "The Umbrellas of Cherbourg" a few years ago on cable with a dinosaur CRT television, and even in that format it glowed. I want to buy the disc, but I'm holding out for Blu-Ray. The movie is stunning in every way. I can imagine a couple of female friends sharing a bottle of wine and a box of Kleenex and having a good, purifying cry. It is everything that a filmed romance should be, an amazing sung story of lost love, with a poignant ending that is--depending on your viewpoint--sweetly happy or deliciously sad. If you haven't seen it yet, don't wait--see it now on DVD. Those of us who have already seen it will patiently await the Blu-Ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Under my umbrella (Ella ella eh eh eh)"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Checking a selection of Euro Art-films which my dad had kindly picked up on Video for me,I was pleased to see that one of the movies starred an actress who I had first her about in connection to a 1977 Giallo called Anima Persa.Taking another look at the case for the Catherine Deneuve movie,something about its title "clicked" with me in an odd way.Searching round on IMDb,I quickly got the answer,when I found that the film had been chosen for the IMDb's Indian Cinema board's next joint viewing,which led me to grabbing my umbrella,and getting ready to come face to face with Deneuve for the first time. The plot: Returning home from a wonderful date with the man of her dreams:Roland Cassard,Genevieve Emery is met with the stern face from her mother,who drains all the joy out of Genevieve's cheeks.Ignoring her mum's (who also works with her daughter in an umbrella shop) extremely vocal disagreement's about her "not knowing what real love is",and also that it is "Far too soon to be talking about marriage", Genevieve continues to have fantastic dates with Cassard.Feeling a deeper sense of intimacy with Roland, Genevieve decides to show the passion and intimacy that has grown between herself and Cassard by going to bed with him.Basking in the glow of the tightening of their bond, Genevieve and Cassard's romance is torn in two,due to Roland being drafted for a 2 year tour of duty in the Algerian War.Shortly after Roland leaves for his tour of duty, Genevieve discovers that she is pregnant with Cassard's child.As the months go by, Genevieve starts to fearfully take her mums words to heart,that Roland may possibly never return to her from his tour of duty. View on the film: Using the opening of the movie to have Roland Cassard take the audience into the film's startling Technicolour world,writer/director Jacques Demy teams up with costume designer Jacquline Moreau to smartly contrast the dark troubles facing Roland and Genevieve's families by aw-ashing the film in dazzling,flowing colours,which along with perfectly matching the detailed costume work of Moreau,also creates a lively atmosphere as the couples relationship increases in passion.Along with the shining colours, Demy also uses expertly stylised constantly moving,long tracking shots to show the life is so exciting and fast moving that Genevieve and Roland don't have a change to notice the changing backgrounds,until freezing the camera,to show the harsh,war light of reality hitting the couple's dream.For the screenplay, (all of which is sung!) Demy shows an impressive restrain of not including any fiddly,overly complicated words,but to instead go for something much more brilliantly simplistic,that allows the viewing to be completely caught,in the pure joy of Genevieve and Cassard's dates.With sharing almost every scene with each other for the first half the film, the beautiful Catherine Deneuve and Marc Michel each give splendid performances that perfectly compliment each other,with Deneuve showing Genevieve to have stars in her eyes every time she looks at Cassard,whilst Michel shows Roland to be someone who desperately wants to see the same stars that Genevieve does,but is sadly unable to get away from the harsh reality taking place around them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danatus-jairus
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1. Coloring, that is absolutely matchless 2. Even the first notes of the main theme make you cry 3. Unique way of singing in a musical 4. One of the most touching love stories 5. Beautiful Catherine Deneuve 6. It's not American 7. Made in the sixties 8. You can watch it over and over again 9. Since you've once seen it.. you must watch it over and over again 10. Esso-scene Ten more or less good reasons why this just might be the one.. the favorite movie of mine. I partly understand people who hate it, the singing is the main reason i think. But the unique way of singing! Not in the traditional way this is a musical, people just happen to sing when they talk. And the music (especially main theme) is so hauntingly beautiful it really does make you want to cry when you hear the first notes. The coloring is like in no other film. The clothing and background have been matched in every single scene of the movie. That's real cinema, that's beautiful! And if that's beautiful already, then what comes when the 20-year old Catherine Deneuve is in the lead role! Just WOW! Once again I don't bother explaining any of the plot, because there's no point really...but one of the saddest scenes in movie history, is the Esso-scene in this one. Watch it! if you're not too busy watching the latest Van-Damme.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie hasn't made me shed tears since A.I. until I watched this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joey Lan
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the credits rolled, I sat there with a tear streak still remaining on my face from a minute passed. I was bewildered. Bewildered by how this movie managed to invoke such strong emotion in me. It isn't a particularly sad movie. I'm not a even French movie buff. I'm not sure if I've even seen a French movie before. The movie is set in the small town of Cherbourg, France from 1957 to 1963. The walls are still all brick and mortar, covered with vibrant colors, hand painted on. Young Genevieve (Catherine Deneuve) lives with her protective mother (Anne Vernon) and together they run a quaint Umbrella shop in Cherbourg, France. Genevieve and Guy (Nino Castelnuovo) , a car mechanic at a local garage, are deeply in love and contemplate marriage but they are forced to put everything on hold as Guy (prounounced Gee in Geese) goes to serve his mandatory two years in the French army. Can their love survive the separation while she is being pushed by her mother to marry a rich jewel merchant by the name of Cassard (Marc Michel) in Guy's absence? It is a quintessential love story. Catherine Deneuve is breathtakingly beautiful. The characters are memorable and their personalities distinct. You might find that their relationship interactions a bit funny by modern standards but remember, this is set in the late 50s. Back when it was normal for ladies to lean on their partner's chest and caress his hands lovingly with their face.....while being pet like a cat. Still it added to the charm of the movie. The daintiness of the Genevieve that is, not the petting. The movie breaks down into four acts. After each act the movie fades to black and you are briefed on the next act. If you went and saw this movie upon its release, you went to the theater to watch......theater. One thing to note is that this is a different form of musical. ALL of the dialogue is sung instead of having musical numbers fitted in between spoken dialogue. The only other movie I've ever seen that has all the dialogue sung is "Repo the Genetic Opera". Imagine a gothicized Paris doing a musical number; Enough said. This one's much better. Back to the movie at hand, Michael Legrand could not have composed a more beautiful and fitting orchestral score. I must mention that the score is continuous throughout the whole movie from beginning to end. And it led to a beautiful song covered many great artists. The definitive and most haunting version by Connie Francis; Titled, "I will wait for you". The cinematography translates the charm of Cherbourg to film, wonderfully. The shots are simple and effective. My favorite shot in the movie is that of a departing train. I have seen my share of train scenes but I don't remember seeing it ever done this way. I recommend this movie, unless you despise theater, can't stand orchestral music and refer to French fries as Freedom Fries. I recommend watching it with your significant other (for maximum effect) and staring into their soul after the movie ends. Then put on some Marvin Gaye and get it on while keeping in mind that tomorrow may never come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ageless jazz opera
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film like this makes me think of my own life choices. It starts out like a painting that comes to life, set in the ancient port town of Cherbourg. (I was surprised to read on Wikipedia that a U.S. Civil War battle was fought off its shores.) From the cobblestone streets to the jewel-box storefronts to the grease monkeys at Guy's garage, this film is a joy to behold. And with Michel LeGrand's score, a delight to listen to. As a Francophile, I wish I could find a copy of its script. I enjoyed the crisp simplicity of the entirely sung dialogue. Adding to the satisfying unity of "Parapluies" is its perfect casting. Catherine Deneuve convinces as a rebellious daughter, infatuated teen, and bemused unwed woman with child. Her own mother, played fascinatingly by Anne Vernon, probably experienced the same out-of-wedlock pregnancy as she did. Clearly, Mme. Emery is attracted to M. Cassard, yet her only conscious wish is for the security of her only child. The mother-daughter relationship here is one of almost-total miscomprehension. Cassard (a dapper Marc Michel) is interesting to watch as the wealthy, somewhat bloodless suitor who actually travels with a crown, ready-made to place on his lady love's head! Nino Castelnuovo is superb as Guy, along with Ellen Farner as Madeleine. I enjoyed the range that Castelnuovo demonstrated, going from carefree lover to read-to-serve draftee, to depressed and acting-out Algerian War vet. The conversation between Guy and Madeleine, prior to marriage, is one of stunningly convincing depth, though its words are few. Of course, the final scene of this film unforgettable. I've seen "Parapluies" no fewer than five times and this viewing I cried perhaps more than ever, due to evermore bittersweet experience of my own under my belt. This must be one of those movies that never grows old. Its haunting melodies soothe and inspire me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Umbrellas of Cherbourg
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I read the title for this film in the book of 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die I knew it was a foreign film, from France, but I had no idea it was a musical, so I was most intrigued to watch, from director Jacques Demy (Lola, The Young Girls of Rochefort). Basically seventeen year old Genevi&egrave;ve Emery (Catherine Deneuve) lives in an umbrella shop in Cherbourg with her widowed mother Madame Emery (Anne Vernon), and she is secretly in love with twenty year old auto mechanic Guy Foucher (Nino Castelnuovo), and the two of them want to get married. She reveals this to her mother however, and she objects thinking that her daughter is too young and that he is not mature and well-established enough, and he may be required to do military service, and shortly later he is sent to Algeria after being drafted to serve in the war, but before leaving he and Genevi&egrave;ve consummate their love. Following this Genevi&egrave;ve is pregnant, while he is away he hardly communicates and they have drifted apart, so she listens to her mother's strong encouragement to accept a marriage proposal from Roland Cassard (Marc Michel) (he previously appeared as the same character in the film Lola), the affluent gem dealer who is in love with her and promises to bring her child up as his own. Guy is discharged from service before his two year term is up due to being wounded, he returns home and finds out Genevi&egrave;ve is married with a child and has moved away, and following this he sinks into deep depression and anger, which he struggles to control. But Guy recovers from his state when he falls in love and married young Madeleine (Ellen Farner) who had been caring for his aunt &Eacute;lise (Mireille Perrey), who is now deceased, and she left him an inheritance which he uses to fulfil his ambition to open a service station. Years pass, and Genevi&egrave;ve, who is now discernibly wealthy, has returned home with Fran&ccedil;oise (Rosalie Varda), her and Guy's daughter, and have an accidental meeting at his service station, their short conversation is obviously filled with unuttered fondness and regret, and in the end they finally part ways. Also starring Jean Champion as Aubin and Harald Wolff as Monsieur Dubourg. Deneuve is beautiful and gives a great delicate performance as the young woman longing for love from one man until fate changes everything, Castelnuovo is interesting as the man who is in and out of her life, and Michel is likable as the wealthy man with good intentions. The story is relatively simple, complicated romance, but what makes this musically distinctive is that every scene has singing, from the most mundane conversations to emotionally charging moments every word is spoken and sun in tune, and the picture has good use of vivid colour and design as well, it is a fantastic musical. It was nominated the Oscar for Best Song for "I Will Wait for You", Best Original Music for Michel Legrand and Jacques Demy, Best Music Adaptation or Treatment for Michel Legrand, Best Writing, Story and Screenplay - Written Directly for the Screen for Demy and Best Foreign Language Film, and it was nominated the Golden Globe for Best Foreign-Language Foreign Film. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A musical that compares the expectations of love with the harsh realities. The heart sings and breaks.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Umbrellas of Cherbourg is a unique film experiment. It's a musical where every line is sung. Even the mundane lines which have little to do with the film. While this style could be expected to be under threat of being too sweet, the film avoids this by approaching sentimentality with heart-wrenching reality, which the musical aspect of the film highlights. It's a love story. And the film is aware that it begins as a movie love story, addressed by the fact that the protagonist genuinely expects to die if they are parted. Instead of dying, the film explores one of my favourite deep subjects in art, by comparing the expectations of love brought on by pop culture with the harsh reality without being overdramatic. It's nostalgic and extremely genuine. As expected, the omnipresent music is absolutely wonderful and can speak for the film's emotion even without translation. How they managed to fit in the dialogue so fluently is incredible, let alone perform it. The set decoration and costume design is another highlight as well, with bright and bold colours, which the sweeping camera movement compliments perfectly. Despite the broad story, the film is surprisingly small scale with a limited use of sets, but the colour palette makes the world feel huge. There's some incredible use of match cuts as well. Though this film has a fantastic and charming atmosphere, it's the simple and effective storytelling that makes it, particularly the heartbreaking and subtle end. Bona fide classic. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    115 reviews so far...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Traversa
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... and they condense every possible information and observation one can make about this awesome movie. I will see it again out of an intense curiosity and nostalgia (I saw it many years ago and left me flabbergasted --patidifuso-- with all its fantastic beauty) after having listened the radio program I mention further down. I write these lines not to review one more time the film, but just to comment that I was listening a radio program from France Culture radio and they made a reportage about Cherbourg, where this movie was shot FIFTY YEARS AGO... and they are celebrating that anniversary in Cherbourg pulling out all the stops. It seems that the filming on that location 50 years ago was a big happening for this small and quiet coal town, apparently very dirty and facing away from the waterfront (now they have changed that concept and all new buildings are facing the waters) since then the huge popularity of this movie worldwide was such a ground shaking event for the inhabitants that they became aware of their own ignored potential and started to change everything, renovating shops and cleaning the city, to such an extent that nowadays the place is unrecognizable from its past dreary image. Japanese tourist go there to visit the umbrella shop where part of the action takes place (still looking and functioning like then) and even French people go there to visit the shop and take pictures!! During these fifty years Catherine Deneuve appeared in 117 films, leaving behind an enormous quantity of documentation to her legendary ice blonde beauty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Sweet Film."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manendra-lodhi (manendra.lodhi@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art cannot be for someone who fears. The director's approach fits in this quote. When I learned (before seeing the film) that it was a musical, I expected a rip off of the sound of Music. But when I started watching, everything started to look weird. All the dialogs in the film are in a musical way. You start to feel funny and irritated at the same time. The story is a very general, so do not expect much from it. It is just one normal love story that has a neutral ending with a good message. But what makes the film a must watch is its colorful cinematography. If for the first few minutes you are feeling irritated because of the musical dialogs then just wait some more and you will find yourself completely immersed in the film. After a time the dialogs, with music and everything look so normal that even such a predictable story can make you feel happy. It needed a lot of faith to make a film like this. The director has given a beautiful film which is definitely going to make you feel lighter. The most charming thing of the film is that none of the characters is shown as evil. It is the circumstances that are acting here as the obstacles. The film made me remember the films of Ghibli studios by Hayao Miyazaki. The film won the Palme d or in its time. But this is not the reason why you should be watching this, but that it is very much watchable in its own weird way. MESSAGE: "Life" VERDICT: "A recommended watch."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch it for the music, the colors, the story, and for the diving Ms. Deneuve
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    info-2752
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always associated my favorite musicals with Broadway, apart from this one, which is up there with my top three favorites. Filed as a love story, it also makes my top three. And Catherine Deneuve? She's definitely in my top three most beautiful actresses of all time. Then there's Michel Legrand, my second favorite composer (after Chopin, and if you must know, the third ones would be the Lennon/McCartney collaboration). How does one get so willingly hooked to a movie? Just sample the first five minutes of it, you don't even wait for the first lines of song to realize you're in for a gem of a film. Before you hear any of it, the sets are bound to get you. For the colors, those vibrant, palpable colors are a veritable visual feast. And have I mentioned the divine Catherine Deneuve? If there's anything most likely to distract your attention from the sets, it would be her presence. And last, but not least, for long after you may have forgotten the plot, you will never forget this: that melodious, hummable music, a song most of us associate with having heard from childhood, that beautifully threads the scenes of the story together--and you have the perfect musical. The most poignant love story (reminiscent of Splendor in the Grass, another coming-of-age film with a most genetically- blessed lead actors), with an ending that breaks the heart, but one which I completely approve of!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful--But Where's the Blu-Ray?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    t_k_matthews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most beautiful movies ever made deserves a Blu-Ray release. I first saw "The Umbrellas of Cherbourg" a few years ago on cable with a dinosaur CRT television, and even in that format it glowed. I want to buy the disc, but I'm holding out for Blu-Ray. The movie is stunning in every way. I can imagine a couple of female friends sharing a bottle of wine and a box of Kleenex and having a good, purifying cry. It is everything that a filmed romance should be, an amazing sung story of lost love, with a poignant ending that is--depending on your viewpoint--sweetly happy or deliciously sad. If you haven't seen it yet, don't wait--see it now on DVD. Those of us who have already seen it will patiently await the Blu-Ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Under my umbrella (Ella ella eh eh eh)"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Checking a selection of Euro Art-films which my dad had kindly picked up on Video for me,I was pleased to see that one of the movies starred an actress who I had first her about in connection to a 1977 Giallo called Anima Persa.Taking another look at the case for the Catherine Deneuve movie,something about its title "clicked" with me in an odd way.Searching round on IMDb,I quickly got the answer,when I found that the film had been chosen for the IMDb's Indian Cinema board's next joint viewing,which led me to grabbing my umbrella,and getting ready to come face to face with Deneuve for the first time. The plot: Returning home from a wonderful date with the man of her dreams:Roland Cassard,Genevieve Emery is met with the stern face from her mother,who drains all the joy out of Genevieve's cheeks.Ignoring her mum's (who also works with her daughter in an umbrella shop) extremely vocal disagreement's about her "not knowing what real love is",and also that it is "Far too soon to be talking about marriage", Genevieve continues to have fantastic dates with Cassard.Feeling a deeper sense of intimacy with Roland, Genevieve decides to show the passion and intimacy that has grown between herself and Cassard by going to bed with him.Basking in the glow of the tightening of their bond, Genevieve and Cassard's romance is torn in two,due to Roland being drafted for a 2 year tour of duty in the Algerian War.Shortly after Roland leaves for his tour of duty, Genevieve discovers that she is pregnant with Cassard's child.As the months go by, Genevieve starts to fearfully take her mums words to heart,that Roland may possibly never return to her from his tour of duty. View on the film: Using the opening of the movie to have Roland Cassard take the audience into the film's startling Technicolour world,writer/director Jacques Demy teams up with costume designer Jacquline Moreau to smartly contrast the dark troubles facing Roland and Genevieve's families by aw-ashing the film in dazzling,flowing colours,which along with perfectly matching the detailed costume work of Moreau,also creates a lively atmosphere as the couples relationship increases in passion.Along with the shining colours, Demy also uses expertly stylised constantly moving,long tracking shots to show the life is so exciting and fast moving that Genevieve and Roland don't have a change to notice the changing backgrounds,until freezing the camera,to show the harsh,war light of reality hitting the couple's dream.For the screenplay, (all of which is sung!) Demy shows an impressive restrain of not including any fiddly,overly complicated words,but to instead go for something much more brilliantly simplistic,that allows the viewing to be completely caught,in the pure joy of Genevieve and Cassard's dates.With sharing almost every scene with each other for the first half the film, the beautiful Catherine Deneuve and Marc Michel each give splendid performances that perfectly compliment each other,with Deneuve showing Genevieve to have stars in her eyes every time she looks at Cassard,whilst Michel shows Roland to be someone who desperately wants to see the same stars that Genevieve does,but is sadly unable to get away from the harsh reality taking place around them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danatus-jairus
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1. Coloring, that is absolutely matchless 2. Even the first notes of the main theme make you cry 3. Unique way of singing in a musical 4. One of the most touching love stories 5. Beautiful Catherine Deneuve 6. It's not American 7. Made in the sixties 8. You can watch it over and over again 9. Since you've once seen it.. you must watch it over and over again 10. Esso-scene Ten more or less good reasons why this just might be the one.. the favorite movie of mine. I partly understand people who hate it, the singing is the main reason i think. But the unique way of singing! Not in the traditional way this is a musical, people just happen to sing when they talk. And the music (especially main theme) is so hauntingly beautiful it really does make you want to cry when you hear the first notes. The coloring is like in no other film. The clothing and background have been matched in every single scene of the movie. That's real cinema, that's beautiful! And if that's beautiful already, then what comes when the 20-year old Catherine Deneuve is in the lead role! Just WOW! Once again I don't bother explaining any of the plot, because there's no point really...but one of the saddest scenes in movie history, is the Esso-scene in this one. Watch it! if you're not too busy watching the latest Van-Damme.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie hasn't made me shed tears since A.I. until I watched this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joey Lan
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the credits rolled, I sat there with a tear streak still remaining on my face from a minute passed. I was bewildered. Bewildered by how this movie managed to invoke such strong emotion in me. It isn't a particularly sad movie. I'm not a even French movie buff. I'm not sure if I've even seen a French movie before. The movie is set in the small town of Cherbourg, France from 1957 to 1963. The walls are still all brick and mortar, covered with vibrant colors, hand painted on. Young Genevieve (Catherine Deneuve) lives with her protective mother (Anne Vernon) and together they run a quaint Umbrella shop in Cherbourg, France. Genevieve and Guy (Nino Castelnuovo) , a car mechanic at a local garage, are deeply in love and contemplate marriage but they are forced to put everything on hold as Guy (prounounced Gee in Geese) goes to serve his mandatory two years in the French army. Can their love survive the separation while she is being pushed by her mother to marry a rich jewel merchant by the name of Cassard (Marc Michel) in Guy's absence? It is a quintessential love story. Catherine Deneuve is breathtakingly beautiful. The characters are memorable and their personalities distinct. You might find that their relationship interactions a bit funny by modern standards but remember, this is set in the late 50s. Back when it was normal for ladies to lean on their partner's chest and caress his hands lovingly with their face.....while being pet like a cat. Still it added to the charm of the movie. The daintiness of the Genevieve that is, not the petting. The movie breaks down into four acts. After each act the movie fades to black and you are briefed on the next act. If you went and saw this movie upon its release, you went to the theater to watch......theater. One thing to note is that this is a different form of musical. ALL of the dialogue is sung instead of having musical numbers fitted in between spoken dialogue. The only other movie I've ever seen that has all the dialogue sung is "Repo the Genetic Opera". Imagine a gothicized Paris doing a musical number; Enough said. This one's much better. Back to the movie at hand, Michael Legrand could not have composed a more beautiful and fitting orchestral score. I must mention that the score is continuous throughout the whole movie from beginning to end. And it led to a beautiful song covered many great artists. The definitive and most haunting version by Connie Francis; Titled, "I will wait for you". The cinematography translates the charm of Cherbourg to film, wonderfully. The shots are simple and effective. My favorite shot in the movie is that of a departing train. I have seen my share of train scenes but I don't remember seeing it ever done this way. I recommend this movie, unless you despise theater, can't stand orchestral music and refer to French fries as Freedom Fries. I recommend watching it with your significant other (for maximum effect) and staring into their soul after the movie ends. Then put on some Marvin Gaye and get it on while keeping in mind that tomorrow may never come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ageless jazz opera
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film like this makes me think of my own life choices. It starts out like a painting that comes to life, set in the ancient port town of Cherbourg. (I was surprised to read on Wikipedia that a U.S. Civil War battle was fought off its shores.) From the cobblestone streets to the jewel-box storefronts to the grease monkeys at Guy's garage, this film is a joy to behold. And with Michel LeGrand's score, a delight to listen to. As a Francophile, I wish I could find a copy of its script. I enjoyed the crisp simplicity of the entirely sung dialogue. Adding to the satisfying unity of "Parapluies" is its perfect casting. Catherine Deneuve convinces as a rebellious daughter, infatuated teen, and bemused unwed woman with child. Her own mother, played fascinatingly by Anne Vernon, probably experienced the same out-of-wedlock pregnancy as she did. Clearly, Mme. Emery is attracted to M. Cassard, yet her only conscious wish is for the security of her only child. The mother-daughter relationship here is one of almost-total miscomprehension. Cassard (a dapper Marc Michel) is interesting to watch as the wealthy, somewhat bloodless suitor who actually travels with a crown, ready-made to place on his lady love's head! Nino Castelnuovo is superb as Guy, along with Ellen Farner as Madeleine. I enjoyed the range that Castelnuovo demonstrated, going from carefree lover to read-to-serve draftee, to depressed and acting-out Algerian War vet. The conversation between Guy and Madeleine, prior to marriage, is one of stunningly convincing depth, though its words are few. Of course, the final scene of this film unforgettable. I've seen "Parapluies" no fewer than five times and this viewing I cried perhaps more than ever, due to evermore bittersweet experience of my own under my belt. This must be one of those movies that never grows old. Its haunting melodies soothe and inspire me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Umbrellas of Cherbourg
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I read the title for this film in the book of 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die I knew it was a foreign film, from France, but I had no idea it was a musical, so I was most intrigued to watch, from director Jacques Demy (Lola, The Young Girls of Rochefort). Basically seventeen year old Genevi&egrave;ve Emery (Catherine Deneuve) lives in an umbrella shop in Cherbourg with her widowed mother Madame Emery (Anne Vernon), and she is secretly in love with twenty year old auto mechanic Guy Foucher (Nino Castelnuovo), and the two of them want to get married. She reveals this to her mother however, and she objects thinking that her daughter is too young and that he is not mature and well-established enough, and he may be required to do military service, and shortly later he is sent to Algeria after being drafted to serve in the war, but before leaving he and Genevi&egrave;ve consummate their love. Following this Genevi&egrave;ve is pregnant, while he is away he hardly communicates and they have drifted apart, so she listens to her mother's strong encouragement to accept a marriage proposal from Roland Cassard (Marc Michel) (he previously appeared as the same character in the film Lola), the affluent gem dealer who is in love with her and promises to bring her child up as his own. Guy is discharged from service before his two year term is up due to being wounded, he returns home and finds out Genevi&egrave;ve is married with a child and has moved away, and following this he sinks into deep depression and anger, which he struggles to control. But Guy recovers from his state when he falls in love and married young Madeleine (Ellen Farner) who had been caring for his aunt &Eacute;lise (Mireille Perrey), who is now deceased, and she left him an inheritance which he uses to fulfil his ambition to open a service station. Years pass, and Genevi&egrave;ve, who is now discernibly wealthy, has returned home with Fran&ccedil;oise (Rosalie Varda), her and Guy's daughter, and have an accidental meeting at his service station, their short conversation is obviously filled with unuttered fondness and regret, and in the end they finally part ways. Also starring Jean Champion as Aubin and Harald Wolff as Monsieur Dubourg. Deneuve is beautiful and gives a great delicate performance as the young woman longing for love from one man until fate changes everything, Castelnuovo is interesting as the man who is in and out of her life, and Michel is likable as the wealthy man with good intentions. The story is relatively simple, complicated romance, but what makes this musically distinctive is that every scene has singing, from the most mundane conversations to emotionally charging moments every word is spoken and sun in tune, and the picture has good use of vivid colour and design as well, it is a fantastic musical. It was nominated the Oscar for Best Song for "I Will Wait for You", Best Original Music for Michel Legrand and Jacques Demy, Best Music Adaptation or Treatment for Michel Legrand, Best Writing, Story and Screenplay - Written Directly for the Screen for Demy and Best Foreign Language Film, and it was nominated the Golden Globe for Best Foreign-Language Foreign Film. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A musical that compares the expectations of love with the harsh realities. The heart sings and breaks.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Umbrellas of Cherbourg is a unique film experiment. It's a musical where every line is sung. Even the mundane lines which have little to do with the film. While this style could be expected to be under threat of being too sweet, the film avoids this by approaching sentimentality with heart-wrenching reality, which the musical aspect of the film highlights. It's a love story. And the film is aware that it begins as a movie love story, addressed by the fact that the protagonist genuinely expects to die if they are parted. Instead of dying, the film explores one of my favourite deep subjects in art, by comparing the expectations of love brought on by pop culture with the harsh reality without being overdramatic. It's nostalgic and extremely genuine. As expected, the omnipresent music is absolutely wonderful and can speak for the film's emotion even without translation. How they managed to fit in the dialogue so fluently is incredible, let alone perform it. The set decoration and costume design is another highlight as well, with bright and bold colours, which the sweeping camera movement compliments perfectly. Despite the broad story, the film is surprisingly small scale with a limited use of sets, but the colour palette makes the world feel huge. There's some incredible use of match cuts as well. Though this film has a fantastic and charming atmosphere, it's the simple and effective storytelling that makes it, particularly the heartbreaking and subtle end. Bona fide classic. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    115 reviews so far...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Traversa
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... and they condense every possible information and observation one can make about this awesome movie. I will see it again out of an intense curiosity and nostalgia (I saw it many years ago and left me flabbergasted --patidifuso-- with all its fantastic beauty) after having listened the radio program I mention further down. I write these lines not to review one more time the film, but just to comment that I was listening a radio program from France Culture radio and they made a reportage about Cherbourg, where this movie was shot FIFTY YEARS AGO... and they are celebrating that anniversary in Cherbourg pulling out all the stops. It seems that the filming on that location 50 years ago was a big happening for this small and quiet coal town, apparently very dirty and facing away from the waterfront (now they have changed that concept and all new buildings are facing the waters) since then the huge popularity of this movie worldwide was such a ground shaking event for the inhabitants that they became aware of their own ignored potential and started to change everything, renovating shops and cleaning the city, to such an extent that nowadays the place is unrecognizable from its past dreary image. Japanese tourist go there to visit the umbrella shop where part of the action takes place (still looking and functioning like then) and even French people go there to visit the shop and take pictures!! During these fifty years Catherine Deneuve appeared in 117 films, leaving behind an enormous quantity of documentation to her legendary ice blonde beauty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Sweet Film."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manendra-lodhi (manendra.lodhi@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art cannot be for someone who fears. The director's approach fits in this quote. When I learned (before seeing the film) that it was a musical, I expected a rip off of the sound of Music. But when I started watching, everything started to look weird. All the dialogs in the film are in a musical way. You start to feel funny and irritated at the same time. The story is a very general, so do not expect much from it. It is just one normal love story that has a neutral ending with a good message. But what makes the film a must watch is its colorful cinematography. If for the first few minutes you are feeling irritated because of the musical dialogs then just wait some more and you will find yourself completely immersed in the film. After a time the dialogs, with music and everything look so normal that even such a predictable story can make you feel happy. It needed a lot of faith to make a film like this. The director has given a beautiful film which is definitely going to make you feel lighter. The most charming thing of the film is that none of the characters is shown as evil. It is the circumstances that are acting here as the obstacles. The film made me remember the films of Ghibli studios by Hayao Miyazaki. The film won the Palme d or in its time. But this is not the reason why you should be watching this, but that it is very much watchable in its own weird way. MESSAGE: "Life" VERDICT: "A recommended watch."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch it for the music, the colors, the story, and for the diving Ms. Deneuve
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    info-2752
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always associated my favorite musicals with Broadway, apart from this one, which is up there with my top three favorites. Filed as a love story, it also makes my top three. And Catherine Deneuve? She's definitely in my top three most beautiful actresses of all time. Then there's Michel Legrand, my second favorite composer (after Chopin, and if you must know, the third ones would be the Lennon/McCartney collaboration). How does one get so willingly hooked to a movie? Just sample the first five minutes of it, you don't even wait for the first lines of song to realize you're in for a gem of a film. Before you hear any of it, the sets are bound to get you. For the colors, those vibrant, palpable colors are a veritable visual feast. And have I mentioned the divine Catherine Deneuve? If there's anything most likely to distract your attention from the sets, it would be her presence. And last, but not least, for long after you may have forgotten the plot, you will never forget this: that melodious, hummable music, a song most of us associate with having heard from childhood, that beautifully threads the scenes of the story together--and you have the perfect musical. The most poignant love story (reminiscent of Splendor in the Grass, another coming-of-age film with a most genetically- blessed lead actors), with an ending that breaks the heart, but one which I completely approve of!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful--But Where's the Blu-Ray?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    t_k_matthews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most beautiful movies ever made deserves a Blu-Ray release. I first saw "The Umbrellas of Cherbourg" a few years ago on cable with a dinosaur CRT television, and even in that format it glowed. I want to buy the disc, but I'm holding out for Blu-Ray. The movie is stunning in every way. I can imagine a couple of female friends sharing a bottle of wine and a box of Kleenex and having a good, purifying cry. It is everything that a filmed romance should be, an amazing sung story of lost love, with a poignant ending that is--depending on your viewpoint--sweetly happy or deliciously sad. If you haven't seen it yet, don't wait--see it now on DVD. Those of us who have already seen it will patiently await the Blu-Ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Under my umbrella (Ella ella eh eh eh)"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Checking a selection of Euro Art-films which my dad had kindly picked up on Video for me,I was pleased to see that one of the movies starred an actress who I had first her about in connection to a 1977 Giallo called Anima Persa.Taking another look at the case for the Catherine Deneuve movie,something about its title "clicked" with me in an odd way.Searching round on IMDb,I quickly got the answer,when I found that the film had been chosen for the IMDb's Indian Cinema board's next joint viewing,which led me to grabbing my umbrella,and getting ready to come face to face with Deneuve for the first time. The plot: Returning home from a wonderful date with the man of her dreams:Roland Cassard,Genevieve Emery is met with the stern face from her mother,who drains all the joy out of Genevieve's cheeks.Ignoring her mum's (who also works with her daughter in an umbrella shop) extremely vocal disagreement's about her "not knowing what real love is",and also that it is "Far too soon to be talking about marriage", Genevieve continues to have fantastic dates with Cassard.Feeling a deeper sense of intimacy with Roland, Genevieve decides to show the passion and intimacy that has grown between herself and Cassard by going to bed with him.Basking in the glow of the tightening of their bond, Genevieve and Cassard's romance is torn in two,due to Roland being drafted for a 2 year tour of duty in the Algerian War.Shortly after Roland leaves for his tour of duty, Genevieve discovers that she is pregnant with Cassard's child.As the months go by, Genevieve starts to fearfully take her mums words to heart,that Roland may possibly never return to her from his tour of duty. View on the film: Using the opening of the movie to have Roland Cassard take the audience into the film's startling Technicolour world,writer/director Jacques Demy teams up with costume designer Jacquline Moreau to smartly contrast the dark troubles facing Roland and Genevieve's families by aw-ashing the film in dazzling,flowing colours,which along with perfectly matching the detailed costume work of Moreau,also creates a lively atmosphere as the couples relationship increases in passion.Along with the shining colours, Demy also uses expertly stylised constantly moving,long tracking shots to show the life is so exciting and fast moving that Genevieve and Roland don't have a change to notice the changing backgrounds,until freezing the camera,to show the harsh,war light of reality hitting the couple's dream.For the screenplay, (all of which is sung!) Demy shows an impressive restrain of not including any fiddly,overly complicated words,but to instead go for something much more brilliantly simplistic,that allows the viewing to be completely caught,in the pure joy of Genevieve and Cassard's dates.With sharing almost every scene with each other for the first half the film, the beautiful Catherine Deneuve and Marc Michel each give splendid performances that perfectly compliment each other,with Deneuve showing Genevieve to have stars in her eyes every time she looks at Cassard,whilst Michel shows Roland to be someone who desperately wants to see the same stars that Genevieve does,but is sadly unable to get away from the harsh reality taking place around them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danatus-jairus
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1. Coloring, that is absolutely matchless 2. Even the first notes of the main theme make you cry 3. Unique way of singing in a musical 4. One of the most touching love stories 5. Beautiful Catherine Deneuve 6. It's not American 7. Made in the sixties 8. You can watch it over and over again 9. Since you've once seen it.. you must watch it over and over again 10. Esso-scene Ten more or less good reasons why this just might be the one.. the favorite movie of mine. I partly understand people who hate it, the singing is the main reason i think. But the unique way of singing! Not in the traditional way this is a musical, people just happen to sing when they talk. And the music (especially main theme) is so hauntingly beautiful it really does make you want to cry when you hear the first notes. The coloring is like in no other film. The clothing and background have been matched in every single scene of the movie. That's real cinema, that's beautiful! And if that's beautiful already, then what comes when the 20-year old Catherine Deneuve is in the lead role! Just WOW! Once again I don't bother explaining any of the plot, because there's no point really...but one of the saddest scenes in movie history, is the Esso-scene in this one. Watch it! if you're not too busy watching the latest Van-Damme.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie hasn't made me shed tears since A.I. until I watched this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joey Lan
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the credits rolled, I sat there with a tear streak still remaining on my face from a minute passed. I was bewildered. Bewildered by how this movie managed to invoke such strong emotion in me. It isn't a particularly sad movie. I'm not a even French movie buff. I'm not sure if I've even seen a French movie before. The movie is set in the small town of Cherbourg, France from 1957 to 1963. The walls are still all brick and mortar, covered with vibrant colors, hand painted on. Young Genevieve (Catherine Deneuve) lives with her protective mother (Anne Vernon) and together they run a quaint Umbrella shop in Cherbourg, France. Genevieve and Guy (Nino Castelnuovo) , a car mechanic at a local garage, are deeply in love and contemplate marriage but they are forced to put everything on hold as Guy (prounounced Gee in Geese) goes to serve his mandatory two years in the French army. Can their love survive the separation while she is being pushed by her mother to marry a rich jewel merchant by the name of Cassard (Marc Michel) in Guy's absence? It is a quintessential love story. Catherine Deneuve is breathtakingly beautiful. The characters are memorable and their personalities distinct. You might find that their relationship interactions a bit funny by modern standards but remember, this is set in the late 50s. Back when it was normal for ladies to lean on their partner's chest and caress his hands lovingly with their face.....while being pet like a cat. Still it added to the charm of the movie. The daintiness of the Genevieve that is, not the petting. The movie breaks down into four acts. After each act the movie fades to black and you are briefed on the next act. If you went and saw this movie upon its release, you went to the theater to watch......theater. One thing to note is that this is a different form of musical. ALL of the dialogue is sung instead of having musical numbers fitted in between spoken dialogue. The only other movie I've ever seen that has all the dialogue sung is "Repo the Genetic Opera". Imagine a gothicized Paris doing a musical number; Enough said. This one's much better. Back to the movie at hand, Michael Legrand could not have composed a more beautiful and fitting orchestral score. I must mention that the score is continuous throughout the whole movie from beginning to end. And it led to a beautiful song covered many great artists. The definitive and most haunting version by Connie Francis; Titled, "I will wait for you". The cinematography translates the charm of Cherbourg to film, wonderfully. The shots are simple and effective. My favorite shot in the movie is that of a departing train. I have seen my share of train scenes but I don't remember seeing it ever done this way. I recommend this movie, unless you despise theater, can't stand orchestral music and refer to French fries as Freedom Fries. I recommend watching it with your significant other (for maximum effect) and staring into their soul after the movie ends. Then put on some Marvin Gaye and get it on while keeping in mind that tomorrow may never come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ageless jazz opera
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film like this makes me think of my own life choices. It starts out like a painting that comes to life, set in the ancient port town of Cherbourg. (I was surprised to read on Wikipedia that a U.S. Civil War battle was fought off its shores.) From the cobblestone streets to the jewel-box storefronts to the grease monkeys at Guy's garage, this film is a joy to behold. And with Michel LeGrand's score, a delight to listen to. As a Francophile, I wish I could find a copy of its script. I enjoyed the crisp simplicity of the entirely sung dialogue. Adding to the satisfying unity of "Parapluies" is its perfect casting. Catherine Deneuve convinces as a rebellious daughter, infatuated teen, and bemused unwed woman with child. Her own mother, played fascinatingly by Anne Vernon, probably experienced the same out-of-wedlock pregnancy as she did. Clearly, Mme. Emery is attracted to M. Cassard, yet her only conscious wish is for the security of her only child. The mother-daughter relationship here is one of almost-total miscomprehension. Cassard (a dapper Marc Michel) is interesting to watch as the wealthy, somewhat bloodless suitor who actually travels with a crown, ready-made to place on his lady love's head! Nino Castelnuovo is superb as Guy, along with Ellen Farner as Madeleine. I enjoyed the range that Castelnuovo demonstrated, going from carefree lover to read-to-serve draftee, to depressed and acting-out Algerian War vet. The conversation between Guy and Madeleine, prior to marriage, is one of stunningly convincing depth, though its words are few. Of course, the final scene of this film unforgettable. I've seen "Parapluies" no fewer than five times and this viewing I cried perhaps more than ever, due to evermore bittersweet experience of my own under my belt. This must be one of those movies that never grows old. Its haunting melodies soothe and inspire me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Umbrellas of Cherbourg
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I read the title for this film in the book of 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die I knew it was a foreign film, from France, but I had no idea it was a musical, so I was most intrigued to watch, from director Jacques Demy (Lola, The Young Girls of Rochefort). Basically seventeen year old Genevi&egrave;ve Emery (Catherine Deneuve) lives in an umbrella shop in Cherbourg with her widowed mother Madame Emery (Anne Vernon), and she is secretly in love with twenty year old auto mechanic Guy Foucher (Nino Castelnuovo), and the two of them want to get married. She reveals this to her mother however, and she objects thinking that her daughter is too young and that he is not mature and well-established enough, and he may be required to do military service, and shortly later he is sent to Algeria after being drafted to serve in the war, but before leaving he and Genevi&egrave;ve consummate their love. Following this Genevi&egrave;ve is pregnant, while he is away he hardly communicates and they have drifted apart, so she listens to her mother's strong encouragement to accept a marriage proposal from Roland Cassard (Marc Michel) (he previously appeared as the same character in the film Lola), the affluent gem dealer who is in love with her and promises to bring her child up as his own. Guy is discharged from service before his two year term is up due to being wounded, he returns home and finds out Genevi&egrave;ve is married with a child and has moved away, and following this he sinks into deep depression and anger, which he struggles to control. But Guy recovers from his state when he falls in love and married young Madeleine (Ellen Farner) who had been caring for his aunt &Eacute;lise (Mireille Perrey), who is now deceased, and she left him an inheritance which he uses to fulfil his ambition to open a service station. Years pass, and Genevi&egrave;ve, who is now discernibly wealthy, has returned home with Fran&ccedil;oise (Rosalie Varda), her and Guy's daughter, and have an accidental meeting at his service station, their short conversation is obviously filled with unuttered fondness and regret, and in the end they finally part ways. Also starring Jean Champion as Aubin and Harald Wolff as Monsieur Dubourg. Deneuve is beautiful and gives a great delicate performance as the young woman longing for love from one man until fate changes everything, Castelnuovo is interesting as the man who is in and out of her life, and Michel is likable as the wealthy man with good intentions. The story is relatively simple, complicated romance, but what makes this musically distinctive is that every scene has singing, from the most mundane conversations to emotionally charging moments every word is spoken and sun in tune, and the picture has good use of vivid colour and design as well, it is a fantastic musical. It was nominated the Oscar for Best Song for "I Will Wait for You", Best Original Music for Michel Legrand and Jacques Demy, Best Music Adaptation or Treatment for Michel Legrand, Best Writing, Story and Screenplay - Written Directly for the Screen for Demy and Best Foreign Language Film, and it was nominated the Golden Globe for Best Foreign-Language Foreign Film. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A musical that compares the expectations of love with the harsh realities. The heart sings and breaks.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Umbrellas of Cherbourg is a unique film experiment. It's a musical where every line is sung. Even the mundane lines which have little to do with the film. While this style could be expected to be under threat of being too sweet, the film avoids this by approaching sentimentality with heart-wrenching reality, which the musical aspect of the film highlights. It's a love story. And the film is aware that it begins as a movie love story, addressed by the fact that the protagonist genuinely expects to die if they are parted. Instead of dying, the film explores one of my favourite deep subjects in art, by comparing the expectations of love brought on by pop culture with the harsh reality without being overdramatic. It's nostalgic and extremely genuine. As expected, the omnipresent music is absolutely wonderful and can speak for the film's emotion even without translation. How they managed to fit in the dialogue so fluently is incredible, let alone perform it. The set decoration and costume design is another highlight as well, with bright and bold colours, which the sweeping camera movement compliments perfectly. Despite the broad story, the film is surprisingly small scale with a limited use of sets, but the colour palette makes the world feel huge. There's some incredible use of match cuts as well. Though this film has a fantastic and charming atmosphere, it's the simple and effective storytelling that makes it, particularly the heartbreaking and subtle end. Bona fide classic. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    115 reviews so far...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Traversa
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... and they condense every possible information and observation one can make about this awesome movie. I will see it again out of an intense curiosity and nostalgia (I saw it many years ago and left me flabbergasted --patidifuso-- with all its fantastic beauty) after having listened the radio program I mention further down. I write these lines not to review one more time the film, but just to comment that I was listening a radio program from France Culture radio and they made a reportage about Cherbourg, where this movie was shot FIFTY YEARS AGO... and they are celebrating that anniversary in Cherbourg pulling out all the stops. It seems that the filming on that location 50 years ago was a big happening for this small and quiet coal town, apparently very dirty and facing away from the waterfront (now they have changed that concept and all new buildings are facing the waters) since then the huge popularity of this movie worldwide was such a ground shaking event for the inhabitants that they became aware of their own ignored potential and started to change everything, renovating shops and cleaning the city, to such an extent that nowadays the place is unrecognizable from its past dreary image. Japanese tourist go there to visit the umbrella shop where part of the action takes place (still looking and functioning like then) and even French people go there to visit the shop and take pictures!! During these fifty years Catherine Deneuve appeared in 117 films, leaving behind an enormous quantity of documentation to her legendary ice blonde beauty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Sweet Film."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manendra-lodhi (manendra.lodhi@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art cannot be for someone who fears. The director's approach fits in this quote. When I learned (before seeing the film) that it was a musical, I expected a rip off of the sound of Music. But when I started watching, everything started to look weird. All the dialogs in the film are in a musical way. You start to feel funny and irritated at the same time. The story is a very general, so do not expect much from it. It is just one normal love story that has a neutral ending with a good message. But what makes the film a must watch is its colorful cinematography. If for the first few minutes you are feeling irritated because of the musical dialogs then just wait some more and you will find yourself completely immersed in the film. After a time the dialogs, with music and everything look so normal that even such a predictable story can make you feel happy. It needed a lot of faith to make a film like this. The director has given a beautiful film which is definitely going to make you feel lighter. The most charming thing of the film is that none of the characters is shown as evil. It is the circumstances that are acting here as the obstacles. The film made me remember the films of Ghibli studios by Hayao Miyazaki. The film won the Palme d or in its time. But this is not the reason why you should be watching this, but that it is very much watchable in its own weird way. MESSAGE: "Life" VERDICT: "A recommended watch."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch it for the music, the colors, the story, and for the diving Ms. Deneuve
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    info-2752
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always associated my favorite musicals with Broadway, apart from this one, which is up there with my top three favorites. Filed as a love story, it also makes my top three. And Catherine Deneuve? She's definitely in my top three most beautiful actresses of all time. Then there's Michel Legrand, my second favorite composer (after Chopin, and if you must know, the third ones would be the Lennon/McCartney collaboration). How does one get so willingly hooked to a movie? Just sample the first five minutes of it, you don't even wait for the first lines of song to realize you're in for a gem of a film. Before you hear any of it, the sets are bound to get you. For the colors, those vibrant, palpable colors are a veritable visual feast. And have I mentioned the divine Catherine Deneuve? If there's anything most likely to distract your attention from the sets, it would be her presence. And last, but not least, for long after you may have forgotten the plot, you will never forget this: that melodious, hummable music, a song most of us associate with having heard from childhood, that beautifully threads the scenes of the story together--and you have the perfect musical. The most poignant love story (reminiscent of Splendor in the Grass, another coming-of-age film with a most genetically- blessed lead actors), with an ending that breaks the heart, but one which I completely approve of!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful--But Where's the Blu-Ray?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    t_k_matthews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most beautiful movies ever made deserves a Blu-Ray release. I first saw "The Umbrellas of Cherbourg" a few years ago on cable with a dinosaur CRT television, and even in that format it glowed. I want to buy the disc, but I'm holding out for Blu-Ray. The movie is stunning in every way. I can imagine a couple of female friends sharing a bottle of wine and a box of Kleenex and having a good, purifying cry. It is everything that a filmed romance should be, an amazing sung story of lost love, with a poignant ending that is--depending on your viewpoint--sweetly happy or deliciously sad. If you haven't seen it yet, don't wait--see it now on DVD. Those of us who have already seen it will patiently await the Blu-Ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Under my umbrella (Ella ella eh eh eh)"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Checking a selection of Euro Art-films which my dad had kindly picked up on Video for me,I was pleased to see that one of the movies starred an actress who I had first her about in connection to a 1977 Giallo called Anima Persa.Taking another look at the case for the Catherine Deneuve movie,something about its title "clicked" with me in an odd way.Searching round on IMDb,I quickly got the answer,when I found that the film had been chosen for the IMDb's Indian Cinema board's next joint viewing,which led me to grabbing my umbrella,and getting ready to come face to face with Deneuve for the first time. The plot: Returning home from a wonderful date with the man of her dreams:Roland Cassard,Genevieve Emery is met with the stern face from her mother,who drains all the joy out of Genevieve's cheeks.Ignoring her mum's (who also works with her daughter in an umbrella shop) extremely vocal disagreement's about her "not knowing what real love is",and also that it is "Far too soon to be talking about marriage", Genevieve continues to have fantastic dates with Cassard.Feeling a deeper sense of intimacy with Roland, Genevieve decides to show the passion and intimacy that has grown between herself and Cassard by going to bed with him.Basking in the glow of the tightening of their bond, Genevieve and Cassard's romance is torn in two,due to Roland being drafted for a 2 year tour of duty in the Algerian War.Shortly after Roland leaves for his tour of duty, Genevieve discovers that she is pregnant with Cassard's child.As the months go by, Genevieve starts to fearfully take her mums words to heart,that Roland may possibly never return to her from his tour of duty. View on the film: Using the opening of the movie to have Roland Cassard take the audience into the film's startling Technicolour world,writer/director Jacques Demy teams up with costume designer Jacquline Moreau to smartly contrast the dark troubles facing Roland and Genevieve's families by aw-ashing the film in dazzling,flowing colours,which along with perfectly matching the detailed costume work of Moreau,also creates a lively atmosphere as the couples relationship increases in passion.Along with the shining colours, Demy also uses expertly stylised constantly moving,long tracking shots to show the life is so exciting and fast moving that Genevieve and Roland don't have a change to notice the changing backgrounds,until freezing the camera,to show the harsh,war light of reality hitting the couple's dream.For the screenplay, (all of which is sung!) Demy shows an impressive restrain of not including any fiddly,overly complicated words,but to instead go for something much more brilliantly simplistic,that allows the viewing to be completely caught,in the pure joy of Genevieve and Cassard's dates.With sharing almost every scene with each other for the first half the film, the beautiful Catherine Deneuve and Marc Michel each give splendid performances that perfectly compliment each other,with Deneuve showing Genevieve to have stars in her eyes every time she looks at Cassard,whilst Michel shows Roland to be someone who desperately wants to see the same stars that Genevieve does,but is sadly unable to get away from the harsh reality taking place around them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danatus-jairus
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1. Coloring, that is absolutely matchless 2. Even the first notes of the main theme make you cry 3. Unique way of singing in a musical 4. One of the most touching love stories 5. Beautiful Catherine Deneuve 6. It's not American 7. Made in the sixties 8. You can watch it over and over again 9. Since you've once seen it.. you must watch it over and over again 10. Esso-scene Ten more or less good reasons why this just might be the one.. the favorite movie of mine. I partly understand people who hate it, the singing is the main reason i think. But the unique way of singing! Not in the traditional way this is a musical, people just happen to sing when they talk. And the music (especially main theme) is so hauntingly beautiful it really does make you want to cry when you hear the first notes. The coloring is like in no other film. The clothing and background have been matched in every single scene of the movie. That's real cinema, that's beautiful! And if that's beautiful already, then what comes when the 20-year old Catherine Deneuve is in the lead role! Just WOW! Once again I don't bother explaining any of the plot, because there's no point really...but one of the saddest scenes in movie history, is the Esso-scene in this one. Watch it! if you're not too busy watching the latest Van-Damme.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie hasn't made me shed tears since A.I. until I watched this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joey Lan
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the credits rolled, I sat there with a tear streak still remaining on my face from a minute passed. I was bewildered. Bewildered by how this movie managed to invoke such strong emotion in me. It isn't a particularly sad movie. I'm not a even French movie buff. I'm not sure if I've even seen a French movie before. The movie is set in the small town of Cherbourg, France from 1957 to 1963. The walls are still all brick and mortar, covered with vibrant colors, hand painted on. Young Genevieve (Catherine Deneuve) lives with her protective mother (Anne Vernon) and together they run a quaint Umbrella shop in Cherbourg, France. Genevieve and Guy (Nino Castelnuovo) , a car mechanic at a local garage, are deeply in love and contemplate marriage but they are forced to put everything on hold as Guy (prounounced Gee in Geese) goes to serve his mandatory two years in the French army. Can their love survive the separation while she is being pushed by her mother to marry a rich jewel merchant by the name of Cassard (Marc Michel) in Guy's absence? It is a quintessential love story. Catherine Deneuve is breathtakingly beautiful. The characters are memorable and their personalities distinct. You might find that their relationship interactions a bit funny by modern standards but remember, this is set in the late 50s. Back when it was normal for ladies to lean on their partner's chest and caress his hands lovingly with their face.....while being pet like a cat. Still it added to the charm of the movie. The daintiness of the Genevieve that is, not the petting. The movie breaks down into four acts. After each act the movie fades to black and you are briefed on the next act. If you went and saw this movie upon its release, you went to the theater to watch......theater. One thing to note is that this is a different form of musical. ALL of the dialogue is sung instead of having musical numbers fitted in between spoken dialogue. The only other movie I've ever seen that has all the dialogue sung is "Repo the Genetic Opera". Imagine a gothicized Paris doing a musical number; Enough said. This one's much better. Back to the movie at hand, Michael Legrand could not have composed a more beautiful and fitting orchestral score. I must mention that the score is continuous throughout the whole movie from beginning to end. And it led to a beautiful song covered many great artists. The definitive and most haunting version by Connie Francis; Titled, "I will wait for you". The cinematography translates the charm of Cherbourg to film, wonderfully. The shots are simple and effective. My favorite shot in the movie is that of a departing train. I have seen my share of train scenes but I don't remember seeing it ever done this way. I recommend this movie, unless you despise theater, can't stand orchestral music and refer to French fries as Freedom Fries. I recommend watching it with your significant other (for maximum effect) and staring into their soul after the movie ends. Then put on some Marvin Gaye and get it on while keeping in mind that tomorrow may never come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ageless jazz opera
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film like this makes me think of my own life choices. It starts out like a painting that comes to life, set in the ancient port town of Cherbourg. (I was surprised to read on Wikipedia that a U.S. Civil War battle was fought off its shores.) From the cobblestone streets to the jewel-box storefronts to the grease monkeys at Guy's garage, this film is a joy to behold. And with Michel LeGrand's score, a delight to listen to. As a Francophile, I wish I could find a copy of its script. I enjoyed the crisp simplicity of the entirely sung dialogue. Adding to the satisfying unity of "Parapluies" is its perfect casting. Catherine Deneuve convinces as a rebellious daughter, infatuated teen, and bemused unwed woman with child. Her own mother, played fascinatingly by Anne Vernon, probably experienced the same out-of-wedlock pregnancy as she did. Clearly, Mme. Emery is attracted to M. Cassard, yet her only conscious wish is for the security of her only child. The mother-daughter relationship here is one of almost-total miscomprehension. Cassard (a dapper Marc Michel) is interesting to watch as the wealthy, somewhat bloodless suitor who actually travels with a crown, ready-made to place on his lady love's head! Nino Castelnuovo is superb as Guy, along with Ellen Farner as Madeleine. I enjoyed the range that Castelnuovo demonstrated, going from carefree lover to read-to-serve draftee, to depressed and acting-out Algerian War vet. The conversation between Guy and Madeleine, prior to marriage, is one of stunningly convincing depth, though its words are few. Of course, the final scene of this film unforgettable. I've seen "Parapluies" no fewer than five times and this viewing I cried perhaps more than ever, due to evermore bittersweet experience of my own under my belt. This must be one of those movies that never grows old. Its haunting melodies soothe and inspire me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Umbrellas of Cherbourg
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I read the title for this film in the book of 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die I knew it was a foreign film, from France, but I had no idea it was a musical, so I was most intrigued to watch, from director Jacques Demy (Lola, The Young Girls of Rochefort). Basically seventeen year old Genevi&egrave;ve Emery (Catherine Deneuve) lives in an umbrella shop in Cherbourg with her widowed mother Madame Emery (Anne Vernon), and she is secretly in love with twenty year old auto mechanic Guy Foucher (Nino Castelnuovo), and the two of them want to get married. She reveals this to her mother however, and she objects thinking that her daughter is too young and that he is not mature and well-established enough, and he may be required to do military service, and shortly later he is sent to Algeria after being drafted to serve in the war, but before leaving he and Genevi&egrave;ve consummate their love. Following this Genevi&egrave;ve is pregnant, while he is away he hardly communicates and they have drifted apart, so she listens to her mother's strong encouragement to accept a marriage proposal from Roland Cassard (Marc Michel) (he previously appeared as the same character in the film Lola), the affluent gem dealer who is in love with her and promises to bring her child up as his own. Guy is discharged from service before his two year term is up due to being wounded, he returns home and finds out Genevi&egrave;ve is married with a child and has moved away, and following this he sinks into deep depression and anger, which he struggles to control. But Guy recovers from his state when he falls in love and married young Madeleine (Ellen Farner) who had been caring for his aunt &Eacute;lise (Mireille Perrey), who is now deceased, and she left him an inheritance which he uses to fulfil his ambition to open a service station. Years pass, and Genevi&egrave;ve, who is now discernibly wealthy, has returned home with Fran&ccedil;oise (Rosalie Varda), her and Guy's daughter, and have an accidental meeting at his service station, their short conversation is obviously filled with unuttered fondness and regret, and in the end they finally part ways. Also starring Jean Champion as Aubin and Harald Wolff as Monsieur Dubourg. Deneuve is beautiful and gives a great delicate performance as the young woman longing for love from one man until fate changes everything, Castelnuovo is interesting as the man who is in and out of her life, and Michel is likable as the wealthy man with good intentions. The story is relatively simple, complicated romance, but what makes this musically distinctive is that every scene has singing, from the most mundane conversations to emotionally charging moments every word is spoken and sun in tune, and the picture has good use of vivid colour and design as well, it is a fantastic musical. It was nominated the Oscar for Best Song for "I Will Wait for You", Best Original Music for Michel Legrand and Jacques Demy, Best Music Adaptation or Treatment for Michel Legrand, Best Writing, Story and Screenplay - Written Directly for the Screen for Demy and Best Foreign Language Film, and it was nominated the Golden Globe for Best Foreign-Language Foreign Film. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A musical that compares the expectations of love with the harsh realities. The heart sings and breaks.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Umbrellas of Cherbourg is a unique film experiment. It's a musical where every line is sung. Even the mundane lines which have little to do with the film. While this style could be expected to be under threat of being too sweet, the film avoids this by approaching sentimentality with heart-wrenching reality, which the musical aspect of the film highlights. It's a love story. And the film is aware that it begins as a movie love story, addressed by the fact that the protagonist genuinely expects to die if they are parted. Instead of dying, the film explores one of my favourite deep subjects in art, by comparing the expectations of love brought on by pop culture with the harsh reality without being overdramatic. It's nostalgic and extremely genuine. As expected, the omnipresent music is absolutely wonderful and can speak for the film's emotion even without translation. How they managed to fit in the dialogue so fluently is incredible, let alone perform it. The set decoration and costume design is another highlight as well, with bright and bold colours, which the sweeping camera movement compliments perfectly. Despite the broad story, the film is surprisingly small scale with a limited use of sets, but the colour palette makes the world feel huge. There's some incredible use of match cuts as well. Though this film has a fantastic and charming atmosphere, it's the simple and effective storytelling that makes it, particularly the heartbreaking and subtle end. Bona fide classic. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    115 reviews so far...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Traversa
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... and they condense every possible information and observation one can make about this awesome movie. I will see it again out of an intense curiosity and nostalgia (I saw it many years ago and left me flabbergasted --patidifuso-- with all its fantastic beauty) after having listened the radio program I mention further down. I write these lines not to review one more time the film, but just to comment that I was listening a radio program from France Culture radio and they made a reportage about Cherbourg, where this movie was shot FIFTY YEARS AGO... and they are celebrating that anniversary in Cherbourg pulling out all the stops. It seems that the filming on that location 50 years ago was a big happening for this small and quiet coal town, apparently very dirty and facing away from the waterfront (now they have changed that concept and all new buildings are facing the waters) since then the huge popularity of this movie worldwide was such a ground shaking event for the inhabitants that they became aware of their own ignored potential and started to change everything, renovating shops and cleaning the city, to such an extent that nowadays the place is unrecognizable from its past dreary image. Japanese tourist go there to visit the umbrella shop where part of the action takes place (still looking and functioning like then) and even French people go there to visit the shop and take pictures!! During these fifty years Catherine Deneuve appeared in 117 films, leaving behind an enormous quantity of documentation to her legendary ice blonde beauty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Sweet Film."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manendra-lodhi (manendra.lodhi@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art cannot be for someone who fears. The director's approach fits in this quote. When I learned (before seeing the film) that it was a musical, I expected a rip off of the sound of Music. But when I started watching, everything started to look weird. All the dialogs in the film are in a musical way. You start to feel funny and irritated at the same time. The story is a very general, so do not expect much from it. It is just one normal love story that has a neutral ending with a good message. But what makes the film a must watch is its colorful cinematography. If for the first few minutes you are feeling irritated because of the musical dialogs then just wait some more and you will find yourself completely immersed in the film. After a time the dialogs, with music and everything look so normal that even such a predictable story can make you feel happy. It needed a lot of faith to make a film like this. The director has given a beautiful film which is definitely going to make you feel lighter. The most charming thing of the film is that none of the characters is shown as evil. It is the circumstances that are acting here as the obstacles. The film made me remember the films of Ghibli studios by Hayao Miyazaki. The film won the Palme d or in its time. But this is not the reason why you should be watching this, but that it is very much watchable in its own weird way. MESSAGE: "Life" VERDICT: "A recommended watch."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch it for the music, the colors, the story, and for the diving Ms. Deneuve
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    info-2752
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always associated my favorite musicals with Broadway, apart from this one, which is up there with my top three favorites. Filed as a love story, it also makes my top three. And Catherine Deneuve? She's definitely in my top three most beautiful actresses of all time. Then there's Michel Legrand, my second favorite composer (after Chopin, and if you must know, the third ones would be the Lennon/McCartney collaboration). How does one get so willingly hooked to a movie? Just sample the first five minutes of it, you don't even wait for the first lines of song to realize you're in for a gem of a film. Before you hear any of it, the sets are bound to get you. For the colors, those vibrant, palpable colors are a veritable visual feast. And have I mentioned the divine Catherine Deneuve? If there's anything most likely to distract your attention from the sets, it would be her presence. And last, but not least, for long after you may have forgotten the plot, you will never forget this: that melodious, hummable music, a song most of us associate with having heard from childhood, that beautifully threads the scenes of the story together--and you have the perfect musical. The most poignant love story (reminiscent of Splendor in the Grass, another coming-of-age film with a most genetically- blessed lead actors), with an ending that breaks the heart, but one which I completely approve of!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful--But Where's the Blu-Ray?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    t_k_matthews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most beautiful movies ever made deserves a Blu-Ray release. I first saw "The Umbrellas of Cherbourg" a few years ago on cable with a dinosaur CRT television, and even in that format it glowed. I want to buy the disc, but I'm holding out for Blu-Ray. The movie is stunning in every way. I can imagine a couple of female friends sharing a bottle of wine and a box of Kleenex and having a good, purifying cry. It is everything that a filmed romance should be, an amazing sung story of lost love, with a poignant ending that is--depending on your viewpoint--sweetly happy or deliciously sad. If you haven't seen it yet, don't wait--see it now on DVD. Those of us who have already seen it will patiently await the Blu-Ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Under my umbrella (Ella ella eh eh eh)"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Checking a selection of Euro Art-films which my dad had kindly picked up on Video for me,I was pleased to see that one of the movies starred an actress who I had first her about in connection to a 1977 Giallo called Anima Persa.Taking another look at the case for the Catherine Deneuve movie,something about its title "clicked" with me in an odd way.Searching round on IMDb,I quickly got the answer,when I found that the film had been chosen for the IMDb's Indian Cinema board's next joint viewing,which led me to grabbing my umbrella,and getting ready to come face to face with Deneuve for the first time. The plot: Returning home from a wonderful date with the man of her dreams:Roland Cassard,Genevieve Emery is met with the stern face from her mother,who drains all the joy out of Genevieve's cheeks.Ignoring her mum's (who also works with her daughter in an umbrella shop) extremely vocal disagreement's about her "not knowing what real love is",and also that it is "Far too soon to be talking about marriage", Genevieve continues to have fantastic dates with Cassard.Feeling a deeper sense of intimacy with Roland, Genevieve decides to show the passion and intimacy that has grown between herself and Cassard by going to bed with him.Basking in the glow of the tightening of their bond, Genevieve and Cassard's romance is torn in two,due to Roland being drafted for a 2 year tour of duty in the Algerian War.Shortly after Roland leaves for his tour of duty, Genevieve discovers that she is pregnant with Cassard's child.As the months go by, Genevieve starts to fearfully take her mums words to heart,that Roland may possibly never return to her from his tour of duty. View on the film: Using the opening of the movie to have Roland Cassard take the audience into the film's startling Technicolour world,writer/director Jacques Demy teams up with costume designer Jacquline Moreau to smartly contrast the dark troubles facing Roland and Genevieve's families by aw-ashing the film in dazzling,flowing colours,which along with perfectly matching the detailed costume work of Moreau,also creates a lively atmosphere as the couples relationship increases in passion.Along with the shining colours, Demy also uses expertly stylised constantly moving,long tracking shots to show the life is so exciting and fast moving that Genevieve and Roland don't have a change to notice the changing backgrounds,until freezing the camera,to show the harsh,war light of reality hitting the couple's dream.For the screenplay, (all of which is sung!) Demy shows an impressive restrain of not including any fiddly,overly complicated words,but to instead go for something much more brilliantly simplistic,that allows the viewing to be completely caught,in the pure joy of Genevieve and Cassard's dates.With sharing almost every scene with each other for the first half the film, the beautiful Catherine Deneuve and Marc Michel each give splendid performances that perfectly compliment each other,with Deneuve showing Genevieve to have stars in her eyes every time she looks at Cassard,whilst Michel shows Roland to be someone who desperately wants to see the same stars that Genevieve does,but is sadly unable to get away from the harsh reality taking place around them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danatus-jairus
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1. Coloring, that is absolutely matchless 2. Even the first notes of the main theme make you cry 3. Unique way of singing in a musical 4. One of the most touching love stories 5. Beautiful Catherine Deneuve 6. It's not American 7. Made in the sixties 8. You can watch it over and over again 9. Since you've once seen it.. you must watch it over and over again 10. Esso-scene Ten more or less good reasons why this just might be the one.. the favorite movie of mine. I partly understand people who hate it, the singing is the main reason i think. But the unique way of singing! Not in the traditional way this is a musical, people just happen to sing when they talk. And the music (especially main theme) is so hauntingly beautiful it really does make you want to cry when you hear the first notes. The coloring is like in no other film. The clothing and background have been matched in every single scene of the movie. That's real cinema, that's beautiful! And if that's beautiful already, then what comes when the 20-year old Catherine Deneuve is in the lead role! Just WOW! Once again I don't bother explaining any of the plot, because there's no point really...but one of the saddest scenes in movie history, is the Esso-scene in this one. Watch it! if you're not too busy watching the latest Van-Damme.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie hasn't made me shed tears since A.I. until I watched this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joey Lan
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the credits rolled, I sat there with a tear streak still remaining on my face from a minute passed. I was bewildered. Bewildered by how this movie managed to invoke such strong emotion in me. It isn't a particularly sad movie. I'm not a even French movie buff. I'm not sure if I've even seen a French movie before. The movie is set in the small town of Cherbourg, France from 1957 to 1963. The walls are still all brick and mortar, covered with vibrant colors, hand painted on. Young Genevieve (Catherine Deneuve) lives with her protective mother (Anne Vernon) and together they run a quaint Umbrella shop in Cherbourg, France. Genevieve and Guy (Nino Castelnuovo) , a car mechanic at a local garage, are deeply in love and contemplate marriage but they are forced to put everything on hold as Guy (prounounced Gee in Geese) goes to serve his mandatory two years in the French army. Can their love survive the separation while she is being pushed by her mother to marry a rich jewel merchant by the name of Cassard (Marc Michel) in Guy's absence? It is a quintessential love story. Catherine Deneuve is breathtakingly beautiful. The characters are memorable and their personalities distinct. You might find that their relationship interactions a bit funny by modern standards but remember, this is set in the late 50s. Back when it was normal for ladies to lean on their partner's chest and caress his hands lovingly with their face.....while being pet like a cat. Still it added to the charm of the movie. The daintiness of the Genevieve that is, not the petting. The movie breaks down into four acts. After each act the movie fades to black and you are briefed on the next act. If you went and saw this movie upon its release, you went to the theater to watch......theater. One thing to note is that this is a different form of musical. ALL of the dialogue is sung instead of having musical numbers fitted in between spoken dialogue. The only other movie I've ever seen that has all the dialogue sung is "Repo the Genetic Opera". Imagine a gothicized Paris doing a musical number; Enough said. This one's much better. Back to the movie at hand, Michael Legrand could not have composed a more beautiful and fitting orchestral score. I must mention that the score is continuous throughout the whole movie from beginning to end. And it led to a beautiful song covered many great artists. The definitive and most haunting version by Connie Francis; Titled, "I will wait for you". The cinematography translates the charm of Cherbourg to film, wonderfully. The shots are simple and effective. My favorite shot in the movie is that of a departing train. I have seen my share of train scenes but I don't remember seeing it ever done this way. I recommend this movie, unless you despise theater, can't stand orchestral music and refer to French fries as Freedom Fries. I recommend watching it with your significant other (for maximum effect) and staring into their soul after the movie ends. Then put on some Marvin Gaye and get it on while keeping in mind that tomorrow may never come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
