<filme>
 <id>
  1126
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0052027
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1958
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Velho e o Mar
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  An old Cuban fisherman's dry spell is broken when he hooks a gigantic fish that drags him out to sea. Based on Ernest Hemingway's story.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Now an old man, a lifelong fisherman sets out to sea to ply his trade as he has done all of his life. He's not had much good fortune of late and has gone almost three months without a major catch while others are catching one or even two large marlins every week. Many of the locals make fun of him and some say he's too old now to be fishing but he still loves what he does and is encouraged by a young boy who loves him and has faith in him. On this day he hooks the fish of a lifetime, a marlin that is larger than his skiff. As it slowly pulls him out to sea, the old man reminisces about his past, his successes and the high points of his life. When he does finally manage to land the fish he has to fight off sharks who are feeding on it as he tries to return to his Cuban village.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   fish
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   fisherman
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sea
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   cuban
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   old man
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   John Sturges
  </diretor>
  <diretor>
   Henry King
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Ernest Hemingway
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Peter Viertel
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Spencer Tracy
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Felipe Pazos
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Harry Bellaver
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Even without having read the book, the DVD is well worth a look
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Admittedly I've never read the book, so maybe there is some ineffable quality to it that the film lacks. But as a viewer with no firsthand knowledge of the source material, I find the film moving and thought- provoking in the way I imagine the novella to be. The story showcases Spencer Tracy's ability to project restraint and dignity, and his careworn face makes him an ideal choice for the role of the old fisherman. The DVD special features reveal that Hemmingway observed the production and contributed to it as a technical adviser, and there is video footage of the author in a fishing boat during the shoot. The B-reel of the leaping marlin is real and impressive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    parable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the Hemingway novel. as seed for a great film. more than an adaptation, it is a impressive parable about hope, fight, desire and limits. each scene - as perfect circle. the fight against sharks scene - memorable. one of the most powerful roles of Tracy. and beautiful nuances of an extraordinary performance.the beauty of images and precise script are keys of this remarkable movie. a parable - movie because it can be a Christian story about faith and will of God. about ambition and sense of a bitter lesson. about yourself. a fisherman in his boat. a huge fish. and the return to home. all - in powerful light and heavy shadows. parts of a movie about small life things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Those who love to read should enjoy this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SimonJack
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's very rare that a movie is made based on a book while the author is still alive, and the author is an adviser and has an active hand in the shooting and production of the film. Such was the case with this original movie based on the novel, "The Old Man and the Sea," by Ernest Hemingway. So, viewers can be sure that the movie we watch is very likely how Hemingway envisioned the story in his mind as he wrote the book. Hemingway was an adviser on this film, and had creative control over the final draft of the screenplay. He also worked as a second unit director for some of the marlin fishing scenes. And, Warner Brothers used his boat, Pilar, for the camera platform in shooting most of the exteriors in Cuban waters. The scenes of the marlin fight were from film footage of the world's record catch by Alfred C. Glassell, Jr., who also acted as an adviser. I can understand how some people would be put off by this movie. Especially a younger generation that has grown up on constant action, CGI, and so many films of make believe, fantasy or of a comic book nature. But to anyone who loves to read, this movie should be a treat. For about half the film, we see just one person, alone in his boat. He searches for, finally hooks, then struggles and waits patiently for the right time to land his fish. Finally, he fights against sharks in his long trip back to port. During all of this we see what the old man does to outwit his catch, and to fight off the predator sharks. He talks out loud to himself, to God and to the fish. And we hear his thoughts as he ruminates about how he will make it back. Hemingway's words come alive in the thoughts of the old man. Haven't most of us at some time in our lives talked to ourselves out loud, and carried on one-sided discussions in our thoughts. The monologue of the old man alone on the sea with his fish, which he called simply, "Fish," brought the pages of the book to life. All aspects of "The Old Man and Sea" were excellent. Spencer Tracy gave one of his finest performances, and the rest of the cast were very good. The Warner Color was spectacular, and the cinematography and settings were outstanding. John Sturges turned in another great film as director, and the music by Dmitri Tiomkin was perfect for this film. The only reason I don't score this a 10 is because of some small details that are distractions. The film couldn't overcome the obvious differences in seas. The sea is almost dead calm or barely rippling in most of the scenes when the old man is rowing or being pulled by the fish. But in the scene when the fish surfaces, and the old man struggles to wear it down, we see fairly heavy seas, with five to eight foot swells and choppy water. In one scene of the village we see palm trees bending and swaying under heavy winds, so there should at least have been small whitecaps on the water. Another little detail was Tracy's appearance  facial and clothing. He didn't seem to look as haggard as he acted, and his clothes and hat might have shown a little more wear and tear from his ordeal. But overall, this is an excellent movie that will appeal to those who like to read the classics. "The Old Man and the Sea" surely is an American classic. It earned Hemingway a Pulitzer Prize in 1953, and was cited as the significant contribution to his winning the Nobel Prize for Literature in 1954. A priceless bonus on the DVD of this movie is a short video entitled, "Hemingway  The Legend of the Sea." It was a film of a fishing trip in the Caribbean with Hemingway and filmmaker Allen Miner. It shows them landing a huge marlin. And one last piece of trivia  Hemingway and a friend did lose half a huge fish to sharks in real life. They caught a marlin so large that they weren't able to bring it into the boat, and sharks got the tail half of the fish before they got back to port. You can find a photo on the Web that shows the two men standing beside the 500-pound half of a marlin.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    last attempt at greatness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I should first admit that I've never read Ernest Hemingway's novel. My interpretation of John Sturges's adaptation of "The Old Man and the Sea" is that the title character, a Cuban fisherman (Spencer Tracy), is making what appears to be his last attempt at greatness. Teased by everyone for his lack of catch over the past few months, the old man sets out with a well defined goal and does everything that he can to fulfill it. I guess that the movie, released in autumn 1958, also served as a last look at Cuba before the revolution (although a full history of the country requires a much more detailed explanation). Anyway, it's definitely worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Hemingway Classic On Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ernest Hemingway's novella,The Old Man and the Sea was probably extremely difficult to film to begin with, but this didn't stop John Sturges from trying to put Hemingway's tight little character study into film.The Old Man and the Sea is a 1958 film starring Spencer Tracy. The screenplay was adapted by Peter Viertel from the novella and the film was directed by Sturges. Spencer Tracy is the Old Man, a Cuban fisherman who tries to haul in a huge fish that he catches far from shore. Tracy's tiny boat is besieged by sharks and by natural elements, but the Old Man stubbornly sticks to his job. In the end, the fish is nothing more than a skeleton, and the Old Man returns to his tiny hovel. In this movie,Tracy did great great for himself as he was able to put to life a movie the features himself mostly with no other characters involved.I personally could say that he was born to play the old fisherman.As for the screenplay,the movie was a great adaptation of Hemingway's novella.The only negative thing I could say was that the film was very poor in its technical aspects as inconsistencies in very obvious all throughout many scenes.I could have given this movie a 10/10 rating if not for this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best example I can think of to illustrate the word 'padded'.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here is the very simple story in its entirety. An old Cuban man (Tracy) sets out in his small boat to do some fishing. This is NOT fancy stuff--no rods and reels or fancy motors--it's a very simple boat with minimal equipment. Yet, miraculously, the old guy hooks into a HUGE billfish--one that pulls him out to sea and gives him the fight of a lifetime. Once he eventually DOES land the fish, he's very far from shore and sharks attack his catch. The old man is beat and life, apparently, sucks. Ernest Hemmingway's story "The Old Man and the Sea" is a very short novel. And, it has a plot that is paper-thin. Because of that, the movie version is also very, very thin. How they can pad it out to 86 minutes is beyond me, as the film should have been half an hour long at the most. And yet, despite this, Spencer Tracy was nominated for an Oscar for his performance in this rather dull and dreary film. Perhaps it was a slow year for the Oscars--all I know is that Tracy had dozens of performances that were better than this one--a film that is the best example of the word 'padded' in Hollywood history. It's watchable but nothing more--and is highly overrated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite over-rated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rgcustomer
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm dismayed by the discussion on IMDb relating to reactions to this film by people of today's generations. Sorry, but maybe the youth of today actually know a thing or two about story, and about film, because they have available to them the sum total of human artistic product. They aren't limited to just what certain folks deem appropriate. Sure, if Old Man And The Sea was one of the few things you could access for entertainment back in the day, you might be impressed by it. Well, life goes on, and some of today's classics will be tomorrow's rubbish. That is how it must be. And guess what? Old Man And The Sea, at least as filmed for 1958, IS rubbish. How can you justify a scene in which a spear is thrown INTO THE OPEN WOUND that it is supposed to yet make? How you can you justify a scene where a line is pulled tight, attached at both ends above the water (boat and fish) and yet the line goes straight down into the depths? Even taking into account the usual curve of a line such as this, it makes no sense. And Spencer Tracy as a Cuban? It's too much to bear. If you can't film it, don't film it. The other annoying thing about this film is the narration. If this was books-on-tape, or descriptive-video, there might be a justification for it. But it's just absurd, annoying, lazy, and pretentious. There are better ways.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spencer Tracy plays Go Fish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After eighty-four days without a catch, seafaring "old man" Spencer Tracy (as Santiago) finds his prowess as a Cuban fisherman slipping away. Hero-worshiping young sidekick Felipe Pazos (as Manolin) is advised, by his parents, to seek fairer waters with another mate - but, the boy won't abandon Mr. Tracy. His unlucky streak ends when Tracy's small boat gets pulled to new waters, where he finds the biggest fish in the sea. As he struggles alone against the elements, you'll wonder who caught who Like the classic Ernest Hemingway story from which it is adapted, there is much to read into "The Old Man and the Sea" - and Tracy earnestly tackles some of the reading, in frequent narrative interludes. The award-winning efforts by Tracy, director John Sturges, and cinematographer James Wong Howe (in color, this time) are certainly worth a look. The "National Board of Review" considered this the best picture of the year. But, this film doesn't catch the wave you can ride in the original story. ****** The Old Man and the Sea (10/7/58) John Sturges ~ Spencer Tracy, Felipe Pazos Jr., Harry Bellaver
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Fine Fish With Much Dignity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spencer Tracy is Santiago, an old impoverished Cuban fisherman who has had eighty-four days of bad luck and is being helped to survive by a young boy of the village. Tracy takes his little fishing boat farther out than usual, lands a giant marlin after a fierce three-day struggle, and then loses his trophy to the sharks who tear the great fish to pieces, leaving only the head, spine, and tail. If it get off to something of a slow start, it nevertheless involves us in Tracy's fate all the way. There are lyrical interludes while Tracy watches the birds, the flying fish, the porpoises, and dreams of lions on the African shore. He follows the baseball in the newspapers and admires Joe DiMaggio. And the battles are monumental. Tracy has to fight the huge marlin, then the multitude of sharks that attack it, and -- constantly -- his own age and fatigue. The viewer gets to feel the desperation behind all of these contests. Tracy pulls it off with the help of Dmitri Tiomkin's somewhat bombastic score, with its echoes of "Rio Bravo" and "High Noon." There are three problems though. First, modern viewers have been spoiled by recent advances in special effects and process work. The marlin, seen up close, looks like the rubber bladder it is, even when disguised by the blurry image representing Tracy's dizziness. After it's been stripped by the sharks, the spine looks like a lead pipe bought at the local plumber's, with a few plastic ribs attached. The scenes of the marlin leaping out of the sea aren't well integrated with the studio footage. Second -- and let's face facts -- Big Ernie doesn't translate well to the screen. His bare-bones attempts at thought-provoking folk poetry come across as stilted and sometimes risible. Tracy (to himself): "Do not blame the hand. It is not the hand's fault." (To his cramped hand): "You have been a long time with the fish." Third, there is a problem with the casting. Harry Bellaver is a pug, or a cop, or a reporter in Hollywood movies. He is not a Cuban bartender; he is not strong and has no aficion. Most of all, there is a problem with Spencer Tracy, an actor whom I deeply admire. Even my crude Irish stepfather from Charlestown who never had a sensitive thought in his life, was once moved to say, "Y'know, he's a good-lookin' guy. I don't mean handsome, but manly." But Tracy is not a poor Cuban fisherman. Ernie himself said Tracy "looks like a fat, rich actor." He didn't care for the boy either, who looked like "a cross between a tadpole and Anita Loos." I'm certain I've read somewhere that Hemingway was among the spectators at the arm wrestling contest flashback but I'm not sure it's true. Despite these deficiencies, the author, the cast and crew pull it off. Hemingway had Hispanic fatalism down pat. In the face of what we would call bad luck, they become Stoics. That Olympian generalization isn't mine. A Latin American professor devoted an entire lecture to it. It's a moving and tragic story touching on Hemingway's familiar themes of pride and defeat. As Hemingway has the fisherman say, "You can destroy a man but you can not defeat him," to which I'm tempted to reply, "Like hell, you can't."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Noble attempt at recreating Hemingway's classic, but...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wgregh
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For a mid-'50s (okay, that tired phrase, "mid-century") film, it is a half-decent depiction of Hemingway's classic, though Spencer Tracy's Cuban accent is obviously forced, if even available, and Tracy needed a good week under a tanning bed if the producer expected us to believe that even a gringo fisherman would look as pale as Tracy's character looked. The scenery was not as much in the studio appearance as I would have expected, except with the fish-fighting scenes looking forward in the boat to the fish. Wasn't the Old Man (Tracy) fighting a swordfish in one scene, or am I mistaken? I'm told by TMC's anchor that it was a fake fish because they couldn't catch a decent fish when shooting for the flick, and Hemingway wasn't a fan of the movie, making comments about Tracy not passing for a Cubano at all. But at least on my old Sony 19" Trinitron television (no digital here), the expired fish, its long backbone exposed, was perfect! And I love the ending shots of the fishermen silhouetted against the sunset, which as a former west Floridian, was totally real.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Even without having read the book, the DVD is well worth a look
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Admittedly I've never read the book, so maybe there is some ineffable quality to it that the film lacks. But as a viewer with no firsthand knowledge of the source material, I find the film moving and thought- provoking in the way I imagine the novella to be. The story showcases Spencer Tracy's ability to project restraint and dignity, and his careworn face makes him an ideal choice for the role of the old fisherman. The DVD special features reveal that Hemmingway observed the production and contributed to it as a technical adviser, and there is video footage of the author in a fishing boat during the shoot. The B-reel of the leaping marlin is real and impressive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    parable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the Hemingway novel. as seed for a great film. more than an adaptation, it is a impressive parable about hope, fight, desire and limits. each scene - as perfect circle. the fight against sharks scene - memorable. one of the most powerful roles of Tracy. and beautiful nuances of an extraordinary performance.the beauty of images and precise script are keys of this remarkable movie. a parable - movie because it can be a Christian story about faith and will of God. about ambition and sense of a bitter lesson. about yourself. a fisherman in his boat. a huge fish. and the return to home. all - in powerful light and heavy shadows. parts of a movie about small life things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Those who love to read should enjoy this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SimonJack
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's very rare that a movie is made based on a book while the author is still alive, and the author is an adviser and has an active hand in the shooting and production of the film. Such was the case with this original movie based on the novel, "The Old Man and the Sea," by Ernest Hemingway. So, viewers can be sure that the movie we watch is very likely how Hemingway envisioned the story in his mind as he wrote the book. Hemingway was an adviser on this film, and had creative control over the final draft of the screenplay. He also worked as a second unit director for some of the marlin fishing scenes. And, Warner Brothers used his boat, Pilar, for the camera platform in shooting most of the exteriors in Cuban waters. The scenes of the marlin fight were from film footage of the world's record catch by Alfred C. Glassell, Jr., who also acted as an adviser. I can understand how some people would be put off by this movie. Especially a younger generation that has grown up on constant action, CGI, and so many films of make believe, fantasy or of a comic book nature. But to anyone who loves to read, this movie should be a treat. For about half the film, we see just one person, alone in his boat. He searches for, finally hooks, then struggles and waits patiently for the right time to land his fish. Finally, he fights against sharks in his long trip back to port. During all of this we see what the old man does to outwit his catch, and to fight off the predator sharks. He talks out loud to himself, to God and to the fish. And we hear his thoughts as he ruminates about how he will make it back. Hemingway's words come alive in the thoughts of the old man. Haven't most of us at some time in our lives talked to ourselves out loud, and carried on one-sided discussions in our thoughts. The monologue of the old man alone on the sea with his fish, which he called simply, "Fish," brought the pages of the book to life. All aspects of "The Old Man and Sea" were excellent. Spencer Tracy gave one of his finest performances, and the rest of the cast were very good. The Warner Color was spectacular, and the cinematography and settings were outstanding. John Sturges turned in another great film as director, and the music by Dmitri Tiomkin was perfect for this film. The only reason I don't score this a 10 is because of some small details that are distractions. The film couldn't overcome the obvious differences in seas. The sea is almost dead calm or barely rippling in most of the scenes when the old man is rowing or being pulled by the fish. But in the scene when the fish surfaces, and the old man struggles to wear it down, we see fairly heavy seas, with five to eight foot swells and choppy water. In one scene of the village we see palm trees bending and swaying under heavy winds, so there should at least have been small whitecaps on the water. Another little detail was Tracy's appearance  facial and clothing. He didn't seem to look as haggard as he acted, and his clothes and hat might have shown a little more wear and tear from his ordeal. But overall, this is an excellent movie that will appeal to those who like to read the classics. "The Old Man and the Sea" surely is an American classic. It earned Hemingway a Pulitzer Prize in 1953, and was cited as the significant contribution to his winning the Nobel Prize for Literature in 1954. A priceless bonus on the DVD of this movie is a short video entitled, "Hemingway  The Legend of the Sea." It was a film of a fishing trip in the Caribbean with Hemingway and filmmaker Allen Miner. It shows them landing a huge marlin. And one last piece of trivia  Hemingway and a friend did lose half a huge fish to sharks in real life. They caught a marlin so large that they weren't able to bring it into the boat, and sharks got the tail half of the fish before they got back to port. You can find a photo on the Web that shows the two men standing beside the 500-pound half of a marlin.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    last attempt at greatness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I should first admit that I've never read Ernest Hemingway's novel. My interpretation of John Sturges's adaptation of "The Old Man and the Sea" is that the title character, a Cuban fisherman (Spencer Tracy), is making what appears to be his last attempt at greatness. Teased by everyone for his lack of catch over the past few months, the old man sets out with a well defined goal and does everything that he can to fulfill it. I guess that the movie, released in autumn 1958, also served as a last look at Cuba before the revolution (although a full history of the country requires a much more detailed explanation). Anyway, it's definitely worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Hemingway Classic On Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ernest Hemingway's novella,The Old Man and the Sea was probably extremely difficult to film to begin with, but this didn't stop John Sturges from trying to put Hemingway's tight little character study into film.The Old Man and the Sea is a 1958 film starring Spencer Tracy. The screenplay was adapted by Peter Viertel from the novella and the film was directed by Sturges. Spencer Tracy is the Old Man, a Cuban fisherman who tries to haul in a huge fish that he catches far from shore. Tracy's tiny boat is besieged by sharks and by natural elements, but the Old Man stubbornly sticks to his job. In the end, the fish is nothing more than a skeleton, and the Old Man returns to his tiny hovel. In this movie,Tracy did great great for himself as he was able to put to life a movie the features himself mostly with no other characters involved.I personally could say that he was born to play the old fisherman.As for the screenplay,the movie was a great adaptation of Hemingway's novella.The only negative thing I could say was that the film was very poor in its technical aspects as inconsistencies in very obvious all throughout many scenes.I could have given this movie a 10/10 rating if not for this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best example I can think of to illustrate the word 'padded'.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here is the very simple story in its entirety. An old Cuban man (Tracy) sets out in his small boat to do some fishing. This is NOT fancy stuff--no rods and reels or fancy motors--it's a very simple boat with minimal equipment. Yet, miraculously, the old guy hooks into a HUGE billfish--one that pulls him out to sea and gives him the fight of a lifetime. Once he eventually DOES land the fish, he's very far from shore and sharks attack his catch. The old man is beat and life, apparently, sucks. Ernest Hemmingway's story "The Old Man and the Sea" is a very short novel. And, it has a plot that is paper-thin. Because of that, the movie version is also very, very thin. How they can pad it out to 86 minutes is beyond me, as the film should have been half an hour long at the most. And yet, despite this, Spencer Tracy was nominated for an Oscar for his performance in this rather dull and dreary film. Perhaps it was a slow year for the Oscars--all I know is that Tracy had dozens of performances that were better than this one--a film that is the best example of the word 'padded' in Hollywood history. It's watchable but nothing more--and is highly overrated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite over-rated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rgcustomer
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm dismayed by the discussion on IMDb relating to reactions to this film by people of today's generations. Sorry, but maybe the youth of today actually know a thing or two about story, and about film, because they have available to them the sum total of human artistic product. They aren't limited to just what certain folks deem appropriate. Sure, if Old Man And The Sea was one of the few things you could access for entertainment back in the day, you might be impressed by it. Well, life goes on, and some of today's classics will be tomorrow's rubbish. That is how it must be. And guess what? Old Man And The Sea, at least as filmed for 1958, IS rubbish. How can you justify a scene in which a spear is thrown INTO THE OPEN WOUND that it is supposed to yet make? How you can you justify a scene where a line is pulled tight, attached at both ends above the water (boat and fish) and yet the line goes straight down into the depths? Even taking into account the usual curve of a line such as this, it makes no sense. And Spencer Tracy as a Cuban? It's too much to bear. If you can't film it, don't film it. The other annoying thing about this film is the narration. If this was books-on-tape, or descriptive-video, there might be a justification for it. But it's just absurd, annoying, lazy, and pretentious. There are better ways.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spencer Tracy plays Go Fish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After eighty-four days without a catch, seafaring "old man" Spencer Tracy (as Santiago) finds his prowess as a Cuban fisherman slipping away. Hero-worshiping young sidekick Felipe Pazos (as Manolin) is advised, by his parents, to seek fairer waters with another mate - but, the boy won't abandon Mr. Tracy. His unlucky streak ends when Tracy's small boat gets pulled to new waters, where he finds the biggest fish in the sea. As he struggles alone against the elements, you'll wonder who caught who Like the classic Ernest Hemingway story from which it is adapted, there is much to read into "The Old Man and the Sea" - and Tracy earnestly tackles some of the reading, in frequent narrative interludes. The award-winning efforts by Tracy, director John Sturges, and cinematographer James Wong Howe (in color, this time) are certainly worth a look. The "National Board of Review" considered this the best picture of the year. But, this film doesn't catch the wave you can ride in the original story. ****** The Old Man and the Sea (10/7/58) John Sturges ~ Spencer Tracy, Felipe Pazos Jr., Harry Bellaver
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Fine Fish With Much Dignity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spencer Tracy is Santiago, an old impoverished Cuban fisherman who has had eighty-four days of bad luck and is being helped to survive by a young boy of the village. Tracy takes his little fishing boat farther out than usual, lands a giant marlin after a fierce three-day struggle, and then loses his trophy to the sharks who tear the great fish to pieces, leaving only the head, spine, and tail. If it get off to something of a slow start, it nevertheless involves us in Tracy's fate all the way. There are lyrical interludes while Tracy watches the birds, the flying fish, the porpoises, and dreams of lions on the African shore. He follows the baseball in the newspapers and admires Joe DiMaggio. And the battles are monumental. Tracy has to fight the huge marlin, then the multitude of sharks that attack it, and -- constantly -- his own age and fatigue. The viewer gets to feel the desperation behind all of these contests. Tracy pulls it off with the help of Dmitri Tiomkin's somewhat bombastic score, with its echoes of "Rio Bravo" and "High Noon." There are three problems though. First, modern viewers have been spoiled by recent advances in special effects and process work. The marlin, seen up close, looks like the rubber bladder it is, even when disguised by the blurry image representing Tracy's dizziness. After it's been stripped by the sharks, the spine looks like a lead pipe bought at the local plumber's, with a few plastic ribs attached. The scenes of the marlin leaping out of the sea aren't well integrated with the studio footage. Second -- and let's face facts -- Big Ernie doesn't translate well to the screen. His bare-bones attempts at thought-provoking folk poetry come across as stilted and sometimes risible. Tracy (to himself): "Do not blame the hand. It is not the hand's fault." (To his cramped hand): "You have been a long time with the fish." Third, there is a problem with the casting. Harry Bellaver is a pug, or a cop, or a reporter in Hollywood movies. He is not a Cuban bartender; he is not strong and has no aficion. Most of all, there is a problem with Spencer Tracy, an actor whom I deeply admire. Even my crude Irish stepfather from Charlestown who never had a sensitive thought in his life, was once moved to say, "Y'know, he's a good-lookin' guy. I don't mean handsome, but manly." But Tracy is not a poor Cuban fisherman. Ernie himself said Tracy "looks like a fat, rich actor." He didn't care for the boy either, who looked like "a cross between a tadpole and Anita Loos." I'm certain I've read somewhere that Hemingway was among the spectators at the arm wrestling contest flashback but I'm not sure it's true. Despite these deficiencies, the author, the cast and crew pull it off. Hemingway had Hispanic fatalism down pat. In the face of what we would call bad luck, they become Stoics. That Olympian generalization isn't mine. A Latin American professor devoted an entire lecture to it. It's a moving and tragic story touching on Hemingway's familiar themes of pride and defeat. As Hemingway has the fisherman say, "You can destroy a man but you can not defeat him," to which I'm tempted to reply, "Like hell, you can't."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Noble attempt at recreating Hemingway's classic, but...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wgregh
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For a mid-'50s (okay, that tired phrase, "mid-century") film, it is a half-decent depiction of Hemingway's classic, though Spencer Tracy's Cuban accent is obviously forced, if even available, and Tracy needed a good week under a tanning bed if the producer expected us to believe that even a gringo fisherman would look as pale as Tracy's character looked. The scenery was not as much in the studio appearance as I would have expected, except with the fish-fighting scenes looking forward in the boat to the fish. Wasn't the Old Man (Tracy) fighting a swordfish in one scene, or am I mistaken? I'm told by TMC's anchor that it was a fake fish because they couldn't catch a decent fish when shooting for the flick, and Hemingway wasn't a fan of the movie, making comments about Tracy not passing for a Cubano at all. But at least on my old Sony 19" Trinitron television (no digital here), the expired fish, its long backbone exposed, was perfect! And I love the ending shots of the fishermen silhouetted against the sunset, which as a former west Floridian, was totally real.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Even without having read the book, the DVD is well worth a look
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Admittedly I've never read the book, so maybe there is some ineffable quality to it that the film lacks. But as a viewer with no firsthand knowledge of the source material, I find the film moving and thought- provoking in the way I imagine the novella to be. The story showcases Spencer Tracy's ability to project restraint and dignity, and his careworn face makes him an ideal choice for the role of the old fisherman. The DVD special features reveal that Hemmingway observed the production and contributed to it as a technical adviser, and there is video footage of the author in a fishing boat during the shoot. The B-reel of the leaping marlin is real and impressive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    parable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the Hemingway novel. as seed for a great film. more than an adaptation, it is a impressive parable about hope, fight, desire and limits. each scene - as perfect circle. the fight against sharks scene - memorable. one of the most powerful roles of Tracy. and beautiful nuances of an extraordinary performance.the beauty of images and precise script are keys of this remarkable movie. a parable - movie because it can be a Christian story about faith and will of God. about ambition and sense of a bitter lesson. about yourself. a fisherman in his boat. a huge fish. and the return to home. all - in powerful light and heavy shadows. parts of a movie about small life things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Those who love to read should enjoy this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SimonJack
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's very rare that a movie is made based on a book while the author is still alive, and the author is an adviser and has an active hand in the shooting and production of the film. Such was the case with this original movie based on the novel, "The Old Man and the Sea," by Ernest Hemingway. So, viewers can be sure that the movie we watch is very likely how Hemingway envisioned the story in his mind as he wrote the book. Hemingway was an adviser on this film, and had creative control over the final draft of the screenplay. He also worked as a second unit director for some of the marlin fishing scenes. And, Warner Brothers used his boat, Pilar, for the camera platform in shooting most of the exteriors in Cuban waters. The scenes of the marlin fight were from film footage of the world's record catch by Alfred C. Glassell, Jr., who also acted as an adviser. I can understand how some people would be put off by this movie. Especially a younger generation that has grown up on constant action, CGI, and so many films of make believe, fantasy or of a comic book nature. But to anyone who loves to read, this movie should be a treat. For about half the film, we see just one person, alone in his boat. He searches for, finally hooks, then struggles and waits patiently for the right time to land his fish. Finally, he fights against sharks in his long trip back to port. During all of this we see what the old man does to outwit his catch, and to fight off the predator sharks. He talks out loud to himself, to God and to the fish. And we hear his thoughts as he ruminates about how he will make it back. Hemingway's words come alive in the thoughts of the old man. Haven't most of us at some time in our lives talked to ourselves out loud, and carried on one-sided discussions in our thoughts. The monologue of the old man alone on the sea with his fish, which he called simply, "Fish," brought the pages of the book to life. All aspects of "The Old Man and Sea" were excellent. Spencer Tracy gave one of his finest performances, and the rest of the cast were very good. The Warner Color was spectacular, and the cinematography and settings were outstanding. John Sturges turned in another great film as director, and the music by Dmitri Tiomkin was perfect for this film. The only reason I don't score this a 10 is because of some small details that are distractions. The film couldn't overcome the obvious differences in seas. The sea is almost dead calm or barely rippling in most of the scenes when the old man is rowing or being pulled by the fish. But in the scene when the fish surfaces, and the old man struggles to wear it down, we see fairly heavy seas, with five to eight foot swells and choppy water. In one scene of the village we see palm trees bending and swaying under heavy winds, so there should at least have been small whitecaps on the water. Another little detail was Tracy's appearance  facial and clothing. He didn't seem to look as haggard as he acted, and his clothes and hat might have shown a little more wear and tear from his ordeal. But overall, this is an excellent movie that will appeal to those who like to read the classics. "The Old Man and the Sea" surely is an American classic. It earned Hemingway a Pulitzer Prize in 1953, and was cited as the significant contribution to his winning the Nobel Prize for Literature in 1954. A priceless bonus on the DVD of this movie is a short video entitled, "Hemingway  The Legend of the Sea." It was a film of a fishing trip in the Caribbean with Hemingway and filmmaker Allen Miner. It shows them landing a huge marlin. And one last piece of trivia  Hemingway and a friend did lose half a huge fish to sharks in real life. They caught a marlin so large that they weren't able to bring it into the boat, and sharks got the tail half of the fish before they got back to port. You can find a photo on the Web that shows the two men standing beside the 500-pound half of a marlin.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    last attempt at greatness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I should first admit that I've never read Ernest Hemingway's novel. My interpretation of John Sturges's adaptation of "The Old Man and the Sea" is that the title character, a Cuban fisherman (Spencer Tracy), is making what appears to be his last attempt at greatness. Teased by everyone for his lack of catch over the past few months, the old man sets out with a well defined goal and does everything that he can to fulfill it. I guess that the movie, released in autumn 1958, also served as a last look at Cuba before the revolution (although a full history of the country requires a much more detailed explanation). Anyway, it's definitely worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Hemingway Classic On Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ernest Hemingway's novella,The Old Man and the Sea was probably extremely difficult to film to begin with, but this didn't stop John Sturges from trying to put Hemingway's tight little character study into film.The Old Man and the Sea is a 1958 film starring Spencer Tracy. The screenplay was adapted by Peter Viertel from the novella and the film was directed by Sturges. Spencer Tracy is the Old Man, a Cuban fisherman who tries to haul in a huge fish that he catches far from shore. Tracy's tiny boat is besieged by sharks and by natural elements, but the Old Man stubbornly sticks to his job. In the end, the fish is nothing more than a skeleton, and the Old Man returns to his tiny hovel. In this movie,Tracy did great great for himself as he was able to put to life a movie the features himself mostly with no other characters involved.I personally could say that he was born to play the old fisherman.As for the screenplay,the movie was a great adaptation of Hemingway's novella.The only negative thing I could say was that the film was very poor in its technical aspects as inconsistencies in very obvious all throughout many scenes.I could have given this movie a 10/10 rating if not for this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best example I can think of to illustrate the word 'padded'.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here is the very simple story in its entirety. An old Cuban man (Tracy) sets out in his small boat to do some fishing. This is NOT fancy stuff--no rods and reels or fancy motors--it's a very simple boat with minimal equipment. Yet, miraculously, the old guy hooks into a HUGE billfish--one that pulls him out to sea and gives him the fight of a lifetime. Once he eventually DOES land the fish, he's very far from shore and sharks attack his catch. The old man is beat and life, apparently, sucks. Ernest Hemmingway's story "The Old Man and the Sea" is a very short novel. And, it has a plot that is paper-thin. Because of that, the movie version is also very, very thin. How they can pad it out to 86 minutes is beyond me, as the film should have been half an hour long at the most. And yet, despite this, Spencer Tracy was nominated for an Oscar for his performance in this rather dull and dreary film. Perhaps it was a slow year for the Oscars--all I know is that Tracy had dozens of performances that were better than this one--a film that is the best example of the word 'padded' in Hollywood history. It's watchable but nothing more--and is highly overrated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite over-rated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rgcustomer
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm dismayed by the discussion on IMDb relating to reactions to this film by people of today's generations. Sorry, but maybe the youth of today actually know a thing or two about story, and about film, because they have available to them the sum total of human artistic product. They aren't limited to just what certain folks deem appropriate. Sure, if Old Man And The Sea was one of the few things you could access for entertainment back in the day, you might be impressed by it. Well, life goes on, and some of today's classics will be tomorrow's rubbish. That is how it must be. And guess what? Old Man And The Sea, at least as filmed for 1958, IS rubbish. How can you justify a scene in which a spear is thrown INTO THE OPEN WOUND that it is supposed to yet make? How you can you justify a scene where a line is pulled tight, attached at both ends above the water (boat and fish) and yet the line goes straight down into the depths? Even taking into account the usual curve of a line such as this, it makes no sense. And Spencer Tracy as a Cuban? It's too much to bear. If you can't film it, don't film it. The other annoying thing about this film is the narration. If this was books-on-tape, or descriptive-video, there might be a justification for it. But it's just absurd, annoying, lazy, and pretentious. There are better ways.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spencer Tracy plays Go Fish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After eighty-four days without a catch, seafaring "old man" Spencer Tracy (as Santiago) finds his prowess as a Cuban fisherman slipping away. Hero-worshiping young sidekick Felipe Pazos (as Manolin) is advised, by his parents, to seek fairer waters with another mate - but, the boy won't abandon Mr. Tracy. His unlucky streak ends when Tracy's small boat gets pulled to new waters, where he finds the biggest fish in the sea. As he struggles alone against the elements, you'll wonder who caught who Like the classic Ernest Hemingway story from which it is adapted, there is much to read into "The Old Man and the Sea" - and Tracy earnestly tackles some of the reading, in frequent narrative interludes. The award-winning efforts by Tracy, director John Sturges, and cinematographer James Wong Howe (in color, this time) are certainly worth a look. The "National Board of Review" considered this the best picture of the year. But, this film doesn't catch the wave you can ride in the original story. ****** The Old Man and the Sea (10/7/58) John Sturges ~ Spencer Tracy, Felipe Pazos Jr., Harry Bellaver
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Fine Fish With Much Dignity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spencer Tracy is Santiago, an old impoverished Cuban fisherman who has had eighty-four days of bad luck and is being helped to survive by a young boy of the village. Tracy takes his little fishing boat farther out than usual, lands a giant marlin after a fierce three-day struggle, and then loses his trophy to the sharks who tear the great fish to pieces, leaving only the head, spine, and tail. If it get off to something of a slow start, it nevertheless involves us in Tracy's fate all the way. There are lyrical interludes while Tracy watches the birds, the flying fish, the porpoises, and dreams of lions on the African shore. He follows the baseball in the newspapers and admires Joe DiMaggio. And the battles are monumental. Tracy has to fight the huge marlin, then the multitude of sharks that attack it, and -- constantly -- his own age and fatigue. The viewer gets to feel the desperation behind all of these contests. Tracy pulls it off with the help of Dmitri Tiomkin's somewhat bombastic score, with its echoes of "Rio Bravo" and "High Noon." There are three problems though. First, modern viewers have been spoiled by recent advances in special effects and process work. The marlin, seen up close, looks like the rubber bladder it is, even when disguised by the blurry image representing Tracy's dizziness. After it's been stripped by the sharks, the spine looks like a lead pipe bought at the local plumber's, with a few plastic ribs attached. The scenes of the marlin leaping out of the sea aren't well integrated with the studio footage. Second -- and let's face facts -- Big Ernie doesn't translate well to the screen. His bare-bones attempts at thought-provoking folk poetry come across as stilted and sometimes risible. Tracy (to himself): "Do not blame the hand. It is not the hand's fault." (To his cramped hand): "You have been a long time with the fish." Third, there is a problem with the casting. Harry Bellaver is a pug, or a cop, or a reporter in Hollywood movies. He is not a Cuban bartender; he is not strong and has no aficion. Most of all, there is a problem with Spencer Tracy, an actor whom I deeply admire. Even my crude Irish stepfather from Charlestown who never had a sensitive thought in his life, was once moved to say, "Y'know, he's a good-lookin' guy. I don't mean handsome, but manly." But Tracy is not a poor Cuban fisherman. Ernie himself said Tracy "looks like a fat, rich actor." He didn't care for the boy either, who looked like "a cross between a tadpole and Anita Loos." I'm certain I've read somewhere that Hemingway was among the spectators at the arm wrestling contest flashback but I'm not sure it's true. Despite these deficiencies, the author, the cast and crew pull it off. Hemingway had Hispanic fatalism down pat. In the face of what we would call bad luck, they become Stoics. That Olympian generalization isn't mine. A Latin American professor devoted an entire lecture to it. It's a moving and tragic story touching on Hemingway's familiar themes of pride and defeat. As Hemingway has the fisherman say, "You can destroy a man but you can not defeat him," to which I'm tempted to reply, "Like hell, you can't."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Noble attempt at recreating Hemingway's classic, but...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wgregh
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For a mid-'50s (okay, that tired phrase, "mid-century") film, it is a half-decent depiction of Hemingway's classic, though Spencer Tracy's Cuban accent is obviously forced, if even available, and Tracy needed a good week under a tanning bed if the producer expected us to believe that even a gringo fisherman would look as pale as Tracy's character looked. The scenery was not as much in the studio appearance as I would have expected, except with the fish-fighting scenes looking forward in the boat to the fish. Wasn't the Old Man (Tracy) fighting a swordfish in one scene, or am I mistaken? I'm told by TMC's anchor that it was a fake fish because they couldn't catch a decent fish when shooting for the flick, and Hemingway wasn't a fan of the movie, making comments about Tracy not passing for a Cubano at all. But at least on my old Sony 19" Trinitron television (no digital here), the expired fish, its long backbone exposed, was perfect! And I love the ending shots of the fishermen silhouetted against the sunset, which as a former west Floridian, was totally real.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Even without having read the book, the DVD is well worth a look
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Admittedly I've never read the book, so maybe there is some ineffable quality to it that the film lacks. But as a viewer with no firsthand knowledge of the source material, I find the film moving and thought- provoking in the way I imagine the novella to be. The story showcases Spencer Tracy's ability to project restraint and dignity, and his careworn face makes him an ideal choice for the role of the old fisherman. The DVD special features reveal that Hemmingway observed the production and contributed to it as a technical adviser, and there is video footage of the author in a fishing boat during the shoot. The B-reel of the leaping marlin is real and impressive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    parable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the Hemingway novel. as seed for a great film. more than an adaptation, it is a impressive parable about hope, fight, desire and limits. each scene - as perfect circle. the fight against sharks scene - memorable. one of the most powerful roles of Tracy. and beautiful nuances of an extraordinary performance.the beauty of images and precise script are keys of this remarkable movie. a parable - movie because it can be a Christian story about faith and will of God. about ambition and sense of a bitter lesson. about yourself. a fisherman in his boat. a huge fish. and the return to home. all - in powerful light and heavy shadows. parts of a movie about small life things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Those who love to read should enjoy this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SimonJack
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's very rare that a movie is made based on a book while the author is still alive, and the author is an adviser and has an active hand in the shooting and production of the film. Such was the case with this original movie based on the novel, "The Old Man and the Sea," by Ernest Hemingway. So, viewers can be sure that the movie we watch is very likely how Hemingway envisioned the story in his mind as he wrote the book. Hemingway was an adviser on this film, and had creative control over the final draft of the screenplay. He also worked as a second unit director for some of the marlin fishing scenes. And, Warner Brothers used his boat, Pilar, for the camera platform in shooting most of the exteriors in Cuban waters. The scenes of the marlin fight were from film footage of the world's record catch by Alfred C. Glassell, Jr., who also acted as an adviser. I can understand how some people would be put off by this movie. Especially a younger generation that has grown up on constant action, CGI, and so many films of make believe, fantasy or of a comic book nature. But to anyone who loves to read, this movie should be a treat. For about half the film, we see just one person, alone in his boat. He searches for, finally hooks, then struggles and waits patiently for the right time to land his fish. Finally, he fights against sharks in his long trip back to port. During all of this we see what the old man does to outwit his catch, and to fight off the predator sharks. He talks out loud to himself, to God and to the fish. And we hear his thoughts as he ruminates about how he will make it back. Hemingway's words come alive in the thoughts of the old man. Haven't most of us at some time in our lives talked to ourselves out loud, and carried on one-sided discussions in our thoughts. The monologue of the old man alone on the sea with his fish, which he called simply, "Fish," brought the pages of the book to life. All aspects of "The Old Man and Sea" were excellent. Spencer Tracy gave one of his finest performances, and the rest of the cast were very good. The Warner Color was spectacular, and the cinematography and settings were outstanding. John Sturges turned in another great film as director, and the music by Dmitri Tiomkin was perfect for this film. The only reason I don't score this a 10 is because of some small details that are distractions. The film couldn't overcome the obvious differences in seas. The sea is almost dead calm or barely rippling in most of the scenes when the old man is rowing or being pulled by the fish. But in the scene when the fish surfaces, and the old man struggles to wear it down, we see fairly heavy seas, with five to eight foot swells and choppy water. In one scene of the village we see palm trees bending and swaying under heavy winds, so there should at least have been small whitecaps on the water. Another little detail was Tracy's appearance  facial and clothing. He didn't seem to look as haggard as he acted, and his clothes and hat might have shown a little more wear and tear from his ordeal. But overall, this is an excellent movie that will appeal to those who like to read the classics. "The Old Man and the Sea" surely is an American classic. It earned Hemingway a Pulitzer Prize in 1953, and was cited as the significant contribution to his winning the Nobel Prize for Literature in 1954. A priceless bonus on the DVD of this movie is a short video entitled, "Hemingway  The Legend of the Sea." It was a film of a fishing trip in the Caribbean with Hemingway and filmmaker Allen Miner. It shows them landing a huge marlin. And one last piece of trivia  Hemingway and a friend did lose half a huge fish to sharks in real life. They caught a marlin so large that they weren't able to bring it into the boat, and sharks got the tail half of the fish before they got back to port. You can find a photo on the Web that shows the two men standing beside the 500-pound half of a marlin.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    last attempt at greatness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I should first admit that I've never read Ernest Hemingway's novel. My interpretation of John Sturges's adaptation of "The Old Man and the Sea" is that the title character, a Cuban fisherman (Spencer Tracy), is making what appears to be his last attempt at greatness. Teased by everyone for his lack of catch over the past few months, the old man sets out with a well defined goal and does everything that he can to fulfill it. I guess that the movie, released in autumn 1958, also served as a last look at Cuba before the revolution (although a full history of the country requires a much more detailed explanation). Anyway, it's definitely worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Hemingway Classic On Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ernest Hemingway's novella,The Old Man and the Sea was probably extremely difficult to film to begin with, but this didn't stop John Sturges from trying to put Hemingway's tight little character study into film.The Old Man and the Sea is a 1958 film starring Spencer Tracy. The screenplay was adapted by Peter Viertel from the novella and the film was directed by Sturges. Spencer Tracy is the Old Man, a Cuban fisherman who tries to haul in a huge fish that he catches far from shore. Tracy's tiny boat is besieged by sharks and by natural elements, but the Old Man stubbornly sticks to his job. In the end, the fish is nothing more than a skeleton, and the Old Man returns to his tiny hovel. In this movie,Tracy did great great for himself as he was able to put to life a movie the features himself mostly with no other characters involved.I personally could say that he was born to play the old fisherman.As for the screenplay,the movie was a great adaptation of Hemingway's novella.The only negative thing I could say was that the film was very poor in its technical aspects as inconsistencies in very obvious all throughout many scenes.I could have given this movie a 10/10 rating if not for this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best example I can think of to illustrate the word 'padded'.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here is the very simple story in its entirety. An old Cuban man (Tracy) sets out in his small boat to do some fishing. This is NOT fancy stuff--no rods and reels or fancy motors--it's a very simple boat with minimal equipment. Yet, miraculously, the old guy hooks into a HUGE billfish--one that pulls him out to sea and gives him the fight of a lifetime. Once he eventually DOES land the fish, he's very far from shore and sharks attack his catch. The old man is beat and life, apparently, sucks. Ernest Hemmingway's story "The Old Man and the Sea" is a very short novel. And, it has a plot that is paper-thin. Because of that, the movie version is also very, very thin. How they can pad it out to 86 minutes is beyond me, as the film should have been half an hour long at the most. And yet, despite this, Spencer Tracy was nominated for an Oscar for his performance in this rather dull and dreary film. Perhaps it was a slow year for the Oscars--all I know is that Tracy had dozens of performances that were better than this one--a film that is the best example of the word 'padded' in Hollywood history. It's watchable but nothing more--and is highly overrated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite over-rated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rgcustomer
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm dismayed by the discussion on IMDb relating to reactions to this film by people of today's generations. Sorry, but maybe the youth of today actually know a thing or two about story, and about film, because they have available to them the sum total of human artistic product. They aren't limited to just what certain folks deem appropriate. Sure, if Old Man And The Sea was one of the few things you could access for entertainment back in the day, you might be impressed by it. Well, life goes on, and some of today's classics will be tomorrow's rubbish. That is how it must be. And guess what? Old Man And The Sea, at least as filmed for 1958, IS rubbish. How can you justify a scene in which a spear is thrown INTO THE OPEN WOUND that it is supposed to yet make? How you can you justify a scene where a line is pulled tight, attached at both ends above the water (boat and fish) and yet the line goes straight down into the depths? Even taking into account the usual curve of a line such as this, it makes no sense. And Spencer Tracy as a Cuban? It's too much to bear. If you can't film it, don't film it. The other annoying thing about this film is the narration. If this was books-on-tape, or descriptive-video, there might be a justification for it. But it's just absurd, annoying, lazy, and pretentious. There are better ways.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spencer Tracy plays Go Fish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After eighty-four days without a catch, seafaring "old man" Spencer Tracy (as Santiago) finds his prowess as a Cuban fisherman slipping away. Hero-worshiping young sidekick Felipe Pazos (as Manolin) is advised, by his parents, to seek fairer waters with another mate - but, the boy won't abandon Mr. Tracy. His unlucky streak ends when Tracy's small boat gets pulled to new waters, where he finds the biggest fish in the sea. As he struggles alone against the elements, you'll wonder who caught who Like the classic Ernest Hemingway story from which it is adapted, there is much to read into "The Old Man and the Sea" - and Tracy earnestly tackles some of the reading, in frequent narrative interludes. The award-winning efforts by Tracy, director John Sturges, and cinematographer James Wong Howe (in color, this time) are certainly worth a look. The "National Board of Review" considered this the best picture of the year. But, this film doesn't catch the wave you can ride in the original story. ****** The Old Man and the Sea (10/7/58) John Sturges ~ Spencer Tracy, Felipe Pazos Jr., Harry Bellaver
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Fine Fish With Much Dignity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spencer Tracy is Santiago, an old impoverished Cuban fisherman who has had eighty-four days of bad luck and is being helped to survive by a young boy of the village. Tracy takes his little fishing boat farther out than usual, lands a giant marlin after a fierce three-day struggle, and then loses his trophy to the sharks who tear the great fish to pieces, leaving only the head, spine, and tail. If it get off to something of a slow start, it nevertheless involves us in Tracy's fate all the way. There are lyrical interludes while Tracy watches the birds, the flying fish, the porpoises, and dreams of lions on the African shore. He follows the baseball in the newspapers and admires Joe DiMaggio. And the battles are monumental. Tracy has to fight the huge marlin, then the multitude of sharks that attack it, and -- constantly -- his own age and fatigue. The viewer gets to feel the desperation behind all of these contests. Tracy pulls it off with the help of Dmitri Tiomkin's somewhat bombastic score, with its echoes of "Rio Bravo" and "High Noon." There are three problems though. First, modern viewers have been spoiled by recent advances in special effects and process work. The marlin, seen up close, looks like the rubber bladder it is, even when disguised by the blurry image representing Tracy's dizziness. After it's been stripped by the sharks, the spine looks like a lead pipe bought at the local plumber's, with a few plastic ribs attached. The scenes of the marlin leaping out of the sea aren't well integrated with the studio footage. Second -- and let's face facts -- Big Ernie doesn't translate well to the screen. His bare-bones attempts at thought-provoking folk poetry come across as stilted and sometimes risible. Tracy (to himself): "Do not blame the hand. It is not the hand's fault." (To his cramped hand): "You have been a long time with the fish." Third, there is a problem with the casting. Harry Bellaver is a pug, or a cop, or a reporter in Hollywood movies. He is not a Cuban bartender; he is not strong and has no aficion. Most of all, there is a problem with Spencer Tracy, an actor whom I deeply admire. Even my crude Irish stepfather from Charlestown who never had a sensitive thought in his life, was once moved to say, "Y'know, he's a good-lookin' guy. I don't mean handsome, but manly." But Tracy is not a poor Cuban fisherman. Ernie himself said Tracy "looks like a fat, rich actor." He didn't care for the boy either, who looked like "a cross between a tadpole and Anita Loos." I'm certain I've read somewhere that Hemingway was among the spectators at the arm wrestling contest flashback but I'm not sure it's true. Despite these deficiencies, the author, the cast and crew pull it off. Hemingway had Hispanic fatalism down pat. In the face of what we would call bad luck, they become Stoics. That Olympian generalization isn't mine. A Latin American professor devoted an entire lecture to it. It's a moving and tragic story touching on Hemingway's familiar themes of pride and defeat. As Hemingway has the fisherman say, "You can destroy a man but you can not defeat him," to which I'm tempted to reply, "Like hell, you can't."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Noble attempt at recreating Hemingway's classic, but...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wgregh
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For a mid-'50s (okay, that tired phrase, "mid-century") film, it is a half-decent depiction of Hemingway's classic, though Spencer Tracy's Cuban accent is obviously forced, if even available, and Tracy needed a good week under a tanning bed if the producer expected us to believe that even a gringo fisherman would look as pale as Tracy's character looked. The scenery was not as much in the studio appearance as I would have expected, except with the fish-fighting scenes looking forward in the boat to the fish. Wasn't the Old Man (Tracy) fighting a swordfish in one scene, or am I mistaken? I'm told by TMC's anchor that it was a fake fish because they couldn't catch a decent fish when shooting for the flick, and Hemingway wasn't a fan of the movie, making comments about Tracy not passing for a Cubano at all. But at least on my old Sony 19" Trinitron television (no digital here), the expired fish, its long backbone exposed, was perfect! And I love the ending shots of the fishermen silhouetted against the sunset, which as a former west Floridian, was totally real.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
