<filme>
 <id>
  113
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0113362
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Cavaleiro do Telhado E a Dama das Sombras
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  In a time of war and disease, a young officer gallantly tries to help a young woman find her husband.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  In 1832, cholera ravages Provence (South of France). After several misadventures, Angelo, young Italian officer hunted by the Austrian secret police, meets Pauline de Theus, a young lady. After a second accidental meeting, both will start the search of Pauline's husband in a chaotic country.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   provence
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   police
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   austrian
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   cholera
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   cleansing by fire
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Jean-Paul Rappeneau
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Jean-Claude Carri&egrave;re
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Nina Companeez
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Olivier Martinez
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Juliette Binoche
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Pierre Arditi
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    These are the basics...........(or: Try this on for size)...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    arizona-philm-phan
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **** (Already there are many, many insightful Comments, but the following is my take.) These are the basics on the acting levels and production values for this film: -In our main character, Olivier gives us someone who is young and brash and beautiful.....and that's all he had to do; he gives us someone who is swashbuckling.....and that's all he had to do; he gives us someone who, above all else, is protective of the one he single-mindedly loves.....and that's all he had to do. -In the character of our Lady in Distress, Juliette gives us someone who is lovely, who is true and who, in all things, keeps heart.....and that's all she had to do. -In Directing and Cinematography, Rappeneau and Arbogast have given us a picture which is sweeping and stunningly beautiful.....and that's all they had to do. PS--Yet another Love Story for the Ages. ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love and a Lot of Death
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cengelm
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Italian patriot Colonel Angelo Pardi is fleeing his country in 1832. He enters the cholera ridden French Provence. There he meets Pauline who is lovelessly married to rich Marquis de Th&eacute;us. Together they will look for him. The road movie starts pretty slow and chaotic. More often than once I was confused about what was going on. A lot of swashbuckling, dead people, crows and crows again, some chases. There seemed to be no real plot or focus. Then after about one hour suddenly it got better and delivered what I was expecting. The romance between Juliette Binoche and Olivier Martinez gained momentum and the story got some direction. The ending was a bit melodramatic and lacked credibility but I won't ask for too much. Both lead actors did a good job. Cinematography was good and benefited from the setup in France's beautiful landscape. There was an improvement to be seen after a rather bad start. 6 / 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a 19th century story that is strongly reminiscent of a "knight in shining armor" story of long, long ago. The handsome hero is both committed to his cause of freeing Italy from Austrian rule AND protecting his lady from all harm--even when she stupidly blunders into it on a couple occasions. From start to finish, this is an excellent historical "chick flick" and is likely to excite the passions of many female viewers, but I am a guy (at least the last time I checked) and I STILL enjoyed it. The acting was excellent and the cinematography outstanding. About the only minor problem with the film was the occasional stupid behaviors by the female lead (Binoche). A couple times, she just seemed too stupid to live--but, of course, the handsome hero came to her rescue. An excellent film, but a little disturbing due to its graphic depiction of plague victims. Plus, with a little nudity towards the end of the film (it was explicit but not gratuitous), this is NOT a film for the kids.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cast A Cold Eye
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writers_reign
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having begun like most directors with small subjects Jean-Paul Rappeneau seems to have acquired a penchant for the crowded canvas given that his last three films - including this one - comprise Cyrano de Bergerac and Bon Voyage. My knowledge of the period - 1830s - is skimpy to say the least so I have no basis for questioning the authenticity or otherwise of the storyline involving both Italian patriots hiding in France and an outbreak of cholera in the Provence region but this is really academic because authentic or not it provides both a dramatic and colourful backdrop to a well-told story in which for once the Romantic element is understated. Olivier Martinez is sufficiently athletic to carry out lots of Errol Flynn-like engagements with a dozen assailants at once and come off incredibly best but he is woefully lacking in Flynn's abundant charm/charisma so it's just as well that leading lady Juliette Binoche has enough for both. Not least of its assets is the support, never more than ten or fifteen minutes in each case, from some of the finest actors in France from Isabelle Huppert to Jean Yanne to Francois Cluzot to Pierre Arditi. A fine film from a fine director.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Excellent Romantic film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sarahmcm-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I found the film historically poignant in reference to the period of history when the plague ravaged Europe. You feel what people must have felt during that era. The romance was sensitive and based on harsh realities of the epoch in question. This was in my mind, different and refreshing. I recommend this movie to the student of history as well as those who would study love and how love grows in a relationship. I felt the actors were a good pick and stood up well to the task at hand. A great example of some of the recent French films that have come on the scene lately.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great old-fashioned entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    burrobaggy
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Horseman on the Roof has to be one of the most beautiful looking films I've ever seen, which is odd for a movie about a cholera epidemic. Set in a beautiful summer in the mid-19th century, it follows Olivier Martinez's Italian in exile as he is chased across France by Austrian agents intent on killing as many Italian rebels as they can only for his pursuers to be outrun by a cholera epidemic that picks off friends and foes. Along the way his path crosses with various victims and survivors - a doctor who teaches him a neat disinfecting trick of setting your hands on fire, a cute governess, Jean Yanne's duplicitous peddler, Gerard Depardieu's paranoid mayor, and most importantly Juliette Binoche, who is determined to find her husband. Naturally they become travelling companions as they try to get through roadblocks and avoid being put into quarantine by the soldiers cordoning off the roads - a virtual death sentence - and eventually nearly become more. The film looks so good in cinemascope and so much of it is terrific than you can just about forgive the fact that the ending is a bit of a washout after everything that's gone before. A really enjoyable old-fashioned epic, I'd definitely pick this up if it ever turned up on DVD uncut with English subtitles (the Miramax disc is typically cut by 17 minutes thanks to Harvey Scissorhands).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Delightful Adventure and a Sensitive Romance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1832, a frightened France has a serious epidemic of Asiatic cholera, which is killing the population specially in the country, and Italy is invaded and dominated by Austria. In this scenery, Angelo (Oliver Martinez) is a 25 years old refined Italian colonel from a wealthy family exiled in France. He is trying to gather his exiled compatriots and return to Milan to organize the Italian resistance against Austria. Angelo is welcomed by the French noble Pauline (Julliete Binoche) in her house in a difficult moment for him, and Pauline travels together with Angelo, trying to find her missing husband in a chaotic country. Along their journey, Angelo becomes her protector, and they fall in love for each other. "Le Hussard Sur le Toit" is a delightful adventure and a sensitive romance. The story is beautiful and the platonic love and the chemistry between Angelo and Pauline are wonderful. An excellent movie, with a beautiful reconstitution of a dark period of French history and highly recommended for any audience. My vote is eight. Title (Brazil): "O Cavaleiro do Telhado e a Dama das Sombras" ("The Knight of the Roof and the Lady of the Shadows")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A ride through Provence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pax-et-forza
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two superstars of the french cinema: adorable Juliette Binoche and hot Olivier Martinez, love and save each other from lost, sickness and death, while horse-riding through the stunningly beautiful Provence. An adaptation of the famous novel by Jean Giono. They are there: on the screen, on their horses, in this magnificent landscape, he tries to become a man, she tries to stay a woman, they are smiling, and soon you'll express the wish of being with them on this screen, to be one of them, maybe both, if this happens, Rappeneau gets to his goal: grace. A great tale about love, renouncement, youth, passion, courage and Honor. A famous novel of the french literature. Patriotism, romanticism, and grace. Rappeneau is the master, Binoche and Martinez are the gifted pupils.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A stunning romance for realists
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    honeybeexx
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Le Hussard sur le Toit presents its audience with the grim reality of cholera-stricken rural France in 1832 and its effect on a journey of escape by two anxious visitors. The frequent images of corpses and mass burial are refreshed by the breathtaking and beautifully shot scenery, itself brought to life by characters who dilute the presence of death with an oxymoronic mix of comedy and despair. Carrion crows regularly appear, mercilessly flying around in sinister anticipation, their cawing beaks wide open with hunger. Juliette Binoche enters only in the second half, her laconic period style beautifully portrayed, and preparing the way for her appearance as George Sand in Les Enfants du Siecle (1999). Le Hussard's plot is simple, its screenplay uncomplicated. But the action is fast and Bond-like and the innocence of Martinez' military-dominated character is uncanny. But it is its simplicity that makes this movie a work of exceptional visual satisfaction, for romantics or action-lovers alike.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent adventure story, entertaining, and emotionally rewarding!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yossarian100
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Horseman on the Roof is one of those rare movies that has everything going for it; breathtaking scenery, fascinating story told in literary style with great attention to detail, stunning main characters with exceptional chemistry and screen presence, and an epic presentation of a great adventure. The central motivation of our young colonel is chivalry and that is so refreshing. Amazing!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    These are the basics...........(or: Try this on for size)...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    arizona-philm-phan
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **** (Already there are many, many insightful Comments, but the following is my take.) These are the basics on the acting levels and production values for this film: -In our main character, Olivier gives us someone who is young and brash and beautiful.....and that's all he had to do; he gives us someone who is swashbuckling.....and that's all he had to do; he gives us someone who, above all else, is protective of the one he single-mindedly loves.....and that's all he had to do. -In the character of our Lady in Distress, Juliette gives us someone who is lovely, who is true and who, in all things, keeps heart.....and that's all she had to do. -In Directing and Cinematography, Rappeneau and Arbogast have given us a picture which is sweeping and stunningly beautiful.....and that's all they had to do. PS--Yet another Love Story for the Ages. ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love and a Lot of Death
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cengelm
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Italian patriot Colonel Angelo Pardi is fleeing his country in 1832. He enters the cholera ridden French Provence. There he meets Pauline who is lovelessly married to rich Marquis de Th&eacute;us. Together they will look for him. The road movie starts pretty slow and chaotic. More often than once I was confused about what was going on. A lot of swashbuckling, dead people, crows and crows again, some chases. There seemed to be no real plot or focus. Then after about one hour suddenly it got better and delivered what I was expecting. The romance between Juliette Binoche and Olivier Martinez gained momentum and the story got some direction. The ending was a bit melodramatic and lacked credibility but I won't ask for too much. Both lead actors did a good job. Cinematography was good and benefited from the setup in France's beautiful landscape. There was an improvement to be seen after a rather bad start. 6 / 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a 19th century story that is strongly reminiscent of a "knight in shining armor" story of long, long ago. The handsome hero is both committed to his cause of freeing Italy from Austrian rule AND protecting his lady from all harm--even when she stupidly blunders into it on a couple occasions. From start to finish, this is an excellent historical "chick flick" and is likely to excite the passions of many female viewers, but I am a guy (at least the last time I checked) and I STILL enjoyed it. The acting was excellent and the cinematography outstanding. About the only minor problem with the film was the occasional stupid behaviors by the female lead (Binoche). A couple times, she just seemed too stupid to live--but, of course, the handsome hero came to her rescue. An excellent film, but a little disturbing due to its graphic depiction of plague victims. Plus, with a little nudity towards the end of the film (it was explicit but not gratuitous), this is NOT a film for the kids.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cast A Cold Eye
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writers_reign
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having begun like most directors with small subjects Jean-Paul Rappeneau seems to have acquired a penchant for the crowded canvas given that his last three films - including this one - comprise Cyrano de Bergerac and Bon Voyage. My knowledge of the period - 1830s - is skimpy to say the least so I have no basis for questioning the authenticity or otherwise of the storyline involving both Italian patriots hiding in France and an outbreak of cholera in the Provence region but this is really academic because authentic or not it provides both a dramatic and colourful backdrop to a well-told story in which for once the Romantic element is understated. Olivier Martinez is sufficiently athletic to carry out lots of Errol Flynn-like engagements with a dozen assailants at once and come off incredibly best but he is woefully lacking in Flynn's abundant charm/charisma so it's just as well that leading lady Juliette Binoche has enough for both. Not least of its assets is the support, never more than ten or fifteen minutes in each case, from some of the finest actors in France from Isabelle Huppert to Jean Yanne to Francois Cluzot to Pierre Arditi. A fine film from a fine director.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Excellent Romantic film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sarahmcm-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I found the film historically poignant in reference to the period of history when the plague ravaged Europe. You feel what people must have felt during that era. The romance was sensitive and based on harsh realities of the epoch in question. This was in my mind, different and refreshing. I recommend this movie to the student of history as well as those who would study love and how love grows in a relationship. I felt the actors were a good pick and stood up well to the task at hand. A great example of some of the recent French films that have come on the scene lately.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great old-fashioned entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    burrobaggy
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Horseman on the Roof has to be one of the most beautiful looking films I've ever seen, which is odd for a movie about a cholera epidemic. Set in a beautiful summer in the mid-19th century, it follows Olivier Martinez's Italian in exile as he is chased across France by Austrian agents intent on killing as many Italian rebels as they can only for his pursuers to be outrun by a cholera epidemic that picks off friends and foes. Along the way his path crosses with various victims and survivors - a doctor who teaches him a neat disinfecting trick of setting your hands on fire, a cute governess, Jean Yanne's duplicitous peddler, Gerard Depardieu's paranoid mayor, and most importantly Juliette Binoche, who is determined to find her husband. Naturally they become travelling companions as they try to get through roadblocks and avoid being put into quarantine by the soldiers cordoning off the roads - a virtual death sentence - and eventually nearly become more. The film looks so good in cinemascope and so much of it is terrific than you can just about forgive the fact that the ending is a bit of a washout after everything that's gone before. A really enjoyable old-fashioned epic, I'd definitely pick this up if it ever turned up on DVD uncut with English subtitles (the Miramax disc is typically cut by 17 minutes thanks to Harvey Scissorhands).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Delightful Adventure and a Sensitive Romance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1832, a frightened France has a serious epidemic of Asiatic cholera, which is killing the population specially in the country, and Italy is invaded and dominated by Austria. In this scenery, Angelo (Oliver Martinez) is a 25 years old refined Italian colonel from a wealthy family exiled in France. He is trying to gather his exiled compatriots and return to Milan to organize the Italian resistance against Austria. Angelo is welcomed by the French noble Pauline (Julliete Binoche) in her house in a difficult moment for him, and Pauline travels together with Angelo, trying to find her missing husband in a chaotic country. Along their journey, Angelo becomes her protector, and they fall in love for each other. "Le Hussard Sur le Toit" is a delightful adventure and a sensitive romance. The story is beautiful and the platonic love and the chemistry between Angelo and Pauline are wonderful. An excellent movie, with a beautiful reconstitution of a dark period of French history and highly recommended for any audience. My vote is eight. Title (Brazil): "O Cavaleiro do Telhado e a Dama das Sombras" ("The Knight of the Roof and the Lady of the Shadows")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A ride through Provence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pax-et-forza
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two superstars of the french cinema: adorable Juliette Binoche and hot Olivier Martinez, love and save each other from lost, sickness and death, while horse-riding through the stunningly beautiful Provence. An adaptation of the famous novel by Jean Giono. They are there: on the screen, on their horses, in this magnificent landscape, he tries to become a man, she tries to stay a woman, they are smiling, and soon you'll express the wish of being with them on this screen, to be one of them, maybe both, if this happens, Rappeneau gets to his goal: grace. A great tale about love, renouncement, youth, passion, courage and Honor. A famous novel of the french literature. Patriotism, romanticism, and grace. Rappeneau is the master, Binoche and Martinez are the gifted pupils.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A stunning romance for realists
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    honeybeexx
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Le Hussard sur le Toit presents its audience with the grim reality of cholera-stricken rural France in 1832 and its effect on a journey of escape by two anxious visitors. The frequent images of corpses and mass burial are refreshed by the breathtaking and beautifully shot scenery, itself brought to life by characters who dilute the presence of death with an oxymoronic mix of comedy and despair. Carrion crows regularly appear, mercilessly flying around in sinister anticipation, their cawing beaks wide open with hunger. Juliette Binoche enters only in the second half, her laconic period style beautifully portrayed, and preparing the way for her appearance as George Sand in Les Enfants du Siecle (1999). Le Hussard's plot is simple, its screenplay uncomplicated. But the action is fast and Bond-like and the innocence of Martinez' military-dominated character is uncanny. But it is its simplicity that makes this movie a work of exceptional visual satisfaction, for romantics or action-lovers alike.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent adventure story, entertaining, and emotionally rewarding!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yossarian100
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Horseman on the Roof is one of those rare movies that has everything going for it; breathtaking scenery, fascinating story told in literary style with great attention to detail, stunning main characters with exceptional chemistry and screen presence, and an epic presentation of a great adventure. The central motivation of our young colonel is chivalry and that is so refreshing. Amazing!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    These are the basics...........(or: Try this on for size)...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    arizona-philm-phan
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **** (Already there are many, many insightful Comments, but the following is my take.) These are the basics on the acting levels and production values for this film: -In our main character, Olivier gives us someone who is young and brash and beautiful.....and that's all he had to do; he gives us someone who is swashbuckling.....and that's all he had to do; he gives us someone who, above all else, is protective of the one he single-mindedly loves.....and that's all he had to do. -In the character of our Lady in Distress, Juliette gives us someone who is lovely, who is true and who, in all things, keeps heart.....and that's all she had to do. -In Directing and Cinematography, Rappeneau and Arbogast have given us a picture which is sweeping and stunningly beautiful.....and that's all they had to do. PS--Yet another Love Story for the Ages. ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love and a Lot of Death
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cengelm
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Italian patriot Colonel Angelo Pardi is fleeing his country in 1832. He enters the cholera ridden French Provence. There he meets Pauline who is lovelessly married to rich Marquis de Th&eacute;us. Together they will look for him. The road movie starts pretty slow and chaotic. More often than once I was confused about what was going on. A lot of swashbuckling, dead people, crows and crows again, some chases. There seemed to be no real plot or focus. Then after about one hour suddenly it got better and delivered what I was expecting. The romance between Juliette Binoche and Olivier Martinez gained momentum and the story got some direction. The ending was a bit melodramatic and lacked credibility but I won't ask for too much. Both lead actors did a good job. Cinematography was good and benefited from the setup in France's beautiful landscape. There was an improvement to be seen after a rather bad start. 6 / 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a 19th century story that is strongly reminiscent of a "knight in shining armor" story of long, long ago. The handsome hero is both committed to his cause of freeing Italy from Austrian rule AND protecting his lady from all harm--even when she stupidly blunders into it on a couple occasions. From start to finish, this is an excellent historical "chick flick" and is likely to excite the passions of many female viewers, but I am a guy (at least the last time I checked) and I STILL enjoyed it. The acting was excellent and the cinematography outstanding. About the only minor problem with the film was the occasional stupid behaviors by the female lead (Binoche). A couple times, she just seemed too stupid to live--but, of course, the handsome hero came to her rescue. An excellent film, but a little disturbing due to its graphic depiction of plague victims. Plus, with a little nudity towards the end of the film (it was explicit but not gratuitous), this is NOT a film for the kids.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cast A Cold Eye
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writers_reign
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having begun like most directors with small subjects Jean-Paul Rappeneau seems to have acquired a penchant for the crowded canvas given that his last three films - including this one - comprise Cyrano de Bergerac and Bon Voyage. My knowledge of the period - 1830s - is skimpy to say the least so I have no basis for questioning the authenticity or otherwise of the storyline involving both Italian patriots hiding in France and an outbreak of cholera in the Provence region but this is really academic because authentic or not it provides both a dramatic and colourful backdrop to a well-told story in which for once the Romantic element is understated. Olivier Martinez is sufficiently athletic to carry out lots of Errol Flynn-like engagements with a dozen assailants at once and come off incredibly best but he is woefully lacking in Flynn's abundant charm/charisma so it's just as well that leading lady Juliette Binoche has enough for both. Not least of its assets is the support, never more than ten or fifteen minutes in each case, from some of the finest actors in France from Isabelle Huppert to Jean Yanne to Francois Cluzot to Pierre Arditi. A fine film from a fine director.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Excellent Romantic film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sarahmcm-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I found the film historically poignant in reference to the period of history when the plague ravaged Europe. You feel what people must have felt during that era. The romance was sensitive and based on harsh realities of the epoch in question. This was in my mind, different and refreshing. I recommend this movie to the student of history as well as those who would study love and how love grows in a relationship. I felt the actors were a good pick and stood up well to the task at hand. A great example of some of the recent French films that have come on the scene lately.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great old-fashioned entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    burrobaggy
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Horseman on the Roof has to be one of the most beautiful looking films I've ever seen, which is odd for a movie about a cholera epidemic. Set in a beautiful summer in the mid-19th century, it follows Olivier Martinez's Italian in exile as he is chased across France by Austrian agents intent on killing as many Italian rebels as they can only for his pursuers to be outrun by a cholera epidemic that picks off friends and foes. Along the way his path crosses with various victims and survivors - a doctor who teaches him a neat disinfecting trick of setting your hands on fire, a cute governess, Jean Yanne's duplicitous peddler, Gerard Depardieu's paranoid mayor, and most importantly Juliette Binoche, who is determined to find her husband. Naturally they become travelling companions as they try to get through roadblocks and avoid being put into quarantine by the soldiers cordoning off the roads - a virtual death sentence - and eventually nearly become more. The film looks so good in cinemascope and so much of it is terrific than you can just about forgive the fact that the ending is a bit of a washout after everything that's gone before. A really enjoyable old-fashioned epic, I'd definitely pick this up if it ever turned up on DVD uncut with English subtitles (the Miramax disc is typically cut by 17 minutes thanks to Harvey Scissorhands).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Delightful Adventure and a Sensitive Romance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1832, a frightened France has a serious epidemic of Asiatic cholera, which is killing the population specially in the country, and Italy is invaded and dominated by Austria. In this scenery, Angelo (Oliver Martinez) is a 25 years old refined Italian colonel from a wealthy family exiled in France. He is trying to gather his exiled compatriots and return to Milan to organize the Italian resistance against Austria. Angelo is welcomed by the French noble Pauline (Julliete Binoche) in her house in a difficult moment for him, and Pauline travels together with Angelo, trying to find her missing husband in a chaotic country. Along their journey, Angelo becomes her protector, and they fall in love for each other. "Le Hussard Sur le Toit" is a delightful adventure and a sensitive romance. The story is beautiful and the platonic love and the chemistry between Angelo and Pauline are wonderful. An excellent movie, with a beautiful reconstitution of a dark period of French history and highly recommended for any audience. My vote is eight. Title (Brazil): "O Cavaleiro do Telhado e a Dama das Sombras" ("The Knight of the Roof and the Lady of the Shadows")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A ride through Provence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pax-et-forza
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two superstars of the french cinema: adorable Juliette Binoche and hot Olivier Martinez, love and save each other from lost, sickness and death, while horse-riding through the stunningly beautiful Provence. An adaptation of the famous novel by Jean Giono. They are there: on the screen, on their horses, in this magnificent landscape, he tries to become a man, she tries to stay a woman, they are smiling, and soon you'll express the wish of being with them on this screen, to be one of them, maybe both, if this happens, Rappeneau gets to his goal: grace. A great tale about love, renouncement, youth, passion, courage and Honor. A famous novel of the french literature. Patriotism, romanticism, and grace. Rappeneau is the master, Binoche and Martinez are the gifted pupils.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A stunning romance for realists
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    honeybeexx
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Le Hussard sur le Toit presents its audience with the grim reality of cholera-stricken rural France in 1832 and its effect on a journey of escape by two anxious visitors. The frequent images of corpses and mass burial are refreshed by the breathtaking and beautifully shot scenery, itself brought to life by characters who dilute the presence of death with an oxymoronic mix of comedy and despair. Carrion crows regularly appear, mercilessly flying around in sinister anticipation, their cawing beaks wide open with hunger. Juliette Binoche enters only in the second half, her laconic period style beautifully portrayed, and preparing the way for her appearance as George Sand in Les Enfants du Siecle (1999). Le Hussard's plot is simple, its screenplay uncomplicated. But the action is fast and Bond-like and the innocence of Martinez' military-dominated character is uncanny. But it is its simplicity that makes this movie a work of exceptional visual satisfaction, for romantics or action-lovers alike.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent adventure story, entertaining, and emotionally rewarding!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yossarian100
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Horseman on the Roof is one of those rare movies that has everything going for it; breathtaking scenery, fascinating story told in literary style with great attention to detail, stunning main characters with exceptional chemistry and screen presence, and an epic presentation of a great adventure. The central motivation of our young colonel is chivalry and that is so refreshing. Amazing!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
