<filme>
 <id>
  1132
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116289
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Paix&atilde;o Bandida
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  An ex-convict and his bumbling crook brother fight for the same woman.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Freddie is a former stripper marrying Sam to repay a debt owed to nightclub owner Red. But Freddie is in love with Jjaks, Sam's brother. Jjaks and Freddie run off together, and Sam finds where they have been hiding and calls the cops. Meanwhile someone calls to blackmail Sam and Jjaks. In the end will it all work out?
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   title based on song
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   family relationships
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bride
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   photo booth
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   corruption
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Steven Baigelman
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Steven Baigelman
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Keanu Reeves
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Vincent D'Onofrio
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Cameron Diaz
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    90s twisting & turning, very funny low-life crime film about users on the take
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bottom line, this is a very funny, silly, slapstick, goofy film - but very adult, with twists and turns as the largely amoral characters grapple and use each other to get what they want. None of the characters are particularly likable, Jjaks (Reeves) seems the most put upon but he's in and out of prison and Freddie (Diaz) is a good time girl who messed with the wrong people and is just doing what she has to do to get by. It's also a sort of romantic love story although despite Reeves acting superbly and being rather cute, the chemistry between him and Diaz is lacking something. Diaz, I don't feel is acting her best and often is a somewhat monotone, as if reading lines, but they are enjoyable to watch and whilst I think she's the weakest performance she has the most difficult and emotionally exposing role and in that case I think she does well. It's the scenes with Reeves and D'Onofrio that are truly engaging in an anti-chemistry kind of way. They rub each other up the wrong way - sibling rivalry - Jjaks having had the bad end of every deal in their childhood - and in doing so provide some scarily good aggression and slapstick comedy timing genius ensues. It's a film where you have to watch closely, for some grand scale and also minutiae performances, and it can be watched over and over again for laughs and the drama. Reeves is animated and light - like Diaz, I think he suits comedy and there are plenty of funny scenes (albeit black comedy as often as not) to enjoy. Diaz is both charming and annoying - her character is understandable and relatable (possibly due to her performance making it so) but also largely without scruples and single mindedness: her dream of working in Vegas - and I like that whilst it ends satisfactorily, it's not particularly Hollywood in it's ending and it's predictable but pleasantly so. Dan Aykroyd is the hapless, stupid, love-sick, cop on the take with a very overblown Minnesota accent - or is it Canadian, or Irish? He brings more laughs, and Courtney Love in a small but nice role adds small town glamour and a stable foil for some of D'Onofrio's eccentric behaviours. Adults only black comedy, lots of bad language, scenes of a sexual nature (though not gratuitous) and a lot of violence and aggression. The subject matter, and plot, make for a very dramatic film but it's played for laughs which makes it an enjoyable romp with all the actors giving it 100%. Amazingly this film flew under the radar of 90s cinema-going and is an unexpectedly good film that I've seen a number of times and it doesn't get old. Not a chick-flick although it may appear as such, and plenty for boys to enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dumb and selfish characters doing dumb and selfish stuff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw this movie when it came out I thought it was a good movie. But watching it now, not as much but just decent at best. But than again I thought Cameron Diaz was overly hot back than. This movie is basically about two brothers quarreling with one another and fighting each other in a very malicious manner. One more malicious than the other and they are both in love with a superficial and selfish girl. And none of the characters are likable and run on greed and their own selfish ambitions while constantly trying to use each other. But than again that somewhat applies to the real world. Watching this movie was like watching "Dumb & Dumber" except the characters aren't as dumb nor as funny. It has this certain black humor going for it and it works sometimes and has a slight bit of the Coen brothers vibe going for it. But the humor isn't all that well grafted and is nowhere near as good as the Coen brothers films. Keanu Reeves who plays the slight good brother between the two brothers is right for this role and although his acting needed some work. He did a good job of playing this dumb character that is oblivious to his surroundings. His character Jjaks is basically a dumb robber that gets into a hole when he bangs his brothers wife who got forced into the marriage by thugs and so on. This movie is basically about dumb selfish people doing dumb and selfish stuff. It's still a entertaining movie to a degree but nothing special. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Dog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This completely failed attempt at a Black Comedy is a painful experience to watch. It is an example of bad direction and a bad script and the on screen performers are left with nowhere to go. That is the feeling that the film elicits. It is all over the place with predictable "surprises" and floundering characters on a road to ruin. It is not for one minute funny, or exciting, or dark. It is nothing dressed up as something with a hip delivery and dull designations. The tension between the brothers is nothing more than rough housing and the film's tone changes so much it is dizzying. This mess is a movie that does not entertain or even pass as anything but an unrelenting bore. In fact it is cinema of the cringe. An ugly affair with unpleasant characters and events. The most interesting part of humanity in this movie is the Dog. Ironically that's what this is, a dog. They must have seen it coming. But it's doubtful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Feeling is to Miss Minnesota *1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very poor film dealing with quite a dysfunctional family to put it mildly. This must have been one of Cameron Diaz's first films and she set the standard for her career: A real cute young lady with absolutely no acting talent whatsoever. In this sub-standard film, two brothers vie for attention and one, Vincent D'Onofrio actually marries her. Tuesday Weld, as the mother of the two losers, is totally unrecognizable and should be considered fortunate to drop dead early in the film. Anything to get away from this. Even the end-plot twist with officer Dan Akroyd is boring at best.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Woeful film has a provocative look and feel...but nothing of interest in the foreground
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Baigelman wrote and directed this uncertain comedy-drama concerning estranged brothers (Keanu Reeves and Vincent D'Onofrio) battling over embezzled cash as well as the affections of a pretty blonde (Cameron Diaz). The gritty ambiance inherent in Walt Lloyd's incredibly vivid cinematography is the most memorable aspect of the picture; capturing a blue-collar realism with such clarity, however, tends to emphasize the unreality of these dunderhead characters, and the movie's look and its story fail to cohere. Baigelman does get things off to a promising start, and he has an attentive eye for what to capture, but these petty people merit little interest. Danny DeVito was one of the many producers (all, presumably, with their own idea of how to film Baigelman's unremarkable script). *1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good loser movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hang_All_Drunkdrivers
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a way it's like Laurel and Hardy in that the two main characters are a couple of idiots always fighting. Keanu Reeves and Vince D'Onofrio play two feuding brothers who want the same women. The women, played very sexily by Cameron Diaz, likes Reeves but is married to D'Onofrio and has eyes on his money. Some people get murdered but the show is really more of a comedy. The three leads do a great job as do the supporting actors like Dan Aykroyd and the always watchable Delroy Lindo. You think of Reeves as being a handsome guy but not here. With his awful hair style and drunk attitude, he's really got loser wrote all over him. Midway in the movie his character does something really clever when he wakes up and finds a dead body in his room and then gets a call saying the police are coming up to talk to him. But he finds a way to fool them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very enjoyable if imperfect film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TilDuDor
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Feeling Minnesota is an entertaining movie, and though it may require some rewatching to be sure, it's probably now one of my favorites. From the beginning it reminded me quite a bit of a certain Coen brothers film with a similar title, only it is much more violent and a little darker. For those of you who haven't seen it, and to sum it up without spoilers, it's basically a movie about two brothers- Keanu Reeves, the petty crook who has a habit of holding up convenience stores (again, remind you of anything?), and D'Onofrio, his jerky brother. If I got everything right, D'Onofrio does accounting for a dope dealer/club owner who gives him this girl (Diaz, not exactly stellar in this role) as a wife as a reward for him for finding money she stole and as a punishment for her (again, he's a jerk). Reeves pretty much steals her away from D'Onofrio, and D'Onofrio isn't havin' none of that. The best thing about this movie is the weird sense of humor- it's rather subtle sometimes, and then out of nowhere there will be goofy physical comedy (the only thing Reeves excelled at in this, oddly enough) and weird situational humor. The tone is fairly dark through most of it, but there are plenty of hilarious scenes (however odd they are). This might be my favorite D'Onofrio movie (I'm a big fan of the man), especially for how over-the-top he was in it and for all of the goofy outfits he wore. There are a bunch of scenes where he and Reeves are stumbling around or beating each other up and the nearly slapstick physical comedy was great. D'Onofrio and Aykroyd especially are great as the whiny, violent brother with a bizarre taste in clothes and the crooked cop with the hots for Diaz. Reeves wasn't the best choice, though he's passable (especially in scenes involving sibling rivalry), but the rest of the cast wasn't exactly delightful. The sex scenes between Reeves and Diaz (again, not exactly my two favorite performers) were pretty awful, there were parts of the ending that I didn't like, and I wish the film had omitted some of the more annoying romantic elements in general, but I really enjoyed it overall. It's certainly something I'd recommend, though it's a little odd and very dark (pretty much all of the characters are simultaneously likable and disgusting), so it may not be for everyone
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    See it because of Keanu Reeves and Cameron Diaz.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gmckeeverbeast94
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw Feeling MInnesota on a Saturday morning. And if it didn't have Keanu Reeves and Cameron Diaz, I wouldn't have watched the whole thing. Reeves plays Jjaks, a man who lives his life on the road, because his mother threw him out when he was only 8. Jjaks has an older brother, Sam who works at a nightclub. The owner of the nightclub found that someone stole his money. He figure that it was Freddie, an ordinary woman played by Cameron Diaz. The nightclub owner is making Freddie pay off the money by marrying Sam. At the wedding, Freddie meets Jjaks and falls in love with him. They run off together and things turn into a disaster. If you enjoy movies with 2 men fighting over the same woman, then I would recommend Feeling Minnesota to you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    J.J. Jameson Quote ... Crap, Crap, ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    smccahon
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    J.J. Jameson (from Spiderman 2) Quote ... Crap, Crap, ... Mega-Crap It pretends to be an homage (un/intentional) to the Coen Brothers ... done poorly. There is no real mystery to the plot. Diaz's performance is totally uninspired. The quirky characters don't really work. There are a lot of "duh" moments. I love black comedy, but this film isn't funny. In my view, it wasn't worth the electricity. There are many films in this genre which are much more entertaining. I hope you find this review helpful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie was a complete waste of my time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I want the 99 minutes of my life back that was wasted on this pathetic excuse for a movie. The acting was horrific! I used to be a fan of Cameron Diaz and Vincent D'Onofrio. I will never look at them the same again. Keanu Reeves and Dan Aykroyd were not a surprise. Everyone knows they never could act. Thankfully, only Dan attempted an accent. His accent was a disaster as expected. I think he was either confused about the location of the film or had never actually spoken to anyone from Minnesota. I hope this review helps anyone who is undecided about what to do with their precious time. The only reason I was able to sit through the whole movie was because I was stuck somewhere without anything better to watch or read.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    90s twisting & turning, very funny low-life crime film about users on the take
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bottom line, this is a very funny, silly, slapstick, goofy film - but very adult, with twists and turns as the largely amoral characters grapple and use each other to get what they want. None of the characters are particularly likable, Jjaks (Reeves) seems the most put upon but he's in and out of prison and Freddie (Diaz) is a good time girl who messed with the wrong people and is just doing what she has to do to get by. It's also a sort of romantic love story although despite Reeves acting superbly and being rather cute, the chemistry between him and Diaz is lacking something. Diaz, I don't feel is acting her best and often is a somewhat monotone, as if reading lines, but they are enjoyable to watch and whilst I think she's the weakest performance she has the most difficult and emotionally exposing role and in that case I think she does well. It's the scenes with Reeves and D'Onofrio that are truly engaging in an anti-chemistry kind of way. They rub each other up the wrong way - sibling rivalry - Jjaks having had the bad end of every deal in their childhood - and in doing so provide some scarily good aggression and slapstick comedy timing genius ensues. It's a film where you have to watch closely, for some grand scale and also minutiae performances, and it can be watched over and over again for laughs and the drama. Reeves is animated and light - like Diaz, I think he suits comedy and there are plenty of funny scenes (albeit black comedy as often as not) to enjoy. Diaz is both charming and annoying - her character is understandable and relatable (possibly due to her performance making it so) but also largely without scruples and single mindedness: her dream of working in Vegas - and I like that whilst it ends satisfactorily, it's not particularly Hollywood in it's ending and it's predictable but pleasantly so. Dan Aykroyd is the hapless, stupid, love-sick, cop on the take with a very overblown Minnesota accent - or is it Canadian, or Irish? He brings more laughs, and Courtney Love in a small but nice role adds small town glamour and a stable foil for some of D'Onofrio's eccentric behaviours. Adults only black comedy, lots of bad language, scenes of a sexual nature (though not gratuitous) and a lot of violence and aggression. The subject matter, and plot, make for a very dramatic film but it's played for laughs which makes it an enjoyable romp with all the actors giving it 100%. Amazingly this film flew under the radar of 90s cinema-going and is an unexpectedly good film that I've seen a number of times and it doesn't get old. Not a chick-flick although it may appear as such, and plenty for boys to enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dumb and selfish characters doing dumb and selfish stuff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw this movie when it came out I thought it was a good movie. But watching it now, not as much but just decent at best. But than again I thought Cameron Diaz was overly hot back than. This movie is basically about two brothers quarreling with one another and fighting each other in a very malicious manner. One more malicious than the other and they are both in love with a superficial and selfish girl. And none of the characters are likable and run on greed and their own selfish ambitions while constantly trying to use each other. But than again that somewhat applies to the real world. Watching this movie was like watching "Dumb & Dumber" except the characters aren't as dumb nor as funny. It has this certain black humor going for it and it works sometimes and has a slight bit of the Coen brothers vibe going for it. But the humor isn't all that well grafted and is nowhere near as good as the Coen brothers films. Keanu Reeves who plays the slight good brother between the two brothers is right for this role and although his acting needed some work. He did a good job of playing this dumb character that is oblivious to his surroundings. His character Jjaks is basically a dumb robber that gets into a hole when he bangs his brothers wife who got forced into the marriage by thugs and so on. This movie is basically about dumb selfish people doing dumb and selfish stuff. It's still a entertaining movie to a degree but nothing special. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Dog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This completely failed attempt at a Black Comedy is a painful experience to watch. It is an example of bad direction and a bad script and the on screen performers are left with nowhere to go. That is the feeling that the film elicits. It is all over the place with predictable "surprises" and floundering characters on a road to ruin. It is not for one minute funny, or exciting, or dark. It is nothing dressed up as something with a hip delivery and dull designations. The tension between the brothers is nothing more than rough housing and the film's tone changes so much it is dizzying. This mess is a movie that does not entertain or even pass as anything but an unrelenting bore. In fact it is cinema of the cringe. An ugly affair with unpleasant characters and events. The most interesting part of humanity in this movie is the Dog. Ironically that's what this is, a dog. They must have seen it coming. But it's doubtful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Feeling is to Miss Minnesota *1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very poor film dealing with quite a dysfunctional family to put it mildly. This must have been one of Cameron Diaz's first films and she set the standard for her career: A real cute young lady with absolutely no acting talent whatsoever. In this sub-standard film, two brothers vie for attention and one, Vincent D'Onofrio actually marries her. Tuesday Weld, as the mother of the two losers, is totally unrecognizable and should be considered fortunate to drop dead early in the film. Anything to get away from this. Even the end-plot twist with officer Dan Akroyd is boring at best.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Woeful film has a provocative look and feel...but nothing of interest in the foreground
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Baigelman wrote and directed this uncertain comedy-drama concerning estranged brothers (Keanu Reeves and Vincent D'Onofrio) battling over embezzled cash as well as the affections of a pretty blonde (Cameron Diaz). The gritty ambiance inherent in Walt Lloyd's incredibly vivid cinematography is the most memorable aspect of the picture; capturing a blue-collar realism with such clarity, however, tends to emphasize the unreality of these dunderhead characters, and the movie's look and its story fail to cohere. Baigelman does get things off to a promising start, and he has an attentive eye for what to capture, but these petty people merit little interest. Danny DeVito was one of the many producers (all, presumably, with their own idea of how to film Baigelman's unremarkable script). *1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good loser movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hang_All_Drunkdrivers
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a way it's like Laurel and Hardy in that the two main characters are a couple of idiots always fighting. Keanu Reeves and Vince D'Onofrio play two feuding brothers who want the same women. The women, played very sexily by Cameron Diaz, likes Reeves but is married to D'Onofrio and has eyes on his money. Some people get murdered but the show is really more of a comedy. The three leads do a great job as do the supporting actors like Dan Aykroyd and the always watchable Delroy Lindo. You think of Reeves as being a handsome guy but not here. With his awful hair style and drunk attitude, he's really got loser wrote all over him. Midway in the movie his character does something really clever when he wakes up and finds a dead body in his room and then gets a call saying the police are coming up to talk to him. But he finds a way to fool them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very enjoyable if imperfect film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TilDuDor
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Feeling Minnesota is an entertaining movie, and though it may require some rewatching to be sure, it's probably now one of my favorites. From the beginning it reminded me quite a bit of a certain Coen brothers film with a similar title, only it is much more violent and a little darker. For those of you who haven't seen it, and to sum it up without spoilers, it's basically a movie about two brothers- Keanu Reeves, the petty crook who has a habit of holding up convenience stores (again, remind you of anything?), and D'Onofrio, his jerky brother. If I got everything right, D'Onofrio does accounting for a dope dealer/club owner who gives him this girl (Diaz, not exactly stellar in this role) as a wife as a reward for him for finding money she stole and as a punishment for her (again, he's a jerk). Reeves pretty much steals her away from D'Onofrio, and D'Onofrio isn't havin' none of that. The best thing about this movie is the weird sense of humor- it's rather subtle sometimes, and then out of nowhere there will be goofy physical comedy (the only thing Reeves excelled at in this, oddly enough) and weird situational humor. The tone is fairly dark through most of it, but there are plenty of hilarious scenes (however odd they are). This might be my favorite D'Onofrio movie (I'm a big fan of the man), especially for how over-the-top he was in it and for all of the goofy outfits he wore. There are a bunch of scenes where he and Reeves are stumbling around or beating each other up and the nearly slapstick physical comedy was great. D'Onofrio and Aykroyd especially are great as the whiny, violent brother with a bizarre taste in clothes and the crooked cop with the hots for Diaz. Reeves wasn't the best choice, though he's passable (especially in scenes involving sibling rivalry), but the rest of the cast wasn't exactly delightful. The sex scenes between Reeves and Diaz (again, not exactly my two favorite performers) were pretty awful, there were parts of the ending that I didn't like, and I wish the film had omitted some of the more annoying romantic elements in general, but I really enjoyed it overall. It's certainly something I'd recommend, though it's a little odd and very dark (pretty much all of the characters are simultaneously likable and disgusting), so it may not be for everyone
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    See it because of Keanu Reeves and Cameron Diaz.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gmckeeverbeast94
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw Feeling MInnesota on a Saturday morning. And if it didn't have Keanu Reeves and Cameron Diaz, I wouldn't have watched the whole thing. Reeves plays Jjaks, a man who lives his life on the road, because his mother threw him out when he was only 8. Jjaks has an older brother, Sam who works at a nightclub. The owner of the nightclub found that someone stole his money. He figure that it was Freddie, an ordinary woman played by Cameron Diaz. The nightclub owner is making Freddie pay off the money by marrying Sam. At the wedding, Freddie meets Jjaks and falls in love with him. They run off together and things turn into a disaster. If you enjoy movies with 2 men fighting over the same woman, then I would recommend Feeling Minnesota to you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    J.J. Jameson Quote ... Crap, Crap, ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    smccahon
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    J.J. Jameson (from Spiderman 2) Quote ... Crap, Crap, ... Mega-Crap It pretends to be an homage (un/intentional) to the Coen Brothers ... done poorly. There is no real mystery to the plot. Diaz's performance is totally uninspired. The quirky characters don't really work. There are a lot of "duh" moments. I love black comedy, but this film isn't funny. In my view, it wasn't worth the electricity. There are many films in this genre which are much more entertaining. I hope you find this review helpful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie was a complete waste of my time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I want the 99 minutes of my life back that was wasted on this pathetic excuse for a movie. The acting was horrific! I used to be a fan of Cameron Diaz and Vincent D'Onofrio. I will never look at them the same again. Keanu Reeves and Dan Aykroyd were not a surprise. Everyone knows they never could act. Thankfully, only Dan attempted an accent. His accent was a disaster as expected. I think he was either confused about the location of the film or had never actually spoken to anyone from Minnesota. I hope this review helps anyone who is undecided about what to do with their precious time. The only reason I was able to sit through the whole movie was because I was stuck somewhere without anything better to watch or read.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    90s twisting & turning, very funny low-life crime film about users on the take
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bottom line, this is a very funny, silly, slapstick, goofy film - but very adult, with twists and turns as the largely amoral characters grapple and use each other to get what they want. None of the characters are particularly likable, Jjaks (Reeves) seems the most put upon but he's in and out of prison and Freddie (Diaz) is a good time girl who messed with the wrong people and is just doing what she has to do to get by. It's also a sort of romantic love story although despite Reeves acting superbly and being rather cute, the chemistry between him and Diaz is lacking something. Diaz, I don't feel is acting her best and often is a somewhat monotone, as if reading lines, but they are enjoyable to watch and whilst I think she's the weakest performance she has the most difficult and emotionally exposing role and in that case I think she does well. It's the scenes with Reeves and D'Onofrio that are truly engaging in an anti-chemistry kind of way. They rub each other up the wrong way - sibling rivalry - Jjaks having had the bad end of every deal in their childhood - and in doing so provide some scarily good aggression and slapstick comedy timing genius ensues. It's a film where you have to watch closely, for some grand scale and also minutiae performances, and it can be watched over and over again for laughs and the drama. Reeves is animated and light - like Diaz, I think he suits comedy and there are plenty of funny scenes (albeit black comedy as often as not) to enjoy. Diaz is both charming and annoying - her character is understandable and relatable (possibly due to her performance making it so) but also largely without scruples and single mindedness: her dream of working in Vegas - and I like that whilst it ends satisfactorily, it's not particularly Hollywood in it's ending and it's predictable but pleasantly so. Dan Aykroyd is the hapless, stupid, love-sick, cop on the take with a very overblown Minnesota accent - or is it Canadian, or Irish? He brings more laughs, and Courtney Love in a small but nice role adds small town glamour and a stable foil for some of D'Onofrio's eccentric behaviours. Adults only black comedy, lots of bad language, scenes of a sexual nature (though not gratuitous) and a lot of violence and aggression. The subject matter, and plot, make for a very dramatic film but it's played for laughs which makes it an enjoyable romp with all the actors giving it 100%. Amazingly this film flew under the radar of 90s cinema-going and is an unexpectedly good film that I've seen a number of times and it doesn't get old. Not a chick-flick although it may appear as such, and plenty for boys to enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dumb and selfish characters doing dumb and selfish stuff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw this movie when it came out I thought it was a good movie. But watching it now, not as much but just decent at best. But than again I thought Cameron Diaz was overly hot back than. This movie is basically about two brothers quarreling with one another and fighting each other in a very malicious manner. One more malicious than the other and they are both in love with a superficial and selfish girl. And none of the characters are likable and run on greed and their own selfish ambitions while constantly trying to use each other. But than again that somewhat applies to the real world. Watching this movie was like watching "Dumb & Dumber" except the characters aren't as dumb nor as funny. It has this certain black humor going for it and it works sometimes and has a slight bit of the Coen brothers vibe going for it. But the humor isn't all that well grafted and is nowhere near as good as the Coen brothers films. Keanu Reeves who plays the slight good brother between the two brothers is right for this role and although his acting needed some work. He did a good job of playing this dumb character that is oblivious to his surroundings. His character Jjaks is basically a dumb robber that gets into a hole when he bangs his brothers wife who got forced into the marriage by thugs and so on. This movie is basically about dumb selfish people doing dumb and selfish stuff. It's still a entertaining movie to a degree but nothing special. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Dog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This completely failed attempt at a Black Comedy is a painful experience to watch. It is an example of bad direction and a bad script and the on screen performers are left with nowhere to go. That is the feeling that the film elicits. It is all over the place with predictable "surprises" and floundering characters on a road to ruin. It is not for one minute funny, or exciting, or dark. It is nothing dressed up as something with a hip delivery and dull designations. The tension between the brothers is nothing more than rough housing and the film's tone changes so much it is dizzying. This mess is a movie that does not entertain or even pass as anything but an unrelenting bore. In fact it is cinema of the cringe. An ugly affair with unpleasant characters and events. The most interesting part of humanity in this movie is the Dog. Ironically that's what this is, a dog. They must have seen it coming. But it's doubtful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Feeling is to Miss Minnesota *1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very poor film dealing with quite a dysfunctional family to put it mildly. This must have been one of Cameron Diaz's first films and she set the standard for her career: A real cute young lady with absolutely no acting talent whatsoever. In this sub-standard film, two brothers vie for attention and one, Vincent D'Onofrio actually marries her. Tuesday Weld, as the mother of the two losers, is totally unrecognizable and should be considered fortunate to drop dead early in the film. Anything to get away from this. Even the end-plot twist with officer Dan Akroyd is boring at best.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Woeful film has a provocative look and feel...but nothing of interest in the foreground
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Baigelman wrote and directed this uncertain comedy-drama concerning estranged brothers (Keanu Reeves and Vincent D'Onofrio) battling over embezzled cash as well as the affections of a pretty blonde (Cameron Diaz). The gritty ambiance inherent in Walt Lloyd's incredibly vivid cinematography is the most memorable aspect of the picture; capturing a blue-collar realism with such clarity, however, tends to emphasize the unreality of these dunderhead characters, and the movie's look and its story fail to cohere. Baigelman does get things off to a promising start, and he has an attentive eye for what to capture, but these petty people merit little interest. Danny DeVito was one of the many producers (all, presumably, with their own idea of how to film Baigelman's unremarkable script). *1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good loser movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hang_All_Drunkdrivers
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a way it's like Laurel and Hardy in that the two main characters are a couple of idiots always fighting. Keanu Reeves and Vince D'Onofrio play two feuding brothers who want the same women. The women, played very sexily by Cameron Diaz, likes Reeves but is married to D'Onofrio and has eyes on his money. Some people get murdered but the show is really more of a comedy. The three leads do a great job as do the supporting actors like Dan Aykroyd and the always watchable Delroy Lindo. You think of Reeves as being a handsome guy but not here. With his awful hair style and drunk attitude, he's really got loser wrote all over him. Midway in the movie his character does something really clever when he wakes up and finds a dead body in his room and then gets a call saying the police are coming up to talk to him. But he finds a way to fool them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very enjoyable if imperfect film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TilDuDor
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Feeling Minnesota is an entertaining movie, and though it may require some rewatching to be sure, it's probably now one of my favorites. From the beginning it reminded me quite a bit of a certain Coen brothers film with a similar title, only it is much more violent and a little darker. For those of you who haven't seen it, and to sum it up without spoilers, it's basically a movie about two brothers- Keanu Reeves, the petty crook who has a habit of holding up convenience stores (again, remind you of anything?), and D'Onofrio, his jerky brother. If I got everything right, D'Onofrio does accounting for a dope dealer/club owner who gives him this girl (Diaz, not exactly stellar in this role) as a wife as a reward for him for finding money she stole and as a punishment for her (again, he's a jerk). Reeves pretty much steals her away from D'Onofrio, and D'Onofrio isn't havin' none of that. The best thing about this movie is the weird sense of humor- it's rather subtle sometimes, and then out of nowhere there will be goofy physical comedy (the only thing Reeves excelled at in this, oddly enough) and weird situational humor. The tone is fairly dark through most of it, but there are plenty of hilarious scenes (however odd they are). This might be my favorite D'Onofrio movie (I'm a big fan of the man), especially for how over-the-top he was in it and for all of the goofy outfits he wore. There are a bunch of scenes where he and Reeves are stumbling around or beating each other up and the nearly slapstick physical comedy was great. D'Onofrio and Aykroyd especially are great as the whiny, violent brother with a bizarre taste in clothes and the crooked cop with the hots for Diaz. Reeves wasn't the best choice, though he's passable (especially in scenes involving sibling rivalry), but the rest of the cast wasn't exactly delightful. The sex scenes between Reeves and Diaz (again, not exactly my two favorite performers) were pretty awful, there were parts of the ending that I didn't like, and I wish the film had omitted some of the more annoying romantic elements in general, but I really enjoyed it overall. It's certainly something I'd recommend, though it's a little odd and very dark (pretty much all of the characters are simultaneously likable and disgusting), so it may not be for everyone
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    See it because of Keanu Reeves and Cameron Diaz.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gmckeeverbeast94
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw Feeling MInnesota on a Saturday morning. And if it didn't have Keanu Reeves and Cameron Diaz, I wouldn't have watched the whole thing. Reeves plays Jjaks, a man who lives his life on the road, because his mother threw him out when he was only 8. Jjaks has an older brother, Sam who works at a nightclub. The owner of the nightclub found that someone stole his money. He figure that it was Freddie, an ordinary woman played by Cameron Diaz. The nightclub owner is making Freddie pay off the money by marrying Sam. At the wedding, Freddie meets Jjaks and falls in love with him. They run off together and things turn into a disaster. If you enjoy movies with 2 men fighting over the same woman, then I would recommend Feeling Minnesota to you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    J.J. Jameson Quote ... Crap, Crap, ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    smccahon
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    J.J. Jameson (from Spiderman 2) Quote ... Crap, Crap, ... Mega-Crap It pretends to be an homage (un/intentional) to the Coen Brothers ... done poorly. There is no real mystery to the plot. Diaz's performance is totally uninspired. The quirky characters don't really work. There are a lot of "duh" moments. I love black comedy, but this film isn't funny. In my view, it wasn't worth the electricity. There are many films in this genre which are much more entertaining. I hope you find this review helpful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie was a complete waste of my time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I want the 99 minutes of my life back that was wasted on this pathetic excuse for a movie. The acting was horrific! I used to be a fan of Cameron Diaz and Vincent D'Onofrio. I will never look at them the same again. Keanu Reeves and Dan Aykroyd were not a surprise. Everyone knows they never could act. Thankfully, only Dan attempted an accent. His accent was a disaster as expected. I think he was either confused about the location of the film or had never actually spoken to anyone from Minnesota. I hope this review helps anyone who is undecided about what to do with their precious time. The only reason I was able to sit through the whole movie was because I was stuck somewhere without anything better to watch or read.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    90s twisting & turning, very funny low-life crime film about users on the take
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bottom line, this is a very funny, silly, slapstick, goofy film - but very adult, with twists and turns as the largely amoral characters grapple and use each other to get what they want. None of the characters are particularly likable, Jjaks (Reeves) seems the most put upon but he's in and out of prison and Freddie (Diaz) is a good time girl who messed with the wrong people and is just doing what she has to do to get by. It's also a sort of romantic love story although despite Reeves acting superbly and being rather cute, the chemistry between him and Diaz is lacking something. Diaz, I don't feel is acting her best and often is a somewhat monotone, as if reading lines, but they are enjoyable to watch and whilst I think she's the weakest performance she has the most difficult and emotionally exposing role and in that case I think she does well. It's the scenes with Reeves and D'Onofrio that are truly engaging in an anti-chemistry kind of way. They rub each other up the wrong way - sibling rivalry - Jjaks having had the bad end of every deal in their childhood - and in doing so provide some scarily good aggression and slapstick comedy timing genius ensues. It's a film where you have to watch closely, for some grand scale and also minutiae performances, and it can be watched over and over again for laughs and the drama. Reeves is animated and light - like Diaz, I think he suits comedy and there are plenty of funny scenes (albeit black comedy as often as not) to enjoy. Diaz is both charming and annoying - her character is understandable and relatable (possibly due to her performance making it so) but also largely without scruples and single mindedness: her dream of working in Vegas - and I like that whilst it ends satisfactorily, it's not particularly Hollywood in it's ending and it's predictable but pleasantly so. Dan Aykroyd is the hapless, stupid, love-sick, cop on the take with a very overblown Minnesota accent - or is it Canadian, or Irish? He brings more laughs, and Courtney Love in a small but nice role adds small town glamour and a stable foil for some of D'Onofrio's eccentric behaviours. Adults only black comedy, lots of bad language, scenes of a sexual nature (though not gratuitous) and a lot of violence and aggression. The subject matter, and plot, make for a very dramatic film but it's played for laughs which makes it an enjoyable romp with all the actors giving it 100%. Amazingly this film flew under the radar of 90s cinema-going and is an unexpectedly good film that I've seen a number of times and it doesn't get old. Not a chick-flick although it may appear as such, and plenty for boys to enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dumb and selfish characters doing dumb and selfish stuff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw this movie when it came out I thought it was a good movie. But watching it now, not as much but just decent at best. But than again I thought Cameron Diaz was overly hot back than. This movie is basically about two brothers quarreling with one another and fighting each other in a very malicious manner. One more malicious than the other and they are both in love with a superficial and selfish girl. And none of the characters are likable and run on greed and their own selfish ambitions while constantly trying to use each other. But than again that somewhat applies to the real world. Watching this movie was like watching "Dumb & Dumber" except the characters aren't as dumb nor as funny. It has this certain black humor going for it and it works sometimes and has a slight bit of the Coen brothers vibe going for it. But the humor isn't all that well grafted and is nowhere near as good as the Coen brothers films. Keanu Reeves who plays the slight good brother between the two brothers is right for this role and although his acting needed some work. He did a good job of playing this dumb character that is oblivious to his surroundings. His character Jjaks is basically a dumb robber that gets into a hole when he bangs his brothers wife who got forced into the marriage by thugs and so on. This movie is basically about dumb selfish people doing dumb and selfish stuff. It's still a entertaining movie to a degree but nothing special. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Dog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This completely failed attempt at a Black Comedy is a painful experience to watch. It is an example of bad direction and a bad script and the on screen performers are left with nowhere to go. That is the feeling that the film elicits. It is all over the place with predictable "surprises" and floundering characters on a road to ruin. It is not for one minute funny, or exciting, or dark. It is nothing dressed up as something with a hip delivery and dull designations. The tension between the brothers is nothing more than rough housing and the film's tone changes so much it is dizzying. This mess is a movie that does not entertain or even pass as anything but an unrelenting bore. In fact it is cinema of the cringe. An ugly affair with unpleasant characters and events. The most interesting part of humanity in this movie is the Dog. Ironically that's what this is, a dog. They must have seen it coming. But it's doubtful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Feeling is to Miss Minnesota *1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very poor film dealing with quite a dysfunctional family to put it mildly. This must have been one of Cameron Diaz's first films and she set the standard for her career: A real cute young lady with absolutely no acting talent whatsoever. In this sub-standard film, two brothers vie for attention and one, Vincent D'Onofrio actually marries her. Tuesday Weld, as the mother of the two losers, is totally unrecognizable and should be considered fortunate to drop dead early in the film. Anything to get away from this. Even the end-plot twist with officer Dan Akroyd is boring at best.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Woeful film has a provocative look and feel...but nothing of interest in the foreground
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Baigelman wrote and directed this uncertain comedy-drama concerning estranged brothers (Keanu Reeves and Vincent D'Onofrio) battling over embezzled cash as well as the affections of a pretty blonde (Cameron Diaz). The gritty ambiance inherent in Walt Lloyd's incredibly vivid cinematography is the most memorable aspect of the picture; capturing a blue-collar realism with such clarity, however, tends to emphasize the unreality of these dunderhead characters, and the movie's look and its story fail to cohere. Baigelman does get things off to a promising start, and he has an attentive eye for what to capture, but these petty people merit little interest. Danny DeVito was one of the many producers (all, presumably, with their own idea of how to film Baigelman's unremarkable script). *1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good loser movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hang_All_Drunkdrivers
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a way it's like Laurel and Hardy in that the two main characters are a couple of idiots always fighting. Keanu Reeves and Vince D'Onofrio play two feuding brothers who want the same women. The women, played very sexily by Cameron Diaz, likes Reeves but is married to D'Onofrio and has eyes on his money. Some people get murdered but the show is really more of a comedy. The three leads do a great job as do the supporting actors like Dan Aykroyd and the always watchable Delroy Lindo. You think of Reeves as being a handsome guy but not here. With his awful hair style and drunk attitude, he's really got loser wrote all over him. Midway in the movie his character does something really clever when he wakes up and finds a dead body in his room and then gets a call saying the police are coming up to talk to him. But he finds a way to fool them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very enjoyable if imperfect film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TilDuDor
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Feeling Minnesota is an entertaining movie, and though it may require some rewatching to be sure, it's probably now one of my favorites. From the beginning it reminded me quite a bit of a certain Coen brothers film with a similar title, only it is much more violent and a little darker. For those of you who haven't seen it, and to sum it up without spoilers, it's basically a movie about two brothers- Keanu Reeves, the petty crook who has a habit of holding up convenience stores (again, remind you of anything?), and D'Onofrio, his jerky brother. If I got everything right, D'Onofrio does accounting for a dope dealer/club owner who gives him this girl (Diaz, not exactly stellar in this role) as a wife as a reward for him for finding money she stole and as a punishment for her (again, he's a jerk). Reeves pretty much steals her away from D'Onofrio, and D'Onofrio isn't havin' none of that. The best thing about this movie is the weird sense of humor- it's rather subtle sometimes, and then out of nowhere there will be goofy physical comedy (the only thing Reeves excelled at in this, oddly enough) and weird situational humor. The tone is fairly dark through most of it, but there are plenty of hilarious scenes (however odd they are). This might be my favorite D'Onofrio movie (I'm a big fan of the man), especially for how over-the-top he was in it and for all of the goofy outfits he wore. There are a bunch of scenes where he and Reeves are stumbling around or beating each other up and the nearly slapstick physical comedy was great. D'Onofrio and Aykroyd especially are great as the whiny, violent brother with a bizarre taste in clothes and the crooked cop with the hots for Diaz. Reeves wasn't the best choice, though he's passable (especially in scenes involving sibling rivalry), but the rest of the cast wasn't exactly delightful. The sex scenes between Reeves and Diaz (again, not exactly my two favorite performers) were pretty awful, there were parts of the ending that I didn't like, and I wish the film had omitted some of the more annoying romantic elements in general, but I really enjoyed it overall. It's certainly something I'd recommend, though it's a little odd and very dark (pretty much all of the characters are simultaneously likable and disgusting), so it may not be for everyone
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    See it because of Keanu Reeves and Cameron Diaz.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gmckeeverbeast94
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw Feeling MInnesota on a Saturday morning. And if it didn't have Keanu Reeves and Cameron Diaz, I wouldn't have watched the whole thing. Reeves plays Jjaks, a man who lives his life on the road, because his mother threw him out when he was only 8. Jjaks has an older brother, Sam who works at a nightclub. The owner of the nightclub found that someone stole his money. He figure that it was Freddie, an ordinary woman played by Cameron Diaz. The nightclub owner is making Freddie pay off the money by marrying Sam. At the wedding, Freddie meets Jjaks and falls in love with him. They run off together and things turn into a disaster. If you enjoy movies with 2 men fighting over the same woman, then I would recommend Feeling Minnesota to you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    J.J. Jameson Quote ... Crap, Crap, ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    smccahon
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    J.J. Jameson (from Spiderman 2) Quote ... Crap, Crap, ... Mega-Crap It pretends to be an homage (un/intentional) to the Coen Brothers ... done poorly. There is no real mystery to the plot. Diaz's performance is totally uninspired. The quirky characters don't really work. There are a lot of "duh" moments. I love black comedy, but this film isn't funny. In my view, it wasn't worth the electricity. There are many films in this genre which are much more entertaining. I hope you find this review helpful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie was a complete waste of my time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I want the 99 minutes of my life back that was wasted on this pathetic excuse for a movie. The acting was horrific! I used to be a fan of Cameron Diaz and Vincent D'Onofrio. I will never look at them the same again. Keanu Reeves and Dan Aykroyd were not a surprise. Everyone knows they never could act. Thankfully, only Dan attempted an accent. His accent was a disaster as expected. I think he was either confused about the location of the film or had never actually spoken to anyone from Minnesota. I hope this review helps anyone who is undecided about what to do with their precious time. The only reason I was able to sit through the whole movie was because I was stuck somewhere without anything better to watch or read.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    90s twisting & turning, very funny low-life crime film about users on the take
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bottom line, this is a very funny, silly, slapstick, goofy film - but very adult, with twists and turns as the largely amoral characters grapple and use each other to get what they want. None of the characters are particularly likable, Jjaks (Reeves) seems the most put upon but he's in and out of prison and Freddie (Diaz) is a good time girl who messed with the wrong people and is just doing what she has to do to get by. It's also a sort of romantic love story although despite Reeves acting superbly and being rather cute, the chemistry between him and Diaz is lacking something. Diaz, I don't feel is acting her best and often is a somewhat monotone, as if reading lines, but they are enjoyable to watch and whilst I think she's the weakest performance she has the most difficult and emotionally exposing role and in that case I think she does well. It's the scenes with Reeves and D'Onofrio that are truly engaging in an anti-chemistry kind of way. They rub each other up the wrong way - sibling rivalry - Jjaks having had the bad end of every deal in their childhood - and in doing so provide some scarily good aggression and slapstick comedy timing genius ensues. It's a film where you have to watch closely, for some grand scale and also minutiae performances, and it can be watched over and over again for laughs and the drama. Reeves is animated and light - like Diaz, I think he suits comedy and there are plenty of funny scenes (albeit black comedy as often as not) to enjoy. Diaz is both charming and annoying - her character is understandable and relatable (possibly due to her performance making it so) but also largely without scruples and single mindedness: her dream of working in Vegas - and I like that whilst it ends satisfactorily, it's not particularly Hollywood in it's ending and it's predictable but pleasantly so. Dan Aykroyd is the hapless, stupid, love-sick, cop on the take with a very overblown Minnesota accent - or is it Canadian, or Irish? He brings more laughs, and Courtney Love in a small but nice role adds small town glamour and a stable foil for some of D'Onofrio's eccentric behaviours. Adults only black comedy, lots of bad language, scenes of a sexual nature (though not gratuitous) and a lot of violence and aggression. The subject matter, and plot, make for a very dramatic film but it's played for laughs which makes it an enjoyable romp with all the actors giving it 100%. Amazingly this film flew under the radar of 90s cinema-going and is an unexpectedly good film that I've seen a number of times and it doesn't get old. Not a chick-flick although it may appear as such, and plenty for boys to enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dumb and selfish characters doing dumb and selfish stuff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw this movie when it came out I thought it was a good movie. But watching it now, not as much but just decent at best. But than again I thought Cameron Diaz was overly hot back than. This movie is basically about two brothers quarreling with one another and fighting each other in a very malicious manner. One more malicious than the other and they are both in love with a superficial and selfish girl. And none of the characters are likable and run on greed and their own selfish ambitions while constantly trying to use each other. But than again that somewhat applies to the real world. Watching this movie was like watching "Dumb & Dumber" except the characters aren't as dumb nor as funny. It has this certain black humor going for it and it works sometimes and has a slight bit of the Coen brothers vibe going for it. But the humor isn't all that well grafted and is nowhere near as good as the Coen brothers films. Keanu Reeves who plays the slight good brother between the two brothers is right for this role and although his acting needed some work. He did a good job of playing this dumb character that is oblivious to his surroundings. His character Jjaks is basically a dumb robber that gets into a hole when he bangs his brothers wife who got forced into the marriage by thugs and so on. This movie is basically about dumb selfish people doing dumb and selfish stuff. It's still a entertaining movie to a degree but nothing special. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Dog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This completely failed attempt at a Black Comedy is a painful experience to watch. It is an example of bad direction and a bad script and the on screen performers are left with nowhere to go. That is the feeling that the film elicits. It is all over the place with predictable "surprises" and floundering characters on a road to ruin. It is not for one minute funny, or exciting, or dark. It is nothing dressed up as something with a hip delivery and dull designations. The tension between the brothers is nothing more than rough housing and the film's tone changes so much it is dizzying. This mess is a movie that does not entertain or even pass as anything but an unrelenting bore. In fact it is cinema of the cringe. An ugly affair with unpleasant characters and events. The most interesting part of humanity in this movie is the Dog. Ironically that's what this is, a dog. They must have seen it coming. But it's doubtful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Feeling is to Miss Minnesota *1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very poor film dealing with quite a dysfunctional family to put it mildly. This must have been one of Cameron Diaz's first films and she set the standard for her career: A real cute young lady with absolutely no acting talent whatsoever. In this sub-standard film, two brothers vie for attention and one, Vincent D'Onofrio actually marries her. Tuesday Weld, as the mother of the two losers, is totally unrecognizable and should be considered fortunate to drop dead early in the film. Anything to get away from this. Even the end-plot twist with officer Dan Akroyd is boring at best.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Woeful film has a provocative look and feel...but nothing of interest in the foreground
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Baigelman wrote and directed this uncertain comedy-drama concerning estranged brothers (Keanu Reeves and Vincent D'Onofrio) battling over embezzled cash as well as the affections of a pretty blonde (Cameron Diaz). The gritty ambiance inherent in Walt Lloyd's incredibly vivid cinematography is the most memorable aspect of the picture; capturing a blue-collar realism with such clarity, however, tends to emphasize the unreality of these dunderhead characters, and the movie's look and its story fail to cohere. Baigelman does get things off to a promising start, and he has an attentive eye for what to capture, but these petty people merit little interest. Danny DeVito was one of the many producers (all, presumably, with their own idea of how to film Baigelman's unremarkable script). *1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good loser movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hang_All_Drunkdrivers
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a way it's like Laurel and Hardy in that the two main characters are a couple of idiots always fighting. Keanu Reeves and Vince D'Onofrio play two feuding brothers who want the same women. The women, played very sexily by Cameron Diaz, likes Reeves but is married to D'Onofrio and has eyes on his money. Some people get murdered but the show is really more of a comedy. The three leads do a great job as do the supporting actors like Dan Aykroyd and the always watchable Delroy Lindo. You think of Reeves as being a handsome guy but not here. With his awful hair style and drunk attitude, he's really got loser wrote all over him. Midway in the movie his character does something really clever when he wakes up and finds a dead body in his room and then gets a call saying the police are coming up to talk to him. But he finds a way to fool them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very enjoyable if imperfect film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TilDuDor
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Feeling Minnesota is an entertaining movie, and though it may require some rewatching to be sure, it's probably now one of my favorites. From the beginning it reminded me quite a bit of a certain Coen brothers film with a similar title, only it is much more violent and a little darker. For those of you who haven't seen it, and to sum it up without spoilers, it's basically a movie about two brothers- Keanu Reeves, the petty crook who has a habit of holding up convenience stores (again, remind you of anything?), and D'Onofrio, his jerky brother. If I got everything right, D'Onofrio does accounting for a dope dealer/club owner who gives him this girl (Diaz, not exactly stellar in this role) as a wife as a reward for him for finding money she stole and as a punishment for her (again, he's a jerk). Reeves pretty much steals her away from D'Onofrio, and D'Onofrio isn't havin' none of that. The best thing about this movie is the weird sense of humor- it's rather subtle sometimes, and then out of nowhere there will be goofy physical comedy (the only thing Reeves excelled at in this, oddly enough) and weird situational humor. The tone is fairly dark through most of it, but there are plenty of hilarious scenes (however odd they are). This might be my favorite D'Onofrio movie (I'm a big fan of the man), especially for how over-the-top he was in it and for all of the goofy outfits he wore. There are a bunch of scenes where he and Reeves are stumbling around or beating each other up and the nearly slapstick physical comedy was great. D'Onofrio and Aykroyd especially are great as the whiny, violent brother with a bizarre taste in clothes and the crooked cop with the hots for Diaz. Reeves wasn't the best choice, though he's passable (especially in scenes involving sibling rivalry), but the rest of the cast wasn't exactly delightful. The sex scenes between Reeves and Diaz (again, not exactly my two favorite performers) were pretty awful, there were parts of the ending that I didn't like, and I wish the film had omitted some of the more annoying romantic elements in general, but I really enjoyed it overall. It's certainly something I'd recommend, though it's a little odd and very dark (pretty much all of the characters are simultaneously likable and disgusting), so it may not be for everyone
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    See it because of Keanu Reeves and Cameron Diaz.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gmckeeverbeast94
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw Feeling MInnesota on a Saturday morning. And if it didn't have Keanu Reeves and Cameron Diaz, I wouldn't have watched the whole thing. Reeves plays Jjaks, a man who lives his life on the road, because his mother threw him out when he was only 8. Jjaks has an older brother, Sam who works at a nightclub. The owner of the nightclub found that someone stole his money. He figure that it was Freddie, an ordinary woman played by Cameron Diaz. The nightclub owner is making Freddie pay off the money by marrying Sam. At the wedding, Freddie meets Jjaks and falls in love with him. They run off together and things turn into a disaster. If you enjoy movies with 2 men fighting over the same woman, then I would recommend Feeling Minnesota to you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    J.J. Jameson Quote ... Crap, Crap, ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    smccahon
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    J.J. Jameson (from Spiderman 2) Quote ... Crap, Crap, ... Mega-Crap It pretends to be an homage (un/intentional) to the Coen Brothers ... done poorly. There is no real mystery to the plot. Diaz's performance is totally uninspired. The quirky characters don't really work. There are a lot of "duh" moments. I love black comedy, but this film isn't funny. In my view, it wasn't worth the electricity. There are many films in this genre which are much more entertaining. I hope you find this review helpful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie was a complete waste of my time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I want the 99 minutes of my life back that was wasted on this pathetic excuse for a movie. The acting was horrific! I used to be a fan of Cameron Diaz and Vincent D'Onofrio. I will never look at them the same again. Keanu Reeves and Dan Aykroyd were not a surprise. Everyone knows they never could act. Thankfully, only Dan attempted an accent. His accent was a disaster as expected. I think he was either confused about the location of the film or had never actually spoken to anyone from Minnesota. I hope this review helps anyone who is undecided about what to do with their precious time. The only reason I was able to sit through the whole movie was because I was stuck somewhere without anything better to watch or read.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    90s twisting & turning, very funny low-life crime film about users on the take
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bottom line, this is a very funny, silly, slapstick, goofy film - but very adult, with twists and turns as the largely amoral characters grapple and use each other to get what they want. None of the characters are particularly likable, Jjaks (Reeves) seems the most put upon but he's in and out of prison and Freddie (Diaz) is a good time girl who messed with the wrong people and is just doing what she has to do to get by. It's also a sort of romantic love story although despite Reeves acting superbly and being rather cute, the chemistry between him and Diaz is lacking something. Diaz, I don't feel is acting her best and often is a somewhat monotone, as if reading lines, but they are enjoyable to watch and whilst I think she's the weakest performance she has the most difficult and emotionally exposing role and in that case I think she does well. It's the scenes with Reeves and D'Onofrio that are truly engaging in an anti-chemistry kind of way. They rub each other up the wrong way - sibling rivalry - Jjaks having had the bad end of every deal in their childhood - and in doing so provide some scarily good aggression and slapstick comedy timing genius ensues. It's a film where you have to watch closely, for some grand scale and also minutiae performances, and it can be watched over and over again for laughs and the drama. Reeves is animated and light - like Diaz, I think he suits comedy and there are plenty of funny scenes (albeit black comedy as often as not) to enjoy. Diaz is both charming and annoying - her character is understandable and relatable (possibly due to her performance making it so) but also largely without scruples and single mindedness: her dream of working in Vegas - and I like that whilst it ends satisfactorily, it's not particularly Hollywood in it's ending and it's predictable but pleasantly so. Dan Aykroyd is the hapless, stupid, love-sick, cop on the take with a very overblown Minnesota accent - or is it Canadian, or Irish? He brings more laughs, and Courtney Love in a small but nice role adds small town glamour and a stable foil for some of D'Onofrio's eccentric behaviours. Adults only black comedy, lots of bad language, scenes of a sexual nature (though not gratuitous) and a lot of violence and aggression. The subject matter, and plot, make for a very dramatic film but it's played for laughs which makes it an enjoyable romp with all the actors giving it 100%. Amazingly this film flew under the radar of 90s cinema-going and is an unexpectedly good film that I've seen a number of times and it doesn't get old. Not a chick-flick although it may appear as such, and plenty for boys to enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dumb and selfish characters doing dumb and selfish stuff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw this movie when it came out I thought it was a good movie. But watching it now, not as much but just decent at best. But than again I thought Cameron Diaz was overly hot back than. This movie is basically about two brothers quarreling with one another and fighting each other in a very malicious manner. One more malicious than the other and they are both in love with a superficial and selfish girl. And none of the characters are likable and run on greed and their own selfish ambitions while constantly trying to use each other. But than again that somewhat applies to the real world. Watching this movie was like watching "Dumb & Dumber" except the characters aren't as dumb nor as funny. It has this certain black humor going for it and it works sometimes and has a slight bit of the Coen brothers vibe going for it. But the humor isn't all that well grafted and is nowhere near as good as the Coen brothers films. Keanu Reeves who plays the slight good brother between the two brothers is right for this role and although his acting needed some work. He did a good job of playing this dumb character that is oblivious to his surroundings. His character Jjaks is basically a dumb robber that gets into a hole when he bangs his brothers wife who got forced into the marriage by thugs and so on. This movie is basically about dumb selfish people doing dumb and selfish stuff. It's still a entertaining movie to a degree but nothing special. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Dog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This completely failed attempt at a Black Comedy is a painful experience to watch. It is an example of bad direction and a bad script and the on screen performers are left with nowhere to go. That is the feeling that the film elicits. It is all over the place with predictable "surprises" and floundering characters on a road to ruin. It is not for one minute funny, or exciting, or dark. It is nothing dressed up as something with a hip delivery and dull designations. The tension between the brothers is nothing more than rough housing and the film's tone changes so much it is dizzying. This mess is a movie that does not entertain or even pass as anything but an unrelenting bore. In fact it is cinema of the cringe. An ugly affair with unpleasant characters and events. The most interesting part of humanity in this movie is the Dog. Ironically that's what this is, a dog. They must have seen it coming. But it's doubtful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Feeling is to Miss Minnesota *1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very poor film dealing with quite a dysfunctional family to put it mildly. This must have been one of Cameron Diaz's first films and she set the standard for her career: A real cute young lady with absolutely no acting talent whatsoever. In this sub-standard film, two brothers vie for attention and one, Vincent D'Onofrio actually marries her. Tuesday Weld, as the mother of the two losers, is totally unrecognizable and should be considered fortunate to drop dead early in the film. Anything to get away from this. Even the end-plot twist with officer Dan Akroyd is boring at best.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Woeful film has a provocative look and feel...but nothing of interest in the foreground
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Baigelman wrote and directed this uncertain comedy-drama concerning estranged brothers (Keanu Reeves and Vincent D'Onofrio) battling over embezzled cash as well as the affections of a pretty blonde (Cameron Diaz). The gritty ambiance inherent in Walt Lloyd's incredibly vivid cinematography is the most memorable aspect of the picture; capturing a blue-collar realism with such clarity, however, tends to emphasize the unreality of these dunderhead characters, and the movie's look and its story fail to cohere. Baigelman does get things off to a promising start, and he has an attentive eye for what to capture, but these petty people merit little interest. Danny DeVito was one of the many producers (all, presumably, with their own idea of how to film Baigelman's unremarkable script). *1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good loser movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hang_All_Drunkdrivers
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a way it's like Laurel and Hardy in that the two main characters are a couple of idiots always fighting. Keanu Reeves and Vince D'Onofrio play two feuding brothers who want the same women. The women, played very sexily by Cameron Diaz, likes Reeves but is married to D'Onofrio and has eyes on his money. Some people get murdered but the show is really more of a comedy. The three leads do a great job as do the supporting actors like Dan Aykroyd and the always watchable Delroy Lindo. You think of Reeves as being a handsome guy but not here. With his awful hair style and drunk attitude, he's really got loser wrote all over him. Midway in the movie his character does something really clever when he wakes up and finds a dead body in his room and then gets a call saying the police are coming up to talk to him. But he finds a way to fool them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very enjoyable if imperfect film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TilDuDor
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Feeling Minnesota is an entertaining movie, and though it may require some rewatching to be sure, it's probably now one of my favorites. From the beginning it reminded me quite a bit of a certain Coen brothers film with a similar title, only it is much more violent and a little darker. For those of you who haven't seen it, and to sum it up without spoilers, it's basically a movie about two brothers- Keanu Reeves, the petty crook who has a habit of holding up convenience stores (again, remind you of anything?), and D'Onofrio, his jerky brother. If I got everything right, D'Onofrio does accounting for a dope dealer/club owner who gives him this girl (Diaz, not exactly stellar in this role) as a wife as a reward for him for finding money she stole and as a punishment for her (again, he's a jerk). Reeves pretty much steals her away from D'Onofrio, and D'Onofrio isn't havin' none of that. The best thing about this movie is the weird sense of humor- it's rather subtle sometimes, and then out of nowhere there will be goofy physical comedy (the only thing Reeves excelled at in this, oddly enough) and weird situational humor. The tone is fairly dark through most of it, but there are plenty of hilarious scenes (however odd they are). This might be my favorite D'Onofrio movie (I'm a big fan of the man), especially for how over-the-top he was in it and for all of the goofy outfits he wore. There are a bunch of scenes where he and Reeves are stumbling around or beating each other up and the nearly slapstick physical comedy was great. D'Onofrio and Aykroyd especially are great as the whiny, violent brother with a bizarre taste in clothes and the crooked cop with the hots for Diaz. Reeves wasn't the best choice, though he's passable (especially in scenes involving sibling rivalry), but the rest of the cast wasn't exactly delightful. The sex scenes between Reeves and Diaz (again, not exactly my two favorite performers) were pretty awful, there were parts of the ending that I didn't like, and I wish the film had omitted some of the more annoying romantic elements in general, but I really enjoyed it overall. It's certainly something I'd recommend, though it's a little odd and very dark (pretty much all of the characters are simultaneously likable and disgusting), so it may not be for everyone
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    See it because of Keanu Reeves and Cameron Diaz.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gmckeeverbeast94
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw Feeling MInnesota on a Saturday morning. And if it didn't have Keanu Reeves and Cameron Diaz, I wouldn't have watched the whole thing. Reeves plays Jjaks, a man who lives his life on the road, because his mother threw him out when he was only 8. Jjaks has an older brother, Sam who works at a nightclub. The owner of the nightclub found that someone stole his money. He figure that it was Freddie, an ordinary woman played by Cameron Diaz. The nightclub owner is making Freddie pay off the money by marrying Sam. At the wedding, Freddie meets Jjaks and falls in love with him. They run off together and things turn into a disaster. If you enjoy movies with 2 men fighting over the same woman, then I would recommend Feeling Minnesota to you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    J.J. Jameson Quote ... Crap, Crap, ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    smccahon
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    J.J. Jameson (from Spiderman 2) Quote ... Crap, Crap, ... Mega-Crap It pretends to be an homage (un/intentional) to the Coen Brothers ... done poorly. There is no real mystery to the plot. Diaz's performance is totally uninspired. The quirky characters don't really work. There are a lot of "duh" moments. I love black comedy, but this film isn't funny. In my view, it wasn't worth the electricity. There are many films in this genre which are much more entertaining. I hope you find this review helpful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie was a complete waste of my time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I want the 99 minutes of my life back that was wasted on this pathetic excuse for a movie. The acting was horrific! I used to be a fan of Cameron Diaz and Vincent D'Onofrio. I will never look at them the same again. Keanu Reeves and Dan Aykroyd were not a surprise. Everyone knows they never could act. Thankfully, only Dan attempted an accent. His accent was a disaster as expected. I think he was either confused about the location of the film or had never actually spoken to anyone from Minnesota. I hope this review helps anyone who is undecided about what to do with their precious time. The only reason I was able to sit through the whole movie was because I was stuck somewhere without anything better to watch or read.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
