<filme>
 <id>
  1136
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116410
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Ghosts of Mississippi
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The widow of murdered civil rights leader Medger Evers and a district attorney struggle to finally bring the murderer to justice.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Ghosts of Mississippi is a drama covering the final trial of Byron De La Beckwith (Woods), the assassin of the 1960s civil rights leader Medgar Evers. It begins with the murder and the events surrounding the two initial trials which both ended in hung juries. The movie then covers District Attorney, Bobby De Laughter's (Baldwin) transformation and alliance with Myrlie Evers (Goldberg), the widow of Medgar Evers, as he becomes more involved with bringing Beckwith to trial for the third time 30 years later. Some of the characters are played by the actual participants in this story.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   trial
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   widow
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   civil rights
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   murder
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   1960s
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Rob Reiner
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Lewis Colick
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Alec Baldwin
  </ator>
  <ator>
   James Woods
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Whoopi Goldberg
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent subject gets bogged down
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thunderclancat
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ghosts of Mississippi tells the story of the assassination of civil rights leader Medgar Evers by Klansman Byron de la Beckwith, and the much-delayed trial of the assassin. Alec Baldwin plays the Prosecutor determined to bring De la Beckwith to justice, and does a serviceable job as does Whoopi Goldberg as Evers' widow. James Woods gives an at-times over-the-top performance as the killer. Unfortunately the story gets bogged down in stories about the Prosecutor's home life, and the decision to bring in Southern Poverty Law Center leader Morris Dees, who completely hams up his time in the film. This is a film that fails it's subject. By trying to make the subject matter less complex and less scary the filmmakers ruined what could have been a very powerful and moving film. It does have a good soundtrack, though, so there's that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting courtroom drama! 7,7!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know anything about the exact real event on which "Ghosts of Mississippi" is based on, but I found them very interesting, and the movie, too. I am quite interested in Law (I almost began the Law degree at my town college and am still a little frustrated not to have done it), so I like many courtroom movies like "The Lincoln lawyer", "A time to kill", "A few good men", "The firm", "Murder in the first"... Those not interested in this subgenre will not probably enjoy the one I am reviewing... "Ghosts of Mississippi" may sound like a horror movie, that is why I think it is not the most apropiated tittle. The story is mainly about a district attorney from Mississippi who allies with the widow of a black civil rights leader who was murdered about thirty years ago while his murderer was living free. The end will be predictable if we know the real case well but even in this case, it is worth to discover this movie with its good acting, cast, scenography and so on. This is not the movie in the subgenre, but really, it is better than some other I have seen. The director is Rob Reiner, who directed very good movies like "A few good men", "Misery" and "The bucket list" as well as other worse like "The magic of Belle Isle" and "When Harry met Sally". In this case, he did a very good job taking into account the script is very tied to the reality. The pace is excellent for a movie of this kind and it has many moving moments and dialogues. I think the duration of the film is the proper one, too. The cast is starred by Alec Baldwin with his powerful voice and believable interpretation of the district attorney convinced of making justice. Although not my favorite, he is noticeable actor with an incredible career, but I think he should work in more varied movies. Anyway, his work in this and others is very intense. Baldwin, in concret, and the performances in general represent a strong point in the movie James Woods (I liked him in "The specialist") is not as present in the movie, but his performance is one of the best I have seen him do. He plays the part of the murderer when he was younger and old: a masterful performance. Whoopi Goldberg plays a very powerful and dramatic and relevant role as the widow. The rest of the cast is OK: Willian H. Macy, Craig T. Nelson... The scenography is simple but realistic and aproppiate as it has to be. In conclusion, the movie is good in every aspect without reaching the top levels of courtroom movies like "A time to kill" and some others, but will really satisfy those interested in this subgenre and realistic reality-based dramas, in general. 7,7.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Monsters in Mississippi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rob Reiner's 'Ghosts of Mississipi' is based on a relatively less known (today) reopening of Medger Evers racially motivated murder case. Starting with the flaws of the film, I can see why many would comment that this is another 'white man rescues the oppressed black people flick'. To balance this out, the director could have portrayed more of Evers's life and the significance of what he did and also developed the story of his wife who's an integral part, show more of her (and the family's) struggle. Here the focus is almost entirely on Baldwin's DeLaughter and the obstacles he faces during the trial. The film also appears to be a tad glossy. What does work, even though the story is predictable, is the level of suspense and tension which is very well maintained. You know what'll happen in the end but you still root for Delaughter to succeed every step. Alec Baldwin does a brilliant job as the lawyer who's taken by the injustice and brutality of the crime and seeks to bring justice to the family and community. Whoopi Goldberg wonderfully downplays her part. 'Wish there was more of her. Her character doesn't seem to have 'aged' in 27 years (except for the darker circles round her eyes). James Wood is great as the hateful De la Beckwith. 'Ghosts of Mississipi' could have been more if only more of the late Medgar and his wife's life was included but it certainly is a watchable film that reminds one of a forgotten important event in America.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Movie Review! - http://tss5078.blogspot.com
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tss5078
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my favorite historical movies ever made. What I really love about this film is just how accurate it is. The film is based on a book written by the prosecutor, Bobby DeLaughter, and before the film was made, all the actually people involved were interviewed and allowed to give their input into how their characters were developed. The story takes place in 1990 and is about the third re-trial of the man accused of killing civil right leader Medger Evers in the 1960's. Alec Baldwin portrays the prosecutor, and while I am by no means a fan of his, he was truly great in this film. I wish he'd stick to roles like this instead of trying to be funny, because he's not funny. Whoopi Goldberg, remains one of the most underrated actresses in Hollywood and was just amazing here. This is a top notch, historically accurate drama that every history buff needs to see. I honestly can't recommend it enough!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ClintnBarbWard1
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Ghosts of Mississippi Alec Baldwin plays bobby delaughter who try to bring MEdger Evers killer Bryon DE la Beck-with played by James woods. Whoopi Goldberg is in the film too as medgers widow. rob directs. i think James woods a tremendous performance as Bryon DE labeckwith Alec Baldwin did a good job better then his usual work and whoopi Goldberg did a decent job even though there is one thing in the whole movie that she does that drives me nuts it is when she first talks to Alec Baldwin over the phone and sacarsa;y talks to him and then simels. William h Macy is my second favorite character in the whole movie when he says i cant get a women to love me now when I'm alive. this movie is really entertaining especially the performances by James woods and William h Macy. its a movie i recommend to everybody
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plodding history lesson ...................
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This could have been a pretty good ninety minute film. Unfortunately it is 130 minutes and the extra 40 minutes is almost fatal. There is an important story being told, that is somewhat dulled by way too much extraneous material, along with some distracting family distress, and child coddling. Less would have been best in the case of "Ghosts of Mississippi. The acting by Alec Baldwin, Whoppi Goldberg, and especially James Woods is totally acceptable, but the movie drags on way too long. I realize being based on fact, the writers were somewhat restricted, but I would have preferred a leaner story, without the distracting extras involving wives and children. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Average Fare...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rob Reiner's 'Ghosts Of Mississippi' is a golden opportunity, gone wrong. Though based on a disturbing yet moving story, the on-screen interpretation doesn't hold you completely. 'Ghosts Of Mississippi' is based on the true story of the 1994 trial of Byron De La Beckwith, a white supremacist accused of the 1963 assassination of civil rights activist Medgar Evers. Rob Reiner knows his job. He is a very talented storyteller, and his direction even in here is good. But, the writing has many loopholes. As mentioned, the true-story, doesn't get it's due. The writing in the first hour doesn't work and bores. Sure, the climax is dramatic & effective, but the damage is already done by then. John Seale's Cinematography is alright. Peroformance-Wise: Alec Baldwin as Bobby DeLaughter does fairly well. James Woods is very impressive as the conniving Byron De La Beckwith, while Whoopi Goldberg as Myrlie Evers is fair. Virginia Madsen is wasted. William H. Macy and Craig T. Nelson are okay. Others lend able support. On the whole, A golden opportunity gone wrong. At best, An Average Fare!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engrossing true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lamadrelrs
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This excellent film tells the true story of a white southern prosecutor who has the courage to try to set right a gross miscarriage of justice that took place in the segregated South at the beginning of the Civil Rights movement 30 years earlier. Alec Balwin as prosecutor Bobby DeLaughter and James Woods as Brian De la Beckwith, the accused, give outstanding performances. Whoopi Goldberg shows her range as an actress portraying Myrlie Evers, widow of slain civil rights leader Medgar Evers whose murder was never solved or prosecuted. Goldberg lets the viewer know that Mrs. Evers is a woman of great dignity, strength and faith. I was a young woman during the actual events that took place in Mississippi so long ago. At the time, I must not have paid much attention because none of this story was really familiar to me. I enjoyed it so much that I bought the DVD and watch it about three times a year. I have recommended the film to social studies teachers. The story serves a springboard for teaching opportunities. The artistic quality of the film never leaves the viewer feeling bored. Really good film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Too Subtle
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amwcsu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The assassination of Medgar Evers was one of the most shocking incidents during the Civil Rights movement. Being that, it should've been done with more attention to detail. If you are going to do a period piece of Evers then you going to have to show what this man did and have done to modern society in order for the audience to know who Medgar Evers really was. Hence, Ghosts of Mississippi should have focused more on the Evers and how he stirred up the ire of the KKK for the first half-hour/45 minutes of the movie then shown the murder. Makes sense, doesn't it? The set design was magnificent and authentic. Nothing was wrong with it. My only gripes are the characters. For example they're wonderfully acted, but not really convincing with the exception of James Woods disturbingly evil, but somewhat funny "old Kook" in boonies rendition of infamous assassin Byron De La Beckwith and Alec Baldwin as the driven and selfless District Attorney Bobby DeLaughter. The characters could have been a little bolder like in "The Long Walk Home". You want people to hate this guy,Beckwith and you want see this film and feel like someone just punched you in the stomach. For example, as the DeLaughter family was being harassed; We could've seen the rawness of racist opposition not just a shattered windshield and name-calling and a sanitized version of a bomb threat at the family home! What bothers me, is that movies that involve racism and the South should give you a feeling of resentment, it shouldn't have a "Disney Channel" subtle tinge to it. This is the "Achille's Heel" that makes Ghosts of Mississippi fall short of a convincing murder mystery. I'm not saying that I hate this film. I actually liked it, I still like it. But it could be bolder. A movie about the Civil Rights era in the South should convince you, shock you, anger you, and show various perspectives about the subject. That, my friends is what makes a docudrama stand out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    awesome film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dr. Michael Hollywood
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Strong performances from Alec Baldwin, James Woods, Whoopi Goldberg, Craig T. Nelson, Bill Smitrovich and William H. Macy makes "Ghosts Of Mississippi" one of the best movies I have seen. "Ghosts Of Mississippi" deserved an Oscar in every single category that one can be given in because it was that good. I never knew the story of Medgar Evers before I saw this film; but, I learned a lot through watching the film. I hope everyone has the same experience and opportunity I had when I saw this movie because it is one history lesson that should be seen rather than read in history books or newspaper archives. I was truly honored to watch this film. There are several reasons this film is a success; one of them are the performances. "Ghosts Of Mississippi" is each actors best film of their career bar none. Alec Baldwin brings intensity, aggressiveness and never say die attitude to his role as Bobby DeLaughter. Whoopi Goldberg stars as Myrlie Evers, widow of Medgar Evers, who with relentless pursuit of justice re-opens this murder case. Finally, James Woods stars as Byron De La Beckwith, the defendant, who with great conviction and sincerity brings the essence of the real person to the surface. As great as Baldwin and Woods are in this they do not hold a candle to Goldberg who gives not only the best performance in the film, year but I dare say the best performance of the decade of the 90's. Known for her comedic roles in the "Sister Act" series, Goldberg turns dramatic for "Ghosts Of Mississippi." This is a very impressive turn and most likely her best dramatic role since "The Color Purple." The intense and aggressive style Golberg brought to her role as the widowed Mrs. Evers was beautiful to watch. The second reason why this film remains on my short list of best films are the messages that brought up. For example, equality for all and the fact that any discrimination will not be tolerated under any circumstances. Another message I got from this film was under no circumstances should anybody underestimate the power of tenacity because it will make dreams come true every time. This film was thought-provoking, brilliant, inspiring and compelling. In addition, "Ghosts Of Mississippi" will move you to tears, put a smile on your face and anger you because these are the emotions I felt watching this movie. Combined with the excellent ensemble performances, brilliant script and messages this film had "Ghosts Of Mississippi" is one film you can't miss. There will most certainly be other inspirational films that come along, but "Ghosts Of The Mississippi" still remains at the top of my list as one of the most inspiring films I've seen. Two thumbs way up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent subject gets bogged down
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thunderclancat
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ghosts of Mississippi tells the story of the assassination of civil rights leader Medgar Evers by Klansman Byron de la Beckwith, and the much-delayed trial of the assassin. Alec Baldwin plays the Prosecutor determined to bring De la Beckwith to justice, and does a serviceable job as does Whoopi Goldberg as Evers' widow. James Woods gives an at-times over-the-top performance as the killer. Unfortunately the story gets bogged down in stories about the Prosecutor's home life, and the decision to bring in Southern Poverty Law Center leader Morris Dees, who completely hams up his time in the film. This is a film that fails it's subject. By trying to make the subject matter less complex and less scary the filmmakers ruined what could have been a very powerful and moving film. It does have a good soundtrack, though, so there's that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting courtroom drama! 7,7!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know anything about the exact real event on which "Ghosts of Mississippi" is based on, but I found them very interesting, and the movie, too. I am quite interested in Law (I almost began the Law degree at my town college and am still a little frustrated not to have done it), so I like many courtroom movies like "The Lincoln lawyer", "A time to kill", "A few good men", "The firm", "Murder in the first"... Those not interested in this subgenre will not probably enjoy the one I am reviewing... "Ghosts of Mississippi" may sound like a horror movie, that is why I think it is not the most apropiated tittle. The story is mainly about a district attorney from Mississippi who allies with the widow of a black civil rights leader who was murdered about thirty years ago while his murderer was living free. The end will be predictable if we know the real case well but even in this case, it is worth to discover this movie with its good acting, cast, scenography and so on. This is not the movie in the subgenre, but really, it is better than some other I have seen. The director is Rob Reiner, who directed very good movies like "A few good men", "Misery" and "The bucket list" as well as other worse like "The magic of Belle Isle" and "When Harry met Sally". In this case, he did a very good job taking into account the script is very tied to the reality. The pace is excellent for a movie of this kind and it has many moving moments and dialogues. I think the duration of the film is the proper one, too. The cast is starred by Alec Baldwin with his powerful voice and believable interpretation of the district attorney convinced of making justice. Although not my favorite, he is noticeable actor with an incredible career, but I think he should work in more varied movies. Anyway, his work in this and others is very intense. Baldwin, in concret, and the performances in general represent a strong point in the movie James Woods (I liked him in "The specialist") is not as present in the movie, but his performance is one of the best I have seen him do. He plays the part of the murderer when he was younger and old: a masterful performance. Whoopi Goldberg plays a very powerful and dramatic and relevant role as the widow. The rest of the cast is OK: Willian H. Macy, Craig T. Nelson... The scenography is simple but realistic and aproppiate as it has to be. In conclusion, the movie is good in every aspect without reaching the top levels of courtroom movies like "A time to kill" and some others, but will really satisfy those interested in this subgenre and realistic reality-based dramas, in general. 7,7.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Monsters in Mississippi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rob Reiner's 'Ghosts of Mississipi' is based on a relatively less known (today) reopening of Medger Evers racially motivated murder case. Starting with the flaws of the film, I can see why many would comment that this is another 'white man rescues the oppressed black people flick'. To balance this out, the director could have portrayed more of Evers's life and the significance of what he did and also developed the story of his wife who's an integral part, show more of her (and the family's) struggle. Here the focus is almost entirely on Baldwin's DeLaughter and the obstacles he faces during the trial. The film also appears to be a tad glossy. What does work, even though the story is predictable, is the level of suspense and tension which is very well maintained. You know what'll happen in the end but you still root for Delaughter to succeed every step. Alec Baldwin does a brilliant job as the lawyer who's taken by the injustice and brutality of the crime and seeks to bring justice to the family and community. Whoopi Goldberg wonderfully downplays her part. 'Wish there was more of her. Her character doesn't seem to have 'aged' in 27 years (except for the darker circles round her eyes). James Wood is great as the hateful De la Beckwith. 'Ghosts of Mississipi' could have been more if only more of the late Medgar and his wife's life was included but it certainly is a watchable film that reminds one of a forgotten important event in America.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Movie Review! - http://tss5078.blogspot.com
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tss5078
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my favorite historical movies ever made. What I really love about this film is just how accurate it is. The film is based on a book written by the prosecutor, Bobby DeLaughter, and before the film was made, all the actually people involved were interviewed and allowed to give their input into how their characters were developed. The story takes place in 1990 and is about the third re-trial of the man accused of killing civil right leader Medger Evers in the 1960's. Alec Baldwin portrays the prosecutor, and while I am by no means a fan of his, he was truly great in this film. I wish he'd stick to roles like this instead of trying to be funny, because he's not funny. Whoopi Goldberg, remains one of the most underrated actresses in Hollywood and was just amazing here. This is a top notch, historically accurate drama that every history buff needs to see. I honestly can't recommend it enough!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ClintnBarbWard1
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Ghosts of Mississippi Alec Baldwin plays bobby delaughter who try to bring MEdger Evers killer Bryon DE la Beck-with played by James woods. Whoopi Goldberg is in the film too as medgers widow. rob directs. i think James woods a tremendous performance as Bryon DE labeckwith Alec Baldwin did a good job better then his usual work and whoopi Goldberg did a decent job even though there is one thing in the whole movie that she does that drives me nuts it is when she first talks to Alec Baldwin over the phone and sacarsa;y talks to him and then simels. William h Macy is my second favorite character in the whole movie when he says i cant get a women to love me now when I'm alive. this movie is really entertaining especially the performances by James woods and William h Macy. its a movie i recommend to everybody
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plodding history lesson ...................
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This could have been a pretty good ninety minute film. Unfortunately it is 130 minutes and the extra 40 minutes is almost fatal. There is an important story being told, that is somewhat dulled by way too much extraneous material, along with some distracting family distress, and child coddling. Less would have been best in the case of "Ghosts of Mississippi. The acting by Alec Baldwin, Whoppi Goldberg, and especially James Woods is totally acceptable, but the movie drags on way too long. I realize being based on fact, the writers were somewhat restricted, but I would have preferred a leaner story, without the distracting extras involving wives and children. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Average Fare...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rob Reiner's 'Ghosts Of Mississippi' is a golden opportunity, gone wrong. Though based on a disturbing yet moving story, the on-screen interpretation doesn't hold you completely. 'Ghosts Of Mississippi' is based on the true story of the 1994 trial of Byron De La Beckwith, a white supremacist accused of the 1963 assassination of civil rights activist Medgar Evers. Rob Reiner knows his job. He is a very talented storyteller, and his direction even in here is good. But, the writing has many loopholes. As mentioned, the true-story, doesn't get it's due. The writing in the first hour doesn't work and bores. Sure, the climax is dramatic & effective, but the damage is already done by then. John Seale's Cinematography is alright. Peroformance-Wise: Alec Baldwin as Bobby DeLaughter does fairly well. James Woods is very impressive as the conniving Byron De La Beckwith, while Whoopi Goldberg as Myrlie Evers is fair. Virginia Madsen is wasted. William H. Macy and Craig T. Nelson are okay. Others lend able support. On the whole, A golden opportunity gone wrong. At best, An Average Fare!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engrossing true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lamadrelrs
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This excellent film tells the true story of a white southern prosecutor who has the courage to try to set right a gross miscarriage of justice that took place in the segregated South at the beginning of the Civil Rights movement 30 years earlier. Alec Balwin as prosecutor Bobby DeLaughter and James Woods as Brian De la Beckwith, the accused, give outstanding performances. Whoopi Goldberg shows her range as an actress portraying Myrlie Evers, widow of slain civil rights leader Medgar Evers whose murder was never solved or prosecuted. Goldberg lets the viewer know that Mrs. Evers is a woman of great dignity, strength and faith. I was a young woman during the actual events that took place in Mississippi so long ago. At the time, I must not have paid much attention because none of this story was really familiar to me. I enjoyed it so much that I bought the DVD and watch it about three times a year. I have recommended the film to social studies teachers. The story serves a springboard for teaching opportunities. The artistic quality of the film never leaves the viewer feeling bored. Really good film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Too Subtle
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amwcsu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The assassination of Medgar Evers was one of the most shocking incidents during the Civil Rights movement. Being that, it should've been done with more attention to detail. If you are going to do a period piece of Evers then you going to have to show what this man did and have done to modern society in order for the audience to know who Medgar Evers really was. Hence, Ghosts of Mississippi should have focused more on the Evers and how he stirred up the ire of the KKK for the first half-hour/45 minutes of the movie then shown the murder. Makes sense, doesn't it? The set design was magnificent and authentic. Nothing was wrong with it. My only gripes are the characters. For example they're wonderfully acted, but not really convincing with the exception of James Woods disturbingly evil, but somewhat funny "old Kook" in boonies rendition of infamous assassin Byron De La Beckwith and Alec Baldwin as the driven and selfless District Attorney Bobby DeLaughter. The characters could have been a little bolder like in "The Long Walk Home". You want people to hate this guy,Beckwith and you want see this film and feel like someone just punched you in the stomach. For example, as the DeLaughter family was being harassed; We could've seen the rawness of racist opposition not just a shattered windshield and name-calling and a sanitized version of a bomb threat at the family home! What bothers me, is that movies that involve racism and the South should give you a feeling of resentment, it shouldn't have a "Disney Channel" subtle tinge to it. This is the "Achille's Heel" that makes Ghosts of Mississippi fall short of a convincing murder mystery. I'm not saying that I hate this film. I actually liked it, I still like it. But it could be bolder. A movie about the Civil Rights era in the South should convince you, shock you, anger you, and show various perspectives about the subject. That, my friends is what makes a docudrama stand out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    awesome film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dr. Michael Hollywood
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Strong performances from Alec Baldwin, James Woods, Whoopi Goldberg, Craig T. Nelson, Bill Smitrovich and William H. Macy makes "Ghosts Of Mississippi" one of the best movies I have seen. "Ghosts Of Mississippi" deserved an Oscar in every single category that one can be given in because it was that good. I never knew the story of Medgar Evers before I saw this film; but, I learned a lot through watching the film. I hope everyone has the same experience and opportunity I had when I saw this movie because it is one history lesson that should be seen rather than read in history books or newspaper archives. I was truly honored to watch this film. There are several reasons this film is a success; one of them are the performances. "Ghosts Of Mississippi" is each actors best film of their career bar none. Alec Baldwin brings intensity, aggressiveness and never say die attitude to his role as Bobby DeLaughter. Whoopi Goldberg stars as Myrlie Evers, widow of Medgar Evers, who with relentless pursuit of justice re-opens this murder case. Finally, James Woods stars as Byron De La Beckwith, the defendant, who with great conviction and sincerity brings the essence of the real person to the surface. As great as Baldwin and Woods are in this they do not hold a candle to Goldberg who gives not only the best performance in the film, year but I dare say the best performance of the decade of the 90's. Known for her comedic roles in the "Sister Act" series, Goldberg turns dramatic for "Ghosts Of Mississippi." This is a very impressive turn and most likely her best dramatic role since "The Color Purple." The intense and aggressive style Golberg brought to her role as the widowed Mrs. Evers was beautiful to watch. The second reason why this film remains on my short list of best films are the messages that brought up. For example, equality for all and the fact that any discrimination will not be tolerated under any circumstances. Another message I got from this film was under no circumstances should anybody underestimate the power of tenacity because it will make dreams come true every time. This film was thought-provoking, brilliant, inspiring and compelling. In addition, "Ghosts Of Mississippi" will move you to tears, put a smile on your face and anger you because these are the emotions I felt watching this movie. Combined with the excellent ensemble performances, brilliant script and messages this film had "Ghosts Of Mississippi" is one film you can't miss. There will most certainly be other inspirational films that come along, but "Ghosts Of The Mississippi" still remains at the top of my list as one of the most inspiring films I've seen. Two thumbs way up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent subject gets bogged down
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thunderclancat
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ghosts of Mississippi tells the story of the assassination of civil rights leader Medgar Evers by Klansman Byron de la Beckwith, and the much-delayed trial of the assassin. Alec Baldwin plays the Prosecutor determined to bring De la Beckwith to justice, and does a serviceable job as does Whoopi Goldberg as Evers' widow. James Woods gives an at-times over-the-top performance as the killer. Unfortunately the story gets bogged down in stories about the Prosecutor's home life, and the decision to bring in Southern Poverty Law Center leader Morris Dees, who completely hams up his time in the film. This is a film that fails it's subject. By trying to make the subject matter less complex and less scary the filmmakers ruined what could have been a very powerful and moving film. It does have a good soundtrack, though, so there's that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting courtroom drama! 7,7!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know anything about the exact real event on which "Ghosts of Mississippi" is based on, but I found them very interesting, and the movie, too. I am quite interested in Law (I almost began the Law degree at my town college and am still a little frustrated not to have done it), so I like many courtroom movies like "The Lincoln lawyer", "A time to kill", "A few good men", "The firm", "Murder in the first"... Those not interested in this subgenre will not probably enjoy the one I am reviewing... "Ghosts of Mississippi" may sound like a horror movie, that is why I think it is not the most apropiated tittle. The story is mainly about a district attorney from Mississippi who allies with the widow of a black civil rights leader who was murdered about thirty years ago while his murderer was living free. The end will be predictable if we know the real case well but even in this case, it is worth to discover this movie with its good acting, cast, scenography and so on. This is not the movie in the subgenre, but really, it is better than some other I have seen. The director is Rob Reiner, who directed very good movies like "A few good men", "Misery" and "The bucket list" as well as other worse like "The magic of Belle Isle" and "When Harry met Sally". In this case, he did a very good job taking into account the script is very tied to the reality. The pace is excellent for a movie of this kind and it has many moving moments and dialogues. I think the duration of the film is the proper one, too. The cast is starred by Alec Baldwin with his powerful voice and believable interpretation of the district attorney convinced of making justice. Although not my favorite, he is noticeable actor with an incredible career, but I think he should work in more varied movies. Anyway, his work in this and others is very intense. Baldwin, in concret, and the performances in general represent a strong point in the movie James Woods (I liked him in "The specialist") is not as present in the movie, but his performance is one of the best I have seen him do. He plays the part of the murderer when he was younger and old: a masterful performance. Whoopi Goldberg plays a very powerful and dramatic and relevant role as the widow. The rest of the cast is OK: Willian H. Macy, Craig T. Nelson... The scenography is simple but realistic and aproppiate as it has to be. In conclusion, the movie is good in every aspect without reaching the top levels of courtroom movies like "A time to kill" and some others, but will really satisfy those interested in this subgenre and realistic reality-based dramas, in general. 7,7.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Monsters in Mississippi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rob Reiner's 'Ghosts of Mississipi' is based on a relatively less known (today) reopening of Medger Evers racially motivated murder case. Starting with the flaws of the film, I can see why many would comment that this is another 'white man rescues the oppressed black people flick'. To balance this out, the director could have portrayed more of Evers's life and the significance of what he did and also developed the story of his wife who's an integral part, show more of her (and the family's) struggle. Here the focus is almost entirely on Baldwin's DeLaughter and the obstacles he faces during the trial. The film also appears to be a tad glossy. What does work, even though the story is predictable, is the level of suspense and tension which is very well maintained. You know what'll happen in the end but you still root for Delaughter to succeed every step. Alec Baldwin does a brilliant job as the lawyer who's taken by the injustice and brutality of the crime and seeks to bring justice to the family and community. Whoopi Goldberg wonderfully downplays her part. 'Wish there was more of her. Her character doesn't seem to have 'aged' in 27 years (except for the darker circles round her eyes). James Wood is great as the hateful De la Beckwith. 'Ghosts of Mississipi' could have been more if only more of the late Medgar and his wife's life was included but it certainly is a watchable film that reminds one of a forgotten important event in America.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Movie Review! - http://tss5078.blogspot.com
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tss5078
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my favorite historical movies ever made. What I really love about this film is just how accurate it is. The film is based on a book written by the prosecutor, Bobby DeLaughter, and before the film was made, all the actually people involved were interviewed and allowed to give their input into how their characters were developed. The story takes place in 1990 and is about the third re-trial of the man accused of killing civil right leader Medger Evers in the 1960's. Alec Baldwin portrays the prosecutor, and while I am by no means a fan of his, he was truly great in this film. I wish he'd stick to roles like this instead of trying to be funny, because he's not funny. Whoopi Goldberg, remains one of the most underrated actresses in Hollywood and was just amazing here. This is a top notch, historically accurate drama that every history buff needs to see. I honestly can't recommend it enough!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ClintnBarbWard1
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Ghosts of Mississippi Alec Baldwin plays bobby delaughter who try to bring MEdger Evers killer Bryon DE la Beck-with played by James woods. Whoopi Goldberg is in the film too as medgers widow. rob directs. i think James woods a tremendous performance as Bryon DE labeckwith Alec Baldwin did a good job better then his usual work and whoopi Goldberg did a decent job even though there is one thing in the whole movie that she does that drives me nuts it is when she first talks to Alec Baldwin over the phone and sacarsa;y talks to him and then simels. William h Macy is my second favorite character in the whole movie when he says i cant get a women to love me now when I'm alive. this movie is really entertaining especially the performances by James woods and William h Macy. its a movie i recommend to everybody
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plodding history lesson ...................
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This could have been a pretty good ninety minute film. Unfortunately it is 130 minutes and the extra 40 minutes is almost fatal. There is an important story being told, that is somewhat dulled by way too much extraneous material, along with some distracting family distress, and child coddling. Less would have been best in the case of "Ghosts of Mississippi. The acting by Alec Baldwin, Whoppi Goldberg, and especially James Woods is totally acceptable, but the movie drags on way too long. I realize being based on fact, the writers were somewhat restricted, but I would have preferred a leaner story, without the distracting extras involving wives and children. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Average Fare...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rob Reiner's 'Ghosts Of Mississippi' is a golden opportunity, gone wrong. Though based on a disturbing yet moving story, the on-screen interpretation doesn't hold you completely. 'Ghosts Of Mississippi' is based on the true story of the 1994 trial of Byron De La Beckwith, a white supremacist accused of the 1963 assassination of civil rights activist Medgar Evers. Rob Reiner knows his job. He is a very talented storyteller, and his direction even in here is good. But, the writing has many loopholes. As mentioned, the true-story, doesn't get it's due. The writing in the first hour doesn't work and bores. Sure, the climax is dramatic & effective, but the damage is already done by then. John Seale's Cinematography is alright. Peroformance-Wise: Alec Baldwin as Bobby DeLaughter does fairly well. James Woods is very impressive as the conniving Byron De La Beckwith, while Whoopi Goldberg as Myrlie Evers is fair. Virginia Madsen is wasted. William H. Macy and Craig T. Nelson are okay. Others lend able support. On the whole, A golden opportunity gone wrong. At best, An Average Fare!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engrossing true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lamadrelrs
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This excellent film tells the true story of a white southern prosecutor who has the courage to try to set right a gross miscarriage of justice that took place in the segregated South at the beginning of the Civil Rights movement 30 years earlier. Alec Balwin as prosecutor Bobby DeLaughter and James Woods as Brian De la Beckwith, the accused, give outstanding performances. Whoopi Goldberg shows her range as an actress portraying Myrlie Evers, widow of slain civil rights leader Medgar Evers whose murder was never solved or prosecuted. Goldberg lets the viewer know that Mrs. Evers is a woman of great dignity, strength and faith. I was a young woman during the actual events that took place in Mississippi so long ago. At the time, I must not have paid much attention because none of this story was really familiar to me. I enjoyed it so much that I bought the DVD and watch it about three times a year. I have recommended the film to social studies teachers. The story serves a springboard for teaching opportunities. The artistic quality of the film never leaves the viewer feeling bored. Really good film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Too Subtle
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amwcsu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The assassination of Medgar Evers was one of the most shocking incidents during the Civil Rights movement. Being that, it should've been done with more attention to detail. If you are going to do a period piece of Evers then you going to have to show what this man did and have done to modern society in order for the audience to know who Medgar Evers really was. Hence, Ghosts of Mississippi should have focused more on the Evers and how he stirred up the ire of the KKK for the first half-hour/45 minutes of the movie then shown the murder. Makes sense, doesn't it? The set design was magnificent and authentic. Nothing was wrong with it. My only gripes are the characters. For example they're wonderfully acted, but not really convincing with the exception of James Woods disturbingly evil, but somewhat funny "old Kook" in boonies rendition of infamous assassin Byron De La Beckwith and Alec Baldwin as the driven and selfless District Attorney Bobby DeLaughter. The characters could have been a little bolder like in "The Long Walk Home". You want people to hate this guy,Beckwith and you want see this film and feel like someone just punched you in the stomach. For example, as the DeLaughter family was being harassed; We could've seen the rawness of racist opposition not just a shattered windshield and name-calling and a sanitized version of a bomb threat at the family home! What bothers me, is that movies that involve racism and the South should give you a feeling of resentment, it shouldn't have a "Disney Channel" subtle tinge to it. This is the "Achille's Heel" that makes Ghosts of Mississippi fall short of a convincing murder mystery. I'm not saying that I hate this film. I actually liked it, I still like it. But it could be bolder. A movie about the Civil Rights era in the South should convince you, shock you, anger you, and show various perspectives about the subject. That, my friends is what makes a docudrama stand out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    awesome film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dr. Michael Hollywood
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Strong performances from Alec Baldwin, James Woods, Whoopi Goldberg, Craig T. Nelson, Bill Smitrovich and William H. Macy makes "Ghosts Of Mississippi" one of the best movies I have seen. "Ghosts Of Mississippi" deserved an Oscar in every single category that one can be given in because it was that good. I never knew the story of Medgar Evers before I saw this film; but, I learned a lot through watching the film. I hope everyone has the same experience and opportunity I had when I saw this movie because it is one history lesson that should be seen rather than read in history books or newspaper archives. I was truly honored to watch this film. There are several reasons this film is a success; one of them are the performances. "Ghosts Of Mississippi" is each actors best film of their career bar none. Alec Baldwin brings intensity, aggressiveness and never say die attitude to his role as Bobby DeLaughter. Whoopi Goldberg stars as Myrlie Evers, widow of Medgar Evers, who with relentless pursuit of justice re-opens this murder case. Finally, James Woods stars as Byron De La Beckwith, the defendant, who with great conviction and sincerity brings the essence of the real person to the surface. As great as Baldwin and Woods are in this they do not hold a candle to Goldberg who gives not only the best performance in the film, year but I dare say the best performance of the decade of the 90's. Known for her comedic roles in the "Sister Act" series, Goldberg turns dramatic for "Ghosts Of Mississippi." This is a very impressive turn and most likely her best dramatic role since "The Color Purple." The intense and aggressive style Golberg brought to her role as the widowed Mrs. Evers was beautiful to watch. The second reason why this film remains on my short list of best films are the messages that brought up. For example, equality for all and the fact that any discrimination will not be tolerated under any circumstances. Another message I got from this film was under no circumstances should anybody underestimate the power of tenacity because it will make dreams come true every time. This film was thought-provoking, brilliant, inspiring and compelling. In addition, "Ghosts Of Mississippi" will move you to tears, put a smile on your face and anger you because these are the emotions I felt watching this movie. Combined with the excellent ensemble performances, brilliant script and messages this film had "Ghosts Of Mississippi" is one film you can't miss. There will most certainly be other inspirational films that come along, but "Ghosts Of The Mississippi" still remains at the top of my list as one of the most inspiring films I've seen. Two thumbs way up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent subject gets bogged down
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thunderclancat
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ghosts of Mississippi tells the story of the assassination of civil rights leader Medgar Evers by Klansman Byron de la Beckwith, and the much-delayed trial of the assassin. Alec Baldwin plays the Prosecutor determined to bring De la Beckwith to justice, and does a serviceable job as does Whoopi Goldberg as Evers' widow. James Woods gives an at-times over-the-top performance as the killer. Unfortunately the story gets bogged down in stories about the Prosecutor's home life, and the decision to bring in Southern Poverty Law Center leader Morris Dees, who completely hams up his time in the film. This is a film that fails it's subject. By trying to make the subject matter less complex and less scary the filmmakers ruined what could have been a very powerful and moving film. It does have a good soundtrack, though, so there's that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting courtroom drama! 7,7!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know anything about the exact real event on which "Ghosts of Mississippi" is based on, but I found them very interesting, and the movie, too. I am quite interested in Law (I almost began the Law degree at my town college and am still a little frustrated not to have done it), so I like many courtroom movies like "The Lincoln lawyer", "A time to kill", "A few good men", "The firm", "Murder in the first"... Those not interested in this subgenre will not probably enjoy the one I am reviewing... "Ghosts of Mississippi" may sound like a horror movie, that is why I think it is not the most apropiated tittle. The story is mainly about a district attorney from Mississippi who allies with the widow of a black civil rights leader who was murdered about thirty years ago while his murderer was living free. The end will be predictable if we know the real case well but even in this case, it is worth to discover this movie with its good acting, cast, scenography and so on. This is not the movie in the subgenre, but really, it is better than some other I have seen. The director is Rob Reiner, who directed very good movies like "A few good men", "Misery" and "The bucket list" as well as other worse like "The magic of Belle Isle" and "When Harry met Sally". In this case, he did a very good job taking into account the script is very tied to the reality. The pace is excellent for a movie of this kind and it has many moving moments and dialogues. I think the duration of the film is the proper one, too. The cast is starred by Alec Baldwin with his powerful voice and believable interpretation of the district attorney convinced of making justice. Although not my favorite, he is noticeable actor with an incredible career, but I think he should work in more varied movies. Anyway, his work in this and others is very intense. Baldwin, in concret, and the performances in general represent a strong point in the movie James Woods (I liked him in "The specialist") is not as present in the movie, but his performance is one of the best I have seen him do. He plays the part of the murderer when he was younger and old: a masterful performance. Whoopi Goldberg plays a very powerful and dramatic and relevant role as the widow. The rest of the cast is OK: Willian H. Macy, Craig T. Nelson... The scenography is simple but realistic and aproppiate as it has to be. In conclusion, the movie is good in every aspect without reaching the top levels of courtroom movies like "A time to kill" and some others, but will really satisfy those interested in this subgenre and realistic reality-based dramas, in general. 7,7.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Monsters in Mississippi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rob Reiner's 'Ghosts of Mississipi' is based on a relatively less known (today) reopening of Medger Evers racially motivated murder case. Starting with the flaws of the film, I can see why many would comment that this is another 'white man rescues the oppressed black people flick'. To balance this out, the director could have portrayed more of Evers's life and the significance of what he did and also developed the story of his wife who's an integral part, show more of her (and the family's) struggle. Here the focus is almost entirely on Baldwin's DeLaughter and the obstacles he faces during the trial. The film also appears to be a tad glossy. What does work, even though the story is predictable, is the level of suspense and tension which is very well maintained. You know what'll happen in the end but you still root for Delaughter to succeed every step. Alec Baldwin does a brilliant job as the lawyer who's taken by the injustice and brutality of the crime and seeks to bring justice to the family and community. Whoopi Goldberg wonderfully downplays her part. 'Wish there was more of her. Her character doesn't seem to have 'aged' in 27 years (except for the darker circles round her eyes). James Wood is great as the hateful De la Beckwith. 'Ghosts of Mississipi' could have been more if only more of the late Medgar and his wife's life was included but it certainly is a watchable film that reminds one of a forgotten important event in America.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Movie Review! - http://tss5078.blogspot.com
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tss5078
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my favorite historical movies ever made. What I really love about this film is just how accurate it is. The film is based on a book written by the prosecutor, Bobby DeLaughter, and before the film was made, all the actually people involved were interviewed and allowed to give their input into how their characters were developed. The story takes place in 1990 and is about the third re-trial of the man accused of killing civil right leader Medger Evers in the 1960's. Alec Baldwin portrays the prosecutor, and while I am by no means a fan of his, he was truly great in this film. I wish he'd stick to roles like this instead of trying to be funny, because he's not funny. Whoopi Goldberg, remains one of the most underrated actresses in Hollywood and was just amazing here. This is a top notch, historically accurate drama that every history buff needs to see. I honestly can't recommend it enough!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ClintnBarbWard1
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Ghosts of Mississippi Alec Baldwin plays bobby delaughter who try to bring MEdger Evers killer Bryon DE la Beck-with played by James woods. Whoopi Goldberg is in the film too as medgers widow. rob directs. i think James woods a tremendous performance as Bryon DE labeckwith Alec Baldwin did a good job better then his usual work and whoopi Goldberg did a decent job even though there is one thing in the whole movie that she does that drives me nuts it is when she first talks to Alec Baldwin over the phone and sacarsa;y talks to him and then simels. William h Macy is my second favorite character in the whole movie when he says i cant get a women to love me now when I'm alive. this movie is really entertaining especially the performances by James woods and William h Macy. its a movie i recommend to everybody
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plodding history lesson ...................
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This could have been a pretty good ninety minute film. Unfortunately it is 130 minutes and the extra 40 minutes is almost fatal. There is an important story being told, that is somewhat dulled by way too much extraneous material, along with some distracting family distress, and child coddling. Less would have been best in the case of "Ghosts of Mississippi. The acting by Alec Baldwin, Whoppi Goldberg, and especially James Woods is totally acceptable, but the movie drags on way too long. I realize being based on fact, the writers were somewhat restricted, but I would have preferred a leaner story, without the distracting extras involving wives and children. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Average Fare...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rob Reiner's 'Ghosts Of Mississippi' is a golden opportunity, gone wrong. Though based on a disturbing yet moving story, the on-screen interpretation doesn't hold you completely. 'Ghosts Of Mississippi' is based on the true story of the 1994 trial of Byron De La Beckwith, a white supremacist accused of the 1963 assassination of civil rights activist Medgar Evers. Rob Reiner knows his job. He is a very talented storyteller, and his direction even in here is good. But, the writing has many loopholes. As mentioned, the true-story, doesn't get it's due. The writing in the first hour doesn't work and bores. Sure, the climax is dramatic & effective, but the damage is already done by then. John Seale's Cinematography is alright. Peroformance-Wise: Alec Baldwin as Bobby DeLaughter does fairly well. James Woods is very impressive as the conniving Byron De La Beckwith, while Whoopi Goldberg as Myrlie Evers is fair. Virginia Madsen is wasted. William H. Macy and Craig T. Nelson are okay. Others lend able support. On the whole, A golden opportunity gone wrong. At best, An Average Fare!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engrossing true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lamadrelrs
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This excellent film tells the true story of a white southern prosecutor who has the courage to try to set right a gross miscarriage of justice that took place in the segregated South at the beginning of the Civil Rights movement 30 years earlier. Alec Balwin as prosecutor Bobby DeLaughter and James Woods as Brian De la Beckwith, the accused, give outstanding performances. Whoopi Goldberg shows her range as an actress portraying Myrlie Evers, widow of slain civil rights leader Medgar Evers whose murder was never solved or prosecuted. Goldberg lets the viewer know that Mrs. Evers is a woman of great dignity, strength and faith. I was a young woman during the actual events that took place in Mississippi so long ago. At the time, I must not have paid much attention because none of this story was really familiar to me. I enjoyed it so much that I bought the DVD and watch it about three times a year. I have recommended the film to social studies teachers. The story serves a springboard for teaching opportunities. The artistic quality of the film never leaves the viewer feeling bored. Really good film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Too Subtle
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amwcsu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The assassination of Medgar Evers was one of the most shocking incidents during the Civil Rights movement. Being that, it should've been done with more attention to detail. If you are going to do a period piece of Evers then you going to have to show what this man did and have done to modern society in order for the audience to know who Medgar Evers really was. Hence, Ghosts of Mississippi should have focused more on the Evers and how he stirred up the ire of the KKK for the first half-hour/45 minutes of the movie then shown the murder. Makes sense, doesn't it? The set design was magnificent and authentic. Nothing was wrong with it. My only gripes are the characters. For example they're wonderfully acted, but not really convincing with the exception of James Woods disturbingly evil, but somewhat funny "old Kook" in boonies rendition of infamous assassin Byron De La Beckwith and Alec Baldwin as the driven and selfless District Attorney Bobby DeLaughter. The characters could have been a little bolder like in "The Long Walk Home". You want people to hate this guy,Beckwith and you want see this film and feel like someone just punched you in the stomach. For example, as the DeLaughter family was being harassed; We could've seen the rawness of racist opposition not just a shattered windshield and name-calling and a sanitized version of a bomb threat at the family home! What bothers me, is that movies that involve racism and the South should give you a feeling of resentment, it shouldn't have a "Disney Channel" subtle tinge to it. This is the "Achille's Heel" that makes Ghosts of Mississippi fall short of a convincing murder mystery. I'm not saying that I hate this film. I actually liked it, I still like it. But it could be bolder. A movie about the Civil Rights era in the South should convince you, shock you, anger you, and show various perspectives about the subject. That, my friends is what makes a docudrama stand out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    awesome film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dr. Michael Hollywood
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Strong performances from Alec Baldwin, James Woods, Whoopi Goldberg, Craig T. Nelson, Bill Smitrovich and William H. Macy makes "Ghosts Of Mississippi" one of the best movies I have seen. "Ghosts Of Mississippi" deserved an Oscar in every single category that one can be given in because it was that good. I never knew the story of Medgar Evers before I saw this film; but, I learned a lot through watching the film. I hope everyone has the same experience and opportunity I had when I saw this movie because it is one history lesson that should be seen rather than read in history books or newspaper archives. I was truly honored to watch this film. There are several reasons this film is a success; one of them are the performances. "Ghosts Of Mississippi" is each actors best film of their career bar none. Alec Baldwin brings intensity, aggressiveness and never say die attitude to his role as Bobby DeLaughter. Whoopi Goldberg stars as Myrlie Evers, widow of Medgar Evers, who with relentless pursuit of justice re-opens this murder case. Finally, James Woods stars as Byron De La Beckwith, the defendant, who with great conviction and sincerity brings the essence of the real person to the surface. As great as Baldwin and Woods are in this they do not hold a candle to Goldberg who gives not only the best performance in the film, year but I dare say the best performance of the decade of the 90's. Known for her comedic roles in the "Sister Act" series, Goldberg turns dramatic for "Ghosts Of Mississippi." This is a very impressive turn and most likely her best dramatic role since "The Color Purple." The intense and aggressive style Golberg brought to her role as the widowed Mrs. Evers was beautiful to watch. The second reason why this film remains on my short list of best films are the messages that brought up. For example, equality for all and the fact that any discrimination will not be tolerated under any circumstances. Another message I got from this film was under no circumstances should anybody underestimate the power of tenacity because it will make dreams come true every time. This film was thought-provoking, brilliant, inspiring and compelling. In addition, "Ghosts Of Mississippi" will move you to tears, put a smile on your face and anger you because these are the emotions I felt watching this movie. Combined with the excellent ensemble performances, brilliant script and messages this film had "Ghosts Of Mississippi" is one film you can't miss. There will most certainly be other inspirational films that come along, but "Ghosts Of The Mississippi" still remains at the top of my list as one of the most inspiring films I've seen. Two thumbs way up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent subject gets bogged down
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thunderclancat
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ghosts of Mississippi tells the story of the assassination of civil rights leader Medgar Evers by Klansman Byron de la Beckwith, and the much-delayed trial of the assassin. Alec Baldwin plays the Prosecutor determined to bring De la Beckwith to justice, and does a serviceable job as does Whoopi Goldberg as Evers' widow. James Woods gives an at-times over-the-top performance as the killer. Unfortunately the story gets bogged down in stories about the Prosecutor's home life, and the decision to bring in Southern Poverty Law Center leader Morris Dees, who completely hams up his time in the film. This is a film that fails it's subject. By trying to make the subject matter less complex and less scary the filmmakers ruined what could have been a very powerful and moving film. It does have a good soundtrack, though, so there's that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting courtroom drama! 7,7!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know anything about the exact real event on which "Ghosts of Mississippi" is based on, but I found them very interesting, and the movie, too. I am quite interested in Law (I almost began the Law degree at my town college and am still a little frustrated not to have done it), so I like many courtroom movies like "The Lincoln lawyer", "A time to kill", "A few good men", "The firm", "Murder in the first"... Those not interested in this subgenre will not probably enjoy the one I am reviewing... "Ghosts of Mississippi" may sound like a horror movie, that is why I think it is not the most apropiated tittle. The story is mainly about a district attorney from Mississippi who allies with the widow of a black civil rights leader who was murdered about thirty years ago while his murderer was living free. The end will be predictable if we know the real case well but even in this case, it is worth to discover this movie with its good acting, cast, scenography and so on. This is not the movie in the subgenre, but really, it is better than some other I have seen. The director is Rob Reiner, who directed very good movies like "A few good men", "Misery" and "The bucket list" as well as other worse like "The magic of Belle Isle" and "When Harry met Sally". In this case, he did a very good job taking into account the script is very tied to the reality. The pace is excellent for a movie of this kind and it has many moving moments and dialogues. I think the duration of the film is the proper one, too. The cast is starred by Alec Baldwin with his powerful voice and believable interpretation of the district attorney convinced of making justice. Although not my favorite, he is noticeable actor with an incredible career, but I think he should work in more varied movies. Anyway, his work in this and others is very intense. Baldwin, in concret, and the performances in general represent a strong point in the movie James Woods (I liked him in "The specialist") is not as present in the movie, but his performance is one of the best I have seen him do. He plays the part of the murderer when he was younger and old: a masterful performance. Whoopi Goldberg plays a very powerful and dramatic and relevant role as the widow. The rest of the cast is OK: Willian H. Macy, Craig T. Nelson... The scenography is simple but realistic and aproppiate as it has to be. In conclusion, the movie is good in every aspect without reaching the top levels of courtroom movies like "A time to kill" and some others, but will really satisfy those interested in this subgenre and realistic reality-based dramas, in general. 7,7.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Monsters in Mississippi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rob Reiner's 'Ghosts of Mississipi' is based on a relatively less known (today) reopening of Medger Evers racially motivated murder case. Starting with the flaws of the film, I can see why many would comment that this is another 'white man rescues the oppressed black people flick'. To balance this out, the director could have portrayed more of Evers's life and the significance of what he did and also developed the story of his wife who's an integral part, show more of her (and the family's) struggle. Here the focus is almost entirely on Baldwin's DeLaughter and the obstacles he faces during the trial. The film also appears to be a tad glossy. What does work, even though the story is predictable, is the level of suspense and tension which is very well maintained. You know what'll happen in the end but you still root for Delaughter to succeed every step. Alec Baldwin does a brilliant job as the lawyer who's taken by the injustice and brutality of the crime and seeks to bring justice to the family and community. Whoopi Goldberg wonderfully downplays her part. 'Wish there was more of her. Her character doesn't seem to have 'aged' in 27 years (except for the darker circles round her eyes). James Wood is great as the hateful De la Beckwith. 'Ghosts of Mississipi' could have been more if only more of the late Medgar and his wife's life was included but it certainly is a watchable film that reminds one of a forgotten important event in America.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Movie Review! - http://tss5078.blogspot.com
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tss5078
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my favorite historical movies ever made. What I really love about this film is just how accurate it is. The film is based on a book written by the prosecutor, Bobby DeLaughter, and before the film was made, all the actually people involved were interviewed and allowed to give their input into how their characters were developed. The story takes place in 1990 and is about the third re-trial of the man accused of killing civil right leader Medger Evers in the 1960's. Alec Baldwin portrays the prosecutor, and while I am by no means a fan of his, he was truly great in this film. I wish he'd stick to roles like this instead of trying to be funny, because he's not funny. Whoopi Goldberg, remains one of the most underrated actresses in Hollywood and was just amazing here. This is a top notch, historically accurate drama that every history buff needs to see. I honestly can't recommend it enough!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ClintnBarbWard1
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Ghosts of Mississippi Alec Baldwin plays bobby delaughter who try to bring MEdger Evers killer Bryon DE la Beck-with played by James woods. Whoopi Goldberg is in the film too as medgers widow. rob directs. i think James woods a tremendous performance as Bryon DE labeckwith Alec Baldwin did a good job better then his usual work and whoopi Goldberg did a decent job even though there is one thing in the whole movie that she does that drives me nuts it is when she first talks to Alec Baldwin over the phone and sacarsa;y talks to him and then simels. William h Macy is my second favorite character in the whole movie when he says i cant get a women to love me now when I'm alive. this movie is really entertaining especially the performances by James woods and William h Macy. its a movie i recommend to everybody
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plodding history lesson ...................
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This could have been a pretty good ninety minute film. Unfortunately it is 130 minutes and the extra 40 minutes is almost fatal. There is an important story being told, that is somewhat dulled by way too much extraneous material, along with some distracting family distress, and child coddling. Less would have been best in the case of "Ghosts of Mississippi. The acting by Alec Baldwin, Whoppi Goldberg, and especially James Woods is totally acceptable, but the movie drags on way too long. I realize being based on fact, the writers were somewhat restricted, but I would have preferred a leaner story, without the distracting extras involving wives and children. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Average Fare...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rob Reiner's 'Ghosts Of Mississippi' is a golden opportunity, gone wrong. Though based on a disturbing yet moving story, the on-screen interpretation doesn't hold you completely. 'Ghosts Of Mississippi' is based on the true story of the 1994 trial of Byron De La Beckwith, a white supremacist accused of the 1963 assassination of civil rights activist Medgar Evers. Rob Reiner knows his job. He is a very talented storyteller, and his direction even in here is good. But, the writing has many loopholes. As mentioned, the true-story, doesn't get it's due. The writing in the first hour doesn't work and bores. Sure, the climax is dramatic & effective, but the damage is already done by then. John Seale's Cinematography is alright. Peroformance-Wise: Alec Baldwin as Bobby DeLaughter does fairly well. James Woods is very impressive as the conniving Byron De La Beckwith, while Whoopi Goldberg as Myrlie Evers is fair. Virginia Madsen is wasted. William H. Macy and Craig T. Nelson are okay. Others lend able support. On the whole, A golden opportunity gone wrong. At best, An Average Fare!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engrossing true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lamadrelrs
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This excellent film tells the true story of a white southern prosecutor who has the courage to try to set right a gross miscarriage of justice that took place in the segregated South at the beginning of the Civil Rights movement 30 years earlier. Alec Balwin as prosecutor Bobby DeLaughter and James Woods as Brian De la Beckwith, the accused, give outstanding performances. Whoopi Goldberg shows her range as an actress portraying Myrlie Evers, widow of slain civil rights leader Medgar Evers whose murder was never solved or prosecuted. Goldberg lets the viewer know that Mrs. Evers is a woman of great dignity, strength and faith. I was a young woman during the actual events that took place in Mississippi so long ago. At the time, I must not have paid much attention because none of this story was really familiar to me. I enjoyed it so much that I bought the DVD and watch it about three times a year. I have recommended the film to social studies teachers. The story serves a springboard for teaching opportunities. The artistic quality of the film never leaves the viewer feeling bored. Really good film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Too Subtle
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amwcsu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The assassination of Medgar Evers was one of the most shocking incidents during the Civil Rights movement. Being that, it should've been done with more attention to detail. If you are going to do a period piece of Evers then you going to have to show what this man did and have done to modern society in order for the audience to know who Medgar Evers really was. Hence, Ghosts of Mississippi should have focused more on the Evers and how he stirred up the ire of the KKK for the first half-hour/45 minutes of the movie then shown the murder. Makes sense, doesn't it? The set design was magnificent and authentic. Nothing was wrong with it. My only gripes are the characters. For example they're wonderfully acted, but not really convincing with the exception of James Woods disturbingly evil, but somewhat funny "old Kook" in boonies rendition of infamous assassin Byron De La Beckwith and Alec Baldwin as the driven and selfless District Attorney Bobby DeLaughter. The characters could have been a little bolder like in "The Long Walk Home". You want people to hate this guy,Beckwith and you want see this film and feel like someone just punched you in the stomach. For example, as the DeLaughter family was being harassed; We could've seen the rawness of racist opposition not just a shattered windshield and name-calling and a sanitized version of a bomb threat at the family home! What bothers me, is that movies that involve racism and the South should give you a feeling of resentment, it shouldn't have a "Disney Channel" subtle tinge to it. This is the "Achille's Heel" that makes Ghosts of Mississippi fall short of a convincing murder mystery. I'm not saying that I hate this film. I actually liked it, I still like it. But it could be bolder. A movie about the Civil Rights era in the South should convince you, shock you, anger you, and show various perspectives about the subject. That, my friends is what makes a docudrama stand out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    awesome film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dr. Michael Hollywood
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Strong performances from Alec Baldwin, James Woods, Whoopi Goldberg, Craig T. Nelson, Bill Smitrovich and William H. Macy makes "Ghosts Of Mississippi" one of the best movies I have seen. "Ghosts Of Mississippi" deserved an Oscar in every single category that one can be given in because it was that good. I never knew the story of Medgar Evers before I saw this film; but, I learned a lot through watching the film. I hope everyone has the same experience and opportunity I had when I saw this movie because it is one history lesson that should be seen rather than read in history books or newspaper archives. I was truly honored to watch this film. There are several reasons this film is a success; one of them are the performances. "Ghosts Of Mississippi" is each actors best film of their career bar none. Alec Baldwin brings intensity, aggressiveness and never say die attitude to his role as Bobby DeLaughter. Whoopi Goldberg stars as Myrlie Evers, widow of Medgar Evers, who with relentless pursuit of justice re-opens this murder case. Finally, James Woods stars as Byron De La Beckwith, the defendant, who with great conviction and sincerity brings the essence of the real person to the surface. As great as Baldwin and Woods are in this they do not hold a candle to Goldberg who gives not only the best performance in the film, year but I dare say the best performance of the decade of the 90's. Known for her comedic roles in the "Sister Act" series, Goldberg turns dramatic for "Ghosts Of Mississippi." This is a very impressive turn and most likely her best dramatic role since "The Color Purple." The intense and aggressive style Golberg brought to her role as the widowed Mrs. Evers was beautiful to watch. The second reason why this film remains on my short list of best films are the messages that brought up. For example, equality for all and the fact that any discrimination will not be tolerated under any circumstances. Another message I got from this film was under no circumstances should anybody underestimate the power of tenacity because it will make dreams come true every time. This film was thought-provoking, brilliant, inspiring and compelling. In addition, "Ghosts Of Mississippi" will move you to tears, put a smile on your face and anger you because these are the emotions I felt watching this movie. Combined with the excellent ensemble performances, brilliant script and messages this film had "Ghosts Of Mississippi" is one film you can't miss. There will most certainly be other inspirational films that come along, but "Ghosts Of The Mississippi" still remains at the top of my list as one of the most inspiring films I've seen. Two thumbs way up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent subject gets bogged down
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thunderclancat
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ghosts of Mississippi tells the story of the assassination of civil rights leader Medgar Evers by Klansman Byron de la Beckwith, and the much-delayed trial of the assassin. Alec Baldwin plays the Prosecutor determined to bring De la Beckwith to justice, and does a serviceable job as does Whoopi Goldberg as Evers' widow. James Woods gives an at-times over-the-top performance as the killer. Unfortunately the story gets bogged down in stories about the Prosecutor's home life, and the decision to bring in Southern Poverty Law Center leader Morris Dees, who completely hams up his time in the film. This is a film that fails it's subject. By trying to make the subject matter less complex and less scary the filmmakers ruined what could have been a very powerful and moving film. It does have a good soundtrack, though, so there's that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting courtroom drama! 7,7!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know anything about the exact real event on which "Ghosts of Mississippi" is based on, but I found them very interesting, and the movie, too. I am quite interested in Law (I almost began the Law degree at my town college and am still a little frustrated not to have done it), so I like many courtroom movies like "The Lincoln lawyer", "A time to kill", "A few good men", "The firm", "Murder in the first"... Those not interested in this subgenre will not probably enjoy the one I am reviewing... "Ghosts of Mississippi" may sound like a horror movie, that is why I think it is not the most apropiated tittle. The story is mainly about a district attorney from Mississippi who allies with the widow of a black civil rights leader who was murdered about thirty years ago while his murderer was living free. The end will be predictable if we know the real case well but even in this case, it is worth to discover this movie with its good acting, cast, scenography and so on. This is not the movie in the subgenre, but really, it is better than some other I have seen. The director is Rob Reiner, who directed very good movies like "A few good men", "Misery" and "The bucket list" as well as other worse like "The magic of Belle Isle" and "When Harry met Sally". In this case, he did a very good job taking into account the script is very tied to the reality. The pace is excellent for a movie of this kind and it has many moving moments and dialogues. I think the duration of the film is the proper one, too. The cast is starred by Alec Baldwin with his powerful voice and believable interpretation of the district attorney convinced of making justice. Although not my favorite, he is noticeable actor with an incredible career, but I think he should work in more varied movies. Anyway, his work in this and others is very intense. Baldwin, in concret, and the performances in general represent a strong point in the movie James Woods (I liked him in "The specialist") is not as present in the movie, but his performance is one of the best I have seen him do. He plays the part of the murderer when he was younger and old: a masterful performance. Whoopi Goldberg plays a very powerful and dramatic and relevant role as the widow. The rest of the cast is OK: Willian H. Macy, Craig T. Nelson... The scenography is simple but realistic and aproppiate as it has to be. In conclusion, the movie is good in every aspect without reaching the top levels of courtroom movies like "A time to kill" and some others, but will really satisfy those interested in this subgenre and realistic reality-based dramas, in general. 7,7.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Monsters in Mississippi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rob Reiner's 'Ghosts of Mississipi' is based on a relatively less known (today) reopening of Medger Evers racially motivated murder case. Starting with the flaws of the film, I can see why many would comment that this is another 'white man rescues the oppressed black people flick'. To balance this out, the director could have portrayed more of Evers's life and the significance of what he did and also developed the story of his wife who's an integral part, show more of her (and the family's) struggle. Here the focus is almost entirely on Baldwin's DeLaughter and the obstacles he faces during the trial. The film also appears to be a tad glossy. What does work, even though the story is predictable, is the level of suspense and tension which is very well maintained. You know what'll happen in the end but you still root for Delaughter to succeed every step. Alec Baldwin does a brilliant job as the lawyer who's taken by the injustice and brutality of the crime and seeks to bring justice to the family and community. Whoopi Goldberg wonderfully downplays her part. 'Wish there was more of her. Her character doesn't seem to have 'aged' in 27 years (except for the darker circles round her eyes). James Wood is great as the hateful De la Beckwith. 'Ghosts of Mississipi' could have been more if only more of the late Medgar and his wife's life was included but it certainly is a watchable film that reminds one of a forgotten important event in America.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Movie Review! - http://tss5078.blogspot.com
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tss5078
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my favorite historical movies ever made. What I really love about this film is just how accurate it is. The film is based on a book written by the prosecutor, Bobby DeLaughter, and before the film was made, all the actually people involved were interviewed and allowed to give their input into how their characters were developed. The story takes place in 1990 and is about the third re-trial of the man accused of killing civil right leader Medger Evers in the 1960's. Alec Baldwin portrays the prosecutor, and while I am by no means a fan of his, he was truly great in this film. I wish he'd stick to roles like this instead of trying to be funny, because he's not funny. Whoopi Goldberg, remains one of the most underrated actresses in Hollywood and was just amazing here. This is a top notch, historically accurate drama that every history buff needs to see. I honestly can't recommend it enough!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ClintnBarbWard1
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Ghosts of Mississippi Alec Baldwin plays bobby delaughter who try to bring MEdger Evers killer Bryon DE la Beck-with played by James woods. Whoopi Goldberg is in the film too as medgers widow. rob directs. i think James woods a tremendous performance as Bryon DE labeckwith Alec Baldwin did a good job better then his usual work and whoopi Goldberg did a decent job even though there is one thing in the whole movie that she does that drives me nuts it is when she first talks to Alec Baldwin over the phone and sacarsa;y talks to him and then simels. William h Macy is my second favorite character in the whole movie when he says i cant get a women to love me now when I'm alive. this movie is really entertaining especially the performances by James woods and William h Macy. its a movie i recommend to everybody
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plodding history lesson ...................
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This could have been a pretty good ninety minute film. Unfortunately it is 130 minutes and the extra 40 minutes is almost fatal. There is an important story being told, that is somewhat dulled by way too much extraneous material, along with some distracting family distress, and child coddling. Less would have been best in the case of "Ghosts of Mississippi. The acting by Alec Baldwin, Whoppi Goldberg, and especially James Woods is totally acceptable, but the movie drags on way too long. I realize being based on fact, the writers were somewhat restricted, but I would have preferred a leaner story, without the distracting extras involving wives and children. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Average Fare...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rob Reiner's 'Ghosts Of Mississippi' is a golden opportunity, gone wrong. Though based on a disturbing yet moving story, the on-screen interpretation doesn't hold you completely. 'Ghosts Of Mississippi' is based on the true story of the 1994 trial of Byron De La Beckwith, a white supremacist accused of the 1963 assassination of civil rights activist Medgar Evers. Rob Reiner knows his job. He is a very talented storyteller, and his direction even in here is good. But, the writing has many loopholes. As mentioned, the true-story, doesn't get it's due. The writing in the first hour doesn't work and bores. Sure, the climax is dramatic & effective, but the damage is already done by then. John Seale's Cinematography is alright. Peroformance-Wise: Alec Baldwin as Bobby DeLaughter does fairly well. James Woods is very impressive as the conniving Byron De La Beckwith, while Whoopi Goldberg as Myrlie Evers is fair. Virginia Madsen is wasted. William H. Macy and Craig T. Nelson are okay. Others lend able support. On the whole, A golden opportunity gone wrong. At best, An Average Fare!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engrossing true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lamadrelrs
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This excellent film tells the true story of a white southern prosecutor who has the courage to try to set right a gross miscarriage of justice that took place in the segregated South at the beginning of the Civil Rights movement 30 years earlier. Alec Balwin as prosecutor Bobby DeLaughter and James Woods as Brian De la Beckwith, the accused, give outstanding performances. Whoopi Goldberg shows her range as an actress portraying Myrlie Evers, widow of slain civil rights leader Medgar Evers whose murder was never solved or prosecuted. Goldberg lets the viewer know that Mrs. Evers is a woman of great dignity, strength and faith. I was a young woman during the actual events that took place in Mississippi so long ago. At the time, I must not have paid much attention because none of this story was really familiar to me. I enjoyed it so much that I bought the DVD and watch it about three times a year. I have recommended the film to social studies teachers. The story serves a springboard for teaching opportunities. The artistic quality of the film never leaves the viewer feeling bored. Really good film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Little Too Subtle
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amwcsu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The assassination of Medgar Evers was one of the most shocking incidents during the Civil Rights movement. Being that, it should've been done with more attention to detail. If you are going to do a period piece of Evers then you going to have to show what this man did and have done to modern society in order for the audience to know who Medgar Evers really was. Hence, Ghosts of Mississippi should have focused more on the Evers and how he stirred up the ire of the KKK for the first half-hour/45 minutes of the movie then shown the murder. Makes sense, doesn't it? The set design was magnificent and authentic. Nothing was wrong with it. My only gripes are the characters. For example they're wonderfully acted, but not really convincing with the exception of James Woods disturbingly evil, but somewhat funny "old Kook" in boonies rendition of infamous assassin Byron De La Beckwith and Alec Baldwin as the driven and selfless District Attorney Bobby DeLaughter. The characters could have been a little bolder like in "The Long Walk Home". You want people to hate this guy,Beckwith and you want see this film and feel like someone just punched you in the stomach. For example, as the DeLaughter family was being harassed; We could've seen the rawness of racist opposition not just a shattered windshield and name-calling and a sanitized version of a bomb threat at the family home! What bothers me, is that movies that involve racism and the South should give you a feeling of resentment, it shouldn't have a "Disney Channel" subtle tinge to it. This is the "Achille's Heel" that makes Ghosts of Mississippi fall short of a convincing murder mystery. I'm not saying that I hate this film. I actually liked it, I still like it. But it could be bolder. A movie about the Civil Rights era in the South should convince you, shock you, anger you, and show various perspectives about the subject. That, my friends is what makes a docudrama stand out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    awesome film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dr. Michael Hollywood
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Strong performances from Alec Baldwin, James Woods, Whoopi Goldberg, Craig T. Nelson, Bill Smitrovich and William H. Macy makes "Ghosts Of Mississippi" one of the best movies I have seen. "Ghosts Of Mississippi" deserved an Oscar in every single category that one can be given in because it was that good. I never knew the story of Medgar Evers before I saw this film; but, I learned a lot through watching the film. I hope everyone has the same experience and opportunity I had when I saw this movie because it is one history lesson that should be seen rather than read in history books or newspaper archives. I was truly honored to watch this film. There are several reasons this film is a success; one of them are the performances. "Ghosts Of Mississippi" is each actors best film of their career bar none. Alec Baldwin brings intensity, aggressiveness and never say die attitude to his role as Bobby DeLaughter. Whoopi Goldberg stars as Myrlie Evers, widow of Medgar Evers, who with relentless pursuit of justice re-opens this murder case. Finally, James Woods stars as Byron De La Beckwith, the defendant, who with great conviction and sincerity brings the essence of the real person to the surface. As great as Baldwin and Woods are in this they do not hold a candle to Goldberg who gives not only the best performance in the film, year but I dare say the best performance of the decade of the 90's. Known for her comedic roles in the "Sister Act" series, Goldberg turns dramatic for "Ghosts Of Mississippi." This is a very impressive turn and most likely her best dramatic role since "The Color Purple." The intense and aggressive style Golberg brought to her role as the widowed Mrs. Evers was beautiful to watch. The second reason why this film remains on my short list of best films are the messages that brought up. For example, equality for all and the fact that any discrimination will not be tolerated under any circumstances. Another message I got from this film was under no circumstances should anybody underestimate the power of tenacity because it will make dreams come true every time. This film was thought-provoking, brilliant, inspiring and compelling. In addition, "Ghosts Of Mississippi" will move you to tears, put a smile on your face and anger you because these are the emotions I felt watching this movie. Combined with the excellent ensemble performances, brilliant script and messages this film had "Ghosts Of Mississippi" is one film you can't miss. There will most certainly be other inspirational films that come along, but "Ghosts Of The Mississippi" still remains at the top of my list as one of the most inspiring films I've seen. Two thumbs way up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
