<filme>
 <id>
  1138
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118702
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  At&eacute; Que O Crime Nos Separe
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The film opens with 4 tuxedo clad men showing up at a penitentiary to meet a friend who has just been released after three years in prison and is going straight from the jail to marry his ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  The film opens with 4 tuxedo clad men showing up at a penitentiary to meet a friend who has just been released after three years in prison and is going straight from the jail to marry his girl friend. En route to the wedding, one of the men asks to stop by a bank to pick up some cash. As it turns out, he is a wanted bank robber who uses Shakespeare passages during his robberies and thus has become known as "Hamlet". Soon all five men are caught up in the bank and involved in the robbery as they end up in a hostage situation. The hostage negotiator shows up who turns out to be Hamlet's father. As the men are all known to those being robbed, this quirky comedy takes a left turn as their hostages all work to support the men.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   friendship
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   high school friends
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   title directed by female
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   shootout
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   siege
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Tamra Davis
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Art Edler Brown
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Tracy Fraim
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Dean Cain
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Andy Dick
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Sean Patrick Flanery
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Black Comedy With A Punch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A black comedy is one of those movie genres that is often hard to pull off successfully because it must be able to be funny and dramatic and sad without diminishing any one of them. And unlike contemporary dramadies, a black comedy truly is a art in itself. In Best Men, the balance is accomplished through comedic inference and avoidance of anything really over the top and the inclusion of serious heart wrenching pain that is both funny and sad. Thelma & Louise (1991), Bonnie & Clyde (1967), Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid (1969) retain the comic and dramatic themes, yet Best Men is more of an ensemble effort. What is fascinating here is that Dean Cain land the starring role (noted mostly from his television role starring in Lois & Clark: The New Adventures of Superman which series ended with the simultaneous release of this movie and only prolific starring roles in B-rated movies and television spots) while acting besides more well known actors Luke Wilson (whose career begin close to the release of this movie) and Drew Barrymore (who had established herself by 1992 in Poison Ivy). Sean Patrick Flanery (who also co-starred in Simply Irresistible (1999), a co-star, also has a rather lengthy acting history similar to as Dean Cain. Brad Dourif as a war veteran also turns in a slightly off character in a memorable role (and comes in with an extensive film acting career both before and after this movie was released). Perhaps the closest contemporary film that could have some comparison and built upon the smooth black comedy genre might be Tropic Thunder (2008).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Men: Not Half Bad but...Not Half Good Either.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happipuppi13
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some movies so bad,that when you watch them on video or TV,you wonder, "Why did they bother with this?" "Why didn't they shelve it?" That's what I wondered when I caught this unoriginal,clich&eacute;' filled movie on late night TV. The first hour of this movie (including commercials) is truly a mess and completely unbelievable. While I can see the possibility of a man getting out of jail and going to his waiting bride, I could not buy how he and his friends end up helping their buddy "Hamlet" (Billy)in the bank and keeping their fellow towns-people hostage. Even more ridiculous is that because the guys are "nice",they end up basically helping them too. Dean Cain is really the only convincing male actor of the five (at least in the first 1/2). Although his coming out of the bank,with guns blazing is just plain stupid,along with the fact that he's wearing guns under his tuxedo in the first place. Andy Dick seems to only be able to play one character his whole career,a strange,nerdy kind of Matthew from "News Radio" boy-man. He really has no place here and his "tell off the wife over the phone" scene has been done way too many times in movies and TV shows,it's completely unoriginal. As is most of this blatant small town rip-off of "Dog Day Afternoon" (which they at least acknowledge their ripping off). We get a sheriff who's the father of wanted criminal "Hamlet". We also get the clich&eacute;' of the crowd cheering for "Hamlet" like he's some kind of Robin Hood folk hero! "I went to high school with that guy!" Says one of them,then they're chanting "Hamlet" over & over. So,we get the "you we're never there for me dad" plot,which has also been done in movies TV shows. Which made it hard to be sympathetic,but not just in that case,I couldn't sympathize with any of these characters. Even after finding out about their personal downfalls. The Vietnam vet is so much a cartoon that what could have been a great character is wasted. As are the acting talents of Drew Barrymore. Her presence in all this is spread quite thin. Then there's the expected FBI converging on the town,with the leader who just wants to blast the bad guys away. He and the sheriff are of course at at odds with each other and the other big city FBI men make fun of the small town's people. "They should be used to shot gun weddings here." (Referring to Barrymore and her boyfriend wanting to get married in the middle of a hostage situation.) I really only got into the movie when the more truthful and real elements came into play. When Andy is the first to get shot and then the FBI shooting up Cain and "Hamlet's" get away bus in a scene somewhat similar to the ending of Clint Eastwood's,"The Gauntlet". "Hamlet" and father make amends just before that and Dad let's his son get away. (Oh please!) Then the final two biggest rip off's of all. Barrymore and soon to be husband are given the stolen money by "Hamlet" and they fly of in the Vietnam Vet's helicopter and escape scott free. Shades of "D.B. Cooper"! Dean Cain and "Hamlet" then have one bullet each in their guns after the bus crashes and their all shot up. Just like the final scene in "Butch Cassidy and The Sundance Kid" they come running out together and Cain takes down the leader of the FBI,who he swore he'd take out. All the supposed "reasons" these characters have for letting themselves into this mess are contrived and flimsy at best. I would say if this movie had been made a long time ago and had there not been "Dog Day Afternoon",it might seem more plausible but even the intense last half,which did hold my interest,is not enough to like this movie. Four stars for the final,intense attempted getaway chase scene and "Hamlet's" very well spoken Shakespearian quotes,which do fit in here and the movie thankfully taking a needed turn into reality. Otheriwse,I'd never bother with "Best Men" again. (END)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruce-gerard
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my personal favorites. This great movie symbolizes camaraderie, and defines friendship on a new level. Love, life, and a lasting impact. This movie has it all. Dean Cain plays a bada**, who just happens to be gay. While coming terms with that, he's confronted with his friends personal demons as well. Sean Patrick Flannery invokes his Shakespearean side, and takes his role to heart. Andy Dick's 'quirkiness' adds a comical side, while Drew Barrymore graces the film with her beauty. Luke Wilson, also plays an excellent role, especially seeing as how he was relatively unknown when this movie was made. His cool demeanor, and mellowness provide 'quiet professional' aspect to the motley crew that make up these band of friends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why so under-rated and unpopular?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xxihottie21
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I would recommend seeing the movie before reading any of the comments posted on this page. If you are thinking of posting a comment, read the comments of other people to get a sturdy point of view and opinion. I would definitely love to meet one of the main characters in the movie Best Men. Dean Cain played Sergeant Buzz Thomas (might I add that he is so incredibly cute!). You probably know him from his role as Superman in Lois and Clark. Best Men is about four guys who get involved in a bank robbery after their friend Billy Phillips (Sean Patrick Flanery) decides to hold up a bank to grab cash for Jesse Reilly's (Luke Wilson) wedding present. Billy uses quotes from Shakespeare's Hamlet during his robberies, earning the nickname Hamlet. Drew Barrymore plays a small but important part as Hope, the bride-to-be. Teddy Pollack (Andy Dick) adds a funny and somewhat unique twist to the movie. Best Men has it's action scenes, but is mainly a comedy that gradually turns into a drama. The characters are flawless, great performance from all the actors. I have read some of the other comments on this movie, and have to agree that I was also disappointed when I found out that Cain's character was gay. I also realized, though, that if he was not gay, he most likely would have taken the role of a sex-driven man. The movie was straight forward, and did not need a distraction. Also, some comments are complaining about the stupidity of the characters. If there weren't parts of the movie where the characters did idiotic things, there wouldn't be much suspense as to where that action would lead them. There seems to be an argument between comments about the genre of the film. A film does not have to be one type, it is actually much better if it is composed of mixed feelings, which is definitely what Best Men imposes. This movie was most likely not intended to be a really action-filled movie, a really tragic one, or one that you will laugh about for the next week. It is a light combination of all three. Watching it a couple times will also help you understand the dialog between the beginning and the end. A lot of what is said shows up in another part of the movie. Overall, a must-see. Best Men definitely gives you a new perspective on shotgun weddings and comedy/action films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a hidden pearl in the cheap movie bin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GoddessArtemis85
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My friend bought this movie out of the $5 bin at Walmart for a laugh. I was just expecting a stupid, mindless romantic comedy. What I found was a brilliant piece of work. The script is quite impressive. The story actually focuses on the "Best Men" like it says, not on the bride and groom. The whole film is chock full of lovable (and not so lovable) vibrant characters from nerdy little Teddy to Billy, the classical romantic hero, to Buzz the top-notch soldier with a heart of gold to Sol the lawyer you don't want to trust. Why had I never heard of this movie before?!? This definitely deserves a place on the shelf for anyone who loves comedy and good writing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't be fooled by the cast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    D C
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a train wreck. Watching the opening credits the audience is granted some manner of false hope; Wilson, Cain, Flanery, Dick, Ward, and Barrymore...not to mention direction from the talented Tamra Davis. Add in music by Mark Mothersbaugh and you might think you were in for a really entertaining hour and a half. You'd be wrong. Instead this is 90 minutes of your life you'll be wishing you had back. This movie fails miserably in spite of its passable cast. The script is miserable tripe, with each member of this derelict wedding party recounting their own unique story, one more clich&eacute; than the next. The supporting cast features a bevy of film stereotypes; the distant father, the crazy veteran, the villainous FBI agent...even a black security guard named after a ball player! How embarrassing. Beyond the bad script, sub par performances, weak story, and average direction, Best Men never really decides where it wants to go. Comedy, dark comedy, action-adventure, drama; as it flounders it never achieves any of these goals. Don't be fooled by the stars, this is grade A loser not worthy of its cast or its director.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hamlet or Robin Hood?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jotix100
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Best Men" probably looked better as a film project when all the people behind it were discussing how to bring it to the screen at a meeting at the Polo Lounge, perhaps. Having admired Tamra Davis films before, most notably, "Guncrazy", we decided to take a look. A sad mistake. This is a movie that has taken its ideas from other, better made films. The result is a mess. The film doesn't work as a black comedy. We don't believe for a moment there are people like this anywhere, but obviously, it seems to be the case. The talents of some of the actors in "Best Men" are totally wasted by a screen play that is as phony as a three dollar bill. The idea of watching the charismatic Drew Barrymore goes out the window because she is only seen in a couple of scenes. The DVD should be a good present to give for Christmas to all those people on your s*#t list. It certainly would make a statement!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A love story with enough action to keep the guys happy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edtay
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great movie..it has comedy, drama, unexpected events, love and real interaction among friends..people you know slightly and total strangers who interact and mesh well in the storyline. Good cast; and for all of you Dean Cain fans, he shows a buff chest. Drew adds an interesting twist to the bride-to-be. Luke Wilson is again great in his role, he gives real depth to his role. The male stars interact like they actually know their roles and the little quirks in their relationships just seems to draw you more into the story and Drew is believable as the bride to be and has a friendship with each of the 5 male stars. I seldom recommend movies, but this is definitely one I plan on seeing a few times just because it was written so well I know I probably missed a few things the first time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its an okay movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Devin (d_e_v_i_n-1)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Summary written by John Sacksteder {jsackste@bellsouth.net}: The film opens with 4 tuxedo clad men showing up at a penitentiary to meet a friend (Luke Wilson) who has just been released after three years in prison and is going straight from the jail to marry his girl friend (Drew Barrymore). En route to the wedding, one of the men (Sean Patrick Flanery) asks to stop by a bank to pick up some cash. As it turns out, he is a wanted bank robber who uses Shakespeare passages during his robberies and thus has become known as "Hamlet". Soon all five men are caught up in the bank and involved in the robbery as they end up in a hostage situation. The hostage negotiator (Fred Ward) shows up who turns out to be Hamlet's father. As the men are all known to those being robbed, this quirky comedy takes a left turn as their hostages all work to support the men. And thats that, there is really no point in seeing this. But if you cant sleep and its on t.v, its good enough to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK comedy-drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Libretio
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    BEST MEN Aspect ratio: 2.39:1 Sound format: Dolby Digital Tamra Davis' OK comedy-drama toplines Sean Patrick Flanery (POWDER) as a Shakespeare-spouting bank robber whose latest heist goes spectacularly awry when a group of his closest friends (Dean Cain, Luke Wilson, Andy Dick and Mitchell Whitfield) stumble into the very same bank whilst on their way to Wilson's wedding, obliging them to join forces with Flanery and take staff and customers hostage as the building is besieged by trigger-happy cops. Raymond J. Barry is the hard-nosed FBI agent who takes charge of the situation from sheriff Fred Ward (playing Flanery's estranged father!), employing heavy-handed methods which ultimately threaten the lives of everyone in the immediate area. Narrative parallels with DOG DAY AFTERNOON are acknowledged in the dialogue (there's also a hint of THELMA & LOUISE, and a significant dollop of BUTCH CASSIDY AND THE SUNDANCE KID), but Davis and her scriptwriters (Art Edler Brown and Tracy Fraim) forego heavy drama for a light-hearted examination of friendship under duress, at least until the climactic showdown, when events take a slightly darker turn. Nicely played by an experienced cast, the movie takes time to establish a roster of likable characters, particularly Cain as an ex-Green Beret whose dreams of a military career were shattered when the Army discharged him for being gay, and Brad Dourif as one of the hostages, a fiercely loyal Vietnam vet whose own Army service ended when he dared to question his superiors' ethics. Drew Barrymore gets lost in the mix as Wilson's bride-to-be, left standing at the altar following his involvement in the heist, but Flanery excels as the benevolent bank robber who steals from the rich and distributes his gains amongst local orphanages; his recitals from "Hamlet" are a highlight of the picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Black Comedy With A Punch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A black comedy is one of those movie genres that is often hard to pull off successfully because it must be able to be funny and dramatic and sad without diminishing any one of them. And unlike contemporary dramadies, a black comedy truly is a art in itself. In Best Men, the balance is accomplished through comedic inference and avoidance of anything really over the top and the inclusion of serious heart wrenching pain that is both funny and sad. Thelma & Louise (1991), Bonnie & Clyde (1967), Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid (1969) retain the comic and dramatic themes, yet Best Men is more of an ensemble effort. What is fascinating here is that Dean Cain land the starring role (noted mostly from his television role starring in Lois & Clark: The New Adventures of Superman which series ended with the simultaneous release of this movie and only prolific starring roles in B-rated movies and television spots) while acting besides more well known actors Luke Wilson (whose career begin close to the release of this movie) and Drew Barrymore (who had established herself by 1992 in Poison Ivy). Sean Patrick Flanery (who also co-starred in Simply Irresistible (1999), a co-star, also has a rather lengthy acting history similar to as Dean Cain. Brad Dourif as a war veteran also turns in a slightly off character in a memorable role (and comes in with an extensive film acting career both before and after this movie was released). Perhaps the closest contemporary film that could have some comparison and built upon the smooth black comedy genre might be Tropic Thunder (2008).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Men: Not Half Bad but...Not Half Good Either.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happipuppi13
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some movies so bad,that when you watch them on video or TV,you wonder, "Why did they bother with this?" "Why didn't they shelve it?" That's what I wondered when I caught this unoriginal,clich&eacute;' filled movie on late night TV. The first hour of this movie (including commercials) is truly a mess and completely unbelievable. While I can see the possibility of a man getting out of jail and going to his waiting bride, I could not buy how he and his friends end up helping their buddy "Hamlet" (Billy)in the bank and keeping their fellow towns-people hostage. Even more ridiculous is that because the guys are "nice",they end up basically helping them too. Dean Cain is really the only convincing male actor of the five (at least in the first 1/2). Although his coming out of the bank,with guns blazing is just plain stupid,along with the fact that he's wearing guns under his tuxedo in the first place. Andy Dick seems to only be able to play one character his whole career,a strange,nerdy kind of Matthew from "News Radio" boy-man. He really has no place here and his "tell off the wife over the phone" scene has been done way too many times in movies and TV shows,it's completely unoriginal. As is most of this blatant small town rip-off of "Dog Day Afternoon" (which they at least acknowledge their ripping off). We get a sheriff who's the father of wanted criminal "Hamlet". We also get the clich&eacute;' of the crowd cheering for "Hamlet" like he's some kind of Robin Hood folk hero! "I went to high school with that guy!" Says one of them,then they're chanting "Hamlet" over & over. So,we get the "you we're never there for me dad" plot,which has also been done in movies TV shows. Which made it hard to be sympathetic,but not just in that case,I couldn't sympathize with any of these characters. Even after finding out about their personal downfalls. The Vietnam vet is so much a cartoon that what could have been a great character is wasted. As are the acting talents of Drew Barrymore. Her presence in all this is spread quite thin. Then there's the expected FBI converging on the town,with the leader who just wants to blast the bad guys away. He and the sheriff are of course at at odds with each other and the other big city FBI men make fun of the small town's people. "They should be used to shot gun weddings here." (Referring to Barrymore and her boyfriend wanting to get married in the middle of a hostage situation.) I really only got into the movie when the more truthful and real elements came into play. When Andy is the first to get shot and then the FBI shooting up Cain and "Hamlet's" get away bus in a scene somewhat similar to the ending of Clint Eastwood's,"The Gauntlet". "Hamlet" and father make amends just before that and Dad let's his son get away. (Oh please!) Then the final two biggest rip off's of all. Barrymore and soon to be husband are given the stolen money by "Hamlet" and they fly of in the Vietnam Vet's helicopter and escape scott free. Shades of "D.B. Cooper"! Dean Cain and "Hamlet" then have one bullet each in their guns after the bus crashes and their all shot up. Just like the final scene in "Butch Cassidy and The Sundance Kid" they come running out together and Cain takes down the leader of the FBI,who he swore he'd take out. All the supposed "reasons" these characters have for letting themselves into this mess are contrived and flimsy at best. I would say if this movie had been made a long time ago and had there not been "Dog Day Afternoon",it might seem more plausible but even the intense last half,which did hold my interest,is not enough to like this movie. Four stars for the final,intense attempted getaway chase scene and "Hamlet's" very well spoken Shakespearian quotes,which do fit in here and the movie thankfully taking a needed turn into reality. Otheriwse,I'd never bother with "Best Men" again. (END)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruce-gerard
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my personal favorites. This great movie symbolizes camaraderie, and defines friendship on a new level. Love, life, and a lasting impact. This movie has it all. Dean Cain plays a bada**, who just happens to be gay. While coming terms with that, he's confronted with his friends personal demons as well. Sean Patrick Flannery invokes his Shakespearean side, and takes his role to heart. Andy Dick's 'quirkiness' adds a comical side, while Drew Barrymore graces the film with her beauty. Luke Wilson, also plays an excellent role, especially seeing as how he was relatively unknown when this movie was made. His cool demeanor, and mellowness provide 'quiet professional' aspect to the motley crew that make up these band of friends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why so under-rated and unpopular?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xxihottie21
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I would recommend seeing the movie before reading any of the comments posted on this page. If you are thinking of posting a comment, read the comments of other people to get a sturdy point of view and opinion. I would definitely love to meet one of the main characters in the movie Best Men. Dean Cain played Sergeant Buzz Thomas (might I add that he is so incredibly cute!). You probably know him from his role as Superman in Lois and Clark. Best Men is about four guys who get involved in a bank robbery after their friend Billy Phillips (Sean Patrick Flanery) decides to hold up a bank to grab cash for Jesse Reilly's (Luke Wilson) wedding present. Billy uses quotes from Shakespeare's Hamlet during his robberies, earning the nickname Hamlet. Drew Barrymore plays a small but important part as Hope, the bride-to-be. Teddy Pollack (Andy Dick) adds a funny and somewhat unique twist to the movie. Best Men has it's action scenes, but is mainly a comedy that gradually turns into a drama. The characters are flawless, great performance from all the actors. I have read some of the other comments on this movie, and have to agree that I was also disappointed when I found out that Cain's character was gay. I also realized, though, that if he was not gay, he most likely would have taken the role of a sex-driven man. The movie was straight forward, and did not need a distraction. Also, some comments are complaining about the stupidity of the characters. If there weren't parts of the movie where the characters did idiotic things, there wouldn't be much suspense as to where that action would lead them. There seems to be an argument between comments about the genre of the film. A film does not have to be one type, it is actually much better if it is composed of mixed feelings, which is definitely what Best Men imposes. This movie was most likely not intended to be a really action-filled movie, a really tragic one, or one that you will laugh about for the next week. It is a light combination of all three. Watching it a couple times will also help you understand the dialog between the beginning and the end. A lot of what is said shows up in another part of the movie. Overall, a must-see. Best Men definitely gives you a new perspective on shotgun weddings and comedy/action films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a hidden pearl in the cheap movie bin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GoddessArtemis85
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My friend bought this movie out of the $5 bin at Walmart for a laugh. I was just expecting a stupid, mindless romantic comedy. What I found was a brilliant piece of work. The script is quite impressive. The story actually focuses on the "Best Men" like it says, not on the bride and groom. The whole film is chock full of lovable (and not so lovable) vibrant characters from nerdy little Teddy to Billy, the classical romantic hero, to Buzz the top-notch soldier with a heart of gold to Sol the lawyer you don't want to trust. Why had I never heard of this movie before?!? This definitely deserves a place on the shelf for anyone who loves comedy and good writing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't be fooled by the cast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    D C
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a train wreck. Watching the opening credits the audience is granted some manner of false hope; Wilson, Cain, Flanery, Dick, Ward, and Barrymore...not to mention direction from the talented Tamra Davis. Add in music by Mark Mothersbaugh and you might think you were in for a really entertaining hour and a half. You'd be wrong. Instead this is 90 minutes of your life you'll be wishing you had back. This movie fails miserably in spite of its passable cast. The script is miserable tripe, with each member of this derelict wedding party recounting their own unique story, one more clich&eacute; than the next. The supporting cast features a bevy of film stereotypes; the distant father, the crazy veteran, the villainous FBI agent...even a black security guard named after a ball player! How embarrassing. Beyond the bad script, sub par performances, weak story, and average direction, Best Men never really decides where it wants to go. Comedy, dark comedy, action-adventure, drama; as it flounders it never achieves any of these goals. Don't be fooled by the stars, this is grade A loser not worthy of its cast or its director.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hamlet or Robin Hood?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jotix100
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Best Men" probably looked better as a film project when all the people behind it were discussing how to bring it to the screen at a meeting at the Polo Lounge, perhaps. Having admired Tamra Davis films before, most notably, "Guncrazy", we decided to take a look. A sad mistake. This is a movie that has taken its ideas from other, better made films. The result is a mess. The film doesn't work as a black comedy. We don't believe for a moment there are people like this anywhere, but obviously, it seems to be the case. The talents of some of the actors in "Best Men" are totally wasted by a screen play that is as phony as a three dollar bill. The idea of watching the charismatic Drew Barrymore goes out the window because she is only seen in a couple of scenes. The DVD should be a good present to give for Christmas to all those people on your s*#t list. It certainly would make a statement!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A love story with enough action to keep the guys happy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edtay
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great movie..it has comedy, drama, unexpected events, love and real interaction among friends..people you know slightly and total strangers who interact and mesh well in the storyline. Good cast; and for all of you Dean Cain fans, he shows a buff chest. Drew adds an interesting twist to the bride-to-be. Luke Wilson is again great in his role, he gives real depth to his role. The male stars interact like they actually know their roles and the little quirks in their relationships just seems to draw you more into the story and Drew is believable as the bride to be and has a friendship with each of the 5 male stars. I seldom recommend movies, but this is definitely one I plan on seeing a few times just because it was written so well I know I probably missed a few things the first time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its an okay movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Devin (d_e_v_i_n-1)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Summary written by John Sacksteder {jsackste@bellsouth.net}: The film opens with 4 tuxedo clad men showing up at a penitentiary to meet a friend (Luke Wilson) who has just been released after three years in prison and is going straight from the jail to marry his girl friend (Drew Barrymore). En route to the wedding, one of the men (Sean Patrick Flanery) asks to stop by a bank to pick up some cash. As it turns out, he is a wanted bank robber who uses Shakespeare passages during his robberies and thus has become known as "Hamlet". Soon all five men are caught up in the bank and involved in the robbery as they end up in a hostage situation. The hostage negotiator (Fred Ward) shows up who turns out to be Hamlet's father. As the men are all known to those being robbed, this quirky comedy takes a left turn as their hostages all work to support the men. And thats that, there is really no point in seeing this. But if you cant sleep and its on t.v, its good enough to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK comedy-drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Libretio
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    BEST MEN Aspect ratio: 2.39:1 Sound format: Dolby Digital Tamra Davis' OK comedy-drama toplines Sean Patrick Flanery (POWDER) as a Shakespeare-spouting bank robber whose latest heist goes spectacularly awry when a group of his closest friends (Dean Cain, Luke Wilson, Andy Dick and Mitchell Whitfield) stumble into the very same bank whilst on their way to Wilson's wedding, obliging them to join forces with Flanery and take staff and customers hostage as the building is besieged by trigger-happy cops. Raymond J. Barry is the hard-nosed FBI agent who takes charge of the situation from sheriff Fred Ward (playing Flanery's estranged father!), employing heavy-handed methods which ultimately threaten the lives of everyone in the immediate area. Narrative parallels with DOG DAY AFTERNOON are acknowledged in the dialogue (there's also a hint of THELMA & LOUISE, and a significant dollop of BUTCH CASSIDY AND THE SUNDANCE KID), but Davis and her scriptwriters (Art Edler Brown and Tracy Fraim) forego heavy drama for a light-hearted examination of friendship under duress, at least until the climactic showdown, when events take a slightly darker turn. Nicely played by an experienced cast, the movie takes time to establish a roster of likable characters, particularly Cain as an ex-Green Beret whose dreams of a military career were shattered when the Army discharged him for being gay, and Brad Dourif as one of the hostages, a fiercely loyal Vietnam vet whose own Army service ended when he dared to question his superiors' ethics. Drew Barrymore gets lost in the mix as Wilson's bride-to-be, left standing at the altar following his involvement in the heist, but Flanery excels as the benevolent bank robber who steals from the rich and distributes his gains amongst local orphanages; his recitals from "Hamlet" are a highlight of the picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Black Comedy With A Punch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A black comedy is one of those movie genres that is often hard to pull off successfully because it must be able to be funny and dramatic and sad without diminishing any one of them. And unlike contemporary dramadies, a black comedy truly is a art in itself. In Best Men, the balance is accomplished through comedic inference and avoidance of anything really over the top and the inclusion of serious heart wrenching pain that is both funny and sad. Thelma & Louise (1991), Bonnie & Clyde (1967), Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid (1969) retain the comic and dramatic themes, yet Best Men is more of an ensemble effort. What is fascinating here is that Dean Cain land the starring role (noted mostly from his television role starring in Lois & Clark: The New Adventures of Superman which series ended with the simultaneous release of this movie and only prolific starring roles in B-rated movies and television spots) while acting besides more well known actors Luke Wilson (whose career begin close to the release of this movie) and Drew Barrymore (who had established herself by 1992 in Poison Ivy). Sean Patrick Flanery (who also co-starred in Simply Irresistible (1999), a co-star, also has a rather lengthy acting history similar to as Dean Cain. Brad Dourif as a war veteran also turns in a slightly off character in a memorable role (and comes in with an extensive film acting career both before and after this movie was released). Perhaps the closest contemporary film that could have some comparison and built upon the smooth black comedy genre might be Tropic Thunder (2008).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Men: Not Half Bad but...Not Half Good Either.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happipuppi13
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some movies so bad,that when you watch them on video or TV,you wonder, "Why did they bother with this?" "Why didn't they shelve it?" That's what I wondered when I caught this unoriginal,clich&eacute;' filled movie on late night TV. The first hour of this movie (including commercials) is truly a mess and completely unbelievable. While I can see the possibility of a man getting out of jail and going to his waiting bride, I could not buy how he and his friends end up helping their buddy "Hamlet" (Billy)in the bank and keeping their fellow towns-people hostage. Even more ridiculous is that because the guys are "nice",they end up basically helping them too. Dean Cain is really the only convincing male actor of the five (at least in the first 1/2). Although his coming out of the bank,with guns blazing is just plain stupid,along with the fact that he's wearing guns under his tuxedo in the first place. Andy Dick seems to only be able to play one character his whole career,a strange,nerdy kind of Matthew from "News Radio" boy-man. He really has no place here and his "tell off the wife over the phone" scene has been done way too many times in movies and TV shows,it's completely unoriginal. As is most of this blatant small town rip-off of "Dog Day Afternoon" (which they at least acknowledge their ripping off). We get a sheriff who's the father of wanted criminal "Hamlet". We also get the clich&eacute;' of the crowd cheering for "Hamlet" like he's some kind of Robin Hood folk hero! "I went to high school with that guy!" Says one of them,then they're chanting "Hamlet" over & over. So,we get the "you we're never there for me dad" plot,which has also been done in movies TV shows. Which made it hard to be sympathetic,but not just in that case,I couldn't sympathize with any of these characters. Even after finding out about their personal downfalls. The Vietnam vet is so much a cartoon that what could have been a great character is wasted. As are the acting talents of Drew Barrymore. Her presence in all this is spread quite thin. Then there's the expected FBI converging on the town,with the leader who just wants to blast the bad guys away. He and the sheriff are of course at at odds with each other and the other big city FBI men make fun of the small town's people. "They should be used to shot gun weddings here." (Referring to Barrymore and her boyfriend wanting to get married in the middle of a hostage situation.) I really only got into the movie when the more truthful and real elements came into play. When Andy is the first to get shot and then the FBI shooting up Cain and "Hamlet's" get away bus in a scene somewhat similar to the ending of Clint Eastwood's,"The Gauntlet". "Hamlet" and father make amends just before that and Dad let's his son get away. (Oh please!) Then the final two biggest rip off's of all. Barrymore and soon to be husband are given the stolen money by "Hamlet" and they fly of in the Vietnam Vet's helicopter and escape scott free. Shades of "D.B. Cooper"! Dean Cain and "Hamlet" then have one bullet each in their guns after the bus crashes and their all shot up. Just like the final scene in "Butch Cassidy and The Sundance Kid" they come running out together and Cain takes down the leader of the FBI,who he swore he'd take out. All the supposed "reasons" these characters have for letting themselves into this mess are contrived and flimsy at best. I would say if this movie had been made a long time ago and had there not been "Dog Day Afternoon",it might seem more plausible but even the intense last half,which did hold my interest,is not enough to like this movie. Four stars for the final,intense attempted getaway chase scene and "Hamlet's" very well spoken Shakespearian quotes,which do fit in here and the movie thankfully taking a needed turn into reality. Otheriwse,I'd never bother with "Best Men" again. (END)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruce-gerard
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my personal favorites. This great movie symbolizes camaraderie, and defines friendship on a new level. Love, life, and a lasting impact. This movie has it all. Dean Cain plays a bada**, who just happens to be gay. While coming terms with that, he's confronted with his friends personal demons as well. Sean Patrick Flannery invokes his Shakespearean side, and takes his role to heart. Andy Dick's 'quirkiness' adds a comical side, while Drew Barrymore graces the film with her beauty. Luke Wilson, also plays an excellent role, especially seeing as how he was relatively unknown when this movie was made. His cool demeanor, and mellowness provide 'quiet professional' aspect to the motley crew that make up these band of friends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why so under-rated and unpopular?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xxihottie21
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I would recommend seeing the movie before reading any of the comments posted on this page. If you are thinking of posting a comment, read the comments of other people to get a sturdy point of view and opinion. I would definitely love to meet one of the main characters in the movie Best Men. Dean Cain played Sergeant Buzz Thomas (might I add that he is so incredibly cute!). You probably know him from his role as Superman in Lois and Clark. Best Men is about four guys who get involved in a bank robbery after their friend Billy Phillips (Sean Patrick Flanery) decides to hold up a bank to grab cash for Jesse Reilly's (Luke Wilson) wedding present. Billy uses quotes from Shakespeare's Hamlet during his robberies, earning the nickname Hamlet. Drew Barrymore plays a small but important part as Hope, the bride-to-be. Teddy Pollack (Andy Dick) adds a funny and somewhat unique twist to the movie. Best Men has it's action scenes, but is mainly a comedy that gradually turns into a drama. The characters are flawless, great performance from all the actors. I have read some of the other comments on this movie, and have to agree that I was also disappointed when I found out that Cain's character was gay. I also realized, though, that if he was not gay, he most likely would have taken the role of a sex-driven man. The movie was straight forward, and did not need a distraction. Also, some comments are complaining about the stupidity of the characters. If there weren't parts of the movie where the characters did idiotic things, there wouldn't be much suspense as to where that action would lead them. There seems to be an argument between comments about the genre of the film. A film does not have to be one type, it is actually much better if it is composed of mixed feelings, which is definitely what Best Men imposes. This movie was most likely not intended to be a really action-filled movie, a really tragic one, or one that you will laugh about for the next week. It is a light combination of all three. Watching it a couple times will also help you understand the dialog between the beginning and the end. A lot of what is said shows up in another part of the movie. Overall, a must-see. Best Men definitely gives you a new perspective on shotgun weddings and comedy/action films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a hidden pearl in the cheap movie bin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GoddessArtemis85
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My friend bought this movie out of the $5 bin at Walmart for a laugh. I was just expecting a stupid, mindless romantic comedy. What I found was a brilliant piece of work. The script is quite impressive. The story actually focuses on the "Best Men" like it says, not on the bride and groom. The whole film is chock full of lovable (and not so lovable) vibrant characters from nerdy little Teddy to Billy, the classical romantic hero, to Buzz the top-notch soldier with a heart of gold to Sol the lawyer you don't want to trust. Why had I never heard of this movie before?!? This definitely deserves a place on the shelf for anyone who loves comedy and good writing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't be fooled by the cast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    D C
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a train wreck. Watching the opening credits the audience is granted some manner of false hope; Wilson, Cain, Flanery, Dick, Ward, and Barrymore...not to mention direction from the talented Tamra Davis. Add in music by Mark Mothersbaugh and you might think you were in for a really entertaining hour and a half. You'd be wrong. Instead this is 90 minutes of your life you'll be wishing you had back. This movie fails miserably in spite of its passable cast. The script is miserable tripe, with each member of this derelict wedding party recounting their own unique story, one more clich&eacute; than the next. The supporting cast features a bevy of film stereotypes; the distant father, the crazy veteran, the villainous FBI agent...even a black security guard named after a ball player! How embarrassing. Beyond the bad script, sub par performances, weak story, and average direction, Best Men never really decides where it wants to go. Comedy, dark comedy, action-adventure, drama; as it flounders it never achieves any of these goals. Don't be fooled by the stars, this is grade A loser not worthy of its cast or its director.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hamlet or Robin Hood?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jotix100
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Best Men" probably looked better as a film project when all the people behind it were discussing how to bring it to the screen at a meeting at the Polo Lounge, perhaps. Having admired Tamra Davis films before, most notably, "Guncrazy", we decided to take a look. A sad mistake. This is a movie that has taken its ideas from other, better made films. The result is a mess. The film doesn't work as a black comedy. We don't believe for a moment there are people like this anywhere, but obviously, it seems to be the case. The talents of some of the actors in "Best Men" are totally wasted by a screen play that is as phony as a three dollar bill. The idea of watching the charismatic Drew Barrymore goes out the window because she is only seen in a couple of scenes. The DVD should be a good present to give for Christmas to all those people on your s*#t list. It certainly would make a statement!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A love story with enough action to keep the guys happy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edtay
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great movie..it has comedy, drama, unexpected events, love and real interaction among friends..people you know slightly and total strangers who interact and mesh well in the storyline. Good cast; and for all of you Dean Cain fans, he shows a buff chest. Drew adds an interesting twist to the bride-to-be. Luke Wilson is again great in his role, he gives real depth to his role. The male stars interact like they actually know their roles and the little quirks in their relationships just seems to draw you more into the story and Drew is believable as the bride to be and has a friendship with each of the 5 male stars. I seldom recommend movies, but this is definitely one I plan on seeing a few times just because it was written so well I know I probably missed a few things the first time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its an okay movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Devin (d_e_v_i_n-1)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Summary written by John Sacksteder {jsackste@bellsouth.net}: The film opens with 4 tuxedo clad men showing up at a penitentiary to meet a friend (Luke Wilson) who has just been released after three years in prison and is going straight from the jail to marry his girl friend (Drew Barrymore). En route to the wedding, one of the men (Sean Patrick Flanery) asks to stop by a bank to pick up some cash. As it turns out, he is a wanted bank robber who uses Shakespeare passages during his robberies and thus has become known as "Hamlet". Soon all five men are caught up in the bank and involved in the robbery as they end up in a hostage situation. The hostage negotiator (Fred Ward) shows up who turns out to be Hamlet's father. As the men are all known to those being robbed, this quirky comedy takes a left turn as their hostages all work to support the men. And thats that, there is really no point in seeing this. But if you cant sleep and its on t.v, its good enough to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK comedy-drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Libretio
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    BEST MEN Aspect ratio: 2.39:1 Sound format: Dolby Digital Tamra Davis' OK comedy-drama toplines Sean Patrick Flanery (POWDER) as a Shakespeare-spouting bank robber whose latest heist goes spectacularly awry when a group of his closest friends (Dean Cain, Luke Wilson, Andy Dick and Mitchell Whitfield) stumble into the very same bank whilst on their way to Wilson's wedding, obliging them to join forces with Flanery and take staff and customers hostage as the building is besieged by trigger-happy cops. Raymond J. Barry is the hard-nosed FBI agent who takes charge of the situation from sheriff Fred Ward (playing Flanery's estranged father!), employing heavy-handed methods which ultimately threaten the lives of everyone in the immediate area. Narrative parallels with DOG DAY AFTERNOON are acknowledged in the dialogue (there's also a hint of THELMA & LOUISE, and a significant dollop of BUTCH CASSIDY AND THE SUNDANCE KID), but Davis and her scriptwriters (Art Edler Brown and Tracy Fraim) forego heavy drama for a light-hearted examination of friendship under duress, at least until the climactic showdown, when events take a slightly darker turn. Nicely played by an experienced cast, the movie takes time to establish a roster of likable characters, particularly Cain as an ex-Green Beret whose dreams of a military career were shattered when the Army discharged him for being gay, and Brad Dourif as one of the hostages, a fiercely loyal Vietnam vet whose own Army service ended when he dared to question his superiors' ethics. Drew Barrymore gets lost in the mix as Wilson's bride-to-be, left standing at the altar following his involvement in the heist, but Flanery excels as the benevolent bank robber who steals from the rich and distributes his gains amongst local orphanages; his recitals from "Hamlet" are a highlight of the picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Black Comedy With A Punch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A black comedy is one of those movie genres that is often hard to pull off successfully because it must be able to be funny and dramatic and sad without diminishing any one of them. And unlike contemporary dramadies, a black comedy truly is a art in itself. In Best Men, the balance is accomplished through comedic inference and avoidance of anything really over the top and the inclusion of serious heart wrenching pain that is both funny and sad. Thelma & Louise (1991), Bonnie & Clyde (1967), Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid (1969) retain the comic and dramatic themes, yet Best Men is more of an ensemble effort. What is fascinating here is that Dean Cain land the starring role (noted mostly from his television role starring in Lois & Clark: The New Adventures of Superman which series ended with the simultaneous release of this movie and only prolific starring roles in B-rated movies and television spots) while acting besides more well known actors Luke Wilson (whose career begin close to the release of this movie) and Drew Barrymore (who had established herself by 1992 in Poison Ivy). Sean Patrick Flanery (who also co-starred in Simply Irresistible (1999), a co-star, also has a rather lengthy acting history similar to as Dean Cain. Brad Dourif as a war veteran also turns in a slightly off character in a memorable role (and comes in with an extensive film acting career both before and after this movie was released). Perhaps the closest contemporary film that could have some comparison and built upon the smooth black comedy genre might be Tropic Thunder (2008).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Men: Not Half Bad but...Not Half Good Either.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happipuppi13
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some movies so bad,that when you watch them on video or TV,you wonder, "Why did they bother with this?" "Why didn't they shelve it?" That's what I wondered when I caught this unoriginal,clich&eacute;' filled movie on late night TV. The first hour of this movie (including commercials) is truly a mess and completely unbelievable. While I can see the possibility of a man getting out of jail and going to his waiting bride, I could not buy how he and his friends end up helping their buddy "Hamlet" (Billy)in the bank and keeping their fellow towns-people hostage. Even more ridiculous is that because the guys are "nice",they end up basically helping them too. Dean Cain is really the only convincing male actor of the five (at least in the first 1/2). Although his coming out of the bank,with guns blazing is just plain stupid,along with the fact that he's wearing guns under his tuxedo in the first place. Andy Dick seems to only be able to play one character his whole career,a strange,nerdy kind of Matthew from "News Radio" boy-man. He really has no place here and his "tell off the wife over the phone" scene has been done way too many times in movies and TV shows,it's completely unoriginal. As is most of this blatant small town rip-off of "Dog Day Afternoon" (which they at least acknowledge their ripping off). We get a sheriff who's the father of wanted criminal "Hamlet". We also get the clich&eacute;' of the crowd cheering for "Hamlet" like he's some kind of Robin Hood folk hero! "I went to high school with that guy!" Says one of them,then they're chanting "Hamlet" over & over. So,we get the "you we're never there for me dad" plot,which has also been done in movies TV shows. Which made it hard to be sympathetic,but not just in that case,I couldn't sympathize with any of these characters. Even after finding out about their personal downfalls. The Vietnam vet is so much a cartoon that what could have been a great character is wasted. As are the acting talents of Drew Barrymore. Her presence in all this is spread quite thin. Then there's the expected FBI converging on the town,with the leader who just wants to blast the bad guys away. He and the sheriff are of course at at odds with each other and the other big city FBI men make fun of the small town's people. "They should be used to shot gun weddings here." (Referring to Barrymore and her boyfriend wanting to get married in the middle of a hostage situation.) I really only got into the movie when the more truthful and real elements came into play. When Andy is the first to get shot and then the FBI shooting up Cain and "Hamlet's" get away bus in a scene somewhat similar to the ending of Clint Eastwood's,"The Gauntlet". "Hamlet" and father make amends just before that and Dad let's his son get away. (Oh please!) Then the final two biggest rip off's of all. Barrymore and soon to be husband are given the stolen money by "Hamlet" and they fly of in the Vietnam Vet's helicopter and escape scott free. Shades of "D.B. Cooper"! Dean Cain and "Hamlet" then have one bullet each in their guns after the bus crashes and their all shot up. Just like the final scene in "Butch Cassidy and The Sundance Kid" they come running out together and Cain takes down the leader of the FBI,who he swore he'd take out. All the supposed "reasons" these characters have for letting themselves into this mess are contrived and flimsy at best. I would say if this movie had been made a long time ago and had there not been "Dog Day Afternoon",it might seem more plausible but even the intense last half,which did hold my interest,is not enough to like this movie. Four stars for the final,intense attempted getaway chase scene and "Hamlet's" very well spoken Shakespearian quotes,which do fit in here and the movie thankfully taking a needed turn into reality. Otheriwse,I'd never bother with "Best Men" again. (END)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruce-gerard
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my personal favorites. This great movie symbolizes camaraderie, and defines friendship on a new level. Love, life, and a lasting impact. This movie has it all. Dean Cain plays a bada**, who just happens to be gay. While coming terms with that, he's confronted with his friends personal demons as well. Sean Patrick Flannery invokes his Shakespearean side, and takes his role to heart. Andy Dick's 'quirkiness' adds a comical side, while Drew Barrymore graces the film with her beauty. Luke Wilson, also plays an excellent role, especially seeing as how he was relatively unknown when this movie was made. His cool demeanor, and mellowness provide 'quiet professional' aspect to the motley crew that make up these band of friends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why so under-rated and unpopular?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xxihottie21
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I would recommend seeing the movie before reading any of the comments posted on this page. If you are thinking of posting a comment, read the comments of other people to get a sturdy point of view and opinion. I would definitely love to meet one of the main characters in the movie Best Men. Dean Cain played Sergeant Buzz Thomas (might I add that he is so incredibly cute!). You probably know him from his role as Superman in Lois and Clark. Best Men is about four guys who get involved in a bank robbery after their friend Billy Phillips (Sean Patrick Flanery) decides to hold up a bank to grab cash for Jesse Reilly's (Luke Wilson) wedding present. Billy uses quotes from Shakespeare's Hamlet during his robberies, earning the nickname Hamlet. Drew Barrymore plays a small but important part as Hope, the bride-to-be. Teddy Pollack (Andy Dick) adds a funny and somewhat unique twist to the movie. Best Men has it's action scenes, but is mainly a comedy that gradually turns into a drama. The characters are flawless, great performance from all the actors. I have read some of the other comments on this movie, and have to agree that I was also disappointed when I found out that Cain's character was gay. I also realized, though, that if he was not gay, he most likely would have taken the role of a sex-driven man. The movie was straight forward, and did not need a distraction. Also, some comments are complaining about the stupidity of the characters. If there weren't parts of the movie where the characters did idiotic things, there wouldn't be much suspense as to where that action would lead them. There seems to be an argument between comments about the genre of the film. A film does not have to be one type, it is actually much better if it is composed of mixed feelings, which is definitely what Best Men imposes. This movie was most likely not intended to be a really action-filled movie, a really tragic one, or one that you will laugh about for the next week. It is a light combination of all three. Watching it a couple times will also help you understand the dialog between the beginning and the end. A lot of what is said shows up in another part of the movie. Overall, a must-see. Best Men definitely gives you a new perspective on shotgun weddings and comedy/action films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a hidden pearl in the cheap movie bin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GoddessArtemis85
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My friend bought this movie out of the $5 bin at Walmart for a laugh. I was just expecting a stupid, mindless romantic comedy. What I found was a brilliant piece of work. The script is quite impressive. The story actually focuses on the "Best Men" like it says, not on the bride and groom. The whole film is chock full of lovable (and not so lovable) vibrant characters from nerdy little Teddy to Billy, the classical romantic hero, to Buzz the top-notch soldier with a heart of gold to Sol the lawyer you don't want to trust. Why had I never heard of this movie before?!? This definitely deserves a place on the shelf for anyone who loves comedy and good writing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't be fooled by the cast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    D C
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a train wreck. Watching the opening credits the audience is granted some manner of false hope; Wilson, Cain, Flanery, Dick, Ward, and Barrymore...not to mention direction from the talented Tamra Davis. Add in music by Mark Mothersbaugh and you might think you were in for a really entertaining hour and a half. You'd be wrong. Instead this is 90 minutes of your life you'll be wishing you had back. This movie fails miserably in spite of its passable cast. The script is miserable tripe, with each member of this derelict wedding party recounting their own unique story, one more clich&eacute; than the next. The supporting cast features a bevy of film stereotypes; the distant father, the crazy veteran, the villainous FBI agent...even a black security guard named after a ball player! How embarrassing. Beyond the bad script, sub par performances, weak story, and average direction, Best Men never really decides where it wants to go. Comedy, dark comedy, action-adventure, drama; as it flounders it never achieves any of these goals. Don't be fooled by the stars, this is grade A loser not worthy of its cast or its director.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hamlet or Robin Hood?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jotix100
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Best Men" probably looked better as a film project when all the people behind it were discussing how to bring it to the screen at a meeting at the Polo Lounge, perhaps. Having admired Tamra Davis films before, most notably, "Guncrazy", we decided to take a look. A sad mistake. This is a movie that has taken its ideas from other, better made films. The result is a mess. The film doesn't work as a black comedy. We don't believe for a moment there are people like this anywhere, but obviously, it seems to be the case. The talents of some of the actors in "Best Men" are totally wasted by a screen play that is as phony as a three dollar bill. The idea of watching the charismatic Drew Barrymore goes out the window because she is only seen in a couple of scenes. The DVD should be a good present to give for Christmas to all those people on your s*#t list. It certainly would make a statement!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A love story with enough action to keep the guys happy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edtay
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great movie..it has comedy, drama, unexpected events, love and real interaction among friends..people you know slightly and total strangers who interact and mesh well in the storyline. Good cast; and for all of you Dean Cain fans, he shows a buff chest. Drew adds an interesting twist to the bride-to-be. Luke Wilson is again great in his role, he gives real depth to his role. The male stars interact like they actually know their roles and the little quirks in their relationships just seems to draw you more into the story and Drew is believable as the bride to be and has a friendship with each of the 5 male stars. I seldom recommend movies, but this is definitely one I plan on seeing a few times just because it was written so well I know I probably missed a few things the first time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its an okay movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Devin (d_e_v_i_n-1)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Summary written by John Sacksteder {jsackste@bellsouth.net}: The film opens with 4 tuxedo clad men showing up at a penitentiary to meet a friend (Luke Wilson) who has just been released after three years in prison and is going straight from the jail to marry his girl friend (Drew Barrymore). En route to the wedding, one of the men (Sean Patrick Flanery) asks to stop by a bank to pick up some cash. As it turns out, he is a wanted bank robber who uses Shakespeare passages during his robberies and thus has become known as "Hamlet". Soon all five men are caught up in the bank and involved in the robbery as they end up in a hostage situation. The hostage negotiator (Fred Ward) shows up who turns out to be Hamlet's father. As the men are all known to those being robbed, this quirky comedy takes a left turn as their hostages all work to support the men. And thats that, there is really no point in seeing this. But if you cant sleep and its on t.v, its good enough to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK comedy-drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Libretio
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    BEST MEN Aspect ratio: 2.39:1 Sound format: Dolby Digital Tamra Davis' OK comedy-drama toplines Sean Patrick Flanery (POWDER) as a Shakespeare-spouting bank robber whose latest heist goes spectacularly awry when a group of his closest friends (Dean Cain, Luke Wilson, Andy Dick and Mitchell Whitfield) stumble into the very same bank whilst on their way to Wilson's wedding, obliging them to join forces with Flanery and take staff and customers hostage as the building is besieged by trigger-happy cops. Raymond J. Barry is the hard-nosed FBI agent who takes charge of the situation from sheriff Fred Ward (playing Flanery's estranged father!), employing heavy-handed methods which ultimately threaten the lives of everyone in the immediate area. Narrative parallels with DOG DAY AFTERNOON are acknowledged in the dialogue (there's also a hint of THELMA & LOUISE, and a significant dollop of BUTCH CASSIDY AND THE SUNDANCE KID), but Davis and her scriptwriters (Art Edler Brown and Tracy Fraim) forego heavy drama for a light-hearted examination of friendship under duress, at least until the climactic showdown, when events take a slightly darker turn. Nicely played by an experienced cast, the movie takes time to establish a roster of likable characters, particularly Cain as an ex-Green Beret whose dreams of a military career were shattered when the Army discharged him for being gay, and Brad Dourif as one of the hostages, a fiercely loyal Vietnam vet whose own Army service ended when he dared to question his superiors' ethics. Drew Barrymore gets lost in the mix as Wilson's bride-to-be, left standing at the altar following his involvement in the heist, but Flanery excels as the benevolent bank robber who steals from the rich and distributes his gains amongst local orphanages; his recitals from "Hamlet" are a highlight of the picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Black Comedy With A Punch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A black comedy is one of those movie genres that is often hard to pull off successfully because it must be able to be funny and dramatic and sad without diminishing any one of them. And unlike contemporary dramadies, a black comedy truly is a art in itself. In Best Men, the balance is accomplished through comedic inference and avoidance of anything really over the top and the inclusion of serious heart wrenching pain that is both funny and sad. Thelma & Louise (1991), Bonnie & Clyde (1967), Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid (1969) retain the comic and dramatic themes, yet Best Men is more of an ensemble effort. What is fascinating here is that Dean Cain land the starring role (noted mostly from his television role starring in Lois & Clark: The New Adventures of Superman which series ended with the simultaneous release of this movie and only prolific starring roles in B-rated movies and television spots) while acting besides more well known actors Luke Wilson (whose career begin close to the release of this movie) and Drew Barrymore (who had established herself by 1992 in Poison Ivy). Sean Patrick Flanery (who also co-starred in Simply Irresistible (1999), a co-star, also has a rather lengthy acting history similar to as Dean Cain. Brad Dourif as a war veteran also turns in a slightly off character in a memorable role (and comes in with an extensive film acting career both before and after this movie was released). Perhaps the closest contemporary film that could have some comparison and built upon the smooth black comedy genre might be Tropic Thunder (2008).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Men: Not Half Bad but...Not Half Good Either.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happipuppi13
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some movies so bad,that when you watch them on video or TV,you wonder, "Why did they bother with this?" "Why didn't they shelve it?" That's what I wondered when I caught this unoriginal,clich&eacute;' filled movie on late night TV. The first hour of this movie (including commercials) is truly a mess and completely unbelievable. While I can see the possibility of a man getting out of jail and going to his waiting bride, I could not buy how he and his friends end up helping their buddy "Hamlet" (Billy)in the bank and keeping their fellow towns-people hostage. Even more ridiculous is that because the guys are "nice",they end up basically helping them too. Dean Cain is really the only convincing male actor of the five (at least in the first 1/2). Although his coming out of the bank,with guns blazing is just plain stupid,along with the fact that he's wearing guns under his tuxedo in the first place. Andy Dick seems to only be able to play one character his whole career,a strange,nerdy kind of Matthew from "News Radio" boy-man. He really has no place here and his "tell off the wife over the phone" scene has been done way too many times in movies and TV shows,it's completely unoriginal. As is most of this blatant small town rip-off of "Dog Day Afternoon" (which they at least acknowledge their ripping off). We get a sheriff who's the father of wanted criminal "Hamlet". We also get the clich&eacute;' of the crowd cheering for "Hamlet" like he's some kind of Robin Hood folk hero! "I went to high school with that guy!" Says one of them,then they're chanting "Hamlet" over & over. So,we get the "you we're never there for me dad" plot,which has also been done in movies TV shows. Which made it hard to be sympathetic,but not just in that case,I couldn't sympathize with any of these characters. Even after finding out about their personal downfalls. The Vietnam vet is so much a cartoon that what could have been a great character is wasted. As are the acting talents of Drew Barrymore. Her presence in all this is spread quite thin. Then there's the expected FBI converging on the town,with the leader who just wants to blast the bad guys away. He and the sheriff are of course at at odds with each other and the other big city FBI men make fun of the small town's people. "They should be used to shot gun weddings here." (Referring to Barrymore and her boyfriend wanting to get married in the middle of a hostage situation.) I really only got into the movie when the more truthful and real elements came into play. When Andy is the first to get shot and then the FBI shooting up Cain and "Hamlet's" get away bus in a scene somewhat similar to the ending of Clint Eastwood's,"The Gauntlet". "Hamlet" and father make amends just before that and Dad let's his son get away. (Oh please!) Then the final two biggest rip off's of all. Barrymore and soon to be husband are given the stolen money by "Hamlet" and they fly of in the Vietnam Vet's helicopter and escape scott free. Shades of "D.B. Cooper"! Dean Cain and "Hamlet" then have one bullet each in their guns after the bus crashes and their all shot up. Just like the final scene in "Butch Cassidy and The Sundance Kid" they come running out together and Cain takes down the leader of the FBI,who he swore he'd take out. All the supposed "reasons" these characters have for letting themselves into this mess are contrived and flimsy at best. I would say if this movie had been made a long time ago and had there not been "Dog Day Afternoon",it might seem more plausible but even the intense last half,which did hold my interest,is not enough to like this movie. Four stars for the final,intense attempted getaway chase scene and "Hamlet's" very well spoken Shakespearian quotes,which do fit in here and the movie thankfully taking a needed turn into reality. Otheriwse,I'd never bother with "Best Men" again. (END)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruce-gerard
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my personal favorites. This great movie symbolizes camaraderie, and defines friendship on a new level. Love, life, and a lasting impact. This movie has it all. Dean Cain plays a bada**, who just happens to be gay. While coming terms with that, he's confronted with his friends personal demons as well. Sean Patrick Flannery invokes his Shakespearean side, and takes his role to heart. Andy Dick's 'quirkiness' adds a comical side, while Drew Barrymore graces the film with her beauty. Luke Wilson, also plays an excellent role, especially seeing as how he was relatively unknown when this movie was made. His cool demeanor, and mellowness provide 'quiet professional' aspect to the motley crew that make up these band of friends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why so under-rated and unpopular?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xxihottie21
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I would recommend seeing the movie before reading any of the comments posted on this page. If you are thinking of posting a comment, read the comments of other people to get a sturdy point of view and opinion. I would definitely love to meet one of the main characters in the movie Best Men. Dean Cain played Sergeant Buzz Thomas (might I add that he is so incredibly cute!). You probably know him from his role as Superman in Lois and Clark. Best Men is about four guys who get involved in a bank robbery after their friend Billy Phillips (Sean Patrick Flanery) decides to hold up a bank to grab cash for Jesse Reilly's (Luke Wilson) wedding present. Billy uses quotes from Shakespeare's Hamlet during his robberies, earning the nickname Hamlet. Drew Barrymore plays a small but important part as Hope, the bride-to-be. Teddy Pollack (Andy Dick) adds a funny and somewhat unique twist to the movie. Best Men has it's action scenes, but is mainly a comedy that gradually turns into a drama. The characters are flawless, great performance from all the actors. I have read some of the other comments on this movie, and have to agree that I was also disappointed when I found out that Cain's character was gay. I also realized, though, that if he was not gay, he most likely would have taken the role of a sex-driven man. The movie was straight forward, and did not need a distraction. Also, some comments are complaining about the stupidity of the characters. If there weren't parts of the movie where the characters did idiotic things, there wouldn't be much suspense as to where that action would lead them. There seems to be an argument between comments about the genre of the film. A film does not have to be one type, it is actually much better if it is composed of mixed feelings, which is definitely what Best Men imposes. This movie was most likely not intended to be a really action-filled movie, a really tragic one, or one that you will laugh about for the next week. It is a light combination of all three. Watching it a couple times will also help you understand the dialog between the beginning and the end. A lot of what is said shows up in another part of the movie. Overall, a must-see. Best Men definitely gives you a new perspective on shotgun weddings and comedy/action films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a hidden pearl in the cheap movie bin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GoddessArtemis85
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My friend bought this movie out of the $5 bin at Walmart for a laugh. I was just expecting a stupid, mindless romantic comedy. What I found was a brilliant piece of work. The script is quite impressive. The story actually focuses on the "Best Men" like it says, not on the bride and groom. The whole film is chock full of lovable (and not so lovable) vibrant characters from nerdy little Teddy to Billy, the classical romantic hero, to Buzz the top-notch soldier with a heart of gold to Sol the lawyer you don't want to trust. Why had I never heard of this movie before?!? This definitely deserves a place on the shelf for anyone who loves comedy and good writing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't be fooled by the cast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    D C
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a train wreck. Watching the opening credits the audience is granted some manner of false hope; Wilson, Cain, Flanery, Dick, Ward, and Barrymore...not to mention direction from the talented Tamra Davis. Add in music by Mark Mothersbaugh and you might think you were in for a really entertaining hour and a half. You'd be wrong. Instead this is 90 minutes of your life you'll be wishing you had back. This movie fails miserably in spite of its passable cast. The script is miserable tripe, with each member of this derelict wedding party recounting their own unique story, one more clich&eacute; than the next. The supporting cast features a bevy of film stereotypes; the distant father, the crazy veteran, the villainous FBI agent...even a black security guard named after a ball player! How embarrassing. Beyond the bad script, sub par performances, weak story, and average direction, Best Men never really decides where it wants to go. Comedy, dark comedy, action-adventure, drama; as it flounders it never achieves any of these goals. Don't be fooled by the stars, this is grade A loser not worthy of its cast or its director.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hamlet or Robin Hood?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jotix100
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Best Men" probably looked better as a film project when all the people behind it were discussing how to bring it to the screen at a meeting at the Polo Lounge, perhaps. Having admired Tamra Davis films before, most notably, "Guncrazy", we decided to take a look. A sad mistake. This is a movie that has taken its ideas from other, better made films. The result is a mess. The film doesn't work as a black comedy. We don't believe for a moment there are people like this anywhere, but obviously, it seems to be the case. The talents of some of the actors in "Best Men" are totally wasted by a screen play that is as phony as a three dollar bill. The idea of watching the charismatic Drew Barrymore goes out the window because she is only seen in a couple of scenes. The DVD should be a good present to give for Christmas to all those people on your s*#t list. It certainly would make a statement!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A love story with enough action to keep the guys happy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edtay
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great movie..it has comedy, drama, unexpected events, love and real interaction among friends..people you know slightly and total strangers who interact and mesh well in the storyline. Good cast; and for all of you Dean Cain fans, he shows a buff chest. Drew adds an interesting twist to the bride-to-be. Luke Wilson is again great in his role, he gives real depth to his role. The male stars interact like they actually know their roles and the little quirks in their relationships just seems to draw you more into the story and Drew is believable as the bride to be and has a friendship with each of the 5 male stars. I seldom recommend movies, but this is definitely one I plan on seeing a few times just because it was written so well I know I probably missed a few things the first time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its an okay movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Devin (d_e_v_i_n-1)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Summary written by John Sacksteder {jsackste@bellsouth.net}: The film opens with 4 tuxedo clad men showing up at a penitentiary to meet a friend (Luke Wilson) who has just been released after three years in prison and is going straight from the jail to marry his girl friend (Drew Barrymore). En route to the wedding, one of the men (Sean Patrick Flanery) asks to stop by a bank to pick up some cash. As it turns out, he is a wanted bank robber who uses Shakespeare passages during his robberies and thus has become known as "Hamlet". Soon all five men are caught up in the bank and involved in the robbery as they end up in a hostage situation. The hostage negotiator (Fred Ward) shows up who turns out to be Hamlet's father. As the men are all known to those being robbed, this quirky comedy takes a left turn as their hostages all work to support the men. And thats that, there is really no point in seeing this. But if you cant sleep and its on t.v, its good enough to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK comedy-drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Libretio
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    BEST MEN Aspect ratio: 2.39:1 Sound format: Dolby Digital Tamra Davis' OK comedy-drama toplines Sean Patrick Flanery (POWDER) as a Shakespeare-spouting bank robber whose latest heist goes spectacularly awry when a group of his closest friends (Dean Cain, Luke Wilson, Andy Dick and Mitchell Whitfield) stumble into the very same bank whilst on their way to Wilson's wedding, obliging them to join forces with Flanery and take staff and customers hostage as the building is besieged by trigger-happy cops. Raymond J. Barry is the hard-nosed FBI agent who takes charge of the situation from sheriff Fred Ward (playing Flanery's estranged father!), employing heavy-handed methods which ultimately threaten the lives of everyone in the immediate area. Narrative parallels with DOG DAY AFTERNOON are acknowledged in the dialogue (there's also a hint of THELMA & LOUISE, and a significant dollop of BUTCH CASSIDY AND THE SUNDANCE KID), but Davis and her scriptwriters (Art Edler Brown and Tracy Fraim) forego heavy drama for a light-hearted examination of friendship under duress, at least until the climactic showdown, when events take a slightly darker turn. Nicely played by an experienced cast, the movie takes time to establish a roster of likable characters, particularly Cain as an ex-Green Beret whose dreams of a military career were shattered when the Army discharged him for being gay, and Brad Dourif as one of the hostages, a fiercely loyal Vietnam vet whose own Army service ended when he dared to question his superiors' ethics. Drew Barrymore gets lost in the mix as Wilson's bride-to-be, left standing at the altar following his involvement in the heist, but Flanery excels as the benevolent bank robber who steals from the rich and distributes his gains amongst local orphanages; his recitals from "Hamlet" are a highlight of the picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
