<filme>
 <id>
  1143
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119256
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Jogada de Risco
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  John has lost all his money. He sits outside a diner in the desert when Sydney happens along, buys him coffee, then takes him to Reno and shows him how to get a free room without losing ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  John has lost all his money. He sits outside a diner in the desert when Sydney happens along, buys him coffee, then takes him to Reno and shows him how to get a free room without losing much money. Under Sydney's fatherly tutelage, John becomes a successful small-time professional gambler, and all is well, until he falls for Clementine, a cocktail waitress and sometimes hooker.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   money
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   waitress
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   casino
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hooker
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   gambler
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Paul Thomas Anderson
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Paul Thomas Anderson
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Philip Baker Hall
  </ator>
  <ator>
   John C. Reilly
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Gwyneth Paltrow
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The last film I needed to watch from Paul Thomas Anderson was his debut Hard Eight and it was a solid start of his illustrious career. I liked how mysterious Philip Baker Hall's character Sydney is for the most part of the film, making you always wonder what are his real intentions with John. Samuel L. Jackson, John C. Reilly and Gwyneth Paltrow give fine performances too, but none of their characters were likable or very interesting for me, so I didn't really care for them. John and Clementine make some bad and even ridiculous decisions sometimes, so it's a bit hard to feel sorry for them when things so wrong. I enjoyed the big reveal of Sydney, being an unpredictable turn of events and that was a great way to establish his real ties with John. While the ending is quite predictable and didn't have much of an impact for me, Hard Eight is still a nice effort from Paul Thomas Anderson.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    naturalistic and character driven.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carlhartwell78
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Hard Eight, first time director Paul Thomas Anderson has constructed a subtle yet powerful commentary on redemption, it's prices and ultimately, its viability. Sydney (Philip Baker Hall) is a professional gambler, we know nothing about his background for most of the film but it becomes quickly apparent that he spends most of his time in casinos (with only brief respites in dinners). At the outset he comes upon John (John C. Reilly) a down and out, apparent loser, whom Sydney takes under his wing. Sydney teaches John, first how to gain casino hospitality with very little loss and eventually mentors him in the ways of professional gambling. For the majority of the film, the intrigue lies in the fact that he seems to have no motive for doing any of this, and it only grows when Sydney seems only too willing to help Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow) out of her damaging lifestyle as well. A cocktail waitress and part time hooker, Clementine, had captured Johns affections and ultimately brings things to a head with a particularly senseless mistake. The fourth (and last) main character is Jimmy (Samuel L. Jackson), who is a friend of Johns, but who Sydney has little time for. The Film is almost entirely character driven and contains impeccable performances by all involved, indeed it has to since the plot is not nearly strong enough without them. Of course it's no bad thing that the plot isn't strong, it's not that type of film, largely any "situation" that happens isn't there for any reason other than to show how the characters react. Hall's performance is particularly impressive, chiefly since his characters motivation isn't fully revealed until about 15 minutes before the end. Despite this he carries the film majestically and one cannot help but get the sense that Sydey is significant and incredibly fascinating. No mean feat when the audience knows so little about his character. Reilly, Paltrow and Jackson's performances are commendable also, but for me, their characters serve mostly as secondary characters to Sydney's. That's not to say that they come across as anything but very three dimensional, each actor has at least one scene in which to shine and shine they do. One of the films many strengths is in it's extremely naturalistic tone, not of course uncommon in many films, but done to perfection in this one. The script constantly has all of the characters stumbling over or at a loss for words, and we're often given the impression that they're completely clueless and out of their depths, they seem like real people! Two scenes in particular stand out as testament to this, the motel room scene and the car scene towards the end with Jackson and Hall. Both are so realistic that one can imagine they were hardly scripted at all. The film, though perhaps not a masterpiece, is extremely good and upon it's release, demonstrated great promise in it's director, who of course went on to direct the sublime Magnolia. It entices the viewer to contemplate the very idea of forgiveness. To what extent does a persons past affect how we perceive him, are some acts truly irredeemable?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Haunting, Poignant & Tense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The unusual circumstances in which two men meet before going on to become good friends, provides "Hard Eight" with an intriguing opening to a story which also features kidnapping, blackmail and a brutal killing. First-time director/writer Paul Thomas Anderson takes time and care to develop his characters and this approach pays off handsomely, as it's the strength of these characters and the relationships between them that ultimately make this movie so interesting and memorable. The tense atmosphere and deliberate pacing, which are established right from the start, create a closeness between the two men and also add emphasis to the anxieties and suspicions that are present between them, especially during their first meeting. As he approaches a roadside diner somewhere in Nevada, Sydney Brown (Philip Baker Hall), a professional gambler in his sixties, sees a young man who's clearly down-on-his-luck sitting on the ground close to the entrance of the building. He offers to buy him a cup of coffee and give him a cigarette. Sydney soon learns that John (John C Reilly) has lost all his money whilst gambling in an attempt to raise enough cash to pay for his mother's funeral. Sydney offers to show the young man how to be successful in the casinos and despite his understandable scepticism, John agrees. A couple of years later, John has prospered as Sydney's prot&eacute;g&eacute; and after having paid off his mother's funeral costs, gets married to an attractive cocktail waitress called Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow). John has also become friendly with Jimmy (Samuel L Jackson) who's a security officer and a man that Sydney dislikes and really doesn't trust. Clementine's part-time work as a hooker leads to trouble when one of her clients refuses to pay and she and John keep the man hostage in their motel room. Sydney is called to help them out and soon takes control of the situation but also runs into bigger trouble shortly after, when Jimmy threatens and blackmails him. Philip Baker Hall gives a top class performance as the lonely, well dressed, experienced gambler with a face that's filled with sadness and lines. He's dignified and shrewd and looks as if he's been through some tough experiences but also finds it gratifying to help John out. John is another lonely person who appreciates the progress he's made under Sydney's guidance but his poor judgement and gullibility will clearly make it impossible for him to ever fully emulate his mentor's success. John C Reilly, in a consistently strong performance, is very natural and convincing in the way that he portrays John's naivety and impetuosity. Clementine is not as streetwise as she needs to be and Gwyneth Paltrow conveys her character's underlying sadness very effectively. Samuel L Jackson is also on great form as the violent thug who totally underestimates Sydney. "Hard Eight" is haunting and poignant and its overall tone and tempo is perfect for a movie in which a dark secret, hidden motives and a need for redemption affect so much of what takes place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazingly accomplished debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red_Identity
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's be clear. This is 2013 and I've seen all of Anderson's other films. While this is probably his weakest (although it's hard to say weakest when they are all great) it's still astonishing how accomplished it feels. You could tell from this film the filmmaker that Anderson would go on to become, and with just six films he's already one of my 5 all-time favorites. The whole cast here is solid, but Baker is amazing in his role, not very spoken, his motivations always ambiguous. Anderson isn't here to spell out everything, and instead the film plays out very nicely and smoothly. Great accomplishment, and it's also fun seeing Philip Seymour Hoffman in his great little cameo
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to Watch, but...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RabbitValleyRebel
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I adore and respect the opening scene. All stories need to start somewhere, and this one started with style, in a setting that most of us have frequented...a Denny's Restaurant basically. Throughout the film, we are made acutely aware of the precious value of food, a bed, coffee, cigarettes, cable movies, and companionship, for someone who has been deprived these things before. Most of us probably take them for granted,unless we have been down-and-out like one of the film's protagonists. But think about how relieved you feel on a long road trip, when you stop at a motel, and partake of these things, after being trapped in your car for hours. They satiate us and bring a sense of domestic tranquility. I needed more character development. Sorry, to those who loved this film. I get the fact that it was a portrayal of "outsider" life and the casino-bubble, but I still needed to know a bit more about how these people became who they are. The plot device of not knowing why the hell Hall is being a caretaker, worked for a while, but eventually I became annoyed with guessing. The final explanation was anti-climatic and cheap. Come on, you can do better than that. Hoffman stole the show with his very brief cameo. Jackson was his usual profane loudmouth stereotype. Hall and Reilly did not have to stretch much, but they were still quite adept at portraying unspoken sadness. I'm not a fan of Paltrow, but she conveyed the torn nature of her character quite well. One other reviewer mentioned the fact that sometimes the characters don't know what to say, but that made it realistic. I totally agree. Real people rarely speak like movie characters. But in this one, the characters did speak like real people. Great job with that. There were enough good aspects to this film, to make it worth seeing. But it is a labor to watch after a while, because not much happens, and not much is said. If you like art films, you will probably like this one. It reminded me of the work of Jim Jarmusch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Smashing Debut For P.T. Anderson.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Paul Thomas Anderson comes his directorial debut, that movie is his 1996 movie known as Hard Eight. And is this movie any good? I'll tell you right now, this movie is a smashing movie, it's greatly acted, greatly written, and greatly directed. Paul Thomas Anderson is a director who does all of his own screen writing, he was only 26 when me made this movie, and not only did he direct it, but he also wrote the screenplay for it, and he wrote it singlehandedly. This movie tells the story of a gambler who meets a young man and makes him an offer to make money, and during the course of this journey, the two men are drawn close to each other in what becomes a father and son relationship, however, events put the relationship in jeopardy. Paul Thomas Anderson tells the story pretty straight forward, the story involves success, romance, setbacks, and numerous other things, all while keeping the viewer focused on what is going on. I really admire P.T. Anderson for writing all of his own screenplays, because there aren't many directors who singlehandedly write their own scripts and manage to stay good. As usual in a P.T. Anderson film, the acting is Oscar-Worthy. Phillip Baker Hall is outstanding as Sydney, the gambler who makes the offer to John C. Reilly's character. John C. Reilly's performance was wonderful too, as where the performances of Gwyneth Paltrow and Samuel L. Jackson. However, if I had to say who's performance in this movie was the best, that would be none other than Phillip Baker Hall. Phillip Baker Hall's performance was worthy of a nomination for the Academy Award for Best Actor, he was in a class by himself. And just think, after this movie, Paul Thomas Anderson would direct five more movies that would receive all sorts of acclaim, Boogie Nights, Magnolia, Punch-Drunk Love, There Will Be Blood, and his most recent movie, The Master. Hard Eight marked the start of greatness for a master film director and screenwriter, Paul Thomas Anderson, who is one of the best directors and screenwriters in recent years. This is a movie that you have got to see if you haven't seen it yet, as it is the film that made Paul Thomas Anderson famous, and it's worth seeing for the wonderful performances from the cast. It makes me so happy that there are actually people out there who still do care about making great movies, as nowadays, we get a lot of rubbish with nonstop explosions and too many flashy special effects and not to mention a lot of CGI. But every now and then, there are directors like Martin Scorsese, The Coen Brothers, and of course, Paul Thomas Anderson, who actually do care about making movies the way that movies are supposed to be made. Well anyway, Hard Eight is an outstanding masterpiece, if you've yet to see this movie, then all I can say is that you've definitely got to see it, because you will say exactly what many people have said already, that this movie is the outstanding writing and directorial debut of a master. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard Eight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Paul Thomas Anderson (Boogie Nights, Magnolia, There Will Be Blood), this was a film I would obviously have never heard of unless it was broadcast on television, and it looked interesting because of an impressive cast list, and was likely to be an independent film, so I was up for trying it. Basically Sydney (Bruce Almighty's Philip Baker Hall) is a sixty year old gamble, who outside a diner meets young man John (John C. Reilly) and offers him a cigarette, then a coffee, and then the opportunity to make the money that he needs for his mother's burial, this would mean travelling to Las Vegas and learning ways of making the money and getting by. After some scepticism John agrees, and he follows the advice of his new friend, and two years later John has the money that he needed for the funeral, he has become Sydney's prot&eacute;g&eacute; staying in Reno, and he has made himself a friend in security worker Jimmy (Samuel L. Jackson), and he is also attracted to and dating cocktail waitress Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow). Late one night Sydney gets a frantic phone call from John, and at the motel he is staying in with Clementine he finds they have kidnapped a man and held him hostage because he wouldn't pay Clementine for her prostitution, and the situation is a little worse because John and Clementine got married. The situation is resolved in some way by Sydney, but he advises the newlyweds to get away and go on a honeymoon, he suggests Niagara Falls, and after they do leave Sydney is confronted by Jimmy who is demanding money in blackmail because he knows a secret that the sixty year old doesn't want to come out, this is that Sydney killed John's father. The old man gives in and pays him the money, but he later goes late at night into Jimmy's house to shoot him dead, and the end sees him return to the diner where he first met John, brushing the blood off his shirt cuff, it is unclear whether his friends finds out the dark secret he has. Also starring F. William Parker as Hostage and Philip Seymour Hoffman as Young Craps Player. Normally a character or supporting actor Baker Hall is actually a good choice as the elderly lead character because he is a wise presence, Reilly is likable as the slow but nice guy that wants to get somewhere in life, and Paltrow does pretty well as the promiscuous woman who is caught in the middle of situations, the story is simple enough, it could have used a bit more action, or the scripting could have tweaked to be wittier and with more pace, but it isn't too bad of a film debut from Anderson, a not bad crime drama. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quirky and confident - decent debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie starts of with the silent and reserved Sydney (Philip Baker Hall) entering a roadside cafeteria, where he comes across a down-trodden John (John C. Reilly). Sydney takes a strong interest in John, where he attempts to offer the younger man solutions to his problems by offering his key services: the talents of a professional gambler. After this encounter John ties himself to the old dog and becomes his prot&eacute;g&eacute;. A few years down the line John finds a love interest in Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow), waitress / part-time hooker, which in turn initiates a sequence of events that change the nature of the relationship between the two men. American cinema loves its cars, its gangsters and its gambling, while art-house delves passionately into quirkiness. I for one never really found inspiration or admiration to either of the mentioned themes. "Hard Eight" dabbles with two of them: gambling with a touch of quirky characters. Nonetheless the story does prove emotionally involving to some level, although underdone and at times hollow or open-ended. The latter is in part due to the restrained character development and jumpy plotting, which delivers us to required locations, but ignores opportunities to connect the dots. Basically "Hard Eight" (in almost Tarantinesque fashion) concentrated the movie around several key scenes, full of emotional full, content and a decent amount of talking, while the rest of the scenes are subservient and essentially meaningless filler. The sell of the story heavily lies on Philip Baker Hall's shoulders, as he does his job excellently with a even-handed, but scene-grabbing, performance. Nonetheless not a thoroughly involving and passable debut (full of beginner's jitters) by the great Paul Thomas Anderson, which nonetheless shows his qualities as a director, especially in regards to actor interaction. Some of the cinematography was questionable and slightly amateurish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent debut for Anderson, but it's not quite there
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Paul Thomas Anderson's debut shows off some of his talent - the excellent work he drives out of character actors in lead parts, effective atmosphere creation and great camera work. Hard Eight doesn't have the spark of There Will Be Blood, Magnolia or Boogie Nights, though, and the script feels half-baked; as a result, the fantastic actors do a great job with very flat characters, and neither them nor the story holds any interest. The effect of this, ironically, is that the film's best scene is a five-minute nameless cameo by Philip Seymour Hoffman. Not surprising that he's had the most impressive career of these actors, while Philip Baker Hall is still to all intents and purposes Detective Bookman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well thought out character study
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    superokapi
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    PT Anderson's first film is a good one, it may be low budget but it packs a quartet of gripping performances. Many people may look at this and think it is an action/crime movie but it is not. This film is a study of a man reaching out in guilt to help others and of the consequences when his prot&eacute;g&eacute; makes some poor friends. The best character in this film to watch is Sydney himself as the kind of man who has been doing the same thing for the last umpteen years and realizes he needs to make an impact in someone's life to make his life worthwhile. Baker Hall's performance is scene stealing, and he takes a character who uses subtle gestures and queues to make a point and lets him dominate the other characters with it. Much credit must be given to Anderson's screenplay for it's ear for character not plot driven dialogue, much like Tarantino, Anderson lets anecdotes and quips reveal details and traits of his characters. My personal favourite scene was the scene in the beginning when Sydney meets John's new friends and is able to read them both like books all without interrogation style questions. This film is worthwhile and rewarding, a good choice for a person who likes thoughtful dialogue and engaging characters.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The last film I needed to watch from Paul Thomas Anderson was his debut Hard Eight and it was a solid start of his illustrious career. I liked how mysterious Philip Baker Hall's character Sydney is for the most part of the film, making you always wonder what are his real intentions with John. Samuel L. Jackson, John C. Reilly and Gwyneth Paltrow give fine performances too, but none of their characters were likable or very interesting for me, so I didn't really care for them. John and Clementine make some bad and even ridiculous decisions sometimes, so it's a bit hard to feel sorry for them when things so wrong. I enjoyed the big reveal of Sydney, being an unpredictable turn of events and that was a great way to establish his real ties with John. While the ending is quite predictable and didn't have much of an impact for me, Hard Eight is still a nice effort from Paul Thomas Anderson.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    naturalistic and character driven.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carlhartwell78
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Hard Eight, first time director Paul Thomas Anderson has constructed a subtle yet powerful commentary on redemption, it's prices and ultimately, its viability. Sydney (Philip Baker Hall) is a professional gambler, we know nothing about his background for most of the film but it becomes quickly apparent that he spends most of his time in casinos (with only brief respites in dinners). At the outset he comes upon John (John C. Reilly) a down and out, apparent loser, whom Sydney takes under his wing. Sydney teaches John, first how to gain casino hospitality with very little loss and eventually mentors him in the ways of professional gambling. For the majority of the film, the intrigue lies in the fact that he seems to have no motive for doing any of this, and it only grows when Sydney seems only too willing to help Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow) out of her damaging lifestyle as well. A cocktail waitress and part time hooker, Clementine, had captured Johns affections and ultimately brings things to a head with a particularly senseless mistake. The fourth (and last) main character is Jimmy (Samuel L. Jackson), who is a friend of Johns, but who Sydney has little time for. The Film is almost entirely character driven and contains impeccable performances by all involved, indeed it has to since the plot is not nearly strong enough without them. Of course it's no bad thing that the plot isn't strong, it's not that type of film, largely any "situation" that happens isn't there for any reason other than to show how the characters react. Hall's performance is particularly impressive, chiefly since his characters motivation isn't fully revealed until about 15 minutes before the end. Despite this he carries the film majestically and one cannot help but get the sense that Sydey is significant and incredibly fascinating. No mean feat when the audience knows so little about his character. Reilly, Paltrow and Jackson's performances are commendable also, but for me, their characters serve mostly as secondary characters to Sydney's. That's not to say that they come across as anything but very three dimensional, each actor has at least one scene in which to shine and shine they do. One of the films many strengths is in it's extremely naturalistic tone, not of course uncommon in many films, but done to perfection in this one. The script constantly has all of the characters stumbling over or at a loss for words, and we're often given the impression that they're completely clueless and out of their depths, they seem like real people! Two scenes in particular stand out as testament to this, the motel room scene and the car scene towards the end with Jackson and Hall. Both are so realistic that one can imagine they were hardly scripted at all. The film, though perhaps not a masterpiece, is extremely good and upon it's release, demonstrated great promise in it's director, who of course went on to direct the sublime Magnolia. It entices the viewer to contemplate the very idea of forgiveness. To what extent does a persons past affect how we perceive him, are some acts truly irredeemable?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Haunting, Poignant & Tense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The unusual circumstances in which two men meet before going on to become good friends, provides "Hard Eight" with an intriguing opening to a story which also features kidnapping, blackmail and a brutal killing. First-time director/writer Paul Thomas Anderson takes time and care to develop his characters and this approach pays off handsomely, as it's the strength of these characters and the relationships between them that ultimately make this movie so interesting and memorable. The tense atmosphere and deliberate pacing, which are established right from the start, create a closeness between the two men and also add emphasis to the anxieties and suspicions that are present between them, especially during their first meeting. As he approaches a roadside diner somewhere in Nevada, Sydney Brown (Philip Baker Hall), a professional gambler in his sixties, sees a young man who's clearly down-on-his-luck sitting on the ground close to the entrance of the building. He offers to buy him a cup of coffee and give him a cigarette. Sydney soon learns that John (John C Reilly) has lost all his money whilst gambling in an attempt to raise enough cash to pay for his mother's funeral. Sydney offers to show the young man how to be successful in the casinos and despite his understandable scepticism, John agrees. A couple of years later, John has prospered as Sydney's prot&eacute;g&eacute; and after having paid off his mother's funeral costs, gets married to an attractive cocktail waitress called Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow). John has also become friendly with Jimmy (Samuel L Jackson) who's a security officer and a man that Sydney dislikes and really doesn't trust. Clementine's part-time work as a hooker leads to trouble when one of her clients refuses to pay and she and John keep the man hostage in their motel room. Sydney is called to help them out and soon takes control of the situation but also runs into bigger trouble shortly after, when Jimmy threatens and blackmails him. Philip Baker Hall gives a top class performance as the lonely, well dressed, experienced gambler with a face that's filled with sadness and lines. He's dignified and shrewd and looks as if he's been through some tough experiences but also finds it gratifying to help John out. John is another lonely person who appreciates the progress he's made under Sydney's guidance but his poor judgement and gullibility will clearly make it impossible for him to ever fully emulate his mentor's success. John C Reilly, in a consistently strong performance, is very natural and convincing in the way that he portrays John's naivety and impetuosity. Clementine is not as streetwise as she needs to be and Gwyneth Paltrow conveys her character's underlying sadness very effectively. Samuel L Jackson is also on great form as the violent thug who totally underestimates Sydney. "Hard Eight" is haunting and poignant and its overall tone and tempo is perfect for a movie in which a dark secret, hidden motives and a need for redemption affect so much of what takes place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazingly accomplished debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red_Identity
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's be clear. This is 2013 and I've seen all of Anderson's other films. While this is probably his weakest (although it's hard to say weakest when they are all great) it's still astonishing how accomplished it feels. You could tell from this film the filmmaker that Anderson would go on to become, and with just six films he's already one of my 5 all-time favorites. The whole cast here is solid, but Baker is amazing in his role, not very spoken, his motivations always ambiguous. Anderson isn't here to spell out everything, and instead the film plays out very nicely and smoothly. Great accomplishment, and it's also fun seeing Philip Seymour Hoffman in his great little cameo
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to Watch, but...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RabbitValleyRebel
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I adore and respect the opening scene. All stories need to start somewhere, and this one started with style, in a setting that most of us have frequented...a Denny's Restaurant basically. Throughout the film, we are made acutely aware of the precious value of food, a bed, coffee, cigarettes, cable movies, and companionship, for someone who has been deprived these things before. Most of us probably take them for granted,unless we have been down-and-out like one of the film's protagonists. But think about how relieved you feel on a long road trip, when you stop at a motel, and partake of these things, after being trapped in your car for hours. They satiate us and bring a sense of domestic tranquility. I needed more character development. Sorry, to those who loved this film. I get the fact that it was a portrayal of "outsider" life and the casino-bubble, but I still needed to know a bit more about how these people became who they are. The plot device of not knowing why the hell Hall is being a caretaker, worked for a while, but eventually I became annoyed with guessing. The final explanation was anti-climatic and cheap. Come on, you can do better than that. Hoffman stole the show with his very brief cameo. Jackson was his usual profane loudmouth stereotype. Hall and Reilly did not have to stretch much, but they were still quite adept at portraying unspoken sadness. I'm not a fan of Paltrow, but she conveyed the torn nature of her character quite well. One other reviewer mentioned the fact that sometimes the characters don't know what to say, but that made it realistic. I totally agree. Real people rarely speak like movie characters. But in this one, the characters did speak like real people. Great job with that. There were enough good aspects to this film, to make it worth seeing. But it is a labor to watch after a while, because not much happens, and not much is said. If you like art films, you will probably like this one. It reminded me of the work of Jim Jarmusch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Smashing Debut For P.T. Anderson.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Paul Thomas Anderson comes his directorial debut, that movie is his 1996 movie known as Hard Eight. And is this movie any good? I'll tell you right now, this movie is a smashing movie, it's greatly acted, greatly written, and greatly directed. Paul Thomas Anderson is a director who does all of his own screen writing, he was only 26 when me made this movie, and not only did he direct it, but he also wrote the screenplay for it, and he wrote it singlehandedly. This movie tells the story of a gambler who meets a young man and makes him an offer to make money, and during the course of this journey, the two men are drawn close to each other in what becomes a father and son relationship, however, events put the relationship in jeopardy. Paul Thomas Anderson tells the story pretty straight forward, the story involves success, romance, setbacks, and numerous other things, all while keeping the viewer focused on what is going on. I really admire P.T. Anderson for writing all of his own screenplays, because there aren't many directors who singlehandedly write their own scripts and manage to stay good. As usual in a P.T. Anderson film, the acting is Oscar-Worthy. Phillip Baker Hall is outstanding as Sydney, the gambler who makes the offer to John C. Reilly's character. John C. Reilly's performance was wonderful too, as where the performances of Gwyneth Paltrow and Samuel L. Jackson. However, if I had to say who's performance in this movie was the best, that would be none other than Phillip Baker Hall. Phillip Baker Hall's performance was worthy of a nomination for the Academy Award for Best Actor, he was in a class by himself. And just think, after this movie, Paul Thomas Anderson would direct five more movies that would receive all sorts of acclaim, Boogie Nights, Magnolia, Punch-Drunk Love, There Will Be Blood, and his most recent movie, The Master. Hard Eight marked the start of greatness for a master film director and screenwriter, Paul Thomas Anderson, who is one of the best directors and screenwriters in recent years. This is a movie that you have got to see if you haven't seen it yet, as it is the film that made Paul Thomas Anderson famous, and it's worth seeing for the wonderful performances from the cast. It makes me so happy that there are actually people out there who still do care about making great movies, as nowadays, we get a lot of rubbish with nonstop explosions and too many flashy special effects and not to mention a lot of CGI. But every now and then, there are directors like Martin Scorsese, The Coen Brothers, and of course, Paul Thomas Anderson, who actually do care about making movies the way that movies are supposed to be made. Well anyway, Hard Eight is an outstanding masterpiece, if you've yet to see this movie, then all I can say is that you've definitely got to see it, because you will say exactly what many people have said already, that this movie is the outstanding writing and directorial debut of a master. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard Eight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Paul Thomas Anderson (Boogie Nights, Magnolia, There Will Be Blood), this was a film I would obviously have never heard of unless it was broadcast on television, and it looked interesting because of an impressive cast list, and was likely to be an independent film, so I was up for trying it. Basically Sydney (Bruce Almighty's Philip Baker Hall) is a sixty year old gamble, who outside a diner meets young man John (John C. Reilly) and offers him a cigarette, then a coffee, and then the opportunity to make the money that he needs for his mother's burial, this would mean travelling to Las Vegas and learning ways of making the money and getting by. After some scepticism John agrees, and he follows the advice of his new friend, and two years later John has the money that he needed for the funeral, he has become Sydney's prot&eacute;g&eacute; staying in Reno, and he has made himself a friend in security worker Jimmy (Samuel L. Jackson), and he is also attracted to and dating cocktail waitress Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow). Late one night Sydney gets a frantic phone call from John, and at the motel he is staying in with Clementine he finds they have kidnapped a man and held him hostage because he wouldn't pay Clementine for her prostitution, and the situation is a little worse because John and Clementine got married. The situation is resolved in some way by Sydney, but he advises the newlyweds to get away and go on a honeymoon, he suggests Niagara Falls, and after they do leave Sydney is confronted by Jimmy who is demanding money in blackmail because he knows a secret that the sixty year old doesn't want to come out, this is that Sydney killed John's father. The old man gives in and pays him the money, but he later goes late at night into Jimmy's house to shoot him dead, and the end sees him return to the diner where he first met John, brushing the blood off his shirt cuff, it is unclear whether his friends finds out the dark secret he has. Also starring F. William Parker as Hostage and Philip Seymour Hoffman as Young Craps Player. Normally a character or supporting actor Baker Hall is actually a good choice as the elderly lead character because he is a wise presence, Reilly is likable as the slow but nice guy that wants to get somewhere in life, and Paltrow does pretty well as the promiscuous woman who is caught in the middle of situations, the story is simple enough, it could have used a bit more action, or the scripting could have tweaked to be wittier and with more pace, but it isn't too bad of a film debut from Anderson, a not bad crime drama. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quirky and confident - decent debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie starts of with the silent and reserved Sydney (Philip Baker Hall) entering a roadside cafeteria, where he comes across a down-trodden John (John C. Reilly). Sydney takes a strong interest in John, where he attempts to offer the younger man solutions to his problems by offering his key services: the talents of a professional gambler. After this encounter John ties himself to the old dog and becomes his prot&eacute;g&eacute;. A few years down the line John finds a love interest in Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow), waitress / part-time hooker, which in turn initiates a sequence of events that change the nature of the relationship between the two men. American cinema loves its cars, its gangsters and its gambling, while art-house delves passionately into quirkiness. I for one never really found inspiration or admiration to either of the mentioned themes. "Hard Eight" dabbles with two of them: gambling with a touch of quirky characters. Nonetheless the story does prove emotionally involving to some level, although underdone and at times hollow or open-ended. The latter is in part due to the restrained character development and jumpy plotting, which delivers us to required locations, but ignores opportunities to connect the dots. Basically "Hard Eight" (in almost Tarantinesque fashion) concentrated the movie around several key scenes, full of emotional full, content and a decent amount of talking, while the rest of the scenes are subservient and essentially meaningless filler. The sell of the story heavily lies on Philip Baker Hall's shoulders, as he does his job excellently with a even-handed, but scene-grabbing, performance. Nonetheless not a thoroughly involving and passable debut (full of beginner's jitters) by the great Paul Thomas Anderson, which nonetheless shows his qualities as a director, especially in regards to actor interaction. Some of the cinematography was questionable and slightly amateurish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent debut for Anderson, but it's not quite there
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Paul Thomas Anderson's debut shows off some of his talent - the excellent work he drives out of character actors in lead parts, effective atmosphere creation and great camera work. Hard Eight doesn't have the spark of There Will Be Blood, Magnolia or Boogie Nights, though, and the script feels half-baked; as a result, the fantastic actors do a great job with very flat characters, and neither them nor the story holds any interest. The effect of this, ironically, is that the film's best scene is a five-minute nameless cameo by Philip Seymour Hoffman. Not surprising that he's had the most impressive career of these actors, while Philip Baker Hall is still to all intents and purposes Detective Bookman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well thought out character study
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    superokapi
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    PT Anderson's first film is a good one, it may be low budget but it packs a quartet of gripping performances. Many people may look at this and think it is an action/crime movie but it is not. This film is a study of a man reaching out in guilt to help others and of the consequences when his prot&eacute;g&eacute; makes some poor friends. The best character in this film to watch is Sydney himself as the kind of man who has been doing the same thing for the last umpteen years and realizes he needs to make an impact in someone's life to make his life worthwhile. Baker Hall's performance is scene stealing, and he takes a character who uses subtle gestures and queues to make a point and lets him dominate the other characters with it. Much credit must be given to Anderson's screenplay for it's ear for character not plot driven dialogue, much like Tarantino, Anderson lets anecdotes and quips reveal details and traits of his characters. My personal favourite scene was the scene in the beginning when Sydney meets John's new friends and is able to read them both like books all without interrogation style questions. This film is worthwhile and rewarding, a good choice for a person who likes thoughtful dialogue and engaging characters.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The last film I needed to watch from Paul Thomas Anderson was his debut Hard Eight and it was a solid start of his illustrious career. I liked how mysterious Philip Baker Hall's character Sydney is for the most part of the film, making you always wonder what are his real intentions with John. Samuel L. Jackson, John C. Reilly and Gwyneth Paltrow give fine performances too, but none of their characters were likable or very interesting for me, so I didn't really care for them. John and Clementine make some bad and even ridiculous decisions sometimes, so it's a bit hard to feel sorry for them when things so wrong. I enjoyed the big reveal of Sydney, being an unpredictable turn of events and that was a great way to establish his real ties with John. While the ending is quite predictable and didn't have much of an impact for me, Hard Eight is still a nice effort from Paul Thomas Anderson.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    naturalistic and character driven.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carlhartwell78
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Hard Eight, first time director Paul Thomas Anderson has constructed a subtle yet powerful commentary on redemption, it's prices and ultimately, its viability. Sydney (Philip Baker Hall) is a professional gambler, we know nothing about his background for most of the film but it becomes quickly apparent that he spends most of his time in casinos (with only brief respites in dinners). At the outset he comes upon John (John C. Reilly) a down and out, apparent loser, whom Sydney takes under his wing. Sydney teaches John, first how to gain casino hospitality with very little loss and eventually mentors him in the ways of professional gambling. For the majority of the film, the intrigue lies in the fact that he seems to have no motive for doing any of this, and it only grows when Sydney seems only too willing to help Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow) out of her damaging lifestyle as well. A cocktail waitress and part time hooker, Clementine, had captured Johns affections and ultimately brings things to a head with a particularly senseless mistake. The fourth (and last) main character is Jimmy (Samuel L. Jackson), who is a friend of Johns, but who Sydney has little time for. The Film is almost entirely character driven and contains impeccable performances by all involved, indeed it has to since the plot is not nearly strong enough without them. Of course it's no bad thing that the plot isn't strong, it's not that type of film, largely any "situation" that happens isn't there for any reason other than to show how the characters react. Hall's performance is particularly impressive, chiefly since his characters motivation isn't fully revealed until about 15 minutes before the end. Despite this he carries the film majestically and one cannot help but get the sense that Sydey is significant and incredibly fascinating. No mean feat when the audience knows so little about his character. Reilly, Paltrow and Jackson's performances are commendable also, but for me, their characters serve mostly as secondary characters to Sydney's. That's not to say that they come across as anything but very three dimensional, each actor has at least one scene in which to shine and shine they do. One of the films many strengths is in it's extremely naturalistic tone, not of course uncommon in many films, but done to perfection in this one. The script constantly has all of the characters stumbling over or at a loss for words, and we're often given the impression that they're completely clueless and out of their depths, they seem like real people! Two scenes in particular stand out as testament to this, the motel room scene and the car scene towards the end with Jackson and Hall. Both are so realistic that one can imagine they were hardly scripted at all. The film, though perhaps not a masterpiece, is extremely good and upon it's release, demonstrated great promise in it's director, who of course went on to direct the sublime Magnolia. It entices the viewer to contemplate the very idea of forgiveness. To what extent does a persons past affect how we perceive him, are some acts truly irredeemable?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Haunting, Poignant & Tense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The unusual circumstances in which two men meet before going on to become good friends, provides "Hard Eight" with an intriguing opening to a story which also features kidnapping, blackmail and a brutal killing. First-time director/writer Paul Thomas Anderson takes time and care to develop his characters and this approach pays off handsomely, as it's the strength of these characters and the relationships between them that ultimately make this movie so interesting and memorable. The tense atmosphere and deliberate pacing, which are established right from the start, create a closeness between the two men and also add emphasis to the anxieties and suspicions that are present between them, especially during their first meeting. As he approaches a roadside diner somewhere in Nevada, Sydney Brown (Philip Baker Hall), a professional gambler in his sixties, sees a young man who's clearly down-on-his-luck sitting on the ground close to the entrance of the building. He offers to buy him a cup of coffee and give him a cigarette. Sydney soon learns that John (John C Reilly) has lost all his money whilst gambling in an attempt to raise enough cash to pay for his mother's funeral. Sydney offers to show the young man how to be successful in the casinos and despite his understandable scepticism, John agrees. A couple of years later, John has prospered as Sydney's prot&eacute;g&eacute; and after having paid off his mother's funeral costs, gets married to an attractive cocktail waitress called Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow). John has also become friendly with Jimmy (Samuel L Jackson) who's a security officer and a man that Sydney dislikes and really doesn't trust. Clementine's part-time work as a hooker leads to trouble when one of her clients refuses to pay and she and John keep the man hostage in their motel room. Sydney is called to help them out and soon takes control of the situation but also runs into bigger trouble shortly after, when Jimmy threatens and blackmails him. Philip Baker Hall gives a top class performance as the lonely, well dressed, experienced gambler with a face that's filled with sadness and lines. He's dignified and shrewd and looks as if he's been through some tough experiences but also finds it gratifying to help John out. John is another lonely person who appreciates the progress he's made under Sydney's guidance but his poor judgement and gullibility will clearly make it impossible for him to ever fully emulate his mentor's success. John C Reilly, in a consistently strong performance, is very natural and convincing in the way that he portrays John's naivety and impetuosity. Clementine is not as streetwise as she needs to be and Gwyneth Paltrow conveys her character's underlying sadness very effectively. Samuel L Jackson is also on great form as the violent thug who totally underestimates Sydney. "Hard Eight" is haunting and poignant and its overall tone and tempo is perfect for a movie in which a dark secret, hidden motives and a need for redemption affect so much of what takes place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazingly accomplished debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red_Identity
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's be clear. This is 2013 and I've seen all of Anderson's other films. While this is probably his weakest (although it's hard to say weakest when they are all great) it's still astonishing how accomplished it feels. You could tell from this film the filmmaker that Anderson would go on to become, and with just six films he's already one of my 5 all-time favorites. The whole cast here is solid, but Baker is amazing in his role, not very spoken, his motivations always ambiguous. Anderson isn't here to spell out everything, and instead the film plays out very nicely and smoothly. Great accomplishment, and it's also fun seeing Philip Seymour Hoffman in his great little cameo
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to Watch, but...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RabbitValleyRebel
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I adore and respect the opening scene. All stories need to start somewhere, and this one started with style, in a setting that most of us have frequented...a Denny's Restaurant basically. Throughout the film, we are made acutely aware of the precious value of food, a bed, coffee, cigarettes, cable movies, and companionship, for someone who has been deprived these things before. Most of us probably take them for granted,unless we have been down-and-out like one of the film's protagonists. But think about how relieved you feel on a long road trip, when you stop at a motel, and partake of these things, after being trapped in your car for hours. They satiate us and bring a sense of domestic tranquility. I needed more character development. Sorry, to those who loved this film. I get the fact that it was a portrayal of "outsider" life and the casino-bubble, but I still needed to know a bit more about how these people became who they are. The plot device of not knowing why the hell Hall is being a caretaker, worked for a while, but eventually I became annoyed with guessing. The final explanation was anti-climatic and cheap. Come on, you can do better than that. Hoffman stole the show with his very brief cameo. Jackson was his usual profane loudmouth stereotype. Hall and Reilly did not have to stretch much, but they were still quite adept at portraying unspoken sadness. I'm not a fan of Paltrow, but she conveyed the torn nature of her character quite well. One other reviewer mentioned the fact that sometimes the characters don't know what to say, but that made it realistic. I totally agree. Real people rarely speak like movie characters. But in this one, the characters did speak like real people. Great job with that. There were enough good aspects to this film, to make it worth seeing. But it is a labor to watch after a while, because not much happens, and not much is said. If you like art films, you will probably like this one. It reminded me of the work of Jim Jarmusch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Smashing Debut For P.T. Anderson.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Paul Thomas Anderson comes his directorial debut, that movie is his 1996 movie known as Hard Eight. And is this movie any good? I'll tell you right now, this movie is a smashing movie, it's greatly acted, greatly written, and greatly directed. Paul Thomas Anderson is a director who does all of his own screen writing, he was only 26 when me made this movie, and not only did he direct it, but he also wrote the screenplay for it, and he wrote it singlehandedly. This movie tells the story of a gambler who meets a young man and makes him an offer to make money, and during the course of this journey, the two men are drawn close to each other in what becomes a father and son relationship, however, events put the relationship in jeopardy. Paul Thomas Anderson tells the story pretty straight forward, the story involves success, romance, setbacks, and numerous other things, all while keeping the viewer focused on what is going on. I really admire P.T. Anderson for writing all of his own screenplays, because there aren't many directors who singlehandedly write their own scripts and manage to stay good. As usual in a P.T. Anderson film, the acting is Oscar-Worthy. Phillip Baker Hall is outstanding as Sydney, the gambler who makes the offer to John C. Reilly's character. John C. Reilly's performance was wonderful too, as where the performances of Gwyneth Paltrow and Samuel L. Jackson. However, if I had to say who's performance in this movie was the best, that would be none other than Phillip Baker Hall. Phillip Baker Hall's performance was worthy of a nomination for the Academy Award for Best Actor, he was in a class by himself. And just think, after this movie, Paul Thomas Anderson would direct five more movies that would receive all sorts of acclaim, Boogie Nights, Magnolia, Punch-Drunk Love, There Will Be Blood, and his most recent movie, The Master. Hard Eight marked the start of greatness for a master film director and screenwriter, Paul Thomas Anderson, who is one of the best directors and screenwriters in recent years. This is a movie that you have got to see if you haven't seen it yet, as it is the film that made Paul Thomas Anderson famous, and it's worth seeing for the wonderful performances from the cast. It makes me so happy that there are actually people out there who still do care about making great movies, as nowadays, we get a lot of rubbish with nonstop explosions and too many flashy special effects and not to mention a lot of CGI. But every now and then, there are directors like Martin Scorsese, The Coen Brothers, and of course, Paul Thomas Anderson, who actually do care about making movies the way that movies are supposed to be made. Well anyway, Hard Eight is an outstanding masterpiece, if you've yet to see this movie, then all I can say is that you've definitely got to see it, because you will say exactly what many people have said already, that this movie is the outstanding writing and directorial debut of a master. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard Eight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Paul Thomas Anderson (Boogie Nights, Magnolia, There Will Be Blood), this was a film I would obviously have never heard of unless it was broadcast on television, and it looked interesting because of an impressive cast list, and was likely to be an independent film, so I was up for trying it. Basically Sydney (Bruce Almighty's Philip Baker Hall) is a sixty year old gamble, who outside a diner meets young man John (John C. Reilly) and offers him a cigarette, then a coffee, and then the opportunity to make the money that he needs for his mother's burial, this would mean travelling to Las Vegas and learning ways of making the money and getting by. After some scepticism John agrees, and he follows the advice of his new friend, and two years later John has the money that he needed for the funeral, he has become Sydney's prot&eacute;g&eacute; staying in Reno, and he has made himself a friend in security worker Jimmy (Samuel L. Jackson), and he is also attracted to and dating cocktail waitress Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow). Late one night Sydney gets a frantic phone call from John, and at the motel he is staying in with Clementine he finds they have kidnapped a man and held him hostage because he wouldn't pay Clementine for her prostitution, and the situation is a little worse because John and Clementine got married. The situation is resolved in some way by Sydney, but he advises the newlyweds to get away and go on a honeymoon, he suggests Niagara Falls, and after they do leave Sydney is confronted by Jimmy who is demanding money in blackmail because he knows a secret that the sixty year old doesn't want to come out, this is that Sydney killed John's father. The old man gives in and pays him the money, but he later goes late at night into Jimmy's house to shoot him dead, and the end sees him return to the diner where he first met John, brushing the blood off his shirt cuff, it is unclear whether his friends finds out the dark secret he has. Also starring F. William Parker as Hostage and Philip Seymour Hoffman as Young Craps Player. Normally a character or supporting actor Baker Hall is actually a good choice as the elderly lead character because he is a wise presence, Reilly is likable as the slow but nice guy that wants to get somewhere in life, and Paltrow does pretty well as the promiscuous woman who is caught in the middle of situations, the story is simple enough, it could have used a bit more action, or the scripting could have tweaked to be wittier and with more pace, but it isn't too bad of a film debut from Anderson, a not bad crime drama. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quirky and confident - decent debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie starts of with the silent and reserved Sydney (Philip Baker Hall) entering a roadside cafeteria, where he comes across a down-trodden John (John C. Reilly). Sydney takes a strong interest in John, where he attempts to offer the younger man solutions to his problems by offering his key services: the talents of a professional gambler. After this encounter John ties himself to the old dog and becomes his prot&eacute;g&eacute;. A few years down the line John finds a love interest in Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow), waitress / part-time hooker, which in turn initiates a sequence of events that change the nature of the relationship between the two men. American cinema loves its cars, its gangsters and its gambling, while art-house delves passionately into quirkiness. I for one never really found inspiration or admiration to either of the mentioned themes. "Hard Eight" dabbles with two of them: gambling with a touch of quirky characters. Nonetheless the story does prove emotionally involving to some level, although underdone and at times hollow or open-ended. The latter is in part due to the restrained character development and jumpy plotting, which delivers us to required locations, but ignores opportunities to connect the dots. Basically "Hard Eight" (in almost Tarantinesque fashion) concentrated the movie around several key scenes, full of emotional full, content and a decent amount of talking, while the rest of the scenes are subservient and essentially meaningless filler. The sell of the story heavily lies on Philip Baker Hall's shoulders, as he does his job excellently with a even-handed, but scene-grabbing, performance. Nonetheless not a thoroughly involving and passable debut (full of beginner's jitters) by the great Paul Thomas Anderson, which nonetheless shows his qualities as a director, especially in regards to actor interaction. Some of the cinematography was questionable and slightly amateurish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent debut for Anderson, but it's not quite there
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Paul Thomas Anderson's debut shows off some of his talent - the excellent work he drives out of character actors in lead parts, effective atmosphere creation and great camera work. Hard Eight doesn't have the spark of There Will Be Blood, Magnolia or Boogie Nights, though, and the script feels half-baked; as a result, the fantastic actors do a great job with very flat characters, and neither them nor the story holds any interest. The effect of this, ironically, is that the film's best scene is a five-minute nameless cameo by Philip Seymour Hoffman. Not surprising that he's had the most impressive career of these actors, while Philip Baker Hall is still to all intents and purposes Detective Bookman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well thought out character study
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    superokapi
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    PT Anderson's first film is a good one, it may be low budget but it packs a quartet of gripping performances. Many people may look at this and think it is an action/crime movie but it is not. This film is a study of a man reaching out in guilt to help others and of the consequences when his prot&eacute;g&eacute; makes some poor friends. The best character in this film to watch is Sydney himself as the kind of man who has been doing the same thing for the last umpteen years and realizes he needs to make an impact in someone's life to make his life worthwhile. Baker Hall's performance is scene stealing, and he takes a character who uses subtle gestures and queues to make a point and lets him dominate the other characters with it. Much credit must be given to Anderson's screenplay for it's ear for character not plot driven dialogue, much like Tarantino, Anderson lets anecdotes and quips reveal details and traits of his characters. My personal favourite scene was the scene in the beginning when Sydney meets John's new friends and is able to read them both like books all without interrogation style questions. This film is worthwhile and rewarding, a good choice for a person who likes thoughtful dialogue and engaging characters.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The last film I needed to watch from Paul Thomas Anderson was his debut Hard Eight and it was a solid start of his illustrious career. I liked how mysterious Philip Baker Hall's character Sydney is for the most part of the film, making you always wonder what are his real intentions with John. Samuel L. Jackson, John C. Reilly and Gwyneth Paltrow give fine performances too, but none of their characters were likable or very interesting for me, so I didn't really care for them. John and Clementine make some bad and even ridiculous decisions sometimes, so it's a bit hard to feel sorry for them when things so wrong. I enjoyed the big reveal of Sydney, being an unpredictable turn of events and that was a great way to establish his real ties with John. While the ending is quite predictable and didn't have much of an impact for me, Hard Eight is still a nice effort from Paul Thomas Anderson.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    naturalistic and character driven.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carlhartwell78
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Hard Eight, first time director Paul Thomas Anderson has constructed a subtle yet powerful commentary on redemption, it's prices and ultimately, its viability. Sydney (Philip Baker Hall) is a professional gambler, we know nothing about his background for most of the film but it becomes quickly apparent that he spends most of his time in casinos (with only brief respites in dinners). At the outset he comes upon John (John C. Reilly) a down and out, apparent loser, whom Sydney takes under his wing. Sydney teaches John, first how to gain casino hospitality with very little loss and eventually mentors him in the ways of professional gambling. For the majority of the film, the intrigue lies in the fact that he seems to have no motive for doing any of this, and it only grows when Sydney seems only too willing to help Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow) out of her damaging lifestyle as well. A cocktail waitress and part time hooker, Clementine, had captured Johns affections and ultimately brings things to a head with a particularly senseless mistake. The fourth (and last) main character is Jimmy (Samuel L. Jackson), who is a friend of Johns, but who Sydney has little time for. The Film is almost entirely character driven and contains impeccable performances by all involved, indeed it has to since the plot is not nearly strong enough without them. Of course it's no bad thing that the plot isn't strong, it's not that type of film, largely any "situation" that happens isn't there for any reason other than to show how the characters react. Hall's performance is particularly impressive, chiefly since his characters motivation isn't fully revealed until about 15 minutes before the end. Despite this he carries the film majestically and one cannot help but get the sense that Sydey is significant and incredibly fascinating. No mean feat when the audience knows so little about his character. Reilly, Paltrow and Jackson's performances are commendable also, but for me, their characters serve mostly as secondary characters to Sydney's. That's not to say that they come across as anything but very three dimensional, each actor has at least one scene in which to shine and shine they do. One of the films many strengths is in it's extremely naturalistic tone, not of course uncommon in many films, but done to perfection in this one. The script constantly has all of the characters stumbling over or at a loss for words, and we're often given the impression that they're completely clueless and out of their depths, they seem like real people! Two scenes in particular stand out as testament to this, the motel room scene and the car scene towards the end with Jackson and Hall. Both are so realistic that one can imagine they were hardly scripted at all. The film, though perhaps not a masterpiece, is extremely good and upon it's release, demonstrated great promise in it's director, who of course went on to direct the sublime Magnolia. It entices the viewer to contemplate the very idea of forgiveness. To what extent does a persons past affect how we perceive him, are some acts truly irredeemable?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Haunting, Poignant & Tense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The unusual circumstances in which two men meet before going on to become good friends, provides "Hard Eight" with an intriguing opening to a story which also features kidnapping, blackmail and a brutal killing. First-time director/writer Paul Thomas Anderson takes time and care to develop his characters and this approach pays off handsomely, as it's the strength of these characters and the relationships between them that ultimately make this movie so interesting and memorable. The tense atmosphere and deliberate pacing, which are established right from the start, create a closeness between the two men and also add emphasis to the anxieties and suspicions that are present between them, especially during their first meeting. As he approaches a roadside diner somewhere in Nevada, Sydney Brown (Philip Baker Hall), a professional gambler in his sixties, sees a young man who's clearly down-on-his-luck sitting on the ground close to the entrance of the building. He offers to buy him a cup of coffee and give him a cigarette. Sydney soon learns that John (John C Reilly) has lost all his money whilst gambling in an attempt to raise enough cash to pay for his mother's funeral. Sydney offers to show the young man how to be successful in the casinos and despite his understandable scepticism, John agrees. A couple of years later, John has prospered as Sydney's prot&eacute;g&eacute; and after having paid off his mother's funeral costs, gets married to an attractive cocktail waitress called Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow). John has also become friendly with Jimmy (Samuel L Jackson) who's a security officer and a man that Sydney dislikes and really doesn't trust. Clementine's part-time work as a hooker leads to trouble when one of her clients refuses to pay and she and John keep the man hostage in their motel room. Sydney is called to help them out and soon takes control of the situation but also runs into bigger trouble shortly after, when Jimmy threatens and blackmails him. Philip Baker Hall gives a top class performance as the lonely, well dressed, experienced gambler with a face that's filled with sadness and lines. He's dignified and shrewd and looks as if he's been through some tough experiences but also finds it gratifying to help John out. John is another lonely person who appreciates the progress he's made under Sydney's guidance but his poor judgement and gullibility will clearly make it impossible for him to ever fully emulate his mentor's success. John C Reilly, in a consistently strong performance, is very natural and convincing in the way that he portrays John's naivety and impetuosity. Clementine is not as streetwise as she needs to be and Gwyneth Paltrow conveys her character's underlying sadness very effectively. Samuel L Jackson is also on great form as the violent thug who totally underestimates Sydney. "Hard Eight" is haunting and poignant and its overall tone and tempo is perfect for a movie in which a dark secret, hidden motives and a need for redemption affect so much of what takes place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazingly accomplished debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red_Identity
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's be clear. This is 2013 and I've seen all of Anderson's other films. While this is probably his weakest (although it's hard to say weakest when they are all great) it's still astonishing how accomplished it feels. You could tell from this film the filmmaker that Anderson would go on to become, and with just six films he's already one of my 5 all-time favorites. The whole cast here is solid, but Baker is amazing in his role, not very spoken, his motivations always ambiguous. Anderson isn't here to spell out everything, and instead the film plays out very nicely and smoothly. Great accomplishment, and it's also fun seeing Philip Seymour Hoffman in his great little cameo
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to Watch, but...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RabbitValleyRebel
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I adore and respect the opening scene. All stories need to start somewhere, and this one started with style, in a setting that most of us have frequented...a Denny's Restaurant basically. Throughout the film, we are made acutely aware of the precious value of food, a bed, coffee, cigarettes, cable movies, and companionship, for someone who has been deprived these things before. Most of us probably take them for granted,unless we have been down-and-out like one of the film's protagonists. But think about how relieved you feel on a long road trip, when you stop at a motel, and partake of these things, after being trapped in your car for hours. They satiate us and bring a sense of domestic tranquility. I needed more character development. Sorry, to those who loved this film. I get the fact that it was a portrayal of "outsider" life and the casino-bubble, but I still needed to know a bit more about how these people became who they are. The plot device of not knowing why the hell Hall is being a caretaker, worked for a while, but eventually I became annoyed with guessing. The final explanation was anti-climatic and cheap. Come on, you can do better than that. Hoffman stole the show with his very brief cameo. Jackson was his usual profane loudmouth stereotype. Hall and Reilly did not have to stretch much, but they were still quite adept at portraying unspoken sadness. I'm not a fan of Paltrow, but she conveyed the torn nature of her character quite well. One other reviewer mentioned the fact that sometimes the characters don't know what to say, but that made it realistic. I totally agree. Real people rarely speak like movie characters. But in this one, the characters did speak like real people. Great job with that. There were enough good aspects to this film, to make it worth seeing. But it is a labor to watch after a while, because not much happens, and not much is said. If you like art films, you will probably like this one. It reminded me of the work of Jim Jarmusch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Smashing Debut For P.T. Anderson.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Paul Thomas Anderson comes his directorial debut, that movie is his 1996 movie known as Hard Eight. And is this movie any good? I'll tell you right now, this movie is a smashing movie, it's greatly acted, greatly written, and greatly directed. Paul Thomas Anderson is a director who does all of his own screen writing, he was only 26 when me made this movie, and not only did he direct it, but he also wrote the screenplay for it, and he wrote it singlehandedly. This movie tells the story of a gambler who meets a young man and makes him an offer to make money, and during the course of this journey, the two men are drawn close to each other in what becomes a father and son relationship, however, events put the relationship in jeopardy. Paul Thomas Anderson tells the story pretty straight forward, the story involves success, romance, setbacks, and numerous other things, all while keeping the viewer focused on what is going on. I really admire P.T. Anderson for writing all of his own screenplays, because there aren't many directors who singlehandedly write their own scripts and manage to stay good. As usual in a P.T. Anderson film, the acting is Oscar-Worthy. Phillip Baker Hall is outstanding as Sydney, the gambler who makes the offer to John C. Reilly's character. John C. Reilly's performance was wonderful too, as where the performances of Gwyneth Paltrow and Samuel L. Jackson. However, if I had to say who's performance in this movie was the best, that would be none other than Phillip Baker Hall. Phillip Baker Hall's performance was worthy of a nomination for the Academy Award for Best Actor, he was in a class by himself. And just think, after this movie, Paul Thomas Anderson would direct five more movies that would receive all sorts of acclaim, Boogie Nights, Magnolia, Punch-Drunk Love, There Will Be Blood, and his most recent movie, The Master. Hard Eight marked the start of greatness for a master film director and screenwriter, Paul Thomas Anderson, who is one of the best directors and screenwriters in recent years. This is a movie that you have got to see if you haven't seen it yet, as it is the film that made Paul Thomas Anderson famous, and it's worth seeing for the wonderful performances from the cast. It makes me so happy that there are actually people out there who still do care about making great movies, as nowadays, we get a lot of rubbish with nonstop explosions and too many flashy special effects and not to mention a lot of CGI. But every now and then, there are directors like Martin Scorsese, The Coen Brothers, and of course, Paul Thomas Anderson, who actually do care about making movies the way that movies are supposed to be made. Well anyway, Hard Eight is an outstanding masterpiece, if you've yet to see this movie, then all I can say is that you've definitely got to see it, because you will say exactly what many people have said already, that this movie is the outstanding writing and directorial debut of a master. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard Eight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Paul Thomas Anderson (Boogie Nights, Magnolia, There Will Be Blood), this was a film I would obviously have never heard of unless it was broadcast on television, and it looked interesting because of an impressive cast list, and was likely to be an independent film, so I was up for trying it. Basically Sydney (Bruce Almighty's Philip Baker Hall) is a sixty year old gamble, who outside a diner meets young man John (John C. Reilly) and offers him a cigarette, then a coffee, and then the opportunity to make the money that he needs for his mother's burial, this would mean travelling to Las Vegas and learning ways of making the money and getting by. After some scepticism John agrees, and he follows the advice of his new friend, and two years later John has the money that he needed for the funeral, he has become Sydney's prot&eacute;g&eacute; staying in Reno, and he has made himself a friend in security worker Jimmy (Samuel L. Jackson), and he is also attracted to and dating cocktail waitress Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow). Late one night Sydney gets a frantic phone call from John, and at the motel he is staying in with Clementine he finds they have kidnapped a man and held him hostage because he wouldn't pay Clementine for her prostitution, and the situation is a little worse because John and Clementine got married. The situation is resolved in some way by Sydney, but he advises the newlyweds to get away and go on a honeymoon, he suggests Niagara Falls, and after they do leave Sydney is confronted by Jimmy who is demanding money in blackmail because he knows a secret that the sixty year old doesn't want to come out, this is that Sydney killed John's father. The old man gives in and pays him the money, but he later goes late at night into Jimmy's house to shoot him dead, and the end sees him return to the diner where he first met John, brushing the blood off his shirt cuff, it is unclear whether his friends finds out the dark secret he has. Also starring F. William Parker as Hostage and Philip Seymour Hoffman as Young Craps Player. Normally a character or supporting actor Baker Hall is actually a good choice as the elderly lead character because he is a wise presence, Reilly is likable as the slow but nice guy that wants to get somewhere in life, and Paltrow does pretty well as the promiscuous woman who is caught in the middle of situations, the story is simple enough, it could have used a bit more action, or the scripting could have tweaked to be wittier and with more pace, but it isn't too bad of a film debut from Anderson, a not bad crime drama. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quirky and confident - decent debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie starts of with the silent and reserved Sydney (Philip Baker Hall) entering a roadside cafeteria, where he comes across a down-trodden John (John C. Reilly). Sydney takes a strong interest in John, where he attempts to offer the younger man solutions to his problems by offering his key services: the talents of a professional gambler. After this encounter John ties himself to the old dog and becomes his prot&eacute;g&eacute;. A few years down the line John finds a love interest in Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow), waitress / part-time hooker, which in turn initiates a sequence of events that change the nature of the relationship between the two men. American cinema loves its cars, its gangsters and its gambling, while art-house delves passionately into quirkiness. I for one never really found inspiration or admiration to either of the mentioned themes. "Hard Eight" dabbles with two of them: gambling with a touch of quirky characters. Nonetheless the story does prove emotionally involving to some level, although underdone and at times hollow or open-ended. The latter is in part due to the restrained character development and jumpy plotting, which delivers us to required locations, but ignores opportunities to connect the dots. Basically "Hard Eight" (in almost Tarantinesque fashion) concentrated the movie around several key scenes, full of emotional full, content and a decent amount of talking, while the rest of the scenes are subservient and essentially meaningless filler. The sell of the story heavily lies on Philip Baker Hall's shoulders, as he does his job excellently with a even-handed, but scene-grabbing, performance. Nonetheless not a thoroughly involving and passable debut (full of beginner's jitters) by the great Paul Thomas Anderson, which nonetheless shows his qualities as a director, especially in regards to actor interaction. Some of the cinematography was questionable and slightly amateurish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent debut for Anderson, but it's not quite there
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Paul Thomas Anderson's debut shows off some of his talent - the excellent work he drives out of character actors in lead parts, effective atmosphere creation and great camera work. Hard Eight doesn't have the spark of There Will Be Blood, Magnolia or Boogie Nights, though, and the script feels half-baked; as a result, the fantastic actors do a great job with very flat characters, and neither them nor the story holds any interest. The effect of this, ironically, is that the film's best scene is a five-minute nameless cameo by Philip Seymour Hoffman. Not surprising that he's had the most impressive career of these actors, while Philip Baker Hall is still to all intents and purposes Detective Bookman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well thought out character study
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    superokapi
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    PT Anderson's first film is a good one, it may be low budget but it packs a quartet of gripping performances. Many people may look at this and think it is an action/crime movie but it is not. This film is a study of a man reaching out in guilt to help others and of the consequences when his prot&eacute;g&eacute; makes some poor friends. The best character in this film to watch is Sydney himself as the kind of man who has been doing the same thing for the last umpteen years and realizes he needs to make an impact in someone's life to make his life worthwhile. Baker Hall's performance is scene stealing, and he takes a character who uses subtle gestures and queues to make a point and lets him dominate the other characters with it. Much credit must be given to Anderson's screenplay for it's ear for character not plot driven dialogue, much like Tarantino, Anderson lets anecdotes and quips reveal details and traits of his characters. My personal favourite scene was the scene in the beginning when Sydney meets John's new friends and is able to read them both like books all without interrogation style questions. This film is worthwhile and rewarding, a good choice for a person who likes thoughtful dialogue and engaging characters.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The last film I needed to watch from Paul Thomas Anderson was his debut Hard Eight and it was a solid start of his illustrious career. I liked how mysterious Philip Baker Hall's character Sydney is for the most part of the film, making you always wonder what are his real intentions with John. Samuel L. Jackson, John C. Reilly and Gwyneth Paltrow give fine performances too, but none of their characters were likable or very interesting for me, so I didn't really care for them. John and Clementine make some bad and even ridiculous decisions sometimes, so it's a bit hard to feel sorry for them when things so wrong. I enjoyed the big reveal of Sydney, being an unpredictable turn of events and that was a great way to establish his real ties with John. While the ending is quite predictable and didn't have much of an impact for me, Hard Eight is still a nice effort from Paul Thomas Anderson.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    naturalistic and character driven.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carlhartwell78
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Hard Eight, first time director Paul Thomas Anderson has constructed a subtle yet powerful commentary on redemption, it's prices and ultimately, its viability. Sydney (Philip Baker Hall) is a professional gambler, we know nothing about his background for most of the film but it becomes quickly apparent that he spends most of his time in casinos (with only brief respites in dinners). At the outset he comes upon John (John C. Reilly) a down and out, apparent loser, whom Sydney takes under his wing. Sydney teaches John, first how to gain casino hospitality with very little loss and eventually mentors him in the ways of professional gambling. For the majority of the film, the intrigue lies in the fact that he seems to have no motive for doing any of this, and it only grows when Sydney seems only too willing to help Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow) out of her damaging lifestyle as well. A cocktail waitress and part time hooker, Clementine, had captured Johns affections and ultimately brings things to a head with a particularly senseless mistake. The fourth (and last) main character is Jimmy (Samuel L. Jackson), who is a friend of Johns, but who Sydney has little time for. The Film is almost entirely character driven and contains impeccable performances by all involved, indeed it has to since the plot is not nearly strong enough without them. Of course it's no bad thing that the plot isn't strong, it's not that type of film, largely any "situation" that happens isn't there for any reason other than to show how the characters react. Hall's performance is particularly impressive, chiefly since his characters motivation isn't fully revealed until about 15 minutes before the end. Despite this he carries the film majestically and one cannot help but get the sense that Sydey is significant and incredibly fascinating. No mean feat when the audience knows so little about his character. Reilly, Paltrow and Jackson's performances are commendable also, but for me, their characters serve mostly as secondary characters to Sydney's. That's not to say that they come across as anything but very three dimensional, each actor has at least one scene in which to shine and shine they do. One of the films many strengths is in it's extremely naturalistic tone, not of course uncommon in many films, but done to perfection in this one. The script constantly has all of the characters stumbling over or at a loss for words, and we're often given the impression that they're completely clueless and out of their depths, they seem like real people! Two scenes in particular stand out as testament to this, the motel room scene and the car scene towards the end with Jackson and Hall. Both are so realistic that one can imagine they were hardly scripted at all. The film, though perhaps not a masterpiece, is extremely good and upon it's release, demonstrated great promise in it's director, who of course went on to direct the sublime Magnolia. It entices the viewer to contemplate the very idea of forgiveness. To what extent does a persons past affect how we perceive him, are some acts truly irredeemable?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Haunting, Poignant & Tense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The unusual circumstances in which two men meet before going on to become good friends, provides "Hard Eight" with an intriguing opening to a story which also features kidnapping, blackmail and a brutal killing. First-time director/writer Paul Thomas Anderson takes time and care to develop his characters and this approach pays off handsomely, as it's the strength of these characters and the relationships between them that ultimately make this movie so interesting and memorable. The tense atmosphere and deliberate pacing, which are established right from the start, create a closeness between the two men and also add emphasis to the anxieties and suspicions that are present between them, especially during their first meeting. As he approaches a roadside diner somewhere in Nevada, Sydney Brown (Philip Baker Hall), a professional gambler in his sixties, sees a young man who's clearly down-on-his-luck sitting on the ground close to the entrance of the building. He offers to buy him a cup of coffee and give him a cigarette. Sydney soon learns that John (John C Reilly) has lost all his money whilst gambling in an attempt to raise enough cash to pay for his mother's funeral. Sydney offers to show the young man how to be successful in the casinos and despite his understandable scepticism, John agrees. A couple of years later, John has prospered as Sydney's prot&eacute;g&eacute; and after having paid off his mother's funeral costs, gets married to an attractive cocktail waitress called Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow). John has also become friendly with Jimmy (Samuel L Jackson) who's a security officer and a man that Sydney dislikes and really doesn't trust. Clementine's part-time work as a hooker leads to trouble when one of her clients refuses to pay and she and John keep the man hostage in their motel room. Sydney is called to help them out and soon takes control of the situation but also runs into bigger trouble shortly after, when Jimmy threatens and blackmails him. Philip Baker Hall gives a top class performance as the lonely, well dressed, experienced gambler with a face that's filled with sadness and lines. He's dignified and shrewd and looks as if he's been through some tough experiences but also finds it gratifying to help John out. John is another lonely person who appreciates the progress he's made under Sydney's guidance but his poor judgement and gullibility will clearly make it impossible for him to ever fully emulate his mentor's success. John C Reilly, in a consistently strong performance, is very natural and convincing in the way that he portrays John's naivety and impetuosity. Clementine is not as streetwise as she needs to be and Gwyneth Paltrow conveys her character's underlying sadness very effectively. Samuel L Jackson is also on great form as the violent thug who totally underestimates Sydney. "Hard Eight" is haunting and poignant and its overall tone and tempo is perfect for a movie in which a dark secret, hidden motives and a need for redemption affect so much of what takes place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazingly accomplished debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red_Identity
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's be clear. This is 2013 and I've seen all of Anderson's other films. While this is probably his weakest (although it's hard to say weakest when they are all great) it's still astonishing how accomplished it feels. You could tell from this film the filmmaker that Anderson would go on to become, and with just six films he's already one of my 5 all-time favorites. The whole cast here is solid, but Baker is amazing in his role, not very spoken, his motivations always ambiguous. Anderson isn't here to spell out everything, and instead the film plays out very nicely and smoothly. Great accomplishment, and it's also fun seeing Philip Seymour Hoffman in his great little cameo
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to Watch, but...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RabbitValleyRebel
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I adore and respect the opening scene. All stories need to start somewhere, and this one started with style, in a setting that most of us have frequented...a Denny's Restaurant basically. Throughout the film, we are made acutely aware of the precious value of food, a bed, coffee, cigarettes, cable movies, and companionship, for someone who has been deprived these things before. Most of us probably take them for granted,unless we have been down-and-out like one of the film's protagonists. But think about how relieved you feel on a long road trip, when you stop at a motel, and partake of these things, after being trapped in your car for hours. They satiate us and bring a sense of domestic tranquility. I needed more character development. Sorry, to those who loved this film. I get the fact that it was a portrayal of "outsider" life and the casino-bubble, but I still needed to know a bit more about how these people became who they are. The plot device of not knowing why the hell Hall is being a caretaker, worked for a while, but eventually I became annoyed with guessing. The final explanation was anti-climatic and cheap. Come on, you can do better than that. Hoffman stole the show with his very brief cameo. Jackson was his usual profane loudmouth stereotype. Hall and Reilly did not have to stretch much, but they were still quite adept at portraying unspoken sadness. I'm not a fan of Paltrow, but she conveyed the torn nature of her character quite well. One other reviewer mentioned the fact that sometimes the characters don't know what to say, but that made it realistic. I totally agree. Real people rarely speak like movie characters. But in this one, the characters did speak like real people. Great job with that. There were enough good aspects to this film, to make it worth seeing. But it is a labor to watch after a while, because not much happens, and not much is said. If you like art films, you will probably like this one. It reminded me of the work of Jim Jarmusch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Smashing Debut For P.T. Anderson.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Paul Thomas Anderson comes his directorial debut, that movie is his 1996 movie known as Hard Eight. And is this movie any good? I'll tell you right now, this movie is a smashing movie, it's greatly acted, greatly written, and greatly directed. Paul Thomas Anderson is a director who does all of his own screen writing, he was only 26 when me made this movie, and not only did he direct it, but he also wrote the screenplay for it, and he wrote it singlehandedly. This movie tells the story of a gambler who meets a young man and makes him an offer to make money, and during the course of this journey, the two men are drawn close to each other in what becomes a father and son relationship, however, events put the relationship in jeopardy. Paul Thomas Anderson tells the story pretty straight forward, the story involves success, romance, setbacks, and numerous other things, all while keeping the viewer focused on what is going on. I really admire P.T. Anderson for writing all of his own screenplays, because there aren't many directors who singlehandedly write their own scripts and manage to stay good. As usual in a P.T. Anderson film, the acting is Oscar-Worthy. Phillip Baker Hall is outstanding as Sydney, the gambler who makes the offer to John C. Reilly's character. John C. Reilly's performance was wonderful too, as where the performances of Gwyneth Paltrow and Samuel L. Jackson. However, if I had to say who's performance in this movie was the best, that would be none other than Phillip Baker Hall. Phillip Baker Hall's performance was worthy of a nomination for the Academy Award for Best Actor, he was in a class by himself. And just think, after this movie, Paul Thomas Anderson would direct five more movies that would receive all sorts of acclaim, Boogie Nights, Magnolia, Punch-Drunk Love, There Will Be Blood, and his most recent movie, The Master. Hard Eight marked the start of greatness for a master film director and screenwriter, Paul Thomas Anderson, who is one of the best directors and screenwriters in recent years. This is a movie that you have got to see if you haven't seen it yet, as it is the film that made Paul Thomas Anderson famous, and it's worth seeing for the wonderful performances from the cast. It makes me so happy that there are actually people out there who still do care about making great movies, as nowadays, we get a lot of rubbish with nonstop explosions and too many flashy special effects and not to mention a lot of CGI. But every now and then, there are directors like Martin Scorsese, The Coen Brothers, and of course, Paul Thomas Anderson, who actually do care about making movies the way that movies are supposed to be made. Well anyway, Hard Eight is an outstanding masterpiece, if you've yet to see this movie, then all I can say is that you've definitely got to see it, because you will say exactly what many people have said already, that this movie is the outstanding writing and directorial debut of a master. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard Eight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Paul Thomas Anderson (Boogie Nights, Magnolia, There Will Be Blood), this was a film I would obviously have never heard of unless it was broadcast on television, and it looked interesting because of an impressive cast list, and was likely to be an independent film, so I was up for trying it. Basically Sydney (Bruce Almighty's Philip Baker Hall) is a sixty year old gamble, who outside a diner meets young man John (John C. Reilly) and offers him a cigarette, then a coffee, and then the opportunity to make the money that he needs for his mother's burial, this would mean travelling to Las Vegas and learning ways of making the money and getting by. After some scepticism John agrees, and he follows the advice of his new friend, and two years later John has the money that he needed for the funeral, he has become Sydney's prot&eacute;g&eacute; staying in Reno, and he has made himself a friend in security worker Jimmy (Samuel L. Jackson), and he is also attracted to and dating cocktail waitress Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow). Late one night Sydney gets a frantic phone call from John, and at the motel he is staying in with Clementine he finds they have kidnapped a man and held him hostage because he wouldn't pay Clementine for her prostitution, and the situation is a little worse because John and Clementine got married. The situation is resolved in some way by Sydney, but he advises the newlyweds to get away and go on a honeymoon, he suggests Niagara Falls, and after they do leave Sydney is confronted by Jimmy who is demanding money in blackmail because he knows a secret that the sixty year old doesn't want to come out, this is that Sydney killed John's father. The old man gives in and pays him the money, but he later goes late at night into Jimmy's house to shoot him dead, and the end sees him return to the diner where he first met John, brushing the blood off his shirt cuff, it is unclear whether his friends finds out the dark secret he has. Also starring F. William Parker as Hostage and Philip Seymour Hoffman as Young Craps Player. Normally a character or supporting actor Baker Hall is actually a good choice as the elderly lead character because he is a wise presence, Reilly is likable as the slow but nice guy that wants to get somewhere in life, and Paltrow does pretty well as the promiscuous woman who is caught in the middle of situations, the story is simple enough, it could have used a bit more action, or the scripting could have tweaked to be wittier and with more pace, but it isn't too bad of a film debut from Anderson, a not bad crime drama. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quirky and confident - decent debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie starts of with the silent and reserved Sydney (Philip Baker Hall) entering a roadside cafeteria, where he comes across a down-trodden John (John C. Reilly). Sydney takes a strong interest in John, where he attempts to offer the younger man solutions to his problems by offering his key services: the talents of a professional gambler. After this encounter John ties himself to the old dog and becomes his prot&eacute;g&eacute;. A few years down the line John finds a love interest in Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow), waitress / part-time hooker, which in turn initiates a sequence of events that change the nature of the relationship between the two men. American cinema loves its cars, its gangsters and its gambling, while art-house delves passionately into quirkiness. I for one never really found inspiration or admiration to either of the mentioned themes. "Hard Eight" dabbles with two of them: gambling with a touch of quirky characters. Nonetheless the story does prove emotionally involving to some level, although underdone and at times hollow or open-ended. The latter is in part due to the restrained character development and jumpy plotting, which delivers us to required locations, but ignores opportunities to connect the dots. Basically "Hard Eight" (in almost Tarantinesque fashion) concentrated the movie around several key scenes, full of emotional full, content and a decent amount of talking, while the rest of the scenes are subservient and essentially meaningless filler. The sell of the story heavily lies on Philip Baker Hall's shoulders, as he does his job excellently with a even-handed, but scene-grabbing, performance. Nonetheless not a thoroughly involving and passable debut (full of beginner's jitters) by the great Paul Thomas Anderson, which nonetheless shows his qualities as a director, especially in regards to actor interaction. Some of the cinematography was questionable and slightly amateurish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent debut for Anderson, but it's not quite there
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Paul Thomas Anderson's debut shows off some of his talent - the excellent work he drives out of character actors in lead parts, effective atmosphere creation and great camera work. Hard Eight doesn't have the spark of There Will Be Blood, Magnolia or Boogie Nights, though, and the script feels half-baked; as a result, the fantastic actors do a great job with very flat characters, and neither them nor the story holds any interest. The effect of this, ironically, is that the film's best scene is a five-minute nameless cameo by Philip Seymour Hoffman. Not surprising that he's had the most impressive career of these actors, while Philip Baker Hall is still to all intents and purposes Detective Bookman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well thought out character study
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    superokapi
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    PT Anderson's first film is a good one, it may be low budget but it packs a quartet of gripping performances. Many people may look at this and think it is an action/crime movie but it is not. This film is a study of a man reaching out in guilt to help others and of the consequences when his prot&eacute;g&eacute; makes some poor friends. The best character in this film to watch is Sydney himself as the kind of man who has been doing the same thing for the last umpteen years and realizes he needs to make an impact in someone's life to make his life worthwhile. Baker Hall's performance is scene stealing, and he takes a character who uses subtle gestures and queues to make a point and lets him dominate the other characters with it. Much credit must be given to Anderson's screenplay for it's ear for character not plot driven dialogue, much like Tarantino, Anderson lets anecdotes and quips reveal details and traits of his characters. My personal favourite scene was the scene in the beginning when Sydney meets John's new friends and is able to read them both like books all without interrogation style questions. This film is worthwhile and rewarding, a good choice for a person who likes thoughtful dialogue and engaging characters.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The last film I needed to watch from Paul Thomas Anderson was his debut Hard Eight and it was a solid start of his illustrious career. I liked how mysterious Philip Baker Hall's character Sydney is for the most part of the film, making you always wonder what are his real intentions with John. Samuel L. Jackson, John C. Reilly and Gwyneth Paltrow give fine performances too, but none of their characters were likable or very interesting for me, so I didn't really care for them. John and Clementine make some bad and even ridiculous decisions sometimes, so it's a bit hard to feel sorry for them when things so wrong. I enjoyed the big reveal of Sydney, being an unpredictable turn of events and that was a great way to establish his real ties with John. While the ending is quite predictable and didn't have much of an impact for me, Hard Eight is still a nice effort from Paul Thomas Anderson.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    naturalistic and character driven.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carlhartwell78
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Hard Eight, first time director Paul Thomas Anderson has constructed a subtle yet powerful commentary on redemption, it's prices and ultimately, its viability. Sydney (Philip Baker Hall) is a professional gambler, we know nothing about his background for most of the film but it becomes quickly apparent that he spends most of his time in casinos (with only brief respites in dinners). At the outset he comes upon John (John C. Reilly) a down and out, apparent loser, whom Sydney takes under his wing. Sydney teaches John, first how to gain casino hospitality with very little loss and eventually mentors him in the ways of professional gambling. For the majority of the film, the intrigue lies in the fact that he seems to have no motive for doing any of this, and it only grows when Sydney seems only too willing to help Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow) out of her damaging lifestyle as well. A cocktail waitress and part time hooker, Clementine, had captured Johns affections and ultimately brings things to a head with a particularly senseless mistake. The fourth (and last) main character is Jimmy (Samuel L. Jackson), who is a friend of Johns, but who Sydney has little time for. The Film is almost entirely character driven and contains impeccable performances by all involved, indeed it has to since the plot is not nearly strong enough without them. Of course it's no bad thing that the plot isn't strong, it's not that type of film, largely any "situation" that happens isn't there for any reason other than to show how the characters react. Hall's performance is particularly impressive, chiefly since his characters motivation isn't fully revealed until about 15 minutes before the end. Despite this he carries the film majestically and one cannot help but get the sense that Sydey is significant and incredibly fascinating. No mean feat when the audience knows so little about his character. Reilly, Paltrow and Jackson's performances are commendable also, but for me, their characters serve mostly as secondary characters to Sydney's. That's not to say that they come across as anything but very three dimensional, each actor has at least one scene in which to shine and shine they do. One of the films many strengths is in it's extremely naturalistic tone, not of course uncommon in many films, but done to perfection in this one. The script constantly has all of the characters stumbling over or at a loss for words, and we're often given the impression that they're completely clueless and out of their depths, they seem like real people! Two scenes in particular stand out as testament to this, the motel room scene and the car scene towards the end with Jackson and Hall. Both are so realistic that one can imagine they were hardly scripted at all. The film, though perhaps not a masterpiece, is extremely good and upon it's release, demonstrated great promise in it's director, who of course went on to direct the sublime Magnolia. It entices the viewer to contemplate the very idea of forgiveness. To what extent does a persons past affect how we perceive him, are some acts truly irredeemable?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Haunting, Poignant & Tense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The unusual circumstances in which two men meet before going on to become good friends, provides "Hard Eight" with an intriguing opening to a story which also features kidnapping, blackmail and a brutal killing. First-time director/writer Paul Thomas Anderson takes time and care to develop his characters and this approach pays off handsomely, as it's the strength of these characters and the relationships between them that ultimately make this movie so interesting and memorable. The tense atmosphere and deliberate pacing, which are established right from the start, create a closeness between the two men and also add emphasis to the anxieties and suspicions that are present between them, especially during their first meeting. As he approaches a roadside diner somewhere in Nevada, Sydney Brown (Philip Baker Hall), a professional gambler in his sixties, sees a young man who's clearly down-on-his-luck sitting on the ground close to the entrance of the building. He offers to buy him a cup of coffee and give him a cigarette. Sydney soon learns that John (John C Reilly) has lost all his money whilst gambling in an attempt to raise enough cash to pay for his mother's funeral. Sydney offers to show the young man how to be successful in the casinos and despite his understandable scepticism, John agrees. A couple of years later, John has prospered as Sydney's prot&eacute;g&eacute; and after having paid off his mother's funeral costs, gets married to an attractive cocktail waitress called Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow). John has also become friendly with Jimmy (Samuel L Jackson) who's a security officer and a man that Sydney dislikes and really doesn't trust. Clementine's part-time work as a hooker leads to trouble when one of her clients refuses to pay and she and John keep the man hostage in their motel room. Sydney is called to help them out and soon takes control of the situation but also runs into bigger trouble shortly after, when Jimmy threatens and blackmails him. Philip Baker Hall gives a top class performance as the lonely, well dressed, experienced gambler with a face that's filled with sadness and lines. He's dignified and shrewd and looks as if he's been through some tough experiences but also finds it gratifying to help John out. John is another lonely person who appreciates the progress he's made under Sydney's guidance but his poor judgement and gullibility will clearly make it impossible for him to ever fully emulate his mentor's success. John C Reilly, in a consistently strong performance, is very natural and convincing in the way that he portrays John's naivety and impetuosity. Clementine is not as streetwise as she needs to be and Gwyneth Paltrow conveys her character's underlying sadness very effectively. Samuel L Jackson is also on great form as the violent thug who totally underestimates Sydney. "Hard Eight" is haunting and poignant and its overall tone and tempo is perfect for a movie in which a dark secret, hidden motives and a need for redemption affect so much of what takes place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazingly accomplished debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red_Identity
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's be clear. This is 2013 and I've seen all of Anderson's other films. While this is probably his weakest (although it's hard to say weakest when they are all great) it's still astonishing how accomplished it feels. You could tell from this film the filmmaker that Anderson would go on to become, and with just six films he's already one of my 5 all-time favorites. The whole cast here is solid, but Baker is amazing in his role, not very spoken, his motivations always ambiguous. Anderson isn't here to spell out everything, and instead the film plays out very nicely and smoothly. Great accomplishment, and it's also fun seeing Philip Seymour Hoffman in his great little cameo
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to Watch, but...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RabbitValleyRebel
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I adore and respect the opening scene. All stories need to start somewhere, and this one started with style, in a setting that most of us have frequented...a Denny's Restaurant basically. Throughout the film, we are made acutely aware of the precious value of food, a bed, coffee, cigarettes, cable movies, and companionship, for someone who has been deprived these things before. Most of us probably take them for granted,unless we have been down-and-out like one of the film's protagonists. But think about how relieved you feel on a long road trip, when you stop at a motel, and partake of these things, after being trapped in your car for hours. They satiate us and bring a sense of domestic tranquility. I needed more character development. Sorry, to those who loved this film. I get the fact that it was a portrayal of "outsider" life and the casino-bubble, but I still needed to know a bit more about how these people became who they are. The plot device of not knowing why the hell Hall is being a caretaker, worked for a while, but eventually I became annoyed with guessing. The final explanation was anti-climatic and cheap. Come on, you can do better than that. Hoffman stole the show with his very brief cameo. Jackson was his usual profane loudmouth stereotype. Hall and Reilly did not have to stretch much, but they were still quite adept at portraying unspoken sadness. I'm not a fan of Paltrow, but she conveyed the torn nature of her character quite well. One other reviewer mentioned the fact that sometimes the characters don't know what to say, but that made it realistic. I totally agree. Real people rarely speak like movie characters. But in this one, the characters did speak like real people. Great job with that. There were enough good aspects to this film, to make it worth seeing. But it is a labor to watch after a while, because not much happens, and not much is said. If you like art films, you will probably like this one. It reminded me of the work of Jim Jarmusch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Smashing Debut For P.T. Anderson.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Paul Thomas Anderson comes his directorial debut, that movie is his 1996 movie known as Hard Eight. And is this movie any good? I'll tell you right now, this movie is a smashing movie, it's greatly acted, greatly written, and greatly directed. Paul Thomas Anderson is a director who does all of his own screen writing, he was only 26 when me made this movie, and not only did he direct it, but he also wrote the screenplay for it, and he wrote it singlehandedly. This movie tells the story of a gambler who meets a young man and makes him an offer to make money, and during the course of this journey, the two men are drawn close to each other in what becomes a father and son relationship, however, events put the relationship in jeopardy. Paul Thomas Anderson tells the story pretty straight forward, the story involves success, romance, setbacks, and numerous other things, all while keeping the viewer focused on what is going on. I really admire P.T. Anderson for writing all of his own screenplays, because there aren't many directors who singlehandedly write their own scripts and manage to stay good. As usual in a P.T. Anderson film, the acting is Oscar-Worthy. Phillip Baker Hall is outstanding as Sydney, the gambler who makes the offer to John C. Reilly's character. John C. Reilly's performance was wonderful too, as where the performances of Gwyneth Paltrow and Samuel L. Jackson. However, if I had to say who's performance in this movie was the best, that would be none other than Phillip Baker Hall. Phillip Baker Hall's performance was worthy of a nomination for the Academy Award for Best Actor, he was in a class by himself. And just think, after this movie, Paul Thomas Anderson would direct five more movies that would receive all sorts of acclaim, Boogie Nights, Magnolia, Punch-Drunk Love, There Will Be Blood, and his most recent movie, The Master. Hard Eight marked the start of greatness for a master film director and screenwriter, Paul Thomas Anderson, who is one of the best directors and screenwriters in recent years. This is a movie that you have got to see if you haven't seen it yet, as it is the film that made Paul Thomas Anderson famous, and it's worth seeing for the wonderful performances from the cast. It makes me so happy that there are actually people out there who still do care about making great movies, as nowadays, we get a lot of rubbish with nonstop explosions and too many flashy special effects and not to mention a lot of CGI. But every now and then, there are directors like Martin Scorsese, The Coen Brothers, and of course, Paul Thomas Anderson, who actually do care about making movies the way that movies are supposed to be made. Well anyway, Hard Eight is an outstanding masterpiece, if you've yet to see this movie, then all I can say is that you've definitely got to see it, because you will say exactly what many people have said already, that this movie is the outstanding writing and directorial debut of a master. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard Eight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Paul Thomas Anderson (Boogie Nights, Magnolia, There Will Be Blood), this was a film I would obviously have never heard of unless it was broadcast on television, and it looked interesting because of an impressive cast list, and was likely to be an independent film, so I was up for trying it. Basically Sydney (Bruce Almighty's Philip Baker Hall) is a sixty year old gamble, who outside a diner meets young man John (John C. Reilly) and offers him a cigarette, then a coffee, and then the opportunity to make the money that he needs for his mother's burial, this would mean travelling to Las Vegas and learning ways of making the money and getting by. After some scepticism John agrees, and he follows the advice of his new friend, and two years later John has the money that he needed for the funeral, he has become Sydney's prot&eacute;g&eacute; staying in Reno, and he has made himself a friend in security worker Jimmy (Samuel L. Jackson), and he is also attracted to and dating cocktail waitress Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow). Late one night Sydney gets a frantic phone call from John, and at the motel he is staying in with Clementine he finds they have kidnapped a man and held him hostage because he wouldn't pay Clementine for her prostitution, and the situation is a little worse because John and Clementine got married. The situation is resolved in some way by Sydney, but he advises the newlyweds to get away and go on a honeymoon, he suggests Niagara Falls, and after they do leave Sydney is confronted by Jimmy who is demanding money in blackmail because he knows a secret that the sixty year old doesn't want to come out, this is that Sydney killed John's father. The old man gives in and pays him the money, but he later goes late at night into Jimmy's house to shoot him dead, and the end sees him return to the diner where he first met John, brushing the blood off his shirt cuff, it is unclear whether his friends finds out the dark secret he has. Also starring F. William Parker as Hostage and Philip Seymour Hoffman as Young Craps Player. Normally a character or supporting actor Baker Hall is actually a good choice as the elderly lead character because he is a wise presence, Reilly is likable as the slow but nice guy that wants to get somewhere in life, and Paltrow does pretty well as the promiscuous woman who is caught in the middle of situations, the story is simple enough, it could have used a bit more action, or the scripting could have tweaked to be wittier and with more pace, but it isn't too bad of a film debut from Anderson, a not bad crime drama. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quirky and confident - decent debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie starts of with the silent and reserved Sydney (Philip Baker Hall) entering a roadside cafeteria, where he comes across a down-trodden John (John C. Reilly). Sydney takes a strong interest in John, where he attempts to offer the younger man solutions to his problems by offering his key services: the talents of a professional gambler. After this encounter John ties himself to the old dog and becomes his prot&eacute;g&eacute;. A few years down the line John finds a love interest in Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow), waitress / part-time hooker, which in turn initiates a sequence of events that change the nature of the relationship between the two men. American cinema loves its cars, its gangsters and its gambling, while art-house delves passionately into quirkiness. I for one never really found inspiration or admiration to either of the mentioned themes. "Hard Eight" dabbles with two of them: gambling with a touch of quirky characters. Nonetheless the story does prove emotionally involving to some level, although underdone and at times hollow or open-ended. The latter is in part due to the restrained character development and jumpy plotting, which delivers us to required locations, but ignores opportunities to connect the dots. Basically "Hard Eight" (in almost Tarantinesque fashion) concentrated the movie around several key scenes, full of emotional full, content and a decent amount of talking, while the rest of the scenes are subservient and essentially meaningless filler. The sell of the story heavily lies on Philip Baker Hall's shoulders, as he does his job excellently with a even-handed, but scene-grabbing, performance. Nonetheless not a thoroughly involving and passable debut (full of beginner's jitters) by the great Paul Thomas Anderson, which nonetheless shows his qualities as a director, especially in regards to actor interaction. Some of the cinematography was questionable and slightly amateurish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent debut for Anderson, but it's not quite there
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Paul Thomas Anderson's debut shows off some of his talent - the excellent work he drives out of character actors in lead parts, effective atmosphere creation and great camera work. Hard Eight doesn't have the spark of There Will Be Blood, Magnolia or Boogie Nights, though, and the script feels half-baked; as a result, the fantastic actors do a great job with very flat characters, and neither them nor the story holds any interest. The effect of this, ironically, is that the film's best scene is a five-minute nameless cameo by Philip Seymour Hoffman. Not surprising that he's had the most impressive career of these actors, while Philip Baker Hall is still to all intents and purposes Detective Bookman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well thought out character study
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    superokapi
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    PT Anderson's first film is a good one, it may be low budget but it packs a quartet of gripping performances. Many people may look at this and think it is an action/crime movie but it is not. This film is a study of a man reaching out in guilt to help others and of the consequences when his prot&eacute;g&eacute; makes some poor friends. The best character in this film to watch is Sydney himself as the kind of man who has been doing the same thing for the last umpteen years and realizes he needs to make an impact in someone's life to make his life worthwhile. Baker Hall's performance is scene stealing, and he takes a character who uses subtle gestures and queues to make a point and lets him dominate the other characters with it. Much credit must be given to Anderson's screenplay for it's ear for character not plot driven dialogue, much like Tarantino, Anderson lets anecdotes and quips reveal details and traits of his characters. My personal favourite scene was the scene in the beginning when Sydney meets John's new friends and is able to read them both like books all without interrogation style questions. This film is worthwhile and rewarding, a good choice for a person who likes thoughtful dialogue and engaging characters.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The last film I needed to watch from Paul Thomas Anderson was his debut Hard Eight and it was a solid start of his illustrious career. I liked how mysterious Philip Baker Hall's character Sydney is for the most part of the film, making you always wonder what are his real intentions with John. Samuel L. Jackson, John C. Reilly and Gwyneth Paltrow give fine performances too, but none of their characters were likable or very interesting for me, so I didn't really care for them. John and Clementine make some bad and even ridiculous decisions sometimes, so it's a bit hard to feel sorry for them when things so wrong. I enjoyed the big reveal of Sydney, being an unpredictable turn of events and that was a great way to establish his real ties with John. While the ending is quite predictable and didn't have much of an impact for me, Hard Eight is still a nice effort from Paul Thomas Anderson.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    naturalistic and character driven.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carlhartwell78
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Hard Eight, first time director Paul Thomas Anderson has constructed a subtle yet powerful commentary on redemption, it's prices and ultimately, its viability. Sydney (Philip Baker Hall) is a professional gambler, we know nothing about his background for most of the film but it becomes quickly apparent that he spends most of his time in casinos (with only brief respites in dinners). At the outset he comes upon John (John C. Reilly) a down and out, apparent loser, whom Sydney takes under his wing. Sydney teaches John, first how to gain casino hospitality with very little loss and eventually mentors him in the ways of professional gambling. For the majority of the film, the intrigue lies in the fact that he seems to have no motive for doing any of this, and it only grows when Sydney seems only too willing to help Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow) out of her damaging lifestyle as well. A cocktail waitress and part time hooker, Clementine, had captured Johns affections and ultimately brings things to a head with a particularly senseless mistake. The fourth (and last) main character is Jimmy (Samuel L. Jackson), who is a friend of Johns, but who Sydney has little time for. The Film is almost entirely character driven and contains impeccable performances by all involved, indeed it has to since the plot is not nearly strong enough without them. Of course it's no bad thing that the plot isn't strong, it's not that type of film, largely any "situation" that happens isn't there for any reason other than to show how the characters react. Hall's performance is particularly impressive, chiefly since his characters motivation isn't fully revealed until about 15 minutes before the end. Despite this he carries the film majestically and one cannot help but get the sense that Sydey is significant and incredibly fascinating. No mean feat when the audience knows so little about his character. Reilly, Paltrow and Jackson's performances are commendable also, but for me, their characters serve mostly as secondary characters to Sydney's. That's not to say that they come across as anything but very three dimensional, each actor has at least one scene in which to shine and shine they do. One of the films many strengths is in it's extremely naturalistic tone, not of course uncommon in many films, but done to perfection in this one. The script constantly has all of the characters stumbling over or at a loss for words, and we're often given the impression that they're completely clueless and out of their depths, they seem like real people! Two scenes in particular stand out as testament to this, the motel room scene and the car scene towards the end with Jackson and Hall. Both are so realistic that one can imagine they were hardly scripted at all. The film, though perhaps not a masterpiece, is extremely good and upon it's release, demonstrated great promise in it's director, who of course went on to direct the sublime Magnolia. It entices the viewer to contemplate the very idea of forgiveness. To what extent does a persons past affect how we perceive him, are some acts truly irredeemable?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Haunting, Poignant & Tense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The unusual circumstances in which two men meet before going on to become good friends, provides "Hard Eight" with an intriguing opening to a story which also features kidnapping, blackmail and a brutal killing. First-time director/writer Paul Thomas Anderson takes time and care to develop his characters and this approach pays off handsomely, as it's the strength of these characters and the relationships between them that ultimately make this movie so interesting and memorable. The tense atmosphere and deliberate pacing, which are established right from the start, create a closeness between the two men and also add emphasis to the anxieties and suspicions that are present between them, especially during their first meeting. As he approaches a roadside diner somewhere in Nevada, Sydney Brown (Philip Baker Hall), a professional gambler in his sixties, sees a young man who's clearly down-on-his-luck sitting on the ground close to the entrance of the building. He offers to buy him a cup of coffee and give him a cigarette. Sydney soon learns that John (John C Reilly) has lost all his money whilst gambling in an attempt to raise enough cash to pay for his mother's funeral. Sydney offers to show the young man how to be successful in the casinos and despite his understandable scepticism, John agrees. A couple of years later, John has prospered as Sydney's prot&eacute;g&eacute; and after having paid off his mother's funeral costs, gets married to an attractive cocktail waitress called Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow). John has also become friendly with Jimmy (Samuel L Jackson) who's a security officer and a man that Sydney dislikes and really doesn't trust. Clementine's part-time work as a hooker leads to trouble when one of her clients refuses to pay and she and John keep the man hostage in their motel room. Sydney is called to help them out and soon takes control of the situation but also runs into bigger trouble shortly after, when Jimmy threatens and blackmails him. Philip Baker Hall gives a top class performance as the lonely, well dressed, experienced gambler with a face that's filled with sadness and lines. He's dignified and shrewd and looks as if he's been through some tough experiences but also finds it gratifying to help John out. John is another lonely person who appreciates the progress he's made under Sydney's guidance but his poor judgement and gullibility will clearly make it impossible for him to ever fully emulate his mentor's success. John C Reilly, in a consistently strong performance, is very natural and convincing in the way that he portrays John's naivety and impetuosity. Clementine is not as streetwise as she needs to be and Gwyneth Paltrow conveys her character's underlying sadness very effectively. Samuel L Jackson is also on great form as the violent thug who totally underestimates Sydney. "Hard Eight" is haunting and poignant and its overall tone and tempo is perfect for a movie in which a dark secret, hidden motives and a need for redemption affect so much of what takes place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazingly accomplished debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red_Identity
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's be clear. This is 2013 and I've seen all of Anderson's other films. While this is probably his weakest (although it's hard to say weakest when they are all great) it's still astonishing how accomplished it feels. You could tell from this film the filmmaker that Anderson would go on to become, and with just six films he's already one of my 5 all-time favorites. The whole cast here is solid, but Baker is amazing in his role, not very spoken, his motivations always ambiguous. Anderson isn't here to spell out everything, and instead the film plays out very nicely and smoothly. Great accomplishment, and it's also fun seeing Philip Seymour Hoffman in his great little cameo
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to Watch, but...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RabbitValleyRebel
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I adore and respect the opening scene. All stories need to start somewhere, and this one started with style, in a setting that most of us have frequented...a Denny's Restaurant basically. Throughout the film, we are made acutely aware of the precious value of food, a bed, coffee, cigarettes, cable movies, and companionship, for someone who has been deprived these things before. Most of us probably take them for granted,unless we have been down-and-out like one of the film's protagonists. But think about how relieved you feel on a long road trip, when you stop at a motel, and partake of these things, after being trapped in your car for hours. They satiate us and bring a sense of domestic tranquility. I needed more character development. Sorry, to those who loved this film. I get the fact that it was a portrayal of "outsider" life and the casino-bubble, but I still needed to know a bit more about how these people became who they are. The plot device of not knowing why the hell Hall is being a caretaker, worked for a while, but eventually I became annoyed with guessing. The final explanation was anti-climatic and cheap. Come on, you can do better than that. Hoffman stole the show with his very brief cameo. Jackson was his usual profane loudmouth stereotype. Hall and Reilly did not have to stretch much, but they were still quite adept at portraying unspoken sadness. I'm not a fan of Paltrow, but she conveyed the torn nature of her character quite well. One other reviewer mentioned the fact that sometimes the characters don't know what to say, but that made it realistic. I totally agree. Real people rarely speak like movie characters. But in this one, the characters did speak like real people. Great job with that. There were enough good aspects to this film, to make it worth seeing. But it is a labor to watch after a while, because not much happens, and not much is said. If you like art films, you will probably like this one. It reminded me of the work of Jim Jarmusch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Smashing Debut For P.T. Anderson.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Paul Thomas Anderson comes his directorial debut, that movie is his 1996 movie known as Hard Eight. And is this movie any good? I'll tell you right now, this movie is a smashing movie, it's greatly acted, greatly written, and greatly directed. Paul Thomas Anderson is a director who does all of his own screen writing, he was only 26 when me made this movie, and not only did he direct it, but he also wrote the screenplay for it, and he wrote it singlehandedly. This movie tells the story of a gambler who meets a young man and makes him an offer to make money, and during the course of this journey, the two men are drawn close to each other in what becomes a father and son relationship, however, events put the relationship in jeopardy. Paul Thomas Anderson tells the story pretty straight forward, the story involves success, romance, setbacks, and numerous other things, all while keeping the viewer focused on what is going on. I really admire P.T. Anderson for writing all of his own screenplays, because there aren't many directors who singlehandedly write their own scripts and manage to stay good. As usual in a P.T. Anderson film, the acting is Oscar-Worthy. Phillip Baker Hall is outstanding as Sydney, the gambler who makes the offer to John C. Reilly's character. John C. Reilly's performance was wonderful too, as where the performances of Gwyneth Paltrow and Samuel L. Jackson. However, if I had to say who's performance in this movie was the best, that would be none other than Phillip Baker Hall. Phillip Baker Hall's performance was worthy of a nomination for the Academy Award for Best Actor, he was in a class by himself. And just think, after this movie, Paul Thomas Anderson would direct five more movies that would receive all sorts of acclaim, Boogie Nights, Magnolia, Punch-Drunk Love, There Will Be Blood, and his most recent movie, The Master. Hard Eight marked the start of greatness for a master film director and screenwriter, Paul Thomas Anderson, who is one of the best directors and screenwriters in recent years. This is a movie that you have got to see if you haven't seen it yet, as it is the film that made Paul Thomas Anderson famous, and it's worth seeing for the wonderful performances from the cast. It makes me so happy that there are actually people out there who still do care about making great movies, as nowadays, we get a lot of rubbish with nonstop explosions and too many flashy special effects and not to mention a lot of CGI. But every now and then, there are directors like Martin Scorsese, The Coen Brothers, and of course, Paul Thomas Anderson, who actually do care about making movies the way that movies are supposed to be made. Well anyway, Hard Eight is an outstanding masterpiece, if you've yet to see this movie, then all I can say is that you've definitely got to see it, because you will say exactly what many people have said already, that this movie is the outstanding writing and directorial debut of a master. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard Eight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Paul Thomas Anderson (Boogie Nights, Magnolia, There Will Be Blood), this was a film I would obviously have never heard of unless it was broadcast on television, and it looked interesting because of an impressive cast list, and was likely to be an independent film, so I was up for trying it. Basically Sydney (Bruce Almighty's Philip Baker Hall) is a sixty year old gamble, who outside a diner meets young man John (John C. Reilly) and offers him a cigarette, then a coffee, and then the opportunity to make the money that he needs for his mother's burial, this would mean travelling to Las Vegas and learning ways of making the money and getting by. After some scepticism John agrees, and he follows the advice of his new friend, and two years later John has the money that he needed for the funeral, he has become Sydney's prot&eacute;g&eacute; staying in Reno, and he has made himself a friend in security worker Jimmy (Samuel L. Jackson), and he is also attracted to and dating cocktail waitress Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow). Late one night Sydney gets a frantic phone call from John, and at the motel he is staying in with Clementine he finds they have kidnapped a man and held him hostage because he wouldn't pay Clementine for her prostitution, and the situation is a little worse because John and Clementine got married. The situation is resolved in some way by Sydney, but he advises the newlyweds to get away and go on a honeymoon, he suggests Niagara Falls, and after they do leave Sydney is confronted by Jimmy who is demanding money in blackmail because he knows a secret that the sixty year old doesn't want to come out, this is that Sydney killed John's father. The old man gives in and pays him the money, but he later goes late at night into Jimmy's house to shoot him dead, and the end sees him return to the diner where he first met John, brushing the blood off his shirt cuff, it is unclear whether his friends finds out the dark secret he has. Also starring F. William Parker as Hostage and Philip Seymour Hoffman as Young Craps Player. Normally a character or supporting actor Baker Hall is actually a good choice as the elderly lead character because he is a wise presence, Reilly is likable as the slow but nice guy that wants to get somewhere in life, and Paltrow does pretty well as the promiscuous woman who is caught in the middle of situations, the story is simple enough, it could have used a bit more action, or the scripting could have tweaked to be wittier and with more pace, but it isn't too bad of a film debut from Anderson, a not bad crime drama. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quirky and confident - decent debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie starts of with the silent and reserved Sydney (Philip Baker Hall) entering a roadside cafeteria, where he comes across a down-trodden John (John C. Reilly). Sydney takes a strong interest in John, where he attempts to offer the younger man solutions to his problems by offering his key services: the talents of a professional gambler. After this encounter John ties himself to the old dog and becomes his prot&eacute;g&eacute;. A few years down the line John finds a love interest in Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow), waitress / part-time hooker, which in turn initiates a sequence of events that change the nature of the relationship between the two men. American cinema loves its cars, its gangsters and its gambling, while art-house delves passionately into quirkiness. I for one never really found inspiration or admiration to either of the mentioned themes. "Hard Eight" dabbles with two of them: gambling with a touch of quirky characters. Nonetheless the story does prove emotionally involving to some level, although underdone and at times hollow or open-ended. The latter is in part due to the restrained character development and jumpy plotting, which delivers us to required locations, but ignores opportunities to connect the dots. Basically "Hard Eight" (in almost Tarantinesque fashion) concentrated the movie around several key scenes, full of emotional full, content and a decent amount of talking, while the rest of the scenes are subservient and essentially meaningless filler. The sell of the story heavily lies on Philip Baker Hall's shoulders, as he does his job excellently with a even-handed, but scene-grabbing, performance. Nonetheless not a thoroughly involving and passable debut (full of beginner's jitters) by the great Paul Thomas Anderson, which nonetheless shows his qualities as a director, especially in regards to actor interaction. Some of the cinematography was questionable and slightly amateurish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent debut for Anderson, but it's not quite there
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Paul Thomas Anderson's debut shows off some of his talent - the excellent work he drives out of character actors in lead parts, effective atmosphere creation and great camera work. Hard Eight doesn't have the spark of There Will Be Blood, Magnolia or Boogie Nights, though, and the script feels half-baked; as a result, the fantastic actors do a great job with very flat characters, and neither them nor the story holds any interest. The effect of this, ironically, is that the film's best scene is a five-minute nameless cameo by Philip Seymour Hoffman. Not surprising that he's had the most impressive career of these actors, while Philip Baker Hall is still to all intents and purposes Detective Bookman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well thought out character study
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    superokapi
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    PT Anderson's first film is a good one, it may be low budget but it packs a quartet of gripping performances. Many people may look at this and think it is an action/crime movie but it is not. This film is a study of a man reaching out in guilt to help others and of the consequences when his prot&eacute;g&eacute; makes some poor friends. The best character in this film to watch is Sydney himself as the kind of man who has been doing the same thing for the last umpteen years and realizes he needs to make an impact in someone's life to make his life worthwhile. Baker Hall's performance is scene stealing, and he takes a character who uses subtle gestures and queues to make a point and lets him dominate the other characters with it. Much credit must be given to Anderson's screenplay for it's ear for character not plot driven dialogue, much like Tarantino, Anderson lets anecdotes and quips reveal details and traits of his characters. My personal favourite scene was the scene in the beginning when Sydney meets John's new friends and is able to read them both like books all without interrogation style questions. This film is worthwhile and rewarding, a good choice for a person who likes thoughtful dialogue and engaging characters.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The last film I needed to watch from Paul Thomas Anderson was his debut Hard Eight and it was a solid start of his illustrious career. I liked how mysterious Philip Baker Hall's character Sydney is for the most part of the film, making you always wonder what are his real intentions with John. Samuel L. Jackson, John C. Reilly and Gwyneth Paltrow give fine performances too, but none of their characters were likable or very interesting for me, so I didn't really care for them. John and Clementine make some bad and even ridiculous decisions sometimes, so it's a bit hard to feel sorry for them when things so wrong. I enjoyed the big reveal of Sydney, being an unpredictable turn of events and that was a great way to establish his real ties with John. While the ending is quite predictable and didn't have much of an impact for me, Hard Eight is still a nice effort from Paul Thomas Anderson.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    naturalistic and character driven.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carlhartwell78
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Hard Eight, first time director Paul Thomas Anderson has constructed a subtle yet powerful commentary on redemption, it's prices and ultimately, its viability. Sydney (Philip Baker Hall) is a professional gambler, we know nothing about his background for most of the film but it becomes quickly apparent that he spends most of his time in casinos (with only brief respites in dinners). At the outset he comes upon John (John C. Reilly) a down and out, apparent loser, whom Sydney takes under his wing. Sydney teaches John, first how to gain casino hospitality with very little loss and eventually mentors him in the ways of professional gambling. For the majority of the film, the intrigue lies in the fact that he seems to have no motive for doing any of this, and it only grows when Sydney seems only too willing to help Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow) out of her damaging lifestyle as well. A cocktail waitress and part time hooker, Clementine, had captured Johns affections and ultimately brings things to a head with a particularly senseless mistake. The fourth (and last) main character is Jimmy (Samuel L. Jackson), who is a friend of Johns, but who Sydney has little time for. The Film is almost entirely character driven and contains impeccable performances by all involved, indeed it has to since the plot is not nearly strong enough without them. Of course it's no bad thing that the plot isn't strong, it's not that type of film, largely any "situation" that happens isn't there for any reason other than to show how the characters react. Hall's performance is particularly impressive, chiefly since his characters motivation isn't fully revealed until about 15 minutes before the end. Despite this he carries the film majestically and one cannot help but get the sense that Sydey is significant and incredibly fascinating. No mean feat when the audience knows so little about his character. Reilly, Paltrow and Jackson's performances are commendable also, but for me, their characters serve mostly as secondary characters to Sydney's. That's not to say that they come across as anything but very three dimensional, each actor has at least one scene in which to shine and shine they do. One of the films many strengths is in it's extremely naturalistic tone, not of course uncommon in many films, but done to perfection in this one. The script constantly has all of the characters stumbling over or at a loss for words, and we're often given the impression that they're completely clueless and out of their depths, they seem like real people! Two scenes in particular stand out as testament to this, the motel room scene and the car scene towards the end with Jackson and Hall. Both are so realistic that one can imagine they were hardly scripted at all. The film, though perhaps not a masterpiece, is extremely good and upon it's release, demonstrated great promise in it's director, who of course went on to direct the sublime Magnolia. It entices the viewer to contemplate the very idea of forgiveness. To what extent does a persons past affect how we perceive him, are some acts truly irredeemable?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Haunting, Poignant & Tense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The unusual circumstances in which two men meet before going on to become good friends, provides "Hard Eight" with an intriguing opening to a story which also features kidnapping, blackmail and a brutal killing. First-time director/writer Paul Thomas Anderson takes time and care to develop his characters and this approach pays off handsomely, as it's the strength of these characters and the relationships between them that ultimately make this movie so interesting and memorable. The tense atmosphere and deliberate pacing, which are established right from the start, create a closeness between the two men and also add emphasis to the anxieties and suspicions that are present between them, especially during their first meeting. As he approaches a roadside diner somewhere in Nevada, Sydney Brown (Philip Baker Hall), a professional gambler in his sixties, sees a young man who's clearly down-on-his-luck sitting on the ground close to the entrance of the building. He offers to buy him a cup of coffee and give him a cigarette. Sydney soon learns that John (John C Reilly) has lost all his money whilst gambling in an attempt to raise enough cash to pay for his mother's funeral. Sydney offers to show the young man how to be successful in the casinos and despite his understandable scepticism, John agrees. A couple of years later, John has prospered as Sydney's prot&eacute;g&eacute; and after having paid off his mother's funeral costs, gets married to an attractive cocktail waitress called Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow). John has also become friendly with Jimmy (Samuel L Jackson) who's a security officer and a man that Sydney dislikes and really doesn't trust. Clementine's part-time work as a hooker leads to trouble when one of her clients refuses to pay and she and John keep the man hostage in their motel room. Sydney is called to help them out and soon takes control of the situation but also runs into bigger trouble shortly after, when Jimmy threatens and blackmails him. Philip Baker Hall gives a top class performance as the lonely, well dressed, experienced gambler with a face that's filled with sadness and lines. He's dignified and shrewd and looks as if he's been through some tough experiences but also finds it gratifying to help John out. John is another lonely person who appreciates the progress he's made under Sydney's guidance but his poor judgement and gullibility will clearly make it impossible for him to ever fully emulate his mentor's success. John C Reilly, in a consistently strong performance, is very natural and convincing in the way that he portrays John's naivety and impetuosity. Clementine is not as streetwise as she needs to be and Gwyneth Paltrow conveys her character's underlying sadness very effectively. Samuel L Jackson is also on great form as the violent thug who totally underestimates Sydney. "Hard Eight" is haunting and poignant and its overall tone and tempo is perfect for a movie in which a dark secret, hidden motives and a need for redemption affect so much of what takes place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazingly accomplished debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red_Identity
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's be clear. This is 2013 and I've seen all of Anderson's other films. While this is probably his weakest (although it's hard to say weakest when they are all great) it's still astonishing how accomplished it feels. You could tell from this film the filmmaker that Anderson would go on to become, and with just six films he's already one of my 5 all-time favorites. The whole cast here is solid, but Baker is amazing in his role, not very spoken, his motivations always ambiguous. Anderson isn't here to spell out everything, and instead the film plays out very nicely and smoothly. Great accomplishment, and it's also fun seeing Philip Seymour Hoffman in his great little cameo
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to Watch, but...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RabbitValleyRebel
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I adore and respect the opening scene. All stories need to start somewhere, and this one started with style, in a setting that most of us have frequented...a Denny's Restaurant basically. Throughout the film, we are made acutely aware of the precious value of food, a bed, coffee, cigarettes, cable movies, and companionship, for someone who has been deprived these things before. Most of us probably take them for granted,unless we have been down-and-out like one of the film's protagonists. But think about how relieved you feel on a long road trip, when you stop at a motel, and partake of these things, after being trapped in your car for hours. They satiate us and bring a sense of domestic tranquility. I needed more character development. Sorry, to those who loved this film. I get the fact that it was a portrayal of "outsider" life and the casino-bubble, but I still needed to know a bit more about how these people became who they are. The plot device of not knowing why the hell Hall is being a caretaker, worked for a while, but eventually I became annoyed with guessing. The final explanation was anti-climatic and cheap. Come on, you can do better than that. Hoffman stole the show with his very brief cameo. Jackson was his usual profane loudmouth stereotype. Hall and Reilly did not have to stretch much, but they were still quite adept at portraying unspoken sadness. I'm not a fan of Paltrow, but she conveyed the torn nature of her character quite well. One other reviewer mentioned the fact that sometimes the characters don't know what to say, but that made it realistic. I totally agree. Real people rarely speak like movie characters. But in this one, the characters did speak like real people. Great job with that. There were enough good aspects to this film, to make it worth seeing. But it is a labor to watch after a while, because not much happens, and not much is said. If you like art films, you will probably like this one. It reminded me of the work of Jim Jarmusch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Smashing Debut For P.T. Anderson.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Paul Thomas Anderson comes his directorial debut, that movie is his 1996 movie known as Hard Eight. And is this movie any good? I'll tell you right now, this movie is a smashing movie, it's greatly acted, greatly written, and greatly directed. Paul Thomas Anderson is a director who does all of his own screen writing, he was only 26 when me made this movie, and not only did he direct it, but he also wrote the screenplay for it, and he wrote it singlehandedly. This movie tells the story of a gambler who meets a young man and makes him an offer to make money, and during the course of this journey, the two men are drawn close to each other in what becomes a father and son relationship, however, events put the relationship in jeopardy. Paul Thomas Anderson tells the story pretty straight forward, the story involves success, romance, setbacks, and numerous other things, all while keeping the viewer focused on what is going on. I really admire P.T. Anderson for writing all of his own screenplays, because there aren't many directors who singlehandedly write their own scripts and manage to stay good. As usual in a P.T. Anderson film, the acting is Oscar-Worthy. Phillip Baker Hall is outstanding as Sydney, the gambler who makes the offer to John C. Reilly's character. John C. Reilly's performance was wonderful too, as where the performances of Gwyneth Paltrow and Samuel L. Jackson. However, if I had to say who's performance in this movie was the best, that would be none other than Phillip Baker Hall. Phillip Baker Hall's performance was worthy of a nomination for the Academy Award for Best Actor, he was in a class by himself. And just think, after this movie, Paul Thomas Anderson would direct five more movies that would receive all sorts of acclaim, Boogie Nights, Magnolia, Punch-Drunk Love, There Will Be Blood, and his most recent movie, The Master. Hard Eight marked the start of greatness for a master film director and screenwriter, Paul Thomas Anderson, who is one of the best directors and screenwriters in recent years. This is a movie that you have got to see if you haven't seen it yet, as it is the film that made Paul Thomas Anderson famous, and it's worth seeing for the wonderful performances from the cast. It makes me so happy that there are actually people out there who still do care about making great movies, as nowadays, we get a lot of rubbish with nonstop explosions and too many flashy special effects and not to mention a lot of CGI. But every now and then, there are directors like Martin Scorsese, The Coen Brothers, and of course, Paul Thomas Anderson, who actually do care about making movies the way that movies are supposed to be made. Well anyway, Hard Eight is an outstanding masterpiece, if you've yet to see this movie, then all I can say is that you've definitely got to see it, because you will say exactly what many people have said already, that this movie is the outstanding writing and directorial debut of a master. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard Eight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Paul Thomas Anderson (Boogie Nights, Magnolia, There Will Be Blood), this was a film I would obviously have never heard of unless it was broadcast on television, and it looked interesting because of an impressive cast list, and was likely to be an independent film, so I was up for trying it. Basically Sydney (Bruce Almighty's Philip Baker Hall) is a sixty year old gamble, who outside a diner meets young man John (John C. Reilly) and offers him a cigarette, then a coffee, and then the opportunity to make the money that he needs for his mother's burial, this would mean travelling to Las Vegas and learning ways of making the money and getting by. After some scepticism John agrees, and he follows the advice of his new friend, and two years later John has the money that he needed for the funeral, he has become Sydney's prot&eacute;g&eacute; staying in Reno, and he has made himself a friend in security worker Jimmy (Samuel L. Jackson), and he is also attracted to and dating cocktail waitress Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow). Late one night Sydney gets a frantic phone call from John, and at the motel he is staying in with Clementine he finds they have kidnapped a man and held him hostage because he wouldn't pay Clementine for her prostitution, and the situation is a little worse because John and Clementine got married. The situation is resolved in some way by Sydney, but he advises the newlyweds to get away and go on a honeymoon, he suggests Niagara Falls, and after they do leave Sydney is confronted by Jimmy who is demanding money in blackmail because he knows a secret that the sixty year old doesn't want to come out, this is that Sydney killed John's father. The old man gives in and pays him the money, but he later goes late at night into Jimmy's house to shoot him dead, and the end sees him return to the diner where he first met John, brushing the blood off his shirt cuff, it is unclear whether his friends finds out the dark secret he has. Also starring F. William Parker as Hostage and Philip Seymour Hoffman as Young Craps Player. Normally a character or supporting actor Baker Hall is actually a good choice as the elderly lead character because he is a wise presence, Reilly is likable as the slow but nice guy that wants to get somewhere in life, and Paltrow does pretty well as the promiscuous woman who is caught in the middle of situations, the story is simple enough, it could have used a bit more action, or the scripting could have tweaked to be wittier and with more pace, but it isn't too bad of a film debut from Anderson, a not bad crime drama. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quirky and confident - decent debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie starts of with the silent and reserved Sydney (Philip Baker Hall) entering a roadside cafeteria, where he comes across a down-trodden John (John C. Reilly). Sydney takes a strong interest in John, where he attempts to offer the younger man solutions to his problems by offering his key services: the talents of a professional gambler. After this encounter John ties himself to the old dog and becomes his prot&eacute;g&eacute;. A few years down the line John finds a love interest in Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow), waitress / part-time hooker, which in turn initiates a sequence of events that change the nature of the relationship between the two men. American cinema loves its cars, its gangsters and its gambling, while art-house delves passionately into quirkiness. I for one never really found inspiration or admiration to either of the mentioned themes. "Hard Eight" dabbles with two of them: gambling with a touch of quirky characters. Nonetheless the story does prove emotionally involving to some level, although underdone and at times hollow or open-ended. The latter is in part due to the restrained character development and jumpy plotting, which delivers us to required locations, but ignores opportunities to connect the dots. Basically "Hard Eight" (in almost Tarantinesque fashion) concentrated the movie around several key scenes, full of emotional full, content and a decent amount of talking, while the rest of the scenes are subservient and essentially meaningless filler. The sell of the story heavily lies on Philip Baker Hall's shoulders, as he does his job excellently with a even-handed, but scene-grabbing, performance. Nonetheless not a thoroughly involving and passable debut (full of beginner's jitters) by the great Paul Thomas Anderson, which nonetheless shows his qualities as a director, especially in regards to actor interaction. Some of the cinematography was questionable and slightly amateurish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent debut for Anderson, but it's not quite there
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Paul Thomas Anderson's debut shows off some of his talent - the excellent work he drives out of character actors in lead parts, effective atmosphere creation and great camera work. Hard Eight doesn't have the spark of There Will Be Blood, Magnolia or Boogie Nights, though, and the script feels half-baked; as a result, the fantastic actors do a great job with very flat characters, and neither them nor the story holds any interest. The effect of this, ironically, is that the film's best scene is a five-minute nameless cameo by Philip Seymour Hoffman. Not surprising that he's had the most impressive career of these actors, while Philip Baker Hall is still to all intents and purposes Detective Bookman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well thought out character study
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    superokapi
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    PT Anderson's first film is a good one, it may be low budget but it packs a quartet of gripping performances. Many people may look at this and think it is an action/crime movie but it is not. This film is a study of a man reaching out in guilt to help others and of the consequences when his prot&eacute;g&eacute; makes some poor friends. The best character in this film to watch is Sydney himself as the kind of man who has been doing the same thing for the last umpteen years and realizes he needs to make an impact in someone's life to make his life worthwhile. Baker Hall's performance is scene stealing, and he takes a character who uses subtle gestures and queues to make a point and lets him dominate the other characters with it. Much credit must be given to Anderson's screenplay for it's ear for character not plot driven dialogue, much like Tarantino, Anderson lets anecdotes and quips reveal details and traits of his characters. My personal favourite scene was the scene in the beginning when Sydney meets John's new friends and is able to read them both like books all without interrogation style questions. This film is worthwhile and rewarding, a good choice for a person who likes thoughtful dialogue and engaging characters.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The last film I needed to watch from Paul Thomas Anderson was his debut Hard Eight and it was a solid start of his illustrious career. I liked how mysterious Philip Baker Hall's character Sydney is for the most part of the film, making you always wonder what are his real intentions with John. Samuel L. Jackson, John C. Reilly and Gwyneth Paltrow give fine performances too, but none of their characters were likable or very interesting for me, so I didn't really care for them. John and Clementine make some bad and even ridiculous decisions sometimes, so it's a bit hard to feel sorry for them when things so wrong. I enjoyed the big reveal of Sydney, being an unpredictable turn of events and that was a great way to establish his real ties with John. While the ending is quite predictable and didn't have much of an impact for me, Hard Eight is still a nice effort from Paul Thomas Anderson.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    naturalistic and character driven.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carlhartwell78
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Hard Eight, first time director Paul Thomas Anderson has constructed a subtle yet powerful commentary on redemption, it's prices and ultimately, its viability. Sydney (Philip Baker Hall) is a professional gambler, we know nothing about his background for most of the film but it becomes quickly apparent that he spends most of his time in casinos (with only brief respites in dinners). At the outset he comes upon John (John C. Reilly) a down and out, apparent loser, whom Sydney takes under his wing. Sydney teaches John, first how to gain casino hospitality with very little loss and eventually mentors him in the ways of professional gambling. For the majority of the film, the intrigue lies in the fact that he seems to have no motive for doing any of this, and it only grows when Sydney seems only too willing to help Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow) out of her damaging lifestyle as well. A cocktail waitress and part time hooker, Clementine, had captured Johns affections and ultimately brings things to a head with a particularly senseless mistake. The fourth (and last) main character is Jimmy (Samuel L. Jackson), who is a friend of Johns, but who Sydney has little time for. The Film is almost entirely character driven and contains impeccable performances by all involved, indeed it has to since the plot is not nearly strong enough without them. Of course it's no bad thing that the plot isn't strong, it's not that type of film, largely any "situation" that happens isn't there for any reason other than to show how the characters react. Hall's performance is particularly impressive, chiefly since his characters motivation isn't fully revealed until about 15 minutes before the end. Despite this he carries the film majestically and one cannot help but get the sense that Sydey is significant and incredibly fascinating. No mean feat when the audience knows so little about his character. Reilly, Paltrow and Jackson's performances are commendable also, but for me, their characters serve mostly as secondary characters to Sydney's. That's not to say that they come across as anything but very three dimensional, each actor has at least one scene in which to shine and shine they do. One of the films many strengths is in it's extremely naturalistic tone, not of course uncommon in many films, but done to perfection in this one. The script constantly has all of the characters stumbling over or at a loss for words, and we're often given the impression that they're completely clueless and out of their depths, they seem like real people! Two scenes in particular stand out as testament to this, the motel room scene and the car scene towards the end with Jackson and Hall. Both are so realistic that one can imagine they were hardly scripted at all. The film, though perhaps not a masterpiece, is extremely good and upon it's release, demonstrated great promise in it's director, who of course went on to direct the sublime Magnolia. It entices the viewer to contemplate the very idea of forgiveness. To what extent does a persons past affect how we perceive him, are some acts truly irredeemable?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Haunting, Poignant & Tense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The unusual circumstances in which two men meet before going on to become good friends, provides "Hard Eight" with an intriguing opening to a story which also features kidnapping, blackmail and a brutal killing. First-time director/writer Paul Thomas Anderson takes time and care to develop his characters and this approach pays off handsomely, as it's the strength of these characters and the relationships between them that ultimately make this movie so interesting and memorable. The tense atmosphere and deliberate pacing, which are established right from the start, create a closeness between the two men and also add emphasis to the anxieties and suspicions that are present between them, especially during their first meeting. As he approaches a roadside diner somewhere in Nevada, Sydney Brown (Philip Baker Hall), a professional gambler in his sixties, sees a young man who's clearly down-on-his-luck sitting on the ground close to the entrance of the building. He offers to buy him a cup of coffee and give him a cigarette. Sydney soon learns that John (John C Reilly) has lost all his money whilst gambling in an attempt to raise enough cash to pay for his mother's funeral. Sydney offers to show the young man how to be successful in the casinos and despite his understandable scepticism, John agrees. A couple of years later, John has prospered as Sydney's prot&eacute;g&eacute; and after having paid off his mother's funeral costs, gets married to an attractive cocktail waitress called Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow). John has also become friendly with Jimmy (Samuel L Jackson) who's a security officer and a man that Sydney dislikes and really doesn't trust. Clementine's part-time work as a hooker leads to trouble when one of her clients refuses to pay and she and John keep the man hostage in their motel room. Sydney is called to help them out and soon takes control of the situation but also runs into bigger trouble shortly after, when Jimmy threatens and blackmails him. Philip Baker Hall gives a top class performance as the lonely, well dressed, experienced gambler with a face that's filled with sadness and lines. He's dignified and shrewd and looks as if he's been through some tough experiences but also finds it gratifying to help John out. John is another lonely person who appreciates the progress he's made under Sydney's guidance but his poor judgement and gullibility will clearly make it impossible for him to ever fully emulate his mentor's success. John C Reilly, in a consistently strong performance, is very natural and convincing in the way that he portrays John's naivety and impetuosity. Clementine is not as streetwise as she needs to be and Gwyneth Paltrow conveys her character's underlying sadness very effectively. Samuel L Jackson is also on great form as the violent thug who totally underestimates Sydney. "Hard Eight" is haunting and poignant and its overall tone and tempo is perfect for a movie in which a dark secret, hidden motives and a need for redemption affect so much of what takes place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazingly accomplished debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red_Identity
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's be clear. This is 2013 and I've seen all of Anderson's other films. While this is probably his weakest (although it's hard to say weakest when they are all great) it's still astonishing how accomplished it feels. You could tell from this film the filmmaker that Anderson would go on to become, and with just six films he's already one of my 5 all-time favorites. The whole cast here is solid, but Baker is amazing in his role, not very spoken, his motivations always ambiguous. Anderson isn't here to spell out everything, and instead the film plays out very nicely and smoothly. Great accomplishment, and it's also fun seeing Philip Seymour Hoffman in his great little cameo
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to Watch, but...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RabbitValleyRebel
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I adore and respect the opening scene. All stories need to start somewhere, and this one started with style, in a setting that most of us have frequented...a Denny's Restaurant basically. Throughout the film, we are made acutely aware of the precious value of food, a bed, coffee, cigarettes, cable movies, and companionship, for someone who has been deprived these things before. Most of us probably take them for granted,unless we have been down-and-out like one of the film's protagonists. But think about how relieved you feel on a long road trip, when you stop at a motel, and partake of these things, after being trapped in your car for hours. They satiate us and bring a sense of domestic tranquility. I needed more character development. Sorry, to those who loved this film. I get the fact that it was a portrayal of "outsider" life and the casino-bubble, but I still needed to know a bit more about how these people became who they are. The plot device of not knowing why the hell Hall is being a caretaker, worked for a while, but eventually I became annoyed with guessing. The final explanation was anti-climatic and cheap. Come on, you can do better than that. Hoffman stole the show with his very brief cameo. Jackson was his usual profane loudmouth stereotype. Hall and Reilly did not have to stretch much, but they were still quite adept at portraying unspoken sadness. I'm not a fan of Paltrow, but she conveyed the torn nature of her character quite well. One other reviewer mentioned the fact that sometimes the characters don't know what to say, but that made it realistic. I totally agree. Real people rarely speak like movie characters. But in this one, the characters did speak like real people. Great job with that. There were enough good aspects to this film, to make it worth seeing. But it is a labor to watch after a while, because not much happens, and not much is said. If you like art films, you will probably like this one. It reminded me of the work of Jim Jarmusch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Smashing Debut For P.T. Anderson.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Paul Thomas Anderson comes his directorial debut, that movie is his 1996 movie known as Hard Eight. And is this movie any good? I'll tell you right now, this movie is a smashing movie, it's greatly acted, greatly written, and greatly directed. Paul Thomas Anderson is a director who does all of his own screen writing, he was only 26 when me made this movie, and not only did he direct it, but he also wrote the screenplay for it, and he wrote it singlehandedly. This movie tells the story of a gambler who meets a young man and makes him an offer to make money, and during the course of this journey, the two men are drawn close to each other in what becomes a father and son relationship, however, events put the relationship in jeopardy. Paul Thomas Anderson tells the story pretty straight forward, the story involves success, romance, setbacks, and numerous other things, all while keeping the viewer focused on what is going on. I really admire P.T. Anderson for writing all of his own screenplays, because there aren't many directors who singlehandedly write their own scripts and manage to stay good. As usual in a P.T. Anderson film, the acting is Oscar-Worthy. Phillip Baker Hall is outstanding as Sydney, the gambler who makes the offer to John C. Reilly's character. John C. Reilly's performance was wonderful too, as where the performances of Gwyneth Paltrow and Samuel L. Jackson. However, if I had to say who's performance in this movie was the best, that would be none other than Phillip Baker Hall. Phillip Baker Hall's performance was worthy of a nomination for the Academy Award for Best Actor, he was in a class by himself. And just think, after this movie, Paul Thomas Anderson would direct five more movies that would receive all sorts of acclaim, Boogie Nights, Magnolia, Punch-Drunk Love, There Will Be Blood, and his most recent movie, The Master. Hard Eight marked the start of greatness for a master film director and screenwriter, Paul Thomas Anderson, who is one of the best directors and screenwriters in recent years. This is a movie that you have got to see if you haven't seen it yet, as it is the film that made Paul Thomas Anderson famous, and it's worth seeing for the wonderful performances from the cast. It makes me so happy that there are actually people out there who still do care about making great movies, as nowadays, we get a lot of rubbish with nonstop explosions and too many flashy special effects and not to mention a lot of CGI. But every now and then, there are directors like Martin Scorsese, The Coen Brothers, and of course, Paul Thomas Anderson, who actually do care about making movies the way that movies are supposed to be made. Well anyway, Hard Eight is an outstanding masterpiece, if you've yet to see this movie, then all I can say is that you've definitely got to see it, because you will say exactly what many people have said already, that this movie is the outstanding writing and directorial debut of a master. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard Eight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Paul Thomas Anderson (Boogie Nights, Magnolia, There Will Be Blood), this was a film I would obviously have never heard of unless it was broadcast on television, and it looked interesting because of an impressive cast list, and was likely to be an independent film, so I was up for trying it. Basically Sydney (Bruce Almighty's Philip Baker Hall) is a sixty year old gamble, who outside a diner meets young man John (John C. Reilly) and offers him a cigarette, then a coffee, and then the opportunity to make the money that he needs for his mother's burial, this would mean travelling to Las Vegas and learning ways of making the money and getting by. After some scepticism John agrees, and he follows the advice of his new friend, and two years later John has the money that he needed for the funeral, he has become Sydney's prot&eacute;g&eacute; staying in Reno, and he has made himself a friend in security worker Jimmy (Samuel L. Jackson), and he is also attracted to and dating cocktail waitress Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow). Late one night Sydney gets a frantic phone call from John, and at the motel he is staying in with Clementine he finds they have kidnapped a man and held him hostage because he wouldn't pay Clementine for her prostitution, and the situation is a little worse because John and Clementine got married. The situation is resolved in some way by Sydney, but he advises the newlyweds to get away and go on a honeymoon, he suggests Niagara Falls, and after they do leave Sydney is confronted by Jimmy who is demanding money in blackmail because he knows a secret that the sixty year old doesn't want to come out, this is that Sydney killed John's father. The old man gives in and pays him the money, but he later goes late at night into Jimmy's house to shoot him dead, and the end sees him return to the diner where he first met John, brushing the blood off his shirt cuff, it is unclear whether his friends finds out the dark secret he has. Also starring F. William Parker as Hostage and Philip Seymour Hoffman as Young Craps Player. Normally a character or supporting actor Baker Hall is actually a good choice as the elderly lead character because he is a wise presence, Reilly is likable as the slow but nice guy that wants to get somewhere in life, and Paltrow does pretty well as the promiscuous woman who is caught in the middle of situations, the story is simple enough, it could have used a bit more action, or the scripting could have tweaked to be wittier and with more pace, but it isn't too bad of a film debut from Anderson, a not bad crime drama. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quirky and confident - decent debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie starts of with the silent and reserved Sydney (Philip Baker Hall) entering a roadside cafeteria, where he comes across a down-trodden John (John C. Reilly). Sydney takes a strong interest in John, where he attempts to offer the younger man solutions to his problems by offering his key services: the talents of a professional gambler. After this encounter John ties himself to the old dog and becomes his prot&eacute;g&eacute;. A few years down the line John finds a love interest in Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow), waitress / part-time hooker, which in turn initiates a sequence of events that change the nature of the relationship between the two men. American cinema loves its cars, its gangsters and its gambling, while art-house delves passionately into quirkiness. I for one never really found inspiration or admiration to either of the mentioned themes. "Hard Eight" dabbles with two of them: gambling with a touch of quirky characters. Nonetheless the story does prove emotionally involving to some level, although underdone and at times hollow or open-ended. The latter is in part due to the restrained character development and jumpy plotting, which delivers us to required locations, but ignores opportunities to connect the dots. Basically "Hard Eight" (in almost Tarantinesque fashion) concentrated the movie around several key scenes, full of emotional full, content and a decent amount of talking, while the rest of the scenes are subservient and essentially meaningless filler. The sell of the story heavily lies on Philip Baker Hall's shoulders, as he does his job excellently with a even-handed, but scene-grabbing, performance. Nonetheless not a thoroughly involving and passable debut (full of beginner's jitters) by the great Paul Thomas Anderson, which nonetheless shows his qualities as a director, especially in regards to actor interaction. Some of the cinematography was questionable and slightly amateurish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent debut for Anderson, but it's not quite there
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Paul Thomas Anderson's debut shows off some of his talent - the excellent work he drives out of character actors in lead parts, effective atmosphere creation and great camera work. Hard Eight doesn't have the spark of There Will Be Blood, Magnolia or Boogie Nights, though, and the script feels half-baked; as a result, the fantastic actors do a great job with very flat characters, and neither them nor the story holds any interest. The effect of this, ironically, is that the film's best scene is a five-minute nameless cameo by Philip Seymour Hoffman. Not surprising that he's had the most impressive career of these actors, while Philip Baker Hall is still to all intents and purposes Detective Bookman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well thought out character study
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    superokapi
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    PT Anderson's first film is a good one, it may be low budget but it packs a quartet of gripping performances. Many people may look at this and think it is an action/crime movie but it is not. This film is a study of a man reaching out in guilt to help others and of the consequences when his prot&eacute;g&eacute; makes some poor friends. The best character in this film to watch is Sydney himself as the kind of man who has been doing the same thing for the last umpteen years and realizes he needs to make an impact in someone's life to make his life worthwhile. Baker Hall's performance is scene stealing, and he takes a character who uses subtle gestures and queues to make a point and lets him dominate the other characters with it. Much credit must be given to Anderson's screenplay for it's ear for character not plot driven dialogue, much like Tarantino, Anderson lets anecdotes and quips reveal details and traits of his characters. My personal favourite scene was the scene in the beginning when Sydney meets John's new friends and is able to read them both like books all without interrogation style questions. This film is worthwhile and rewarding, a good choice for a person who likes thoughtful dialogue and engaging characters.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The last film I needed to watch from Paul Thomas Anderson was his debut Hard Eight and it was a solid start of his illustrious career. I liked how mysterious Philip Baker Hall's character Sydney is for the most part of the film, making you always wonder what are his real intentions with John. Samuel L. Jackson, John C. Reilly and Gwyneth Paltrow give fine performances too, but none of their characters were likable or very interesting for me, so I didn't really care for them. John and Clementine make some bad and even ridiculous decisions sometimes, so it's a bit hard to feel sorry for them when things so wrong. I enjoyed the big reveal of Sydney, being an unpredictable turn of events and that was a great way to establish his real ties with John. While the ending is quite predictable and didn't have much of an impact for me, Hard Eight is still a nice effort from Paul Thomas Anderson.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    naturalistic and character driven.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carlhartwell78
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Hard Eight, first time director Paul Thomas Anderson has constructed a subtle yet powerful commentary on redemption, it's prices and ultimately, its viability. Sydney (Philip Baker Hall) is a professional gambler, we know nothing about his background for most of the film but it becomes quickly apparent that he spends most of his time in casinos (with only brief respites in dinners). At the outset he comes upon John (John C. Reilly) a down and out, apparent loser, whom Sydney takes under his wing. Sydney teaches John, first how to gain casino hospitality with very little loss and eventually mentors him in the ways of professional gambling. For the majority of the film, the intrigue lies in the fact that he seems to have no motive for doing any of this, and it only grows when Sydney seems only too willing to help Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow) out of her damaging lifestyle as well. A cocktail waitress and part time hooker, Clementine, had captured Johns affections and ultimately brings things to a head with a particularly senseless mistake. The fourth (and last) main character is Jimmy (Samuel L. Jackson), who is a friend of Johns, but who Sydney has little time for. The Film is almost entirely character driven and contains impeccable performances by all involved, indeed it has to since the plot is not nearly strong enough without them. Of course it's no bad thing that the plot isn't strong, it's not that type of film, largely any "situation" that happens isn't there for any reason other than to show how the characters react. Hall's performance is particularly impressive, chiefly since his characters motivation isn't fully revealed until about 15 minutes before the end. Despite this he carries the film majestically and one cannot help but get the sense that Sydey is significant and incredibly fascinating. No mean feat when the audience knows so little about his character. Reilly, Paltrow and Jackson's performances are commendable also, but for me, their characters serve mostly as secondary characters to Sydney's. That's not to say that they come across as anything but very three dimensional, each actor has at least one scene in which to shine and shine they do. One of the films many strengths is in it's extremely naturalistic tone, not of course uncommon in many films, but done to perfection in this one. The script constantly has all of the characters stumbling over or at a loss for words, and we're often given the impression that they're completely clueless and out of their depths, they seem like real people! Two scenes in particular stand out as testament to this, the motel room scene and the car scene towards the end with Jackson and Hall. Both are so realistic that one can imagine they were hardly scripted at all. The film, though perhaps not a masterpiece, is extremely good and upon it's release, demonstrated great promise in it's director, who of course went on to direct the sublime Magnolia. It entices the viewer to contemplate the very idea of forgiveness. To what extent does a persons past affect how we perceive him, are some acts truly irredeemable?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Haunting, Poignant & Tense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The unusual circumstances in which two men meet before going on to become good friends, provides "Hard Eight" with an intriguing opening to a story which also features kidnapping, blackmail and a brutal killing. First-time director/writer Paul Thomas Anderson takes time and care to develop his characters and this approach pays off handsomely, as it's the strength of these characters and the relationships between them that ultimately make this movie so interesting and memorable. The tense atmosphere and deliberate pacing, which are established right from the start, create a closeness between the two men and also add emphasis to the anxieties and suspicions that are present between them, especially during their first meeting. As he approaches a roadside diner somewhere in Nevada, Sydney Brown (Philip Baker Hall), a professional gambler in his sixties, sees a young man who's clearly down-on-his-luck sitting on the ground close to the entrance of the building. He offers to buy him a cup of coffee and give him a cigarette. Sydney soon learns that John (John C Reilly) has lost all his money whilst gambling in an attempt to raise enough cash to pay for his mother's funeral. Sydney offers to show the young man how to be successful in the casinos and despite his understandable scepticism, John agrees. A couple of years later, John has prospered as Sydney's prot&eacute;g&eacute; and after having paid off his mother's funeral costs, gets married to an attractive cocktail waitress called Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow). John has also become friendly with Jimmy (Samuel L Jackson) who's a security officer and a man that Sydney dislikes and really doesn't trust. Clementine's part-time work as a hooker leads to trouble when one of her clients refuses to pay and she and John keep the man hostage in their motel room. Sydney is called to help them out and soon takes control of the situation but also runs into bigger trouble shortly after, when Jimmy threatens and blackmails him. Philip Baker Hall gives a top class performance as the lonely, well dressed, experienced gambler with a face that's filled with sadness and lines. He's dignified and shrewd and looks as if he's been through some tough experiences but also finds it gratifying to help John out. John is another lonely person who appreciates the progress he's made under Sydney's guidance but his poor judgement and gullibility will clearly make it impossible for him to ever fully emulate his mentor's success. John C Reilly, in a consistently strong performance, is very natural and convincing in the way that he portrays John's naivety and impetuosity. Clementine is not as streetwise as she needs to be and Gwyneth Paltrow conveys her character's underlying sadness very effectively. Samuel L Jackson is also on great form as the violent thug who totally underestimates Sydney. "Hard Eight" is haunting and poignant and its overall tone and tempo is perfect for a movie in which a dark secret, hidden motives and a need for redemption affect so much of what takes place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazingly accomplished debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red_Identity
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's be clear. This is 2013 and I've seen all of Anderson's other films. While this is probably his weakest (although it's hard to say weakest when they are all great) it's still astonishing how accomplished it feels. You could tell from this film the filmmaker that Anderson would go on to become, and with just six films he's already one of my 5 all-time favorites. The whole cast here is solid, but Baker is amazing in his role, not very spoken, his motivations always ambiguous. Anderson isn't here to spell out everything, and instead the film plays out very nicely and smoothly. Great accomplishment, and it's also fun seeing Philip Seymour Hoffman in his great little cameo
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to Watch, but...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RabbitValleyRebel
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I adore and respect the opening scene. All stories need to start somewhere, and this one started with style, in a setting that most of us have frequented...a Denny's Restaurant basically. Throughout the film, we are made acutely aware of the precious value of food, a bed, coffee, cigarettes, cable movies, and companionship, for someone who has been deprived these things before. Most of us probably take them for granted,unless we have been down-and-out like one of the film's protagonists. But think about how relieved you feel on a long road trip, when you stop at a motel, and partake of these things, after being trapped in your car for hours. They satiate us and bring a sense of domestic tranquility. I needed more character development. Sorry, to those who loved this film. I get the fact that it was a portrayal of "outsider" life and the casino-bubble, but I still needed to know a bit more about how these people became who they are. The plot device of not knowing why the hell Hall is being a caretaker, worked for a while, but eventually I became annoyed with guessing. The final explanation was anti-climatic and cheap. Come on, you can do better than that. Hoffman stole the show with his very brief cameo. Jackson was his usual profane loudmouth stereotype. Hall and Reilly did not have to stretch much, but they were still quite adept at portraying unspoken sadness. I'm not a fan of Paltrow, but she conveyed the torn nature of her character quite well. One other reviewer mentioned the fact that sometimes the characters don't know what to say, but that made it realistic. I totally agree. Real people rarely speak like movie characters. But in this one, the characters did speak like real people. Great job with that. There were enough good aspects to this film, to make it worth seeing. But it is a labor to watch after a while, because not much happens, and not much is said. If you like art films, you will probably like this one. It reminded me of the work of Jim Jarmusch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Smashing Debut For P.T. Anderson.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Paul Thomas Anderson comes his directorial debut, that movie is his 1996 movie known as Hard Eight. And is this movie any good? I'll tell you right now, this movie is a smashing movie, it's greatly acted, greatly written, and greatly directed. Paul Thomas Anderson is a director who does all of his own screen writing, he was only 26 when me made this movie, and not only did he direct it, but he also wrote the screenplay for it, and he wrote it singlehandedly. This movie tells the story of a gambler who meets a young man and makes him an offer to make money, and during the course of this journey, the two men are drawn close to each other in what becomes a father and son relationship, however, events put the relationship in jeopardy. Paul Thomas Anderson tells the story pretty straight forward, the story involves success, romance, setbacks, and numerous other things, all while keeping the viewer focused on what is going on. I really admire P.T. Anderson for writing all of his own screenplays, because there aren't many directors who singlehandedly write their own scripts and manage to stay good. As usual in a P.T. Anderson film, the acting is Oscar-Worthy. Phillip Baker Hall is outstanding as Sydney, the gambler who makes the offer to John C. Reilly's character. John C. Reilly's performance was wonderful too, as where the performances of Gwyneth Paltrow and Samuel L. Jackson. However, if I had to say who's performance in this movie was the best, that would be none other than Phillip Baker Hall. Phillip Baker Hall's performance was worthy of a nomination for the Academy Award for Best Actor, he was in a class by himself. And just think, after this movie, Paul Thomas Anderson would direct five more movies that would receive all sorts of acclaim, Boogie Nights, Magnolia, Punch-Drunk Love, There Will Be Blood, and his most recent movie, The Master. Hard Eight marked the start of greatness for a master film director and screenwriter, Paul Thomas Anderson, who is one of the best directors and screenwriters in recent years. This is a movie that you have got to see if you haven't seen it yet, as it is the film that made Paul Thomas Anderson famous, and it's worth seeing for the wonderful performances from the cast. It makes me so happy that there are actually people out there who still do care about making great movies, as nowadays, we get a lot of rubbish with nonstop explosions and too many flashy special effects and not to mention a lot of CGI. But every now and then, there are directors like Martin Scorsese, The Coen Brothers, and of course, Paul Thomas Anderson, who actually do care about making movies the way that movies are supposed to be made. Well anyway, Hard Eight is an outstanding masterpiece, if you've yet to see this movie, then all I can say is that you've definitely got to see it, because you will say exactly what many people have said already, that this movie is the outstanding writing and directorial debut of a master. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard Eight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From director Paul Thomas Anderson (Boogie Nights, Magnolia, There Will Be Blood), this was a film I would obviously have never heard of unless it was broadcast on television, and it looked interesting because of an impressive cast list, and was likely to be an independent film, so I was up for trying it. Basically Sydney (Bruce Almighty's Philip Baker Hall) is a sixty year old gamble, who outside a diner meets young man John (John C. Reilly) and offers him a cigarette, then a coffee, and then the opportunity to make the money that he needs for his mother's burial, this would mean travelling to Las Vegas and learning ways of making the money and getting by. After some scepticism John agrees, and he follows the advice of his new friend, and two years later John has the money that he needed for the funeral, he has become Sydney's prot&eacute;g&eacute; staying in Reno, and he has made himself a friend in security worker Jimmy (Samuel L. Jackson), and he is also attracted to and dating cocktail waitress Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow). Late one night Sydney gets a frantic phone call from John, and at the motel he is staying in with Clementine he finds they have kidnapped a man and held him hostage because he wouldn't pay Clementine for her prostitution, and the situation is a little worse because John and Clementine got married. The situation is resolved in some way by Sydney, but he advises the newlyweds to get away and go on a honeymoon, he suggests Niagara Falls, and after they do leave Sydney is confronted by Jimmy who is demanding money in blackmail because he knows a secret that the sixty year old doesn't want to come out, this is that Sydney killed John's father. The old man gives in and pays him the money, but he later goes late at night into Jimmy's house to shoot him dead, and the end sees him return to the diner where he first met John, brushing the blood off his shirt cuff, it is unclear whether his friends finds out the dark secret he has. Also starring F. William Parker as Hostage and Philip Seymour Hoffman as Young Craps Player. Normally a character or supporting actor Baker Hall is actually a good choice as the elderly lead character because he is a wise presence, Reilly is likable as the slow but nice guy that wants to get somewhere in life, and Paltrow does pretty well as the promiscuous woman who is caught in the middle of situations, the story is simple enough, it could have used a bit more action, or the scripting could have tweaked to be wittier and with more pace, but it isn't too bad of a film debut from Anderson, a not bad crime drama. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quirky and confident - decent debut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie starts of with the silent and reserved Sydney (Philip Baker Hall) entering a roadside cafeteria, where he comes across a down-trodden John (John C. Reilly). Sydney takes a strong interest in John, where he attempts to offer the younger man solutions to his problems by offering his key services: the talents of a professional gambler. After this encounter John ties himself to the old dog and becomes his prot&eacute;g&eacute;. A few years down the line John finds a love interest in Clementine (Gwyneth Paltrow), waitress / part-time hooker, which in turn initiates a sequence of events that change the nature of the relationship between the two men. American cinema loves its cars, its gangsters and its gambling, while art-house delves passionately into quirkiness. I for one never really found inspiration or admiration to either of the mentioned themes. "Hard Eight" dabbles with two of them: gambling with a touch of quirky characters. Nonetheless the story does prove emotionally involving to some level, although underdone and at times hollow or open-ended. The latter is in part due to the restrained character development and jumpy plotting, which delivers us to required locations, but ignores opportunities to connect the dots. Basically "Hard Eight" (in almost Tarantinesque fashion) concentrated the movie around several key scenes, full of emotional full, content and a decent amount of talking, while the rest of the scenes are subservient and essentially meaningless filler. The sell of the story heavily lies on Philip Baker Hall's shoulders, as he does his job excellently with a even-handed, but scene-grabbing, performance. Nonetheless not a thoroughly involving and passable debut (full of beginner's jitters) by the great Paul Thomas Anderson, which nonetheless shows his qualities as a director, especially in regards to actor interaction. Some of the cinematography was questionable and slightly amateurish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent debut for Anderson, but it's not quite there
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Paul Thomas Anderson's debut shows off some of his talent - the excellent work he drives out of character actors in lead parts, effective atmosphere creation and great camera work. Hard Eight doesn't have the spark of There Will Be Blood, Magnolia or Boogie Nights, though, and the script feels half-baked; as a result, the fantastic actors do a great job with very flat characters, and neither them nor the story holds any interest. The effect of this, ironically, is that the film's best scene is a five-minute nameless cameo by Philip Seymour Hoffman. Not surprising that he's had the most impressive career of these actors, while Philip Baker Hall is still to all intents and purposes Detective Bookman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well thought out character study
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    superokapi
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    PT Anderson's first film is a good one, it may be low budget but it packs a quartet of gripping performances. Many people may look at this and think it is an action/crime movie but it is not. This film is a study of a man reaching out in guilt to help others and of the consequences when his prot&eacute;g&eacute; makes some poor friends. The best character in this film to watch is Sydney himself as the kind of man who has been doing the same thing for the last umpteen years and realizes he needs to make an impact in someone's life to make his life worthwhile. Baker Hall's performance is scene stealing, and he takes a character who uses subtle gestures and queues to make a point and lets him dominate the other characters with it. Much credit must be given to Anderson's screenplay for it's ear for character not plot driven dialogue, much like Tarantino, Anderson lets anecdotes and quips reveal details and traits of his characters. My personal favourite scene was the scene in the beginning when Sydney meets John's new friends and is able to read them both like books all without interrogation style questions. This film is worthwhile and rewarding, a good choice for a person who likes thoughtful dialogue and engaging characters.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
