<filme>
 <id>
  1152
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116621
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  No Amor e na Guerra
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Reporter Ernest Hemingway is an ambulance driver in Italy during World War I. While bravely risking his life in the line of duty, he is injured and ends up in the hospital, where he falls ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Reporter Ernest Hemingway is an ambulance driver in Italy during World War I. While bravely risking his life in the line of duty, he is injured and ends up in the hospital, where he falls in love with his nurse, Agnes von Kurowsky.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Biography
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   ernest hemingway
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   nurse
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   driver
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   ambulance driver
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   world war one
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Richard Attenborough
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Henry S. Villard
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   James Nagel
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Sandra Bullock
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Chris O'Donnell
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Mackenzie Astin
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Boy Papa
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leonard Maltin rates this a bomb in his review, but I didn't think it was so bad. It's definitely got a Mills & Boon feel to it, but then what would you expect from a wartime love story called In Love and War? And you know straight off that any film directed by Richard Attenborough is going to have an old-fashioned feel about it. I even quite liked Chris O'Donnell as the young Ernest Hemingway  young, dumb and full of something unmentionable, who falls for the nurse who fights to save his leg when the Italian doctor  who will become Hemingway's love rival  is intent on chopping it off. For me, O'Donnell has just the right mix of youthful macho posturing and roguish charm that the film calls for. Sandra Bullock looks perhaps a little too lovely as the nurse for whom Hemingway falls, even when she's covered in blood and dirt, but still gives a decent performance  and any star up for collecting their Razzie award in person always shoots way up in my estimation. The film also looks good. I liked it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In Love And War Agnes & Hemingway
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johneberwine
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always liked Sandra Bullock as an actress; I think she can play any part, any role and make you believe she is that person being portrayed. I believe she is one of the top 3 actresses in the USA, maybe even first. I also have always been intrigued by Ernest Hemingway and his tragic suicide. I've read a few of his books over the years. So when I saw this movie coming on Cable, I thought it might be interesting. Calling this a love story does not give it justice; to call it a war story also does not give justice; It is a Romantic Tragedy, one that, "I'm sure", everyone who saw the film was hoping for Ernest to turn around and call out to Agnes at the end!!! I would have, in a split second, but Ernest's ego would not allow. How different his remaining life may have been had he just overcome his stubbornness. The old expression, "Tis better to have loved and lost, than never to have loved at all." hardly seems to fit here; I believe both Agnes and Ernest suffered painfully all the remainder of their lives because of his decision to not turn around! How sorrowful for Agnes!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Offensively superficial
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stevemt
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it hadn't been about Ernest Hemingway the move would have been a mediocre, quickly digested and forgotten romance. If you know anything about Hemingway the movie is basically unwatchable. Chris O'Donnel's "Hemingway" is nothing but your stereotypical, one dimensional "kid goes off to war" type and seems to bear no relation to Hemingway himself. Sandra Bullock manages to bring a little depth to her character which I am guessing was dead on the page. She earned a little respect from me in that regard. If you want to watch this movie because you are interested in the subject matter, for the love of God skip it. If you just want to watch a mindless romance and you've chosen this one because it's the most available to you at the moment, go ahead I guess, just don't feel like you've learned something from it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pace?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    p-hogan1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a Hemmingway fan. I like Sandra Bullock, was very impressed with the cinematography. Production values are very high. Attenborough is a load of Emperor's clothes. I was interested to watch this film but it was --so--very--slow. Like many films and television programmes it seems to be made on the economic film principle, where, having got the cast and crew to a location/set the l-o-n-g-e-r the screen time that can be dragged out there, the cheaper the 'per minute' cost of the whole film. Whereas a single shot used to average about 3 seconds we now get 3 seconds establishing the characters in a place, a slow two shot sequence of slow moody conversation with pregnant pauses (nine months!?) and eventually one character leaves while the other pulls faces to the music, sometimes for as long as another 11 seconds.Having established the hospital we do not need to keep seeing it or people walking about it without advancing the plot. The ironic thing with this film is that Hemmingway wrote like John Ford directed. Ford started the camera and the actor on the mark and put his fist over the lens as he shouted 'cut'. One take and no way for the studio to drag out the editing. Casablanca takes place 90% in a caf&eacute;'e, slow? No. Curtiz did not need 600 horses to get pace.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rozinda
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Excellently cast, poignant movie. Sandra Bullock as always shines and is given a part that lives up to her quality. Attenbrough directs with unfailing dignity and control. I know nothing of Hemingway except what this movie tells us. I've never read his work. This tender story of late-teen Hemingway in WW1 and the somewhat older nurse he falls in love with is wonderful viewing. You may wonder why she decides in the end not to marry him, but I suggest it is because he is still so very young and she's afraid he will grow bored with her after a few years. After a war, so many men have died, and there are so many surplus women vying for the attention of the men who are left. I would assume the Agnes was uncertain that she could hold him, or uncertain that he could hold her. In any case, she's rightly tempted by the doctor's offer to help run his new hospital, though I can't say I'd have thought that would make a good personal marriage as well so thank goodness it didn't really happen. Apparently, the real Ernest and Agnes did not meet again after the war although there was a little correspondence, but the movie shows Agnes visiting Ernest and finally telling him to his face that she loves him and clearly hoping the relationship will recommence. Unfortunately there has to be a reason why in the movie it can't since in real life it didn't, so Ernest is shown in a childish rage and she has to walk away, humiliated and despairing, never to see him again but saying, "I love you. I will love you for the rest of my life..." whilst he's left weeping - out of her sight. Now just suppose if she'd turned back..... I can't say I thought it would be wise for this relationship to continue - Ernest's rage is too intense, it wouldn't bode well for a marriage. He was either too immature or in some other way unsuitable to become her husband and she had been mistaken to be tempted to go back to him, so I would suggest, in the context of the movie, she had a very lucky escape. What she will think, after a while, is "Well, I've seen him. I was right the first time. It wouldn't work. This gives me closure." And she'll move on. This scene is so beautifully handled by the actors that it saddens me to have to object strongly to it being included and that's why I drop my rating from 10 to 9. In all other ways but this one unfortunate scene, this movie is a 10-star. Of course, it suits a movie maker to leave the ending bitter and hurtful to both of them, a ghastly final meeting when they are both despairing even though it's clear a reunion would have been more likely, or at least a relationship for a while, seeing they both actually seemed to want it. How frustrating this kind of scene is once you've got over the tear-jerking reaction, typical irritating aspect of movie making trying to extract every last emotion, not all that realistic sometimes. So then I looked on the internet for information re the real people. I see Agnes wrote to him explaining she had firmly decided he was too young for her and the marriage would be a mistake. That's how this movie should have ended - Bullock writing this letter and Ernest perhaps slinging it into the lake, but then rescuing it and putting it somewhere safe. And then an indication that they corresponded a little more for a while. A gentle, realistic ending that didn't humiliate either real person. But please, still go and see the movie as it's otherwise completely wonderful and if you can forget the real people you may love the finale as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Real Hemingway
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mrgolf145
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Agnes Von Kurowsky denied up to her dying day that she and "Ernie" had a sexual relationship. Considering his reputation for exaggeration and out and out lying I'll take her word. In his earlier years he was a brilliant writer before alcohol abuse and depression did him in. He was also a liar, braggart, bully, racist, anti-Semite,misogynist and an easy rider who lived off the trust funds of his first two wives, Hadley and Pauline. If he was so Macho and eager for Combat then I guess he would have joined the American Army and volunteered for infantry duty in France instead of driving an ambulance in Italy and being wounded accidentally taking cigarettes and candy to real soldiers on the front lines.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pleasant and interesting true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guynvistaca
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought the acting was perfect and the story very true. As I watched this film I googled Ernest Hemingway and read what I was actually seeing on the screen. To capsule this mans life in a little under two hours is almost impossible-but I liked the way we were able to see the early life of this great writer. Sandra Bullock always in top form as an actress gives a sweet performance as Agnes and Chris O'Donnell was a good catch for the young Hemingway-if you look at his early photos you will see that he was not as gruff as in his older years. A bit more sensitive and caring than his older years. Might be a bit slow for some but the war moments were very real and the scenery of Italy was stunning!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hemingway's First Love All Wrong
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CitizenCaine
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris O'Donnell and Sandra Bullock star in Richard Attenborough's story of Hemingway's first love with Agnes Kurowsky, the red cross nurse. It's near the end of World War I and the young Hemingway finds love with an older red cross nurse behind the trenches after he's injured helping an infantryman to safety. This must be the Hallmark greeting card version of the story because the scenery is great, the period authentic, the dialog sentimental and proper, and the chemistry between the leads completely absent. O'Donnell has absolutely no zest to foreshadow the larger than life figure the famous Hemingway was. Maybe that was part of the point Attenborough was making with the film: the romance was more of a young man's fancy than reality. This was a film made in retrospect after the discovery of Kurowsky's love letters with the young Hemingway, and it stands to reason the truth was softened somewhat to make for a romanticized story. Some viewers will question the notion implied by the epilogue of how this episode influenced the elder Hemingway. He later wrote A Farewell To Arms, which of course he based on this same episode of his life. That film, at least the older version from the thirties, is far more satisfying than what viewers will see here. This appears to have been made strictly for the Lifetime network crowd. ** of 4 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nonsense in the Trivia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freelance-7
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trivia. "Attenborough had wanted Julia Roberts to play the female lead at one time but by the time the film was made she had become too old for the part." Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967). Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967). Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967). Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967). Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967). Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In Love and War
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From Lord Sir Richard Attenborough directing, I thought Cry Freedom was better, but this is okay in some ways. It tells the story of Ernest 'Ernie' Hemingway (Chris O'Donnell), the young soldier who volunteered to fight in the front line during World War I. Unfortunately, while rescuing another soldier, and escaping, he was shot in the leg, and his friend who see later was covered in injury. Agnes 'Aggie/Ag' Von Kurowsky (Sandra Bullock) is the nurse who tries to help him without having his leg cutoff, because of gangrene. During treatment and time in the hospital Ernie forms a close friendship with Aggie, and soon it becomes a question as to whether they are in love. They get the chance to get together before Ernie leaves for a mission, but after, she dumps him for another man. Later, she realises it was a mistake, but Ernie can't forgive her, and they never see each other again after a final chat. Okay!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Boy Papa
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leonard Maltin rates this a bomb in his review, but I didn't think it was so bad. It's definitely got a Mills & Boon feel to it, but then what would you expect from a wartime love story called In Love and War? And you know straight off that any film directed by Richard Attenborough is going to have an old-fashioned feel about it. I even quite liked Chris O'Donnell as the young Ernest Hemingway  young, dumb and full of something unmentionable, who falls for the nurse who fights to save his leg when the Italian doctor  who will become Hemingway's love rival  is intent on chopping it off. For me, O'Donnell has just the right mix of youthful macho posturing and roguish charm that the film calls for. Sandra Bullock looks perhaps a little too lovely as the nurse for whom Hemingway falls, even when she's covered in blood and dirt, but still gives a decent performance  and any star up for collecting their Razzie award in person always shoots way up in my estimation. The film also looks good. I liked it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In Love And War Agnes & Hemingway
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johneberwine
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always liked Sandra Bullock as an actress; I think she can play any part, any role and make you believe she is that person being portrayed. I believe she is one of the top 3 actresses in the USA, maybe even first. I also have always been intrigued by Ernest Hemingway and his tragic suicide. I've read a few of his books over the years. So when I saw this movie coming on Cable, I thought it might be interesting. Calling this a love story does not give it justice; to call it a war story also does not give justice; It is a Romantic Tragedy, one that, "I'm sure", everyone who saw the film was hoping for Ernest to turn around and call out to Agnes at the end!!! I would have, in a split second, but Ernest's ego would not allow. How different his remaining life may have been had he just overcome his stubbornness. The old expression, "Tis better to have loved and lost, than never to have loved at all." hardly seems to fit here; I believe both Agnes and Ernest suffered painfully all the remainder of their lives because of his decision to not turn around! How sorrowful for Agnes!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Offensively superficial
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stevemt
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it hadn't been about Ernest Hemingway the move would have been a mediocre, quickly digested and forgotten romance. If you know anything about Hemingway the movie is basically unwatchable. Chris O'Donnel's "Hemingway" is nothing but your stereotypical, one dimensional "kid goes off to war" type and seems to bear no relation to Hemingway himself. Sandra Bullock manages to bring a little depth to her character which I am guessing was dead on the page. She earned a little respect from me in that regard. If you want to watch this movie because you are interested in the subject matter, for the love of God skip it. If you just want to watch a mindless romance and you've chosen this one because it's the most available to you at the moment, go ahead I guess, just don't feel like you've learned something from it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pace?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    p-hogan1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a Hemmingway fan. I like Sandra Bullock, was very impressed with the cinematography. Production values are very high. Attenborough is a load of Emperor's clothes. I was interested to watch this film but it was --so--very--slow. Like many films and television programmes it seems to be made on the economic film principle, where, having got the cast and crew to a location/set the l-o-n-g-e-r the screen time that can be dragged out there, the cheaper the 'per minute' cost of the whole film. Whereas a single shot used to average about 3 seconds we now get 3 seconds establishing the characters in a place, a slow two shot sequence of slow moody conversation with pregnant pauses (nine months!?) and eventually one character leaves while the other pulls faces to the music, sometimes for as long as another 11 seconds.Having established the hospital we do not need to keep seeing it or people walking about it without advancing the plot. The ironic thing with this film is that Hemmingway wrote like John Ford directed. Ford started the camera and the actor on the mark and put his fist over the lens as he shouted 'cut'. One take and no way for the studio to drag out the editing. Casablanca takes place 90% in a caf&eacute;'e, slow? No. Curtiz did not need 600 horses to get pace.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rozinda
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Excellently cast, poignant movie. Sandra Bullock as always shines and is given a part that lives up to her quality. Attenbrough directs with unfailing dignity and control. I know nothing of Hemingway except what this movie tells us. I've never read his work. This tender story of late-teen Hemingway in WW1 and the somewhat older nurse he falls in love with is wonderful viewing. You may wonder why she decides in the end not to marry him, but I suggest it is because he is still so very young and she's afraid he will grow bored with her after a few years. After a war, so many men have died, and there are so many surplus women vying for the attention of the men who are left. I would assume the Agnes was uncertain that she could hold him, or uncertain that he could hold her. In any case, she's rightly tempted by the doctor's offer to help run his new hospital, though I can't say I'd have thought that would make a good personal marriage as well so thank goodness it didn't really happen. Apparently, the real Ernest and Agnes did not meet again after the war although there was a little correspondence, but the movie shows Agnes visiting Ernest and finally telling him to his face that she loves him and clearly hoping the relationship will recommence. Unfortunately there has to be a reason why in the movie it can't since in real life it didn't, so Ernest is shown in a childish rage and she has to walk away, humiliated and despairing, never to see him again but saying, "I love you. I will love you for the rest of my life..." whilst he's left weeping - out of her sight. Now just suppose if she'd turned back..... I can't say I thought it would be wise for this relationship to continue - Ernest's rage is too intense, it wouldn't bode well for a marriage. He was either too immature or in some other way unsuitable to become her husband and she had been mistaken to be tempted to go back to him, so I would suggest, in the context of the movie, she had a very lucky escape. What she will think, after a while, is "Well, I've seen him. I was right the first time. It wouldn't work. This gives me closure." And she'll move on. This scene is so beautifully handled by the actors that it saddens me to have to object strongly to it being included and that's why I drop my rating from 10 to 9. In all other ways but this one unfortunate scene, this movie is a 10-star. Of course, it suits a movie maker to leave the ending bitter and hurtful to both of them, a ghastly final meeting when they are both despairing even though it's clear a reunion would have been more likely, or at least a relationship for a while, seeing they both actually seemed to want it. How frustrating this kind of scene is once you've got over the tear-jerking reaction, typical irritating aspect of movie making trying to extract every last emotion, not all that realistic sometimes. So then I looked on the internet for information re the real people. I see Agnes wrote to him explaining she had firmly decided he was too young for her and the marriage would be a mistake. That's how this movie should have ended - Bullock writing this letter and Ernest perhaps slinging it into the lake, but then rescuing it and putting it somewhere safe. And then an indication that they corresponded a little more for a while. A gentle, realistic ending that didn't humiliate either real person. But please, still go and see the movie as it's otherwise completely wonderful and if you can forget the real people you may love the finale as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Real Hemingway
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mrgolf145
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Agnes Von Kurowsky denied up to her dying day that she and "Ernie" had a sexual relationship. Considering his reputation for exaggeration and out and out lying I'll take her word. In his earlier years he was a brilliant writer before alcohol abuse and depression did him in. He was also a liar, braggart, bully, racist, anti-Semite,misogynist and an easy rider who lived off the trust funds of his first two wives, Hadley and Pauline. If he was so Macho and eager for Combat then I guess he would have joined the American Army and volunteered for infantry duty in France instead of driving an ambulance in Italy and being wounded accidentally taking cigarettes and candy to real soldiers on the front lines.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pleasant and interesting true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guynvistaca
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought the acting was perfect and the story very true. As I watched this film I googled Ernest Hemingway and read what I was actually seeing on the screen. To capsule this mans life in a little under two hours is almost impossible-but I liked the way we were able to see the early life of this great writer. Sandra Bullock always in top form as an actress gives a sweet performance as Agnes and Chris O'Donnell was a good catch for the young Hemingway-if you look at his early photos you will see that he was not as gruff as in his older years. A bit more sensitive and caring than his older years. Might be a bit slow for some but the war moments were very real and the scenery of Italy was stunning!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hemingway's First Love All Wrong
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CitizenCaine
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris O'Donnell and Sandra Bullock star in Richard Attenborough's story of Hemingway's first love with Agnes Kurowsky, the red cross nurse. It's near the end of World War I and the young Hemingway finds love with an older red cross nurse behind the trenches after he's injured helping an infantryman to safety. This must be the Hallmark greeting card version of the story because the scenery is great, the period authentic, the dialog sentimental and proper, and the chemistry between the leads completely absent. O'Donnell has absolutely no zest to foreshadow the larger than life figure the famous Hemingway was. Maybe that was part of the point Attenborough was making with the film: the romance was more of a young man's fancy than reality. This was a film made in retrospect after the discovery of Kurowsky's love letters with the young Hemingway, and it stands to reason the truth was softened somewhat to make for a romanticized story. Some viewers will question the notion implied by the epilogue of how this episode influenced the elder Hemingway. He later wrote A Farewell To Arms, which of course he based on this same episode of his life. That film, at least the older version from the thirties, is far more satisfying than what viewers will see here. This appears to have been made strictly for the Lifetime network crowd. ** of 4 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nonsense in the Trivia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freelance-7
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trivia. "Attenborough had wanted Julia Roberts to play the female lead at one time but by the time the film was made she had become too old for the part." Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967). Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967). Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967). Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967). Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967). Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In Love and War
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From Lord Sir Richard Attenborough directing, I thought Cry Freedom was better, but this is okay in some ways. It tells the story of Ernest 'Ernie' Hemingway (Chris O'Donnell), the young soldier who volunteered to fight in the front line during World War I. Unfortunately, while rescuing another soldier, and escaping, he was shot in the leg, and his friend who see later was covered in injury. Agnes 'Aggie/Ag' Von Kurowsky (Sandra Bullock) is the nurse who tries to help him without having his leg cutoff, because of gangrene. During treatment and time in the hospital Ernie forms a close friendship with Aggie, and soon it becomes a question as to whether they are in love. They get the chance to get together before Ernie leaves for a mission, but after, she dumps him for another man. Later, she realises it was a mistake, but Ernie can't forgive her, and they never see each other again after a final chat. Okay!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Boy Papa
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leonard Maltin rates this a bomb in his review, but I didn't think it was so bad. It's definitely got a Mills & Boon feel to it, but then what would you expect from a wartime love story called In Love and War? And you know straight off that any film directed by Richard Attenborough is going to have an old-fashioned feel about it. I even quite liked Chris O'Donnell as the young Ernest Hemingway  young, dumb and full of something unmentionable, who falls for the nurse who fights to save his leg when the Italian doctor  who will become Hemingway's love rival  is intent on chopping it off. For me, O'Donnell has just the right mix of youthful macho posturing and roguish charm that the film calls for. Sandra Bullock looks perhaps a little too lovely as the nurse for whom Hemingway falls, even when she's covered in blood and dirt, but still gives a decent performance  and any star up for collecting their Razzie award in person always shoots way up in my estimation. The film also looks good. I liked it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In Love And War Agnes & Hemingway
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johneberwine
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always liked Sandra Bullock as an actress; I think she can play any part, any role and make you believe she is that person being portrayed. I believe she is one of the top 3 actresses in the USA, maybe even first. I also have always been intrigued by Ernest Hemingway and his tragic suicide. I've read a few of his books over the years. So when I saw this movie coming on Cable, I thought it might be interesting. Calling this a love story does not give it justice; to call it a war story also does not give justice; It is a Romantic Tragedy, one that, "I'm sure", everyone who saw the film was hoping for Ernest to turn around and call out to Agnes at the end!!! I would have, in a split second, but Ernest's ego would not allow. How different his remaining life may have been had he just overcome his stubbornness. The old expression, "Tis better to have loved and lost, than never to have loved at all." hardly seems to fit here; I believe both Agnes and Ernest suffered painfully all the remainder of their lives because of his decision to not turn around! How sorrowful for Agnes!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Offensively superficial
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stevemt
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it hadn't been about Ernest Hemingway the move would have been a mediocre, quickly digested and forgotten romance. If you know anything about Hemingway the movie is basically unwatchable. Chris O'Donnel's "Hemingway" is nothing but your stereotypical, one dimensional "kid goes off to war" type and seems to bear no relation to Hemingway himself. Sandra Bullock manages to bring a little depth to her character which I am guessing was dead on the page. She earned a little respect from me in that regard. If you want to watch this movie because you are interested in the subject matter, for the love of God skip it. If you just want to watch a mindless romance and you've chosen this one because it's the most available to you at the moment, go ahead I guess, just don't feel like you've learned something from it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pace?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    p-hogan1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a Hemmingway fan. I like Sandra Bullock, was very impressed with the cinematography. Production values are very high. Attenborough is a load of Emperor's clothes. I was interested to watch this film but it was --so--very--slow. Like many films and television programmes it seems to be made on the economic film principle, where, having got the cast and crew to a location/set the l-o-n-g-e-r the screen time that can be dragged out there, the cheaper the 'per minute' cost of the whole film. Whereas a single shot used to average about 3 seconds we now get 3 seconds establishing the characters in a place, a slow two shot sequence of slow moody conversation with pregnant pauses (nine months!?) and eventually one character leaves while the other pulls faces to the music, sometimes for as long as another 11 seconds.Having established the hospital we do not need to keep seeing it or people walking about it without advancing the plot. The ironic thing with this film is that Hemmingway wrote like John Ford directed. Ford started the camera and the actor on the mark and put his fist over the lens as he shouted 'cut'. One take and no way for the studio to drag out the editing. Casablanca takes place 90% in a caf&eacute;'e, slow? No. Curtiz did not need 600 horses to get pace.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rozinda
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Excellently cast, poignant movie. Sandra Bullock as always shines and is given a part that lives up to her quality. Attenbrough directs with unfailing dignity and control. I know nothing of Hemingway except what this movie tells us. I've never read his work. This tender story of late-teen Hemingway in WW1 and the somewhat older nurse he falls in love with is wonderful viewing. You may wonder why she decides in the end not to marry him, but I suggest it is because he is still so very young and she's afraid he will grow bored with her after a few years. After a war, so many men have died, and there are so many surplus women vying for the attention of the men who are left. I would assume the Agnes was uncertain that she could hold him, or uncertain that he could hold her. In any case, she's rightly tempted by the doctor's offer to help run his new hospital, though I can't say I'd have thought that would make a good personal marriage as well so thank goodness it didn't really happen. Apparently, the real Ernest and Agnes did not meet again after the war although there was a little correspondence, but the movie shows Agnes visiting Ernest and finally telling him to his face that she loves him and clearly hoping the relationship will recommence. Unfortunately there has to be a reason why in the movie it can't since in real life it didn't, so Ernest is shown in a childish rage and she has to walk away, humiliated and despairing, never to see him again but saying, "I love you. I will love you for the rest of my life..." whilst he's left weeping - out of her sight. Now just suppose if she'd turned back..... I can't say I thought it would be wise for this relationship to continue - Ernest's rage is too intense, it wouldn't bode well for a marriage. He was either too immature or in some other way unsuitable to become her husband and she had been mistaken to be tempted to go back to him, so I would suggest, in the context of the movie, she had a very lucky escape. What she will think, after a while, is "Well, I've seen him. I was right the first time. It wouldn't work. This gives me closure." And she'll move on. This scene is so beautifully handled by the actors that it saddens me to have to object strongly to it being included and that's why I drop my rating from 10 to 9. In all other ways but this one unfortunate scene, this movie is a 10-star. Of course, it suits a movie maker to leave the ending bitter and hurtful to both of them, a ghastly final meeting when they are both despairing even though it's clear a reunion would have been more likely, or at least a relationship for a while, seeing they both actually seemed to want it. How frustrating this kind of scene is once you've got over the tear-jerking reaction, typical irritating aspect of movie making trying to extract every last emotion, not all that realistic sometimes. So then I looked on the internet for information re the real people. I see Agnes wrote to him explaining she had firmly decided he was too young for her and the marriage would be a mistake. That's how this movie should have ended - Bullock writing this letter and Ernest perhaps slinging it into the lake, but then rescuing it and putting it somewhere safe. And then an indication that they corresponded a little more for a while. A gentle, realistic ending that didn't humiliate either real person. But please, still go and see the movie as it's otherwise completely wonderful and if you can forget the real people you may love the finale as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Real Hemingway
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mrgolf145
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Agnes Von Kurowsky denied up to her dying day that she and "Ernie" had a sexual relationship. Considering his reputation for exaggeration and out and out lying I'll take her word. In his earlier years he was a brilliant writer before alcohol abuse and depression did him in. He was also a liar, braggart, bully, racist, anti-Semite,misogynist and an easy rider who lived off the trust funds of his first two wives, Hadley and Pauline. If he was so Macho and eager for Combat then I guess he would have joined the American Army and volunteered for infantry duty in France instead of driving an ambulance in Italy and being wounded accidentally taking cigarettes and candy to real soldiers on the front lines.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pleasant and interesting true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guynvistaca
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought the acting was perfect and the story very true. As I watched this film I googled Ernest Hemingway and read what I was actually seeing on the screen. To capsule this mans life in a little under two hours is almost impossible-but I liked the way we were able to see the early life of this great writer. Sandra Bullock always in top form as an actress gives a sweet performance as Agnes and Chris O'Donnell was a good catch for the young Hemingway-if you look at his early photos you will see that he was not as gruff as in his older years. A bit more sensitive and caring than his older years. Might be a bit slow for some but the war moments were very real and the scenery of Italy was stunning!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hemingway's First Love All Wrong
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CitizenCaine
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris O'Donnell and Sandra Bullock star in Richard Attenborough's story of Hemingway's first love with Agnes Kurowsky, the red cross nurse. It's near the end of World War I and the young Hemingway finds love with an older red cross nurse behind the trenches after he's injured helping an infantryman to safety. This must be the Hallmark greeting card version of the story because the scenery is great, the period authentic, the dialog sentimental and proper, and the chemistry between the leads completely absent. O'Donnell has absolutely no zest to foreshadow the larger than life figure the famous Hemingway was. Maybe that was part of the point Attenborough was making with the film: the romance was more of a young man's fancy than reality. This was a film made in retrospect after the discovery of Kurowsky's love letters with the young Hemingway, and it stands to reason the truth was softened somewhat to make for a romanticized story. Some viewers will question the notion implied by the epilogue of how this episode influenced the elder Hemingway. He later wrote A Farewell To Arms, which of course he based on this same episode of his life. That film, at least the older version from the thirties, is far more satisfying than what viewers will see here. This appears to have been made strictly for the Lifetime network crowd. ** of 4 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nonsense in the Trivia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freelance-7
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trivia. "Attenborough had wanted Julia Roberts to play the female lead at one time but by the time the film was made she had become too old for the part." Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967). Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967). Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967). Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967). Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967). Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In Love and War
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From Lord Sir Richard Attenborough directing, I thought Cry Freedom was better, but this is okay in some ways. It tells the story of Ernest 'Ernie' Hemingway (Chris O'Donnell), the young soldier who volunteered to fight in the front line during World War I. Unfortunately, while rescuing another soldier, and escaping, he was shot in the leg, and his friend who see later was covered in injury. Agnes 'Aggie/Ag' Von Kurowsky (Sandra Bullock) is the nurse who tries to help him without having his leg cutoff, because of gangrene. During treatment and time in the hospital Ernie forms a close friendship with Aggie, and soon it becomes a question as to whether they are in love. They get the chance to get together before Ernie leaves for a mission, but after, she dumps him for another man. Later, she realises it was a mistake, but Ernie can't forgive her, and they never see each other again after a final chat. Okay!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Boy Papa
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leonard Maltin rates this a bomb in his review, but I didn't think it was so bad. It's definitely got a Mills & Boon feel to it, but then what would you expect from a wartime love story called In Love and War? And you know straight off that any film directed by Richard Attenborough is going to have an old-fashioned feel about it. I even quite liked Chris O'Donnell as the young Ernest Hemingway  young, dumb and full of something unmentionable, who falls for the nurse who fights to save his leg when the Italian doctor  who will become Hemingway's love rival  is intent on chopping it off. For me, O'Donnell has just the right mix of youthful macho posturing and roguish charm that the film calls for. Sandra Bullock looks perhaps a little too lovely as the nurse for whom Hemingway falls, even when she's covered in blood and dirt, but still gives a decent performance  and any star up for collecting their Razzie award in person always shoots way up in my estimation. The film also looks good. I liked it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In Love And War Agnes & Hemingway
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johneberwine
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always liked Sandra Bullock as an actress; I think she can play any part, any role and make you believe she is that person being portrayed. I believe she is one of the top 3 actresses in the USA, maybe even first. I also have always been intrigued by Ernest Hemingway and his tragic suicide. I've read a few of his books over the years. So when I saw this movie coming on Cable, I thought it might be interesting. Calling this a love story does not give it justice; to call it a war story also does not give justice; It is a Romantic Tragedy, one that, "I'm sure", everyone who saw the film was hoping for Ernest to turn around and call out to Agnes at the end!!! I would have, in a split second, but Ernest's ego would not allow. How different his remaining life may have been had he just overcome his stubbornness. The old expression, "Tis better to have loved and lost, than never to have loved at all." hardly seems to fit here; I believe both Agnes and Ernest suffered painfully all the remainder of their lives because of his decision to not turn around! How sorrowful for Agnes!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Offensively superficial
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stevemt
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it hadn't been about Ernest Hemingway the move would have been a mediocre, quickly digested and forgotten romance. If you know anything about Hemingway the movie is basically unwatchable. Chris O'Donnel's "Hemingway" is nothing but your stereotypical, one dimensional "kid goes off to war" type and seems to bear no relation to Hemingway himself. Sandra Bullock manages to bring a little depth to her character which I am guessing was dead on the page. She earned a little respect from me in that regard. If you want to watch this movie because you are interested in the subject matter, for the love of God skip it. If you just want to watch a mindless romance and you've chosen this one because it's the most available to you at the moment, go ahead I guess, just don't feel like you've learned something from it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pace?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    p-hogan1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a Hemmingway fan. I like Sandra Bullock, was very impressed with the cinematography. Production values are very high. Attenborough is a load of Emperor's clothes. I was interested to watch this film but it was --so--very--slow. Like many films and television programmes it seems to be made on the economic film principle, where, having got the cast and crew to a location/set the l-o-n-g-e-r the screen time that can be dragged out there, the cheaper the 'per minute' cost of the whole film. Whereas a single shot used to average about 3 seconds we now get 3 seconds establishing the characters in a place, a slow two shot sequence of slow moody conversation with pregnant pauses (nine months!?) and eventually one character leaves while the other pulls faces to the music, sometimes for as long as another 11 seconds.Having established the hospital we do not need to keep seeing it or people walking about it without advancing the plot. The ironic thing with this film is that Hemmingway wrote like John Ford directed. Ford started the camera and the actor on the mark and put his fist over the lens as he shouted 'cut'. One take and no way for the studio to drag out the editing. Casablanca takes place 90% in a caf&eacute;'e, slow? No. Curtiz did not need 600 horses to get pace.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rozinda
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Excellently cast, poignant movie. Sandra Bullock as always shines and is given a part that lives up to her quality. Attenbrough directs with unfailing dignity and control. I know nothing of Hemingway except what this movie tells us. I've never read his work. This tender story of late-teen Hemingway in WW1 and the somewhat older nurse he falls in love with is wonderful viewing. You may wonder why she decides in the end not to marry him, but I suggest it is because he is still so very young and she's afraid he will grow bored with her after a few years. After a war, so many men have died, and there are so many surplus women vying for the attention of the men who are left. I would assume the Agnes was uncertain that she could hold him, or uncertain that he could hold her. In any case, she's rightly tempted by the doctor's offer to help run his new hospital, though I can't say I'd have thought that would make a good personal marriage as well so thank goodness it didn't really happen. Apparently, the real Ernest and Agnes did not meet again after the war although there was a little correspondence, but the movie shows Agnes visiting Ernest and finally telling him to his face that she loves him and clearly hoping the relationship will recommence. Unfortunately there has to be a reason why in the movie it can't since in real life it didn't, so Ernest is shown in a childish rage and she has to walk away, humiliated and despairing, never to see him again but saying, "I love you. I will love you for the rest of my life..." whilst he's left weeping - out of her sight. Now just suppose if she'd turned back..... I can't say I thought it would be wise for this relationship to continue - Ernest's rage is too intense, it wouldn't bode well for a marriage. He was either too immature or in some other way unsuitable to become her husband and she had been mistaken to be tempted to go back to him, so I would suggest, in the context of the movie, she had a very lucky escape. What she will think, after a while, is "Well, I've seen him. I was right the first time. It wouldn't work. This gives me closure." And she'll move on. This scene is so beautifully handled by the actors that it saddens me to have to object strongly to it being included and that's why I drop my rating from 10 to 9. In all other ways but this one unfortunate scene, this movie is a 10-star. Of course, it suits a movie maker to leave the ending bitter and hurtful to both of them, a ghastly final meeting when they are both despairing even though it's clear a reunion would have been more likely, or at least a relationship for a while, seeing they both actually seemed to want it. How frustrating this kind of scene is once you've got over the tear-jerking reaction, typical irritating aspect of movie making trying to extract every last emotion, not all that realistic sometimes. So then I looked on the internet for information re the real people. I see Agnes wrote to him explaining she had firmly decided he was too young for her and the marriage would be a mistake. That's how this movie should have ended - Bullock writing this letter and Ernest perhaps slinging it into the lake, but then rescuing it and putting it somewhere safe. And then an indication that they corresponded a little more for a while. A gentle, realistic ending that didn't humiliate either real person. But please, still go and see the movie as it's otherwise completely wonderful and if you can forget the real people you may love the finale as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Real Hemingway
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mrgolf145
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Agnes Von Kurowsky denied up to her dying day that she and "Ernie" had a sexual relationship. Considering his reputation for exaggeration and out and out lying I'll take her word. In his earlier years he was a brilliant writer before alcohol abuse and depression did him in. He was also a liar, braggart, bully, racist, anti-Semite,misogynist and an easy rider who lived off the trust funds of his first two wives, Hadley and Pauline. If he was so Macho and eager for Combat then I guess he would have joined the American Army and volunteered for infantry duty in France instead of driving an ambulance in Italy and being wounded accidentally taking cigarettes and candy to real soldiers on the front lines.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pleasant and interesting true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guynvistaca
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought the acting was perfect and the story very true. As I watched this film I googled Ernest Hemingway and read what I was actually seeing on the screen. To capsule this mans life in a little under two hours is almost impossible-but I liked the way we were able to see the early life of this great writer. Sandra Bullock always in top form as an actress gives a sweet performance as Agnes and Chris O'Donnell was a good catch for the young Hemingway-if you look at his early photos you will see that he was not as gruff as in his older years. A bit more sensitive and caring than his older years. Might be a bit slow for some but the war moments were very real and the scenery of Italy was stunning!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hemingway's First Love All Wrong
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CitizenCaine
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris O'Donnell and Sandra Bullock star in Richard Attenborough's story of Hemingway's first love with Agnes Kurowsky, the red cross nurse. It's near the end of World War I and the young Hemingway finds love with an older red cross nurse behind the trenches after he's injured helping an infantryman to safety. This must be the Hallmark greeting card version of the story because the scenery is great, the period authentic, the dialog sentimental and proper, and the chemistry between the leads completely absent. O'Donnell has absolutely no zest to foreshadow the larger than life figure the famous Hemingway was. Maybe that was part of the point Attenborough was making with the film: the romance was more of a young man's fancy than reality. This was a film made in retrospect after the discovery of Kurowsky's love letters with the young Hemingway, and it stands to reason the truth was softened somewhat to make for a romanticized story. Some viewers will question the notion implied by the epilogue of how this episode influenced the elder Hemingway. He later wrote A Farewell To Arms, which of course he based on this same episode of his life. That film, at least the older version from the thirties, is far more satisfying than what viewers will see here. This appears to have been made strictly for the Lifetime network crowd. ** of 4 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nonsense in the Trivia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freelance-7
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trivia. "Attenborough had wanted Julia Roberts to play the female lead at one time but by the time the film was made she had become too old for the part." Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967). Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967). Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967). Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967). Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967). Sandra Bullock (*1964) who is the actual female lead is older that Julia Roberst (*1967).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In Love and War
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From Lord Sir Richard Attenborough directing, I thought Cry Freedom was better, but this is okay in some ways. It tells the story of Ernest 'Ernie' Hemingway (Chris O'Donnell), the young soldier who volunteered to fight in the front line during World War I. Unfortunately, while rescuing another soldier, and escaping, he was shot in the leg, and his friend who see later was covered in injury. Agnes 'Aggie/Ag' Von Kurowsky (Sandra Bullock) is the nurse who tries to help him without having his leg cutoff, because of gangrene. During treatment and time in the hospital Ernie forms a close friendship with Aggie, and soon it becomes a question as to whether they are in love. They get the chance to get together before Ernie leaves for a mission, but after, she dumps him for another man. Later, she realises it was a mistake, but Ernie can't forgive her, and they never see each other again after a final chat. Okay!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
