<filme>
 <id>
  1159
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0079944
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1979
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Stalker
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A guide leads two men through an area known as the Zone to find a room that grants wishes.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Near a gray and unnamed city is the Zone, an alien place guarded by barbed wire and soldiers. Over his wife's numerous objections, a man rises in the dead of night: he's a stalker, one of a handful who have the mental gifts (and who risk imprisonment) to lead people into the Zone to the Room, a place where one's secret hopes come true. That night, he takes two people into the Zone: a popular writer who is burned out, cynical, and questioning his genius; and a quiet scientist more concerned about his knapsack than the journey. In the deserted Zone, the approach to the Room must be indirect. As they draw near, the rules seem to change and the stalker faces a crisis.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   stalker
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hope
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   scientist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   barbed wire
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   alien
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Andrei Tarkovsky
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Arkadiy Strugatskiy
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Boris Strugatskiy
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Alisa Freyndlikh
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Aleksandr Kaydanovskiy
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Anatoliy Solonitsyn
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmm...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    srmontgo
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a hard movie to rate. There was a good amount to love and a lot to hate for me. First, the good. I can appreciate that this is not a movie to just sit back and passively be entertained by. This is a movie that encourages you to be thoughtful and observant, kind of like a Professor and a Scientist. There are scenes in this movie that made me question my beliefs about what motivates humans to act, faith, and what in life is actually worth pursuing... those are some deep and big questions to arouse in a viewer and for that I definitely appreciate the film. It is definitely beautiful. The camera movements make you feel like you are watching a dream and pretty much each shot looks like it could be framed and hung at an art exhibit. The acting, while confusing at times, was very good. Now, the bad. It is long and confusing. I understand that some people love to let their imaginations fly when finding meaning in these "art" movies. I can appreciate that to an extent. However, I prefer to have some level of cohesiveness and direction. I could not care about any of the characters because I was not given anything to care about. Since I did not care about the characters or understand what motivates them, I could not care or understand their actions or how they interacted with the other characters. When a dog shows up, I attempted to interpret the meaning... but I simply lacked the information to make any sense of it. My point is, I prefer to have at least some context in order to interpret and prescribe meaning to what I'm watching. I like movies that make you think and are up to interpretation, but I this was just too abstract for my taste. My wife saw me watching this movie. She sat down and watched 10 minutes. She then got up and asked me why I do this to myself. "This" meaning watching boring old movies. I usually don't answer he because she wouldn't understand anyway, but with this movie I wouldn't have been able to respond even if I wanted to. Her question actually posed the most meaningful and philosophically challenging question of the night. Why spend my time after work fighting sleep and working to understand a boring old movie when I could be doing something fun or productive? This movie is essentially a stream of consciousness, a nonsensical plot to display a collection of beautiful philosophical vignettes, a long slog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ideas about the meaning
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hatem Krema
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS ... What was the hidden concept ?? I think the movie Stalker with its strong symbolism can be interpreted in the context of the Soviet era when religion was brutally suppressed. "The zone"/religion is a place that provides a comfortable sanctuary from the material dull life, and is guarded from entering by the military/ communist authorities. It came to exist from a meteorite/ a heavenly message to earth. For the stalker/ the religious man, it represents home and comfort, although he always enters it with fear to make it/God angry. The zone/ religion has its own natural laws/miracles that defies logic, but you have to get along with. It promises a "room"/paradise were your innermost wishes come true. The road/ life work to reach the room/paradise is tough and requires guidance from a stalker/ religious man. The existence of the room/ paradise has been always challenged by science/the professor and philosophy/the writer, and despite that they try to explore the facts of religion, and have some understanding for it, they could not accept it at the end. Science/the professor was ready to destroy what he could not rationalize, and from the standpoint of the stalker/religious man, science/the professor and philosophy/the writer are completely ignorant despite their knowledge. The stalker personal life/ the religious man life is not materially fulfilling and may be disappointing. The daughter may represent the outcome of following religion blindly, the mind/body may be crippled to move freely but it may have sensitivity and mysticism not owned by others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The BEST film ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Keldi Victoria Konung
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalker (made by cinematography genius Andrei Tarkovsky) is a visually unforgettable film. It's my most favourite film of all time. It's based on short science fiction novel Roadside Picnic - written by Russian science fiction authors Arkady and Boris Strugatsky. It has a very deep storyline that held my interest from the first to the last minute. I was very impressed by the acting of Alexander Kaidanovsky. For most of the film there are only three actors - they did their job amazingly well. From a technical point of view - it is the BEST film ever made! I strongly recommend to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Couldn't sit through the whole film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    l_eeburgess
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most boring films I have ever watched in my whole life. I managed to watch an hour and a half of it, but just could not make it to the end. Art does not make a movie, eerie music and bleak landscapes are all well and good but two and a half hours of it is too much. The endless and monotonous conversations between the characters is basically just mindless babble. Lots of time spent standing around in fields or lying in pools of water. Perhaps I am the wrong person to watch this kind of film, I like substance to a film, I like an engaging story, this provided nothing of enjoyment to me. For the life of me I cannot understand how so many people can rate it so highly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stalker
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My third Tarkovsky's film (after SOLARIS 1972, 8/10 and NOSTALGHIA 1983, 8/10), STALKER is a startling eye-opener, set in a sordid clanking land of rural Soviet Union, after the falling of a meteorite, an enigmatic area "The Zone" has emerged, inside there is a room can grant incomers' innermost wishes, but cordoned by the government with armies, only with the guidance of so called "stalkers", one can reach the room. So the expedition involves one stalker and his two clients, a writer and a professor, one begs for inspiration and the other conceals an ulterior motive. As one can predict, the film is teeming with Tarkovsky's trademark static/panning long shots, mesmerizing and conjuring up a recondite sense of metaphysics, for example, a steady long shot of various items in the water finishes with the focus on a human hand, sometimes it's baffling, as viewers (as well as the two clients) have been warned numerous times by the stalker, the place is precarious, many a predecessor dies mysteriously in the zone, among a large chunk of the time Tarkovsky successfully maintains the stifling suspense to tally with the seedy locale, the movement is painstakingly strung out, so the audiences cannot shun the unknown danger but only succumb to a thorough wallow in the wasteland. Tarkovsky never resort to cheap horror to give vent to excitement or relief, instead, he utilizes a man-made natural surrounding to trap oneself in, and let our own inside demon out to divulge a sense of thrill and frisson. I don't speak Russian, so it probably hinders my apprehension of the dialog, only if the English interpretation could be better, nevertheless, STALKER seems bit chattier than Tarkovsky's other works, their debate ranges from the philosophy of human beings' psychological trials and tribulations, the socio-political radicalism to the awe and frustration towards the mystery and miracles plus the unselfishness of art, etc. I may not be able to fully cover all the implications from the first viewing, but one can not deny here the luxuriant imagery is louder than words at any rate. The cast is also memorable, the monochrome close-ups endow each character with a pictorial impact of their own resolution, the friend-or-foe association motivates the storytelling and excellently penetrates the harmony of the trio thus overshoots viewers' expectation. Myself find the supernatural elements have been fascinatingly deployed in this film, scattering into many inscrutable shots, sometimes only in a jiffy and most strikingly is the ending, with the daughter of the stalker, mind-controls still objects until one glass falls on the ground but the sound is drowned by the strident train running nearby, which ultimately veils the film with a stratum of mystique that qualifies Tarkovsky as one of the most unique and essential filmmaker of all time!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bizarre Russian Science Fiction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A guide known as The Stalker (Alexander Kaidanovsky) leads two men, "the Writer" (Anatoly Solonitsyn) and "the Professor" (Nikolai Grinko), through an area known as the Zone to find a room that grants wishes. Can you believe the film contains 142 shots in 163 minutes, with an average shot length of more than one minute and many shots lasting for more than four minutes. There is no question that the camera lingers, and no surprise that the picture is considered to be slow by many people (early audiences and critics definitely thought so). Almost all of the scenes not set in the Zone are in a high-contrast brown monochrome. What does this mean? That is for you to decide, but it does add an element of fantasy to the picture. The director reportedly said, "I am only interested in the views of two people: one is called Bresson and one called Bergman." Yes, folks, this is art and not entertainment. If you happen to be entertained, that is even better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Has some interesting footage of a run down Russian town but that's about it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Curtin
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    PLEASE NOTE: Spoiler alert(if that's possible). OK. Here's the movie in a nutshell. Man get's up in the middle of the night, wife get's cross and worried he'll get thrown into jail. Man leaves, meets up with a couple of people who have organised to meet him. They make there way through a curfew section of the city patrolled by police/law enforcement, in a Range Rover. They swap to a train car, that they use to get them out of the city into 'The Zone'. The Zone is simply outside the city and is beautiful simply because it's nature and scenery. There's objects such as concrete blocks, tunnels and misc run down rooms they walk through, there journey ends in a room where they all sit and throw rocks into the water. Then it cuts back to the city, man goes for a walk with his wife and kid, they talk, then his daughter puts her head on the table looks incredibly bored and appears to move some glass wear with a psionic ability. One glass falls off the table, the others stop, camera pans to her almost bored to death face end of film. Yes, I get that the poetic points that are mentioned and in particular the message: "Weak is beautiful and strength is nothing, in that when a child is born it is adaptable and flexible. When the child becomes a man it get's hard and set in it's ways, therefore weak is far more beautiful than strength", is a worthy one but hey 3 hours for that? Other points like this but ultimately nothing to do with the overall story which is simply that 'The Stalker' is simply someone who walks people through the zone which is essentially like a walk in the country in an effort to expand there minds from there otherwise pointless existence(talk about ironic, the Stalker is beyond pointless in himself to say the least). For some reason there not meant to go there. Why not is not really explained.(More than likely because some Russian dictator declared it was off limits to ordinary civilians for some reason(we see various signs of war amidst the rubble, bunkers, a gun etc but overall just a lot of pointless walking around scenes with absolutely no meaning, not even poetically). Overall this is an incredibly boring film and I have no idea why it get's such a high rating. As for watch it again. NO WAY, I'd rather stick red hot needles in my eyes. Seriously, don't waste your time, I only gave it 2 stars because 1. The scene in the practically war torn Russian streets was interesting and 2. for the finale at the end of the film which showed that had the movie focused on the talented young girl, it might have been great. Instead she was really depressed because her whole role got 1 minute at the end of the film and the rest of the film was essentially a tangential screed of rubbish. My strong recommendation for a movie with poetic license and far more impact and strong points but still has a great story and is actually endlessly re-watchable(especially if you get the Criterion Collection edition with the bonus versions), is the Terry Gilliam film BRAZIL. Watch that instead, you'll be glad you did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Do you know interesting facts?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leostalker
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's my most dear, secret movie, which I'm ready to watch again and again making journey with characters. As already mentioned in some comments, it's not even film, it's co-existence with travelers, it's a road to your heart or to God, or to elsewhere. I could tell much about this masterpiece, but would like to say about things people, even fond of Tarkovsky art, might unaware of. Below is a quote from Tarkovsky; "For me this work is expression of power of a weak man, man of faith, man of highest spirit. His actions might be impractical and absurd. But impracticality is a sign of high spirit. He has an idea. There is no Zone. He just invented so to take two-three desperate people, bring them there and inspire an idea of some hope for the happiness sake. But finally none of them want to enter this simple room". This is a answer to those (I'm also amongst them), who expressed they guesses that the Zone and the Room are not actually produce miracles or disasters, but just Stalker's words. Though we see corpses, tanks and other things that supposedly confirms the existence of something supernatural, but real miracle (or peril, or change of mind, or growing of souls, if you want) takes places spiritually. This Tarkovsky's explanation (some people, as I am, realized this even before learning Tarkovsky's words) only adds depth to the film. Another interesting point is that the final monologue of Stalker's Wife supposed to be IN BAR (and it's actually shot THERE  look at the wall behind her, when she is speaking), not in Stalker's home. I learnt about it from interwiev of the editor of the film. She (it was a women) offered Tarkovsky to move this scene from the bar closer to the end so to have an effect of addressing not only to Writer and Professor, but to the soul of an amateur. The editor said to Tarkovsky that the difference of the surroundings would not be marked by a amateur because his attention on that moment is fixed on the face of Alisa Freindlich (Wife). Tarkovsky finally agreed and put this scene to the final and it became much deeper then it would have been in the bar. Wife now addresses to all of us (as Writer did sitting near a hole in the Zone after going through the "meatgrinder'). I rewatched film many times and paid attention to the interior of Wife's monologue  it's in the bar! Thanks to advise of films editor we have such a important change of the final moments of film. To end it I would like to mark a strong scene, almost nowhere mentioned. When crippled daughter of Stalker seems to walk Film returns in color and Artemiev's music is heard as to underline the miracle. And several seconds later camera moves revealing us the truth  she is sitting on Stalker's shoulders. What a piercing, shrill moment of a miracle that took place only in our imagination. Wonderful moments!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Atmospheric, weird, intelligent, a little too slow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nate J
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalker is quintessentially Tarkovskii and stagnation-era. Tarkovskii's extended silences, slow painting-like shots, color filters, and obsession with dripping water permeate the film. From the stagnation era, Stalker borrows middle age, cynicism, nihilism, listlessness, and unfulfilled desire. The film is remarkably atmospheric; aside from a few strange occurrences, nothing actually corroborates the titular Stalker's claims of supernatural danger in the Zone, and yet the fog, the ruins, the unearthly electronic music, and the apprehension of the characters gives an air of ominous oppression to what is objectively a very simple film. Alienation is a constant theme. In one sense, the Zone disobeys physical laws, traps and kills, and inspires introspection in a terrifyingly sublime way. In another sense, the Zone is the most "real" place in the film  it is in color, it is a place of hope, and it is the only place the Stalker claims to be at home, in opposition to the muddy-brown drudgery of the outside world. The dichotomy of Zone and reality, hope and cynicism, comfort and danger, unconscious desires and active passions are constantly at play, and often flipping. I couldn't shake the feeling that the film had something to say about communism and the stagnation period: the Zone is a place of refuge and also a place of weirdness, it attracts the hopeless, and yet offers possibility. One character wants to destroy it, due to the terrible power it might give to bad men. Another character argues that this cannot happen, because man's inner desires will always trump their ideological positions. The Stalker wants only to bring visitors to the Zone for hope and happiness, and grieves at the inability of "intellectuals" to give it their faith. His wife narrates, "If we hadn't had our misfortunes, it would have been worsethere wouldn't have been any hope." Whether or not these stagnation themes were deliberately placed or an osmotic result of the era is irrelevant  the film is imminently malleable in interpretation. Stalker is nothing if not strange, and there are scenes that cannot be described with any justice in writing. The atmosphere is beautifully wrought, and the film thankfully does not spoil its own premise with over-exposition or ludicrous elements, as science fiction is often wont to do, but scenes tend to drag, and the film might have benefited from some more judicious editing. The most striking and well-timed scene in the entire story occurs in the last two minutes, and one wonders what Tarkovskii might have done with a little more money and a more hawk-eyed editor. Overall, Stalker is strange, atmospheric, introspective, and a little too long for its own good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    stalking the truth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dminkin
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What is happiness? What is the meaning of life? What is the Zone? And what exactly is reality? These questions and many more you will find yourselves asking as you enter the Zone, a place with a Room where all wishes come true. Don't expect too many answers, but try to enjoy the journey, even amidst the decay and ruin of both man and machine. Tarkovsky's Zone is a place of magic, a place where ordinary physical laws don't apply. If one is skeptical that the scenery is what it is, and that there is nothing more to it than what you see with your eyes, the camera in conjunction with the dialogue works hard to convince you otherwise. Distance, scale, and position are all warped, not by any special effect of the camera as in ordinary sci-fi movies, but by the positioning, angle, and movement of the camera within a shot. To take one harrowing example: In the early part of the journey to the Room contained within the central core of the Zone, the small company of travelers, the Stalker, the Professor, and the Writer, pass a blackened trailer containing intact fleshy skeletons. The camera tracks the travelers as they move from a vantage point that deliberately inserts this trailer of death in between. Ever so slowly it creeps up to the scene of death, enlarging and magnifying the details of the decaying corpses, until the camera, having just gotten past the point where it has crept so far up, then overshoots the dead. But it stops; so that while the travelers contemplate the fate of these dead "tourists" to the Zone, we are aware that we are actually sitting on top of them. Metal armor, assorted trinkets, and other material possessions that man has donned or created all fall by the wayside and are discarded and rusted at the bottom of pools of water that saturate the Zone. Man's life and possessions are ephemeral and in a constant state of decay in our industrialized, bleak world. Man is removed from Nature, not just in Soviet life but everywhere we look. It becomes apparent that the only way to survive such ruin of both spirit and home is with faith and hope. But we don't always know our innermost desires so a trip to the Room is fruitless if we have a specific goal in mind. The central dilemma is that the Stalker's faith is predicated upon his belief that the inner desires of most people are good. However, the Writer and Professor, from different but not necessarily opposing perspectives, espouse a view that their deepest desires may not necessarily have the best intentions, despite a basic sense of morality that pervades their respective consciences. This is what I think Tarkovsky was trying to depict, without giving an answer, since there may not be one in this brilliant, philosophical, haunting, and beautifully poetic meditation on what it means to be human in a particular reality that we can see but not really ever grasp.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmm...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    srmontgo
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a hard movie to rate. There was a good amount to love and a lot to hate for me. First, the good. I can appreciate that this is not a movie to just sit back and passively be entertained by. This is a movie that encourages you to be thoughtful and observant, kind of like a Professor and a Scientist. There are scenes in this movie that made me question my beliefs about what motivates humans to act, faith, and what in life is actually worth pursuing... those are some deep and big questions to arouse in a viewer and for that I definitely appreciate the film. It is definitely beautiful. The camera movements make you feel like you are watching a dream and pretty much each shot looks like it could be framed and hung at an art exhibit. The acting, while confusing at times, was very good. Now, the bad. It is long and confusing. I understand that some people love to let their imaginations fly when finding meaning in these "art" movies. I can appreciate that to an extent. However, I prefer to have some level of cohesiveness and direction. I could not care about any of the characters because I was not given anything to care about. Since I did not care about the characters or understand what motivates them, I could not care or understand their actions or how they interacted with the other characters. When a dog shows up, I attempted to interpret the meaning... but I simply lacked the information to make any sense of it. My point is, I prefer to have at least some context in order to interpret and prescribe meaning to what I'm watching. I like movies that make you think and are up to interpretation, but I this was just too abstract for my taste. My wife saw me watching this movie. She sat down and watched 10 minutes. She then got up and asked me why I do this to myself. "This" meaning watching boring old movies. I usually don't answer he because she wouldn't understand anyway, but with this movie I wouldn't have been able to respond even if I wanted to. Her question actually posed the most meaningful and philosophically challenging question of the night. Why spend my time after work fighting sleep and working to understand a boring old movie when I could be doing something fun or productive? This movie is essentially a stream of consciousness, a nonsensical plot to display a collection of beautiful philosophical vignettes, a long slog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ideas about the meaning
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hatem Krema
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS ... What was the hidden concept ?? I think the movie Stalker with its strong symbolism can be interpreted in the context of the Soviet era when religion was brutally suppressed. "The zone"/religion is a place that provides a comfortable sanctuary from the material dull life, and is guarded from entering by the military/ communist authorities. It came to exist from a meteorite/ a heavenly message to earth. For the stalker/ the religious man, it represents home and comfort, although he always enters it with fear to make it/God angry. The zone/ religion has its own natural laws/miracles that defies logic, but you have to get along with. It promises a "room"/paradise were your innermost wishes come true. The road/ life work to reach the room/paradise is tough and requires guidance from a stalker/ religious man. The existence of the room/ paradise has been always challenged by science/the professor and philosophy/the writer, and despite that they try to explore the facts of religion, and have some understanding for it, they could not accept it at the end. Science/the professor was ready to destroy what he could not rationalize, and from the standpoint of the stalker/religious man, science/the professor and philosophy/the writer are completely ignorant despite their knowledge. The stalker personal life/ the religious man life is not materially fulfilling and may be disappointing. The daughter may represent the outcome of following religion blindly, the mind/body may be crippled to move freely but it may have sensitivity and mysticism not owned by others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The BEST film ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Keldi Victoria Konung
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalker (made by cinematography genius Andrei Tarkovsky) is a visually unforgettable film. It's my most favourite film of all time. It's based on short science fiction novel Roadside Picnic - written by Russian science fiction authors Arkady and Boris Strugatsky. It has a very deep storyline that held my interest from the first to the last minute. I was very impressed by the acting of Alexander Kaidanovsky. For most of the film there are only three actors - they did their job amazingly well. From a technical point of view - it is the BEST film ever made! I strongly recommend to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Couldn't sit through the whole film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    l_eeburgess
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most boring films I have ever watched in my whole life. I managed to watch an hour and a half of it, but just could not make it to the end. Art does not make a movie, eerie music and bleak landscapes are all well and good but two and a half hours of it is too much. The endless and monotonous conversations between the characters is basically just mindless babble. Lots of time spent standing around in fields or lying in pools of water. Perhaps I am the wrong person to watch this kind of film, I like substance to a film, I like an engaging story, this provided nothing of enjoyment to me. For the life of me I cannot understand how so many people can rate it so highly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stalker
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My third Tarkovsky's film (after SOLARIS 1972, 8/10 and NOSTALGHIA 1983, 8/10), STALKER is a startling eye-opener, set in a sordid clanking land of rural Soviet Union, after the falling of a meteorite, an enigmatic area "The Zone" has emerged, inside there is a room can grant incomers' innermost wishes, but cordoned by the government with armies, only with the guidance of so called "stalkers", one can reach the room. So the expedition involves one stalker and his two clients, a writer and a professor, one begs for inspiration and the other conceals an ulterior motive. As one can predict, the film is teeming with Tarkovsky's trademark static/panning long shots, mesmerizing and conjuring up a recondite sense of metaphysics, for example, a steady long shot of various items in the water finishes with the focus on a human hand, sometimes it's baffling, as viewers (as well as the two clients) have been warned numerous times by the stalker, the place is precarious, many a predecessor dies mysteriously in the zone, among a large chunk of the time Tarkovsky successfully maintains the stifling suspense to tally with the seedy locale, the movement is painstakingly strung out, so the audiences cannot shun the unknown danger but only succumb to a thorough wallow in the wasteland. Tarkovsky never resort to cheap horror to give vent to excitement or relief, instead, he utilizes a man-made natural surrounding to trap oneself in, and let our own inside demon out to divulge a sense of thrill and frisson. I don't speak Russian, so it probably hinders my apprehension of the dialog, only if the English interpretation could be better, nevertheless, STALKER seems bit chattier than Tarkovsky's other works, their debate ranges from the philosophy of human beings' psychological trials and tribulations, the socio-political radicalism to the awe and frustration towards the mystery and miracles plus the unselfishness of art, etc. I may not be able to fully cover all the implications from the first viewing, but one can not deny here the luxuriant imagery is louder than words at any rate. The cast is also memorable, the monochrome close-ups endow each character with a pictorial impact of their own resolution, the friend-or-foe association motivates the storytelling and excellently penetrates the harmony of the trio thus overshoots viewers' expectation. Myself find the supernatural elements have been fascinatingly deployed in this film, scattering into many inscrutable shots, sometimes only in a jiffy and most strikingly is the ending, with the daughter of the stalker, mind-controls still objects until one glass falls on the ground but the sound is drowned by the strident train running nearby, which ultimately veils the film with a stratum of mystique that qualifies Tarkovsky as one of the most unique and essential filmmaker of all time!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bizarre Russian Science Fiction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A guide known as The Stalker (Alexander Kaidanovsky) leads two men, "the Writer" (Anatoly Solonitsyn) and "the Professor" (Nikolai Grinko), through an area known as the Zone to find a room that grants wishes. Can you believe the film contains 142 shots in 163 minutes, with an average shot length of more than one minute and many shots lasting for more than four minutes. There is no question that the camera lingers, and no surprise that the picture is considered to be slow by many people (early audiences and critics definitely thought so). Almost all of the scenes not set in the Zone are in a high-contrast brown monochrome. What does this mean? That is for you to decide, but it does add an element of fantasy to the picture. The director reportedly said, "I am only interested in the views of two people: one is called Bresson and one called Bergman." Yes, folks, this is art and not entertainment. If you happen to be entertained, that is even better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Has some interesting footage of a run down Russian town but that's about it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Curtin
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    PLEASE NOTE: Spoiler alert(if that's possible). OK. Here's the movie in a nutshell. Man get's up in the middle of the night, wife get's cross and worried he'll get thrown into jail. Man leaves, meets up with a couple of people who have organised to meet him. They make there way through a curfew section of the city patrolled by police/law enforcement, in a Range Rover. They swap to a train car, that they use to get them out of the city into 'The Zone'. The Zone is simply outside the city and is beautiful simply because it's nature and scenery. There's objects such as concrete blocks, tunnels and misc run down rooms they walk through, there journey ends in a room where they all sit and throw rocks into the water. Then it cuts back to the city, man goes for a walk with his wife and kid, they talk, then his daughter puts her head on the table looks incredibly bored and appears to move some glass wear with a psionic ability. One glass falls off the table, the others stop, camera pans to her almost bored to death face end of film. Yes, I get that the poetic points that are mentioned and in particular the message: "Weak is beautiful and strength is nothing, in that when a child is born it is adaptable and flexible. When the child becomes a man it get's hard and set in it's ways, therefore weak is far more beautiful than strength", is a worthy one but hey 3 hours for that? Other points like this but ultimately nothing to do with the overall story which is simply that 'The Stalker' is simply someone who walks people through the zone which is essentially like a walk in the country in an effort to expand there minds from there otherwise pointless existence(talk about ironic, the Stalker is beyond pointless in himself to say the least). For some reason there not meant to go there. Why not is not really explained.(More than likely because some Russian dictator declared it was off limits to ordinary civilians for some reason(we see various signs of war amidst the rubble, bunkers, a gun etc but overall just a lot of pointless walking around scenes with absolutely no meaning, not even poetically). Overall this is an incredibly boring film and I have no idea why it get's such a high rating. As for watch it again. NO WAY, I'd rather stick red hot needles in my eyes. Seriously, don't waste your time, I only gave it 2 stars because 1. The scene in the practically war torn Russian streets was interesting and 2. for the finale at the end of the film which showed that had the movie focused on the talented young girl, it might have been great. Instead she was really depressed because her whole role got 1 minute at the end of the film and the rest of the film was essentially a tangential screed of rubbish. My strong recommendation for a movie with poetic license and far more impact and strong points but still has a great story and is actually endlessly re-watchable(especially if you get the Criterion Collection edition with the bonus versions), is the Terry Gilliam film BRAZIL. Watch that instead, you'll be glad you did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Do you know interesting facts?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leostalker
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's my most dear, secret movie, which I'm ready to watch again and again making journey with characters. As already mentioned in some comments, it's not even film, it's co-existence with travelers, it's a road to your heart or to God, or to elsewhere. I could tell much about this masterpiece, but would like to say about things people, even fond of Tarkovsky art, might unaware of. Below is a quote from Tarkovsky; "For me this work is expression of power of a weak man, man of faith, man of highest spirit. His actions might be impractical and absurd. But impracticality is a sign of high spirit. He has an idea. There is no Zone. He just invented so to take two-three desperate people, bring them there and inspire an idea of some hope for the happiness sake. But finally none of them want to enter this simple room". This is a answer to those (I'm also amongst them), who expressed they guesses that the Zone and the Room are not actually produce miracles or disasters, but just Stalker's words. Though we see corpses, tanks and other things that supposedly confirms the existence of something supernatural, but real miracle (or peril, or change of mind, or growing of souls, if you want) takes places spiritually. This Tarkovsky's explanation (some people, as I am, realized this even before learning Tarkovsky's words) only adds depth to the film. Another interesting point is that the final monologue of Stalker's Wife supposed to be IN BAR (and it's actually shot THERE  look at the wall behind her, when she is speaking), not in Stalker's home. I learnt about it from interwiev of the editor of the film. She (it was a women) offered Tarkovsky to move this scene from the bar closer to the end so to have an effect of addressing not only to Writer and Professor, but to the soul of an amateur. The editor said to Tarkovsky that the difference of the surroundings would not be marked by a amateur because his attention on that moment is fixed on the face of Alisa Freindlich (Wife). Tarkovsky finally agreed and put this scene to the final and it became much deeper then it would have been in the bar. Wife now addresses to all of us (as Writer did sitting near a hole in the Zone after going through the "meatgrinder'). I rewatched film many times and paid attention to the interior of Wife's monologue  it's in the bar! Thanks to advise of films editor we have such a important change of the final moments of film. To end it I would like to mark a strong scene, almost nowhere mentioned. When crippled daughter of Stalker seems to walk Film returns in color and Artemiev's music is heard as to underline the miracle. And several seconds later camera moves revealing us the truth  she is sitting on Stalker's shoulders. What a piercing, shrill moment of a miracle that took place only in our imagination. Wonderful moments!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Atmospheric, weird, intelligent, a little too slow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nate J
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalker is quintessentially Tarkovskii and stagnation-era. Tarkovskii's extended silences, slow painting-like shots, color filters, and obsession with dripping water permeate the film. From the stagnation era, Stalker borrows middle age, cynicism, nihilism, listlessness, and unfulfilled desire. The film is remarkably atmospheric; aside from a few strange occurrences, nothing actually corroborates the titular Stalker's claims of supernatural danger in the Zone, and yet the fog, the ruins, the unearthly electronic music, and the apprehension of the characters gives an air of ominous oppression to what is objectively a very simple film. Alienation is a constant theme. In one sense, the Zone disobeys physical laws, traps and kills, and inspires introspection in a terrifyingly sublime way. In another sense, the Zone is the most "real" place in the film  it is in color, it is a place of hope, and it is the only place the Stalker claims to be at home, in opposition to the muddy-brown drudgery of the outside world. The dichotomy of Zone and reality, hope and cynicism, comfort and danger, unconscious desires and active passions are constantly at play, and often flipping. I couldn't shake the feeling that the film had something to say about communism and the stagnation period: the Zone is a place of refuge and also a place of weirdness, it attracts the hopeless, and yet offers possibility. One character wants to destroy it, due to the terrible power it might give to bad men. Another character argues that this cannot happen, because man's inner desires will always trump their ideological positions. The Stalker wants only to bring visitors to the Zone for hope and happiness, and grieves at the inability of "intellectuals" to give it their faith. His wife narrates, "If we hadn't had our misfortunes, it would have been worsethere wouldn't have been any hope." Whether or not these stagnation themes were deliberately placed or an osmotic result of the era is irrelevant  the film is imminently malleable in interpretation. Stalker is nothing if not strange, and there are scenes that cannot be described with any justice in writing. The atmosphere is beautifully wrought, and the film thankfully does not spoil its own premise with over-exposition or ludicrous elements, as science fiction is often wont to do, but scenes tend to drag, and the film might have benefited from some more judicious editing. The most striking and well-timed scene in the entire story occurs in the last two minutes, and one wonders what Tarkovskii might have done with a little more money and a more hawk-eyed editor. Overall, Stalker is strange, atmospheric, introspective, and a little too long for its own good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    stalking the truth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dminkin
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What is happiness? What is the meaning of life? What is the Zone? And what exactly is reality? These questions and many more you will find yourselves asking as you enter the Zone, a place with a Room where all wishes come true. Don't expect too many answers, but try to enjoy the journey, even amidst the decay and ruin of both man and machine. Tarkovsky's Zone is a place of magic, a place where ordinary physical laws don't apply. If one is skeptical that the scenery is what it is, and that there is nothing more to it than what you see with your eyes, the camera in conjunction with the dialogue works hard to convince you otherwise. Distance, scale, and position are all warped, not by any special effect of the camera as in ordinary sci-fi movies, but by the positioning, angle, and movement of the camera within a shot. To take one harrowing example: In the early part of the journey to the Room contained within the central core of the Zone, the small company of travelers, the Stalker, the Professor, and the Writer, pass a blackened trailer containing intact fleshy skeletons. The camera tracks the travelers as they move from a vantage point that deliberately inserts this trailer of death in between. Ever so slowly it creeps up to the scene of death, enlarging and magnifying the details of the decaying corpses, until the camera, having just gotten past the point where it has crept so far up, then overshoots the dead. But it stops; so that while the travelers contemplate the fate of these dead "tourists" to the Zone, we are aware that we are actually sitting on top of them. Metal armor, assorted trinkets, and other material possessions that man has donned or created all fall by the wayside and are discarded and rusted at the bottom of pools of water that saturate the Zone. Man's life and possessions are ephemeral and in a constant state of decay in our industrialized, bleak world. Man is removed from Nature, not just in Soviet life but everywhere we look. It becomes apparent that the only way to survive such ruin of both spirit and home is with faith and hope. But we don't always know our innermost desires so a trip to the Room is fruitless if we have a specific goal in mind. The central dilemma is that the Stalker's faith is predicated upon his belief that the inner desires of most people are good. However, the Writer and Professor, from different but not necessarily opposing perspectives, espouse a view that their deepest desires may not necessarily have the best intentions, despite a basic sense of morality that pervades their respective consciences. This is what I think Tarkovsky was trying to depict, without giving an answer, since there may not be one in this brilliant, philosophical, haunting, and beautifully poetic meditation on what it means to be human in a particular reality that we can see but not really ever grasp.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmm...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    srmontgo
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a hard movie to rate. There was a good amount to love and a lot to hate for me. First, the good. I can appreciate that this is not a movie to just sit back and passively be entertained by. This is a movie that encourages you to be thoughtful and observant, kind of like a Professor and a Scientist. There are scenes in this movie that made me question my beliefs about what motivates humans to act, faith, and what in life is actually worth pursuing... those are some deep and big questions to arouse in a viewer and for that I definitely appreciate the film. It is definitely beautiful. The camera movements make you feel like you are watching a dream and pretty much each shot looks like it could be framed and hung at an art exhibit. The acting, while confusing at times, was very good. Now, the bad. It is long and confusing. I understand that some people love to let their imaginations fly when finding meaning in these "art" movies. I can appreciate that to an extent. However, I prefer to have some level of cohesiveness and direction. I could not care about any of the characters because I was not given anything to care about. Since I did not care about the characters or understand what motivates them, I could not care or understand their actions or how they interacted with the other characters. When a dog shows up, I attempted to interpret the meaning... but I simply lacked the information to make any sense of it. My point is, I prefer to have at least some context in order to interpret and prescribe meaning to what I'm watching. I like movies that make you think and are up to interpretation, but I this was just too abstract for my taste. My wife saw me watching this movie. She sat down and watched 10 minutes. She then got up and asked me why I do this to myself. "This" meaning watching boring old movies. I usually don't answer he because she wouldn't understand anyway, but with this movie I wouldn't have been able to respond even if I wanted to. Her question actually posed the most meaningful and philosophically challenging question of the night. Why spend my time after work fighting sleep and working to understand a boring old movie when I could be doing something fun or productive? This movie is essentially a stream of consciousness, a nonsensical plot to display a collection of beautiful philosophical vignettes, a long slog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ideas about the meaning
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hatem Krema
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS ... What was the hidden concept ?? I think the movie Stalker with its strong symbolism can be interpreted in the context of the Soviet era when religion was brutally suppressed. "The zone"/religion is a place that provides a comfortable sanctuary from the material dull life, and is guarded from entering by the military/ communist authorities. It came to exist from a meteorite/ a heavenly message to earth. For the stalker/ the religious man, it represents home and comfort, although he always enters it with fear to make it/God angry. The zone/ religion has its own natural laws/miracles that defies logic, but you have to get along with. It promises a "room"/paradise were your innermost wishes come true. The road/ life work to reach the room/paradise is tough and requires guidance from a stalker/ religious man. The existence of the room/ paradise has been always challenged by science/the professor and philosophy/the writer, and despite that they try to explore the facts of religion, and have some understanding for it, they could not accept it at the end. Science/the professor was ready to destroy what he could not rationalize, and from the standpoint of the stalker/religious man, science/the professor and philosophy/the writer are completely ignorant despite their knowledge. The stalker personal life/ the religious man life is not materially fulfilling and may be disappointing. The daughter may represent the outcome of following religion blindly, the mind/body may be crippled to move freely but it may have sensitivity and mysticism not owned by others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The BEST film ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Keldi Victoria Konung
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalker (made by cinematography genius Andrei Tarkovsky) is a visually unforgettable film. It's my most favourite film of all time. It's based on short science fiction novel Roadside Picnic - written by Russian science fiction authors Arkady and Boris Strugatsky. It has a very deep storyline that held my interest from the first to the last minute. I was very impressed by the acting of Alexander Kaidanovsky. For most of the film there are only three actors - they did their job amazingly well. From a technical point of view - it is the BEST film ever made! I strongly recommend to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Couldn't sit through the whole film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    l_eeburgess
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most boring films I have ever watched in my whole life. I managed to watch an hour and a half of it, but just could not make it to the end. Art does not make a movie, eerie music and bleak landscapes are all well and good but two and a half hours of it is too much. The endless and monotonous conversations between the characters is basically just mindless babble. Lots of time spent standing around in fields or lying in pools of water. Perhaps I am the wrong person to watch this kind of film, I like substance to a film, I like an engaging story, this provided nothing of enjoyment to me. For the life of me I cannot understand how so many people can rate it so highly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stalker
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My third Tarkovsky's film (after SOLARIS 1972, 8/10 and NOSTALGHIA 1983, 8/10), STALKER is a startling eye-opener, set in a sordid clanking land of rural Soviet Union, after the falling of a meteorite, an enigmatic area "The Zone" has emerged, inside there is a room can grant incomers' innermost wishes, but cordoned by the government with armies, only with the guidance of so called "stalkers", one can reach the room. So the expedition involves one stalker and his two clients, a writer and a professor, one begs for inspiration and the other conceals an ulterior motive. As one can predict, the film is teeming with Tarkovsky's trademark static/panning long shots, mesmerizing and conjuring up a recondite sense of metaphysics, for example, a steady long shot of various items in the water finishes with the focus on a human hand, sometimes it's baffling, as viewers (as well as the two clients) have been warned numerous times by the stalker, the place is precarious, many a predecessor dies mysteriously in the zone, among a large chunk of the time Tarkovsky successfully maintains the stifling suspense to tally with the seedy locale, the movement is painstakingly strung out, so the audiences cannot shun the unknown danger but only succumb to a thorough wallow in the wasteland. Tarkovsky never resort to cheap horror to give vent to excitement or relief, instead, he utilizes a man-made natural surrounding to trap oneself in, and let our own inside demon out to divulge a sense of thrill and frisson. I don't speak Russian, so it probably hinders my apprehension of the dialog, only if the English interpretation could be better, nevertheless, STALKER seems bit chattier than Tarkovsky's other works, their debate ranges from the philosophy of human beings' psychological trials and tribulations, the socio-political radicalism to the awe and frustration towards the mystery and miracles plus the unselfishness of art, etc. I may not be able to fully cover all the implications from the first viewing, but one can not deny here the luxuriant imagery is louder than words at any rate. The cast is also memorable, the monochrome close-ups endow each character with a pictorial impact of their own resolution, the friend-or-foe association motivates the storytelling and excellently penetrates the harmony of the trio thus overshoots viewers' expectation. Myself find the supernatural elements have been fascinatingly deployed in this film, scattering into many inscrutable shots, sometimes only in a jiffy and most strikingly is the ending, with the daughter of the stalker, mind-controls still objects until one glass falls on the ground but the sound is drowned by the strident train running nearby, which ultimately veils the film with a stratum of mystique that qualifies Tarkovsky as one of the most unique and essential filmmaker of all time!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bizarre Russian Science Fiction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A guide known as The Stalker (Alexander Kaidanovsky) leads two men, "the Writer" (Anatoly Solonitsyn) and "the Professor" (Nikolai Grinko), through an area known as the Zone to find a room that grants wishes. Can you believe the film contains 142 shots in 163 minutes, with an average shot length of more than one minute and many shots lasting for more than four minutes. There is no question that the camera lingers, and no surprise that the picture is considered to be slow by many people (early audiences and critics definitely thought so). Almost all of the scenes not set in the Zone are in a high-contrast brown monochrome. What does this mean? That is for you to decide, but it does add an element of fantasy to the picture. The director reportedly said, "I am only interested in the views of two people: one is called Bresson and one called Bergman." Yes, folks, this is art and not entertainment. If you happen to be entertained, that is even better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Has some interesting footage of a run down Russian town but that's about it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Curtin
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    PLEASE NOTE: Spoiler alert(if that's possible). OK. Here's the movie in a nutshell. Man get's up in the middle of the night, wife get's cross and worried he'll get thrown into jail. Man leaves, meets up with a couple of people who have organised to meet him. They make there way through a curfew section of the city patrolled by police/law enforcement, in a Range Rover. They swap to a train car, that they use to get them out of the city into 'The Zone'. The Zone is simply outside the city and is beautiful simply because it's nature and scenery. There's objects such as concrete blocks, tunnels and misc run down rooms they walk through, there journey ends in a room where they all sit and throw rocks into the water. Then it cuts back to the city, man goes for a walk with his wife and kid, they talk, then his daughter puts her head on the table looks incredibly bored and appears to move some glass wear with a psionic ability. One glass falls off the table, the others stop, camera pans to her almost bored to death face end of film. Yes, I get that the poetic points that are mentioned and in particular the message: "Weak is beautiful and strength is nothing, in that when a child is born it is adaptable and flexible. When the child becomes a man it get's hard and set in it's ways, therefore weak is far more beautiful than strength", is a worthy one but hey 3 hours for that? Other points like this but ultimately nothing to do with the overall story which is simply that 'The Stalker' is simply someone who walks people through the zone which is essentially like a walk in the country in an effort to expand there minds from there otherwise pointless existence(talk about ironic, the Stalker is beyond pointless in himself to say the least). For some reason there not meant to go there. Why not is not really explained.(More than likely because some Russian dictator declared it was off limits to ordinary civilians for some reason(we see various signs of war amidst the rubble, bunkers, a gun etc but overall just a lot of pointless walking around scenes with absolutely no meaning, not even poetically). Overall this is an incredibly boring film and I have no idea why it get's such a high rating. As for watch it again. NO WAY, I'd rather stick red hot needles in my eyes. Seriously, don't waste your time, I only gave it 2 stars because 1. The scene in the practically war torn Russian streets was interesting and 2. for the finale at the end of the film which showed that had the movie focused on the talented young girl, it might have been great. Instead she was really depressed because her whole role got 1 minute at the end of the film and the rest of the film was essentially a tangential screed of rubbish. My strong recommendation for a movie with poetic license and far more impact and strong points but still has a great story and is actually endlessly re-watchable(especially if you get the Criterion Collection edition with the bonus versions), is the Terry Gilliam film BRAZIL. Watch that instead, you'll be glad you did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Do you know interesting facts?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leostalker
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's my most dear, secret movie, which I'm ready to watch again and again making journey with characters. As already mentioned in some comments, it's not even film, it's co-existence with travelers, it's a road to your heart or to God, or to elsewhere. I could tell much about this masterpiece, but would like to say about things people, even fond of Tarkovsky art, might unaware of. Below is a quote from Tarkovsky; "For me this work is expression of power of a weak man, man of faith, man of highest spirit. His actions might be impractical and absurd. But impracticality is a sign of high spirit. He has an idea. There is no Zone. He just invented so to take two-three desperate people, bring them there and inspire an idea of some hope for the happiness sake. But finally none of them want to enter this simple room". This is a answer to those (I'm also amongst them), who expressed they guesses that the Zone and the Room are not actually produce miracles or disasters, but just Stalker's words. Though we see corpses, tanks and other things that supposedly confirms the existence of something supernatural, but real miracle (or peril, or change of mind, or growing of souls, if you want) takes places spiritually. This Tarkovsky's explanation (some people, as I am, realized this even before learning Tarkovsky's words) only adds depth to the film. Another interesting point is that the final monologue of Stalker's Wife supposed to be IN BAR (and it's actually shot THERE  look at the wall behind her, when she is speaking), not in Stalker's home. I learnt about it from interwiev of the editor of the film. She (it was a women) offered Tarkovsky to move this scene from the bar closer to the end so to have an effect of addressing not only to Writer and Professor, but to the soul of an amateur. The editor said to Tarkovsky that the difference of the surroundings would not be marked by a amateur because his attention on that moment is fixed on the face of Alisa Freindlich (Wife). Tarkovsky finally agreed and put this scene to the final and it became much deeper then it would have been in the bar. Wife now addresses to all of us (as Writer did sitting near a hole in the Zone after going through the "meatgrinder'). I rewatched film many times and paid attention to the interior of Wife's monologue  it's in the bar! Thanks to advise of films editor we have such a important change of the final moments of film. To end it I would like to mark a strong scene, almost nowhere mentioned. When crippled daughter of Stalker seems to walk Film returns in color and Artemiev's music is heard as to underline the miracle. And several seconds later camera moves revealing us the truth  she is sitting on Stalker's shoulders. What a piercing, shrill moment of a miracle that took place only in our imagination. Wonderful moments!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Atmospheric, weird, intelligent, a little too slow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nate J
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalker is quintessentially Tarkovskii and stagnation-era. Tarkovskii's extended silences, slow painting-like shots, color filters, and obsession with dripping water permeate the film. From the stagnation era, Stalker borrows middle age, cynicism, nihilism, listlessness, and unfulfilled desire. The film is remarkably atmospheric; aside from a few strange occurrences, nothing actually corroborates the titular Stalker's claims of supernatural danger in the Zone, and yet the fog, the ruins, the unearthly electronic music, and the apprehension of the characters gives an air of ominous oppression to what is objectively a very simple film. Alienation is a constant theme. In one sense, the Zone disobeys physical laws, traps and kills, and inspires introspection in a terrifyingly sublime way. In another sense, the Zone is the most "real" place in the film  it is in color, it is a place of hope, and it is the only place the Stalker claims to be at home, in opposition to the muddy-brown drudgery of the outside world. The dichotomy of Zone and reality, hope and cynicism, comfort and danger, unconscious desires and active passions are constantly at play, and often flipping. I couldn't shake the feeling that the film had something to say about communism and the stagnation period: the Zone is a place of refuge and also a place of weirdness, it attracts the hopeless, and yet offers possibility. One character wants to destroy it, due to the terrible power it might give to bad men. Another character argues that this cannot happen, because man's inner desires will always trump their ideological positions. The Stalker wants only to bring visitors to the Zone for hope and happiness, and grieves at the inability of "intellectuals" to give it their faith. His wife narrates, "If we hadn't had our misfortunes, it would have been worsethere wouldn't have been any hope." Whether or not these stagnation themes were deliberately placed or an osmotic result of the era is irrelevant  the film is imminently malleable in interpretation. Stalker is nothing if not strange, and there are scenes that cannot be described with any justice in writing. The atmosphere is beautifully wrought, and the film thankfully does not spoil its own premise with over-exposition or ludicrous elements, as science fiction is often wont to do, but scenes tend to drag, and the film might have benefited from some more judicious editing. The most striking and well-timed scene in the entire story occurs in the last two minutes, and one wonders what Tarkovskii might have done with a little more money and a more hawk-eyed editor. Overall, Stalker is strange, atmospheric, introspective, and a little too long for its own good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    stalking the truth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dminkin
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What is happiness? What is the meaning of life? What is the Zone? And what exactly is reality? These questions and many more you will find yourselves asking as you enter the Zone, a place with a Room where all wishes come true. Don't expect too many answers, but try to enjoy the journey, even amidst the decay and ruin of both man and machine. Tarkovsky's Zone is a place of magic, a place where ordinary physical laws don't apply. If one is skeptical that the scenery is what it is, and that there is nothing more to it than what you see with your eyes, the camera in conjunction with the dialogue works hard to convince you otherwise. Distance, scale, and position are all warped, not by any special effect of the camera as in ordinary sci-fi movies, but by the positioning, angle, and movement of the camera within a shot. To take one harrowing example: In the early part of the journey to the Room contained within the central core of the Zone, the small company of travelers, the Stalker, the Professor, and the Writer, pass a blackened trailer containing intact fleshy skeletons. The camera tracks the travelers as they move from a vantage point that deliberately inserts this trailer of death in between. Ever so slowly it creeps up to the scene of death, enlarging and magnifying the details of the decaying corpses, until the camera, having just gotten past the point where it has crept so far up, then overshoots the dead. But it stops; so that while the travelers contemplate the fate of these dead "tourists" to the Zone, we are aware that we are actually sitting on top of them. Metal armor, assorted trinkets, and other material possessions that man has donned or created all fall by the wayside and are discarded and rusted at the bottom of pools of water that saturate the Zone. Man's life and possessions are ephemeral and in a constant state of decay in our industrialized, bleak world. Man is removed from Nature, not just in Soviet life but everywhere we look. It becomes apparent that the only way to survive such ruin of both spirit and home is with faith and hope. But we don't always know our innermost desires so a trip to the Room is fruitless if we have a specific goal in mind. The central dilemma is that the Stalker's faith is predicated upon his belief that the inner desires of most people are good. However, the Writer and Professor, from different but not necessarily opposing perspectives, espouse a view that their deepest desires may not necessarily have the best intentions, despite a basic sense of morality that pervades their respective consciences. This is what I think Tarkovsky was trying to depict, without giving an answer, since there may not be one in this brilliant, philosophical, haunting, and beautifully poetic meditation on what it means to be human in a particular reality that we can see but not really ever grasp.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmm...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    srmontgo
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a hard movie to rate. There was a good amount to love and a lot to hate for me. First, the good. I can appreciate that this is not a movie to just sit back and passively be entertained by. This is a movie that encourages you to be thoughtful and observant, kind of like a Professor and a Scientist. There are scenes in this movie that made me question my beliefs about what motivates humans to act, faith, and what in life is actually worth pursuing... those are some deep and big questions to arouse in a viewer and for that I definitely appreciate the film. It is definitely beautiful. The camera movements make you feel like you are watching a dream and pretty much each shot looks like it could be framed and hung at an art exhibit. The acting, while confusing at times, was very good. Now, the bad. It is long and confusing. I understand that some people love to let their imaginations fly when finding meaning in these "art" movies. I can appreciate that to an extent. However, I prefer to have some level of cohesiveness and direction. I could not care about any of the characters because I was not given anything to care about. Since I did not care about the characters or understand what motivates them, I could not care or understand their actions or how they interacted with the other characters. When a dog shows up, I attempted to interpret the meaning... but I simply lacked the information to make any sense of it. My point is, I prefer to have at least some context in order to interpret and prescribe meaning to what I'm watching. I like movies that make you think and are up to interpretation, but I this was just too abstract for my taste. My wife saw me watching this movie. She sat down and watched 10 minutes. She then got up and asked me why I do this to myself. "This" meaning watching boring old movies. I usually don't answer he because she wouldn't understand anyway, but with this movie I wouldn't have been able to respond even if I wanted to. Her question actually posed the most meaningful and philosophically challenging question of the night. Why spend my time after work fighting sleep and working to understand a boring old movie when I could be doing something fun or productive? This movie is essentially a stream of consciousness, a nonsensical plot to display a collection of beautiful philosophical vignettes, a long slog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ideas about the meaning
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hatem Krema
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS ... What was the hidden concept ?? I think the movie Stalker with its strong symbolism can be interpreted in the context of the Soviet era when religion was brutally suppressed. "The zone"/religion is a place that provides a comfortable sanctuary from the material dull life, and is guarded from entering by the military/ communist authorities. It came to exist from a meteorite/ a heavenly message to earth. For the stalker/ the religious man, it represents home and comfort, although he always enters it with fear to make it/God angry. The zone/ religion has its own natural laws/miracles that defies logic, but you have to get along with. It promises a "room"/paradise were your innermost wishes come true. The road/ life work to reach the room/paradise is tough and requires guidance from a stalker/ religious man. The existence of the room/ paradise has been always challenged by science/the professor and philosophy/the writer, and despite that they try to explore the facts of religion, and have some understanding for it, they could not accept it at the end. Science/the professor was ready to destroy what he could not rationalize, and from the standpoint of the stalker/religious man, science/the professor and philosophy/the writer are completely ignorant despite their knowledge. The stalker personal life/ the religious man life is not materially fulfilling and may be disappointing. The daughter may represent the outcome of following religion blindly, the mind/body may be crippled to move freely but it may have sensitivity and mysticism not owned by others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The BEST film ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Keldi Victoria Konung
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalker (made by cinematography genius Andrei Tarkovsky) is a visually unforgettable film. It's my most favourite film of all time. It's based on short science fiction novel Roadside Picnic - written by Russian science fiction authors Arkady and Boris Strugatsky. It has a very deep storyline that held my interest from the first to the last minute. I was very impressed by the acting of Alexander Kaidanovsky. For most of the film there are only three actors - they did their job amazingly well. From a technical point of view - it is the BEST film ever made! I strongly recommend to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Couldn't sit through the whole film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    l_eeburgess
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most boring films I have ever watched in my whole life. I managed to watch an hour and a half of it, but just could not make it to the end. Art does not make a movie, eerie music and bleak landscapes are all well and good but two and a half hours of it is too much. The endless and monotonous conversations between the characters is basically just mindless babble. Lots of time spent standing around in fields or lying in pools of water. Perhaps I am the wrong person to watch this kind of film, I like substance to a film, I like an engaging story, this provided nothing of enjoyment to me. For the life of me I cannot understand how so many people can rate it so highly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stalker
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My third Tarkovsky's film (after SOLARIS 1972, 8/10 and NOSTALGHIA 1983, 8/10), STALKER is a startling eye-opener, set in a sordid clanking land of rural Soviet Union, after the falling of a meteorite, an enigmatic area "The Zone" has emerged, inside there is a room can grant incomers' innermost wishes, but cordoned by the government with armies, only with the guidance of so called "stalkers", one can reach the room. So the expedition involves one stalker and his two clients, a writer and a professor, one begs for inspiration and the other conceals an ulterior motive. As one can predict, the film is teeming with Tarkovsky's trademark static/panning long shots, mesmerizing and conjuring up a recondite sense of metaphysics, for example, a steady long shot of various items in the water finishes with the focus on a human hand, sometimes it's baffling, as viewers (as well as the two clients) have been warned numerous times by the stalker, the place is precarious, many a predecessor dies mysteriously in the zone, among a large chunk of the time Tarkovsky successfully maintains the stifling suspense to tally with the seedy locale, the movement is painstakingly strung out, so the audiences cannot shun the unknown danger but only succumb to a thorough wallow in the wasteland. Tarkovsky never resort to cheap horror to give vent to excitement or relief, instead, he utilizes a man-made natural surrounding to trap oneself in, and let our own inside demon out to divulge a sense of thrill and frisson. I don't speak Russian, so it probably hinders my apprehension of the dialog, only if the English interpretation could be better, nevertheless, STALKER seems bit chattier than Tarkovsky's other works, their debate ranges from the philosophy of human beings' psychological trials and tribulations, the socio-political radicalism to the awe and frustration towards the mystery and miracles plus the unselfishness of art, etc. I may not be able to fully cover all the implications from the first viewing, but one can not deny here the luxuriant imagery is louder than words at any rate. The cast is also memorable, the monochrome close-ups endow each character with a pictorial impact of their own resolution, the friend-or-foe association motivates the storytelling and excellently penetrates the harmony of the trio thus overshoots viewers' expectation. Myself find the supernatural elements have been fascinatingly deployed in this film, scattering into many inscrutable shots, sometimes only in a jiffy and most strikingly is the ending, with the daughter of the stalker, mind-controls still objects until one glass falls on the ground but the sound is drowned by the strident train running nearby, which ultimately veils the film with a stratum of mystique that qualifies Tarkovsky as one of the most unique and essential filmmaker of all time!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bizarre Russian Science Fiction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A guide known as The Stalker (Alexander Kaidanovsky) leads two men, "the Writer" (Anatoly Solonitsyn) and "the Professor" (Nikolai Grinko), through an area known as the Zone to find a room that grants wishes. Can you believe the film contains 142 shots in 163 minutes, with an average shot length of more than one minute and many shots lasting for more than four minutes. There is no question that the camera lingers, and no surprise that the picture is considered to be slow by many people (early audiences and critics definitely thought so). Almost all of the scenes not set in the Zone are in a high-contrast brown monochrome. What does this mean? That is for you to decide, but it does add an element of fantasy to the picture. The director reportedly said, "I am only interested in the views of two people: one is called Bresson and one called Bergman." Yes, folks, this is art and not entertainment. If you happen to be entertained, that is even better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Has some interesting footage of a run down Russian town but that's about it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Curtin
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    PLEASE NOTE: Spoiler alert(if that's possible). OK. Here's the movie in a nutshell. Man get's up in the middle of the night, wife get's cross and worried he'll get thrown into jail. Man leaves, meets up with a couple of people who have organised to meet him. They make there way through a curfew section of the city patrolled by police/law enforcement, in a Range Rover. They swap to a train car, that they use to get them out of the city into 'The Zone'. The Zone is simply outside the city and is beautiful simply because it's nature and scenery. There's objects such as concrete blocks, tunnels and misc run down rooms they walk through, there journey ends in a room where they all sit and throw rocks into the water. Then it cuts back to the city, man goes for a walk with his wife and kid, they talk, then his daughter puts her head on the table looks incredibly bored and appears to move some glass wear with a psionic ability. One glass falls off the table, the others stop, camera pans to her almost bored to death face end of film. Yes, I get that the poetic points that are mentioned and in particular the message: "Weak is beautiful and strength is nothing, in that when a child is born it is adaptable and flexible. When the child becomes a man it get's hard and set in it's ways, therefore weak is far more beautiful than strength", is a worthy one but hey 3 hours for that? Other points like this but ultimately nothing to do with the overall story which is simply that 'The Stalker' is simply someone who walks people through the zone which is essentially like a walk in the country in an effort to expand there minds from there otherwise pointless existence(talk about ironic, the Stalker is beyond pointless in himself to say the least). For some reason there not meant to go there. Why not is not really explained.(More than likely because some Russian dictator declared it was off limits to ordinary civilians for some reason(we see various signs of war amidst the rubble, bunkers, a gun etc but overall just a lot of pointless walking around scenes with absolutely no meaning, not even poetically). Overall this is an incredibly boring film and I have no idea why it get's such a high rating. As for watch it again. NO WAY, I'd rather stick red hot needles in my eyes. Seriously, don't waste your time, I only gave it 2 stars because 1. The scene in the practically war torn Russian streets was interesting and 2. for the finale at the end of the film which showed that had the movie focused on the talented young girl, it might have been great. Instead she was really depressed because her whole role got 1 minute at the end of the film and the rest of the film was essentially a tangential screed of rubbish. My strong recommendation for a movie with poetic license and far more impact and strong points but still has a great story and is actually endlessly re-watchable(especially if you get the Criterion Collection edition with the bonus versions), is the Terry Gilliam film BRAZIL. Watch that instead, you'll be glad you did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Do you know interesting facts?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leostalker
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's my most dear, secret movie, which I'm ready to watch again and again making journey with characters. As already mentioned in some comments, it's not even film, it's co-existence with travelers, it's a road to your heart or to God, or to elsewhere. I could tell much about this masterpiece, but would like to say about things people, even fond of Tarkovsky art, might unaware of. Below is a quote from Tarkovsky; "For me this work is expression of power of a weak man, man of faith, man of highest spirit. His actions might be impractical and absurd. But impracticality is a sign of high spirit. He has an idea. There is no Zone. He just invented so to take two-three desperate people, bring them there and inspire an idea of some hope for the happiness sake. But finally none of them want to enter this simple room". This is a answer to those (I'm also amongst them), who expressed they guesses that the Zone and the Room are not actually produce miracles or disasters, but just Stalker's words. Though we see corpses, tanks and other things that supposedly confirms the existence of something supernatural, but real miracle (or peril, or change of mind, or growing of souls, if you want) takes places spiritually. This Tarkovsky's explanation (some people, as I am, realized this even before learning Tarkovsky's words) only adds depth to the film. Another interesting point is that the final monologue of Stalker's Wife supposed to be IN BAR (and it's actually shot THERE  look at the wall behind her, when she is speaking), not in Stalker's home. I learnt about it from interwiev of the editor of the film. She (it was a women) offered Tarkovsky to move this scene from the bar closer to the end so to have an effect of addressing not only to Writer and Professor, but to the soul of an amateur. The editor said to Tarkovsky that the difference of the surroundings would not be marked by a amateur because his attention on that moment is fixed on the face of Alisa Freindlich (Wife). Tarkovsky finally agreed and put this scene to the final and it became much deeper then it would have been in the bar. Wife now addresses to all of us (as Writer did sitting near a hole in the Zone after going through the "meatgrinder'). I rewatched film many times and paid attention to the interior of Wife's monologue  it's in the bar! Thanks to advise of films editor we have such a important change of the final moments of film. To end it I would like to mark a strong scene, almost nowhere mentioned. When crippled daughter of Stalker seems to walk Film returns in color and Artemiev's music is heard as to underline the miracle. And several seconds later camera moves revealing us the truth  she is sitting on Stalker's shoulders. What a piercing, shrill moment of a miracle that took place only in our imagination. Wonderful moments!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Atmospheric, weird, intelligent, a little too slow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nate J
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalker is quintessentially Tarkovskii and stagnation-era. Tarkovskii's extended silences, slow painting-like shots, color filters, and obsession with dripping water permeate the film. From the stagnation era, Stalker borrows middle age, cynicism, nihilism, listlessness, and unfulfilled desire. The film is remarkably atmospheric; aside from a few strange occurrences, nothing actually corroborates the titular Stalker's claims of supernatural danger in the Zone, and yet the fog, the ruins, the unearthly electronic music, and the apprehension of the characters gives an air of ominous oppression to what is objectively a very simple film. Alienation is a constant theme. In one sense, the Zone disobeys physical laws, traps and kills, and inspires introspection in a terrifyingly sublime way. In another sense, the Zone is the most "real" place in the film  it is in color, it is a place of hope, and it is the only place the Stalker claims to be at home, in opposition to the muddy-brown drudgery of the outside world. The dichotomy of Zone and reality, hope and cynicism, comfort and danger, unconscious desires and active passions are constantly at play, and often flipping. I couldn't shake the feeling that the film had something to say about communism and the stagnation period: the Zone is a place of refuge and also a place of weirdness, it attracts the hopeless, and yet offers possibility. One character wants to destroy it, due to the terrible power it might give to bad men. Another character argues that this cannot happen, because man's inner desires will always trump their ideological positions. The Stalker wants only to bring visitors to the Zone for hope and happiness, and grieves at the inability of "intellectuals" to give it their faith. His wife narrates, "If we hadn't had our misfortunes, it would have been worsethere wouldn't have been any hope." Whether or not these stagnation themes were deliberately placed or an osmotic result of the era is irrelevant  the film is imminently malleable in interpretation. Stalker is nothing if not strange, and there are scenes that cannot be described with any justice in writing. The atmosphere is beautifully wrought, and the film thankfully does not spoil its own premise with over-exposition or ludicrous elements, as science fiction is often wont to do, but scenes tend to drag, and the film might have benefited from some more judicious editing. The most striking and well-timed scene in the entire story occurs in the last two minutes, and one wonders what Tarkovskii might have done with a little more money and a more hawk-eyed editor. Overall, Stalker is strange, atmospheric, introspective, and a little too long for its own good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    stalking the truth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dminkin
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What is happiness? What is the meaning of life? What is the Zone? And what exactly is reality? These questions and many more you will find yourselves asking as you enter the Zone, a place with a Room where all wishes come true. Don't expect too many answers, but try to enjoy the journey, even amidst the decay and ruin of both man and machine. Tarkovsky's Zone is a place of magic, a place where ordinary physical laws don't apply. If one is skeptical that the scenery is what it is, and that there is nothing more to it than what you see with your eyes, the camera in conjunction with the dialogue works hard to convince you otherwise. Distance, scale, and position are all warped, not by any special effect of the camera as in ordinary sci-fi movies, but by the positioning, angle, and movement of the camera within a shot. To take one harrowing example: In the early part of the journey to the Room contained within the central core of the Zone, the small company of travelers, the Stalker, the Professor, and the Writer, pass a blackened trailer containing intact fleshy skeletons. The camera tracks the travelers as they move from a vantage point that deliberately inserts this trailer of death in between. Ever so slowly it creeps up to the scene of death, enlarging and magnifying the details of the decaying corpses, until the camera, having just gotten past the point where it has crept so far up, then overshoots the dead. But it stops; so that while the travelers contemplate the fate of these dead "tourists" to the Zone, we are aware that we are actually sitting on top of them. Metal armor, assorted trinkets, and other material possessions that man has donned or created all fall by the wayside and are discarded and rusted at the bottom of pools of water that saturate the Zone. Man's life and possessions are ephemeral and in a constant state of decay in our industrialized, bleak world. Man is removed from Nature, not just in Soviet life but everywhere we look. It becomes apparent that the only way to survive such ruin of both spirit and home is with faith and hope. But we don't always know our innermost desires so a trip to the Room is fruitless if we have a specific goal in mind. The central dilemma is that the Stalker's faith is predicated upon his belief that the inner desires of most people are good. However, the Writer and Professor, from different but not necessarily opposing perspectives, espouse a view that their deepest desires may not necessarily have the best intentions, despite a basic sense of morality that pervades their respective consciences. This is what I think Tarkovsky was trying to depict, without giving an answer, since there may not be one in this brilliant, philosophical, haunting, and beautifully poetic meditation on what it means to be human in a particular reality that we can see but not really ever grasp.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmm...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    srmontgo
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a hard movie to rate. There was a good amount to love and a lot to hate for me. First, the good. I can appreciate that this is not a movie to just sit back and passively be entertained by. This is a movie that encourages you to be thoughtful and observant, kind of like a Professor and a Scientist. There are scenes in this movie that made me question my beliefs about what motivates humans to act, faith, and what in life is actually worth pursuing... those are some deep and big questions to arouse in a viewer and for that I definitely appreciate the film. It is definitely beautiful. The camera movements make you feel like you are watching a dream and pretty much each shot looks like it could be framed and hung at an art exhibit. The acting, while confusing at times, was very good. Now, the bad. It is long and confusing. I understand that some people love to let their imaginations fly when finding meaning in these "art" movies. I can appreciate that to an extent. However, I prefer to have some level of cohesiveness and direction. I could not care about any of the characters because I was not given anything to care about. Since I did not care about the characters or understand what motivates them, I could not care or understand their actions or how they interacted with the other characters. When a dog shows up, I attempted to interpret the meaning... but I simply lacked the information to make any sense of it. My point is, I prefer to have at least some context in order to interpret and prescribe meaning to what I'm watching. I like movies that make you think and are up to interpretation, but I this was just too abstract for my taste. My wife saw me watching this movie. She sat down and watched 10 minutes. She then got up and asked me why I do this to myself. "This" meaning watching boring old movies. I usually don't answer he because she wouldn't understand anyway, but with this movie I wouldn't have been able to respond even if I wanted to. Her question actually posed the most meaningful and philosophically challenging question of the night. Why spend my time after work fighting sleep and working to understand a boring old movie when I could be doing something fun or productive? This movie is essentially a stream of consciousness, a nonsensical plot to display a collection of beautiful philosophical vignettes, a long slog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ideas about the meaning
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hatem Krema
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS ... What was the hidden concept ?? I think the movie Stalker with its strong symbolism can be interpreted in the context of the Soviet era when religion was brutally suppressed. "The zone"/religion is a place that provides a comfortable sanctuary from the material dull life, and is guarded from entering by the military/ communist authorities. It came to exist from a meteorite/ a heavenly message to earth. For the stalker/ the religious man, it represents home and comfort, although he always enters it with fear to make it/God angry. The zone/ religion has its own natural laws/miracles that defies logic, but you have to get along with. It promises a "room"/paradise were your innermost wishes come true. The road/ life work to reach the room/paradise is tough and requires guidance from a stalker/ religious man. The existence of the room/ paradise has been always challenged by science/the professor and philosophy/the writer, and despite that they try to explore the facts of religion, and have some understanding for it, they could not accept it at the end. Science/the professor was ready to destroy what he could not rationalize, and from the standpoint of the stalker/religious man, science/the professor and philosophy/the writer are completely ignorant despite their knowledge. The stalker personal life/ the religious man life is not materially fulfilling and may be disappointing. The daughter may represent the outcome of following religion blindly, the mind/body may be crippled to move freely but it may have sensitivity and mysticism not owned by others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The BEST film ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Keldi Victoria Konung
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalker (made by cinematography genius Andrei Tarkovsky) is a visually unforgettable film. It's my most favourite film of all time. It's based on short science fiction novel Roadside Picnic - written by Russian science fiction authors Arkady and Boris Strugatsky. It has a very deep storyline that held my interest from the first to the last minute. I was very impressed by the acting of Alexander Kaidanovsky. For most of the film there are only three actors - they did their job amazingly well. From a technical point of view - it is the BEST film ever made! I strongly recommend to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Couldn't sit through the whole film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    l_eeburgess
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most boring films I have ever watched in my whole life. I managed to watch an hour and a half of it, but just could not make it to the end. Art does not make a movie, eerie music and bleak landscapes are all well and good but two and a half hours of it is too much. The endless and monotonous conversations between the characters is basically just mindless babble. Lots of time spent standing around in fields or lying in pools of water. Perhaps I am the wrong person to watch this kind of film, I like substance to a film, I like an engaging story, this provided nothing of enjoyment to me. For the life of me I cannot understand how so many people can rate it so highly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stalker
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My third Tarkovsky's film (after SOLARIS 1972, 8/10 and NOSTALGHIA 1983, 8/10), STALKER is a startling eye-opener, set in a sordid clanking land of rural Soviet Union, after the falling of a meteorite, an enigmatic area "The Zone" has emerged, inside there is a room can grant incomers' innermost wishes, but cordoned by the government with armies, only with the guidance of so called "stalkers", one can reach the room. So the expedition involves one stalker and his two clients, a writer and a professor, one begs for inspiration and the other conceals an ulterior motive. As one can predict, the film is teeming with Tarkovsky's trademark static/panning long shots, mesmerizing and conjuring up a recondite sense of metaphysics, for example, a steady long shot of various items in the water finishes with the focus on a human hand, sometimes it's baffling, as viewers (as well as the two clients) have been warned numerous times by the stalker, the place is precarious, many a predecessor dies mysteriously in the zone, among a large chunk of the time Tarkovsky successfully maintains the stifling suspense to tally with the seedy locale, the movement is painstakingly strung out, so the audiences cannot shun the unknown danger but only succumb to a thorough wallow in the wasteland. Tarkovsky never resort to cheap horror to give vent to excitement or relief, instead, he utilizes a man-made natural surrounding to trap oneself in, and let our own inside demon out to divulge a sense of thrill and frisson. I don't speak Russian, so it probably hinders my apprehension of the dialog, only if the English interpretation could be better, nevertheless, STALKER seems bit chattier than Tarkovsky's other works, their debate ranges from the philosophy of human beings' psychological trials and tribulations, the socio-political radicalism to the awe and frustration towards the mystery and miracles plus the unselfishness of art, etc. I may not be able to fully cover all the implications from the first viewing, but one can not deny here the luxuriant imagery is louder than words at any rate. The cast is also memorable, the monochrome close-ups endow each character with a pictorial impact of their own resolution, the friend-or-foe association motivates the storytelling and excellently penetrates the harmony of the trio thus overshoots viewers' expectation. Myself find the supernatural elements have been fascinatingly deployed in this film, scattering into many inscrutable shots, sometimes only in a jiffy and most strikingly is the ending, with the daughter of the stalker, mind-controls still objects until one glass falls on the ground but the sound is drowned by the strident train running nearby, which ultimately veils the film with a stratum of mystique that qualifies Tarkovsky as one of the most unique and essential filmmaker of all time!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bizarre Russian Science Fiction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A guide known as The Stalker (Alexander Kaidanovsky) leads two men, "the Writer" (Anatoly Solonitsyn) and "the Professor" (Nikolai Grinko), through an area known as the Zone to find a room that grants wishes. Can you believe the film contains 142 shots in 163 minutes, with an average shot length of more than one minute and many shots lasting for more than four minutes. There is no question that the camera lingers, and no surprise that the picture is considered to be slow by many people (early audiences and critics definitely thought so). Almost all of the scenes not set in the Zone are in a high-contrast brown monochrome. What does this mean? That is for you to decide, but it does add an element of fantasy to the picture. The director reportedly said, "I am only interested in the views of two people: one is called Bresson and one called Bergman." Yes, folks, this is art and not entertainment. If you happen to be entertained, that is even better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Has some interesting footage of a run down Russian town but that's about it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Curtin
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    PLEASE NOTE: Spoiler alert(if that's possible). OK. Here's the movie in a nutshell. Man get's up in the middle of the night, wife get's cross and worried he'll get thrown into jail. Man leaves, meets up with a couple of people who have organised to meet him. They make there way through a curfew section of the city patrolled by police/law enforcement, in a Range Rover. They swap to a train car, that they use to get them out of the city into 'The Zone'. The Zone is simply outside the city and is beautiful simply because it's nature and scenery. There's objects such as concrete blocks, tunnels and misc run down rooms they walk through, there journey ends in a room where they all sit and throw rocks into the water. Then it cuts back to the city, man goes for a walk with his wife and kid, they talk, then his daughter puts her head on the table looks incredibly bored and appears to move some glass wear with a psionic ability. One glass falls off the table, the others stop, camera pans to her almost bored to death face end of film. Yes, I get that the poetic points that are mentioned and in particular the message: "Weak is beautiful and strength is nothing, in that when a child is born it is adaptable and flexible. When the child becomes a man it get's hard and set in it's ways, therefore weak is far more beautiful than strength", is a worthy one but hey 3 hours for that? Other points like this but ultimately nothing to do with the overall story which is simply that 'The Stalker' is simply someone who walks people through the zone which is essentially like a walk in the country in an effort to expand there minds from there otherwise pointless existence(talk about ironic, the Stalker is beyond pointless in himself to say the least). For some reason there not meant to go there. Why not is not really explained.(More than likely because some Russian dictator declared it was off limits to ordinary civilians for some reason(we see various signs of war amidst the rubble, bunkers, a gun etc but overall just a lot of pointless walking around scenes with absolutely no meaning, not even poetically). Overall this is an incredibly boring film and I have no idea why it get's such a high rating. As for watch it again. NO WAY, I'd rather stick red hot needles in my eyes. Seriously, don't waste your time, I only gave it 2 stars because 1. The scene in the practically war torn Russian streets was interesting and 2. for the finale at the end of the film which showed that had the movie focused on the talented young girl, it might have been great. Instead she was really depressed because her whole role got 1 minute at the end of the film and the rest of the film was essentially a tangential screed of rubbish. My strong recommendation for a movie with poetic license and far more impact and strong points but still has a great story and is actually endlessly re-watchable(especially if you get the Criterion Collection edition with the bonus versions), is the Terry Gilliam film BRAZIL. Watch that instead, you'll be glad you did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Do you know interesting facts?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leostalker
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's my most dear, secret movie, which I'm ready to watch again and again making journey with characters. As already mentioned in some comments, it's not even film, it's co-existence with travelers, it's a road to your heart or to God, or to elsewhere. I could tell much about this masterpiece, but would like to say about things people, even fond of Tarkovsky art, might unaware of. Below is a quote from Tarkovsky; "For me this work is expression of power of a weak man, man of faith, man of highest spirit. His actions might be impractical and absurd. But impracticality is a sign of high spirit. He has an idea. There is no Zone. He just invented so to take two-three desperate people, bring them there and inspire an idea of some hope for the happiness sake. But finally none of them want to enter this simple room". This is a answer to those (I'm also amongst them), who expressed they guesses that the Zone and the Room are not actually produce miracles or disasters, but just Stalker's words. Though we see corpses, tanks and other things that supposedly confirms the existence of something supernatural, but real miracle (or peril, or change of mind, or growing of souls, if you want) takes places spiritually. This Tarkovsky's explanation (some people, as I am, realized this even before learning Tarkovsky's words) only adds depth to the film. Another interesting point is that the final monologue of Stalker's Wife supposed to be IN BAR (and it's actually shot THERE  look at the wall behind her, when she is speaking), not in Stalker's home. I learnt about it from interwiev of the editor of the film. She (it was a women) offered Tarkovsky to move this scene from the bar closer to the end so to have an effect of addressing not only to Writer and Professor, but to the soul of an amateur. The editor said to Tarkovsky that the difference of the surroundings would not be marked by a amateur because his attention on that moment is fixed on the face of Alisa Freindlich (Wife). Tarkovsky finally agreed and put this scene to the final and it became much deeper then it would have been in the bar. Wife now addresses to all of us (as Writer did sitting near a hole in the Zone after going through the "meatgrinder'). I rewatched film many times and paid attention to the interior of Wife's monologue  it's in the bar! Thanks to advise of films editor we have such a important change of the final moments of film. To end it I would like to mark a strong scene, almost nowhere mentioned. When crippled daughter of Stalker seems to walk Film returns in color and Artemiev's music is heard as to underline the miracle. And several seconds later camera moves revealing us the truth  she is sitting on Stalker's shoulders. What a piercing, shrill moment of a miracle that took place only in our imagination. Wonderful moments!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Atmospheric, weird, intelligent, a little too slow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nate J
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalker is quintessentially Tarkovskii and stagnation-era. Tarkovskii's extended silences, slow painting-like shots, color filters, and obsession with dripping water permeate the film. From the stagnation era, Stalker borrows middle age, cynicism, nihilism, listlessness, and unfulfilled desire. The film is remarkably atmospheric; aside from a few strange occurrences, nothing actually corroborates the titular Stalker's claims of supernatural danger in the Zone, and yet the fog, the ruins, the unearthly electronic music, and the apprehension of the characters gives an air of ominous oppression to what is objectively a very simple film. Alienation is a constant theme. In one sense, the Zone disobeys physical laws, traps and kills, and inspires introspection in a terrifyingly sublime way. In another sense, the Zone is the most "real" place in the film  it is in color, it is a place of hope, and it is the only place the Stalker claims to be at home, in opposition to the muddy-brown drudgery of the outside world. The dichotomy of Zone and reality, hope and cynicism, comfort and danger, unconscious desires and active passions are constantly at play, and often flipping. I couldn't shake the feeling that the film had something to say about communism and the stagnation period: the Zone is a place of refuge and also a place of weirdness, it attracts the hopeless, and yet offers possibility. One character wants to destroy it, due to the terrible power it might give to bad men. Another character argues that this cannot happen, because man's inner desires will always trump their ideological positions. The Stalker wants only to bring visitors to the Zone for hope and happiness, and grieves at the inability of "intellectuals" to give it their faith. His wife narrates, "If we hadn't had our misfortunes, it would have been worsethere wouldn't have been any hope." Whether or not these stagnation themes were deliberately placed or an osmotic result of the era is irrelevant  the film is imminently malleable in interpretation. Stalker is nothing if not strange, and there are scenes that cannot be described with any justice in writing. The atmosphere is beautifully wrought, and the film thankfully does not spoil its own premise with over-exposition or ludicrous elements, as science fiction is often wont to do, but scenes tend to drag, and the film might have benefited from some more judicious editing. The most striking and well-timed scene in the entire story occurs in the last two minutes, and one wonders what Tarkovskii might have done with a little more money and a more hawk-eyed editor. Overall, Stalker is strange, atmospheric, introspective, and a little too long for its own good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    stalking the truth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dminkin
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What is happiness? What is the meaning of life? What is the Zone? And what exactly is reality? These questions and many more you will find yourselves asking as you enter the Zone, a place with a Room where all wishes come true. Don't expect too many answers, but try to enjoy the journey, even amidst the decay and ruin of both man and machine. Tarkovsky's Zone is a place of magic, a place where ordinary physical laws don't apply. If one is skeptical that the scenery is what it is, and that there is nothing more to it than what you see with your eyes, the camera in conjunction with the dialogue works hard to convince you otherwise. Distance, scale, and position are all warped, not by any special effect of the camera as in ordinary sci-fi movies, but by the positioning, angle, and movement of the camera within a shot. To take one harrowing example: In the early part of the journey to the Room contained within the central core of the Zone, the small company of travelers, the Stalker, the Professor, and the Writer, pass a blackened trailer containing intact fleshy skeletons. The camera tracks the travelers as they move from a vantage point that deliberately inserts this trailer of death in between. Ever so slowly it creeps up to the scene of death, enlarging and magnifying the details of the decaying corpses, until the camera, having just gotten past the point where it has crept so far up, then overshoots the dead. But it stops; so that while the travelers contemplate the fate of these dead "tourists" to the Zone, we are aware that we are actually sitting on top of them. Metal armor, assorted trinkets, and other material possessions that man has donned or created all fall by the wayside and are discarded and rusted at the bottom of pools of water that saturate the Zone. Man's life and possessions are ephemeral and in a constant state of decay in our industrialized, bleak world. Man is removed from Nature, not just in Soviet life but everywhere we look. It becomes apparent that the only way to survive such ruin of both spirit and home is with faith and hope. But we don't always know our innermost desires so a trip to the Room is fruitless if we have a specific goal in mind. The central dilemma is that the Stalker's faith is predicated upon his belief that the inner desires of most people are good. However, the Writer and Professor, from different but not necessarily opposing perspectives, espouse a view that their deepest desires may not necessarily have the best intentions, despite a basic sense of morality that pervades their respective consciences. This is what I think Tarkovsky was trying to depict, without giving an answer, since there may not be one in this brilliant, philosophical, haunting, and beautifully poetic meditation on what it means to be human in a particular reality that we can see but not really ever grasp.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmm...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    srmontgo
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a hard movie to rate. There was a good amount to love and a lot to hate for me. First, the good. I can appreciate that this is not a movie to just sit back and passively be entertained by. This is a movie that encourages you to be thoughtful and observant, kind of like a Professor and a Scientist. There are scenes in this movie that made me question my beliefs about what motivates humans to act, faith, and what in life is actually worth pursuing... those are some deep and big questions to arouse in a viewer and for that I definitely appreciate the film. It is definitely beautiful. The camera movements make you feel like you are watching a dream and pretty much each shot looks like it could be framed and hung at an art exhibit. The acting, while confusing at times, was very good. Now, the bad. It is long and confusing. I understand that some people love to let their imaginations fly when finding meaning in these "art" movies. I can appreciate that to an extent. However, I prefer to have some level of cohesiveness and direction. I could not care about any of the characters because I was not given anything to care about. Since I did not care about the characters or understand what motivates them, I could not care or understand their actions or how they interacted with the other characters. When a dog shows up, I attempted to interpret the meaning... but I simply lacked the information to make any sense of it. My point is, I prefer to have at least some context in order to interpret and prescribe meaning to what I'm watching. I like movies that make you think and are up to interpretation, but I this was just too abstract for my taste. My wife saw me watching this movie. She sat down and watched 10 minutes. She then got up and asked me why I do this to myself. "This" meaning watching boring old movies. I usually don't answer he because she wouldn't understand anyway, but with this movie I wouldn't have been able to respond even if I wanted to. Her question actually posed the most meaningful and philosophically challenging question of the night. Why spend my time after work fighting sleep and working to understand a boring old movie when I could be doing something fun or productive? This movie is essentially a stream of consciousness, a nonsensical plot to display a collection of beautiful philosophical vignettes, a long slog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ideas about the meaning
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hatem Krema
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS ... What was the hidden concept ?? I think the movie Stalker with its strong symbolism can be interpreted in the context of the Soviet era when religion was brutally suppressed. "The zone"/religion is a place that provides a comfortable sanctuary from the material dull life, and is guarded from entering by the military/ communist authorities. It came to exist from a meteorite/ a heavenly message to earth. For the stalker/ the religious man, it represents home and comfort, although he always enters it with fear to make it/God angry. The zone/ religion has its own natural laws/miracles that defies logic, but you have to get along with. It promises a "room"/paradise were your innermost wishes come true. The road/ life work to reach the room/paradise is tough and requires guidance from a stalker/ religious man. The existence of the room/ paradise has been always challenged by science/the professor and philosophy/the writer, and despite that they try to explore the facts of religion, and have some understanding for it, they could not accept it at the end. Science/the professor was ready to destroy what he could not rationalize, and from the standpoint of the stalker/religious man, science/the professor and philosophy/the writer are completely ignorant despite their knowledge. The stalker personal life/ the religious man life is not materially fulfilling and may be disappointing. The daughter may represent the outcome of following religion blindly, the mind/body may be crippled to move freely but it may have sensitivity and mysticism not owned by others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The BEST film ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Keldi Victoria Konung
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalker (made by cinematography genius Andrei Tarkovsky) is a visually unforgettable film. It's my most favourite film of all time. It's based on short science fiction novel Roadside Picnic - written by Russian science fiction authors Arkady and Boris Strugatsky. It has a very deep storyline that held my interest from the first to the last minute. I was very impressed by the acting of Alexander Kaidanovsky. For most of the film there are only three actors - they did their job amazingly well. From a technical point of view - it is the BEST film ever made! I strongly recommend to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Couldn't sit through the whole film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    l_eeburgess
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most boring films I have ever watched in my whole life. I managed to watch an hour and a half of it, but just could not make it to the end. Art does not make a movie, eerie music and bleak landscapes are all well and good but two and a half hours of it is too much. The endless and monotonous conversations between the characters is basically just mindless babble. Lots of time spent standing around in fields or lying in pools of water. Perhaps I am the wrong person to watch this kind of film, I like substance to a film, I like an engaging story, this provided nothing of enjoyment to me. For the life of me I cannot understand how so many people can rate it so highly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stalker
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My third Tarkovsky's film (after SOLARIS 1972, 8/10 and NOSTALGHIA 1983, 8/10), STALKER is a startling eye-opener, set in a sordid clanking land of rural Soviet Union, after the falling of a meteorite, an enigmatic area "The Zone" has emerged, inside there is a room can grant incomers' innermost wishes, but cordoned by the government with armies, only with the guidance of so called "stalkers", one can reach the room. So the expedition involves one stalker and his two clients, a writer and a professor, one begs for inspiration and the other conceals an ulterior motive. As one can predict, the film is teeming with Tarkovsky's trademark static/panning long shots, mesmerizing and conjuring up a recondite sense of metaphysics, for example, a steady long shot of various items in the water finishes with the focus on a human hand, sometimes it's baffling, as viewers (as well as the two clients) have been warned numerous times by the stalker, the place is precarious, many a predecessor dies mysteriously in the zone, among a large chunk of the time Tarkovsky successfully maintains the stifling suspense to tally with the seedy locale, the movement is painstakingly strung out, so the audiences cannot shun the unknown danger but only succumb to a thorough wallow in the wasteland. Tarkovsky never resort to cheap horror to give vent to excitement or relief, instead, he utilizes a man-made natural surrounding to trap oneself in, and let our own inside demon out to divulge a sense of thrill and frisson. I don't speak Russian, so it probably hinders my apprehension of the dialog, only if the English interpretation could be better, nevertheless, STALKER seems bit chattier than Tarkovsky's other works, their debate ranges from the philosophy of human beings' psychological trials and tribulations, the socio-political radicalism to the awe and frustration towards the mystery and miracles plus the unselfishness of art, etc. I may not be able to fully cover all the implications from the first viewing, but one can not deny here the luxuriant imagery is louder than words at any rate. The cast is also memorable, the monochrome close-ups endow each character with a pictorial impact of their own resolution, the friend-or-foe association motivates the storytelling and excellently penetrates the harmony of the trio thus overshoots viewers' expectation. Myself find the supernatural elements have been fascinatingly deployed in this film, scattering into many inscrutable shots, sometimes only in a jiffy and most strikingly is the ending, with the daughter of the stalker, mind-controls still objects until one glass falls on the ground but the sound is drowned by the strident train running nearby, which ultimately veils the film with a stratum of mystique that qualifies Tarkovsky as one of the most unique and essential filmmaker of all time!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bizarre Russian Science Fiction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A guide known as The Stalker (Alexander Kaidanovsky) leads two men, "the Writer" (Anatoly Solonitsyn) and "the Professor" (Nikolai Grinko), through an area known as the Zone to find a room that grants wishes. Can you believe the film contains 142 shots in 163 minutes, with an average shot length of more than one minute and many shots lasting for more than four minutes. There is no question that the camera lingers, and no surprise that the picture is considered to be slow by many people (early audiences and critics definitely thought so). Almost all of the scenes not set in the Zone are in a high-contrast brown monochrome. What does this mean? That is for you to decide, but it does add an element of fantasy to the picture. The director reportedly said, "I am only interested in the views of two people: one is called Bresson and one called Bergman." Yes, folks, this is art and not entertainment. If you happen to be entertained, that is even better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Has some interesting footage of a run down Russian town but that's about it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Curtin
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    PLEASE NOTE: Spoiler alert(if that's possible). OK. Here's the movie in a nutshell. Man get's up in the middle of the night, wife get's cross and worried he'll get thrown into jail. Man leaves, meets up with a couple of people who have organised to meet him. They make there way through a curfew section of the city patrolled by police/law enforcement, in a Range Rover. They swap to a train car, that they use to get them out of the city into 'The Zone'. The Zone is simply outside the city and is beautiful simply because it's nature and scenery. There's objects such as concrete blocks, tunnels and misc run down rooms they walk through, there journey ends in a room where they all sit and throw rocks into the water. Then it cuts back to the city, man goes for a walk with his wife and kid, they talk, then his daughter puts her head on the table looks incredibly bored and appears to move some glass wear with a psionic ability. One glass falls off the table, the others stop, camera pans to her almost bored to death face end of film. Yes, I get that the poetic points that are mentioned and in particular the message: "Weak is beautiful and strength is nothing, in that when a child is born it is adaptable and flexible. When the child becomes a man it get's hard and set in it's ways, therefore weak is far more beautiful than strength", is a worthy one but hey 3 hours for that? Other points like this but ultimately nothing to do with the overall story which is simply that 'The Stalker' is simply someone who walks people through the zone which is essentially like a walk in the country in an effort to expand there minds from there otherwise pointless existence(talk about ironic, the Stalker is beyond pointless in himself to say the least). For some reason there not meant to go there. Why not is not really explained.(More than likely because some Russian dictator declared it was off limits to ordinary civilians for some reason(we see various signs of war amidst the rubble, bunkers, a gun etc but overall just a lot of pointless walking around scenes with absolutely no meaning, not even poetically). Overall this is an incredibly boring film and I have no idea why it get's such a high rating. As for watch it again. NO WAY, I'd rather stick red hot needles in my eyes. Seriously, don't waste your time, I only gave it 2 stars because 1. The scene in the practically war torn Russian streets was interesting and 2. for the finale at the end of the film which showed that had the movie focused on the talented young girl, it might have been great. Instead she was really depressed because her whole role got 1 minute at the end of the film and the rest of the film was essentially a tangential screed of rubbish. My strong recommendation for a movie with poetic license and far more impact and strong points but still has a great story and is actually endlessly re-watchable(especially if you get the Criterion Collection edition with the bonus versions), is the Terry Gilliam film BRAZIL. Watch that instead, you'll be glad you did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Do you know interesting facts?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leostalker
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's my most dear, secret movie, which I'm ready to watch again and again making journey with characters. As already mentioned in some comments, it's not even film, it's co-existence with travelers, it's a road to your heart or to God, or to elsewhere. I could tell much about this masterpiece, but would like to say about things people, even fond of Tarkovsky art, might unaware of. Below is a quote from Tarkovsky; "For me this work is expression of power of a weak man, man of faith, man of highest spirit. His actions might be impractical and absurd. But impracticality is a sign of high spirit. He has an idea. There is no Zone. He just invented so to take two-three desperate people, bring them there and inspire an idea of some hope for the happiness sake. But finally none of them want to enter this simple room". This is a answer to those (I'm also amongst them), who expressed they guesses that the Zone and the Room are not actually produce miracles or disasters, but just Stalker's words. Though we see corpses, tanks and other things that supposedly confirms the existence of something supernatural, but real miracle (or peril, or change of mind, or growing of souls, if you want) takes places spiritually. This Tarkovsky's explanation (some people, as I am, realized this even before learning Tarkovsky's words) only adds depth to the film. Another interesting point is that the final monologue of Stalker's Wife supposed to be IN BAR (and it's actually shot THERE  look at the wall behind her, when she is speaking), not in Stalker's home. I learnt about it from interwiev of the editor of the film. She (it was a women) offered Tarkovsky to move this scene from the bar closer to the end so to have an effect of addressing not only to Writer and Professor, but to the soul of an amateur. The editor said to Tarkovsky that the difference of the surroundings would not be marked by a amateur because his attention on that moment is fixed on the face of Alisa Freindlich (Wife). Tarkovsky finally agreed and put this scene to the final and it became much deeper then it would have been in the bar. Wife now addresses to all of us (as Writer did sitting near a hole in the Zone after going through the "meatgrinder'). I rewatched film many times and paid attention to the interior of Wife's monologue  it's in the bar! Thanks to advise of films editor we have such a important change of the final moments of film. To end it I would like to mark a strong scene, almost nowhere mentioned. When crippled daughter of Stalker seems to walk Film returns in color and Artemiev's music is heard as to underline the miracle. And several seconds later camera moves revealing us the truth  she is sitting on Stalker's shoulders. What a piercing, shrill moment of a miracle that took place only in our imagination. Wonderful moments!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Atmospheric, weird, intelligent, a little too slow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nate J
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalker is quintessentially Tarkovskii and stagnation-era. Tarkovskii's extended silences, slow painting-like shots, color filters, and obsession with dripping water permeate the film. From the stagnation era, Stalker borrows middle age, cynicism, nihilism, listlessness, and unfulfilled desire. The film is remarkably atmospheric; aside from a few strange occurrences, nothing actually corroborates the titular Stalker's claims of supernatural danger in the Zone, and yet the fog, the ruins, the unearthly electronic music, and the apprehension of the characters gives an air of ominous oppression to what is objectively a very simple film. Alienation is a constant theme. In one sense, the Zone disobeys physical laws, traps and kills, and inspires introspection in a terrifyingly sublime way. In another sense, the Zone is the most "real" place in the film  it is in color, it is a place of hope, and it is the only place the Stalker claims to be at home, in opposition to the muddy-brown drudgery of the outside world. The dichotomy of Zone and reality, hope and cynicism, comfort and danger, unconscious desires and active passions are constantly at play, and often flipping. I couldn't shake the feeling that the film had something to say about communism and the stagnation period: the Zone is a place of refuge and also a place of weirdness, it attracts the hopeless, and yet offers possibility. One character wants to destroy it, due to the terrible power it might give to bad men. Another character argues that this cannot happen, because man's inner desires will always trump their ideological positions. The Stalker wants only to bring visitors to the Zone for hope and happiness, and grieves at the inability of "intellectuals" to give it their faith. His wife narrates, "If we hadn't had our misfortunes, it would have been worsethere wouldn't have been any hope." Whether or not these stagnation themes were deliberately placed or an osmotic result of the era is irrelevant  the film is imminently malleable in interpretation. Stalker is nothing if not strange, and there are scenes that cannot be described with any justice in writing. The atmosphere is beautifully wrought, and the film thankfully does not spoil its own premise with over-exposition or ludicrous elements, as science fiction is often wont to do, but scenes tend to drag, and the film might have benefited from some more judicious editing. The most striking and well-timed scene in the entire story occurs in the last two minutes, and one wonders what Tarkovskii might have done with a little more money and a more hawk-eyed editor. Overall, Stalker is strange, atmospheric, introspective, and a little too long for its own good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    stalking the truth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dminkin
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What is happiness? What is the meaning of life? What is the Zone? And what exactly is reality? These questions and many more you will find yourselves asking as you enter the Zone, a place with a Room where all wishes come true. Don't expect too many answers, but try to enjoy the journey, even amidst the decay and ruin of both man and machine. Tarkovsky's Zone is a place of magic, a place where ordinary physical laws don't apply. If one is skeptical that the scenery is what it is, and that there is nothing more to it than what you see with your eyes, the camera in conjunction with the dialogue works hard to convince you otherwise. Distance, scale, and position are all warped, not by any special effect of the camera as in ordinary sci-fi movies, but by the positioning, angle, and movement of the camera within a shot. To take one harrowing example: In the early part of the journey to the Room contained within the central core of the Zone, the small company of travelers, the Stalker, the Professor, and the Writer, pass a blackened trailer containing intact fleshy skeletons. The camera tracks the travelers as they move from a vantage point that deliberately inserts this trailer of death in between. Ever so slowly it creeps up to the scene of death, enlarging and magnifying the details of the decaying corpses, until the camera, having just gotten past the point where it has crept so far up, then overshoots the dead. But it stops; so that while the travelers contemplate the fate of these dead "tourists" to the Zone, we are aware that we are actually sitting on top of them. Metal armor, assorted trinkets, and other material possessions that man has donned or created all fall by the wayside and are discarded and rusted at the bottom of pools of water that saturate the Zone. Man's life and possessions are ephemeral and in a constant state of decay in our industrialized, bleak world. Man is removed from Nature, not just in Soviet life but everywhere we look. It becomes apparent that the only way to survive such ruin of both spirit and home is with faith and hope. But we don't always know our innermost desires so a trip to the Room is fruitless if we have a specific goal in mind. The central dilemma is that the Stalker's faith is predicated upon his belief that the inner desires of most people are good. However, the Writer and Professor, from different but not necessarily opposing perspectives, espouse a view that their deepest desires may not necessarily have the best intentions, despite a basic sense of morality that pervades their respective consciences. This is what I think Tarkovsky was trying to depict, without giving an answer, since there may not be one in this brilliant, philosophical, haunting, and beautifully poetic meditation on what it means to be human in a particular reality that we can see but not really ever grasp.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmm...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    srmontgo
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a hard movie to rate. There was a good amount to love and a lot to hate for me. First, the good. I can appreciate that this is not a movie to just sit back and passively be entertained by. This is a movie that encourages you to be thoughtful and observant, kind of like a Professor and a Scientist. There are scenes in this movie that made me question my beliefs about what motivates humans to act, faith, and what in life is actually worth pursuing... those are some deep and big questions to arouse in a viewer and for that I definitely appreciate the film. It is definitely beautiful. The camera movements make you feel like you are watching a dream and pretty much each shot looks like it could be framed and hung at an art exhibit. The acting, while confusing at times, was very good. Now, the bad. It is long and confusing. I understand that some people love to let their imaginations fly when finding meaning in these "art" movies. I can appreciate that to an extent. However, I prefer to have some level of cohesiveness and direction. I could not care about any of the characters because I was not given anything to care about. Since I did not care about the characters or understand what motivates them, I could not care or understand their actions or how they interacted with the other characters. When a dog shows up, I attempted to interpret the meaning... but I simply lacked the information to make any sense of it. My point is, I prefer to have at least some context in order to interpret and prescribe meaning to what I'm watching. I like movies that make you think and are up to interpretation, but I this was just too abstract for my taste. My wife saw me watching this movie. She sat down and watched 10 minutes. She then got up and asked me why I do this to myself. "This" meaning watching boring old movies. I usually don't answer he because she wouldn't understand anyway, but with this movie I wouldn't have been able to respond even if I wanted to. Her question actually posed the most meaningful and philosophically challenging question of the night. Why spend my time after work fighting sleep and working to understand a boring old movie when I could be doing something fun or productive? This movie is essentially a stream of consciousness, a nonsensical plot to display a collection of beautiful philosophical vignettes, a long slog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ideas about the meaning
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hatem Krema
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS ... What was the hidden concept ?? I think the movie Stalker with its strong symbolism can be interpreted in the context of the Soviet era when religion was brutally suppressed. "The zone"/religion is a place that provides a comfortable sanctuary from the material dull life, and is guarded from entering by the military/ communist authorities. It came to exist from a meteorite/ a heavenly message to earth. For the stalker/ the religious man, it represents home and comfort, although he always enters it with fear to make it/God angry. The zone/ religion has its own natural laws/miracles that defies logic, but you have to get along with. It promises a "room"/paradise were your innermost wishes come true. The road/ life work to reach the room/paradise is tough and requires guidance from a stalker/ religious man. The existence of the room/ paradise has been always challenged by science/the professor and philosophy/the writer, and despite that they try to explore the facts of religion, and have some understanding for it, they could not accept it at the end. Science/the professor was ready to destroy what he could not rationalize, and from the standpoint of the stalker/religious man, science/the professor and philosophy/the writer are completely ignorant despite their knowledge. The stalker personal life/ the religious man life is not materially fulfilling and may be disappointing. The daughter may represent the outcome of following religion blindly, the mind/body may be crippled to move freely but it may have sensitivity and mysticism not owned by others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The BEST film ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Keldi Victoria Konung
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalker (made by cinematography genius Andrei Tarkovsky) is a visually unforgettable film. It's my most favourite film of all time. It's based on short science fiction novel Roadside Picnic - written by Russian science fiction authors Arkady and Boris Strugatsky. It has a very deep storyline that held my interest from the first to the last minute. I was very impressed by the acting of Alexander Kaidanovsky. For most of the film there are only three actors - they did their job amazingly well. From a technical point of view - it is the BEST film ever made! I strongly recommend to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Couldn't sit through the whole film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    l_eeburgess
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most boring films I have ever watched in my whole life. I managed to watch an hour and a half of it, but just could not make it to the end. Art does not make a movie, eerie music and bleak landscapes are all well and good but two and a half hours of it is too much. The endless and monotonous conversations between the characters is basically just mindless babble. Lots of time spent standing around in fields or lying in pools of water. Perhaps I am the wrong person to watch this kind of film, I like substance to a film, I like an engaging story, this provided nothing of enjoyment to me. For the life of me I cannot understand how so many people can rate it so highly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stalker
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My third Tarkovsky's film (after SOLARIS 1972, 8/10 and NOSTALGHIA 1983, 8/10), STALKER is a startling eye-opener, set in a sordid clanking land of rural Soviet Union, after the falling of a meteorite, an enigmatic area "The Zone" has emerged, inside there is a room can grant incomers' innermost wishes, but cordoned by the government with armies, only with the guidance of so called "stalkers", one can reach the room. So the expedition involves one stalker and his two clients, a writer and a professor, one begs for inspiration and the other conceals an ulterior motive. As one can predict, the film is teeming with Tarkovsky's trademark static/panning long shots, mesmerizing and conjuring up a recondite sense of metaphysics, for example, a steady long shot of various items in the water finishes with the focus on a human hand, sometimes it's baffling, as viewers (as well as the two clients) have been warned numerous times by the stalker, the place is precarious, many a predecessor dies mysteriously in the zone, among a large chunk of the time Tarkovsky successfully maintains the stifling suspense to tally with the seedy locale, the movement is painstakingly strung out, so the audiences cannot shun the unknown danger but only succumb to a thorough wallow in the wasteland. Tarkovsky never resort to cheap horror to give vent to excitement or relief, instead, he utilizes a man-made natural surrounding to trap oneself in, and let our own inside demon out to divulge a sense of thrill and frisson. I don't speak Russian, so it probably hinders my apprehension of the dialog, only if the English interpretation could be better, nevertheless, STALKER seems bit chattier than Tarkovsky's other works, their debate ranges from the philosophy of human beings' psychological trials and tribulations, the socio-political radicalism to the awe and frustration towards the mystery and miracles plus the unselfishness of art, etc. I may not be able to fully cover all the implications from the first viewing, but one can not deny here the luxuriant imagery is louder than words at any rate. The cast is also memorable, the monochrome close-ups endow each character with a pictorial impact of their own resolution, the friend-or-foe association motivates the storytelling and excellently penetrates the harmony of the trio thus overshoots viewers' expectation. Myself find the supernatural elements have been fascinatingly deployed in this film, scattering into many inscrutable shots, sometimes only in a jiffy and most strikingly is the ending, with the daughter of the stalker, mind-controls still objects until one glass falls on the ground but the sound is drowned by the strident train running nearby, which ultimately veils the film with a stratum of mystique that qualifies Tarkovsky as one of the most unique and essential filmmaker of all time!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bizarre Russian Science Fiction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A guide known as The Stalker (Alexander Kaidanovsky) leads two men, "the Writer" (Anatoly Solonitsyn) and "the Professor" (Nikolai Grinko), through an area known as the Zone to find a room that grants wishes. Can you believe the film contains 142 shots in 163 minutes, with an average shot length of more than one minute and many shots lasting for more than four minutes. There is no question that the camera lingers, and no surprise that the picture is considered to be slow by many people (early audiences and critics definitely thought so). Almost all of the scenes not set in the Zone are in a high-contrast brown monochrome. What does this mean? That is for you to decide, but it does add an element of fantasy to the picture. The director reportedly said, "I am only interested in the views of two people: one is called Bresson and one called Bergman." Yes, folks, this is art and not entertainment. If you happen to be entertained, that is even better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Has some interesting footage of a run down Russian town but that's about it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Curtin
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    PLEASE NOTE: Spoiler alert(if that's possible). OK. Here's the movie in a nutshell. Man get's up in the middle of the night, wife get's cross and worried he'll get thrown into jail. Man leaves, meets up with a couple of people who have organised to meet him. They make there way through a curfew section of the city patrolled by police/law enforcement, in a Range Rover. They swap to a train car, that they use to get them out of the city into 'The Zone'. The Zone is simply outside the city and is beautiful simply because it's nature and scenery. There's objects such as concrete blocks, tunnels and misc run down rooms they walk through, there journey ends in a room where they all sit and throw rocks into the water. Then it cuts back to the city, man goes for a walk with his wife and kid, they talk, then his daughter puts her head on the table looks incredibly bored and appears to move some glass wear with a psionic ability. One glass falls off the table, the others stop, camera pans to her almost bored to death face end of film. Yes, I get that the poetic points that are mentioned and in particular the message: "Weak is beautiful and strength is nothing, in that when a child is born it is adaptable and flexible. When the child becomes a man it get's hard and set in it's ways, therefore weak is far more beautiful than strength", is a worthy one but hey 3 hours for that? Other points like this but ultimately nothing to do with the overall story which is simply that 'The Stalker' is simply someone who walks people through the zone which is essentially like a walk in the country in an effort to expand there minds from there otherwise pointless existence(talk about ironic, the Stalker is beyond pointless in himself to say the least). For some reason there not meant to go there. Why not is not really explained.(More than likely because some Russian dictator declared it was off limits to ordinary civilians for some reason(we see various signs of war amidst the rubble, bunkers, a gun etc but overall just a lot of pointless walking around scenes with absolutely no meaning, not even poetically). Overall this is an incredibly boring film and I have no idea why it get's such a high rating. As for watch it again. NO WAY, I'd rather stick red hot needles in my eyes. Seriously, don't waste your time, I only gave it 2 stars because 1. The scene in the practically war torn Russian streets was interesting and 2. for the finale at the end of the film which showed that had the movie focused on the talented young girl, it might have been great. Instead she was really depressed because her whole role got 1 minute at the end of the film and the rest of the film was essentially a tangential screed of rubbish. My strong recommendation for a movie with poetic license and far more impact and strong points but still has a great story and is actually endlessly re-watchable(especially if you get the Criterion Collection edition with the bonus versions), is the Terry Gilliam film BRAZIL. Watch that instead, you'll be glad you did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Do you know interesting facts?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leostalker
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's my most dear, secret movie, which I'm ready to watch again and again making journey with characters. As already mentioned in some comments, it's not even film, it's co-existence with travelers, it's a road to your heart or to God, or to elsewhere. I could tell much about this masterpiece, but would like to say about things people, even fond of Tarkovsky art, might unaware of. Below is a quote from Tarkovsky; "For me this work is expression of power of a weak man, man of faith, man of highest spirit. His actions might be impractical and absurd. But impracticality is a sign of high spirit. He has an idea. There is no Zone. He just invented so to take two-three desperate people, bring them there and inspire an idea of some hope for the happiness sake. But finally none of them want to enter this simple room". This is a answer to those (I'm also amongst them), who expressed they guesses that the Zone and the Room are not actually produce miracles or disasters, but just Stalker's words. Though we see corpses, tanks and other things that supposedly confirms the existence of something supernatural, but real miracle (or peril, or change of mind, or growing of souls, if you want) takes places spiritually. This Tarkovsky's explanation (some people, as I am, realized this even before learning Tarkovsky's words) only adds depth to the film. Another interesting point is that the final monologue of Stalker's Wife supposed to be IN BAR (and it's actually shot THERE  look at the wall behind her, when she is speaking), not in Stalker's home. I learnt about it from interwiev of the editor of the film. She (it was a women) offered Tarkovsky to move this scene from the bar closer to the end so to have an effect of addressing not only to Writer and Professor, but to the soul of an amateur. The editor said to Tarkovsky that the difference of the surroundings would not be marked by a amateur because his attention on that moment is fixed on the face of Alisa Freindlich (Wife). Tarkovsky finally agreed and put this scene to the final and it became much deeper then it would have been in the bar. Wife now addresses to all of us (as Writer did sitting near a hole in the Zone after going through the "meatgrinder'). I rewatched film many times and paid attention to the interior of Wife's monologue  it's in the bar! Thanks to advise of films editor we have such a important change of the final moments of film. To end it I would like to mark a strong scene, almost nowhere mentioned. When crippled daughter of Stalker seems to walk Film returns in color and Artemiev's music is heard as to underline the miracle. And several seconds later camera moves revealing us the truth  she is sitting on Stalker's shoulders. What a piercing, shrill moment of a miracle that took place only in our imagination. Wonderful moments!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Atmospheric, weird, intelligent, a little too slow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nate J
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalker is quintessentially Tarkovskii and stagnation-era. Tarkovskii's extended silences, slow painting-like shots, color filters, and obsession with dripping water permeate the film. From the stagnation era, Stalker borrows middle age, cynicism, nihilism, listlessness, and unfulfilled desire. The film is remarkably atmospheric; aside from a few strange occurrences, nothing actually corroborates the titular Stalker's claims of supernatural danger in the Zone, and yet the fog, the ruins, the unearthly electronic music, and the apprehension of the characters gives an air of ominous oppression to what is objectively a very simple film. Alienation is a constant theme. In one sense, the Zone disobeys physical laws, traps and kills, and inspires introspection in a terrifyingly sublime way. In another sense, the Zone is the most "real" place in the film  it is in color, it is a place of hope, and it is the only place the Stalker claims to be at home, in opposition to the muddy-brown drudgery of the outside world. The dichotomy of Zone and reality, hope and cynicism, comfort and danger, unconscious desires and active passions are constantly at play, and often flipping. I couldn't shake the feeling that the film had something to say about communism and the stagnation period: the Zone is a place of refuge and also a place of weirdness, it attracts the hopeless, and yet offers possibility. One character wants to destroy it, due to the terrible power it might give to bad men. Another character argues that this cannot happen, because man's inner desires will always trump their ideological positions. The Stalker wants only to bring visitors to the Zone for hope and happiness, and grieves at the inability of "intellectuals" to give it their faith. His wife narrates, "If we hadn't had our misfortunes, it would have been worsethere wouldn't have been any hope." Whether or not these stagnation themes were deliberately placed or an osmotic result of the era is irrelevant  the film is imminently malleable in interpretation. Stalker is nothing if not strange, and there are scenes that cannot be described with any justice in writing. The atmosphere is beautifully wrought, and the film thankfully does not spoil its own premise with over-exposition or ludicrous elements, as science fiction is often wont to do, but scenes tend to drag, and the film might have benefited from some more judicious editing. The most striking and well-timed scene in the entire story occurs in the last two minutes, and one wonders what Tarkovskii might have done with a little more money and a more hawk-eyed editor. Overall, Stalker is strange, atmospheric, introspective, and a little too long for its own good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    stalking the truth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dminkin
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What is happiness? What is the meaning of life? What is the Zone? And what exactly is reality? These questions and many more you will find yourselves asking as you enter the Zone, a place with a Room where all wishes come true. Don't expect too many answers, but try to enjoy the journey, even amidst the decay and ruin of both man and machine. Tarkovsky's Zone is a place of magic, a place where ordinary physical laws don't apply. If one is skeptical that the scenery is what it is, and that there is nothing more to it than what you see with your eyes, the camera in conjunction with the dialogue works hard to convince you otherwise. Distance, scale, and position are all warped, not by any special effect of the camera as in ordinary sci-fi movies, but by the positioning, angle, and movement of the camera within a shot. To take one harrowing example: In the early part of the journey to the Room contained within the central core of the Zone, the small company of travelers, the Stalker, the Professor, and the Writer, pass a blackened trailer containing intact fleshy skeletons. The camera tracks the travelers as they move from a vantage point that deliberately inserts this trailer of death in between. Ever so slowly it creeps up to the scene of death, enlarging and magnifying the details of the decaying corpses, until the camera, having just gotten past the point where it has crept so far up, then overshoots the dead. But it stops; so that while the travelers contemplate the fate of these dead "tourists" to the Zone, we are aware that we are actually sitting on top of them. Metal armor, assorted trinkets, and other material possessions that man has donned or created all fall by the wayside and are discarded and rusted at the bottom of pools of water that saturate the Zone. Man's life and possessions are ephemeral and in a constant state of decay in our industrialized, bleak world. Man is removed from Nature, not just in Soviet life but everywhere we look. It becomes apparent that the only way to survive such ruin of both spirit and home is with faith and hope. But we don't always know our innermost desires so a trip to the Room is fruitless if we have a specific goal in mind. The central dilemma is that the Stalker's faith is predicated upon his belief that the inner desires of most people are good. However, the Writer and Professor, from different but not necessarily opposing perspectives, espouse a view that their deepest desires may not necessarily have the best intentions, despite a basic sense of morality that pervades their respective consciences. This is what I think Tarkovsky was trying to depict, without giving an answer, since there may not be one in this brilliant, philosophical, haunting, and beautifully poetic meditation on what it means to be human in a particular reality that we can see but not really ever grasp.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmm...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    srmontgo
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a hard movie to rate. There was a good amount to love and a lot to hate for me. First, the good. I can appreciate that this is not a movie to just sit back and passively be entertained by. This is a movie that encourages you to be thoughtful and observant, kind of like a Professor and a Scientist. There are scenes in this movie that made me question my beliefs about what motivates humans to act, faith, and what in life is actually worth pursuing... those are some deep and big questions to arouse in a viewer and for that I definitely appreciate the film. It is definitely beautiful. The camera movements make you feel like you are watching a dream and pretty much each shot looks like it could be framed and hung at an art exhibit. The acting, while confusing at times, was very good. Now, the bad. It is long and confusing. I understand that some people love to let their imaginations fly when finding meaning in these "art" movies. I can appreciate that to an extent. However, I prefer to have some level of cohesiveness and direction. I could not care about any of the characters because I was not given anything to care about. Since I did not care about the characters or understand what motivates them, I could not care or understand their actions or how they interacted with the other characters. When a dog shows up, I attempted to interpret the meaning... but I simply lacked the information to make any sense of it. My point is, I prefer to have at least some context in order to interpret and prescribe meaning to what I'm watching. I like movies that make you think and are up to interpretation, but I this was just too abstract for my taste. My wife saw me watching this movie. She sat down and watched 10 minutes. She then got up and asked me why I do this to myself. "This" meaning watching boring old movies. I usually don't answer he because she wouldn't understand anyway, but with this movie I wouldn't have been able to respond even if I wanted to. Her question actually posed the most meaningful and philosophically challenging question of the night. Why spend my time after work fighting sleep and working to understand a boring old movie when I could be doing something fun or productive? This movie is essentially a stream of consciousness, a nonsensical plot to display a collection of beautiful philosophical vignettes, a long slog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ideas about the meaning
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hatem Krema
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS ... What was the hidden concept ?? I think the movie Stalker with its strong symbolism can be interpreted in the context of the Soviet era when religion was brutally suppressed. "The zone"/religion is a place that provides a comfortable sanctuary from the material dull life, and is guarded from entering by the military/ communist authorities. It came to exist from a meteorite/ a heavenly message to earth. For the stalker/ the religious man, it represents home and comfort, although he always enters it with fear to make it/God angry. The zone/ religion has its own natural laws/miracles that defies logic, but you have to get along with. It promises a "room"/paradise were your innermost wishes come true. The road/ life work to reach the room/paradise is tough and requires guidance from a stalker/ religious man. The existence of the room/ paradise has been always challenged by science/the professor and philosophy/the writer, and despite that they try to explore the facts of religion, and have some understanding for it, they could not accept it at the end. Science/the professor was ready to destroy what he could not rationalize, and from the standpoint of the stalker/religious man, science/the professor and philosophy/the writer are completely ignorant despite their knowledge. The stalker personal life/ the religious man life is not materially fulfilling and may be disappointing. The daughter may represent the outcome of following religion blindly, the mind/body may be crippled to move freely but it may have sensitivity and mysticism not owned by others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The BEST film ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Keldi Victoria Konung
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalker (made by cinematography genius Andrei Tarkovsky) is a visually unforgettable film. It's my most favourite film of all time. It's based on short science fiction novel Roadside Picnic - written by Russian science fiction authors Arkady and Boris Strugatsky. It has a very deep storyline that held my interest from the first to the last minute. I was very impressed by the acting of Alexander Kaidanovsky. For most of the film there are only three actors - they did their job amazingly well. From a technical point of view - it is the BEST film ever made! I strongly recommend to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Couldn't sit through the whole film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    l_eeburgess
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most boring films I have ever watched in my whole life. I managed to watch an hour and a half of it, but just could not make it to the end. Art does not make a movie, eerie music and bleak landscapes are all well and good but two and a half hours of it is too much. The endless and monotonous conversations between the characters is basically just mindless babble. Lots of time spent standing around in fields or lying in pools of water. Perhaps I am the wrong person to watch this kind of film, I like substance to a film, I like an engaging story, this provided nothing of enjoyment to me. For the life of me I cannot understand how so many people can rate it so highly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stalker
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My third Tarkovsky's film (after SOLARIS 1972, 8/10 and NOSTALGHIA 1983, 8/10), STALKER is a startling eye-opener, set in a sordid clanking land of rural Soviet Union, after the falling of a meteorite, an enigmatic area "The Zone" has emerged, inside there is a room can grant incomers' innermost wishes, but cordoned by the government with armies, only with the guidance of so called "stalkers", one can reach the room. So the expedition involves one stalker and his two clients, a writer and a professor, one begs for inspiration and the other conceals an ulterior motive. As one can predict, the film is teeming with Tarkovsky's trademark static/panning long shots, mesmerizing and conjuring up a recondite sense of metaphysics, for example, a steady long shot of various items in the water finishes with the focus on a human hand, sometimes it's baffling, as viewers (as well as the two clients) have been warned numerous times by the stalker, the place is precarious, many a predecessor dies mysteriously in the zone, among a large chunk of the time Tarkovsky successfully maintains the stifling suspense to tally with the seedy locale, the movement is painstakingly strung out, so the audiences cannot shun the unknown danger but only succumb to a thorough wallow in the wasteland. Tarkovsky never resort to cheap horror to give vent to excitement or relief, instead, he utilizes a man-made natural surrounding to trap oneself in, and let our own inside demon out to divulge a sense of thrill and frisson. I don't speak Russian, so it probably hinders my apprehension of the dialog, only if the English interpretation could be better, nevertheless, STALKER seems bit chattier than Tarkovsky's other works, their debate ranges from the philosophy of human beings' psychological trials and tribulations, the socio-political radicalism to the awe and frustration towards the mystery and miracles plus the unselfishness of art, etc. I may not be able to fully cover all the implications from the first viewing, but one can not deny here the luxuriant imagery is louder than words at any rate. The cast is also memorable, the monochrome close-ups endow each character with a pictorial impact of their own resolution, the friend-or-foe association motivates the storytelling and excellently penetrates the harmony of the trio thus overshoots viewers' expectation. Myself find the supernatural elements have been fascinatingly deployed in this film, scattering into many inscrutable shots, sometimes only in a jiffy and most strikingly is the ending, with the daughter of the stalker, mind-controls still objects until one glass falls on the ground but the sound is drowned by the strident train running nearby, which ultimately veils the film with a stratum of mystique that qualifies Tarkovsky as one of the most unique and essential filmmaker of all time!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bizarre Russian Science Fiction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A guide known as The Stalker (Alexander Kaidanovsky) leads two men, "the Writer" (Anatoly Solonitsyn) and "the Professor" (Nikolai Grinko), through an area known as the Zone to find a room that grants wishes. Can you believe the film contains 142 shots in 163 minutes, with an average shot length of more than one minute and many shots lasting for more than four minutes. There is no question that the camera lingers, and no surprise that the picture is considered to be slow by many people (early audiences and critics definitely thought so). Almost all of the scenes not set in the Zone are in a high-contrast brown monochrome. What does this mean? That is for you to decide, but it does add an element of fantasy to the picture. The director reportedly said, "I am only interested in the views of two people: one is called Bresson and one called Bergman." Yes, folks, this is art and not entertainment. If you happen to be entertained, that is even better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Has some interesting footage of a run down Russian town but that's about it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Curtin
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    PLEASE NOTE: Spoiler alert(if that's possible). OK. Here's the movie in a nutshell. Man get's up in the middle of the night, wife get's cross and worried he'll get thrown into jail. Man leaves, meets up with a couple of people who have organised to meet him. They make there way through a curfew section of the city patrolled by police/law enforcement, in a Range Rover. They swap to a train car, that they use to get them out of the city into 'The Zone'. The Zone is simply outside the city and is beautiful simply because it's nature and scenery. There's objects such as concrete blocks, tunnels and misc run down rooms they walk through, there journey ends in a room where they all sit and throw rocks into the water. Then it cuts back to the city, man goes for a walk with his wife and kid, they talk, then his daughter puts her head on the table looks incredibly bored and appears to move some glass wear with a psionic ability. One glass falls off the table, the others stop, camera pans to her almost bored to death face end of film. Yes, I get that the poetic points that are mentioned and in particular the message: "Weak is beautiful and strength is nothing, in that when a child is born it is adaptable and flexible. When the child becomes a man it get's hard and set in it's ways, therefore weak is far more beautiful than strength", is a worthy one but hey 3 hours for that? Other points like this but ultimately nothing to do with the overall story which is simply that 'The Stalker' is simply someone who walks people through the zone which is essentially like a walk in the country in an effort to expand there minds from there otherwise pointless existence(talk about ironic, the Stalker is beyond pointless in himself to say the least). For some reason there not meant to go there. Why not is not really explained.(More than likely because some Russian dictator declared it was off limits to ordinary civilians for some reason(we see various signs of war amidst the rubble, bunkers, a gun etc but overall just a lot of pointless walking around scenes with absolutely no meaning, not even poetically). Overall this is an incredibly boring film and I have no idea why it get's such a high rating. As for watch it again. NO WAY, I'd rather stick red hot needles in my eyes. Seriously, don't waste your time, I only gave it 2 stars because 1. The scene in the practically war torn Russian streets was interesting and 2. for the finale at the end of the film which showed that had the movie focused on the talented young girl, it might have been great. Instead she was really depressed because her whole role got 1 minute at the end of the film and the rest of the film was essentially a tangential screed of rubbish. My strong recommendation for a movie with poetic license and far more impact and strong points but still has a great story and is actually endlessly re-watchable(especially if you get the Criterion Collection edition with the bonus versions), is the Terry Gilliam film BRAZIL. Watch that instead, you'll be glad you did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Do you know interesting facts?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leostalker
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's my most dear, secret movie, which I'm ready to watch again and again making journey with characters. As already mentioned in some comments, it's not even film, it's co-existence with travelers, it's a road to your heart or to God, or to elsewhere. I could tell much about this masterpiece, but would like to say about things people, even fond of Tarkovsky art, might unaware of. Below is a quote from Tarkovsky; "For me this work is expression of power of a weak man, man of faith, man of highest spirit. His actions might be impractical and absurd. But impracticality is a sign of high spirit. He has an idea. There is no Zone. He just invented so to take two-three desperate people, bring them there and inspire an idea of some hope for the happiness sake. But finally none of them want to enter this simple room". This is a answer to those (I'm also amongst them), who expressed they guesses that the Zone and the Room are not actually produce miracles or disasters, but just Stalker's words. Though we see corpses, tanks and other things that supposedly confirms the existence of something supernatural, but real miracle (or peril, or change of mind, or growing of souls, if you want) takes places spiritually. This Tarkovsky's explanation (some people, as I am, realized this even before learning Tarkovsky's words) only adds depth to the film. Another interesting point is that the final monologue of Stalker's Wife supposed to be IN BAR (and it's actually shot THERE  look at the wall behind her, when she is speaking), not in Stalker's home. I learnt about it from interwiev of the editor of the film. She (it was a women) offered Tarkovsky to move this scene from the bar closer to the end so to have an effect of addressing not only to Writer and Professor, but to the soul of an amateur. The editor said to Tarkovsky that the difference of the surroundings would not be marked by a amateur because his attention on that moment is fixed on the face of Alisa Freindlich (Wife). Tarkovsky finally agreed and put this scene to the final and it became much deeper then it would have been in the bar. Wife now addresses to all of us (as Writer did sitting near a hole in the Zone after going through the "meatgrinder'). I rewatched film many times and paid attention to the interior of Wife's monologue  it's in the bar! Thanks to advise of films editor we have such a important change of the final moments of film. To end it I would like to mark a strong scene, almost nowhere mentioned. When crippled daughter of Stalker seems to walk Film returns in color and Artemiev's music is heard as to underline the miracle. And several seconds later camera moves revealing us the truth  she is sitting on Stalker's shoulders. What a piercing, shrill moment of a miracle that took place only in our imagination. Wonderful moments!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Atmospheric, weird, intelligent, a little too slow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nate J
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalker is quintessentially Tarkovskii and stagnation-era. Tarkovskii's extended silences, slow painting-like shots, color filters, and obsession with dripping water permeate the film. From the stagnation era, Stalker borrows middle age, cynicism, nihilism, listlessness, and unfulfilled desire. The film is remarkably atmospheric; aside from a few strange occurrences, nothing actually corroborates the titular Stalker's claims of supernatural danger in the Zone, and yet the fog, the ruins, the unearthly electronic music, and the apprehension of the characters gives an air of ominous oppression to what is objectively a very simple film. Alienation is a constant theme. In one sense, the Zone disobeys physical laws, traps and kills, and inspires introspection in a terrifyingly sublime way. In another sense, the Zone is the most "real" place in the film  it is in color, it is a place of hope, and it is the only place the Stalker claims to be at home, in opposition to the muddy-brown drudgery of the outside world. The dichotomy of Zone and reality, hope and cynicism, comfort and danger, unconscious desires and active passions are constantly at play, and often flipping. I couldn't shake the feeling that the film had something to say about communism and the stagnation period: the Zone is a place of refuge and also a place of weirdness, it attracts the hopeless, and yet offers possibility. One character wants to destroy it, due to the terrible power it might give to bad men. Another character argues that this cannot happen, because man's inner desires will always trump their ideological positions. The Stalker wants only to bring visitors to the Zone for hope and happiness, and grieves at the inability of "intellectuals" to give it their faith. His wife narrates, "If we hadn't had our misfortunes, it would have been worsethere wouldn't have been any hope." Whether or not these stagnation themes were deliberately placed or an osmotic result of the era is irrelevant  the film is imminently malleable in interpretation. Stalker is nothing if not strange, and there are scenes that cannot be described with any justice in writing. The atmosphere is beautifully wrought, and the film thankfully does not spoil its own premise with over-exposition or ludicrous elements, as science fiction is often wont to do, but scenes tend to drag, and the film might have benefited from some more judicious editing. The most striking and well-timed scene in the entire story occurs in the last two minutes, and one wonders what Tarkovskii might have done with a little more money and a more hawk-eyed editor. Overall, Stalker is strange, atmospheric, introspective, and a little too long for its own good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    stalking the truth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dminkin
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What is happiness? What is the meaning of life? What is the Zone? And what exactly is reality? These questions and many more you will find yourselves asking as you enter the Zone, a place with a Room where all wishes come true. Don't expect too many answers, but try to enjoy the journey, even amidst the decay and ruin of both man and machine. Tarkovsky's Zone is a place of magic, a place where ordinary physical laws don't apply. If one is skeptical that the scenery is what it is, and that there is nothing more to it than what you see with your eyes, the camera in conjunction with the dialogue works hard to convince you otherwise. Distance, scale, and position are all warped, not by any special effect of the camera as in ordinary sci-fi movies, but by the positioning, angle, and movement of the camera within a shot. To take one harrowing example: In the early part of the journey to the Room contained within the central core of the Zone, the small company of travelers, the Stalker, the Professor, and the Writer, pass a blackened trailer containing intact fleshy skeletons. The camera tracks the travelers as they move from a vantage point that deliberately inserts this trailer of death in between. Ever so slowly it creeps up to the scene of death, enlarging and magnifying the details of the decaying corpses, until the camera, having just gotten past the point where it has crept so far up, then overshoots the dead. But it stops; so that while the travelers contemplate the fate of these dead "tourists" to the Zone, we are aware that we are actually sitting on top of them. Metal armor, assorted trinkets, and other material possessions that man has donned or created all fall by the wayside and are discarded and rusted at the bottom of pools of water that saturate the Zone. Man's life and possessions are ephemeral and in a constant state of decay in our industrialized, bleak world. Man is removed from Nature, not just in Soviet life but everywhere we look. It becomes apparent that the only way to survive such ruin of both spirit and home is with faith and hope. But we don't always know our innermost desires so a trip to the Room is fruitless if we have a specific goal in mind. The central dilemma is that the Stalker's faith is predicated upon his belief that the inner desires of most people are good. However, the Writer and Professor, from different but not necessarily opposing perspectives, espouse a view that their deepest desires may not necessarily have the best intentions, despite a basic sense of morality that pervades their respective consciences. This is what I think Tarkovsky was trying to depict, without giving an answer, since there may not be one in this brilliant, philosophical, haunting, and beautifully poetic meditation on what it means to be human in a particular reality that we can see but not really ever grasp.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmm...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    srmontgo
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a hard movie to rate. There was a good amount to love and a lot to hate for me. First, the good. I can appreciate that this is not a movie to just sit back and passively be entertained by. This is a movie that encourages you to be thoughtful and observant, kind of like a Professor and a Scientist. There are scenes in this movie that made me question my beliefs about what motivates humans to act, faith, and what in life is actually worth pursuing... those are some deep and big questions to arouse in a viewer and for that I definitely appreciate the film. It is definitely beautiful. The camera movements make you feel like you are watching a dream and pretty much each shot looks like it could be framed and hung at an art exhibit. The acting, while confusing at times, was very good. Now, the bad. It is long and confusing. I understand that some people love to let their imaginations fly when finding meaning in these "art" movies. I can appreciate that to an extent. However, I prefer to have some level of cohesiveness and direction. I could not care about any of the characters because I was not given anything to care about. Since I did not care about the characters or understand what motivates them, I could not care or understand their actions or how they interacted with the other characters. When a dog shows up, I attempted to interpret the meaning... but I simply lacked the information to make any sense of it. My point is, I prefer to have at least some context in order to interpret and prescribe meaning to what I'm watching. I like movies that make you think and are up to interpretation, but I this was just too abstract for my taste. My wife saw me watching this movie. She sat down and watched 10 minutes. She then got up and asked me why I do this to myself. "This" meaning watching boring old movies. I usually don't answer he because she wouldn't understand anyway, but with this movie I wouldn't have been able to respond even if I wanted to. Her question actually posed the most meaningful and philosophically challenging question of the night. Why spend my time after work fighting sleep and working to understand a boring old movie when I could be doing something fun or productive? This movie is essentially a stream of consciousness, a nonsensical plot to display a collection of beautiful philosophical vignettes, a long slog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ideas about the meaning
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hatem Krema
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS ... What was the hidden concept ?? I think the movie Stalker with its strong symbolism can be interpreted in the context of the Soviet era when religion was brutally suppressed. "The zone"/religion is a place that provides a comfortable sanctuary from the material dull life, and is guarded from entering by the military/ communist authorities. It came to exist from a meteorite/ a heavenly message to earth. For the stalker/ the religious man, it represents home and comfort, although he always enters it with fear to make it/God angry. The zone/ religion has its own natural laws/miracles that defies logic, but you have to get along with. It promises a "room"/paradise were your innermost wishes come true. The road/ life work to reach the room/paradise is tough and requires guidance from a stalker/ religious man. The existence of the room/ paradise has been always challenged by science/the professor and philosophy/the writer, and despite that they try to explore the facts of religion, and have some understanding for it, they could not accept it at the end. Science/the professor was ready to destroy what he could not rationalize, and from the standpoint of the stalker/religious man, science/the professor and philosophy/the writer are completely ignorant despite their knowledge. The stalker personal life/ the religious man life is not materially fulfilling and may be disappointing. The daughter may represent the outcome of following religion blindly, the mind/body may be crippled to move freely but it may have sensitivity and mysticism not owned by others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The BEST film ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Keldi Victoria Konung
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalker (made by cinematography genius Andrei Tarkovsky) is a visually unforgettable film. It's my most favourite film of all time. It's based on short science fiction novel Roadside Picnic - written by Russian science fiction authors Arkady and Boris Strugatsky. It has a very deep storyline that held my interest from the first to the last minute. I was very impressed by the acting of Alexander Kaidanovsky. For most of the film there are only three actors - they did their job amazingly well. From a technical point of view - it is the BEST film ever made! I strongly recommend to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Couldn't sit through the whole film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    l_eeburgess
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most boring films I have ever watched in my whole life. I managed to watch an hour and a half of it, but just could not make it to the end. Art does not make a movie, eerie music and bleak landscapes are all well and good but two and a half hours of it is too much. The endless and monotonous conversations between the characters is basically just mindless babble. Lots of time spent standing around in fields or lying in pools of water. Perhaps I am the wrong person to watch this kind of film, I like substance to a film, I like an engaging story, this provided nothing of enjoyment to me. For the life of me I cannot understand how so many people can rate it so highly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stalker
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My third Tarkovsky's film (after SOLARIS 1972, 8/10 and NOSTALGHIA 1983, 8/10), STALKER is a startling eye-opener, set in a sordid clanking land of rural Soviet Union, after the falling of a meteorite, an enigmatic area "The Zone" has emerged, inside there is a room can grant incomers' innermost wishes, but cordoned by the government with armies, only with the guidance of so called "stalkers", one can reach the room. So the expedition involves one stalker and his two clients, a writer and a professor, one begs for inspiration and the other conceals an ulterior motive. As one can predict, the film is teeming with Tarkovsky's trademark static/panning long shots, mesmerizing and conjuring up a recondite sense of metaphysics, for example, a steady long shot of various items in the water finishes with the focus on a human hand, sometimes it's baffling, as viewers (as well as the two clients) have been warned numerous times by the stalker, the place is precarious, many a predecessor dies mysteriously in the zone, among a large chunk of the time Tarkovsky successfully maintains the stifling suspense to tally with the seedy locale, the movement is painstakingly strung out, so the audiences cannot shun the unknown danger but only succumb to a thorough wallow in the wasteland. Tarkovsky never resort to cheap horror to give vent to excitement or relief, instead, he utilizes a man-made natural surrounding to trap oneself in, and let our own inside demon out to divulge a sense of thrill and frisson. I don't speak Russian, so it probably hinders my apprehension of the dialog, only if the English interpretation could be better, nevertheless, STALKER seems bit chattier than Tarkovsky's other works, their debate ranges from the philosophy of human beings' psychological trials and tribulations, the socio-political radicalism to the awe and frustration towards the mystery and miracles plus the unselfishness of art, etc. I may not be able to fully cover all the implications from the first viewing, but one can not deny here the luxuriant imagery is louder than words at any rate. The cast is also memorable, the monochrome close-ups endow each character with a pictorial impact of their own resolution, the friend-or-foe association motivates the storytelling and excellently penetrates the harmony of the trio thus overshoots viewers' expectation. Myself find the supernatural elements have been fascinatingly deployed in this film, scattering into many inscrutable shots, sometimes only in a jiffy and most strikingly is the ending, with the daughter of the stalker, mind-controls still objects until one glass falls on the ground but the sound is drowned by the strident train running nearby, which ultimately veils the film with a stratum of mystique that qualifies Tarkovsky as one of the most unique and essential filmmaker of all time!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bizarre Russian Science Fiction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A guide known as The Stalker (Alexander Kaidanovsky) leads two men, "the Writer" (Anatoly Solonitsyn) and "the Professor" (Nikolai Grinko), through an area known as the Zone to find a room that grants wishes. Can you believe the film contains 142 shots in 163 minutes, with an average shot length of more than one minute and many shots lasting for more than four minutes. There is no question that the camera lingers, and no surprise that the picture is considered to be slow by many people (early audiences and critics definitely thought so). Almost all of the scenes not set in the Zone are in a high-contrast brown monochrome. What does this mean? That is for you to decide, but it does add an element of fantasy to the picture. The director reportedly said, "I am only interested in the views of two people: one is called Bresson and one called Bergman." Yes, folks, this is art and not entertainment. If you happen to be entertained, that is even better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Has some interesting footage of a run down Russian town but that's about it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Curtin
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    PLEASE NOTE: Spoiler alert(if that's possible). OK. Here's the movie in a nutshell. Man get's up in the middle of the night, wife get's cross and worried he'll get thrown into jail. Man leaves, meets up with a couple of people who have organised to meet him. They make there way through a curfew section of the city patrolled by police/law enforcement, in a Range Rover. They swap to a train car, that they use to get them out of the city into 'The Zone'. The Zone is simply outside the city and is beautiful simply because it's nature and scenery. There's objects such as concrete blocks, tunnels and misc run down rooms they walk through, there journey ends in a room where they all sit and throw rocks into the water. Then it cuts back to the city, man goes for a walk with his wife and kid, they talk, then his daughter puts her head on the table looks incredibly bored and appears to move some glass wear with a psionic ability. One glass falls off the table, the others stop, camera pans to her almost bored to death face end of film. Yes, I get that the poetic points that are mentioned and in particular the message: "Weak is beautiful and strength is nothing, in that when a child is born it is adaptable and flexible. When the child becomes a man it get's hard and set in it's ways, therefore weak is far more beautiful than strength", is a worthy one but hey 3 hours for that? Other points like this but ultimately nothing to do with the overall story which is simply that 'The Stalker' is simply someone who walks people through the zone which is essentially like a walk in the country in an effort to expand there minds from there otherwise pointless existence(talk about ironic, the Stalker is beyond pointless in himself to say the least). For some reason there not meant to go there. Why not is not really explained.(More than likely because some Russian dictator declared it was off limits to ordinary civilians for some reason(we see various signs of war amidst the rubble, bunkers, a gun etc but overall just a lot of pointless walking around scenes with absolutely no meaning, not even poetically). Overall this is an incredibly boring film and I have no idea why it get's such a high rating. As for watch it again. NO WAY, I'd rather stick red hot needles in my eyes. Seriously, don't waste your time, I only gave it 2 stars because 1. The scene in the practically war torn Russian streets was interesting and 2. for the finale at the end of the film which showed that had the movie focused on the talented young girl, it might have been great. Instead she was really depressed because her whole role got 1 minute at the end of the film and the rest of the film was essentially a tangential screed of rubbish. My strong recommendation for a movie with poetic license and far more impact and strong points but still has a great story and is actually endlessly re-watchable(especially if you get the Criterion Collection edition with the bonus versions), is the Terry Gilliam film BRAZIL. Watch that instead, you'll be glad you did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Do you know interesting facts?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leostalker
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's my most dear, secret movie, which I'm ready to watch again and again making journey with characters. As already mentioned in some comments, it's not even film, it's co-existence with travelers, it's a road to your heart or to God, or to elsewhere. I could tell much about this masterpiece, but would like to say about things people, even fond of Tarkovsky art, might unaware of. Below is a quote from Tarkovsky; "For me this work is expression of power of a weak man, man of faith, man of highest spirit. His actions might be impractical and absurd. But impracticality is a sign of high spirit. He has an idea. There is no Zone. He just invented so to take two-three desperate people, bring them there and inspire an idea of some hope for the happiness sake. But finally none of them want to enter this simple room". This is a answer to those (I'm also amongst them), who expressed they guesses that the Zone and the Room are not actually produce miracles or disasters, but just Stalker's words. Though we see corpses, tanks and other things that supposedly confirms the existence of something supernatural, but real miracle (or peril, or change of mind, or growing of souls, if you want) takes places spiritually. This Tarkovsky's explanation (some people, as I am, realized this even before learning Tarkovsky's words) only adds depth to the film. Another interesting point is that the final monologue of Stalker's Wife supposed to be IN BAR (and it's actually shot THERE  look at the wall behind her, when she is speaking), not in Stalker's home. I learnt about it from interwiev of the editor of the film. She (it was a women) offered Tarkovsky to move this scene from the bar closer to the end so to have an effect of addressing not only to Writer and Professor, but to the soul of an amateur. The editor said to Tarkovsky that the difference of the surroundings would not be marked by a amateur because his attention on that moment is fixed on the face of Alisa Freindlich (Wife). Tarkovsky finally agreed and put this scene to the final and it became much deeper then it would have been in the bar. Wife now addresses to all of us (as Writer did sitting near a hole in the Zone after going through the "meatgrinder'). I rewatched film many times and paid attention to the interior of Wife's monologue  it's in the bar! Thanks to advise of films editor we have such a important change of the final moments of film. To end it I would like to mark a strong scene, almost nowhere mentioned. When crippled daughter of Stalker seems to walk Film returns in color and Artemiev's music is heard as to underline the miracle. And several seconds later camera moves revealing us the truth  she is sitting on Stalker's shoulders. What a piercing, shrill moment of a miracle that took place only in our imagination. Wonderful moments!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Atmospheric, weird, intelligent, a little too slow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nate J
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalker is quintessentially Tarkovskii and stagnation-era. Tarkovskii's extended silences, slow painting-like shots, color filters, and obsession with dripping water permeate the film. From the stagnation era, Stalker borrows middle age, cynicism, nihilism, listlessness, and unfulfilled desire. The film is remarkably atmospheric; aside from a few strange occurrences, nothing actually corroborates the titular Stalker's claims of supernatural danger in the Zone, and yet the fog, the ruins, the unearthly electronic music, and the apprehension of the characters gives an air of ominous oppression to what is objectively a very simple film. Alienation is a constant theme. In one sense, the Zone disobeys physical laws, traps and kills, and inspires introspection in a terrifyingly sublime way. In another sense, the Zone is the most "real" place in the film  it is in color, it is a place of hope, and it is the only place the Stalker claims to be at home, in opposition to the muddy-brown drudgery of the outside world. The dichotomy of Zone and reality, hope and cynicism, comfort and danger, unconscious desires and active passions are constantly at play, and often flipping. I couldn't shake the feeling that the film had something to say about communism and the stagnation period: the Zone is a place of refuge and also a place of weirdness, it attracts the hopeless, and yet offers possibility. One character wants to destroy it, due to the terrible power it might give to bad men. Another character argues that this cannot happen, because man's inner desires will always trump their ideological positions. The Stalker wants only to bring visitors to the Zone for hope and happiness, and grieves at the inability of "intellectuals" to give it their faith. His wife narrates, "If we hadn't had our misfortunes, it would have been worsethere wouldn't have been any hope." Whether or not these stagnation themes were deliberately placed or an osmotic result of the era is irrelevant  the film is imminently malleable in interpretation. Stalker is nothing if not strange, and there are scenes that cannot be described with any justice in writing. The atmosphere is beautifully wrought, and the film thankfully does not spoil its own premise with over-exposition or ludicrous elements, as science fiction is often wont to do, but scenes tend to drag, and the film might have benefited from some more judicious editing. The most striking and well-timed scene in the entire story occurs in the last two minutes, and one wonders what Tarkovskii might have done with a little more money and a more hawk-eyed editor. Overall, Stalker is strange, atmospheric, introspective, and a little too long for its own good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    stalking the truth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dminkin
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What is happiness? What is the meaning of life? What is the Zone? And what exactly is reality? These questions and many more you will find yourselves asking as you enter the Zone, a place with a Room where all wishes come true. Don't expect too many answers, but try to enjoy the journey, even amidst the decay and ruin of both man and machine. Tarkovsky's Zone is a place of magic, a place where ordinary physical laws don't apply. If one is skeptical that the scenery is what it is, and that there is nothing more to it than what you see with your eyes, the camera in conjunction with the dialogue works hard to convince you otherwise. Distance, scale, and position are all warped, not by any special effect of the camera as in ordinary sci-fi movies, but by the positioning, angle, and movement of the camera within a shot. To take one harrowing example: In the early part of the journey to the Room contained within the central core of the Zone, the small company of travelers, the Stalker, the Professor, and the Writer, pass a blackened trailer containing intact fleshy skeletons. The camera tracks the travelers as they move from a vantage point that deliberately inserts this trailer of death in between. Ever so slowly it creeps up to the scene of death, enlarging and magnifying the details of the decaying corpses, until the camera, having just gotten past the point where it has crept so far up, then overshoots the dead. But it stops; so that while the travelers contemplate the fate of these dead "tourists" to the Zone, we are aware that we are actually sitting on top of them. Metal armor, assorted trinkets, and other material possessions that man has donned or created all fall by the wayside and are discarded and rusted at the bottom of pools of water that saturate the Zone. Man's life and possessions are ephemeral and in a constant state of decay in our industrialized, bleak world. Man is removed from Nature, not just in Soviet life but everywhere we look. It becomes apparent that the only way to survive such ruin of both spirit and home is with faith and hope. But we don't always know our innermost desires so a trip to the Room is fruitless if we have a specific goal in mind. The central dilemma is that the Stalker's faith is predicated upon his belief that the inner desires of most people are good. However, the Writer and Professor, from different but not necessarily opposing perspectives, espouse a view that their deepest desires may not necessarily have the best intentions, despite a basic sense of morality that pervades their respective consciences. This is what I think Tarkovsky was trying to depict, without giving an answer, since there may not be one in this brilliant, philosophical, haunting, and beautifully poetic meditation on what it means to be human in a particular reality that we can see but not really ever grasp.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmm...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    srmontgo
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a hard movie to rate. There was a good amount to love and a lot to hate for me. First, the good. I can appreciate that this is not a movie to just sit back and passively be entertained by. This is a movie that encourages you to be thoughtful and observant, kind of like a Professor and a Scientist. There are scenes in this movie that made me question my beliefs about what motivates humans to act, faith, and what in life is actually worth pursuing... those are some deep and big questions to arouse in a viewer and for that I definitely appreciate the film. It is definitely beautiful. The camera movements make you feel like you are watching a dream and pretty much each shot looks like it could be framed and hung at an art exhibit. The acting, while confusing at times, was very good. Now, the bad. It is long and confusing. I understand that some people love to let their imaginations fly when finding meaning in these "art" movies. I can appreciate that to an extent. However, I prefer to have some level of cohesiveness and direction. I could not care about any of the characters because I was not given anything to care about. Since I did not care about the characters or understand what motivates them, I could not care or understand their actions or how they interacted with the other characters. When a dog shows up, I attempted to interpret the meaning... but I simply lacked the information to make any sense of it. My point is, I prefer to have at least some context in order to interpret and prescribe meaning to what I'm watching. I like movies that make you think and are up to interpretation, but I this was just too abstract for my taste. My wife saw me watching this movie. She sat down and watched 10 minutes. She then got up and asked me why I do this to myself. "This" meaning watching boring old movies. I usually don't answer he because she wouldn't understand anyway, but with this movie I wouldn't have been able to respond even if I wanted to. Her question actually posed the most meaningful and philosophically challenging question of the night. Why spend my time after work fighting sleep and working to understand a boring old movie when I could be doing something fun or productive? This movie is essentially a stream of consciousness, a nonsensical plot to display a collection of beautiful philosophical vignettes, a long slog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ideas about the meaning
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hatem Krema
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS ... What was the hidden concept ?? I think the movie Stalker with its strong symbolism can be interpreted in the context of the Soviet era when religion was brutally suppressed. "The zone"/religion is a place that provides a comfortable sanctuary from the material dull life, and is guarded from entering by the military/ communist authorities. It came to exist from a meteorite/ a heavenly message to earth. For the stalker/ the religious man, it represents home and comfort, although he always enters it with fear to make it/God angry. The zone/ religion has its own natural laws/miracles that defies logic, but you have to get along with. It promises a "room"/paradise were your innermost wishes come true. The road/ life work to reach the room/paradise is tough and requires guidance from a stalker/ religious man. The existence of the room/ paradise has been always challenged by science/the professor and philosophy/the writer, and despite that they try to explore the facts of religion, and have some understanding for it, they could not accept it at the end. Science/the professor was ready to destroy what he could not rationalize, and from the standpoint of the stalker/religious man, science/the professor and philosophy/the writer are completely ignorant despite their knowledge. The stalker personal life/ the religious man life is not materially fulfilling and may be disappointing. The daughter may represent the outcome of following religion blindly, the mind/body may be crippled to move freely but it may have sensitivity and mysticism not owned by others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The BEST film ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Keldi Victoria Konung
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalker (made by cinematography genius Andrei Tarkovsky) is a visually unforgettable film. It's my most favourite film of all time. It's based on short science fiction novel Roadside Picnic - written by Russian science fiction authors Arkady and Boris Strugatsky. It has a very deep storyline that held my interest from the first to the last minute. I was very impressed by the acting of Alexander Kaidanovsky. For most of the film there are only three actors - they did their job amazingly well. From a technical point of view - it is the BEST film ever made! I strongly recommend to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Couldn't sit through the whole film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    l_eeburgess
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most boring films I have ever watched in my whole life. I managed to watch an hour and a half of it, but just could not make it to the end. Art does not make a movie, eerie music and bleak landscapes are all well and good but two and a half hours of it is too much. The endless and monotonous conversations between the characters is basically just mindless babble. Lots of time spent standing around in fields or lying in pools of water. Perhaps I am the wrong person to watch this kind of film, I like substance to a film, I like an engaging story, this provided nothing of enjoyment to me. For the life of me I cannot understand how so many people can rate it so highly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stalker
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My third Tarkovsky's film (after SOLARIS 1972, 8/10 and NOSTALGHIA 1983, 8/10), STALKER is a startling eye-opener, set in a sordid clanking land of rural Soviet Union, after the falling of a meteorite, an enigmatic area "The Zone" has emerged, inside there is a room can grant incomers' innermost wishes, but cordoned by the government with armies, only with the guidance of so called "stalkers", one can reach the room. So the expedition involves one stalker and his two clients, a writer and a professor, one begs for inspiration and the other conceals an ulterior motive. As one can predict, the film is teeming with Tarkovsky's trademark static/panning long shots, mesmerizing and conjuring up a recondite sense of metaphysics, for example, a steady long shot of various items in the water finishes with the focus on a human hand, sometimes it's baffling, as viewers (as well as the two clients) have been warned numerous times by the stalker, the place is precarious, many a predecessor dies mysteriously in the zone, among a large chunk of the time Tarkovsky successfully maintains the stifling suspense to tally with the seedy locale, the movement is painstakingly strung out, so the audiences cannot shun the unknown danger but only succumb to a thorough wallow in the wasteland. Tarkovsky never resort to cheap horror to give vent to excitement or relief, instead, he utilizes a man-made natural surrounding to trap oneself in, and let our own inside demon out to divulge a sense of thrill and frisson. I don't speak Russian, so it probably hinders my apprehension of the dialog, only if the English interpretation could be better, nevertheless, STALKER seems bit chattier than Tarkovsky's other works, their debate ranges from the philosophy of human beings' psychological trials and tribulations, the socio-political radicalism to the awe and frustration towards the mystery and miracles plus the unselfishness of art, etc. I may not be able to fully cover all the implications from the first viewing, but one can not deny here the luxuriant imagery is louder than words at any rate. The cast is also memorable, the monochrome close-ups endow each character with a pictorial impact of their own resolution, the friend-or-foe association motivates the storytelling and excellently penetrates the harmony of the trio thus overshoots viewers' expectation. Myself find the supernatural elements have been fascinatingly deployed in this film, scattering into many inscrutable shots, sometimes only in a jiffy and most strikingly is the ending, with the daughter of the stalker, mind-controls still objects until one glass falls on the ground but the sound is drowned by the strident train running nearby, which ultimately veils the film with a stratum of mystique that qualifies Tarkovsky as one of the most unique and essential filmmaker of all time!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bizarre Russian Science Fiction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A guide known as The Stalker (Alexander Kaidanovsky) leads two men, "the Writer" (Anatoly Solonitsyn) and "the Professor" (Nikolai Grinko), through an area known as the Zone to find a room that grants wishes. Can you believe the film contains 142 shots in 163 minutes, with an average shot length of more than one minute and many shots lasting for more than four minutes. There is no question that the camera lingers, and no surprise that the picture is considered to be slow by many people (early audiences and critics definitely thought so). Almost all of the scenes not set in the Zone are in a high-contrast brown monochrome. What does this mean? That is for you to decide, but it does add an element of fantasy to the picture. The director reportedly said, "I am only interested in the views of two people: one is called Bresson and one called Bergman." Yes, folks, this is art and not entertainment. If you happen to be entertained, that is even better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Has some interesting footage of a run down Russian town but that's about it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Curtin
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    PLEASE NOTE: Spoiler alert(if that's possible). OK. Here's the movie in a nutshell. Man get's up in the middle of the night, wife get's cross and worried he'll get thrown into jail. Man leaves, meets up with a couple of people who have organised to meet him. They make there way through a curfew section of the city patrolled by police/law enforcement, in a Range Rover. They swap to a train car, that they use to get them out of the city into 'The Zone'. The Zone is simply outside the city and is beautiful simply because it's nature and scenery. There's objects such as concrete blocks, tunnels and misc run down rooms they walk through, there journey ends in a room where they all sit and throw rocks into the water. Then it cuts back to the city, man goes for a walk with his wife and kid, they talk, then his daughter puts her head on the table looks incredibly bored and appears to move some glass wear with a psionic ability. One glass falls off the table, the others stop, camera pans to her almost bored to death face end of film. Yes, I get that the poetic points that are mentioned and in particular the message: "Weak is beautiful and strength is nothing, in that when a child is born it is adaptable and flexible. When the child becomes a man it get's hard and set in it's ways, therefore weak is far more beautiful than strength", is a worthy one but hey 3 hours for that? Other points like this but ultimately nothing to do with the overall story which is simply that 'The Stalker' is simply someone who walks people through the zone which is essentially like a walk in the country in an effort to expand there minds from there otherwise pointless existence(talk about ironic, the Stalker is beyond pointless in himself to say the least). For some reason there not meant to go there. Why not is not really explained.(More than likely because some Russian dictator declared it was off limits to ordinary civilians for some reason(we see various signs of war amidst the rubble, bunkers, a gun etc but overall just a lot of pointless walking around scenes with absolutely no meaning, not even poetically). Overall this is an incredibly boring film and I have no idea why it get's such a high rating. As for watch it again. NO WAY, I'd rather stick red hot needles in my eyes. Seriously, don't waste your time, I only gave it 2 stars because 1. The scene in the practically war torn Russian streets was interesting and 2. for the finale at the end of the film which showed that had the movie focused on the talented young girl, it might have been great. Instead she was really depressed because her whole role got 1 minute at the end of the film and the rest of the film was essentially a tangential screed of rubbish. My strong recommendation for a movie with poetic license and far more impact and strong points but still has a great story and is actually endlessly re-watchable(especially if you get the Criterion Collection edition with the bonus versions), is the Terry Gilliam film BRAZIL. Watch that instead, you'll be glad you did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Do you know interesting facts?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leostalker
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's my most dear, secret movie, which I'm ready to watch again and again making journey with characters. As already mentioned in some comments, it's not even film, it's co-existence with travelers, it's a road to your heart or to God, or to elsewhere. I could tell much about this masterpiece, but would like to say about things people, even fond of Tarkovsky art, might unaware of. Below is a quote from Tarkovsky; "For me this work is expression of power of a weak man, man of faith, man of highest spirit. His actions might be impractical and absurd. But impracticality is a sign of high spirit. He has an idea. There is no Zone. He just invented so to take two-three desperate people, bring them there and inspire an idea of some hope for the happiness sake. But finally none of them want to enter this simple room". This is a answer to those (I'm also amongst them), who expressed they guesses that the Zone and the Room are not actually produce miracles or disasters, but just Stalker's words. Though we see corpses, tanks and other things that supposedly confirms the existence of something supernatural, but real miracle (or peril, or change of mind, or growing of souls, if you want) takes places spiritually. This Tarkovsky's explanation (some people, as I am, realized this even before learning Tarkovsky's words) only adds depth to the film. Another interesting point is that the final monologue of Stalker's Wife supposed to be IN BAR (and it's actually shot THERE  look at the wall behind her, when she is speaking), not in Stalker's home. I learnt about it from interwiev of the editor of the film. She (it was a women) offered Tarkovsky to move this scene from the bar closer to the end so to have an effect of addressing not only to Writer and Professor, but to the soul of an amateur. The editor said to Tarkovsky that the difference of the surroundings would not be marked by a amateur because his attention on that moment is fixed on the face of Alisa Freindlich (Wife). Tarkovsky finally agreed and put this scene to the final and it became much deeper then it would have been in the bar. Wife now addresses to all of us (as Writer did sitting near a hole in the Zone after going through the "meatgrinder'). I rewatched film many times and paid attention to the interior of Wife's monologue  it's in the bar! Thanks to advise of films editor we have such a important change of the final moments of film. To end it I would like to mark a strong scene, almost nowhere mentioned. When crippled daughter of Stalker seems to walk Film returns in color and Artemiev's music is heard as to underline the miracle. And several seconds later camera moves revealing us the truth  she is sitting on Stalker's shoulders. What a piercing, shrill moment of a miracle that took place only in our imagination. Wonderful moments!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Atmospheric, weird, intelligent, a little too slow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nate J
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalker is quintessentially Tarkovskii and stagnation-era. Tarkovskii's extended silences, slow painting-like shots, color filters, and obsession with dripping water permeate the film. From the stagnation era, Stalker borrows middle age, cynicism, nihilism, listlessness, and unfulfilled desire. The film is remarkably atmospheric; aside from a few strange occurrences, nothing actually corroborates the titular Stalker's claims of supernatural danger in the Zone, and yet the fog, the ruins, the unearthly electronic music, and the apprehension of the characters gives an air of ominous oppression to what is objectively a very simple film. Alienation is a constant theme. In one sense, the Zone disobeys physical laws, traps and kills, and inspires introspection in a terrifyingly sublime way. In another sense, the Zone is the most "real" place in the film  it is in color, it is a place of hope, and it is the only place the Stalker claims to be at home, in opposition to the muddy-brown drudgery of the outside world. The dichotomy of Zone and reality, hope and cynicism, comfort and danger, unconscious desires and active passions are constantly at play, and often flipping. I couldn't shake the feeling that the film had something to say about communism and the stagnation period: the Zone is a place of refuge and also a place of weirdness, it attracts the hopeless, and yet offers possibility. One character wants to destroy it, due to the terrible power it might give to bad men. Another character argues that this cannot happen, because man's inner desires will always trump their ideological positions. The Stalker wants only to bring visitors to the Zone for hope and happiness, and grieves at the inability of "intellectuals" to give it their faith. His wife narrates, "If we hadn't had our misfortunes, it would have been worsethere wouldn't have been any hope." Whether or not these stagnation themes were deliberately placed or an osmotic result of the era is irrelevant  the film is imminently malleable in interpretation. Stalker is nothing if not strange, and there are scenes that cannot be described with any justice in writing. The atmosphere is beautifully wrought, and the film thankfully does not spoil its own premise with over-exposition or ludicrous elements, as science fiction is often wont to do, but scenes tend to drag, and the film might have benefited from some more judicious editing. The most striking and well-timed scene in the entire story occurs in the last two minutes, and one wonders what Tarkovskii might have done with a little more money and a more hawk-eyed editor. Overall, Stalker is strange, atmospheric, introspective, and a little too long for its own good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    stalking the truth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dminkin
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What is happiness? What is the meaning of life? What is the Zone? And what exactly is reality? These questions and many more you will find yourselves asking as you enter the Zone, a place with a Room where all wishes come true. Don't expect too many answers, but try to enjoy the journey, even amidst the decay and ruin of both man and machine. Tarkovsky's Zone is a place of magic, a place where ordinary physical laws don't apply. If one is skeptical that the scenery is what it is, and that there is nothing more to it than what you see with your eyes, the camera in conjunction with the dialogue works hard to convince you otherwise. Distance, scale, and position are all warped, not by any special effect of the camera as in ordinary sci-fi movies, but by the positioning, angle, and movement of the camera within a shot. To take one harrowing example: In the early part of the journey to the Room contained within the central core of the Zone, the small company of travelers, the Stalker, the Professor, and the Writer, pass a blackened trailer containing intact fleshy skeletons. The camera tracks the travelers as they move from a vantage point that deliberately inserts this trailer of death in between. Ever so slowly it creeps up to the scene of death, enlarging and magnifying the details of the decaying corpses, until the camera, having just gotten past the point where it has crept so far up, then overshoots the dead. But it stops; so that while the travelers contemplate the fate of these dead "tourists" to the Zone, we are aware that we are actually sitting on top of them. Metal armor, assorted trinkets, and other material possessions that man has donned or created all fall by the wayside and are discarded and rusted at the bottom of pools of water that saturate the Zone. Man's life and possessions are ephemeral and in a constant state of decay in our industrialized, bleak world. Man is removed from Nature, not just in Soviet life but everywhere we look. It becomes apparent that the only way to survive such ruin of both spirit and home is with faith and hope. But we don't always know our innermost desires so a trip to the Room is fruitless if we have a specific goal in mind. The central dilemma is that the Stalker's faith is predicated upon his belief that the inner desires of most people are good. However, the Writer and Professor, from different but not necessarily opposing perspectives, espouse a view that their deepest desires may not necessarily have the best intentions, despite a basic sense of morality that pervades their respective consciences. This is what I think Tarkovsky was trying to depict, without giving an answer, since there may not be one in this brilliant, philosophical, haunting, and beautifully poetic meditation on what it means to be human in a particular reality that we can see but not really ever grasp.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
