<filme>
 <id>
  1163
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0117364
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Retratos de Uma Mulher
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Isabel Archer, an American heiress and free thinker travels to Europe to find herself. She tactfully rebuffs the advances of Caspar Goodwood, another American who has followed her to ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Isabel Archer, an American heiress and free thinker travels to Europe to find herself. She tactfully rebuffs the advances of Caspar Goodwood, another American who has followed her to England. Her cousin, Ralph Touchett, wise but sickly becomes a soulmate of sorts for her. She makes an unfortunate alliance with the creepy Madame Merle who leads her to make an even more unfortunate alliance with Gilbert Osmond, a smooth but cold collector of Objets' de art who seduces her with an intense but unattainable sexuality. Isabel marries Osmond only to realize she's just another piece of art for his collection and that Madame Merle and Osmond are lovers who had hatched a diabolical scheme to take Isabel's fortune. Isabel's only comfort is the innocent daughter of Osmond, Pansy, but even that friendship is spoiled when Countess Gemini, Osmond's sister, reveals the child's true parentage. Isabel finally breaks free of Osmond and returns to Ralph's bedside, where, while breathing his last, they ...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   art
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   american
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   travel
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   europe
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   friendship
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Jane Campion
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Henry James
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Laura Jones
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Nicole Kidman
  </ator>
  <ator>
   John Malkovich
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Barbara Hershey
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an excellent complete movie, a total artistic experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nostalgiapopescu
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've repeatedly seen this movie, I simply can't help myself from watching this example of good taste that has the ideas, the feeling, the meanings and also the means of a work of art. This movie is simply adorable from the beginning to the end. The actors, the story, the costumes, the soundtrack, scenery, everything is beautiful and full of authenticity. The adaptation from the novel appropriately reveals the subtle, simple and total story about life and mistakes, not only about women, but an extension about choosing wrong and about chances of choosing again, of hoping. But hoping itself is a choice, we all have the choice of hoping or not. This category is called "sublime" in art I guess...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why would anyone do this to Henry James?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marc-herbert
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A dreadful version of the great novel. Shame on you Laura Jones. Shame on the director for depicting Isabel Archer (Nicole Kidman) as a rather plain, uninteresting young woman with a goofy hairdo. What can possibly attract all of those men who want to marry her? And the ending was completely unsatisfactory. A much better way of telling this story, since James' prose is so rich with internal motivations and feelings which cannot easily be revealed by dialogue or even by facial expressions, would be to have voice-over. This would have allowed for a much improved climax. There are only two commendable elements here. One is the cinematography and the other actor John Malkovich, who portrayed a superb Osmond.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stuck in Mid=Pacific
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry James has never struck me as being the most cinematic of authors; his novels generally involve detailed explorations of the psychology of his characters and are marked by a highly elaborate prose style, characterised by lengthy, complex sentences and Latinate vocabulary. Yet a number of films have been based on his works, some of them very successful, dating back to "The Lost Moment" (based on "The Aspern Papers") and "The Heiress" (based on "Washington Square") in the late forties. The Merchant-Ivory team made three film adaptations of his novels, "The Europeans", "The Bostonians" and "The Golden Bowl". Like many of James's novels, "The Portrait of a Lady" is set among American expatriates in Europe. The central character, Isabel Archer, is a young American woman who becomes financially independent after she inherits a large amount of money from her English uncle Mr Touchett. While travelling on the Continent she meets another American expatriate, Gilbert Osmond, in Florence. The two marry, but the marriage is not a happy one, and Isabel comes to suspect that Osmond is a fortune-hunter whose only interest in her is financial. The film is made in the "heritage cinema" style, popular in the eighties and nineties, and is reminiscent of the work of Merchant-Ivory and of certain other films of the period, such as Martin Scorsese's "The Age of Innocence" and Terence Davies's "The House of Mirth". Films in this style are generally set in the nineteenth or early twentieth century among the well-to-do classes, are generally based upon a literary source and are characterised by a detailed recreation of the look of the period and by an emphasis on dialogue and character development rather than physical action. Nicole Kidman's acting career got off to a promising start with films like "Dead Calm" and "Flirting", but over the next ten years or so she seemed to get stuck in something of a rut, appearing in far too many dull or second-rate films like "Far and Away", "Batman Forever", "Practical Magic" and the dreadful "Moulin Rouge". "The Portrait of a Lady" is considerably better than any of those films, but Kidman's performance is not her best, and her accent is not always reliable. It has become commonplace to describe American actors unsuccessfully attempting a British accent (or vice-versa) as being stuck in mid- Atlantic. Kidman's Aussie-tinged American accent is probably the first example of a major stat being linguistically stuck in mid-Pacific. John Malkovich is a lot better; like his Valmont in another period drama, "Dangerous Liaisons" his Osmond is the sort of character he excels at playing, able to combine an icy reptilian coldness with a certain smooth and plausible charm. There are also good contributions from Barbara Hershey as Osmond's friend and co-conspirator Madame Merle and from John Gielgud in a cameo as the elderly Touchett. (Gielgud was 92 at the time, and this was far from being his last film; he was to continue working up until his death in 2000 at the age of 96). Although Henry James was a dramatist as well as a novelist, and adapted several of his books for the stage, he considered "The Portrait of a Lady" to be unsuitable for dramatic presentation and dissuaded a friend who wanted to turn it into a play. That, however, did not dissuade Jane Campion from attempting to film the novel. Having recently watched the film for the first time since seeing it in the cinema in 1996, I can say that, in my view, James was probably right. It is, like many examples of "heritage cinema", visually attractive, but it is also rather emotionally cold and too slow-moving. There is nothing much about it which remains in the mind for long afterwards. It does not really compare with the greatest heritage movies like "The Age of Innocence", "The House of Mirth" or the best examples of Merchant-Ivory's work such as "Howard's End". Or, for that matter, with Jane Campion's own earlier, more dramatic and passionate period drama, "The Piano". 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as good as I'd hoped compared with the wonderful earlier British TV series
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rozinda
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers throughout Most of the acting is fine. But I had a problem with the later Kidman scenes. Kidman needed less of the weeping and more anger or deviousness, to keep herself away from her vile husband as much as possible. Instead she is a typical victim, inviting his spite and weeping when he exerts it. She even lets the thug hit her. Clearly Isabel was heading for a fall right from the start of the story. She's quite convinced there's no point in marrying her decent suitor Goodwood, she wants as people often do to live it up for some years before marriage. Unfortunately, she isn't nearly as clever as she thinks she is and it's not long before she's met the devious Merle and has been hoodwinked into marriage with Merle's vile lover Osmond so that the pair of them can live on Isabel's money. Standard Henry James type of theme. American girls take people at face value but expect value for money. Europeans are devious and will say/do anything to get an American heiress's money as they are always had up but want to live the high life. Isabel is naive - totally fooled by Osmond's pretence to be an aesthete. Osmond is a self-satisfied, conceited, totally self-centred and selfish jerk who thinks he's a wonderful and admirable aesthete whom everyone should admire but we audience see through him right from the start. Even his long-time mistress and mother of the child Pansy, Merle, is deceived by him until he finally, at the end, tells her he never cared about her either and she realises she has wasted her life on him and suffered from having to hide the true identity of her child for nothing. Osmond's method is the well-known "Whatever happens it's always your fault, I am perfect and blameless, I am a saint and you are selfish/thoughtless/stupid/venomous/a liar/hiding the truth/whatever along with the ruthless Victorian head of the family you do as I say nonsense that women had to put up with in that period. The jaw dropping thing is that Isabel becomes totally witless - seems to believe all this drivel from her vicious husband and begs his forgiveness every time. She becomes aware gradually that he is being unfair but hasn't the guts to tell him so to his face and then walk out - it would be difficult but perfectly possible for her to have fled with her American lover Goodwood who is at his wits end why it is she won't be with him even though clearly she has feelings for him. Osmond's daughter falls for "the wrong man". Isabel tries to help Pansy, by helping to deter the suitor her father wants, but Osmond soon finds out, accuses his wife of being treacherous and sends his daughter to a convent to "think about her errors and her future". Pansy proves to be like her father - treacherous. She tells Isabel dismissively, "I have learned that I must always obey my father." So much for Isabel trying to help the girl to be with the man who loved her - Pansy is revealed as shallow like her parents. Isabel is a fool - she has allowed herself to be brainwashed by a jerk because she thought he was glamorous (though anyone less glamorous than this Osmond would be hard to find, I disliked him on sight, quite correctly). Isabel's kindly cousin Ralph has the sadly not unusual consumption, and now is dying and Isabel goes to him in England in spite of her husband refusing to believe Ralph was that ill, ie a means to again force his wife to his own bidding through trading on her loyalty. But Isabel is more loyal to Ralph and goes to him. Ralph dies. Goodwood is there and at last we think it is his time. Can Isabel is well away from her Florence-based husband. She can now go back to the USA with devoted Goodwood? In an outdoor scene, she finally makes clear she now loves Goodwood and kisses him, but then she runs away from him back into the house. The movie ends with her standing at the door of the house looking towards the camera. You can't tell for sure what she'll do next but there's a feeling of foreboding. Beats me why the movie didn't finish the story. Goodwood calls next day only to discover that Isabel has gone straight back to her husband. We are told her friend who has been Ralph's companion has "taught Goodwood how to wait". How long, the reader wonders? Presumably until Osmond dies, but that man I would suspect will outlive everyone and Isabel will never leave him because if she did, she'd betray her own original conceit that she wanted to live an exciting and meaningful life. Basically, Isabel is a silly, self-destructive woman. She could never make any man happy. She needs, it seems, to be bullied.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Atmospheric character drama..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    New Zealand screenwriter and director Jane Campion's fourth feature film is an adaptation of a novel from 1881 written by American writer Henry James (1843-1916). The screenplay for this USA-England co-production which premiered at the 53rd Venice Film Festival in 1996, was written by Australian screenwriter Laura Jones. It tells the story about Isabel Archer, an independent woman from New York who after the death of her father visits her aunt Lydia and her wealthy uncle Daniel Tuchett at his estate near London. During her stay she socializes with an elder woman named Madame Serena Merle and some young men who one by one asks her for her hand in marriage. When Isabel's uncle dies, she inherits large parts of his estate and decides to travel the continent. In Florence she encounters an American expatriate named Gilbert Osmond who charms her with his knowledge and articulacy. Though having declined several proposals of marriage due to her ideals, Isabel agrees to marry Gilbert and starts a new life with him and his young daughter Pansy in Rome. This visually notable and dialog-driven period piece from the mid-1990s which draws ardent milieu depictions, is a detailed study of character about an 18th century feminist protagonist, driven by her personal choices, who seeks out and confronts her destiny while trying to maintain her integrity, but finds herself the victim of a deceitful and manipulative conspiracy. Jane Campion's second adaptation of previously written material is more of an in-depth and atmospheric character drama about a woman who is torn between her values and desires than a passionately romantic love story like "The Piano" (1993). Shot in England, USA, Turkey, Italy and Australia and acutely and distinctly directed by the brilliant filmmaker Jane Campion who has created several remarkable female character portraits since her feature film debut "Sweetie" (1989), this subtly narrated fictional tale is beautifully photographed by English-born New Zealand cinematographer Stuart Dryburgh. This lyrical epic which focuses on themes such as independence, freedom, love and betrayal, is distinguished by the prominent production and costume design by the director's frequent collaborator Janet Patterson and has a fine score by Polish composer Wojciech Kilar which reinforces the shifting atmosphere. Nicole Kidman, John Malkovich and Barbara Hershey delivers fine acting performances in this historical costume drama which gained, among other awards, the Pasinetti Award for Best Film at the 53rd Venice International Film Festival in 1996 and was nominated for Best Supporting Actress Barbara Hershey and Best Costume Design Janet Patterson at the 69th Academy Awards in 1997.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cold film, lacking the novel's passion
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheScholarGypsy
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is well-made, but there is a severity or coldness about it which is false to the temperament of the novel by Henry James on which it is based. Not so much in the portrayal of Gilbert Osmund by John Malkovich (although he brings to it his trademark air of sick malevolence, it seems excessive, not quite in key, even for the evil Gilbert Osmund), but very much so in the manner in which the heroine, Isabel Archer, is represented. In the novel she is a creature of passion; in the film, she is quite rightly adrift (true to the original) but altogether too much in the manner of an iceberg off the English coast rather than as an American "jeune fille" in sunny Italy. What passion she is given has a tortuous, fantastic character, represented by skewed hallucinations rather than by the robust erotic musings of innocent naivet&eacute;. Consequently, the movie ambles along, technically perfect but ultimately boring. Characters who appear to be bored and indifferent to their own lives not surprisingly fail to rouse in the audience any compensating interest. Ironically, it is given to the veteran actor John Gielgud (albeit perhaps unwittingly) to pronounce judgment upon this film in his character's dying scene: as Isabel fixes upon him an intent gaze, rapt with the serious business of grasping to her bosom a pearl of wisdom from this aged man poised on the brink of his ultimate odyssey, Gielgud emits as his final word-to-the-wise an elaborate yawn. In this curious version of James's energetic novel even death is a bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darkly textured, darkly felt...and darkly photographed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    23-year-old American in 1872 England, orphaned and now residing with wealthy relatives, is preyed upon by a fortune hunter who--despite coming up against a determinedly independent lass with a cynical overview of marriage--breaks down the girl's defenses and takes her as his wife; years later, their marriage on the rocks, the woman upsets her husband's plans by interfering in the love-life of her stepdaughter who is being unsuccessfully wooed by a Lord. Director Jane Campion opens this adaptation of Henry James' novel with a collage of modern women's faces, free and forthright and fulfilled, but then hands us a heroine who is duped, abused, and reduced easily to tears. This is not Nicole Kidman's fault, her performance as Isabel Archer is as good as can be expected. Campion fails to reveal any dimensions of this girl, and Isabel's circling conversations with men have a one-note, droning quality which matches Campion's chilly visual style: colorless. Campion's artistic attributes certainly give select sequences a stunning, eerie romantic flavor, but she doesn't do much with the actors (some of whom, Mary Louise Parker and Shelley Duvall in particular, seem woefully out of place). Kidman is under-lit and posed like a porcelain doll (at one point, her grayish pallor perfectly matches that of a pillar just behind her); yet, while these shots are thoughtfully composed, they call attention to themselves in a negative way for an audience very likely to get fed up with such pretensions (especially in a film which is already methodically paced). Ironically, "The Portrait of a Lady" comes mostly to life when dealing with John Malkovich's cunning hubby; the actor has played roles similar to this in the past, but his relish in bringing out the dark side of this tale can clearly be felt. The picture is literate, but almost in an exasperating way; the tastefulness of it as 'art', and the tactfulness of Laura Jones' screenplay, nearly kills off our interest. ** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Biggest Cinematic WTFs I've Ever Experienced
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one can accuse Jane Campion of lack of ambition in bringing Henry James' novel to the screen, but her film is a total disaster. The audacious style that made "The Piano" so compelling and memorable is a Frankenstein's monster here, and it runs away with Campion's film. The result is incomprehensible. Actors are stranded walking around opulent sets saying lines, while Campion pulls out every trick in the book to confounding effect. Though the fact that the film is incoherent probably means that it's a good adaptation, since it was after all based on a novel by Henry James.... Grade: F
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrible bore
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about a wealthy American heiress and her romantic pursuits of varying success in Europe. "The Portrait of a Lady" is immensely dull. The pace is slower than a snail, with many self indulgent artistic shots in between the already very slow plot. To make it even more boring, every character delivers their line in a flat and monotonous way. That may be the way how upper class speaks, but it is terribly dull and emotionless in a film. There is no emotional climax in the film either, everything is just plain and boring. Even the plethora of big stars can do nothing to save this film from being a bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    disappointing mess!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carolyn-epps
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember going to see this movie with a boyfriend back in 1997. I wanted to see this movie because I thought it would be romantic. I practically had to drag my boyfriend to see it with me, he laughed and slept thru most of it, while I tried desperately to understand the plot of the story. Nothing in this movie captured my interest!! I was so disappointed when I left the theater, I was tempted to ask for a refund!!!! I have even thought about renting the movie, if just to see if my understanding of the plot will become clear, but afraid it will only leave me feeling angry and unfulfilled. I can't give this film a good, not even a mediocre rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an excellent complete movie, a total artistic experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nostalgiapopescu
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've repeatedly seen this movie, I simply can't help myself from watching this example of good taste that has the ideas, the feeling, the meanings and also the means of a work of art. This movie is simply adorable from the beginning to the end. The actors, the story, the costumes, the soundtrack, scenery, everything is beautiful and full of authenticity. The adaptation from the novel appropriately reveals the subtle, simple and total story about life and mistakes, not only about women, but an extension about choosing wrong and about chances of choosing again, of hoping. But hoping itself is a choice, we all have the choice of hoping or not. This category is called "sublime" in art I guess...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why would anyone do this to Henry James?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marc-herbert
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A dreadful version of the great novel. Shame on you Laura Jones. Shame on the director for depicting Isabel Archer (Nicole Kidman) as a rather plain, uninteresting young woman with a goofy hairdo. What can possibly attract all of those men who want to marry her? And the ending was completely unsatisfactory. A much better way of telling this story, since James' prose is so rich with internal motivations and feelings which cannot easily be revealed by dialogue or even by facial expressions, would be to have voice-over. This would have allowed for a much improved climax. There are only two commendable elements here. One is the cinematography and the other actor John Malkovich, who portrayed a superb Osmond.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stuck in Mid=Pacific
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry James has never struck me as being the most cinematic of authors; his novels generally involve detailed explorations of the psychology of his characters and are marked by a highly elaborate prose style, characterised by lengthy, complex sentences and Latinate vocabulary. Yet a number of films have been based on his works, some of them very successful, dating back to "The Lost Moment" (based on "The Aspern Papers") and "The Heiress" (based on "Washington Square") in the late forties. The Merchant-Ivory team made three film adaptations of his novels, "The Europeans", "The Bostonians" and "The Golden Bowl". Like many of James's novels, "The Portrait of a Lady" is set among American expatriates in Europe. The central character, Isabel Archer, is a young American woman who becomes financially independent after she inherits a large amount of money from her English uncle Mr Touchett. While travelling on the Continent she meets another American expatriate, Gilbert Osmond, in Florence. The two marry, but the marriage is not a happy one, and Isabel comes to suspect that Osmond is a fortune-hunter whose only interest in her is financial. The film is made in the "heritage cinema" style, popular in the eighties and nineties, and is reminiscent of the work of Merchant-Ivory and of certain other films of the period, such as Martin Scorsese's "The Age of Innocence" and Terence Davies's "The House of Mirth". Films in this style are generally set in the nineteenth or early twentieth century among the well-to-do classes, are generally based upon a literary source and are characterised by a detailed recreation of the look of the period and by an emphasis on dialogue and character development rather than physical action. Nicole Kidman's acting career got off to a promising start with films like "Dead Calm" and "Flirting", but over the next ten years or so she seemed to get stuck in something of a rut, appearing in far too many dull or second-rate films like "Far and Away", "Batman Forever", "Practical Magic" and the dreadful "Moulin Rouge". "The Portrait of a Lady" is considerably better than any of those films, but Kidman's performance is not her best, and her accent is not always reliable. It has become commonplace to describe American actors unsuccessfully attempting a British accent (or vice-versa) as being stuck in mid- Atlantic. Kidman's Aussie-tinged American accent is probably the first example of a major stat being linguistically stuck in mid-Pacific. John Malkovich is a lot better; like his Valmont in another period drama, "Dangerous Liaisons" his Osmond is the sort of character he excels at playing, able to combine an icy reptilian coldness with a certain smooth and plausible charm. There are also good contributions from Barbara Hershey as Osmond's friend and co-conspirator Madame Merle and from John Gielgud in a cameo as the elderly Touchett. (Gielgud was 92 at the time, and this was far from being his last film; he was to continue working up until his death in 2000 at the age of 96). Although Henry James was a dramatist as well as a novelist, and adapted several of his books for the stage, he considered "The Portrait of a Lady" to be unsuitable for dramatic presentation and dissuaded a friend who wanted to turn it into a play. That, however, did not dissuade Jane Campion from attempting to film the novel. Having recently watched the film for the first time since seeing it in the cinema in 1996, I can say that, in my view, James was probably right. It is, like many examples of "heritage cinema", visually attractive, but it is also rather emotionally cold and too slow-moving. There is nothing much about it which remains in the mind for long afterwards. It does not really compare with the greatest heritage movies like "The Age of Innocence", "The House of Mirth" or the best examples of Merchant-Ivory's work such as "Howard's End". Or, for that matter, with Jane Campion's own earlier, more dramatic and passionate period drama, "The Piano". 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as good as I'd hoped compared with the wonderful earlier British TV series
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rozinda
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers throughout Most of the acting is fine. But I had a problem with the later Kidman scenes. Kidman needed less of the weeping and more anger or deviousness, to keep herself away from her vile husband as much as possible. Instead she is a typical victim, inviting his spite and weeping when he exerts it. She even lets the thug hit her. Clearly Isabel was heading for a fall right from the start of the story. She's quite convinced there's no point in marrying her decent suitor Goodwood, she wants as people often do to live it up for some years before marriage. Unfortunately, she isn't nearly as clever as she thinks she is and it's not long before she's met the devious Merle and has been hoodwinked into marriage with Merle's vile lover Osmond so that the pair of them can live on Isabel's money. Standard Henry James type of theme. American girls take people at face value but expect value for money. Europeans are devious and will say/do anything to get an American heiress's money as they are always had up but want to live the high life. Isabel is naive - totally fooled by Osmond's pretence to be an aesthete. Osmond is a self-satisfied, conceited, totally self-centred and selfish jerk who thinks he's a wonderful and admirable aesthete whom everyone should admire but we audience see through him right from the start. Even his long-time mistress and mother of the child Pansy, Merle, is deceived by him until he finally, at the end, tells her he never cared about her either and she realises she has wasted her life on him and suffered from having to hide the true identity of her child for nothing. Osmond's method is the well-known "Whatever happens it's always your fault, I am perfect and blameless, I am a saint and you are selfish/thoughtless/stupid/venomous/a liar/hiding the truth/whatever along with the ruthless Victorian head of the family you do as I say nonsense that women had to put up with in that period. The jaw dropping thing is that Isabel becomes totally witless - seems to believe all this drivel from her vicious husband and begs his forgiveness every time. She becomes aware gradually that he is being unfair but hasn't the guts to tell him so to his face and then walk out - it would be difficult but perfectly possible for her to have fled with her American lover Goodwood who is at his wits end why it is she won't be with him even though clearly she has feelings for him. Osmond's daughter falls for "the wrong man". Isabel tries to help Pansy, by helping to deter the suitor her father wants, but Osmond soon finds out, accuses his wife of being treacherous and sends his daughter to a convent to "think about her errors and her future". Pansy proves to be like her father - treacherous. She tells Isabel dismissively, "I have learned that I must always obey my father." So much for Isabel trying to help the girl to be with the man who loved her - Pansy is revealed as shallow like her parents. Isabel is a fool - she has allowed herself to be brainwashed by a jerk because she thought he was glamorous (though anyone less glamorous than this Osmond would be hard to find, I disliked him on sight, quite correctly). Isabel's kindly cousin Ralph has the sadly not unusual consumption, and now is dying and Isabel goes to him in England in spite of her husband refusing to believe Ralph was that ill, ie a means to again force his wife to his own bidding through trading on her loyalty. But Isabel is more loyal to Ralph and goes to him. Ralph dies. Goodwood is there and at last we think it is his time. Can Isabel is well away from her Florence-based husband. She can now go back to the USA with devoted Goodwood? In an outdoor scene, she finally makes clear she now loves Goodwood and kisses him, but then she runs away from him back into the house. The movie ends with her standing at the door of the house looking towards the camera. You can't tell for sure what she'll do next but there's a feeling of foreboding. Beats me why the movie didn't finish the story. Goodwood calls next day only to discover that Isabel has gone straight back to her husband. We are told her friend who has been Ralph's companion has "taught Goodwood how to wait". How long, the reader wonders? Presumably until Osmond dies, but that man I would suspect will outlive everyone and Isabel will never leave him because if she did, she'd betray her own original conceit that she wanted to live an exciting and meaningful life. Basically, Isabel is a silly, self-destructive woman. She could never make any man happy. She needs, it seems, to be bullied.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Atmospheric character drama..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    New Zealand screenwriter and director Jane Campion's fourth feature film is an adaptation of a novel from 1881 written by American writer Henry James (1843-1916). The screenplay for this USA-England co-production which premiered at the 53rd Venice Film Festival in 1996, was written by Australian screenwriter Laura Jones. It tells the story about Isabel Archer, an independent woman from New York who after the death of her father visits her aunt Lydia and her wealthy uncle Daniel Tuchett at his estate near London. During her stay she socializes with an elder woman named Madame Serena Merle and some young men who one by one asks her for her hand in marriage. When Isabel's uncle dies, she inherits large parts of his estate and decides to travel the continent. In Florence she encounters an American expatriate named Gilbert Osmond who charms her with his knowledge and articulacy. Though having declined several proposals of marriage due to her ideals, Isabel agrees to marry Gilbert and starts a new life with him and his young daughter Pansy in Rome. This visually notable and dialog-driven period piece from the mid-1990s which draws ardent milieu depictions, is a detailed study of character about an 18th century feminist protagonist, driven by her personal choices, who seeks out and confronts her destiny while trying to maintain her integrity, but finds herself the victim of a deceitful and manipulative conspiracy. Jane Campion's second adaptation of previously written material is more of an in-depth and atmospheric character drama about a woman who is torn between her values and desires than a passionately romantic love story like "The Piano" (1993). Shot in England, USA, Turkey, Italy and Australia and acutely and distinctly directed by the brilliant filmmaker Jane Campion who has created several remarkable female character portraits since her feature film debut "Sweetie" (1989), this subtly narrated fictional tale is beautifully photographed by English-born New Zealand cinematographer Stuart Dryburgh. This lyrical epic which focuses on themes such as independence, freedom, love and betrayal, is distinguished by the prominent production and costume design by the director's frequent collaborator Janet Patterson and has a fine score by Polish composer Wojciech Kilar which reinforces the shifting atmosphere. Nicole Kidman, John Malkovich and Barbara Hershey delivers fine acting performances in this historical costume drama which gained, among other awards, the Pasinetti Award for Best Film at the 53rd Venice International Film Festival in 1996 and was nominated for Best Supporting Actress Barbara Hershey and Best Costume Design Janet Patterson at the 69th Academy Awards in 1997.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cold film, lacking the novel's passion
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheScholarGypsy
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is well-made, but there is a severity or coldness about it which is false to the temperament of the novel by Henry James on which it is based. Not so much in the portrayal of Gilbert Osmund by John Malkovich (although he brings to it his trademark air of sick malevolence, it seems excessive, not quite in key, even for the evil Gilbert Osmund), but very much so in the manner in which the heroine, Isabel Archer, is represented. In the novel she is a creature of passion; in the film, she is quite rightly adrift (true to the original) but altogether too much in the manner of an iceberg off the English coast rather than as an American "jeune fille" in sunny Italy. What passion she is given has a tortuous, fantastic character, represented by skewed hallucinations rather than by the robust erotic musings of innocent naivet&eacute;. Consequently, the movie ambles along, technically perfect but ultimately boring. Characters who appear to be bored and indifferent to their own lives not surprisingly fail to rouse in the audience any compensating interest. Ironically, it is given to the veteran actor John Gielgud (albeit perhaps unwittingly) to pronounce judgment upon this film in his character's dying scene: as Isabel fixes upon him an intent gaze, rapt with the serious business of grasping to her bosom a pearl of wisdom from this aged man poised on the brink of his ultimate odyssey, Gielgud emits as his final word-to-the-wise an elaborate yawn. In this curious version of James's energetic novel even death is a bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darkly textured, darkly felt...and darkly photographed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    23-year-old American in 1872 England, orphaned and now residing with wealthy relatives, is preyed upon by a fortune hunter who--despite coming up against a determinedly independent lass with a cynical overview of marriage--breaks down the girl's defenses and takes her as his wife; years later, their marriage on the rocks, the woman upsets her husband's plans by interfering in the love-life of her stepdaughter who is being unsuccessfully wooed by a Lord. Director Jane Campion opens this adaptation of Henry James' novel with a collage of modern women's faces, free and forthright and fulfilled, but then hands us a heroine who is duped, abused, and reduced easily to tears. This is not Nicole Kidman's fault, her performance as Isabel Archer is as good as can be expected. Campion fails to reveal any dimensions of this girl, and Isabel's circling conversations with men have a one-note, droning quality which matches Campion's chilly visual style: colorless. Campion's artistic attributes certainly give select sequences a stunning, eerie romantic flavor, but she doesn't do much with the actors (some of whom, Mary Louise Parker and Shelley Duvall in particular, seem woefully out of place). Kidman is under-lit and posed like a porcelain doll (at one point, her grayish pallor perfectly matches that of a pillar just behind her); yet, while these shots are thoughtfully composed, they call attention to themselves in a negative way for an audience very likely to get fed up with such pretensions (especially in a film which is already methodically paced). Ironically, "The Portrait of a Lady" comes mostly to life when dealing with John Malkovich's cunning hubby; the actor has played roles similar to this in the past, but his relish in bringing out the dark side of this tale can clearly be felt. The picture is literate, but almost in an exasperating way; the tastefulness of it as 'art', and the tactfulness of Laura Jones' screenplay, nearly kills off our interest. ** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Biggest Cinematic WTFs I've Ever Experienced
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one can accuse Jane Campion of lack of ambition in bringing Henry James' novel to the screen, but her film is a total disaster. The audacious style that made "The Piano" so compelling and memorable is a Frankenstein's monster here, and it runs away with Campion's film. The result is incomprehensible. Actors are stranded walking around opulent sets saying lines, while Campion pulls out every trick in the book to confounding effect. Though the fact that the film is incoherent probably means that it's a good adaptation, since it was after all based on a novel by Henry James.... Grade: F
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrible bore
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about a wealthy American heiress and her romantic pursuits of varying success in Europe. "The Portrait of a Lady" is immensely dull. The pace is slower than a snail, with many self indulgent artistic shots in between the already very slow plot. To make it even more boring, every character delivers their line in a flat and monotonous way. That may be the way how upper class speaks, but it is terribly dull and emotionless in a film. There is no emotional climax in the film either, everything is just plain and boring. Even the plethora of big stars can do nothing to save this film from being a bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    disappointing mess!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carolyn-epps
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember going to see this movie with a boyfriend back in 1997. I wanted to see this movie because I thought it would be romantic. I practically had to drag my boyfriend to see it with me, he laughed and slept thru most of it, while I tried desperately to understand the plot of the story. Nothing in this movie captured my interest!! I was so disappointed when I left the theater, I was tempted to ask for a refund!!!! I have even thought about renting the movie, if just to see if my understanding of the plot will become clear, but afraid it will only leave me feeling angry and unfulfilled. I can't give this film a good, not even a mediocre rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an excellent complete movie, a total artistic experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nostalgiapopescu
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've repeatedly seen this movie, I simply can't help myself from watching this example of good taste that has the ideas, the feeling, the meanings and also the means of a work of art. This movie is simply adorable from the beginning to the end. The actors, the story, the costumes, the soundtrack, scenery, everything is beautiful and full of authenticity. The adaptation from the novel appropriately reveals the subtle, simple and total story about life and mistakes, not only about women, but an extension about choosing wrong and about chances of choosing again, of hoping. But hoping itself is a choice, we all have the choice of hoping or not. This category is called "sublime" in art I guess...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why would anyone do this to Henry James?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marc-herbert
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A dreadful version of the great novel. Shame on you Laura Jones. Shame on the director for depicting Isabel Archer (Nicole Kidman) as a rather plain, uninteresting young woman with a goofy hairdo. What can possibly attract all of those men who want to marry her? And the ending was completely unsatisfactory. A much better way of telling this story, since James' prose is so rich with internal motivations and feelings which cannot easily be revealed by dialogue or even by facial expressions, would be to have voice-over. This would have allowed for a much improved climax. There are only two commendable elements here. One is the cinematography and the other actor John Malkovich, who portrayed a superb Osmond.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stuck in Mid=Pacific
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry James has never struck me as being the most cinematic of authors; his novels generally involve detailed explorations of the psychology of his characters and are marked by a highly elaborate prose style, characterised by lengthy, complex sentences and Latinate vocabulary. Yet a number of films have been based on his works, some of them very successful, dating back to "The Lost Moment" (based on "The Aspern Papers") and "The Heiress" (based on "Washington Square") in the late forties. The Merchant-Ivory team made three film adaptations of his novels, "The Europeans", "The Bostonians" and "The Golden Bowl". Like many of James's novels, "The Portrait of a Lady" is set among American expatriates in Europe. The central character, Isabel Archer, is a young American woman who becomes financially independent after she inherits a large amount of money from her English uncle Mr Touchett. While travelling on the Continent she meets another American expatriate, Gilbert Osmond, in Florence. The two marry, but the marriage is not a happy one, and Isabel comes to suspect that Osmond is a fortune-hunter whose only interest in her is financial. The film is made in the "heritage cinema" style, popular in the eighties and nineties, and is reminiscent of the work of Merchant-Ivory and of certain other films of the period, such as Martin Scorsese's "The Age of Innocence" and Terence Davies's "The House of Mirth". Films in this style are generally set in the nineteenth or early twentieth century among the well-to-do classes, are generally based upon a literary source and are characterised by a detailed recreation of the look of the period and by an emphasis on dialogue and character development rather than physical action. Nicole Kidman's acting career got off to a promising start with films like "Dead Calm" and "Flirting", but over the next ten years or so she seemed to get stuck in something of a rut, appearing in far too many dull or second-rate films like "Far and Away", "Batman Forever", "Practical Magic" and the dreadful "Moulin Rouge". "The Portrait of a Lady" is considerably better than any of those films, but Kidman's performance is not her best, and her accent is not always reliable. It has become commonplace to describe American actors unsuccessfully attempting a British accent (or vice-versa) as being stuck in mid- Atlantic. Kidman's Aussie-tinged American accent is probably the first example of a major stat being linguistically stuck in mid-Pacific. John Malkovich is a lot better; like his Valmont in another period drama, "Dangerous Liaisons" his Osmond is the sort of character he excels at playing, able to combine an icy reptilian coldness with a certain smooth and plausible charm. There are also good contributions from Barbara Hershey as Osmond's friend and co-conspirator Madame Merle and from John Gielgud in a cameo as the elderly Touchett. (Gielgud was 92 at the time, and this was far from being his last film; he was to continue working up until his death in 2000 at the age of 96). Although Henry James was a dramatist as well as a novelist, and adapted several of his books for the stage, he considered "The Portrait of a Lady" to be unsuitable for dramatic presentation and dissuaded a friend who wanted to turn it into a play. That, however, did not dissuade Jane Campion from attempting to film the novel. Having recently watched the film for the first time since seeing it in the cinema in 1996, I can say that, in my view, James was probably right. It is, like many examples of "heritage cinema", visually attractive, but it is also rather emotionally cold and too slow-moving. There is nothing much about it which remains in the mind for long afterwards. It does not really compare with the greatest heritage movies like "The Age of Innocence", "The House of Mirth" or the best examples of Merchant-Ivory's work such as "Howard's End". Or, for that matter, with Jane Campion's own earlier, more dramatic and passionate period drama, "The Piano". 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as good as I'd hoped compared with the wonderful earlier British TV series
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rozinda
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers throughout Most of the acting is fine. But I had a problem with the later Kidman scenes. Kidman needed less of the weeping and more anger or deviousness, to keep herself away from her vile husband as much as possible. Instead she is a typical victim, inviting his spite and weeping when he exerts it. She even lets the thug hit her. Clearly Isabel was heading for a fall right from the start of the story. She's quite convinced there's no point in marrying her decent suitor Goodwood, she wants as people often do to live it up for some years before marriage. Unfortunately, she isn't nearly as clever as she thinks she is and it's not long before she's met the devious Merle and has been hoodwinked into marriage with Merle's vile lover Osmond so that the pair of them can live on Isabel's money. Standard Henry James type of theme. American girls take people at face value but expect value for money. Europeans are devious and will say/do anything to get an American heiress's money as they are always had up but want to live the high life. Isabel is naive - totally fooled by Osmond's pretence to be an aesthete. Osmond is a self-satisfied, conceited, totally self-centred and selfish jerk who thinks he's a wonderful and admirable aesthete whom everyone should admire but we audience see through him right from the start. Even his long-time mistress and mother of the child Pansy, Merle, is deceived by him until he finally, at the end, tells her he never cared about her either and she realises she has wasted her life on him and suffered from having to hide the true identity of her child for nothing. Osmond's method is the well-known "Whatever happens it's always your fault, I am perfect and blameless, I am a saint and you are selfish/thoughtless/stupid/venomous/a liar/hiding the truth/whatever along with the ruthless Victorian head of the family you do as I say nonsense that women had to put up with in that period. The jaw dropping thing is that Isabel becomes totally witless - seems to believe all this drivel from her vicious husband and begs his forgiveness every time. She becomes aware gradually that he is being unfair but hasn't the guts to tell him so to his face and then walk out - it would be difficult but perfectly possible for her to have fled with her American lover Goodwood who is at his wits end why it is she won't be with him even though clearly she has feelings for him. Osmond's daughter falls for "the wrong man". Isabel tries to help Pansy, by helping to deter the suitor her father wants, but Osmond soon finds out, accuses his wife of being treacherous and sends his daughter to a convent to "think about her errors and her future". Pansy proves to be like her father - treacherous. She tells Isabel dismissively, "I have learned that I must always obey my father." So much for Isabel trying to help the girl to be with the man who loved her - Pansy is revealed as shallow like her parents. Isabel is a fool - she has allowed herself to be brainwashed by a jerk because she thought he was glamorous (though anyone less glamorous than this Osmond would be hard to find, I disliked him on sight, quite correctly). Isabel's kindly cousin Ralph has the sadly not unusual consumption, and now is dying and Isabel goes to him in England in spite of her husband refusing to believe Ralph was that ill, ie a means to again force his wife to his own bidding through trading on her loyalty. But Isabel is more loyal to Ralph and goes to him. Ralph dies. Goodwood is there and at last we think it is his time. Can Isabel is well away from her Florence-based husband. She can now go back to the USA with devoted Goodwood? In an outdoor scene, she finally makes clear she now loves Goodwood and kisses him, but then she runs away from him back into the house. The movie ends with her standing at the door of the house looking towards the camera. You can't tell for sure what she'll do next but there's a feeling of foreboding. Beats me why the movie didn't finish the story. Goodwood calls next day only to discover that Isabel has gone straight back to her husband. We are told her friend who has been Ralph's companion has "taught Goodwood how to wait". How long, the reader wonders? Presumably until Osmond dies, but that man I would suspect will outlive everyone and Isabel will never leave him because if she did, she'd betray her own original conceit that she wanted to live an exciting and meaningful life. Basically, Isabel is a silly, self-destructive woman. She could never make any man happy. She needs, it seems, to be bullied.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Atmospheric character drama..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    New Zealand screenwriter and director Jane Campion's fourth feature film is an adaptation of a novel from 1881 written by American writer Henry James (1843-1916). The screenplay for this USA-England co-production which premiered at the 53rd Venice Film Festival in 1996, was written by Australian screenwriter Laura Jones. It tells the story about Isabel Archer, an independent woman from New York who after the death of her father visits her aunt Lydia and her wealthy uncle Daniel Tuchett at his estate near London. During her stay she socializes with an elder woman named Madame Serena Merle and some young men who one by one asks her for her hand in marriage. When Isabel's uncle dies, she inherits large parts of his estate and decides to travel the continent. In Florence she encounters an American expatriate named Gilbert Osmond who charms her with his knowledge and articulacy. Though having declined several proposals of marriage due to her ideals, Isabel agrees to marry Gilbert and starts a new life with him and his young daughter Pansy in Rome. This visually notable and dialog-driven period piece from the mid-1990s which draws ardent milieu depictions, is a detailed study of character about an 18th century feminist protagonist, driven by her personal choices, who seeks out and confronts her destiny while trying to maintain her integrity, but finds herself the victim of a deceitful and manipulative conspiracy. Jane Campion's second adaptation of previously written material is more of an in-depth and atmospheric character drama about a woman who is torn between her values and desires than a passionately romantic love story like "The Piano" (1993). Shot in England, USA, Turkey, Italy and Australia and acutely and distinctly directed by the brilliant filmmaker Jane Campion who has created several remarkable female character portraits since her feature film debut "Sweetie" (1989), this subtly narrated fictional tale is beautifully photographed by English-born New Zealand cinematographer Stuart Dryburgh. This lyrical epic which focuses on themes such as independence, freedom, love and betrayal, is distinguished by the prominent production and costume design by the director's frequent collaborator Janet Patterson and has a fine score by Polish composer Wojciech Kilar which reinforces the shifting atmosphere. Nicole Kidman, John Malkovich and Barbara Hershey delivers fine acting performances in this historical costume drama which gained, among other awards, the Pasinetti Award for Best Film at the 53rd Venice International Film Festival in 1996 and was nominated for Best Supporting Actress Barbara Hershey and Best Costume Design Janet Patterson at the 69th Academy Awards in 1997.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cold film, lacking the novel's passion
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheScholarGypsy
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is well-made, but there is a severity or coldness about it which is false to the temperament of the novel by Henry James on which it is based. Not so much in the portrayal of Gilbert Osmund by John Malkovich (although he brings to it his trademark air of sick malevolence, it seems excessive, not quite in key, even for the evil Gilbert Osmund), but very much so in the manner in which the heroine, Isabel Archer, is represented. In the novel she is a creature of passion; in the film, she is quite rightly adrift (true to the original) but altogether too much in the manner of an iceberg off the English coast rather than as an American "jeune fille" in sunny Italy. What passion she is given has a tortuous, fantastic character, represented by skewed hallucinations rather than by the robust erotic musings of innocent naivet&eacute;. Consequently, the movie ambles along, technically perfect but ultimately boring. Characters who appear to be bored and indifferent to their own lives not surprisingly fail to rouse in the audience any compensating interest. Ironically, it is given to the veteran actor John Gielgud (albeit perhaps unwittingly) to pronounce judgment upon this film in his character's dying scene: as Isabel fixes upon him an intent gaze, rapt with the serious business of grasping to her bosom a pearl of wisdom from this aged man poised on the brink of his ultimate odyssey, Gielgud emits as his final word-to-the-wise an elaborate yawn. In this curious version of James's energetic novel even death is a bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darkly textured, darkly felt...and darkly photographed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    23-year-old American in 1872 England, orphaned and now residing with wealthy relatives, is preyed upon by a fortune hunter who--despite coming up against a determinedly independent lass with a cynical overview of marriage--breaks down the girl's defenses and takes her as his wife; years later, their marriage on the rocks, the woman upsets her husband's plans by interfering in the love-life of her stepdaughter who is being unsuccessfully wooed by a Lord. Director Jane Campion opens this adaptation of Henry James' novel with a collage of modern women's faces, free and forthright and fulfilled, but then hands us a heroine who is duped, abused, and reduced easily to tears. This is not Nicole Kidman's fault, her performance as Isabel Archer is as good as can be expected. Campion fails to reveal any dimensions of this girl, and Isabel's circling conversations with men have a one-note, droning quality which matches Campion's chilly visual style: colorless. Campion's artistic attributes certainly give select sequences a stunning, eerie romantic flavor, but she doesn't do much with the actors (some of whom, Mary Louise Parker and Shelley Duvall in particular, seem woefully out of place). Kidman is under-lit and posed like a porcelain doll (at one point, her grayish pallor perfectly matches that of a pillar just behind her); yet, while these shots are thoughtfully composed, they call attention to themselves in a negative way for an audience very likely to get fed up with such pretensions (especially in a film which is already methodically paced). Ironically, "The Portrait of a Lady" comes mostly to life when dealing with John Malkovich's cunning hubby; the actor has played roles similar to this in the past, but his relish in bringing out the dark side of this tale can clearly be felt. The picture is literate, but almost in an exasperating way; the tastefulness of it as 'art', and the tactfulness of Laura Jones' screenplay, nearly kills off our interest. ** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Biggest Cinematic WTFs I've Ever Experienced
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one can accuse Jane Campion of lack of ambition in bringing Henry James' novel to the screen, but her film is a total disaster. The audacious style that made "The Piano" so compelling and memorable is a Frankenstein's monster here, and it runs away with Campion's film. The result is incomprehensible. Actors are stranded walking around opulent sets saying lines, while Campion pulls out every trick in the book to confounding effect. Though the fact that the film is incoherent probably means that it's a good adaptation, since it was after all based on a novel by Henry James.... Grade: F
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrible bore
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about a wealthy American heiress and her romantic pursuits of varying success in Europe. "The Portrait of a Lady" is immensely dull. The pace is slower than a snail, with many self indulgent artistic shots in between the already very slow plot. To make it even more boring, every character delivers their line in a flat and monotonous way. That may be the way how upper class speaks, but it is terribly dull and emotionless in a film. There is no emotional climax in the film either, everything is just plain and boring. Even the plethora of big stars can do nothing to save this film from being a bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    disappointing mess!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carolyn-epps
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember going to see this movie with a boyfriend back in 1997. I wanted to see this movie because I thought it would be romantic. I practically had to drag my boyfriend to see it with me, he laughed and slept thru most of it, while I tried desperately to understand the plot of the story. Nothing in this movie captured my interest!! I was so disappointed when I left the theater, I was tempted to ask for a refund!!!! I have even thought about renting the movie, if just to see if my understanding of the plot will become clear, but afraid it will only leave me feeling angry and unfulfilled. I can't give this film a good, not even a mediocre rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an excellent complete movie, a total artistic experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nostalgiapopescu
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've repeatedly seen this movie, I simply can't help myself from watching this example of good taste that has the ideas, the feeling, the meanings and also the means of a work of art. This movie is simply adorable from the beginning to the end. The actors, the story, the costumes, the soundtrack, scenery, everything is beautiful and full of authenticity. The adaptation from the novel appropriately reveals the subtle, simple and total story about life and mistakes, not only about women, but an extension about choosing wrong and about chances of choosing again, of hoping. But hoping itself is a choice, we all have the choice of hoping or not. This category is called "sublime" in art I guess...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why would anyone do this to Henry James?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marc-herbert
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A dreadful version of the great novel. Shame on you Laura Jones. Shame on the director for depicting Isabel Archer (Nicole Kidman) as a rather plain, uninteresting young woman with a goofy hairdo. What can possibly attract all of those men who want to marry her? And the ending was completely unsatisfactory. A much better way of telling this story, since James' prose is so rich with internal motivations and feelings which cannot easily be revealed by dialogue or even by facial expressions, would be to have voice-over. This would have allowed for a much improved climax. There are only two commendable elements here. One is the cinematography and the other actor John Malkovich, who portrayed a superb Osmond.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stuck in Mid=Pacific
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry James has never struck me as being the most cinematic of authors; his novels generally involve detailed explorations of the psychology of his characters and are marked by a highly elaborate prose style, characterised by lengthy, complex sentences and Latinate vocabulary. Yet a number of films have been based on his works, some of them very successful, dating back to "The Lost Moment" (based on "The Aspern Papers") and "The Heiress" (based on "Washington Square") in the late forties. The Merchant-Ivory team made three film adaptations of his novels, "The Europeans", "The Bostonians" and "The Golden Bowl". Like many of James's novels, "The Portrait of a Lady" is set among American expatriates in Europe. The central character, Isabel Archer, is a young American woman who becomes financially independent after she inherits a large amount of money from her English uncle Mr Touchett. While travelling on the Continent she meets another American expatriate, Gilbert Osmond, in Florence. The two marry, but the marriage is not a happy one, and Isabel comes to suspect that Osmond is a fortune-hunter whose only interest in her is financial. The film is made in the "heritage cinema" style, popular in the eighties and nineties, and is reminiscent of the work of Merchant-Ivory and of certain other films of the period, such as Martin Scorsese's "The Age of Innocence" and Terence Davies's "The House of Mirth". Films in this style are generally set in the nineteenth or early twentieth century among the well-to-do classes, are generally based upon a literary source and are characterised by a detailed recreation of the look of the period and by an emphasis on dialogue and character development rather than physical action. Nicole Kidman's acting career got off to a promising start with films like "Dead Calm" and "Flirting", but over the next ten years or so she seemed to get stuck in something of a rut, appearing in far too many dull or second-rate films like "Far and Away", "Batman Forever", "Practical Magic" and the dreadful "Moulin Rouge". "The Portrait of a Lady" is considerably better than any of those films, but Kidman's performance is not her best, and her accent is not always reliable. It has become commonplace to describe American actors unsuccessfully attempting a British accent (or vice-versa) as being stuck in mid- Atlantic. Kidman's Aussie-tinged American accent is probably the first example of a major stat being linguistically stuck in mid-Pacific. John Malkovich is a lot better; like his Valmont in another period drama, "Dangerous Liaisons" his Osmond is the sort of character he excels at playing, able to combine an icy reptilian coldness with a certain smooth and plausible charm. There are also good contributions from Barbara Hershey as Osmond's friend and co-conspirator Madame Merle and from John Gielgud in a cameo as the elderly Touchett. (Gielgud was 92 at the time, and this was far from being his last film; he was to continue working up until his death in 2000 at the age of 96). Although Henry James was a dramatist as well as a novelist, and adapted several of his books for the stage, he considered "The Portrait of a Lady" to be unsuitable for dramatic presentation and dissuaded a friend who wanted to turn it into a play. That, however, did not dissuade Jane Campion from attempting to film the novel. Having recently watched the film for the first time since seeing it in the cinema in 1996, I can say that, in my view, James was probably right. It is, like many examples of "heritage cinema", visually attractive, but it is also rather emotionally cold and too slow-moving. There is nothing much about it which remains in the mind for long afterwards. It does not really compare with the greatest heritage movies like "The Age of Innocence", "The House of Mirth" or the best examples of Merchant-Ivory's work such as "Howard's End". Or, for that matter, with Jane Campion's own earlier, more dramatic and passionate period drama, "The Piano". 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as good as I'd hoped compared with the wonderful earlier British TV series
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rozinda
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers throughout Most of the acting is fine. But I had a problem with the later Kidman scenes. Kidman needed less of the weeping and more anger or deviousness, to keep herself away from her vile husband as much as possible. Instead she is a typical victim, inviting his spite and weeping when he exerts it. She even lets the thug hit her. Clearly Isabel was heading for a fall right from the start of the story. She's quite convinced there's no point in marrying her decent suitor Goodwood, she wants as people often do to live it up for some years before marriage. Unfortunately, she isn't nearly as clever as she thinks she is and it's not long before she's met the devious Merle and has been hoodwinked into marriage with Merle's vile lover Osmond so that the pair of them can live on Isabel's money. Standard Henry James type of theme. American girls take people at face value but expect value for money. Europeans are devious and will say/do anything to get an American heiress's money as they are always had up but want to live the high life. Isabel is naive - totally fooled by Osmond's pretence to be an aesthete. Osmond is a self-satisfied, conceited, totally self-centred and selfish jerk who thinks he's a wonderful and admirable aesthete whom everyone should admire but we audience see through him right from the start. Even his long-time mistress and mother of the child Pansy, Merle, is deceived by him until he finally, at the end, tells her he never cared about her either and she realises she has wasted her life on him and suffered from having to hide the true identity of her child for nothing. Osmond's method is the well-known "Whatever happens it's always your fault, I am perfect and blameless, I am a saint and you are selfish/thoughtless/stupid/venomous/a liar/hiding the truth/whatever along with the ruthless Victorian head of the family you do as I say nonsense that women had to put up with in that period. The jaw dropping thing is that Isabel becomes totally witless - seems to believe all this drivel from her vicious husband and begs his forgiveness every time. She becomes aware gradually that he is being unfair but hasn't the guts to tell him so to his face and then walk out - it would be difficult but perfectly possible for her to have fled with her American lover Goodwood who is at his wits end why it is she won't be with him even though clearly she has feelings for him. Osmond's daughter falls for "the wrong man". Isabel tries to help Pansy, by helping to deter the suitor her father wants, but Osmond soon finds out, accuses his wife of being treacherous and sends his daughter to a convent to "think about her errors and her future". Pansy proves to be like her father - treacherous. She tells Isabel dismissively, "I have learned that I must always obey my father." So much for Isabel trying to help the girl to be with the man who loved her - Pansy is revealed as shallow like her parents. Isabel is a fool - she has allowed herself to be brainwashed by a jerk because she thought he was glamorous (though anyone less glamorous than this Osmond would be hard to find, I disliked him on sight, quite correctly). Isabel's kindly cousin Ralph has the sadly not unusual consumption, and now is dying and Isabel goes to him in England in spite of her husband refusing to believe Ralph was that ill, ie a means to again force his wife to his own bidding through trading on her loyalty. But Isabel is more loyal to Ralph and goes to him. Ralph dies. Goodwood is there and at last we think it is his time. Can Isabel is well away from her Florence-based husband. She can now go back to the USA with devoted Goodwood? In an outdoor scene, she finally makes clear she now loves Goodwood and kisses him, but then she runs away from him back into the house. The movie ends with her standing at the door of the house looking towards the camera. You can't tell for sure what she'll do next but there's a feeling of foreboding. Beats me why the movie didn't finish the story. Goodwood calls next day only to discover that Isabel has gone straight back to her husband. We are told her friend who has been Ralph's companion has "taught Goodwood how to wait". How long, the reader wonders? Presumably until Osmond dies, but that man I would suspect will outlive everyone and Isabel will never leave him because if she did, she'd betray her own original conceit that she wanted to live an exciting and meaningful life. Basically, Isabel is a silly, self-destructive woman. She could never make any man happy. She needs, it seems, to be bullied.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Atmospheric character drama..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    New Zealand screenwriter and director Jane Campion's fourth feature film is an adaptation of a novel from 1881 written by American writer Henry James (1843-1916). The screenplay for this USA-England co-production which premiered at the 53rd Venice Film Festival in 1996, was written by Australian screenwriter Laura Jones. It tells the story about Isabel Archer, an independent woman from New York who after the death of her father visits her aunt Lydia and her wealthy uncle Daniel Tuchett at his estate near London. During her stay she socializes with an elder woman named Madame Serena Merle and some young men who one by one asks her for her hand in marriage. When Isabel's uncle dies, she inherits large parts of his estate and decides to travel the continent. In Florence she encounters an American expatriate named Gilbert Osmond who charms her with his knowledge and articulacy. Though having declined several proposals of marriage due to her ideals, Isabel agrees to marry Gilbert and starts a new life with him and his young daughter Pansy in Rome. This visually notable and dialog-driven period piece from the mid-1990s which draws ardent milieu depictions, is a detailed study of character about an 18th century feminist protagonist, driven by her personal choices, who seeks out and confronts her destiny while trying to maintain her integrity, but finds herself the victim of a deceitful and manipulative conspiracy. Jane Campion's second adaptation of previously written material is more of an in-depth and atmospheric character drama about a woman who is torn between her values and desires than a passionately romantic love story like "The Piano" (1993). Shot in England, USA, Turkey, Italy and Australia and acutely and distinctly directed by the brilliant filmmaker Jane Campion who has created several remarkable female character portraits since her feature film debut "Sweetie" (1989), this subtly narrated fictional tale is beautifully photographed by English-born New Zealand cinematographer Stuart Dryburgh. This lyrical epic which focuses on themes such as independence, freedom, love and betrayal, is distinguished by the prominent production and costume design by the director's frequent collaborator Janet Patterson and has a fine score by Polish composer Wojciech Kilar which reinforces the shifting atmosphere. Nicole Kidman, John Malkovich and Barbara Hershey delivers fine acting performances in this historical costume drama which gained, among other awards, the Pasinetti Award for Best Film at the 53rd Venice International Film Festival in 1996 and was nominated for Best Supporting Actress Barbara Hershey and Best Costume Design Janet Patterson at the 69th Academy Awards in 1997.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cold film, lacking the novel's passion
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheScholarGypsy
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is well-made, but there is a severity or coldness about it which is false to the temperament of the novel by Henry James on which it is based. Not so much in the portrayal of Gilbert Osmund by John Malkovich (although he brings to it his trademark air of sick malevolence, it seems excessive, not quite in key, even for the evil Gilbert Osmund), but very much so in the manner in which the heroine, Isabel Archer, is represented. In the novel she is a creature of passion; in the film, she is quite rightly adrift (true to the original) but altogether too much in the manner of an iceberg off the English coast rather than as an American "jeune fille" in sunny Italy. What passion she is given has a tortuous, fantastic character, represented by skewed hallucinations rather than by the robust erotic musings of innocent naivet&eacute;. Consequently, the movie ambles along, technically perfect but ultimately boring. Characters who appear to be bored and indifferent to their own lives not surprisingly fail to rouse in the audience any compensating interest. Ironically, it is given to the veteran actor John Gielgud (albeit perhaps unwittingly) to pronounce judgment upon this film in his character's dying scene: as Isabel fixes upon him an intent gaze, rapt with the serious business of grasping to her bosom a pearl of wisdom from this aged man poised on the brink of his ultimate odyssey, Gielgud emits as his final word-to-the-wise an elaborate yawn. In this curious version of James's energetic novel even death is a bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darkly textured, darkly felt...and darkly photographed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    23-year-old American in 1872 England, orphaned and now residing with wealthy relatives, is preyed upon by a fortune hunter who--despite coming up against a determinedly independent lass with a cynical overview of marriage--breaks down the girl's defenses and takes her as his wife; years later, their marriage on the rocks, the woman upsets her husband's plans by interfering in the love-life of her stepdaughter who is being unsuccessfully wooed by a Lord. Director Jane Campion opens this adaptation of Henry James' novel with a collage of modern women's faces, free and forthright and fulfilled, but then hands us a heroine who is duped, abused, and reduced easily to tears. This is not Nicole Kidman's fault, her performance as Isabel Archer is as good as can be expected. Campion fails to reveal any dimensions of this girl, and Isabel's circling conversations with men have a one-note, droning quality which matches Campion's chilly visual style: colorless. Campion's artistic attributes certainly give select sequences a stunning, eerie romantic flavor, but she doesn't do much with the actors (some of whom, Mary Louise Parker and Shelley Duvall in particular, seem woefully out of place). Kidman is under-lit and posed like a porcelain doll (at one point, her grayish pallor perfectly matches that of a pillar just behind her); yet, while these shots are thoughtfully composed, they call attention to themselves in a negative way for an audience very likely to get fed up with such pretensions (especially in a film which is already methodically paced). Ironically, "The Portrait of a Lady" comes mostly to life when dealing with John Malkovich's cunning hubby; the actor has played roles similar to this in the past, but his relish in bringing out the dark side of this tale can clearly be felt. The picture is literate, but almost in an exasperating way; the tastefulness of it as 'art', and the tactfulness of Laura Jones' screenplay, nearly kills off our interest. ** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Biggest Cinematic WTFs I've Ever Experienced
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one can accuse Jane Campion of lack of ambition in bringing Henry James' novel to the screen, but her film is a total disaster. The audacious style that made "The Piano" so compelling and memorable is a Frankenstein's monster here, and it runs away with Campion's film. The result is incomprehensible. Actors are stranded walking around opulent sets saying lines, while Campion pulls out every trick in the book to confounding effect. Though the fact that the film is incoherent probably means that it's a good adaptation, since it was after all based on a novel by Henry James.... Grade: F
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrible bore
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about a wealthy American heiress and her romantic pursuits of varying success in Europe. "The Portrait of a Lady" is immensely dull. The pace is slower than a snail, with many self indulgent artistic shots in between the already very slow plot. To make it even more boring, every character delivers their line in a flat and monotonous way. That may be the way how upper class speaks, but it is terribly dull and emotionless in a film. There is no emotional climax in the film either, everything is just plain and boring. Even the plethora of big stars can do nothing to save this film from being a bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    disappointing mess!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carolyn-epps
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember going to see this movie with a boyfriend back in 1997. I wanted to see this movie because I thought it would be romantic. I practically had to drag my boyfriend to see it with me, he laughed and slept thru most of it, while I tried desperately to understand the plot of the story. Nothing in this movie captured my interest!! I was so disappointed when I left the theater, I was tempted to ask for a refund!!!! I have even thought about renting the movie, if just to see if my understanding of the plot will become clear, but afraid it will only leave me feeling angry and unfulfilled. I can't give this film a good, not even a mediocre rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an excellent complete movie, a total artistic experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nostalgiapopescu
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've repeatedly seen this movie, I simply can't help myself from watching this example of good taste that has the ideas, the feeling, the meanings and also the means of a work of art. This movie is simply adorable from the beginning to the end. The actors, the story, the costumes, the soundtrack, scenery, everything is beautiful and full of authenticity. The adaptation from the novel appropriately reveals the subtle, simple and total story about life and mistakes, not only about women, but an extension about choosing wrong and about chances of choosing again, of hoping. But hoping itself is a choice, we all have the choice of hoping or not. This category is called "sublime" in art I guess...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why would anyone do this to Henry James?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marc-herbert
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A dreadful version of the great novel. Shame on you Laura Jones. Shame on the director for depicting Isabel Archer (Nicole Kidman) as a rather plain, uninteresting young woman with a goofy hairdo. What can possibly attract all of those men who want to marry her? And the ending was completely unsatisfactory. A much better way of telling this story, since James' prose is so rich with internal motivations and feelings which cannot easily be revealed by dialogue or even by facial expressions, would be to have voice-over. This would have allowed for a much improved climax. There are only two commendable elements here. One is the cinematography and the other actor John Malkovich, who portrayed a superb Osmond.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stuck in Mid=Pacific
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry James has never struck me as being the most cinematic of authors; his novels generally involve detailed explorations of the psychology of his characters and are marked by a highly elaborate prose style, characterised by lengthy, complex sentences and Latinate vocabulary. Yet a number of films have been based on his works, some of them very successful, dating back to "The Lost Moment" (based on "The Aspern Papers") and "The Heiress" (based on "Washington Square") in the late forties. The Merchant-Ivory team made three film adaptations of his novels, "The Europeans", "The Bostonians" and "The Golden Bowl". Like many of James's novels, "The Portrait of a Lady" is set among American expatriates in Europe. The central character, Isabel Archer, is a young American woman who becomes financially independent after she inherits a large amount of money from her English uncle Mr Touchett. While travelling on the Continent she meets another American expatriate, Gilbert Osmond, in Florence. The two marry, but the marriage is not a happy one, and Isabel comes to suspect that Osmond is a fortune-hunter whose only interest in her is financial. The film is made in the "heritage cinema" style, popular in the eighties and nineties, and is reminiscent of the work of Merchant-Ivory and of certain other films of the period, such as Martin Scorsese's "The Age of Innocence" and Terence Davies's "The House of Mirth". Films in this style are generally set in the nineteenth or early twentieth century among the well-to-do classes, are generally based upon a literary source and are characterised by a detailed recreation of the look of the period and by an emphasis on dialogue and character development rather than physical action. Nicole Kidman's acting career got off to a promising start with films like "Dead Calm" and "Flirting", but over the next ten years or so she seemed to get stuck in something of a rut, appearing in far too many dull or second-rate films like "Far and Away", "Batman Forever", "Practical Magic" and the dreadful "Moulin Rouge". "The Portrait of a Lady" is considerably better than any of those films, but Kidman's performance is not her best, and her accent is not always reliable. It has become commonplace to describe American actors unsuccessfully attempting a British accent (or vice-versa) as being stuck in mid- Atlantic. Kidman's Aussie-tinged American accent is probably the first example of a major stat being linguistically stuck in mid-Pacific. John Malkovich is a lot better; like his Valmont in another period drama, "Dangerous Liaisons" his Osmond is the sort of character he excels at playing, able to combine an icy reptilian coldness with a certain smooth and plausible charm. There are also good contributions from Barbara Hershey as Osmond's friend and co-conspirator Madame Merle and from John Gielgud in a cameo as the elderly Touchett. (Gielgud was 92 at the time, and this was far from being his last film; he was to continue working up until his death in 2000 at the age of 96). Although Henry James was a dramatist as well as a novelist, and adapted several of his books for the stage, he considered "The Portrait of a Lady" to be unsuitable for dramatic presentation and dissuaded a friend who wanted to turn it into a play. That, however, did not dissuade Jane Campion from attempting to film the novel. Having recently watched the film for the first time since seeing it in the cinema in 1996, I can say that, in my view, James was probably right. It is, like many examples of "heritage cinema", visually attractive, but it is also rather emotionally cold and too slow-moving. There is nothing much about it which remains in the mind for long afterwards. It does not really compare with the greatest heritage movies like "The Age of Innocence", "The House of Mirth" or the best examples of Merchant-Ivory's work such as "Howard's End". Or, for that matter, with Jane Campion's own earlier, more dramatic and passionate period drama, "The Piano". 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as good as I'd hoped compared with the wonderful earlier British TV series
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rozinda
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers throughout Most of the acting is fine. But I had a problem with the later Kidman scenes. Kidman needed less of the weeping and more anger or deviousness, to keep herself away from her vile husband as much as possible. Instead she is a typical victim, inviting his spite and weeping when he exerts it. She even lets the thug hit her. Clearly Isabel was heading for a fall right from the start of the story. She's quite convinced there's no point in marrying her decent suitor Goodwood, she wants as people often do to live it up for some years before marriage. Unfortunately, she isn't nearly as clever as she thinks she is and it's not long before she's met the devious Merle and has been hoodwinked into marriage with Merle's vile lover Osmond so that the pair of them can live on Isabel's money. Standard Henry James type of theme. American girls take people at face value but expect value for money. Europeans are devious and will say/do anything to get an American heiress's money as they are always had up but want to live the high life. Isabel is naive - totally fooled by Osmond's pretence to be an aesthete. Osmond is a self-satisfied, conceited, totally self-centred and selfish jerk who thinks he's a wonderful and admirable aesthete whom everyone should admire but we audience see through him right from the start. Even his long-time mistress and mother of the child Pansy, Merle, is deceived by him until he finally, at the end, tells her he never cared about her either and she realises she has wasted her life on him and suffered from having to hide the true identity of her child for nothing. Osmond's method is the well-known "Whatever happens it's always your fault, I am perfect and blameless, I am a saint and you are selfish/thoughtless/stupid/venomous/a liar/hiding the truth/whatever along with the ruthless Victorian head of the family you do as I say nonsense that women had to put up with in that period. The jaw dropping thing is that Isabel becomes totally witless - seems to believe all this drivel from her vicious husband and begs his forgiveness every time. She becomes aware gradually that he is being unfair but hasn't the guts to tell him so to his face and then walk out - it would be difficult but perfectly possible for her to have fled with her American lover Goodwood who is at his wits end why it is she won't be with him even though clearly she has feelings for him. Osmond's daughter falls for "the wrong man". Isabel tries to help Pansy, by helping to deter the suitor her father wants, but Osmond soon finds out, accuses his wife of being treacherous and sends his daughter to a convent to "think about her errors and her future". Pansy proves to be like her father - treacherous. She tells Isabel dismissively, "I have learned that I must always obey my father." So much for Isabel trying to help the girl to be with the man who loved her - Pansy is revealed as shallow like her parents. Isabel is a fool - she has allowed herself to be brainwashed by a jerk because she thought he was glamorous (though anyone less glamorous than this Osmond would be hard to find, I disliked him on sight, quite correctly). Isabel's kindly cousin Ralph has the sadly not unusual consumption, and now is dying and Isabel goes to him in England in spite of her husband refusing to believe Ralph was that ill, ie a means to again force his wife to his own bidding through trading on her loyalty. But Isabel is more loyal to Ralph and goes to him. Ralph dies. Goodwood is there and at last we think it is his time. Can Isabel is well away from her Florence-based husband. She can now go back to the USA with devoted Goodwood? In an outdoor scene, she finally makes clear she now loves Goodwood and kisses him, but then she runs away from him back into the house. The movie ends with her standing at the door of the house looking towards the camera. You can't tell for sure what she'll do next but there's a feeling of foreboding. Beats me why the movie didn't finish the story. Goodwood calls next day only to discover that Isabel has gone straight back to her husband. We are told her friend who has been Ralph's companion has "taught Goodwood how to wait". How long, the reader wonders? Presumably until Osmond dies, but that man I would suspect will outlive everyone and Isabel will never leave him because if she did, she'd betray her own original conceit that she wanted to live an exciting and meaningful life. Basically, Isabel is a silly, self-destructive woman. She could never make any man happy. She needs, it seems, to be bullied.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Atmospheric character drama..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    New Zealand screenwriter and director Jane Campion's fourth feature film is an adaptation of a novel from 1881 written by American writer Henry James (1843-1916). The screenplay for this USA-England co-production which premiered at the 53rd Venice Film Festival in 1996, was written by Australian screenwriter Laura Jones. It tells the story about Isabel Archer, an independent woman from New York who after the death of her father visits her aunt Lydia and her wealthy uncle Daniel Tuchett at his estate near London. During her stay she socializes with an elder woman named Madame Serena Merle and some young men who one by one asks her for her hand in marriage. When Isabel's uncle dies, she inherits large parts of his estate and decides to travel the continent. In Florence she encounters an American expatriate named Gilbert Osmond who charms her with his knowledge and articulacy. Though having declined several proposals of marriage due to her ideals, Isabel agrees to marry Gilbert and starts a new life with him and his young daughter Pansy in Rome. This visually notable and dialog-driven period piece from the mid-1990s which draws ardent milieu depictions, is a detailed study of character about an 18th century feminist protagonist, driven by her personal choices, who seeks out and confronts her destiny while trying to maintain her integrity, but finds herself the victim of a deceitful and manipulative conspiracy. Jane Campion's second adaptation of previously written material is more of an in-depth and atmospheric character drama about a woman who is torn between her values and desires than a passionately romantic love story like "The Piano" (1993). Shot in England, USA, Turkey, Italy and Australia and acutely and distinctly directed by the brilliant filmmaker Jane Campion who has created several remarkable female character portraits since her feature film debut "Sweetie" (1989), this subtly narrated fictional tale is beautifully photographed by English-born New Zealand cinematographer Stuart Dryburgh. This lyrical epic which focuses on themes such as independence, freedom, love and betrayal, is distinguished by the prominent production and costume design by the director's frequent collaborator Janet Patterson and has a fine score by Polish composer Wojciech Kilar which reinforces the shifting atmosphere. Nicole Kidman, John Malkovich and Barbara Hershey delivers fine acting performances in this historical costume drama which gained, among other awards, the Pasinetti Award for Best Film at the 53rd Venice International Film Festival in 1996 and was nominated for Best Supporting Actress Barbara Hershey and Best Costume Design Janet Patterson at the 69th Academy Awards in 1997.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cold film, lacking the novel's passion
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheScholarGypsy
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is well-made, but there is a severity or coldness about it which is false to the temperament of the novel by Henry James on which it is based. Not so much in the portrayal of Gilbert Osmund by John Malkovich (although he brings to it his trademark air of sick malevolence, it seems excessive, not quite in key, even for the evil Gilbert Osmund), but very much so in the manner in which the heroine, Isabel Archer, is represented. In the novel she is a creature of passion; in the film, she is quite rightly adrift (true to the original) but altogether too much in the manner of an iceberg off the English coast rather than as an American "jeune fille" in sunny Italy. What passion she is given has a tortuous, fantastic character, represented by skewed hallucinations rather than by the robust erotic musings of innocent naivet&eacute;. Consequently, the movie ambles along, technically perfect but ultimately boring. Characters who appear to be bored and indifferent to their own lives not surprisingly fail to rouse in the audience any compensating interest. Ironically, it is given to the veteran actor John Gielgud (albeit perhaps unwittingly) to pronounce judgment upon this film in his character's dying scene: as Isabel fixes upon him an intent gaze, rapt with the serious business of grasping to her bosom a pearl of wisdom from this aged man poised on the brink of his ultimate odyssey, Gielgud emits as his final word-to-the-wise an elaborate yawn. In this curious version of James's energetic novel even death is a bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darkly textured, darkly felt...and darkly photographed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    23-year-old American in 1872 England, orphaned and now residing with wealthy relatives, is preyed upon by a fortune hunter who--despite coming up against a determinedly independent lass with a cynical overview of marriage--breaks down the girl's defenses and takes her as his wife; years later, their marriage on the rocks, the woman upsets her husband's plans by interfering in the love-life of her stepdaughter who is being unsuccessfully wooed by a Lord. Director Jane Campion opens this adaptation of Henry James' novel with a collage of modern women's faces, free and forthright and fulfilled, but then hands us a heroine who is duped, abused, and reduced easily to tears. This is not Nicole Kidman's fault, her performance as Isabel Archer is as good as can be expected. Campion fails to reveal any dimensions of this girl, and Isabel's circling conversations with men have a one-note, droning quality which matches Campion's chilly visual style: colorless. Campion's artistic attributes certainly give select sequences a stunning, eerie romantic flavor, but she doesn't do much with the actors (some of whom, Mary Louise Parker and Shelley Duvall in particular, seem woefully out of place). Kidman is under-lit and posed like a porcelain doll (at one point, her grayish pallor perfectly matches that of a pillar just behind her); yet, while these shots are thoughtfully composed, they call attention to themselves in a negative way for an audience very likely to get fed up with such pretensions (especially in a film which is already methodically paced). Ironically, "The Portrait of a Lady" comes mostly to life when dealing with John Malkovich's cunning hubby; the actor has played roles similar to this in the past, but his relish in bringing out the dark side of this tale can clearly be felt. The picture is literate, but almost in an exasperating way; the tastefulness of it as 'art', and the tactfulness of Laura Jones' screenplay, nearly kills off our interest. ** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Biggest Cinematic WTFs I've Ever Experienced
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one can accuse Jane Campion of lack of ambition in bringing Henry James' novel to the screen, but her film is a total disaster. The audacious style that made "The Piano" so compelling and memorable is a Frankenstein's monster here, and it runs away with Campion's film. The result is incomprehensible. Actors are stranded walking around opulent sets saying lines, while Campion pulls out every trick in the book to confounding effect. Though the fact that the film is incoherent probably means that it's a good adaptation, since it was after all based on a novel by Henry James.... Grade: F
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrible bore
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about a wealthy American heiress and her romantic pursuits of varying success in Europe. "The Portrait of a Lady" is immensely dull. The pace is slower than a snail, with many self indulgent artistic shots in between the already very slow plot. To make it even more boring, every character delivers their line in a flat and monotonous way. That may be the way how upper class speaks, but it is terribly dull and emotionless in a film. There is no emotional climax in the film either, everything is just plain and boring. Even the plethora of big stars can do nothing to save this film from being a bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    disappointing mess!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carolyn-epps
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember going to see this movie with a boyfriend back in 1997. I wanted to see this movie because I thought it would be romantic. I practically had to drag my boyfriend to see it with me, he laughed and slept thru most of it, while I tried desperately to understand the plot of the story. Nothing in this movie captured my interest!! I was so disappointed when I left the theater, I was tempted to ask for a refund!!!! I have even thought about renting the movie, if just to see if my understanding of the plot will become clear, but afraid it will only leave me feeling angry and unfulfilled. I can't give this film a good, not even a mediocre rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an excellent complete movie, a total artistic experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nostalgiapopescu
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've repeatedly seen this movie, I simply can't help myself from watching this example of good taste that has the ideas, the feeling, the meanings and also the means of a work of art. This movie is simply adorable from the beginning to the end. The actors, the story, the costumes, the soundtrack, scenery, everything is beautiful and full of authenticity. The adaptation from the novel appropriately reveals the subtle, simple and total story about life and mistakes, not only about women, but an extension about choosing wrong and about chances of choosing again, of hoping. But hoping itself is a choice, we all have the choice of hoping or not. This category is called "sublime" in art I guess...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why would anyone do this to Henry James?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marc-herbert
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A dreadful version of the great novel. Shame on you Laura Jones. Shame on the director for depicting Isabel Archer (Nicole Kidman) as a rather plain, uninteresting young woman with a goofy hairdo. What can possibly attract all of those men who want to marry her? And the ending was completely unsatisfactory. A much better way of telling this story, since James' prose is so rich with internal motivations and feelings which cannot easily be revealed by dialogue or even by facial expressions, would be to have voice-over. This would have allowed for a much improved climax. There are only two commendable elements here. One is the cinematography and the other actor John Malkovich, who portrayed a superb Osmond.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stuck in Mid=Pacific
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry James has never struck me as being the most cinematic of authors; his novels generally involve detailed explorations of the psychology of his characters and are marked by a highly elaborate prose style, characterised by lengthy, complex sentences and Latinate vocabulary. Yet a number of films have been based on his works, some of them very successful, dating back to "The Lost Moment" (based on "The Aspern Papers") and "The Heiress" (based on "Washington Square") in the late forties. The Merchant-Ivory team made three film adaptations of his novels, "The Europeans", "The Bostonians" and "The Golden Bowl". Like many of James's novels, "The Portrait of a Lady" is set among American expatriates in Europe. The central character, Isabel Archer, is a young American woman who becomes financially independent after she inherits a large amount of money from her English uncle Mr Touchett. While travelling on the Continent she meets another American expatriate, Gilbert Osmond, in Florence. The two marry, but the marriage is not a happy one, and Isabel comes to suspect that Osmond is a fortune-hunter whose only interest in her is financial. The film is made in the "heritage cinema" style, popular in the eighties and nineties, and is reminiscent of the work of Merchant-Ivory and of certain other films of the period, such as Martin Scorsese's "The Age of Innocence" and Terence Davies's "The House of Mirth". Films in this style are generally set in the nineteenth or early twentieth century among the well-to-do classes, are generally based upon a literary source and are characterised by a detailed recreation of the look of the period and by an emphasis on dialogue and character development rather than physical action. Nicole Kidman's acting career got off to a promising start with films like "Dead Calm" and "Flirting", but over the next ten years or so she seemed to get stuck in something of a rut, appearing in far too many dull or second-rate films like "Far and Away", "Batman Forever", "Practical Magic" and the dreadful "Moulin Rouge". "The Portrait of a Lady" is considerably better than any of those films, but Kidman's performance is not her best, and her accent is not always reliable. It has become commonplace to describe American actors unsuccessfully attempting a British accent (or vice-versa) as being stuck in mid- Atlantic. Kidman's Aussie-tinged American accent is probably the first example of a major stat being linguistically stuck in mid-Pacific. John Malkovich is a lot better; like his Valmont in another period drama, "Dangerous Liaisons" his Osmond is the sort of character he excels at playing, able to combine an icy reptilian coldness with a certain smooth and plausible charm. There are also good contributions from Barbara Hershey as Osmond's friend and co-conspirator Madame Merle and from John Gielgud in a cameo as the elderly Touchett. (Gielgud was 92 at the time, and this was far from being his last film; he was to continue working up until his death in 2000 at the age of 96). Although Henry James was a dramatist as well as a novelist, and adapted several of his books for the stage, he considered "The Portrait of a Lady" to be unsuitable for dramatic presentation and dissuaded a friend who wanted to turn it into a play. That, however, did not dissuade Jane Campion from attempting to film the novel. Having recently watched the film for the first time since seeing it in the cinema in 1996, I can say that, in my view, James was probably right. It is, like many examples of "heritage cinema", visually attractive, but it is also rather emotionally cold and too slow-moving. There is nothing much about it which remains in the mind for long afterwards. It does not really compare with the greatest heritage movies like "The Age of Innocence", "The House of Mirth" or the best examples of Merchant-Ivory's work such as "Howard's End". Or, for that matter, with Jane Campion's own earlier, more dramatic and passionate period drama, "The Piano". 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as good as I'd hoped compared with the wonderful earlier British TV series
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rozinda
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers throughout Most of the acting is fine. But I had a problem with the later Kidman scenes. Kidman needed less of the weeping and more anger or deviousness, to keep herself away from her vile husband as much as possible. Instead she is a typical victim, inviting his spite and weeping when he exerts it. She even lets the thug hit her. Clearly Isabel was heading for a fall right from the start of the story. She's quite convinced there's no point in marrying her decent suitor Goodwood, she wants as people often do to live it up for some years before marriage. Unfortunately, she isn't nearly as clever as she thinks she is and it's not long before she's met the devious Merle and has been hoodwinked into marriage with Merle's vile lover Osmond so that the pair of them can live on Isabel's money. Standard Henry James type of theme. American girls take people at face value but expect value for money. Europeans are devious and will say/do anything to get an American heiress's money as they are always had up but want to live the high life. Isabel is naive - totally fooled by Osmond's pretence to be an aesthete. Osmond is a self-satisfied, conceited, totally self-centred and selfish jerk who thinks he's a wonderful and admirable aesthete whom everyone should admire but we audience see through him right from the start. Even his long-time mistress and mother of the child Pansy, Merle, is deceived by him until he finally, at the end, tells her he never cared about her either and she realises she has wasted her life on him and suffered from having to hide the true identity of her child for nothing. Osmond's method is the well-known "Whatever happens it's always your fault, I am perfect and blameless, I am a saint and you are selfish/thoughtless/stupid/venomous/a liar/hiding the truth/whatever along with the ruthless Victorian head of the family you do as I say nonsense that women had to put up with in that period. The jaw dropping thing is that Isabel becomes totally witless - seems to believe all this drivel from her vicious husband and begs his forgiveness every time. She becomes aware gradually that he is being unfair but hasn't the guts to tell him so to his face and then walk out - it would be difficult but perfectly possible for her to have fled with her American lover Goodwood who is at his wits end why it is she won't be with him even though clearly she has feelings for him. Osmond's daughter falls for "the wrong man". Isabel tries to help Pansy, by helping to deter the suitor her father wants, but Osmond soon finds out, accuses his wife of being treacherous and sends his daughter to a convent to "think about her errors and her future". Pansy proves to be like her father - treacherous. She tells Isabel dismissively, "I have learned that I must always obey my father." So much for Isabel trying to help the girl to be with the man who loved her - Pansy is revealed as shallow like her parents. Isabel is a fool - she has allowed herself to be brainwashed by a jerk because she thought he was glamorous (though anyone less glamorous than this Osmond would be hard to find, I disliked him on sight, quite correctly). Isabel's kindly cousin Ralph has the sadly not unusual consumption, and now is dying and Isabel goes to him in England in spite of her husband refusing to believe Ralph was that ill, ie a means to again force his wife to his own bidding through trading on her loyalty. But Isabel is more loyal to Ralph and goes to him. Ralph dies. Goodwood is there and at last we think it is his time. Can Isabel is well away from her Florence-based husband. She can now go back to the USA with devoted Goodwood? In an outdoor scene, she finally makes clear she now loves Goodwood and kisses him, but then she runs away from him back into the house. The movie ends with her standing at the door of the house looking towards the camera. You can't tell for sure what she'll do next but there's a feeling of foreboding. Beats me why the movie didn't finish the story. Goodwood calls next day only to discover that Isabel has gone straight back to her husband. We are told her friend who has been Ralph's companion has "taught Goodwood how to wait". How long, the reader wonders? Presumably until Osmond dies, but that man I would suspect will outlive everyone and Isabel will never leave him because if she did, she'd betray her own original conceit that she wanted to live an exciting and meaningful life. Basically, Isabel is a silly, self-destructive woman. She could never make any man happy. She needs, it seems, to be bullied.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Atmospheric character drama..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    New Zealand screenwriter and director Jane Campion's fourth feature film is an adaptation of a novel from 1881 written by American writer Henry James (1843-1916). The screenplay for this USA-England co-production which premiered at the 53rd Venice Film Festival in 1996, was written by Australian screenwriter Laura Jones. It tells the story about Isabel Archer, an independent woman from New York who after the death of her father visits her aunt Lydia and her wealthy uncle Daniel Tuchett at his estate near London. During her stay she socializes with an elder woman named Madame Serena Merle and some young men who one by one asks her for her hand in marriage. When Isabel's uncle dies, she inherits large parts of his estate and decides to travel the continent. In Florence she encounters an American expatriate named Gilbert Osmond who charms her with his knowledge and articulacy. Though having declined several proposals of marriage due to her ideals, Isabel agrees to marry Gilbert and starts a new life with him and his young daughter Pansy in Rome. This visually notable and dialog-driven period piece from the mid-1990s which draws ardent milieu depictions, is a detailed study of character about an 18th century feminist protagonist, driven by her personal choices, who seeks out and confronts her destiny while trying to maintain her integrity, but finds herself the victim of a deceitful and manipulative conspiracy. Jane Campion's second adaptation of previously written material is more of an in-depth and atmospheric character drama about a woman who is torn between her values and desires than a passionately romantic love story like "The Piano" (1993). Shot in England, USA, Turkey, Italy and Australia and acutely and distinctly directed by the brilliant filmmaker Jane Campion who has created several remarkable female character portraits since her feature film debut "Sweetie" (1989), this subtly narrated fictional tale is beautifully photographed by English-born New Zealand cinematographer Stuart Dryburgh. This lyrical epic which focuses on themes such as independence, freedom, love and betrayal, is distinguished by the prominent production and costume design by the director's frequent collaborator Janet Patterson and has a fine score by Polish composer Wojciech Kilar which reinforces the shifting atmosphere. Nicole Kidman, John Malkovich and Barbara Hershey delivers fine acting performances in this historical costume drama which gained, among other awards, the Pasinetti Award for Best Film at the 53rd Venice International Film Festival in 1996 and was nominated for Best Supporting Actress Barbara Hershey and Best Costume Design Janet Patterson at the 69th Academy Awards in 1997.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cold film, lacking the novel's passion
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheScholarGypsy
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is well-made, but there is a severity or coldness about it which is false to the temperament of the novel by Henry James on which it is based. Not so much in the portrayal of Gilbert Osmund by John Malkovich (although he brings to it his trademark air of sick malevolence, it seems excessive, not quite in key, even for the evil Gilbert Osmund), but very much so in the manner in which the heroine, Isabel Archer, is represented. In the novel she is a creature of passion; in the film, she is quite rightly adrift (true to the original) but altogether too much in the manner of an iceberg off the English coast rather than as an American "jeune fille" in sunny Italy. What passion she is given has a tortuous, fantastic character, represented by skewed hallucinations rather than by the robust erotic musings of innocent naivet&eacute;. Consequently, the movie ambles along, technically perfect but ultimately boring. Characters who appear to be bored and indifferent to their own lives not surprisingly fail to rouse in the audience any compensating interest. Ironically, it is given to the veteran actor John Gielgud (albeit perhaps unwittingly) to pronounce judgment upon this film in his character's dying scene: as Isabel fixes upon him an intent gaze, rapt with the serious business of grasping to her bosom a pearl of wisdom from this aged man poised on the brink of his ultimate odyssey, Gielgud emits as his final word-to-the-wise an elaborate yawn. In this curious version of James's energetic novel even death is a bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darkly textured, darkly felt...and darkly photographed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    23-year-old American in 1872 England, orphaned and now residing with wealthy relatives, is preyed upon by a fortune hunter who--despite coming up against a determinedly independent lass with a cynical overview of marriage--breaks down the girl's defenses and takes her as his wife; years later, their marriage on the rocks, the woman upsets her husband's plans by interfering in the love-life of her stepdaughter who is being unsuccessfully wooed by a Lord. Director Jane Campion opens this adaptation of Henry James' novel with a collage of modern women's faces, free and forthright and fulfilled, but then hands us a heroine who is duped, abused, and reduced easily to tears. This is not Nicole Kidman's fault, her performance as Isabel Archer is as good as can be expected. Campion fails to reveal any dimensions of this girl, and Isabel's circling conversations with men have a one-note, droning quality which matches Campion's chilly visual style: colorless. Campion's artistic attributes certainly give select sequences a stunning, eerie romantic flavor, but she doesn't do much with the actors (some of whom, Mary Louise Parker and Shelley Duvall in particular, seem woefully out of place). Kidman is under-lit and posed like a porcelain doll (at one point, her grayish pallor perfectly matches that of a pillar just behind her); yet, while these shots are thoughtfully composed, they call attention to themselves in a negative way for an audience very likely to get fed up with such pretensions (especially in a film which is already methodically paced). Ironically, "The Portrait of a Lady" comes mostly to life when dealing with John Malkovich's cunning hubby; the actor has played roles similar to this in the past, but his relish in bringing out the dark side of this tale can clearly be felt. The picture is literate, but almost in an exasperating way; the tastefulness of it as 'art', and the tactfulness of Laura Jones' screenplay, nearly kills off our interest. ** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Biggest Cinematic WTFs I've Ever Experienced
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one can accuse Jane Campion of lack of ambition in bringing Henry James' novel to the screen, but her film is a total disaster. The audacious style that made "The Piano" so compelling and memorable is a Frankenstein's monster here, and it runs away with Campion's film. The result is incomprehensible. Actors are stranded walking around opulent sets saying lines, while Campion pulls out every trick in the book to confounding effect. Though the fact that the film is incoherent probably means that it's a good adaptation, since it was after all based on a novel by Henry James.... Grade: F
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrible bore
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about a wealthy American heiress and her romantic pursuits of varying success in Europe. "The Portrait of a Lady" is immensely dull. The pace is slower than a snail, with many self indulgent artistic shots in between the already very slow plot. To make it even more boring, every character delivers their line in a flat and monotonous way. That may be the way how upper class speaks, but it is terribly dull and emotionless in a film. There is no emotional climax in the film either, everything is just plain and boring. Even the plethora of big stars can do nothing to save this film from being a bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    disappointing mess!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carolyn-epps
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember going to see this movie with a boyfriend back in 1997. I wanted to see this movie because I thought it would be romantic. I practically had to drag my boyfriend to see it with me, he laughed and slept thru most of it, while I tried desperately to understand the plot of the story. Nothing in this movie captured my interest!! I was so disappointed when I left the theater, I was tempted to ask for a refund!!!! I have even thought about renting the movie, if just to see if my understanding of the plot will become clear, but afraid it will only leave me feeling angry and unfulfilled. I can't give this film a good, not even a mediocre rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an excellent complete movie, a total artistic experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nostalgiapopescu
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've repeatedly seen this movie, I simply can't help myself from watching this example of good taste that has the ideas, the feeling, the meanings and also the means of a work of art. This movie is simply adorable from the beginning to the end. The actors, the story, the costumes, the soundtrack, scenery, everything is beautiful and full of authenticity. The adaptation from the novel appropriately reveals the subtle, simple and total story about life and mistakes, not only about women, but an extension about choosing wrong and about chances of choosing again, of hoping. But hoping itself is a choice, we all have the choice of hoping or not. This category is called "sublime" in art I guess...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why would anyone do this to Henry James?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marc-herbert
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A dreadful version of the great novel. Shame on you Laura Jones. Shame on the director for depicting Isabel Archer (Nicole Kidman) as a rather plain, uninteresting young woman with a goofy hairdo. What can possibly attract all of those men who want to marry her? And the ending was completely unsatisfactory. A much better way of telling this story, since James' prose is so rich with internal motivations and feelings which cannot easily be revealed by dialogue or even by facial expressions, would be to have voice-over. This would have allowed for a much improved climax. There are only two commendable elements here. One is the cinematography and the other actor John Malkovich, who portrayed a superb Osmond.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stuck in Mid=Pacific
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry James has never struck me as being the most cinematic of authors; his novels generally involve detailed explorations of the psychology of his characters and are marked by a highly elaborate prose style, characterised by lengthy, complex sentences and Latinate vocabulary. Yet a number of films have been based on his works, some of them very successful, dating back to "The Lost Moment" (based on "The Aspern Papers") and "The Heiress" (based on "Washington Square") in the late forties. The Merchant-Ivory team made three film adaptations of his novels, "The Europeans", "The Bostonians" and "The Golden Bowl". Like many of James's novels, "The Portrait of a Lady" is set among American expatriates in Europe. The central character, Isabel Archer, is a young American woman who becomes financially independent after she inherits a large amount of money from her English uncle Mr Touchett. While travelling on the Continent she meets another American expatriate, Gilbert Osmond, in Florence. The two marry, but the marriage is not a happy one, and Isabel comes to suspect that Osmond is a fortune-hunter whose only interest in her is financial. The film is made in the "heritage cinema" style, popular in the eighties and nineties, and is reminiscent of the work of Merchant-Ivory and of certain other films of the period, such as Martin Scorsese's "The Age of Innocence" and Terence Davies's "The House of Mirth". Films in this style are generally set in the nineteenth or early twentieth century among the well-to-do classes, are generally based upon a literary source and are characterised by a detailed recreation of the look of the period and by an emphasis on dialogue and character development rather than physical action. Nicole Kidman's acting career got off to a promising start with films like "Dead Calm" and "Flirting", but over the next ten years or so she seemed to get stuck in something of a rut, appearing in far too many dull or second-rate films like "Far and Away", "Batman Forever", "Practical Magic" and the dreadful "Moulin Rouge". "The Portrait of a Lady" is considerably better than any of those films, but Kidman's performance is not her best, and her accent is not always reliable. It has become commonplace to describe American actors unsuccessfully attempting a British accent (or vice-versa) as being stuck in mid- Atlantic. Kidman's Aussie-tinged American accent is probably the first example of a major stat being linguistically stuck in mid-Pacific. John Malkovich is a lot better; like his Valmont in another period drama, "Dangerous Liaisons" his Osmond is the sort of character he excels at playing, able to combine an icy reptilian coldness with a certain smooth and plausible charm. There are also good contributions from Barbara Hershey as Osmond's friend and co-conspirator Madame Merle and from John Gielgud in a cameo as the elderly Touchett. (Gielgud was 92 at the time, and this was far from being his last film; he was to continue working up until his death in 2000 at the age of 96). Although Henry James was a dramatist as well as a novelist, and adapted several of his books for the stage, he considered "The Portrait of a Lady" to be unsuitable for dramatic presentation and dissuaded a friend who wanted to turn it into a play. That, however, did not dissuade Jane Campion from attempting to film the novel. Having recently watched the film for the first time since seeing it in the cinema in 1996, I can say that, in my view, James was probably right. It is, like many examples of "heritage cinema", visually attractive, but it is also rather emotionally cold and too slow-moving. There is nothing much about it which remains in the mind for long afterwards. It does not really compare with the greatest heritage movies like "The Age of Innocence", "The House of Mirth" or the best examples of Merchant-Ivory's work such as "Howard's End". Or, for that matter, with Jane Campion's own earlier, more dramatic and passionate period drama, "The Piano". 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as good as I'd hoped compared with the wonderful earlier British TV series
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rozinda
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers throughout Most of the acting is fine. But I had a problem with the later Kidman scenes. Kidman needed less of the weeping and more anger or deviousness, to keep herself away from her vile husband as much as possible. Instead she is a typical victim, inviting his spite and weeping when he exerts it. She even lets the thug hit her. Clearly Isabel was heading for a fall right from the start of the story. She's quite convinced there's no point in marrying her decent suitor Goodwood, she wants as people often do to live it up for some years before marriage. Unfortunately, she isn't nearly as clever as she thinks she is and it's not long before she's met the devious Merle and has been hoodwinked into marriage with Merle's vile lover Osmond so that the pair of them can live on Isabel's money. Standard Henry James type of theme. American girls take people at face value but expect value for money. Europeans are devious and will say/do anything to get an American heiress's money as they are always had up but want to live the high life. Isabel is naive - totally fooled by Osmond's pretence to be an aesthete. Osmond is a self-satisfied, conceited, totally self-centred and selfish jerk who thinks he's a wonderful and admirable aesthete whom everyone should admire but we audience see through him right from the start. Even his long-time mistress and mother of the child Pansy, Merle, is deceived by him until he finally, at the end, tells her he never cared about her either and she realises she has wasted her life on him and suffered from having to hide the true identity of her child for nothing. Osmond's method is the well-known "Whatever happens it's always your fault, I am perfect and blameless, I am a saint and you are selfish/thoughtless/stupid/venomous/a liar/hiding the truth/whatever along with the ruthless Victorian head of the family you do as I say nonsense that women had to put up with in that period. The jaw dropping thing is that Isabel becomes totally witless - seems to believe all this drivel from her vicious husband and begs his forgiveness every time. She becomes aware gradually that he is being unfair but hasn't the guts to tell him so to his face and then walk out - it would be difficult but perfectly possible for her to have fled with her American lover Goodwood who is at his wits end why it is she won't be with him even though clearly she has feelings for him. Osmond's daughter falls for "the wrong man". Isabel tries to help Pansy, by helping to deter the suitor her father wants, but Osmond soon finds out, accuses his wife of being treacherous and sends his daughter to a convent to "think about her errors and her future". Pansy proves to be like her father - treacherous. She tells Isabel dismissively, "I have learned that I must always obey my father." So much for Isabel trying to help the girl to be with the man who loved her - Pansy is revealed as shallow like her parents. Isabel is a fool - she has allowed herself to be brainwashed by a jerk because she thought he was glamorous (though anyone less glamorous than this Osmond would be hard to find, I disliked him on sight, quite correctly). Isabel's kindly cousin Ralph has the sadly not unusual consumption, and now is dying and Isabel goes to him in England in spite of her husband refusing to believe Ralph was that ill, ie a means to again force his wife to his own bidding through trading on her loyalty. But Isabel is more loyal to Ralph and goes to him. Ralph dies. Goodwood is there and at last we think it is his time. Can Isabel is well away from her Florence-based husband. She can now go back to the USA with devoted Goodwood? In an outdoor scene, she finally makes clear she now loves Goodwood and kisses him, but then she runs away from him back into the house. The movie ends with her standing at the door of the house looking towards the camera. You can't tell for sure what she'll do next but there's a feeling of foreboding. Beats me why the movie didn't finish the story. Goodwood calls next day only to discover that Isabel has gone straight back to her husband. We are told her friend who has been Ralph's companion has "taught Goodwood how to wait". How long, the reader wonders? Presumably until Osmond dies, but that man I would suspect will outlive everyone and Isabel will never leave him because if she did, she'd betray her own original conceit that she wanted to live an exciting and meaningful life. Basically, Isabel is a silly, self-destructive woman. She could never make any man happy. She needs, it seems, to be bullied.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Atmospheric character drama..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    New Zealand screenwriter and director Jane Campion's fourth feature film is an adaptation of a novel from 1881 written by American writer Henry James (1843-1916). The screenplay for this USA-England co-production which premiered at the 53rd Venice Film Festival in 1996, was written by Australian screenwriter Laura Jones. It tells the story about Isabel Archer, an independent woman from New York who after the death of her father visits her aunt Lydia and her wealthy uncle Daniel Tuchett at his estate near London. During her stay she socializes with an elder woman named Madame Serena Merle and some young men who one by one asks her for her hand in marriage. When Isabel's uncle dies, she inherits large parts of his estate and decides to travel the continent. In Florence she encounters an American expatriate named Gilbert Osmond who charms her with his knowledge and articulacy. Though having declined several proposals of marriage due to her ideals, Isabel agrees to marry Gilbert and starts a new life with him and his young daughter Pansy in Rome. This visually notable and dialog-driven period piece from the mid-1990s which draws ardent milieu depictions, is a detailed study of character about an 18th century feminist protagonist, driven by her personal choices, who seeks out and confronts her destiny while trying to maintain her integrity, but finds herself the victim of a deceitful and manipulative conspiracy. Jane Campion's second adaptation of previously written material is more of an in-depth and atmospheric character drama about a woman who is torn between her values and desires than a passionately romantic love story like "The Piano" (1993). Shot in England, USA, Turkey, Italy and Australia and acutely and distinctly directed by the brilliant filmmaker Jane Campion who has created several remarkable female character portraits since her feature film debut "Sweetie" (1989), this subtly narrated fictional tale is beautifully photographed by English-born New Zealand cinematographer Stuart Dryburgh. This lyrical epic which focuses on themes such as independence, freedom, love and betrayal, is distinguished by the prominent production and costume design by the director's frequent collaborator Janet Patterson and has a fine score by Polish composer Wojciech Kilar which reinforces the shifting atmosphere. Nicole Kidman, John Malkovich and Barbara Hershey delivers fine acting performances in this historical costume drama which gained, among other awards, the Pasinetti Award for Best Film at the 53rd Venice International Film Festival in 1996 and was nominated for Best Supporting Actress Barbara Hershey and Best Costume Design Janet Patterson at the 69th Academy Awards in 1997.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cold film, lacking the novel's passion
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheScholarGypsy
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is well-made, but there is a severity or coldness about it which is false to the temperament of the novel by Henry James on which it is based. Not so much in the portrayal of Gilbert Osmund by John Malkovich (although he brings to it his trademark air of sick malevolence, it seems excessive, not quite in key, even for the evil Gilbert Osmund), but very much so in the manner in which the heroine, Isabel Archer, is represented. In the novel she is a creature of passion; in the film, she is quite rightly adrift (true to the original) but altogether too much in the manner of an iceberg off the English coast rather than as an American "jeune fille" in sunny Italy. What passion she is given has a tortuous, fantastic character, represented by skewed hallucinations rather than by the robust erotic musings of innocent naivet&eacute;. Consequently, the movie ambles along, technically perfect but ultimately boring. Characters who appear to be bored and indifferent to their own lives not surprisingly fail to rouse in the audience any compensating interest. Ironically, it is given to the veteran actor John Gielgud (albeit perhaps unwittingly) to pronounce judgment upon this film in his character's dying scene: as Isabel fixes upon him an intent gaze, rapt with the serious business of grasping to her bosom a pearl of wisdom from this aged man poised on the brink of his ultimate odyssey, Gielgud emits as his final word-to-the-wise an elaborate yawn. In this curious version of James's energetic novel even death is a bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darkly textured, darkly felt...and darkly photographed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    23-year-old American in 1872 England, orphaned and now residing with wealthy relatives, is preyed upon by a fortune hunter who--despite coming up against a determinedly independent lass with a cynical overview of marriage--breaks down the girl's defenses and takes her as his wife; years later, their marriage on the rocks, the woman upsets her husband's plans by interfering in the love-life of her stepdaughter who is being unsuccessfully wooed by a Lord. Director Jane Campion opens this adaptation of Henry James' novel with a collage of modern women's faces, free and forthright and fulfilled, but then hands us a heroine who is duped, abused, and reduced easily to tears. This is not Nicole Kidman's fault, her performance as Isabel Archer is as good as can be expected. Campion fails to reveal any dimensions of this girl, and Isabel's circling conversations with men have a one-note, droning quality which matches Campion's chilly visual style: colorless. Campion's artistic attributes certainly give select sequences a stunning, eerie romantic flavor, but she doesn't do much with the actors (some of whom, Mary Louise Parker and Shelley Duvall in particular, seem woefully out of place). Kidman is under-lit and posed like a porcelain doll (at one point, her grayish pallor perfectly matches that of a pillar just behind her); yet, while these shots are thoughtfully composed, they call attention to themselves in a negative way for an audience very likely to get fed up with such pretensions (especially in a film which is already methodically paced). Ironically, "The Portrait of a Lady" comes mostly to life when dealing with John Malkovich's cunning hubby; the actor has played roles similar to this in the past, but his relish in bringing out the dark side of this tale can clearly be felt. The picture is literate, but almost in an exasperating way; the tastefulness of it as 'art', and the tactfulness of Laura Jones' screenplay, nearly kills off our interest. ** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Biggest Cinematic WTFs I've Ever Experienced
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one can accuse Jane Campion of lack of ambition in bringing Henry James' novel to the screen, but her film is a total disaster. The audacious style that made "The Piano" so compelling and memorable is a Frankenstein's monster here, and it runs away with Campion's film. The result is incomprehensible. Actors are stranded walking around opulent sets saying lines, while Campion pulls out every trick in the book to confounding effect. Though the fact that the film is incoherent probably means that it's a good adaptation, since it was after all based on a novel by Henry James.... Grade: F
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrible bore
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about a wealthy American heiress and her romantic pursuits of varying success in Europe. "The Portrait of a Lady" is immensely dull. The pace is slower than a snail, with many self indulgent artistic shots in between the already very slow plot. To make it even more boring, every character delivers their line in a flat and monotonous way. That may be the way how upper class speaks, but it is terribly dull and emotionless in a film. There is no emotional climax in the film either, everything is just plain and boring. Even the plethora of big stars can do nothing to save this film from being a bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    disappointing mess!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carolyn-epps
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember going to see this movie with a boyfriend back in 1997. I wanted to see this movie because I thought it would be romantic. I practically had to drag my boyfriend to see it with me, he laughed and slept thru most of it, while I tried desperately to understand the plot of the story. Nothing in this movie captured my interest!! I was so disappointed when I left the theater, I was tempted to ask for a refund!!!! I have even thought about renting the movie, if just to see if my understanding of the plot will become clear, but afraid it will only leave me feeling angry and unfulfilled. I can't give this film a good, not even a mediocre rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
