<filme>
 <id>
  1166
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0107447
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1993
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Amor e Restos Humanos
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Set in a dreary urban landscape of an anonymous Canadian city, LOVE AND HUMAN REMAINS is a dark comedy about a group of twentysomethings looking for love and meaning in the '90s. The film ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Set in a dreary urban landscape of an anonymous Canadian city, LOVE AND HUMAN REMAINS is a dark comedy about a group of twentysomethings looking for love and meaning in the '90s. The film focuses on roommates David, a gay waiter who has has given up on his acting career, and Candy, a book reviewer who is also David's ex-lover. David and Candy's lives are entangled with those of David's friends (a busboy, a psychic dominatrix, and a misogynistic civil-servant) and Candy's dates (a male bartender and a lesbian schoolteacher). Meanwhile, a serial killer menaces the concrete and asphalt neighbourhood in which David and Candy live.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   lesbian
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   serial killer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   gay
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   dominatrix
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Denys Arcand
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Brad Fraser
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Thomas Gibson
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ruth Marshall
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Cameron Bancroft
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ahead of it's time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phoenixfyrs
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first watched this movie in a hotel room with my then boyfriend. I looked all over to own a copy of it, and only found it at 1 BB video store in the early 2000s. So I rented it and told them I lost it. I love this movie. I'd really seen nothing like it before. Most of the gay cinema I'd seen was very trite, pretty boys, lots of nudity, bad acting and little plot. The plot of this movie happens while a serial killer is killing off random women. Usually the serial killer would walk into frame and I would say "that's him" or "that's her" but it didn't even occur to me. It isn't that the mystery is so intricate it's that the plot is going off in so many directions that are interesting while also being slightly distracting. It follows a main character but also his friends, who I actually cared about. They aren't 2 dimensional. There is even a young love interest, a 16 y/o boy who's the main characters biggest fan ever, I won't tell you if they get together or not but the thing is, you really don't care. That's how good the movie is. Usually when watching gay cinema everyone who watches including me wants the main character to find love. I didn't care if he did. He had an interesting journey and took me with him and that was satisfying enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like watching nuclear fission
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kitty
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is, as many reviews have observed, a strong dark streak to this movie. The director it most recalls to me is John Landis (yeah, go ahead and howl about what a peasant I am). Arcand has the gift of exploring frivolous things in a bleak, gray kind of way, then turning round and exploring the horrors of life with a lighthearted touch. The cast is, without exception, above average. Thomas Gibson, as David, is outstanding as the moody and self-deceptive center around whom the rest of the characters revolve. He talks a good nihilist, but his actions reflect more love in his character than he is willing to acknowledge. Gibson was already a strong and subtle actor in 1993. It was difficult to look at him and see Greg Montgomery, let alone Agent Hotchner of Criminal Minds. Perhaps not the best scene, but the one I enjoy most, my "rewind scene," is the section where Candy is expecting a visitor, and one uninvited person after another shows up at the door. As Candy's interpersonal environment swings further and further out of control, David just grows bouncier, perkier, and more enthusiastic, like a gaunt Gen-X "Tigger."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolute blunder from Canadian maverick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmCriticLalitRao
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love and human remains directed by Denys Arcand is an abysmally pathetic film as it is completely different from the kind of films he has been making all through his career.Making a different film is not an objectionable matter,what is troublesome is the fact that if a film from a master is complete out of tune then it is a really bad event. The film begins on a good note as there is some suspense created. However as the film progresses what is shown is just a futile attempt at creating something meaningful as Arcand shows us half a dozen oddball,whimsical characters whose lives are intertwined with each other.Homosexuality and Lesbianism are not of any consequences here. What is even more bothersome is the feeling of guilt related to the characters who are rather in a fix regarding their feelings towards each other and sexuality.Such a film would be of interest to some who wants to see a different Denys Arcand film.All in all,there would surely not be many takers for this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    movie dragged, but Ruth Marshall was GREAT!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watched this flick on Saturday afternoon cable. Man, did it drag. I got the metaphors, symbolism, and all that stuff. No, I didn't care one way or another about the sexuality of the characters. But, the pacing of the story and the scripting almost put me to sleep. That is..... until Ruth Marshall got naked. If you're a breast-man who is not homo-phobic, you may want to rent it. Ruth has a lesbian sex scene that's pretty hot, and then a hetero sex scene that is a notch higher than most standard movie fare. Her jiggly D-cups made the film worth the watch. --The Mighty Avatar
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One stupid flick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George Parker
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Love and Human Remains" is one of those obviously scripted, obviously acted, obviously staged flicks which is so obvious that the escape velocity from its contrivances and fabrication is beyond me. Not worth explaining, this amateurish flick tries to cram every clever line, every misanthropic overtone, every peculiar sexual predilection into one film with an absence of concern for making the pieces fit. In short, sensationalistic crap without the sensation...which pretty much just leaves crap.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Thought Provoking and Offbeat Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mitch-38
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Extremely good cinematic story of gay, embittered former teen star, now waiting tables. The sexual ambiguities are explored here realistically, and with an actual human face. This, and throw in a serial killer on the loose, and you have LOVE AND THE HUMAN REMAINS. A well portrayed drama, a strange sense of humor and a mystery. The screenplay is fluid and believable. The performances are well above average, and the twists in the story are sharp. This certainly isn't everyone's ideal notion of a movie, but for those who appreciate something different and slickly written, it's very much worthy of your time. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little off the mark
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Antoine Harris (ccstronger@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie had two great, compelling characters in Candy and David, but it fell flat on its face looking for a plot. The serial killer thing has been explored for ages, and I would have liked to see this movie take another route. Oh well, it's still better than Scream.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my all-time favourite films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    saveespy (saveespy@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2000
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film that I always find myself coming back to every so often. Still, almost a decade since I first saw it, "Love and Human Remains" still has so much to say about men, women, relationships, sexuality and most compellingly in the film, how we as people relate to one another. Perfomances are absolutely incredible and totally convincing. Why I love this film so much is that it shows that, irrespective of one's own sexual orintation, we as people very much share the same experiences and that people shouldn't create 'walls' based on sexuality. We all experience this life. See this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (npollotta@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2000
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quirky, brilliant, twisted, dark, inventive, unnerving. This is a wonderful film, extremely well acted and smoothly directed. Moody and atmospheric, death stalks this mixed assortment of oddball lovers, both inside and out. Yet it is not a bleak tale of destruction, but a story of redemption, survival, and finally love. A great job by everybody involved. Top marks!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I didn't find this to be a comedy, more a tragedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sic Coyote
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2000
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I bought this film from my local blockbuster for 99p an it's been sitting in my video bookcase for at least a year now. Then tonight I decided to see it, the film was quite different to what I had expected and I didn't find any humour in it all I saw was that it was a bleak look at people dealing with love relationships and sexual orientation and I didn't really see the psycho killer plot really having a point except to add tension to the end of the film. I felt that the person playing the lesbian woman did a great job. I was following her emotions and what happened around her. Some people would probably have seen some of the stuff that she does as funny but I could really put myself in her place, loving someone but them rejecting you at every turn no matter how hard you try. I thought it was a very moving film and dealt with all the different sexualities well. I was expecting something like Bound & Gagged : A love story, but this is a very different film. Not for bigots.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ahead of it's time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phoenixfyrs
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first watched this movie in a hotel room with my then boyfriend. I looked all over to own a copy of it, and only found it at 1 BB video store in the early 2000s. So I rented it and told them I lost it. I love this movie. I'd really seen nothing like it before. Most of the gay cinema I'd seen was very trite, pretty boys, lots of nudity, bad acting and little plot. The plot of this movie happens while a serial killer is killing off random women. Usually the serial killer would walk into frame and I would say "that's him" or "that's her" but it didn't even occur to me. It isn't that the mystery is so intricate it's that the plot is going off in so many directions that are interesting while also being slightly distracting. It follows a main character but also his friends, who I actually cared about. They aren't 2 dimensional. There is even a young love interest, a 16 y/o boy who's the main characters biggest fan ever, I won't tell you if they get together or not but the thing is, you really don't care. That's how good the movie is. Usually when watching gay cinema everyone who watches including me wants the main character to find love. I didn't care if he did. He had an interesting journey and took me with him and that was satisfying enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like watching nuclear fission
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kitty
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is, as many reviews have observed, a strong dark streak to this movie. The director it most recalls to me is John Landis (yeah, go ahead and howl about what a peasant I am). Arcand has the gift of exploring frivolous things in a bleak, gray kind of way, then turning round and exploring the horrors of life with a lighthearted touch. The cast is, without exception, above average. Thomas Gibson, as David, is outstanding as the moody and self-deceptive center around whom the rest of the characters revolve. He talks a good nihilist, but his actions reflect more love in his character than he is willing to acknowledge. Gibson was already a strong and subtle actor in 1993. It was difficult to look at him and see Greg Montgomery, let alone Agent Hotchner of Criminal Minds. Perhaps not the best scene, but the one I enjoy most, my "rewind scene," is the section where Candy is expecting a visitor, and one uninvited person after another shows up at the door. As Candy's interpersonal environment swings further and further out of control, David just grows bouncier, perkier, and more enthusiastic, like a gaunt Gen-X "Tigger."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolute blunder from Canadian maverick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmCriticLalitRao
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love and human remains directed by Denys Arcand is an abysmally pathetic film as it is completely different from the kind of films he has been making all through his career.Making a different film is not an objectionable matter,what is troublesome is the fact that if a film from a master is complete out of tune then it is a really bad event. The film begins on a good note as there is some suspense created. However as the film progresses what is shown is just a futile attempt at creating something meaningful as Arcand shows us half a dozen oddball,whimsical characters whose lives are intertwined with each other.Homosexuality and Lesbianism are not of any consequences here. What is even more bothersome is the feeling of guilt related to the characters who are rather in a fix regarding their feelings towards each other and sexuality.Such a film would be of interest to some who wants to see a different Denys Arcand film.All in all,there would surely not be many takers for this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    movie dragged, but Ruth Marshall was GREAT!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watched this flick on Saturday afternoon cable. Man, did it drag. I got the metaphors, symbolism, and all that stuff. No, I didn't care one way or another about the sexuality of the characters. But, the pacing of the story and the scripting almost put me to sleep. That is..... until Ruth Marshall got naked. If you're a breast-man who is not homo-phobic, you may want to rent it. Ruth has a lesbian sex scene that's pretty hot, and then a hetero sex scene that is a notch higher than most standard movie fare. Her jiggly D-cups made the film worth the watch. --The Mighty Avatar
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One stupid flick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George Parker
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Love and Human Remains" is one of those obviously scripted, obviously acted, obviously staged flicks which is so obvious that the escape velocity from its contrivances and fabrication is beyond me. Not worth explaining, this amateurish flick tries to cram every clever line, every misanthropic overtone, every peculiar sexual predilection into one film with an absence of concern for making the pieces fit. In short, sensationalistic crap without the sensation...which pretty much just leaves crap.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Thought Provoking and Offbeat Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mitch-38
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Extremely good cinematic story of gay, embittered former teen star, now waiting tables. The sexual ambiguities are explored here realistically, and with an actual human face. This, and throw in a serial killer on the loose, and you have LOVE AND THE HUMAN REMAINS. A well portrayed drama, a strange sense of humor and a mystery. The screenplay is fluid and believable. The performances are well above average, and the twists in the story are sharp. This certainly isn't everyone's ideal notion of a movie, but for those who appreciate something different and slickly written, it's very much worthy of your time. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little off the mark
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Antoine Harris (ccstronger@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie had two great, compelling characters in Candy and David, but it fell flat on its face looking for a plot. The serial killer thing has been explored for ages, and I would have liked to see this movie take another route. Oh well, it's still better than Scream.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my all-time favourite films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    saveespy (saveespy@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2000
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film that I always find myself coming back to every so often. Still, almost a decade since I first saw it, "Love and Human Remains" still has so much to say about men, women, relationships, sexuality and most compellingly in the film, how we as people relate to one another. Perfomances are absolutely incredible and totally convincing. Why I love this film so much is that it shows that, irrespective of one's own sexual orintation, we as people very much share the same experiences and that people shouldn't create 'walls' based on sexuality. We all experience this life. See this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (npollotta@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2000
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quirky, brilliant, twisted, dark, inventive, unnerving. This is a wonderful film, extremely well acted and smoothly directed. Moody and atmospheric, death stalks this mixed assortment of oddball lovers, both inside and out. Yet it is not a bleak tale of destruction, but a story of redemption, survival, and finally love. A great job by everybody involved. Top marks!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I didn't find this to be a comedy, more a tragedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sic Coyote
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2000
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I bought this film from my local blockbuster for 99p an it's been sitting in my video bookcase for at least a year now. Then tonight I decided to see it, the film was quite different to what I had expected and I didn't find any humour in it all I saw was that it was a bleak look at people dealing with love relationships and sexual orientation and I didn't really see the psycho killer plot really having a point except to add tension to the end of the film. I felt that the person playing the lesbian woman did a great job. I was following her emotions and what happened around her. Some people would probably have seen some of the stuff that she does as funny but I could really put myself in her place, loving someone but them rejecting you at every turn no matter how hard you try. I thought it was a very moving film and dealt with all the different sexualities well. I was expecting something like Bound & Gagged : A love story, but this is a very different film. Not for bigots.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
