<filme>
 <id>
  1169
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109842
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Fresh
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Michael (or Fresh as he's well known) is a 12-year-old drug pusher who lives in a crowded housing project with his cousins and aunt. His father has become a street bum, but still meets with... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Michael (or Fresh as he's well known) is a 12-year-old drug pusher who lives in a crowded housing project with his cousins and aunt. His father has become a street bum, but still meets with Fresh on occasion to play chess. Fresh is rather quiet in a crazy world. Fresh's sister is a junkie who sleeps with the dealers who Fresh sells for. As the story progresses Fresh realizes that he doesn't want to sell drugs anymore, he wants out.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   drugs
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   chess
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   drug pusher
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   drug courier
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   extended family
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Boaz Yakin
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Boaz Yakin
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Sean Nelson
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Giancarlo Esposito
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Samuel L. Jackson
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unusual
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ctomvelu1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This slice of ghetto life is like nothing else I ave seen. A young drug runner decides he wants out of the life. He also wants to save his sister, who has taken up with one of the kid's drug kingpins. In order to get out, he has to do some pretty fancy footwork. But he is a master strategist as we see when he plays chess with his dad. Wonderful location photography and acting, with a large cast of mostly unknown actors except for Sam Jackson as the dad and Giancarlo Esposito as the drug kingpin. The plot doesn't necessarily go in the direction you might think. There is a fair amount of violence, but most of it is off camera or quickly cut away from.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    R Bruce Hudson
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While learning chess against his expert player dad, Fresh also learns how to play for life. Another brilliant basketball playing kid, is deliberately fouled by a thug, a hood. To get back, he dazzles that hood - embarrassing him. The enraged hood goes gets a gun, and shoots him dead. Collateral damage is a sweet innocent girl who's character has been built sufficiently, just so we know that Fresh has a soft spot for her. A dogfight build's Fresh's character more - we know he has sound morals but gets swept along to the dog fight anyway. We know that Fresh is troubled. We then weave through the movie like a game of chess, where pieces are sacrificed for the final victory. There are lessons through out, metaphors and texture for anyone who cares to look. Thoroughly enjoyed it. Gave it an 8 out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Best Films Ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    McCamyTaylor
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie for about the twentieth time. It never fails to astound me and make me cry. This film is the perfect mix of cerebral and tear jerker. Even when you know what is going to happen, you have to watch and be amazed at the 1) writer who came up with this 2) the actors who play the characters, especially the boy, Michael. It is very, very close to being as good as my other favorite crime drama, "LA Confidential". Solid editing and score, too. Just be sure to pay close attention, or the plot, with its many twists and turns will lose you, and the second half of the film will make absolutely no sense. The moral---if you are too attached, you can not save those things that you truly value---may throw some folks in the U.S. who are used to good versus evil themes. Thematically, this movie is a lot like another done by the same director, "A Price Above Rubies."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent cross of "hood" movie and thriller with great delivery across acting, score, cinematography and direction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you will allow me a personal moment, Fresh was one of the films that I saw at a time when I was really in love with film. I had just moved to England in 1995 and had gone from being a 20 minute drive to a small multiplex chain cinema, to being a 5 minute walk away from the Light House independent cinema in Wolverhampton. Not only was it close but it was cheap and I would regularly go there to see films big and small. I was lucky because this rough period was throwing up things like Usual Suspects, Pulp Fiction and many other really strong films. Fresh was one of these and I remembered thinking it was great but, not having seen it since, I wasn't sure if maybe the period in my life was also giving it a rose-tinted memory in my head. I watched it again last night and did so as a different person  35 instead of 18, living comfortably instead of a struggling student; regardless of time and place though, the film still gripped me from start to finish and justifies my memory of it being an excellent film. The plot starts out as a "ghetto" film that fits into the genre of the early 90's (Menace II Society, Boyz n the Hood etc) but then in the middle it becomes much more of a thriller where young Fresh tries to turn the table on his dealing employers in revenge for the murder of one of his friends. Both parts of the film work equally well and merge into each other seamlessly. Just like the construction of the city environment in the opening titles, the film builds on the details and at times the viewer will be a few steps behind Fresh in terms of his plan. It is a dangerous game and there are quite brutal moments in it, but these just help up the tension, of which there is lots. Yakin directs really well throughout the film and is aided by excellent cinematography, capturing a sense of place really well. The patient orchestral score also fits with this and the slower pace that it can at times have, however all of these qualities (however good they are) tend to get lost in the background of the praise because front and centre is a terrific performance from a very young Sean Nelson. He is the heart of the film and the ability to deliver his character is key  and he nails it. Fresh isn't on a moral quest for what is right, he is very much on a personal mission and he does it by playing cynically with those around him, making sacrifices of both himself and of them. It is a great performance throughout and it is hard to imagine anyone else but him in that role  perfect bit of casting. That he stands up on his own with such a strong support cast is also impressive. Esposito is great despite hamming up his accent and his abs a little bit  amusing to watch this character back through the filter of Breaking Bad as well! Jackson was pushing to the front on the DVD cover due to Pulp Fiction's success, but he is only in a small role, albeit a good one. Beyond them La Marre, Brice, Wright and others are also good. Almost twenty years old, Fresh is an excellent film that is well made across the board as both a hood movie and a thriller  my memory was not faded, this is a great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good ghetto film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gangstahippie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fresh was one of the many urban ghetto films which came out in the 90's, around the same time gangsta rap was at it's peak.Films like Boyz N The Hood, Menace 2 Society & this film showed the dangers of urban life, while other films such as Friday showed that it could be fun.If you dislike these types of movies, you may still like fresh.It is actually a fairly smart film with a good storyline, acting and some funny moments as well.The film is centred around a young twelve year old drug dealer and his relationships with the dealers he works for.He is actually a very smart and calculating child and hatches a plan to end all the drug dealers in the neighbourhood.The score by Stu Copeland is great, however they could have incorporated some early 90's hip-hop/rap in the film.Some may like it better if it didn't but I find that it adds to the whole feel of the film.Anyway, if you like urban ghetto films, you owe it to yourself to watch Fresh, it is probably one of the better ones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Crime/Chess Film of All-Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thelockbox
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was excellent. The score well-used. It's well-acted, greatly written and executed, and it manages to capture a lot of nuances of childhood and children's behavior. The movie follows Fresh, a drug runner for two different major pushers in his hood. After a series of events he makes the decision to play the pushers as he would an opponent in chess. As the game of chess plays out over the last 15 minutes, the suspense grips you. The film guest stars Samuel L. Jackson as the absentee, alcoholic father of Fresh who is a great source for chess strategy, but not for compassion or love. The star of the film is the 12 year old (at the time) Sean Nelson, who does a fabulous job in the title role as Fresh. This movie makes Boys in the Hood, and Menace II Society look low-rate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Blaxploitation At Its Worst
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    luvley238
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This had to be one of the worst written movies i've ever seen. I am highly insulted by the ridiculous/fake dialogue. These people are supposed to be in New York. The sad attempt at 'ghetto slang,' and so-called realistic portrayal of 'life on the streets' makes my stomach turn. I am from the Bronx. Most of my family is from NYC. And my childhood/adolescence took part in the Bronx in the early 90s. As a black person I am offended. This movie is a prime example of why movies like 'Hollywood Shuffle' were created--to exploit offensive movies like this. I'm so tired of movies trying to normalize this type of sick behavior. this is where stereotypes come from. And if you believe the lifestyles presented in this movie are realistic scenarios, you're an idiot. Get over it. and by the way, the plot sucked. I'd have to write another post to address that... oh, and that little Spanish kid--"She be likin you Homes...I'm kickin the stupid dope moves"?!? what the heck?!? are they in fake south central or fake new york? No one talks like that. seriously, homes. everyone sucked--from sam jackson to fresh to his crack-ho sister. they can't possibly be proud of this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How is this movie not in the top 250?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    supra926hp
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I almost never review movies but after watching Fresh I felt compelled to. From the beginning of the movie my eyes were glued to the screen. I though it was just another "hood" movie but it turned out to be deeply complex. All I really want to say is that Fresh struck a cord for me on many levels. Its a coming of age story like no other, he goes through school, crushes, friends, fights, and his parents but set in the projects where violence and drugs are a commonplace. In fact, it would be an insult to pigeon-hole this movie into one genre it is one of the best dramas and action movies I have ever seen. The final scene was such a devastating moment and I'll admit I started weeping. Rarely do I cry because of a movie and even rarer will I admit to it. Go see this movie, you won't regret it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    supersam032
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The modern day "Through the Looking Glass". Enough said. But because of requirements here is a bit more. I caught this movie midway through in the middle of the night on one of the movie channels. I was intrigued by the honesty of the characters, the lines, and the idea of Samuel L. Jackson in a cameo. Fresh, as he is known, is a boy dealing with the harsh realities of inner city life and a broken family but rises above his circumstances although he is walking in them. This movie is a drama and a thriller. Just a heads up- there is a lot of brash language and situations but none gratuitous and no glamorization of crime. I found it to be a deep, thoughtful, heart-wrenching tale of the realities of life's circumstances and how one little hero overcame through the wisdom of chess.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I have seen the movie before BUT NOT LIKE THIS
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dasked (hvorfor@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hi all. I have seen this movie before and it didn't touch me then. Now 10 years after, much have happened in my life. Now I was touched all the way into my bones. What a movie. So real. So cruel. So a world of drugs and feelings blended to, much death and some hope. A hope so strong that nothing breaks through. Like life. A road is to be decided. You, other decide. All life will be affected by your choices. This movie contains 2 well known highways along your journey of decisions. Thanks for a great experience on my journey around. D. Severinsen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unusual
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ctomvelu1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This slice of ghetto life is like nothing else I ave seen. A young drug runner decides he wants out of the life. He also wants to save his sister, who has taken up with one of the kid's drug kingpins. In order to get out, he has to do some pretty fancy footwork. But he is a master strategist as we see when he plays chess with his dad. Wonderful location photography and acting, with a large cast of mostly unknown actors except for Sam Jackson as the dad and Giancarlo Esposito as the drug kingpin. The plot doesn't necessarily go in the direction you might think. There is a fair amount of violence, but most of it is off camera or quickly cut away from.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    R Bruce Hudson
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While learning chess against his expert player dad, Fresh also learns how to play for life. Another brilliant basketball playing kid, is deliberately fouled by a thug, a hood. To get back, he dazzles that hood - embarrassing him. The enraged hood goes gets a gun, and shoots him dead. Collateral damage is a sweet innocent girl who's character has been built sufficiently, just so we know that Fresh has a soft spot for her. A dogfight build's Fresh's character more - we know he has sound morals but gets swept along to the dog fight anyway. We know that Fresh is troubled. We then weave through the movie like a game of chess, where pieces are sacrificed for the final victory. There are lessons through out, metaphors and texture for anyone who cares to look. Thoroughly enjoyed it. Gave it an 8 out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Best Films Ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    McCamyTaylor
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie for about the twentieth time. It never fails to astound me and make me cry. This film is the perfect mix of cerebral and tear jerker. Even when you know what is going to happen, you have to watch and be amazed at the 1) writer who came up with this 2) the actors who play the characters, especially the boy, Michael. It is very, very close to being as good as my other favorite crime drama, "LA Confidential". Solid editing and score, too. Just be sure to pay close attention, or the plot, with its many twists and turns will lose you, and the second half of the film will make absolutely no sense. The moral---if you are too attached, you can not save those things that you truly value---may throw some folks in the U.S. who are used to good versus evil themes. Thematically, this movie is a lot like another done by the same director, "A Price Above Rubies."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent cross of "hood" movie and thriller with great delivery across acting, score, cinematography and direction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you will allow me a personal moment, Fresh was one of the films that I saw at a time when I was really in love with film. I had just moved to England in 1995 and had gone from being a 20 minute drive to a small multiplex chain cinema, to being a 5 minute walk away from the Light House independent cinema in Wolverhampton. Not only was it close but it was cheap and I would regularly go there to see films big and small. I was lucky because this rough period was throwing up things like Usual Suspects, Pulp Fiction and many other really strong films. Fresh was one of these and I remembered thinking it was great but, not having seen it since, I wasn't sure if maybe the period in my life was also giving it a rose-tinted memory in my head. I watched it again last night and did so as a different person  35 instead of 18, living comfortably instead of a struggling student; regardless of time and place though, the film still gripped me from start to finish and justifies my memory of it being an excellent film. The plot starts out as a "ghetto" film that fits into the genre of the early 90's (Menace II Society, Boyz n the Hood etc) but then in the middle it becomes much more of a thriller where young Fresh tries to turn the table on his dealing employers in revenge for the murder of one of his friends. Both parts of the film work equally well and merge into each other seamlessly. Just like the construction of the city environment in the opening titles, the film builds on the details and at times the viewer will be a few steps behind Fresh in terms of his plan. It is a dangerous game and there are quite brutal moments in it, but these just help up the tension, of which there is lots. Yakin directs really well throughout the film and is aided by excellent cinematography, capturing a sense of place really well. The patient orchestral score also fits with this and the slower pace that it can at times have, however all of these qualities (however good they are) tend to get lost in the background of the praise because front and centre is a terrific performance from a very young Sean Nelson. He is the heart of the film and the ability to deliver his character is key  and he nails it. Fresh isn't on a moral quest for what is right, he is very much on a personal mission and he does it by playing cynically with those around him, making sacrifices of both himself and of them. It is a great performance throughout and it is hard to imagine anyone else but him in that role  perfect bit of casting. That he stands up on his own with such a strong support cast is also impressive. Esposito is great despite hamming up his accent and his abs a little bit  amusing to watch this character back through the filter of Breaking Bad as well! Jackson was pushing to the front on the DVD cover due to Pulp Fiction's success, but he is only in a small role, albeit a good one. Beyond them La Marre, Brice, Wright and others are also good. Almost twenty years old, Fresh is an excellent film that is well made across the board as both a hood movie and a thriller  my memory was not faded, this is a great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good ghetto film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gangstahippie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fresh was one of the many urban ghetto films which came out in the 90's, around the same time gangsta rap was at it's peak.Films like Boyz N The Hood, Menace 2 Society & this film showed the dangers of urban life, while other films such as Friday showed that it could be fun.If you dislike these types of movies, you may still like fresh.It is actually a fairly smart film with a good storyline, acting and some funny moments as well.The film is centred around a young twelve year old drug dealer and his relationships with the dealers he works for.He is actually a very smart and calculating child and hatches a plan to end all the drug dealers in the neighbourhood.The score by Stu Copeland is great, however they could have incorporated some early 90's hip-hop/rap in the film.Some may like it better if it didn't but I find that it adds to the whole feel of the film.Anyway, if you like urban ghetto films, you owe it to yourself to watch Fresh, it is probably one of the better ones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Crime/Chess Film of All-Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thelockbox
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was excellent. The score well-used. It's well-acted, greatly written and executed, and it manages to capture a lot of nuances of childhood and children's behavior. The movie follows Fresh, a drug runner for two different major pushers in his hood. After a series of events he makes the decision to play the pushers as he would an opponent in chess. As the game of chess plays out over the last 15 minutes, the suspense grips you. The film guest stars Samuel L. Jackson as the absentee, alcoholic father of Fresh who is a great source for chess strategy, but not for compassion or love. The star of the film is the 12 year old (at the time) Sean Nelson, who does a fabulous job in the title role as Fresh. This movie makes Boys in the Hood, and Menace II Society look low-rate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Blaxploitation At Its Worst
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    luvley238
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This had to be one of the worst written movies i've ever seen. I am highly insulted by the ridiculous/fake dialogue. These people are supposed to be in New York. The sad attempt at 'ghetto slang,' and so-called realistic portrayal of 'life on the streets' makes my stomach turn. I am from the Bronx. Most of my family is from NYC. And my childhood/adolescence took part in the Bronx in the early 90s. As a black person I am offended. This movie is a prime example of why movies like 'Hollywood Shuffle' were created--to exploit offensive movies like this. I'm so tired of movies trying to normalize this type of sick behavior. this is where stereotypes come from. And if you believe the lifestyles presented in this movie are realistic scenarios, you're an idiot. Get over it. and by the way, the plot sucked. I'd have to write another post to address that... oh, and that little Spanish kid--"She be likin you Homes...I'm kickin the stupid dope moves"?!? what the heck?!? are they in fake south central or fake new york? No one talks like that. seriously, homes. everyone sucked--from sam jackson to fresh to his crack-ho sister. they can't possibly be proud of this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How is this movie not in the top 250?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    supra926hp
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I almost never review movies but after watching Fresh I felt compelled to. From the beginning of the movie my eyes were glued to the screen. I though it was just another "hood" movie but it turned out to be deeply complex. All I really want to say is that Fresh struck a cord for me on many levels. Its a coming of age story like no other, he goes through school, crushes, friends, fights, and his parents but set in the projects where violence and drugs are a commonplace. In fact, it would be an insult to pigeon-hole this movie into one genre it is one of the best dramas and action movies I have ever seen. The final scene was such a devastating moment and I'll admit I started weeping. Rarely do I cry because of a movie and even rarer will I admit to it. Go see this movie, you won't regret it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    supersam032
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The modern day "Through the Looking Glass". Enough said. But because of requirements here is a bit more. I caught this movie midway through in the middle of the night on one of the movie channels. I was intrigued by the honesty of the characters, the lines, and the idea of Samuel L. Jackson in a cameo. Fresh, as he is known, is a boy dealing with the harsh realities of inner city life and a broken family but rises above his circumstances although he is walking in them. This movie is a drama and a thriller. Just a heads up- there is a lot of brash language and situations but none gratuitous and no glamorization of crime. I found it to be a deep, thoughtful, heart-wrenching tale of the realities of life's circumstances and how one little hero overcame through the wisdom of chess.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I have seen the movie before BUT NOT LIKE THIS
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dasked (hvorfor@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hi all. I have seen this movie before and it didn't touch me then. Now 10 years after, much have happened in my life. Now I was touched all the way into my bones. What a movie. So real. So cruel. So a world of drugs and feelings blended to, much death and some hope. A hope so strong that nothing breaks through. Like life. A road is to be decided. You, other decide. All life will be affected by your choices. This movie contains 2 well known highways along your journey of decisions. Thanks for a great experience on my journey around. D. Severinsen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unusual
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ctomvelu1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This slice of ghetto life is like nothing else I ave seen. A young drug runner decides he wants out of the life. He also wants to save his sister, who has taken up with one of the kid's drug kingpins. In order to get out, he has to do some pretty fancy footwork. But he is a master strategist as we see when he plays chess with his dad. Wonderful location photography and acting, with a large cast of mostly unknown actors except for Sam Jackson as the dad and Giancarlo Esposito as the drug kingpin. The plot doesn't necessarily go in the direction you might think. There is a fair amount of violence, but most of it is off camera or quickly cut away from.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    R Bruce Hudson
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While learning chess against his expert player dad, Fresh also learns how to play for life. Another brilliant basketball playing kid, is deliberately fouled by a thug, a hood. To get back, he dazzles that hood - embarrassing him. The enraged hood goes gets a gun, and shoots him dead. Collateral damage is a sweet innocent girl who's character has been built sufficiently, just so we know that Fresh has a soft spot for her. A dogfight build's Fresh's character more - we know he has sound morals but gets swept along to the dog fight anyway. We know that Fresh is troubled. We then weave through the movie like a game of chess, where pieces are sacrificed for the final victory. There are lessons through out, metaphors and texture for anyone who cares to look. Thoroughly enjoyed it. Gave it an 8 out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Best Films Ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    McCamyTaylor
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie for about the twentieth time. It never fails to astound me and make me cry. This film is the perfect mix of cerebral and tear jerker. Even when you know what is going to happen, you have to watch and be amazed at the 1) writer who came up with this 2) the actors who play the characters, especially the boy, Michael. It is very, very close to being as good as my other favorite crime drama, "LA Confidential". Solid editing and score, too. Just be sure to pay close attention, or the plot, with its many twists and turns will lose you, and the second half of the film will make absolutely no sense. The moral---if you are too attached, you can not save those things that you truly value---may throw some folks in the U.S. who are used to good versus evil themes. Thematically, this movie is a lot like another done by the same director, "A Price Above Rubies."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent cross of "hood" movie and thriller with great delivery across acting, score, cinematography and direction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you will allow me a personal moment, Fresh was one of the films that I saw at a time when I was really in love with film. I had just moved to England in 1995 and had gone from being a 20 minute drive to a small multiplex chain cinema, to being a 5 minute walk away from the Light House independent cinema in Wolverhampton. Not only was it close but it was cheap and I would regularly go there to see films big and small. I was lucky because this rough period was throwing up things like Usual Suspects, Pulp Fiction and many other really strong films. Fresh was one of these and I remembered thinking it was great but, not having seen it since, I wasn't sure if maybe the period in my life was also giving it a rose-tinted memory in my head. I watched it again last night and did so as a different person  35 instead of 18, living comfortably instead of a struggling student; regardless of time and place though, the film still gripped me from start to finish and justifies my memory of it being an excellent film. The plot starts out as a "ghetto" film that fits into the genre of the early 90's (Menace II Society, Boyz n the Hood etc) but then in the middle it becomes much more of a thriller where young Fresh tries to turn the table on his dealing employers in revenge for the murder of one of his friends. Both parts of the film work equally well and merge into each other seamlessly. Just like the construction of the city environment in the opening titles, the film builds on the details and at times the viewer will be a few steps behind Fresh in terms of his plan. It is a dangerous game and there are quite brutal moments in it, but these just help up the tension, of which there is lots. Yakin directs really well throughout the film and is aided by excellent cinematography, capturing a sense of place really well. The patient orchestral score also fits with this and the slower pace that it can at times have, however all of these qualities (however good they are) tend to get lost in the background of the praise because front and centre is a terrific performance from a very young Sean Nelson. He is the heart of the film and the ability to deliver his character is key  and he nails it. Fresh isn't on a moral quest for what is right, he is very much on a personal mission and he does it by playing cynically with those around him, making sacrifices of both himself and of them. It is a great performance throughout and it is hard to imagine anyone else but him in that role  perfect bit of casting. That he stands up on his own with such a strong support cast is also impressive. Esposito is great despite hamming up his accent and his abs a little bit  amusing to watch this character back through the filter of Breaking Bad as well! Jackson was pushing to the front on the DVD cover due to Pulp Fiction's success, but he is only in a small role, albeit a good one. Beyond them La Marre, Brice, Wright and others are also good. Almost twenty years old, Fresh is an excellent film that is well made across the board as both a hood movie and a thriller  my memory was not faded, this is a great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good ghetto film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gangstahippie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fresh was one of the many urban ghetto films which came out in the 90's, around the same time gangsta rap was at it's peak.Films like Boyz N The Hood, Menace 2 Society & this film showed the dangers of urban life, while other films such as Friday showed that it could be fun.If you dislike these types of movies, you may still like fresh.It is actually a fairly smart film with a good storyline, acting and some funny moments as well.The film is centred around a young twelve year old drug dealer and his relationships with the dealers he works for.He is actually a very smart and calculating child and hatches a plan to end all the drug dealers in the neighbourhood.The score by Stu Copeland is great, however they could have incorporated some early 90's hip-hop/rap in the film.Some may like it better if it didn't but I find that it adds to the whole feel of the film.Anyway, if you like urban ghetto films, you owe it to yourself to watch Fresh, it is probably one of the better ones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Crime/Chess Film of All-Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thelockbox
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was excellent. The score well-used. It's well-acted, greatly written and executed, and it manages to capture a lot of nuances of childhood and children's behavior. The movie follows Fresh, a drug runner for two different major pushers in his hood. After a series of events he makes the decision to play the pushers as he would an opponent in chess. As the game of chess plays out over the last 15 minutes, the suspense grips you. The film guest stars Samuel L. Jackson as the absentee, alcoholic father of Fresh who is a great source for chess strategy, but not for compassion or love. The star of the film is the 12 year old (at the time) Sean Nelson, who does a fabulous job in the title role as Fresh. This movie makes Boys in the Hood, and Menace II Society look low-rate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Blaxploitation At Its Worst
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    luvley238
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This had to be one of the worst written movies i've ever seen. I am highly insulted by the ridiculous/fake dialogue. These people are supposed to be in New York. The sad attempt at 'ghetto slang,' and so-called realistic portrayal of 'life on the streets' makes my stomach turn. I am from the Bronx. Most of my family is from NYC. And my childhood/adolescence took part in the Bronx in the early 90s. As a black person I am offended. This movie is a prime example of why movies like 'Hollywood Shuffle' were created--to exploit offensive movies like this. I'm so tired of movies trying to normalize this type of sick behavior. this is where stereotypes come from. And if you believe the lifestyles presented in this movie are realistic scenarios, you're an idiot. Get over it. and by the way, the plot sucked. I'd have to write another post to address that... oh, and that little Spanish kid--"She be likin you Homes...I'm kickin the stupid dope moves"?!? what the heck?!? are they in fake south central or fake new york? No one talks like that. seriously, homes. everyone sucked--from sam jackson to fresh to his crack-ho sister. they can't possibly be proud of this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How is this movie not in the top 250?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    supra926hp
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I almost never review movies but after watching Fresh I felt compelled to. From the beginning of the movie my eyes were glued to the screen. I though it was just another "hood" movie but it turned out to be deeply complex. All I really want to say is that Fresh struck a cord for me on many levels. Its a coming of age story like no other, he goes through school, crushes, friends, fights, and his parents but set in the projects where violence and drugs are a commonplace. In fact, it would be an insult to pigeon-hole this movie into one genre it is one of the best dramas and action movies I have ever seen. The final scene was such a devastating moment and I'll admit I started weeping. Rarely do I cry because of a movie and even rarer will I admit to it. Go see this movie, you won't regret it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    supersam032
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The modern day "Through the Looking Glass". Enough said. But because of requirements here is a bit more. I caught this movie midway through in the middle of the night on one of the movie channels. I was intrigued by the honesty of the characters, the lines, and the idea of Samuel L. Jackson in a cameo. Fresh, as he is known, is a boy dealing with the harsh realities of inner city life and a broken family but rises above his circumstances although he is walking in them. This movie is a drama and a thriller. Just a heads up- there is a lot of brash language and situations but none gratuitous and no glamorization of crime. I found it to be a deep, thoughtful, heart-wrenching tale of the realities of life's circumstances and how one little hero overcame through the wisdom of chess.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I have seen the movie before BUT NOT LIKE THIS
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dasked (hvorfor@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hi all. I have seen this movie before and it didn't touch me then. Now 10 years after, much have happened in my life. Now I was touched all the way into my bones. What a movie. So real. So cruel. So a world of drugs and feelings blended to, much death and some hope. A hope so strong that nothing breaks through. Like life. A road is to be decided. You, other decide. All life will be affected by your choices. This movie contains 2 well known highways along your journey of decisions. Thanks for a great experience on my journey around. D. Severinsen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unusual
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ctomvelu1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This slice of ghetto life is like nothing else I ave seen. A young drug runner decides he wants out of the life. He also wants to save his sister, who has taken up with one of the kid's drug kingpins. In order to get out, he has to do some pretty fancy footwork. But he is a master strategist as we see when he plays chess with his dad. Wonderful location photography and acting, with a large cast of mostly unknown actors except for Sam Jackson as the dad and Giancarlo Esposito as the drug kingpin. The plot doesn't necessarily go in the direction you might think. There is a fair amount of violence, but most of it is off camera or quickly cut away from.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    R Bruce Hudson
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While learning chess against his expert player dad, Fresh also learns how to play for life. Another brilliant basketball playing kid, is deliberately fouled by a thug, a hood. To get back, he dazzles that hood - embarrassing him. The enraged hood goes gets a gun, and shoots him dead. Collateral damage is a sweet innocent girl who's character has been built sufficiently, just so we know that Fresh has a soft spot for her. A dogfight build's Fresh's character more - we know he has sound morals but gets swept along to the dog fight anyway. We know that Fresh is troubled. We then weave through the movie like a game of chess, where pieces are sacrificed for the final victory. There are lessons through out, metaphors and texture for anyone who cares to look. Thoroughly enjoyed it. Gave it an 8 out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Best Films Ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    McCamyTaylor
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie for about the twentieth time. It never fails to astound me and make me cry. This film is the perfect mix of cerebral and tear jerker. Even when you know what is going to happen, you have to watch and be amazed at the 1) writer who came up with this 2) the actors who play the characters, especially the boy, Michael. It is very, very close to being as good as my other favorite crime drama, "LA Confidential". Solid editing and score, too. Just be sure to pay close attention, or the plot, with its many twists and turns will lose you, and the second half of the film will make absolutely no sense. The moral---if you are too attached, you can not save those things that you truly value---may throw some folks in the U.S. who are used to good versus evil themes. Thematically, this movie is a lot like another done by the same director, "A Price Above Rubies."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent cross of "hood" movie and thriller with great delivery across acting, score, cinematography and direction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you will allow me a personal moment, Fresh was one of the films that I saw at a time when I was really in love with film. I had just moved to England in 1995 and had gone from being a 20 minute drive to a small multiplex chain cinema, to being a 5 minute walk away from the Light House independent cinema in Wolverhampton. Not only was it close but it was cheap and I would regularly go there to see films big and small. I was lucky because this rough period was throwing up things like Usual Suspects, Pulp Fiction and many other really strong films. Fresh was one of these and I remembered thinking it was great but, not having seen it since, I wasn't sure if maybe the period in my life was also giving it a rose-tinted memory in my head. I watched it again last night and did so as a different person  35 instead of 18, living comfortably instead of a struggling student; regardless of time and place though, the film still gripped me from start to finish and justifies my memory of it being an excellent film. The plot starts out as a "ghetto" film that fits into the genre of the early 90's (Menace II Society, Boyz n the Hood etc) but then in the middle it becomes much more of a thriller where young Fresh tries to turn the table on his dealing employers in revenge for the murder of one of his friends. Both parts of the film work equally well and merge into each other seamlessly. Just like the construction of the city environment in the opening titles, the film builds on the details and at times the viewer will be a few steps behind Fresh in terms of his plan. It is a dangerous game and there are quite brutal moments in it, but these just help up the tension, of which there is lots. Yakin directs really well throughout the film and is aided by excellent cinematography, capturing a sense of place really well. The patient orchestral score also fits with this and the slower pace that it can at times have, however all of these qualities (however good they are) tend to get lost in the background of the praise because front and centre is a terrific performance from a very young Sean Nelson. He is the heart of the film and the ability to deliver his character is key  and he nails it. Fresh isn't on a moral quest for what is right, he is very much on a personal mission and he does it by playing cynically with those around him, making sacrifices of both himself and of them. It is a great performance throughout and it is hard to imagine anyone else but him in that role  perfect bit of casting. That he stands up on his own with such a strong support cast is also impressive. Esposito is great despite hamming up his accent and his abs a little bit  amusing to watch this character back through the filter of Breaking Bad as well! Jackson was pushing to the front on the DVD cover due to Pulp Fiction's success, but he is only in a small role, albeit a good one. Beyond them La Marre, Brice, Wright and others are also good. Almost twenty years old, Fresh is an excellent film that is well made across the board as both a hood movie and a thriller  my memory was not faded, this is a great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good ghetto film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gangstahippie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fresh was one of the many urban ghetto films which came out in the 90's, around the same time gangsta rap was at it's peak.Films like Boyz N The Hood, Menace 2 Society & this film showed the dangers of urban life, while other films such as Friday showed that it could be fun.If you dislike these types of movies, you may still like fresh.It is actually a fairly smart film with a good storyline, acting and some funny moments as well.The film is centred around a young twelve year old drug dealer and his relationships with the dealers he works for.He is actually a very smart and calculating child and hatches a plan to end all the drug dealers in the neighbourhood.The score by Stu Copeland is great, however they could have incorporated some early 90's hip-hop/rap in the film.Some may like it better if it didn't but I find that it adds to the whole feel of the film.Anyway, if you like urban ghetto films, you owe it to yourself to watch Fresh, it is probably one of the better ones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Crime/Chess Film of All-Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thelockbox
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was excellent. The score well-used. It's well-acted, greatly written and executed, and it manages to capture a lot of nuances of childhood and children's behavior. The movie follows Fresh, a drug runner for two different major pushers in his hood. After a series of events he makes the decision to play the pushers as he would an opponent in chess. As the game of chess plays out over the last 15 minutes, the suspense grips you. The film guest stars Samuel L. Jackson as the absentee, alcoholic father of Fresh who is a great source for chess strategy, but not for compassion or love. The star of the film is the 12 year old (at the time) Sean Nelson, who does a fabulous job in the title role as Fresh. This movie makes Boys in the Hood, and Menace II Society look low-rate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Blaxploitation At Its Worst
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    luvley238
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This had to be one of the worst written movies i've ever seen. I am highly insulted by the ridiculous/fake dialogue. These people are supposed to be in New York. The sad attempt at 'ghetto slang,' and so-called realistic portrayal of 'life on the streets' makes my stomach turn. I am from the Bronx. Most of my family is from NYC. And my childhood/adolescence took part in the Bronx in the early 90s. As a black person I am offended. This movie is a prime example of why movies like 'Hollywood Shuffle' were created--to exploit offensive movies like this. I'm so tired of movies trying to normalize this type of sick behavior. this is where stereotypes come from. And if you believe the lifestyles presented in this movie are realistic scenarios, you're an idiot. Get over it. and by the way, the plot sucked. I'd have to write another post to address that... oh, and that little Spanish kid--"She be likin you Homes...I'm kickin the stupid dope moves"?!? what the heck?!? are they in fake south central or fake new york? No one talks like that. seriously, homes. everyone sucked--from sam jackson to fresh to his crack-ho sister. they can't possibly be proud of this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How is this movie not in the top 250?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    supra926hp
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I almost never review movies but after watching Fresh I felt compelled to. From the beginning of the movie my eyes were glued to the screen. I though it was just another "hood" movie but it turned out to be deeply complex. All I really want to say is that Fresh struck a cord for me on many levels. Its a coming of age story like no other, he goes through school, crushes, friends, fights, and his parents but set in the projects where violence and drugs are a commonplace. In fact, it would be an insult to pigeon-hole this movie into one genre it is one of the best dramas and action movies I have ever seen. The final scene was such a devastating moment and I'll admit I started weeping. Rarely do I cry because of a movie and even rarer will I admit to it. Go see this movie, you won't regret it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    supersam032
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The modern day "Through the Looking Glass". Enough said. But because of requirements here is a bit more. I caught this movie midway through in the middle of the night on one of the movie channels. I was intrigued by the honesty of the characters, the lines, and the idea of Samuel L. Jackson in a cameo. Fresh, as he is known, is a boy dealing with the harsh realities of inner city life and a broken family but rises above his circumstances although he is walking in them. This movie is a drama and a thriller. Just a heads up- there is a lot of brash language and situations but none gratuitous and no glamorization of crime. I found it to be a deep, thoughtful, heart-wrenching tale of the realities of life's circumstances and how one little hero overcame through the wisdom of chess.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I have seen the movie before BUT NOT LIKE THIS
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dasked (hvorfor@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hi all. I have seen this movie before and it didn't touch me then. Now 10 years after, much have happened in my life. Now I was touched all the way into my bones. What a movie. So real. So cruel. So a world of drugs and feelings blended to, much death and some hope. A hope so strong that nothing breaks through. Like life. A road is to be decided. You, other decide. All life will be affected by your choices. This movie contains 2 well known highways along your journey of decisions. Thanks for a great experience on my journey around. D. Severinsen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unusual
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ctomvelu1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This slice of ghetto life is like nothing else I ave seen. A young drug runner decides he wants out of the life. He also wants to save his sister, who has taken up with one of the kid's drug kingpins. In order to get out, he has to do some pretty fancy footwork. But he is a master strategist as we see when he plays chess with his dad. Wonderful location photography and acting, with a large cast of mostly unknown actors except for Sam Jackson as the dad and Giancarlo Esposito as the drug kingpin. The plot doesn't necessarily go in the direction you might think. There is a fair amount of violence, but most of it is off camera or quickly cut away from.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    R Bruce Hudson
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While learning chess against his expert player dad, Fresh also learns how to play for life. Another brilliant basketball playing kid, is deliberately fouled by a thug, a hood. To get back, he dazzles that hood - embarrassing him. The enraged hood goes gets a gun, and shoots him dead. Collateral damage is a sweet innocent girl who's character has been built sufficiently, just so we know that Fresh has a soft spot for her. A dogfight build's Fresh's character more - we know he has sound morals but gets swept along to the dog fight anyway. We know that Fresh is troubled. We then weave through the movie like a game of chess, where pieces are sacrificed for the final victory. There are lessons through out, metaphors and texture for anyone who cares to look. Thoroughly enjoyed it. Gave it an 8 out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Best Films Ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    McCamyTaylor
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie for about the twentieth time. It never fails to astound me and make me cry. This film is the perfect mix of cerebral and tear jerker. Even when you know what is going to happen, you have to watch and be amazed at the 1) writer who came up with this 2) the actors who play the characters, especially the boy, Michael. It is very, very close to being as good as my other favorite crime drama, "LA Confidential". Solid editing and score, too. Just be sure to pay close attention, or the plot, with its many twists and turns will lose you, and the second half of the film will make absolutely no sense. The moral---if you are too attached, you can not save those things that you truly value---may throw some folks in the U.S. who are used to good versus evil themes. Thematically, this movie is a lot like another done by the same director, "A Price Above Rubies."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent cross of "hood" movie and thriller with great delivery across acting, score, cinematography and direction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you will allow me a personal moment, Fresh was one of the films that I saw at a time when I was really in love with film. I had just moved to England in 1995 and had gone from being a 20 minute drive to a small multiplex chain cinema, to being a 5 minute walk away from the Light House independent cinema in Wolverhampton. Not only was it close but it was cheap and I would regularly go there to see films big and small. I was lucky because this rough period was throwing up things like Usual Suspects, Pulp Fiction and many other really strong films. Fresh was one of these and I remembered thinking it was great but, not having seen it since, I wasn't sure if maybe the period in my life was also giving it a rose-tinted memory in my head. I watched it again last night and did so as a different person  35 instead of 18, living comfortably instead of a struggling student; regardless of time and place though, the film still gripped me from start to finish and justifies my memory of it being an excellent film. The plot starts out as a "ghetto" film that fits into the genre of the early 90's (Menace II Society, Boyz n the Hood etc) but then in the middle it becomes much more of a thriller where young Fresh tries to turn the table on his dealing employers in revenge for the murder of one of his friends. Both parts of the film work equally well and merge into each other seamlessly. Just like the construction of the city environment in the opening titles, the film builds on the details and at times the viewer will be a few steps behind Fresh in terms of his plan. It is a dangerous game and there are quite brutal moments in it, but these just help up the tension, of which there is lots. Yakin directs really well throughout the film and is aided by excellent cinematography, capturing a sense of place really well. The patient orchestral score also fits with this and the slower pace that it can at times have, however all of these qualities (however good they are) tend to get lost in the background of the praise because front and centre is a terrific performance from a very young Sean Nelson. He is the heart of the film and the ability to deliver his character is key  and he nails it. Fresh isn't on a moral quest for what is right, he is very much on a personal mission and he does it by playing cynically with those around him, making sacrifices of both himself and of them. It is a great performance throughout and it is hard to imagine anyone else but him in that role  perfect bit of casting. That he stands up on his own with such a strong support cast is also impressive. Esposito is great despite hamming up his accent and his abs a little bit  amusing to watch this character back through the filter of Breaking Bad as well! Jackson was pushing to the front on the DVD cover due to Pulp Fiction's success, but he is only in a small role, albeit a good one. Beyond them La Marre, Brice, Wright and others are also good. Almost twenty years old, Fresh is an excellent film that is well made across the board as both a hood movie and a thriller  my memory was not faded, this is a great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good ghetto film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gangstahippie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fresh was one of the many urban ghetto films which came out in the 90's, around the same time gangsta rap was at it's peak.Films like Boyz N The Hood, Menace 2 Society & this film showed the dangers of urban life, while other films such as Friday showed that it could be fun.If you dislike these types of movies, you may still like fresh.It is actually a fairly smart film with a good storyline, acting and some funny moments as well.The film is centred around a young twelve year old drug dealer and his relationships with the dealers he works for.He is actually a very smart and calculating child and hatches a plan to end all the drug dealers in the neighbourhood.The score by Stu Copeland is great, however they could have incorporated some early 90's hip-hop/rap in the film.Some may like it better if it didn't but I find that it adds to the whole feel of the film.Anyway, if you like urban ghetto films, you owe it to yourself to watch Fresh, it is probably one of the better ones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Crime/Chess Film of All-Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thelockbox
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was excellent. The score well-used. It's well-acted, greatly written and executed, and it manages to capture a lot of nuances of childhood and children's behavior. The movie follows Fresh, a drug runner for two different major pushers in his hood. After a series of events he makes the decision to play the pushers as he would an opponent in chess. As the game of chess plays out over the last 15 minutes, the suspense grips you. The film guest stars Samuel L. Jackson as the absentee, alcoholic father of Fresh who is a great source for chess strategy, but not for compassion or love. The star of the film is the 12 year old (at the time) Sean Nelson, who does a fabulous job in the title role as Fresh. This movie makes Boys in the Hood, and Menace II Society look low-rate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Blaxploitation At Its Worst
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    luvley238
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This had to be one of the worst written movies i've ever seen. I am highly insulted by the ridiculous/fake dialogue. These people are supposed to be in New York. The sad attempt at 'ghetto slang,' and so-called realistic portrayal of 'life on the streets' makes my stomach turn. I am from the Bronx. Most of my family is from NYC. And my childhood/adolescence took part in the Bronx in the early 90s. As a black person I am offended. This movie is a prime example of why movies like 'Hollywood Shuffle' were created--to exploit offensive movies like this. I'm so tired of movies trying to normalize this type of sick behavior. this is where stereotypes come from. And if you believe the lifestyles presented in this movie are realistic scenarios, you're an idiot. Get over it. and by the way, the plot sucked. I'd have to write another post to address that... oh, and that little Spanish kid--"She be likin you Homes...I'm kickin the stupid dope moves"?!? what the heck?!? are they in fake south central or fake new york? No one talks like that. seriously, homes. everyone sucked--from sam jackson to fresh to his crack-ho sister. they can't possibly be proud of this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How is this movie not in the top 250?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    supra926hp
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I almost never review movies but after watching Fresh I felt compelled to. From the beginning of the movie my eyes were glued to the screen. I though it was just another "hood" movie but it turned out to be deeply complex. All I really want to say is that Fresh struck a cord for me on many levels. Its a coming of age story like no other, he goes through school, crushes, friends, fights, and his parents but set in the projects where violence and drugs are a commonplace. In fact, it would be an insult to pigeon-hole this movie into one genre it is one of the best dramas and action movies I have ever seen. The final scene was such a devastating moment and I'll admit I started weeping. Rarely do I cry because of a movie and even rarer will I admit to it. Go see this movie, you won't regret it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    supersam032
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The modern day "Through the Looking Glass". Enough said. But because of requirements here is a bit more. I caught this movie midway through in the middle of the night on one of the movie channels. I was intrigued by the honesty of the characters, the lines, and the idea of Samuel L. Jackson in a cameo. Fresh, as he is known, is a boy dealing with the harsh realities of inner city life and a broken family but rises above his circumstances although he is walking in them. This movie is a drama and a thriller. Just a heads up- there is a lot of brash language and situations but none gratuitous and no glamorization of crime. I found it to be a deep, thoughtful, heart-wrenching tale of the realities of life's circumstances and how one little hero overcame through the wisdom of chess.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I have seen the movie before BUT NOT LIKE THIS
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dasked (hvorfor@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hi all. I have seen this movie before and it didn't touch me then. Now 10 years after, much have happened in my life. Now I was touched all the way into my bones. What a movie. So real. So cruel. So a world of drugs and feelings blended to, much death and some hope. A hope so strong that nothing breaks through. Like life. A road is to be decided. You, other decide. All life will be affected by your choices. This movie contains 2 well known highways along your journey of decisions. Thanks for a great experience on my journey around. D. Severinsen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unusual
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ctomvelu1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This slice of ghetto life is like nothing else I ave seen. A young drug runner decides he wants out of the life. He also wants to save his sister, who has taken up with one of the kid's drug kingpins. In order to get out, he has to do some pretty fancy footwork. But he is a master strategist as we see when he plays chess with his dad. Wonderful location photography and acting, with a large cast of mostly unknown actors except for Sam Jackson as the dad and Giancarlo Esposito as the drug kingpin. The plot doesn't necessarily go in the direction you might think. There is a fair amount of violence, but most of it is off camera or quickly cut away from.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    R Bruce Hudson
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While learning chess against his expert player dad, Fresh also learns how to play for life. Another brilliant basketball playing kid, is deliberately fouled by a thug, a hood. To get back, he dazzles that hood - embarrassing him. The enraged hood goes gets a gun, and shoots him dead. Collateral damage is a sweet innocent girl who's character has been built sufficiently, just so we know that Fresh has a soft spot for her. A dogfight build's Fresh's character more - we know he has sound morals but gets swept along to the dog fight anyway. We know that Fresh is troubled. We then weave through the movie like a game of chess, where pieces are sacrificed for the final victory. There are lessons through out, metaphors and texture for anyone who cares to look. Thoroughly enjoyed it. Gave it an 8 out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Best Films Ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    McCamyTaylor
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie for about the twentieth time. It never fails to astound me and make me cry. This film is the perfect mix of cerebral and tear jerker. Even when you know what is going to happen, you have to watch and be amazed at the 1) writer who came up with this 2) the actors who play the characters, especially the boy, Michael. It is very, very close to being as good as my other favorite crime drama, "LA Confidential". Solid editing and score, too. Just be sure to pay close attention, or the plot, with its many twists and turns will lose you, and the second half of the film will make absolutely no sense. The moral---if you are too attached, you can not save those things that you truly value---may throw some folks in the U.S. who are used to good versus evil themes. Thematically, this movie is a lot like another done by the same director, "A Price Above Rubies."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent cross of "hood" movie and thriller with great delivery across acting, score, cinematography and direction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you will allow me a personal moment, Fresh was one of the films that I saw at a time when I was really in love with film. I had just moved to England in 1995 and had gone from being a 20 minute drive to a small multiplex chain cinema, to being a 5 minute walk away from the Light House independent cinema in Wolverhampton. Not only was it close but it was cheap and I would regularly go there to see films big and small. I was lucky because this rough period was throwing up things like Usual Suspects, Pulp Fiction and many other really strong films. Fresh was one of these and I remembered thinking it was great but, not having seen it since, I wasn't sure if maybe the period in my life was also giving it a rose-tinted memory in my head. I watched it again last night and did so as a different person  35 instead of 18, living comfortably instead of a struggling student; regardless of time and place though, the film still gripped me from start to finish and justifies my memory of it being an excellent film. The plot starts out as a "ghetto" film that fits into the genre of the early 90's (Menace II Society, Boyz n the Hood etc) but then in the middle it becomes much more of a thriller where young Fresh tries to turn the table on his dealing employers in revenge for the murder of one of his friends. Both parts of the film work equally well and merge into each other seamlessly. Just like the construction of the city environment in the opening titles, the film builds on the details and at times the viewer will be a few steps behind Fresh in terms of his plan. It is a dangerous game and there are quite brutal moments in it, but these just help up the tension, of which there is lots. Yakin directs really well throughout the film and is aided by excellent cinematography, capturing a sense of place really well. The patient orchestral score also fits with this and the slower pace that it can at times have, however all of these qualities (however good they are) tend to get lost in the background of the praise because front and centre is a terrific performance from a very young Sean Nelson. He is the heart of the film and the ability to deliver his character is key  and he nails it. Fresh isn't on a moral quest for what is right, he is very much on a personal mission and he does it by playing cynically with those around him, making sacrifices of both himself and of them. It is a great performance throughout and it is hard to imagine anyone else but him in that role  perfect bit of casting. That he stands up on his own with such a strong support cast is also impressive. Esposito is great despite hamming up his accent and his abs a little bit  amusing to watch this character back through the filter of Breaking Bad as well! Jackson was pushing to the front on the DVD cover due to Pulp Fiction's success, but he is only in a small role, albeit a good one. Beyond them La Marre, Brice, Wright and others are also good. Almost twenty years old, Fresh is an excellent film that is well made across the board as both a hood movie and a thriller  my memory was not faded, this is a great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good ghetto film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gangstahippie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fresh was one of the many urban ghetto films which came out in the 90's, around the same time gangsta rap was at it's peak.Films like Boyz N The Hood, Menace 2 Society & this film showed the dangers of urban life, while other films such as Friday showed that it could be fun.If you dislike these types of movies, you may still like fresh.It is actually a fairly smart film with a good storyline, acting and some funny moments as well.The film is centred around a young twelve year old drug dealer and his relationships with the dealers he works for.He is actually a very smart and calculating child and hatches a plan to end all the drug dealers in the neighbourhood.The score by Stu Copeland is great, however they could have incorporated some early 90's hip-hop/rap in the film.Some may like it better if it didn't but I find that it adds to the whole feel of the film.Anyway, if you like urban ghetto films, you owe it to yourself to watch Fresh, it is probably one of the better ones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Crime/Chess Film of All-Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thelockbox
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was excellent. The score well-used. It's well-acted, greatly written and executed, and it manages to capture a lot of nuances of childhood and children's behavior. The movie follows Fresh, a drug runner for two different major pushers in his hood. After a series of events he makes the decision to play the pushers as he would an opponent in chess. As the game of chess plays out over the last 15 minutes, the suspense grips you. The film guest stars Samuel L. Jackson as the absentee, alcoholic father of Fresh who is a great source for chess strategy, but not for compassion or love. The star of the film is the 12 year old (at the time) Sean Nelson, who does a fabulous job in the title role as Fresh. This movie makes Boys in the Hood, and Menace II Society look low-rate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Blaxploitation At Its Worst
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    luvley238
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This had to be one of the worst written movies i've ever seen. I am highly insulted by the ridiculous/fake dialogue. These people are supposed to be in New York. The sad attempt at 'ghetto slang,' and so-called realistic portrayal of 'life on the streets' makes my stomach turn. I am from the Bronx. Most of my family is from NYC. And my childhood/adolescence took part in the Bronx in the early 90s. As a black person I am offended. This movie is a prime example of why movies like 'Hollywood Shuffle' were created--to exploit offensive movies like this. I'm so tired of movies trying to normalize this type of sick behavior. this is where stereotypes come from. And if you believe the lifestyles presented in this movie are realistic scenarios, you're an idiot. Get over it. and by the way, the plot sucked. I'd have to write another post to address that... oh, and that little Spanish kid--"She be likin you Homes...I'm kickin the stupid dope moves"?!? what the heck?!? are they in fake south central or fake new york? No one talks like that. seriously, homes. everyone sucked--from sam jackson to fresh to his crack-ho sister. they can't possibly be proud of this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How is this movie not in the top 250?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    supra926hp
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I almost never review movies but after watching Fresh I felt compelled to. From the beginning of the movie my eyes were glued to the screen. I though it was just another "hood" movie but it turned out to be deeply complex. All I really want to say is that Fresh struck a cord for me on many levels. Its a coming of age story like no other, he goes through school, crushes, friends, fights, and his parents but set in the projects where violence and drugs are a commonplace. In fact, it would be an insult to pigeon-hole this movie into one genre it is one of the best dramas and action movies I have ever seen. The final scene was such a devastating moment and I'll admit I started weeping. Rarely do I cry because of a movie and even rarer will I admit to it. Go see this movie, you won't regret it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    supersam032
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The modern day "Through the Looking Glass". Enough said. But because of requirements here is a bit more. I caught this movie midway through in the middle of the night on one of the movie channels. I was intrigued by the honesty of the characters, the lines, and the idea of Samuel L. Jackson in a cameo. Fresh, as he is known, is a boy dealing with the harsh realities of inner city life and a broken family but rises above his circumstances although he is walking in them. This movie is a drama and a thriller. Just a heads up- there is a lot of brash language and situations but none gratuitous and no glamorization of crime. I found it to be a deep, thoughtful, heart-wrenching tale of the realities of life's circumstances and how one little hero overcame through the wisdom of chess.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I have seen the movie before BUT NOT LIKE THIS
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dasked (hvorfor@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hi all. I have seen this movie before and it didn't touch me then. Now 10 years after, much have happened in my life. Now I was touched all the way into my bones. What a movie. So real. So cruel. So a world of drugs and feelings blended to, much death and some hope. A hope so strong that nothing breaks through. Like life. A road is to be decided. You, other decide. All life will be affected by your choices. This movie contains 2 well known highways along your journey of decisions. Thanks for a great experience on my journey around. D. Severinsen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
