<filme>
 <id>
  1171
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0111019
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Rosas Selvagens
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  In a village in the Southwest of France, 1962. Maite and Francois are 18 years old. They are friends, not lovers. In Francois's classroom, there are Serge, whose brother has just married to... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  In a village in the Southwest of France, 1962. Maite and Francois are 18 years old. They are friends, not lovers. In Francois's classroom, there are Serge, whose brother has just married to try to escape from the war in Algeria, and Henri, a pied-noir (Algerian-born Frenchman). Francois and Serge will have a homosexual relationship, but Serge wants to marry his brother's wife...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   classroom
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   homosexual
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   friend
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   pills
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   masochist
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Andr&eacute; T&eacute;chin&eacute;
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Olivier Massart
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Gilles Taurand
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   &Eacute;lodie Bouchez
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ga&euml;l Morel
  </ator>
  <ator>
   St&eacute;phane Rideau
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A decent movie. No more, no less.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ANightToRemember
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've been a bit confused as to some other reviews I've seen on this site. Most call the film "beautiful" and a great realistic love story. In some cases they seem to right, but in other cases they aren't. Let's start with the plot: It's 1960's France, and we've got three guys at a boarding school. Fran&ccedil;ois (our main character), Serge (our main character's love interest/lust), and Henri (some kid with a radio). Fran&ccedil;ois is in some kind of borderline relationship with his best friend, Ma&iuml;t&eacute;. They're at a wedding of the older brother of Serge, even though we aren't totally sure who knows who and how they were invited there. I'll just assume that Ma&iuml;t&eacute;'s mother, Madame Alvarez, somehow knows Serge's brother. Anyways they go through a horribly shot wedding (more on that later), then go. We get some dialog in which Fran&ccedil;ois claims Serge is "weird". Serge's older brother says something about being attracted to Madam Alvarez, and that she can help him get out of going to the war in Algeria. Oh, and he attempts to almost rape her, but don't worry: it's never brought up again. Anyways, Sergi seduces Fran&ccedil;ois one night, and it all goes from there. That kid with the radio is involved too, don't worry. Henri is apparently a Fascist from Algeria (strange, considering he's about as North African as a taco) who is always eager for news from there. It all goes from there, I don't want to give away too much. Okay, now let's start with my first problem: the cinematography. Some call it "beautiful" and it looks like "summer" and so "pure" all the time. Okay, no. It just sucks in this movie. NOTHING is unique about it. I could pick up a camera and make a movie in the same place with the same outdoor light, and it'd look so "artsy" to some. It is just... nothing. Nothing looks pretty, nothing looks unique. It's just average. And don't get me started on my main problem: the editing. The GODFORSAKEN EDITING. It's just awful. There are no transitions, at some points it seems to cut in mid-conversation. Let's use an example. At the beginning, there's a scene with Madam Alvarez is dancing with Serge's brother at his wedding. First of all, they are dancing incredibly quickly for a waltz, and they spin and spin and spin. We're with one camera angle (never cuts to another), so it's almost like both are trying to talk, but the other person continues to block them with their head. The scene ends with the two talking, only it's his shoulder covering half her face and his, well shoulder. It just looks terrible, almost unprofessional. A lot of elements seem tacked on. There's a whole sub plot with Madam Alvarez as well, with her going crazy over something (I'll leave it to you to see). Only there isn't a reason for it. At all. There isn't any resolution to her problem, no relation to our main characters, it's like they just wanted to add more drama, but it seems like two movies that were accidentally edited together when they should have been separate. The acting is quite good, though. They all seem to know their characters and do perfectly fine with what they have. I wouldn't mind seeing most of them in other films. But the direction that everyone calls "fantastic" isn't really that. Half the time the characters do things for no particular reason, leaving you wondering their motivations for half the things they do. While it isn't a bad movie, it isn't good. It's entertaining, but just an average piece of film. Nothing special. Go ahead and see it if you want to. By seeing it, you won't gain anything. By skipping it you won't miss anything. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch if you want to relive painful dead ends
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    filmtherapy
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is painful for gay people. This is a coming of age movie set about 1962 near Toulouse. The Algerian war is almost over.It takes place at a high school although some of the students are a bit older (21). The main character Francois is gay. He has a female friend (fag hag) Maite who is a communist (looks like a cross between Greta Van Sustren and Frieda= ugly). Francois falls in love with first Serge and then Henri...both straight. Serge is a macho peasant and Henri an upper class right wing pied noir (from Algeria). This movie has too much PC content (my all time greatest annoyance). The all around good communists Maite and her mother (would they be bad?) represent the moral high ground. The teacher helping the anti Arab Henri has an Arabic wife. Typical left wing homage you see in almost all French movies and Hollywood for that matter. This sort of political intrusion would be tolerable if the gay thing had a happy ending it doesn't and is two hours of reliving all the dead ends gay people encounter when young. The shoe salesman is a good example. It isn't much fun. There are so many better gay films. Watch the Israeli movie Eyes Wide Open or The Country Teacher instead. This one is mostly boring, the 4 main actors look too old for the role. The gay one (in one small saving grace) is the the best looking and most likable, the girl is positively homely. I long for the day when there are gay characters who beat the system and don't humiliate themselves---gay James Bonds. DO NOT RECOMMEND
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sexuality, war, desire and self-discovery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arcadio Bolanos
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the past, director Andr&eacute; T&eacute;chin&eacute; has relentlessly pursued complex subjects. His films don't pander to the audience, nor do they allow the public to be emotionally detached. In "Les T&eacute;moins", for instance, AIDS is understood not as a simple disease but as something that profoundly alters social discourse and human interaction. In "Les Roseaux Sauvages" there is an immanent bellicosity among France and Algeria which lingers on in the background long enough to affect the protagonists. At the beginning of the film a wedding becomes the scenario in which we observe Serge's brother clumsily plotting how to desert from French troops, while Fran&ccedil;ois is idly chatting with Ma&iuml;t&eacute;, a girl he doesn't love but dates nonetheless. The war strongly infiltrates the world of these youngsters, as a new student arrives to the boarding school attended by Serge (interpreted by St&eacute;phane Rideau in what would be the first of many gay related productions) and Fran&ccedil;ois (interpreted by Ga&euml;l Morel, director of several films of gay interest), an older boy named Henri that has experienced the aftermaths of the armed conflict in the flesh. After a couple of visits Serge pays to Fran&ccedil;ois in the middle of the night, the two boys soon become friends, but not before sharing some intimate secrets and practicing mutual masturbation and sexual intercourse. Of course, for Serge this one night stand is the product of revolting hormones and teenage horniness, but for Fran&ccedil;ois this moment changes everything: he will come forward to Ma&iuml;t&eacute; and from that moment, what at first seemed a typical high school relationship, is utterly modified. It's not long before Henri finds out, quite easily, about the sexual escapades of the two boys, but seems preoccupied only with the development of the war. Henri is unable to come through a normal grieving process regarding his father and the Algerian reality. The need for a symbolic death becomes patently necessary for Henri. Jacques Lacan defined the symbolic death as a narrative of closure, as the final sentence one must utter in order to let the dead ones go. If every culture in the planet respects some sort of funerary rites it is precisely because of that. The real death comes naturally when a heart stops beating, but the symbolic death is something cultural, something that depends on any given individual and the ability to cope with loss. Coming to terms with death means to be able to write that epitaph in our head, to be able to understand someone else's life and then to let go of it. Serge, on the contrary, will eventually accept the casualties of war, and instead of being paralyzed by death he will keep moving on. When Ma&iuml;t&eacute;'s mother suffers a psychological breakdown after hearing about the demise of one of her students, her daughter feels devastated. None of this matters to Fran&ccedil;ois who's having a hard time understanding his own sexuality. A most relevant moment takes place when he confronts his image in the mirror and starts repeating "Je suis p&eacute;d&eacute;", ashamed of being gay. This degrading word will lead to the reformulation of the object of desire, according to new terms and surpassing the phallic response; Fran&ccedil;ois's desire will be inextricably linked to the question of the desire of the other in its ethical dimension insofar as it bears the possibility of alterity, of authentic otherness. Of course it's never easy to be young and gay, but it's even more difficult in an isolated French province in the early 60s. It is then that Ma&iuml;t&eacute;'s emotional support proves to be fundamental for Fran&ccedil;ois, as he will comprehend that his initial object of desire may well be out of his reach. The characters of the film adopt contrasting postures. Serge and Fran&ccedil;ois possess an adaptability and flexibility that will become indispensable. Henri and Ma&iuml;t&eacute;, however, are determined and stubborn individuals. Henri's teacher tries to make him understand that being strong like an oak is a disadvantage as oaks break when the storm comes, only reeds survive the storm because they bend but do not break. Drawing a divisor line between war and sexuality, T&eacute;chin&eacute; finally gathers the three boys and the girl in one final sequence that instead of focusing on the clich&eacute; of hope is centered on the pervasive reiteration of uncertainty and friendship.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stupid French Film with Useful Idiots.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Herag Halli
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am still asking myself as to how and why I ended up getting this movie from Netflix. There is nothing to see for an intelligent viewer. Stupid idiotic teenagers wander aimlessly in the French country side with one kid clutching his radio for good part of the movie. They are all effete looking and talk gibberish (atleast from what I read in the sub-titles.) The movie is a bore and lacks any kind of continuity that is sign of a good film maker. The class room scene is the most boring piece of movie I ever seen. These French Films are overrated by these French Media Morons here to reffered as morons for brevity, who probably have never seen non French films since they are narcissistic and don't know or don't care there is life outside France or outside of French films. Quite a bunch of useful and strange idiots. To the credit of this movie..the cinematography is breathtaking specially the canal scene and the greenery of the countryside.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love and politics
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Taylor (bob998@sympatico.ca)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A superb film from T&eacute;chin&eacute;. The small town of Villeneuve-sur-Lot is filmed beautifully, the characters are well-drawn, the story moves along believably (not always the case with this director). Gael Morel as Fran&ccedil;ois is fresh, ardent and appealing; his love for Serge will not be returned, to his chagrin. &Eacute;lodie Bouchez impresses us as Mait&eacute;, who has grown up without a father; in a sense, the Communist Party has become her father. The one sinister character is Mariani the pied-noir: his bigoted notions of life have been formed by his parents and the OAS, he has no real philosophy just an internalized sense of rage at the unfairness of life. There are wonderful scenes. Mme Alvarez, the teacher at the lyc&eacute;e, might help Serge's older brother to desert from the army so he won't have to go back to fight in Algeria, but refuses to do so out of professional pride. Later she hears of the young man's death in combat and falls into a profound depression. The sleep cure is prescribed for her, it's a cure worse than the disease. Mariani has a chance to pass his bac if he works hard (he has already failed it) but working with the teacher Morelli (a pied-noir himself) is forcing him to confront his mental strait-jacket. Since he would rather be wrong in solidarity with his parents than right with these progressive Frenchmen he despises, he abandons his studies. The student-teacher confrontations are sour and hopeless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Down-to-earth, genuine and beautiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    M A
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a genuine and convincing portrayal of how teenagers from different backgrounds facing different problems find their true selves, and how they shape and transform their philosophies of life through the mutually interwoven processes of love, hate, learning, accepting and enlightening. This is a story on how purity and love will transcend across very different people and help them become awake to what they are and what they long for when facing the real world. A beautiful masterpiece that would move you without doing something "big". The 4 lead characters delivered convincing and promising performances, each making them very likable people without glorifying, stereotyping or idolising any ideology. All in all, a highly recommended beautiful, genuine and poetic gem.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dull and uninspiring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dull, uninspiring tale of young love from a reputed master of French cinema. Andre Techine's film fails on many levels, unable as it is to grab our attention, hold our interest or endear us to its participants. "Wild Reeds" has a very weak link, and that is its script. From director Techine, Gilles Taurand and Olivier Massart, it misses the mark on both plot and character development. The story, concerning a young boy's love for a fellow student who has lost his brother in the Algiers war, and a young girl's confusion about life and love which is compounded by her mother's nervous breakdown, never manages to captivate or even slightly interests us. Coupled with this is the scripters failure to present characters we can care about. Ensuring the film's complete destruction is the awful, pointed dialogue that is totally embarrassing and never works. In this light "Wild Reeds" did not stand a chance, and any attempts by the young cast to salvage the film are doomed. Having said this, Gael Morel, Elodie Bouchez, Frederic Corny and Stephane Rideau all try hard to reach us from their confused, youthful worlds. Alas none of them can. Cinematography from Jeanne Lapoirie is fetching. Monday, August 4, 1997 - Hoyts Croydon
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another load of French tripe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    limau
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, actually, I exaggerate, it isn't really too bad, but I just feel obliged to balance off the hyperventilating praises that this film got from so many reviewers. This is a just so-so film that tells the lives and sexual awakenings of four teenagers in a school. The story itself is good, plainly told, and parts of it are well-done, and evocative of the feel at a particular time in history as well as of the confusion that teenagers can feel grappling with their sexuality and love lives. However, there are a number of problems. The acting of the main characters is really rather wooden (although the girl who played Ma&iuml;t&eacute; is an exception) - whether they are telling going through a personal crisis or telling an affecting story, there is little change in their expressions. The dialogue is sometimes verging on the silly - do young French people really constantly go round declaiming their thoughts and views in the way they do in this film? If you put some of the dialogue in the mouths of American teenagers and you will see how stupid and pretentious they are, but many reviewers seem to think that since it is French, it must be deep and profound rather than ridiculous. It is a shame that so many lose they critical faculty when judging non-American films. One reviewer claimed that it put 99% of American films to shame, when really, if truth must be told, the vast majority of foreign films are really quite poor, and this one is not an exceptional one. Some, perhaps the great majority, of the astonishing good and imaginative films in recent times comes out of America, while those from elsewhere often get stuck in retreading old stuff and mire in mediocrity. The awarding of the Palme D'Or this year to Ken Loach's utterly second-rate The Wind That Shakes the Barley is perhaps the ultimate example of this kind of blindness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The movie of my life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vandrade
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is absolutely impossible to make a film like this one without carrying out the personal memories of an our own teenage time. That's why this so called 'teenage movie' is so far away from all other experiences within this field. T&eacute;chin&eacute; had written and directed a part of his own life. Villeneuve-sur-Lot, Paris, Lisbon, who cares? This is the movie of my life. And if it is so, it's not only because of the unexpected beauty of all frames on the movie, but, essentially because that I felt every inch of the road walked by the characters of this film, as if their experiences, a long time ago, in a galaxy far, far away, were my own teenage experiences and hopes. I saw this film ten years ago, and still I can remember every image, every phrase... And I kept these memories as a guideline for a future life, when I was 23 years old. I know what I have lived, I still don't know what the future reserves to me. But, on those days, ten years ago, I have increased my hope. I found that there was people like me, and like the others around me... The time and the place doesn't matter. No film will never make me feel so strongly about my youth, and, simultaneously, about my future as a man. This is not a 'teenage movie', it's a collection of memories about the construction of our personality. And, we all, with that age, were a little bit of Fran&ccedil;ois, Serge, Henri and Maite. And we still are. (...I'm sorry about my English...)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best T&eacute;chin&eacute; film yet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alexandre-extra
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    &laquo;Les Roseaux Sauvages&raquo; (in Portuguese, &laquo;Juncos Silvestres&raquo;) isn't just an ordinary film about the awakening of adolescence: it is a romantic treatise, an unforgettable example of delicacy and fidelity in the approach of such sensible themes such as the sexual ambiguity in adolescence and, above all, the love as a superior statement, domineering - even metaphysical. Although I haven't seen much of T&eacute;chin&eacute; (I saw, besides &laquo;Les roseaux sauvages&raquo;, the movies &laquo;Loin&raquo;, &laquo;Les &eacute;gar&eacute;s&raquo;, and the recent &laquo;Les temps qui changent&raquo;), I believe that, to the date, this is without a doubt his best film, the most ravishing. T&eacute;chin&eacute; tells us the story of four teenagers: Fran&ccedil;ois Forestier (interpreted sublimely by Ga&euml;l Morel in his eternal look of sweet innocence), Serge Bartolo (interpreted by St&eacute;phane Rideau, the eternal seducer confirmed later in &laquo;Loin&raquo;, &laquo;Presque Rien&raquo;, &laquo;A toute vitesse&raquo;...), Ma&iuml;te Alvarez (interpreted by the well known &Eacute;lodie Bouchez) and Henri Mariani (Fr&eacute;d&eacute;ric Gorny). The film starts with Fran&ccedil;ois talking to Ma&iuml;te about the movie &laquo;S&aring;som i en Spegel&raquo; (that reports us to the idea of 'search for the real truth'), from the Swedish director Ingmar Bergman, although that isn't said. Truly, the entire film is the search for the truth by the 4 teenagers. Fran&ccedil;ois is Ma&iuml;te's boyfriend, although that relationship is more of a platonic protection against adulthood pressures than a physical passion. At the same time, Fran&ccedil;ois, Serge and Henri study in the same masculine boarding school, where they share rooms. Serge, in his sexual ambiguity, desires Ma&iuml;te and at the same time seduces Fran&ccedil;ois, and ends up having sex with him. From that day on, Fran&ccedil;ois faces the homosexual desires that he had yet not perceived, while he falls in love for Serge and feels excited by Henri. On its turn, Serge, although always hesitant, breaks the relationship with Fran&ccedil;ois to search a more peaceful village life, next to any woman that fulfills his needs. The scene where Serge first breaks with Fran&ccedil;ois is brutal and pungent. Fran&ccedil;ois, always interpreted as the most fragile and delicate of the four, meets Serge while the last is walking to the river to drown his cat's cubs. At the same time that he tells Fran&ccedil;ois (always sensitive) in cold blood that &laquo;they are not good for each other&raquo;, he throws the innocent cubs into the river. For the first time in his life, Fran&ccedil;ois' heart is broken, in a scene that reminds us the archetype &laquo;the lost of innocence&raquo;. From that moment on, Fran&ccedil;ois is always searching for fortuitous encounters with Serge, living as, in his own words, a &laquo;thieve stilling moments&raquo;: one time he travels in a motorcycle hugging Serge, in another time he sleeps next to him, etc. The scenes in the classroom are bright, solar, reminding the purity of childhood; and alternate with the scenes taken place at night, that are incredibly sensual. Fran&ccedil;ois is also portrayed as an intellectual that reads Jean-Arthur-Nicolas Rimbaud, a homosexual writer revolted against the world, that leaves everything to live with the also writer Paul Verlaine, while he was still a teenager. That is what Fran&ccedil;ois wants to be. Ma&iuml;te, on her side, is a communist that, after knowing about Fran&ccedil;ois passion for Serge, is jealous, but finally realizes the true platonic nature of her relationship with him. After a while, she falls in love with Henri, a pied-noir (French born Algerian) teenager revolted against the situation in his native country. He is also in love with her, although ideologically they are rivals. And this is why love, in this film, is taken as a superior and dominant statement: it surpasses all human ideologies, even the most complex and rooted ones; it surpasses intellectuals who read Rimbaud and even the most practical persons. The action takes place in 1962, at the same time as the Algerian crises, that is not exploited, although, to a certain pace, it is. The soundtrack confirms the excellence of this film, with Chubby Checker giving a sixties atmosphere, and the Adagio for string by Samuel Barber yielding the dramatic dimension that the film deserves, like in the highly stylized scene where Henri his sleeping by the river, or when Fran&ccedil;ois travels in the motorcycle hugging Serge. In the end, Fran&ccedil;ois meets a shoe salesman that everyone knows his a homosexual, in a scene that represents the almost desperate search for a way to destroy the lowliness, incomprehension, and lack of role models that are destined by his sexual orientation. Although he doesn't find the answer for his problems, because there isn't one, Fran&ccedil;ois remains optimistic &#8722; and this is another lesson that this film teaches us: to stay in the fight, always optimistic in a future happiness. This is one of those movies where I would like to penetrate and live in forever, between Ma&iuml;te, Serge, Henri and, above all, the character unifying the destiny of the four, Fran&ccedil;ois, 'searching the truth'. I have seen films in the come-of-age theme, but this remains my favorite. Some good ones are &laquo;Presque Rien&raquo; (with J&eacute;r&eacute;mie Elka&iuml;m and St&eacute;phane Rideau), &laquo;A cause d'un garcon&raquo; (also with J&eacute;r&eacute;mie Elka&iuml;m), &laquo;Maurice&raquo; (based on E. M. Forster homonymous work) and &laquo;Beautiful thing&raquo;. It remains to be said that this film won four C&eacute;sar (in the Cannes festival): best film, best director, best script and best actress-revelation for &Eacute;lodie Bouchez.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A decent movie. No more, no less.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ANightToRemember
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've been a bit confused as to some other reviews I've seen on this site. Most call the film "beautiful" and a great realistic love story. In some cases they seem to right, but in other cases they aren't. Let's start with the plot: It's 1960's France, and we've got three guys at a boarding school. Fran&ccedil;ois (our main character), Serge (our main character's love interest/lust), and Henri (some kid with a radio). Fran&ccedil;ois is in some kind of borderline relationship with his best friend, Ma&iuml;t&eacute;. They're at a wedding of the older brother of Serge, even though we aren't totally sure who knows who and how they were invited there. I'll just assume that Ma&iuml;t&eacute;'s mother, Madame Alvarez, somehow knows Serge's brother. Anyways they go through a horribly shot wedding (more on that later), then go. We get some dialog in which Fran&ccedil;ois claims Serge is "weird". Serge's older brother says something about being attracted to Madam Alvarez, and that she can help him get out of going to the war in Algeria. Oh, and he attempts to almost rape her, but don't worry: it's never brought up again. Anyways, Sergi seduces Fran&ccedil;ois one night, and it all goes from there. That kid with the radio is involved too, don't worry. Henri is apparently a Fascist from Algeria (strange, considering he's about as North African as a taco) who is always eager for news from there. It all goes from there, I don't want to give away too much. Okay, now let's start with my first problem: the cinematography. Some call it "beautiful" and it looks like "summer" and so "pure" all the time. Okay, no. It just sucks in this movie. NOTHING is unique about it. I could pick up a camera and make a movie in the same place with the same outdoor light, and it'd look so "artsy" to some. It is just... nothing. Nothing looks pretty, nothing looks unique. It's just average. And don't get me started on my main problem: the editing. The GODFORSAKEN EDITING. It's just awful. There are no transitions, at some points it seems to cut in mid-conversation. Let's use an example. At the beginning, there's a scene with Madam Alvarez is dancing with Serge's brother at his wedding. First of all, they are dancing incredibly quickly for a waltz, and they spin and spin and spin. We're with one camera angle (never cuts to another), so it's almost like both are trying to talk, but the other person continues to block them with their head. The scene ends with the two talking, only it's his shoulder covering half her face and his, well shoulder. It just looks terrible, almost unprofessional. A lot of elements seem tacked on. There's a whole sub plot with Madam Alvarez as well, with her going crazy over something (I'll leave it to you to see). Only there isn't a reason for it. At all. There isn't any resolution to her problem, no relation to our main characters, it's like they just wanted to add more drama, but it seems like two movies that were accidentally edited together when they should have been separate. The acting is quite good, though. They all seem to know their characters and do perfectly fine with what they have. I wouldn't mind seeing most of them in other films. But the direction that everyone calls "fantastic" isn't really that. Half the time the characters do things for no particular reason, leaving you wondering their motivations for half the things they do. While it isn't a bad movie, it isn't good. It's entertaining, but just an average piece of film. Nothing special. Go ahead and see it if you want to. By seeing it, you won't gain anything. By skipping it you won't miss anything. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch if you want to relive painful dead ends
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    filmtherapy
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is painful for gay people. This is a coming of age movie set about 1962 near Toulouse. The Algerian war is almost over.It takes place at a high school although some of the students are a bit older (21). The main character Francois is gay. He has a female friend (fag hag) Maite who is a communist (looks like a cross between Greta Van Sustren and Frieda= ugly). Francois falls in love with first Serge and then Henri...both straight. Serge is a macho peasant and Henri an upper class right wing pied noir (from Algeria). This movie has too much PC content (my all time greatest annoyance). The all around good communists Maite and her mother (would they be bad?) represent the moral high ground. The teacher helping the anti Arab Henri has an Arabic wife. Typical left wing homage you see in almost all French movies and Hollywood for that matter. This sort of political intrusion would be tolerable if the gay thing had a happy ending it doesn't and is two hours of reliving all the dead ends gay people encounter when young. The shoe salesman is a good example. It isn't much fun. There are so many better gay films. Watch the Israeli movie Eyes Wide Open or The Country Teacher instead. This one is mostly boring, the 4 main actors look too old for the role. The gay one (in one small saving grace) is the the best looking and most likable, the girl is positively homely. I long for the day when there are gay characters who beat the system and don't humiliate themselves---gay James Bonds. DO NOT RECOMMEND
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sexuality, war, desire and self-discovery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arcadio Bolanos
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the past, director Andr&eacute; T&eacute;chin&eacute; has relentlessly pursued complex subjects. His films don't pander to the audience, nor do they allow the public to be emotionally detached. In "Les T&eacute;moins", for instance, AIDS is understood not as a simple disease but as something that profoundly alters social discourse and human interaction. In "Les Roseaux Sauvages" there is an immanent bellicosity among France and Algeria which lingers on in the background long enough to affect the protagonists. At the beginning of the film a wedding becomes the scenario in which we observe Serge's brother clumsily plotting how to desert from French troops, while Fran&ccedil;ois is idly chatting with Ma&iuml;t&eacute;, a girl he doesn't love but dates nonetheless. The war strongly infiltrates the world of these youngsters, as a new student arrives to the boarding school attended by Serge (interpreted by St&eacute;phane Rideau in what would be the first of many gay related productions) and Fran&ccedil;ois (interpreted by Ga&euml;l Morel, director of several films of gay interest), an older boy named Henri that has experienced the aftermaths of the armed conflict in the flesh. After a couple of visits Serge pays to Fran&ccedil;ois in the middle of the night, the two boys soon become friends, but not before sharing some intimate secrets and practicing mutual masturbation and sexual intercourse. Of course, for Serge this one night stand is the product of revolting hormones and teenage horniness, but for Fran&ccedil;ois this moment changes everything: he will come forward to Ma&iuml;t&eacute; and from that moment, what at first seemed a typical high school relationship, is utterly modified. It's not long before Henri finds out, quite easily, about the sexual escapades of the two boys, but seems preoccupied only with the development of the war. Henri is unable to come through a normal grieving process regarding his father and the Algerian reality. The need for a symbolic death becomes patently necessary for Henri. Jacques Lacan defined the symbolic death as a narrative of closure, as the final sentence one must utter in order to let the dead ones go. If every culture in the planet respects some sort of funerary rites it is precisely because of that. The real death comes naturally when a heart stops beating, but the symbolic death is something cultural, something that depends on any given individual and the ability to cope with loss. Coming to terms with death means to be able to write that epitaph in our head, to be able to understand someone else's life and then to let go of it. Serge, on the contrary, will eventually accept the casualties of war, and instead of being paralyzed by death he will keep moving on. When Ma&iuml;t&eacute;'s mother suffers a psychological breakdown after hearing about the demise of one of her students, her daughter feels devastated. None of this matters to Fran&ccedil;ois who's having a hard time understanding his own sexuality. A most relevant moment takes place when he confronts his image in the mirror and starts repeating "Je suis p&eacute;d&eacute;", ashamed of being gay. This degrading word will lead to the reformulation of the object of desire, according to new terms and surpassing the phallic response; Fran&ccedil;ois's desire will be inextricably linked to the question of the desire of the other in its ethical dimension insofar as it bears the possibility of alterity, of authentic otherness. Of course it's never easy to be young and gay, but it's even more difficult in an isolated French province in the early 60s. It is then that Ma&iuml;t&eacute;'s emotional support proves to be fundamental for Fran&ccedil;ois, as he will comprehend that his initial object of desire may well be out of his reach. The characters of the film adopt contrasting postures. Serge and Fran&ccedil;ois possess an adaptability and flexibility that will become indispensable. Henri and Ma&iuml;t&eacute;, however, are determined and stubborn individuals. Henri's teacher tries to make him understand that being strong like an oak is a disadvantage as oaks break when the storm comes, only reeds survive the storm because they bend but do not break. Drawing a divisor line between war and sexuality, T&eacute;chin&eacute; finally gathers the three boys and the girl in one final sequence that instead of focusing on the clich&eacute; of hope is centered on the pervasive reiteration of uncertainty and friendship.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stupid French Film with Useful Idiots.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Herag Halli
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am still asking myself as to how and why I ended up getting this movie from Netflix. There is nothing to see for an intelligent viewer. Stupid idiotic teenagers wander aimlessly in the French country side with one kid clutching his radio for good part of the movie. They are all effete looking and talk gibberish (atleast from what I read in the sub-titles.) The movie is a bore and lacks any kind of continuity that is sign of a good film maker. The class room scene is the most boring piece of movie I ever seen. These French Films are overrated by these French Media Morons here to reffered as morons for brevity, who probably have never seen non French films since they are narcissistic and don't know or don't care there is life outside France or outside of French films. Quite a bunch of useful and strange idiots. To the credit of this movie..the cinematography is breathtaking specially the canal scene and the greenery of the countryside.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love and politics
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Taylor (bob998@sympatico.ca)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A superb film from T&eacute;chin&eacute;. The small town of Villeneuve-sur-Lot is filmed beautifully, the characters are well-drawn, the story moves along believably (not always the case with this director). Gael Morel as Fran&ccedil;ois is fresh, ardent and appealing; his love for Serge will not be returned, to his chagrin. &Eacute;lodie Bouchez impresses us as Mait&eacute;, who has grown up without a father; in a sense, the Communist Party has become her father. The one sinister character is Mariani the pied-noir: his bigoted notions of life have been formed by his parents and the OAS, he has no real philosophy just an internalized sense of rage at the unfairness of life. There are wonderful scenes. Mme Alvarez, the teacher at the lyc&eacute;e, might help Serge's older brother to desert from the army so he won't have to go back to fight in Algeria, but refuses to do so out of professional pride. Later she hears of the young man's death in combat and falls into a profound depression. The sleep cure is prescribed for her, it's a cure worse than the disease. Mariani has a chance to pass his bac if he works hard (he has already failed it) but working with the teacher Morelli (a pied-noir himself) is forcing him to confront his mental strait-jacket. Since he would rather be wrong in solidarity with his parents than right with these progressive Frenchmen he despises, he abandons his studies. The student-teacher confrontations are sour and hopeless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Down-to-earth, genuine and beautiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    M A
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a genuine and convincing portrayal of how teenagers from different backgrounds facing different problems find their true selves, and how they shape and transform their philosophies of life through the mutually interwoven processes of love, hate, learning, accepting and enlightening. This is a story on how purity and love will transcend across very different people and help them become awake to what they are and what they long for when facing the real world. A beautiful masterpiece that would move you without doing something "big". The 4 lead characters delivered convincing and promising performances, each making them very likable people without glorifying, stereotyping or idolising any ideology. All in all, a highly recommended beautiful, genuine and poetic gem.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dull and uninspiring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dull, uninspiring tale of young love from a reputed master of French cinema. Andre Techine's film fails on many levels, unable as it is to grab our attention, hold our interest or endear us to its participants. "Wild Reeds" has a very weak link, and that is its script. From director Techine, Gilles Taurand and Olivier Massart, it misses the mark on both plot and character development. The story, concerning a young boy's love for a fellow student who has lost his brother in the Algiers war, and a young girl's confusion about life and love which is compounded by her mother's nervous breakdown, never manages to captivate or even slightly interests us. Coupled with this is the scripters failure to present characters we can care about. Ensuring the film's complete destruction is the awful, pointed dialogue that is totally embarrassing and never works. In this light "Wild Reeds" did not stand a chance, and any attempts by the young cast to salvage the film are doomed. Having said this, Gael Morel, Elodie Bouchez, Frederic Corny and Stephane Rideau all try hard to reach us from their confused, youthful worlds. Alas none of them can. Cinematography from Jeanne Lapoirie is fetching. Monday, August 4, 1997 - Hoyts Croydon
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another load of French tripe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    limau
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, actually, I exaggerate, it isn't really too bad, but I just feel obliged to balance off the hyperventilating praises that this film got from so many reviewers. This is a just so-so film that tells the lives and sexual awakenings of four teenagers in a school. The story itself is good, plainly told, and parts of it are well-done, and evocative of the feel at a particular time in history as well as of the confusion that teenagers can feel grappling with their sexuality and love lives. However, there are a number of problems. The acting of the main characters is really rather wooden (although the girl who played Ma&iuml;t&eacute; is an exception) - whether they are telling going through a personal crisis or telling an affecting story, there is little change in their expressions. The dialogue is sometimes verging on the silly - do young French people really constantly go round declaiming their thoughts and views in the way they do in this film? If you put some of the dialogue in the mouths of American teenagers and you will see how stupid and pretentious they are, but many reviewers seem to think that since it is French, it must be deep and profound rather than ridiculous. It is a shame that so many lose they critical faculty when judging non-American films. One reviewer claimed that it put 99% of American films to shame, when really, if truth must be told, the vast majority of foreign films are really quite poor, and this one is not an exceptional one. Some, perhaps the great majority, of the astonishing good and imaginative films in recent times comes out of America, while those from elsewhere often get stuck in retreading old stuff and mire in mediocrity. The awarding of the Palme D'Or this year to Ken Loach's utterly second-rate The Wind That Shakes the Barley is perhaps the ultimate example of this kind of blindness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The movie of my life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vandrade
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is absolutely impossible to make a film like this one without carrying out the personal memories of an our own teenage time. That's why this so called 'teenage movie' is so far away from all other experiences within this field. T&eacute;chin&eacute; had written and directed a part of his own life. Villeneuve-sur-Lot, Paris, Lisbon, who cares? This is the movie of my life. And if it is so, it's not only because of the unexpected beauty of all frames on the movie, but, essentially because that I felt every inch of the road walked by the characters of this film, as if their experiences, a long time ago, in a galaxy far, far away, were my own teenage experiences and hopes. I saw this film ten years ago, and still I can remember every image, every phrase... And I kept these memories as a guideline for a future life, when I was 23 years old. I know what I have lived, I still don't know what the future reserves to me. But, on those days, ten years ago, I have increased my hope. I found that there was people like me, and like the others around me... The time and the place doesn't matter. No film will never make me feel so strongly about my youth, and, simultaneously, about my future as a man. This is not a 'teenage movie', it's a collection of memories about the construction of our personality. And, we all, with that age, were a little bit of Fran&ccedil;ois, Serge, Henri and Maite. And we still are. (...I'm sorry about my English...)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best T&eacute;chin&eacute; film yet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alexandre-extra
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    &laquo;Les Roseaux Sauvages&raquo; (in Portuguese, &laquo;Juncos Silvestres&raquo;) isn't just an ordinary film about the awakening of adolescence: it is a romantic treatise, an unforgettable example of delicacy and fidelity in the approach of such sensible themes such as the sexual ambiguity in adolescence and, above all, the love as a superior statement, domineering - even metaphysical. Although I haven't seen much of T&eacute;chin&eacute; (I saw, besides &laquo;Les roseaux sauvages&raquo;, the movies &laquo;Loin&raquo;, &laquo;Les &eacute;gar&eacute;s&raquo;, and the recent &laquo;Les temps qui changent&raquo;), I believe that, to the date, this is without a doubt his best film, the most ravishing. T&eacute;chin&eacute; tells us the story of four teenagers: Fran&ccedil;ois Forestier (interpreted sublimely by Ga&euml;l Morel in his eternal look of sweet innocence), Serge Bartolo (interpreted by St&eacute;phane Rideau, the eternal seducer confirmed later in &laquo;Loin&raquo;, &laquo;Presque Rien&raquo;, &laquo;A toute vitesse&raquo;...), Ma&iuml;te Alvarez (interpreted by the well known &Eacute;lodie Bouchez) and Henri Mariani (Fr&eacute;d&eacute;ric Gorny). The film starts with Fran&ccedil;ois talking to Ma&iuml;te about the movie &laquo;S&aring;som i en Spegel&raquo; (that reports us to the idea of 'search for the real truth'), from the Swedish director Ingmar Bergman, although that isn't said. Truly, the entire film is the search for the truth by the 4 teenagers. Fran&ccedil;ois is Ma&iuml;te's boyfriend, although that relationship is more of a platonic protection against adulthood pressures than a physical passion. At the same time, Fran&ccedil;ois, Serge and Henri study in the same masculine boarding school, where they share rooms. Serge, in his sexual ambiguity, desires Ma&iuml;te and at the same time seduces Fran&ccedil;ois, and ends up having sex with him. From that day on, Fran&ccedil;ois faces the homosexual desires that he had yet not perceived, while he falls in love for Serge and feels excited by Henri. On its turn, Serge, although always hesitant, breaks the relationship with Fran&ccedil;ois to search a more peaceful village life, next to any woman that fulfills his needs. The scene where Serge first breaks with Fran&ccedil;ois is brutal and pungent. Fran&ccedil;ois, always interpreted as the most fragile and delicate of the four, meets Serge while the last is walking to the river to drown his cat's cubs. At the same time that he tells Fran&ccedil;ois (always sensitive) in cold blood that &laquo;they are not good for each other&raquo;, he throws the innocent cubs into the river. For the first time in his life, Fran&ccedil;ois' heart is broken, in a scene that reminds us the archetype &laquo;the lost of innocence&raquo;. From that moment on, Fran&ccedil;ois is always searching for fortuitous encounters with Serge, living as, in his own words, a &laquo;thieve stilling moments&raquo;: one time he travels in a motorcycle hugging Serge, in another time he sleeps next to him, etc. The scenes in the classroom are bright, solar, reminding the purity of childhood; and alternate with the scenes taken place at night, that are incredibly sensual. Fran&ccedil;ois is also portrayed as an intellectual that reads Jean-Arthur-Nicolas Rimbaud, a homosexual writer revolted against the world, that leaves everything to live with the also writer Paul Verlaine, while he was still a teenager. That is what Fran&ccedil;ois wants to be. Ma&iuml;te, on her side, is a communist that, after knowing about Fran&ccedil;ois passion for Serge, is jealous, but finally realizes the true platonic nature of her relationship with him. After a while, she falls in love with Henri, a pied-noir (French born Algerian) teenager revolted against the situation in his native country. He is also in love with her, although ideologically they are rivals. And this is why love, in this film, is taken as a superior and dominant statement: it surpasses all human ideologies, even the most complex and rooted ones; it surpasses intellectuals who read Rimbaud and even the most practical persons. The action takes place in 1962, at the same time as the Algerian crises, that is not exploited, although, to a certain pace, it is. The soundtrack confirms the excellence of this film, with Chubby Checker giving a sixties atmosphere, and the Adagio for string by Samuel Barber yielding the dramatic dimension that the film deserves, like in the highly stylized scene where Henri his sleeping by the river, or when Fran&ccedil;ois travels in the motorcycle hugging Serge. In the end, Fran&ccedil;ois meets a shoe salesman that everyone knows his a homosexual, in a scene that represents the almost desperate search for a way to destroy the lowliness, incomprehension, and lack of role models that are destined by his sexual orientation. Although he doesn't find the answer for his problems, because there isn't one, Fran&ccedil;ois remains optimistic &#8722; and this is another lesson that this film teaches us: to stay in the fight, always optimistic in a future happiness. This is one of those movies where I would like to penetrate and live in forever, between Ma&iuml;te, Serge, Henri and, above all, the character unifying the destiny of the four, Fran&ccedil;ois, 'searching the truth'. I have seen films in the come-of-age theme, but this remains my favorite. Some good ones are &laquo;Presque Rien&raquo; (with J&eacute;r&eacute;mie Elka&iuml;m and St&eacute;phane Rideau), &laquo;A cause d'un garcon&raquo; (also with J&eacute;r&eacute;mie Elka&iuml;m), &laquo;Maurice&raquo; (based on E. M. Forster homonymous work) and &laquo;Beautiful thing&raquo;. It remains to be said that this film won four C&eacute;sar (in the Cannes festival): best film, best director, best script and best actress-revelation for &Eacute;lodie Bouchez.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A decent movie. No more, no less.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ANightToRemember
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've been a bit confused as to some other reviews I've seen on this site. Most call the film "beautiful" and a great realistic love story. In some cases they seem to right, but in other cases they aren't. Let's start with the plot: It's 1960's France, and we've got three guys at a boarding school. Fran&ccedil;ois (our main character), Serge (our main character's love interest/lust), and Henri (some kid with a radio). Fran&ccedil;ois is in some kind of borderline relationship with his best friend, Ma&iuml;t&eacute;. They're at a wedding of the older brother of Serge, even though we aren't totally sure who knows who and how they were invited there. I'll just assume that Ma&iuml;t&eacute;'s mother, Madame Alvarez, somehow knows Serge's brother. Anyways they go through a horribly shot wedding (more on that later), then go. We get some dialog in which Fran&ccedil;ois claims Serge is "weird". Serge's older brother says something about being attracted to Madam Alvarez, and that she can help him get out of going to the war in Algeria. Oh, and he attempts to almost rape her, but don't worry: it's never brought up again. Anyways, Sergi seduces Fran&ccedil;ois one night, and it all goes from there. That kid with the radio is involved too, don't worry. Henri is apparently a Fascist from Algeria (strange, considering he's about as North African as a taco) who is always eager for news from there. It all goes from there, I don't want to give away too much. Okay, now let's start with my first problem: the cinematography. Some call it "beautiful" and it looks like "summer" and so "pure" all the time. Okay, no. It just sucks in this movie. NOTHING is unique about it. I could pick up a camera and make a movie in the same place with the same outdoor light, and it'd look so "artsy" to some. It is just... nothing. Nothing looks pretty, nothing looks unique. It's just average. And don't get me started on my main problem: the editing. The GODFORSAKEN EDITING. It's just awful. There are no transitions, at some points it seems to cut in mid-conversation. Let's use an example. At the beginning, there's a scene with Madam Alvarez is dancing with Serge's brother at his wedding. First of all, they are dancing incredibly quickly for a waltz, and they spin and spin and spin. We're with one camera angle (never cuts to another), so it's almost like both are trying to talk, but the other person continues to block them with their head. The scene ends with the two talking, only it's his shoulder covering half her face and his, well shoulder. It just looks terrible, almost unprofessional. A lot of elements seem tacked on. There's a whole sub plot with Madam Alvarez as well, with her going crazy over something (I'll leave it to you to see). Only there isn't a reason for it. At all. There isn't any resolution to her problem, no relation to our main characters, it's like they just wanted to add more drama, but it seems like two movies that were accidentally edited together when they should have been separate. The acting is quite good, though. They all seem to know their characters and do perfectly fine with what they have. I wouldn't mind seeing most of them in other films. But the direction that everyone calls "fantastic" isn't really that. Half the time the characters do things for no particular reason, leaving you wondering their motivations for half the things they do. While it isn't a bad movie, it isn't good. It's entertaining, but just an average piece of film. Nothing special. Go ahead and see it if you want to. By seeing it, you won't gain anything. By skipping it you won't miss anything. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch if you want to relive painful dead ends
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    filmtherapy
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is painful for gay people. This is a coming of age movie set about 1962 near Toulouse. The Algerian war is almost over.It takes place at a high school although some of the students are a bit older (21). The main character Francois is gay. He has a female friend (fag hag) Maite who is a communist (looks like a cross between Greta Van Sustren and Frieda= ugly). Francois falls in love with first Serge and then Henri...both straight. Serge is a macho peasant and Henri an upper class right wing pied noir (from Algeria). This movie has too much PC content (my all time greatest annoyance). The all around good communists Maite and her mother (would they be bad?) represent the moral high ground. The teacher helping the anti Arab Henri has an Arabic wife. Typical left wing homage you see in almost all French movies and Hollywood for that matter. This sort of political intrusion would be tolerable if the gay thing had a happy ending it doesn't and is two hours of reliving all the dead ends gay people encounter when young. The shoe salesman is a good example. It isn't much fun. There are so many better gay films. Watch the Israeli movie Eyes Wide Open or The Country Teacher instead. This one is mostly boring, the 4 main actors look too old for the role. The gay one (in one small saving grace) is the the best looking and most likable, the girl is positively homely. I long for the day when there are gay characters who beat the system and don't humiliate themselves---gay James Bonds. DO NOT RECOMMEND
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sexuality, war, desire and self-discovery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arcadio Bolanos
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the past, director Andr&eacute; T&eacute;chin&eacute; has relentlessly pursued complex subjects. His films don't pander to the audience, nor do they allow the public to be emotionally detached. In "Les T&eacute;moins", for instance, AIDS is understood not as a simple disease but as something that profoundly alters social discourse and human interaction. In "Les Roseaux Sauvages" there is an immanent bellicosity among France and Algeria which lingers on in the background long enough to affect the protagonists. At the beginning of the film a wedding becomes the scenario in which we observe Serge's brother clumsily plotting how to desert from French troops, while Fran&ccedil;ois is idly chatting with Ma&iuml;t&eacute;, a girl he doesn't love but dates nonetheless. The war strongly infiltrates the world of these youngsters, as a new student arrives to the boarding school attended by Serge (interpreted by St&eacute;phane Rideau in what would be the first of many gay related productions) and Fran&ccedil;ois (interpreted by Ga&euml;l Morel, director of several films of gay interest), an older boy named Henri that has experienced the aftermaths of the armed conflict in the flesh. After a couple of visits Serge pays to Fran&ccedil;ois in the middle of the night, the two boys soon become friends, but not before sharing some intimate secrets and practicing mutual masturbation and sexual intercourse. Of course, for Serge this one night stand is the product of revolting hormones and teenage horniness, but for Fran&ccedil;ois this moment changes everything: he will come forward to Ma&iuml;t&eacute; and from that moment, what at first seemed a typical high school relationship, is utterly modified. It's not long before Henri finds out, quite easily, about the sexual escapades of the two boys, but seems preoccupied only with the development of the war. Henri is unable to come through a normal grieving process regarding his father and the Algerian reality. The need for a symbolic death becomes patently necessary for Henri. Jacques Lacan defined the symbolic death as a narrative of closure, as the final sentence one must utter in order to let the dead ones go. If every culture in the planet respects some sort of funerary rites it is precisely because of that. The real death comes naturally when a heart stops beating, but the symbolic death is something cultural, something that depends on any given individual and the ability to cope with loss. Coming to terms with death means to be able to write that epitaph in our head, to be able to understand someone else's life and then to let go of it. Serge, on the contrary, will eventually accept the casualties of war, and instead of being paralyzed by death he will keep moving on. When Ma&iuml;t&eacute;'s mother suffers a psychological breakdown after hearing about the demise of one of her students, her daughter feels devastated. None of this matters to Fran&ccedil;ois who's having a hard time understanding his own sexuality. A most relevant moment takes place when he confronts his image in the mirror and starts repeating "Je suis p&eacute;d&eacute;", ashamed of being gay. This degrading word will lead to the reformulation of the object of desire, according to new terms and surpassing the phallic response; Fran&ccedil;ois's desire will be inextricably linked to the question of the desire of the other in its ethical dimension insofar as it bears the possibility of alterity, of authentic otherness. Of course it's never easy to be young and gay, but it's even more difficult in an isolated French province in the early 60s. It is then that Ma&iuml;t&eacute;'s emotional support proves to be fundamental for Fran&ccedil;ois, as he will comprehend that his initial object of desire may well be out of his reach. The characters of the film adopt contrasting postures. Serge and Fran&ccedil;ois possess an adaptability and flexibility that will become indispensable. Henri and Ma&iuml;t&eacute;, however, are determined and stubborn individuals. Henri's teacher tries to make him understand that being strong like an oak is a disadvantage as oaks break when the storm comes, only reeds survive the storm because they bend but do not break. Drawing a divisor line between war and sexuality, T&eacute;chin&eacute; finally gathers the three boys and the girl in one final sequence that instead of focusing on the clich&eacute; of hope is centered on the pervasive reiteration of uncertainty and friendship.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stupid French Film with Useful Idiots.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Herag Halli
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am still asking myself as to how and why I ended up getting this movie from Netflix. There is nothing to see for an intelligent viewer. Stupid idiotic teenagers wander aimlessly in the French country side with one kid clutching his radio for good part of the movie. They are all effete looking and talk gibberish (atleast from what I read in the sub-titles.) The movie is a bore and lacks any kind of continuity that is sign of a good film maker. The class room scene is the most boring piece of movie I ever seen. These French Films are overrated by these French Media Morons here to reffered as morons for brevity, who probably have never seen non French films since they are narcissistic and don't know or don't care there is life outside France or outside of French films. Quite a bunch of useful and strange idiots. To the credit of this movie..the cinematography is breathtaking specially the canal scene and the greenery of the countryside.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love and politics
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Taylor (bob998@sympatico.ca)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A superb film from T&eacute;chin&eacute;. The small town of Villeneuve-sur-Lot is filmed beautifully, the characters are well-drawn, the story moves along believably (not always the case with this director). Gael Morel as Fran&ccedil;ois is fresh, ardent and appealing; his love for Serge will not be returned, to his chagrin. &Eacute;lodie Bouchez impresses us as Mait&eacute;, who has grown up without a father; in a sense, the Communist Party has become her father. The one sinister character is Mariani the pied-noir: his bigoted notions of life have been formed by his parents and the OAS, he has no real philosophy just an internalized sense of rage at the unfairness of life. There are wonderful scenes. Mme Alvarez, the teacher at the lyc&eacute;e, might help Serge's older brother to desert from the army so he won't have to go back to fight in Algeria, but refuses to do so out of professional pride. Later she hears of the young man's death in combat and falls into a profound depression. The sleep cure is prescribed for her, it's a cure worse than the disease. Mariani has a chance to pass his bac if he works hard (he has already failed it) but working with the teacher Morelli (a pied-noir himself) is forcing him to confront his mental strait-jacket. Since he would rather be wrong in solidarity with his parents than right with these progressive Frenchmen he despises, he abandons his studies. The student-teacher confrontations are sour and hopeless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Down-to-earth, genuine and beautiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    M A
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a genuine and convincing portrayal of how teenagers from different backgrounds facing different problems find their true selves, and how they shape and transform their philosophies of life through the mutually interwoven processes of love, hate, learning, accepting and enlightening. This is a story on how purity and love will transcend across very different people and help them become awake to what they are and what they long for when facing the real world. A beautiful masterpiece that would move you without doing something "big". The 4 lead characters delivered convincing and promising performances, each making them very likable people without glorifying, stereotyping or idolising any ideology. All in all, a highly recommended beautiful, genuine and poetic gem.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dull and uninspiring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dull, uninspiring tale of young love from a reputed master of French cinema. Andre Techine's film fails on many levels, unable as it is to grab our attention, hold our interest or endear us to its participants. "Wild Reeds" has a very weak link, and that is its script. From director Techine, Gilles Taurand and Olivier Massart, it misses the mark on both plot and character development. The story, concerning a young boy's love for a fellow student who has lost his brother in the Algiers war, and a young girl's confusion about life and love which is compounded by her mother's nervous breakdown, never manages to captivate or even slightly interests us. Coupled with this is the scripters failure to present characters we can care about. Ensuring the film's complete destruction is the awful, pointed dialogue that is totally embarrassing and never works. In this light "Wild Reeds" did not stand a chance, and any attempts by the young cast to salvage the film are doomed. Having said this, Gael Morel, Elodie Bouchez, Frederic Corny and Stephane Rideau all try hard to reach us from their confused, youthful worlds. Alas none of them can. Cinematography from Jeanne Lapoirie is fetching. Monday, August 4, 1997 - Hoyts Croydon
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another load of French tripe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    limau
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, actually, I exaggerate, it isn't really too bad, but I just feel obliged to balance off the hyperventilating praises that this film got from so many reviewers. This is a just so-so film that tells the lives and sexual awakenings of four teenagers in a school. The story itself is good, plainly told, and parts of it are well-done, and evocative of the feel at a particular time in history as well as of the confusion that teenagers can feel grappling with their sexuality and love lives. However, there are a number of problems. The acting of the main characters is really rather wooden (although the girl who played Ma&iuml;t&eacute; is an exception) - whether they are telling going through a personal crisis or telling an affecting story, there is little change in their expressions. The dialogue is sometimes verging on the silly - do young French people really constantly go round declaiming their thoughts and views in the way they do in this film? If you put some of the dialogue in the mouths of American teenagers and you will see how stupid and pretentious they are, but many reviewers seem to think that since it is French, it must be deep and profound rather than ridiculous. It is a shame that so many lose they critical faculty when judging non-American films. One reviewer claimed that it put 99% of American films to shame, when really, if truth must be told, the vast majority of foreign films are really quite poor, and this one is not an exceptional one. Some, perhaps the great majority, of the astonishing good and imaginative films in recent times comes out of America, while those from elsewhere often get stuck in retreading old stuff and mire in mediocrity. The awarding of the Palme D'Or this year to Ken Loach's utterly second-rate The Wind That Shakes the Barley is perhaps the ultimate example of this kind of blindness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The movie of my life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vandrade
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is absolutely impossible to make a film like this one without carrying out the personal memories of an our own teenage time. That's why this so called 'teenage movie' is so far away from all other experiences within this field. T&eacute;chin&eacute; had written and directed a part of his own life. Villeneuve-sur-Lot, Paris, Lisbon, who cares? This is the movie of my life. And if it is so, it's not only because of the unexpected beauty of all frames on the movie, but, essentially because that I felt every inch of the road walked by the characters of this film, as if their experiences, a long time ago, in a galaxy far, far away, were my own teenage experiences and hopes. I saw this film ten years ago, and still I can remember every image, every phrase... And I kept these memories as a guideline for a future life, when I was 23 years old. I know what I have lived, I still don't know what the future reserves to me. But, on those days, ten years ago, I have increased my hope. I found that there was people like me, and like the others around me... The time and the place doesn't matter. No film will never make me feel so strongly about my youth, and, simultaneously, about my future as a man. This is not a 'teenage movie', it's a collection of memories about the construction of our personality. And, we all, with that age, were a little bit of Fran&ccedil;ois, Serge, Henri and Maite. And we still are. (...I'm sorry about my English...)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best T&eacute;chin&eacute; film yet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alexandre-extra
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    &laquo;Les Roseaux Sauvages&raquo; (in Portuguese, &laquo;Juncos Silvestres&raquo;) isn't just an ordinary film about the awakening of adolescence: it is a romantic treatise, an unforgettable example of delicacy and fidelity in the approach of such sensible themes such as the sexual ambiguity in adolescence and, above all, the love as a superior statement, domineering - even metaphysical. Although I haven't seen much of T&eacute;chin&eacute; (I saw, besides &laquo;Les roseaux sauvages&raquo;, the movies &laquo;Loin&raquo;, &laquo;Les &eacute;gar&eacute;s&raquo;, and the recent &laquo;Les temps qui changent&raquo;), I believe that, to the date, this is without a doubt his best film, the most ravishing. T&eacute;chin&eacute; tells us the story of four teenagers: Fran&ccedil;ois Forestier (interpreted sublimely by Ga&euml;l Morel in his eternal look of sweet innocence), Serge Bartolo (interpreted by St&eacute;phane Rideau, the eternal seducer confirmed later in &laquo;Loin&raquo;, &laquo;Presque Rien&raquo;, &laquo;A toute vitesse&raquo;...), Ma&iuml;te Alvarez (interpreted by the well known &Eacute;lodie Bouchez) and Henri Mariani (Fr&eacute;d&eacute;ric Gorny). The film starts with Fran&ccedil;ois talking to Ma&iuml;te about the movie &laquo;S&aring;som i en Spegel&raquo; (that reports us to the idea of 'search for the real truth'), from the Swedish director Ingmar Bergman, although that isn't said. Truly, the entire film is the search for the truth by the 4 teenagers. Fran&ccedil;ois is Ma&iuml;te's boyfriend, although that relationship is more of a platonic protection against adulthood pressures than a physical passion. At the same time, Fran&ccedil;ois, Serge and Henri study in the same masculine boarding school, where they share rooms. Serge, in his sexual ambiguity, desires Ma&iuml;te and at the same time seduces Fran&ccedil;ois, and ends up having sex with him. From that day on, Fran&ccedil;ois faces the homosexual desires that he had yet not perceived, while he falls in love for Serge and feels excited by Henri. On its turn, Serge, although always hesitant, breaks the relationship with Fran&ccedil;ois to search a more peaceful village life, next to any woman that fulfills his needs. The scene where Serge first breaks with Fran&ccedil;ois is brutal and pungent. Fran&ccedil;ois, always interpreted as the most fragile and delicate of the four, meets Serge while the last is walking to the river to drown his cat's cubs. At the same time that he tells Fran&ccedil;ois (always sensitive) in cold blood that &laquo;they are not good for each other&raquo;, he throws the innocent cubs into the river. For the first time in his life, Fran&ccedil;ois' heart is broken, in a scene that reminds us the archetype &laquo;the lost of innocence&raquo;. From that moment on, Fran&ccedil;ois is always searching for fortuitous encounters with Serge, living as, in his own words, a &laquo;thieve stilling moments&raquo;: one time he travels in a motorcycle hugging Serge, in another time he sleeps next to him, etc. The scenes in the classroom are bright, solar, reminding the purity of childhood; and alternate with the scenes taken place at night, that are incredibly sensual. Fran&ccedil;ois is also portrayed as an intellectual that reads Jean-Arthur-Nicolas Rimbaud, a homosexual writer revolted against the world, that leaves everything to live with the also writer Paul Verlaine, while he was still a teenager. That is what Fran&ccedil;ois wants to be. Ma&iuml;te, on her side, is a communist that, after knowing about Fran&ccedil;ois passion for Serge, is jealous, but finally realizes the true platonic nature of her relationship with him. After a while, she falls in love with Henri, a pied-noir (French born Algerian) teenager revolted against the situation in his native country. He is also in love with her, although ideologically they are rivals. And this is why love, in this film, is taken as a superior and dominant statement: it surpasses all human ideologies, even the most complex and rooted ones; it surpasses intellectuals who read Rimbaud and even the most practical persons. The action takes place in 1962, at the same time as the Algerian crises, that is not exploited, although, to a certain pace, it is. The soundtrack confirms the excellence of this film, with Chubby Checker giving a sixties atmosphere, and the Adagio for string by Samuel Barber yielding the dramatic dimension that the film deserves, like in the highly stylized scene where Henri his sleeping by the river, or when Fran&ccedil;ois travels in the motorcycle hugging Serge. In the end, Fran&ccedil;ois meets a shoe salesman that everyone knows his a homosexual, in a scene that represents the almost desperate search for a way to destroy the lowliness, incomprehension, and lack of role models that are destined by his sexual orientation. Although he doesn't find the answer for his problems, because there isn't one, Fran&ccedil;ois remains optimistic &#8722; and this is another lesson that this film teaches us: to stay in the fight, always optimistic in a future happiness. This is one of those movies where I would like to penetrate and live in forever, between Ma&iuml;te, Serge, Henri and, above all, the character unifying the destiny of the four, Fran&ccedil;ois, 'searching the truth'. I have seen films in the come-of-age theme, but this remains my favorite. Some good ones are &laquo;Presque Rien&raquo; (with J&eacute;r&eacute;mie Elka&iuml;m and St&eacute;phane Rideau), &laquo;A cause d'un garcon&raquo; (also with J&eacute;r&eacute;mie Elka&iuml;m), &laquo;Maurice&raquo; (based on E. M. Forster homonymous work) and &laquo;Beautiful thing&raquo;. It remains to be said that this film won four C&eacute;sar (in the Cannes festival): best film, best director, best script and best actress-revelation for &Eacute;lodie Bouchez.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
