<filme>
 <id>
  1173
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118742
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Bliss
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Joseph and Maria are married for six months and Maria still has never had an orgasm with her husband. They begin to visit mysterious doctor Baltazar who teaches them how to reach ecstasy in... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Joseph and Maria are married for six months and Maria still has never had an orgasm with her husband. They begin to visit mysterious doctor Baltazar who teaches them how to reach ecstasy in sex.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   doctor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sex
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   ecstasy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   orgasm
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   passion
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Lance Young
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Lance Young
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Craig Sheffer
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Terence Stamp
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Sheryl Lee
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Staggering Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    henrikibsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As difficult as this movie is to watch and an as strange as it many seem in the end what we learn through watching it is that some men are capable of doing the most disturbing things, even when it's to their own female children and that we should be ever vigilant and in the case on the mother in this story not deny what the adult child finally realizes. One of things I learn to value about myself through the story is that we should all accept our bodies as they are and not try to make them into some males ideal. The story is a sad commentary on the male of the species, but I have to believe that the percentage of men that think that way are rare. At least I'd hope so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not for those who are shy about sex!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebl7
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When this movie first came out, sexual dysfunction in women was less commonly talked about than it is now. The interesting thing about this movie is that the focus is supposedly about female issues but it is, in fact, a rare glimpse into the issues that men have about sex. Not too many movies have two men talking openly and seriously about sex in a way that is respectful of woman. Although it is a work of fiction, there are many truths in this film. It stands the test of time and may well help a couple who are having similar problems to the couple in the movie, if they were to watch it together. Terence Stamp holds the movie together, offsetting some of the slightly amateurish acting on behalf of some of the lesser roles. His unconventional character is actually believable because it is acted with such sincerity. Craig Sheffer is much more convincing in his acting than Sheryl Lee but the overall texture of the film, combined with beautiful music throughout, is not diminished by a few flaws. Definitely worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to watch...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    harquill
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    But especially hard to watch because I am married to a BPD woman. My wife turned the movie on and then went to bed, leaving me to just take it all in. This movie is quite accurate in its portrayal of a BPD person in a relationship (especially when she was caulking the entire house, priceless). They do compulsive things and expect people to go along for the ride. Even more of a power struggle than one's average marriage. The only unrealistic part about the movie (besides Balthazar having sex with patients and being open about it) is that Lee's character is actually interested in getting better and shows such improvement in what seems to be short time. Often, facing such a difficult road proves too much for an already fragile psychology. Yes, discovering a history of sexual abuse in one's past would lead to some level of healing but there is a genetic component to BPD. Just like any disorder involving the brain, the affected person has to relearn how to interact with people they care about because they process stimuli differently. In reality, if a therapist discovered that a person is Borderline or NPD, they would likely advise the spouse to leave the marriage when there are no children involved. Recovery is not the norm, and yes, spouses of these people often have their own problems... In any event, this movie hit close to home and I felt like sharing. For people dealing with a BPD spouse "Bliss" it is both hard to and fulfilling to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bold and Blissfull
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    samkay1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bliss is psychological, Bliss is sexually Educational, Bliss is poetry, Bliss is a dream ...At the same time, Bliss is also sort of pretentious in that it thinks it is making important or original statements. At the most basic level, Bliss is about a couple who have trouble in bed, but it is in the way this is sold that makes the movie feel refreshing, and unique. Bliss is about as bold as they come. It succeeds in being erotic without being gratuitous and the photography is exceptional. Cinematic sex never looked so up close or intimate, not just physically but in words. David Cronenberg's Crash is the only film of the top of my head which may be able to match Bliss for....well.....detail. What I think could use a tune up about Bliss is Sheryl Lee. You get the sense that the material is a bit beyond her, perhaps a bit too distant. She has a bit of trouble breathing life into her role. This is essential seeing as she is the catalyst for the story. Her inability to have an orgasm puts enough pressure on her husband to seek out a rogue sexual therapist who agrees to train him in the art of making love (using nine stages of intimacy, if I quote him correctly). Bliss is not for credibility-obsessed viewers, nor is it a film for the impatient or the immature. It is sexuality on a professional level. It might not perfect but It certainly stands out, and is certainly recommendable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genuine, heartfelt, with imagination
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruce_Stern
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An exploration of a couple's, especially the man's, devotion to love and to his marriage. Despite her obsessive-compulsive behavior Joseph (Craig Sheffer) loves Maria (Sheryl Lee). Initially, their sexual love appears to be an expression of their love, but all is not right, most profoundly within Maria. They attempt to work with a therapist (Spalding Gray). Maria visits an unorthodox practitioner (Terence Stamp). Joseph's discovery of this fully opens his eyes, and eventually his heart. I've seen this movie many times, and I learn or re-learn a new lesson with each viewing about the meaning of love and devotion, the importance of self-discovery, despite its discomforts, and power of the human spirit to overcome a potentially catastrophic personal history. I love the unorthodox ideas presented by Stamp's character, although they aren't fully explained. There are gaps in the telling which ought to have been filled in. Yet, this is a movie that I believe many people and many couples would benefit from. The story-telling, the narrative drive, moves forward quite well-enough for those with lessened attention spans, yet devotes the time to exploring a loving relationship with heart, understanding, compassion and imagination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Waiting...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    damalfieri
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this is an unusual "inner growing" movie. It runs away from "easy, commercial topics" about sex, comedy and violence. Too bad for the money: good intentions (even if you consider them accomplished or not) must be rewarded, no matter if they make money or not. A lot of easy trash consumers will find it boring, or ridiculous. Few very experienced sexologists and psychologist will find it "naive". But sensitive people will find it at least inspiring, full of good willing. I applaud the director, because he dared to make a definitely non-commercial movie about sex. A serious movie, very honest. In my opinion, a must. I would like the director (or anyone else) to make more movies like this one, and the producers to give money to make them. OK, Balthazar is too much like the "perfect guru", incredibly steady and "I always say the right thing in the right moment". But the director balances this at the end, or at least tries to do it. OK, the husband falls too quickly for a standard occidental man into a reasonable mood, but... too often, in "normal" films, the characters act the natural, instinctive way, instead that in a mature way. The film is about people acting in a civilized, adult way. And, if that have the risk to be unbelievable, on the other side I like it. Men are not animals, it is time for movies (and books) to consider interesting characters like this. Sorry for my poor English!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An under rated exploration of the nature of sexual love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rboon33455
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bliss is a powerful and absorbing movie which explores the nature of adult sexuality and love. The plot revolves around the relationship of a newly married yuppie couple,Steve and Maria.We quickly discover that Maria is a compulsive neurotic bordering on the psychotic who is already in therapy and who soon reveals herself to be incapable of having an orgasm. Although an acutely sensitive person she is essentially very loving and copes by faking it. This leads her and eventually her husband to meet with Baltazzar, a sex therapist played with a beguiling calm charisma by Terence Stamp. They thus begin a difficult journey leading to some very important discoveries about themselves. On this journey the Director, Lance Young, engages strongly with such themes as the very nature of sex and love and our capacity to fully give.Steve is a reasonably sensitive man, but like most men has to deal with a strong sexual libido and a dominant male culture which encourages us to put its satisfaction first.His journey is therefore towards increasing awareness and selflessness which ultimately brings its own rewards as he begins to understand the nature of real love and to be able to give and receive it. The sex we see is never gratuitous and has an emotional reality which is rooted in the context of this developing relationship. It is light years away from porn and the simplistic banality of much Hollywood sexual depiction. I suspect many men will be challenged by it in the same way Steve was by the situation he found himself faced with, but it is a journey worth taking.Craig Sheffer and Sheryl Lee give performances as the young couple which ultimately draw us into the movie,but it is Stamp who holds the film together supported by an engaging and often beautiful sound track that heightens its mood. There is a nice twist at the end when Baltazzar embarks on his own new relationship and Steve wryly reflects on the difference between giving advice and putting it into practise with someone you love and whose personality you therefore accept as part of the deal.A film for adults with open hearts and minds. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    sublime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Laura C
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I see this movie on TV...For three times. I was touched. It is a masterpiece... I am a psychotherapist and first of all, I am a soul of a woman. I would recommended " Bliss " to my patients. I am sure that only special people can really feel this movie. I felt every touch between Joseph and Maria. First time when I see it, I was fall in love with Craig Sheffer. His performed was exceptionally also the Sheryl Lee performed. It is rich in sensuality and emotions. I cannot find the right words...This movie are worth watching. Moreover, feel it! I will try to find more movies like this one. However, I think it does not exist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finally, an intelligent movie about sex
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BillLamond
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you tired of "hard-edged" action, booty call, and fake-it-till-you-make-it sex scenes, give yourself a real treat and see "Bliss." This is a movie that entertains and educates by taking on a subject about which most people are absolutely ignorant, i.e. real Eros. With a beautiful soundtrack, intelligent dialog and fine acting, "Bliss" challenges our notions of sexuality and requires audiences to think outside the box. Women will recognize this film as...ah, finally! A bonus - the information about Eros portrayed in the film is absolutely accurate. This film is fine entertainment and a crash course in what sex is really all about - getting more turned on and staying that way. This should be required viewing for adolescent male Americam film-makers of all ages.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    hate to say it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amy3-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I agree with the poor plot device comments previously mentioned. But I think this movie is very important. Now, I am quite OK with men, I am not a feminist, nor do I have any distaste for strong-willed or -minded men. But I think the movie is actually about the husband and about a common problem with men. Bliss presents the idea that very few western men allow the notion of a balanced male, taught in Eastern philosophies and faiths, anywhere near their minds. Stamps's character is presented as the balanced man, although almost ridiculously so. Anyway, I think Bliss shows how a man can use his strength to be a more gentle, confident leader, who is even more sexually alluring and commanding, than a common American man. In the West, men have been programmed to away from their feminine side(read: communicator, appreciative of beauty, nurturer). I think this movie wants to say that men who understand it and embrace it can do amazing things and have a great effect on the people in their world, and on themselves. This is emphasized by the abusive father. He shows the worst extreme: if left to twist up on himself, a man can become a terrible thing. And the extremity of Stamp's character is used to show how each man (ie, Craig) can pick and choose his own style. He doesn't have to be 'everything' like Stamp is, he can find his own way. I know the landslide at the end seems strange and out of place, but, it shows how Craig's character's changes helped in his own life: it gave him the patience and confidence with which to wait for his wife, and the gentleness to forgive her and try again. I think we are supposed to guess that if he had not changed, and they had split up, that a reconciliation could not have happened. I think in some ways the movie is great. Well, the story and theme are.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Staggering Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    henrikibsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As difficult as this movie is to watch and an as strange as it many seem in the end what we learn through watching it is that some men are capable of doing the most disturbing things, even when it's to their own female children and that we should be ever vigilant and in the case on the mother in this story not deny what the adult child finally realizes. One of things I learn to value about myself through the story is that we should all accept our bodies as they are and not try to make them into some males ideal. The story is a sad commentary on the male of the species, but I have to believe that the percentage of men that think that way are rare. At least I'd hope so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not for those who are shy about sex!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebl7
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When this movie first came out, sexual dysfunction in women was less commonly talked about than it is now. The interesting thing about this movie is that the focus is supposedly about female issues but it is, in fact, a rare glimpse into the issues that men have about sex. Not too many movies have two men talking openly and seriously about sex in a way that is respectful of woman. Although it is a work of fiction, there are many truths in this film. It stands the test of time and may well help a couple who are having similar problems to the couple in the movie, if they were to watch it together. Terence Stamp holds the movie together, offsetting some of the slightly amateurish acting on behalf of some of the lesser roles. His unconventional character is actually believable because it is acted with such sincerity. Craig Sheffer is much more convincing in his acting than Sheryl Lee but the overall texture of the film, combined with beautiful music throughout, is not diminished by a few flaws. Definitely worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to watch...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    harquill
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    But especially hard to watch because I am married to a BPD woman. My wife turned the movie on and then went to bed, leaving me to just take it all in. This movie is quite accurate in its portrayal of a BPD person in a relationship (especially when she was caulking the entire house, priceless). They do compulsive things and expect people to go along for the ride. Even more of a power struggle than one's average marriage. The only unrealistic part about the movie (besides Balthazar having sex with patients and being open about it) is that Lee's character is actually interested in getting better and shows such improvement in what seems to be short time. Often, facing such a difficult road proves too much for an already fragile psychology. Yes, discovering a history of sexual abuse in one's past would lead to some level of healing but there is a genetic component to BPD. Just like any disorder involving the brain, the affected person has to relearn how to interact with people they care about because they process stimuli differently. In reality, if a therapist discovered that a person is Borderline or NPD, they would likely advise the spouse to leave the marriage when there are no children involved. Recovery is not the norm, and yes, spouses of these people often have their own problems... In any event, this movie hit close to home and I felt like sharing. For people dealing with a BPD spouse "Bliss" it is both hard to and fulfilling to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bold and Blissfull
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    samkay1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bliss is psychological, Bliss is sexually Educational, Bliss is poetry, Bliss is a dream ...At the same time, Bliss is also sort of pretentious in that it thinks it is making important or original statements. At the most basic level, Bliss is about a couple who have trouble in bed, but it is in the way this is sold that makes the movie feel refreshing, and unique. Bliss is about as bold as they come. It succeeds in being erotic without being gratuitous and the photography is exceptional. Cinematic sex never looked so up close or intimate, not just physically but in words. David Cronenberg's Crash is the only film of the top of my head which may be able to match Bliss for....well.....detail. What I think could use a tune up about Bliss is Sheryl Lee. You get the sense that the material is a bit beyond her, perhaps a bit too distant. She has a bit of trouble breathing life into her role. This is essential seeing as she is the catalyst for the story. Her inability to have an orgasm puts enough pressure on her husband to seek out a rogue sexual therapist who agrees to train him in the art of making love (using nine stages of intimacy, if I quote him correctly). Bliss is not for credibility-obsessed viewers, nor is it a film for the impatient or the immature. It is sexuality on a professional level. It might not perfect but It certainly stands out, and is certainly recommendable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genuine, heartfelt, with imagination
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruce_Stern
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An exploration of a couple's, especially the man's, devotion to love and to his marriage. Despite her obsessive-compulsive behavior Joseph (Craig Sheffer) loves Maria (Sheryl Lee). Initially, their sexual love appears to be an expression of their love, but all is not right, most profoundly within Maria. They attempt to work with a therapist (Spalding Gray). Maria visits an unorthodox practitioner (Terence Stamp). Joseph's discovery of this fully opens his eyes, and eventually his heart. I've seen this movie many times, and I learn or re-learn a new lesson with each viewing about the meaning of love and devotion, the importance of self-discovery, despite its discomforts, and power of the human spirit to overcome a potentially catastrophic personal history. I love the unorthodox ideas presented by Stamp's character, although they aren't fully explained. There are gaps in the telling which ought to have been filled in. Yet, this is a movie that I believe many people and many couples would benefit from. The story-telling, the narrative drive, moves forward quite well-enough for those with lessened attention spans, yet devotes the time to exploring a loving relationship with heart, understanding, compassion and imagination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Waiting...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    damalfieri
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this is an unusual "inner growing" movie. It runs away from "easy, commercial topics" about sex, comedy and violence. Too bad for the money: good intentions (even if you consider them accomplished or not) must be rewarded, no matter if they make money or not. A lot of easy trash consumers will find it boring, or ridiculous. Few very experienced sexologists and psychologist will find it "naive". But sensitive people will find it at least inspiring, full of good willing. I applaud the director, because he dared to make a definitely non-commercial movie about sex. A serious movie, very honest. In my opinion, a must. I would like the director (or anyone else) to make more movies like this one, and the producers to give money to make them. OK, Balthazar is too much like the "perfect guru", incredibly steady and "I always say the right thing in the right moment". But the director balances this at the end, or at least tries to do it. OK, the husband falls too quickly for a standard occidental man into a reasonable mood, but... too often, in "normal" films, the characters act the natural, instinctive way, instead that in a mature way. The film is about people acting in a civilized, adult way. And, if that have the risk to be unbelievable, on the other side I like it. Men are not animals, it is time for movies (and books) to consider interesting characters like this. Sorry for my poor English!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An under rated exploration of the nature of sexual love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rboon33455
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bliss is a powerful and absorbing movie which explores the nature of adult sexuality and love. The plot revolves around the relationship of a newly married yuppie couple,Steve and Maria.We quickly discover that Maria is a compulsive neurotic bordering on the psychotic who is already in therapy and who soon reveals herself to be incapable of having an orgasm. Although an acutely sensitive person she is essentially very loving and copes by faking it. This leads her and eventually her husband to meet with Baltazzar, a sex therapist played with a beguiling calm charisma by Terence Stamp. They thus begin a difficult journey leading to some very important discoveries about themselves. On this journey the Director, Lance Young, engages strongly with such themes as the very nature of sex and love and our capacity to fully give.Steve is a reasonably sensitive man, but like most men has to deal with a strong sexual libido and a dominant male culture which encourages us to put its satisfaction first.His journey is therefore towards increasing awareness and selflessness which ultimately brings its own rewards as he begins to understand the nature of real love and to be able to give and receive it. The sex we see is never gratuitous and has an emotional reality which is rooted in the context of this developing relationship. It is light years away from porn and the simplistic banality of much Hollywood sexual depiction. I suspect many men will be challenged by it in the same way Steve was by the situation he found himself faced with, but it is a journey worth taking.Craig Sheffer and Sheryl Lee give performances as the young couple which ultimately draw us into the movie,but it is Stamp who holds the film together supported by an engaging and often beautiful sound track that heightens its mood. There is a nice twist at the end when Baltazzar embarks on his own new relationship and Steve wryly reflects on the difference between giving advice and putting it into practise with someone you love and whose personality you therefore accept as part of the deal.A film for adults with open hearts and minds. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    sublime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Laura C
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I see this movie on TV...For three times. I was touched. It is a masterpiece... I am a psychotherapist and first of all, I am a soul of a woman. I would recommended " Bliss " to my patients. I am sure that only special people can really feel this movie. I felt every touch between Joseph and Maria. First time when I see it, I was fall in love with Craig Sheffer. His performed was exceptionally also the Sheryl Lee performed. It is rich in sensuality and emotions. I cannot find the right words...This movie are worth watching. Moreover, feel it! I will try to find more movies like this one. However, I think it does not exist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finally, an intelligent movie about sex
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BillLamond
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you tired of "hard-edged" action, booty call, and fake-it-till-you-make-it sex scenes, give yourself a real treat and see "Bliss." This is a movie that entertains and educates by taking on a subject about which most people are absolutely ignorant, i.e. real Eros. With a beautiful soundtrack, intelligent dialog and fine acting, "Bliss" challenges our notions of sexuality and requires audiences to think outside the box. Women will recognize this film as...ah, finally! A bonus - the information about Eros portrayed in the film is absolutely accurate. This film is fine entertainment and a crash course in what sex is really all about - getting more turned on and staying that way. This should be required viewing for adolescent male Americam film-makers of all ages.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    hate to say it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amy3-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I agree with the poor plot device comments previously mentioned. But I think this movie is very important. Now, I am quite OK with men, I am not a feminist, nor do I have any distaste for strong-willed or -minded men. But I think the movie is actually about the husband and about a common problem with men. Bliss presents the idea that very few western men allow the notion of a balanced male, taught in Eastern philosophies and faiths, anywhere near their minds. Stamps's character is presented as the balanced man, although almost ridiculously so. Anyway, I think Bliss shows how a man can use his strength to be a more gentle, confident leader, who is even more sexually alluring and commanding, than a common American man. In the West, men have been programmed to away from their feminine side(read: communicator, appreciative of beauty, nurturer). I think this movie wants to say that men who understand it and embrace it can do amazing things and have a great effect on the people in their world, and on themselves. This is emphasized by the abusive father. He shows the worst extreme: if left to twist up on himself, a man can become a terrible thing. And the extremity of Stamp's character is used to show how each man (ie, Craig) can pick and choose his own style. He doesn't have to be 'everything' like Stamp is, he can find his own way. I know the landslide at the end seems strange and out of place, but, it shows how Craig's character's changes helped in his own life: it gave him the patience and confidence with which to wait for his wife, and the gentleness to forgive her and try again. I think we are supposed to guess that if he had not changed, and they had split up, that a reconciliation could not have happened. I think in some ways the movie is great. Well, the story and theme are.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Staggering Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    henrikibsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As difficult as this movie is to watch and an as strange as it many seem in the end what we learn through watching it is that some men are capable of doing the most disturbing things, even when it's to their own female children and that we should be ever vigilant and in the case on the mother in this story not deny what the adult child finally realizes. One of things I learn to value about myself through the story is that we should all accept our bodies as they are and not try to make them into some males ideal. The story is a sad commentary on the male of the species, but I have to believe that the percentage of men that think that way are rare. At least I'd hope so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not for those who are shy about sex!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebl7
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When this movie first came out, sexual dysfunction in women was less commonly talked about than it is now. The interesting thing about this movie is that the focus is supposedly about female issues but it is, in fact, a rare glimpse into the issues that men have about sex. Not too many movies have two men talking openly and seriously about sex in a way that is respectful of woman. Although it is a work of fiction, there are many truths in this film. It stands the test of time and may well help a couple who are having similar problems to the couple in the movie, if they were to watch it together. Terence Stamp holds the movie together, offsetting some of the slightly amateurish acting on behalf of some of the lesser roles. His unconventional character is actually believable because it is acted with such sincerity. Craig Sheffer is much more convincing in his acting than Sheryl Lee but the overall texture of the film, combined with beautiful music throughout, is not diminished by a few flaws. Definitely worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to watch...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    harquill
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    But especially hard to watch because I am married to a BPD woman. My wife turned the movie on and then went to bed, leaving me to just take it all in. This movie is quite accurate in its portrayal of a BPD person in a relationship (especially when she was caulking the entire house, priceless). They do compulsive things and expect people to go along for the ride. Even more of a power struggle than one's average marriage. The only unrealistic part about the movie (besides Balthazar having sex with patients and being open about it) is that Lee's character is actually interested in getting better and shows such improvement in what seems to be short time. Often, facing such a difficult road proves too much for an already fragile psychology. Yes, discovering a history of sexual abuse in one's past would lead to some level of healing but there is a genetic component to BPD. Just like any disorder involving the brain, the affected person has to relearn how to interact with people they care about because they process stimuli differently. In reality, if a therapist discovered that a person is Borderline or NPD, they would likely advise the spouse to leave the marriage when there are no children involved. Recovery is not the norm, and yes, spouses of these people often have their own problems... In any event, this movie hit close to home and I felt like sharing. For people dealing with a BPD spouse "Bliss" it is both hard to and fulfilling to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bold and Blissfull
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    samkay1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bliss is psychological, Bliss is sexually Educational, Bliss is poetry, Bliss is a dream ...At the same time, Bliss is also sort of pretentious in that it thinks it is making important or original statements. At the most basic level, Bliss is about a couple who have trouble in bed, but it is in the way this is sold that makes the movie feel refreshing, and unique. Bliss is about as bold as they come. It succeeds in being erotic without being gratuitous and the photography is exceptional. Cinematic sex never looked so up close or intimate, not just physically but in words. David Cronenberg's Crash is the only film of the top of my head which may be able to match Bliss for....well.....detail. What I think could use a tune up about Bliss is Sheryl Lee. You get the sense that the material is a bit beyond her, perhaps a bit too distant. She has a bit of trouble breathing life into her role. This is essential seeing as she is the catalyst for the story. Her inability to have an orgasm puts enough pressure on her husband to seek out a rogue sexual therapist who agrees to train him in the art of making love (using nine stages of intimacy, if I quote him correctly). Bliss is not for credibility-obsessed viewers, nor is it a film for the impatient or the immature. It is sexuality on a professional level. It might not perfect but It certainly stands out, and is certainly recommendable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genuine, heartfelt, with imagination
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruce_Stern
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An exploration of a couple's, especially the man's, devotion to love and to his marriage. Despite her obsessive-compulsive behavior Joseph (Craig Sheffer) loves Maria (Sheryl Lee). Initially, their sexual love appears to be an expression of their love, but all is not right, most profoundly within Maria. They attempt to work with a therapist (Spalding Gray). Maria visits an unorthodox practitioner (Terence Stamp). Joseph's discovery of this fully opens his eyes, and eventually his heart. I've seen this movie many times, and I learn or re-learn a new lesson with each viewing about the meaning of love and devotion, the importance of self-discovery, despite its discomforts, and power of the human spirit to overcome a potentially catastrophic personal history. I love the unorthodox ideas presented by Stamp's character, although they aren't fully explained. There are gaps in the telling which ought to have been filled in. Yet, this is a movie that I believe many people and many couples would benefit from. The story-telling, the narrative drive, moves forward quite well-enough for those with lessened attention spans, yet devotes the time to exploring a loving relationship with heart, understanding, compassion and imagination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Waiting...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    damalfieri
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this is an unusual "inner growing" movie. It runs away from "easy, commercial topics" about sex, comedy and violence. Too bad for the money: good intentions (even if you consider them accomplished or not) must be rewarded, no matter if they make money or not. A lot of easy trash consumers will find it boring, or ridiculous. Few very experienced sexologists and psychologist will find it "naive". But sensitive people will find it at least inspiring, full of good willing. I applaud the director, because he dared to make a definitely non-commercial movie about sex. A serious movie, very honest. In my opinion, a must. I would like the director (or anyone else) to make more movies like this one, and the producers to give money to make them. OK, Balthazar is too much like the "perfect guru", incredibly steady and "I always say the right thing in the right moment". But the director balances this at the end, or at least tries to do it. OK, the husband falls too quickly for a standard occidental man into a reasonable mood, but... too often, in "normal" films, the characters act the natural, instinctive way, instead that in a mature way. The film is about people acting in a civilized, adult way. And, if that have the risk to be unbelievable, on the other side I like it. Men are not animals, it is time for movies (and books) to consider interesting characters like this. Sorry for my poor English!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An under rated exploration of the nature of sexual love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rboon33455
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bliss is a powerful and absorbing movie which explores the nature of adult sexuality and love. The plot revolves around the relationship of a newly married yuppie couple,Steve and Maria.We quickly discover that Maria is a compulsive neurotic bordering on the psychotic who is already in therapy and who soon reveals herself to be incapable of having an orgasm. Although an acutely sensitive person she is essentially very loving and copes by faking it. This leads her and eventually her husband to meet with Baltazzar, a sex therapist played with a beguiling calm charisma by Terence Stamp. They thus begin a difficult journey leading to some very important discoveries about themselves. On this journey the Director, Lance Young, engages strongly with such themes as the very nature of sex and love and our capacity to fully give.Steve is a reasonably sensitive man, but like most men has to deal with a strong sexual libido and a dominant male culture which encourages us to put its satisfaction first.His journey is therefore towards increasing awareness and selflessness which ultimately brings its own rewards as he begins to understand the nature of real love and to be able to give and receive it. The sex we see is never gratuitous and has an emotional reality which is rooted in the context of this developing relationship. It is light years away from porn and the simplistic banality of much Hollywood sexual depiction. I suspect many men will be challenged by it in the same way Steve was by the situation he found himself faced with, but it is a journey worth taking.Craig Sheffer and Sheryl Lee give performances as the young couple which ultimately draw us into the movie,but it is Stamp who holds the film together supported by an engaging and often beautiful sound track that heightens its mood. There is a nice twist at the end when Baltazzar embarks on his own new relationship and Steve wryly reflects on the difference between giving advice and putting it into practise with someone you love and whose personality you therefore accept as part of the deal.A film for adults with open hearts and minds. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    sublime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Laura C
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I see this movie on TV...For three times. I was touched. It is a masterpiece... I am a psychotherapist and first of all, I am a soul of a woman. I would recommended " Bliss " to my patients. I am sure that only special people can really feel this movie. I felt every touch between Joseph and Maria. First time when I see it, I was fall in love with Craig Sheffer. His performed was exceptionally also the Sheryl Lee performed. It is rich in sensuality and emotions. I cannot find the right words...This movie are worth watching. Moreover, feel it! I will try to find more movies like this one. However, I think it does not exist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finally, an intelligent movie about sex
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BillLamond
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you tired of "hard-edged" action, booty call, and fake-it-till-you-make-it sex scenes, give yourself a real treat and see "Bliss." This is a movie that entertains and educates by taking on a subject about which most people are absolutely ignorant, i.e. real Eros. With a beautiful soundtrack, intelligent dialog and fine acting, "Bliss" challenges our notions of sexuality and requires audiences to think outside the box. Women will recognize this film as...ah, finally! A bonus - the information about Eros portrayed in the film is absolutely accurate. This film is fine entertainment and a crash course in what sex is really all about - getting more turned on and staying that way. This should be required viewing for adolescent male Americam film-makers of all ages.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    hate to say it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amy3-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I agree with the poor plot device comments previously mentioned. But I think this movie is very important. Now, I am quite OK with men, I am not a feminist, nor do I have any distaste for strong-willed or -minded men. But I think the movie is actually about the husband and about a common problem with men. Bliss presents the idea that very few western men allow the notion of a balanced male, taught in Eastern philosophies and faiths, anywhere near their minds. Stamps's character is presented as the balanced man, although almost ridiculously so. Anyway, I think Bliss shows how a man can use his strength to be a more gentle, confident leader, who is even more sexually alluring and commanding, than a common American man. In the West, men have been programmed to away from their feminine side(read: communicator, appreciative of beauty, nurturer). I think this movie wants to say that men who understand it and embrace it can do amazing things and have a great effect on the people in their world, and on themselves. This is emphasized by the abusive father. He shows the worst extreme: if left to twist up on himself, a man can become a terrible thing. And the extremity of Stamp's character is used to show how each man (ie, Craig) can pick and choose his own style. He doesn't have to be 'everything' like Stamp is, he can find his own way. I know the landslide at the end seems strange and out of place, but, it shows how Craig's character's changes helped in his own life: it gave him the patience and confidence with which to wait for his wife, and the gentleness to forgive her and try again. I think we are supposed to guess that if he had not changed, and they had split up, that a reconciliation could not have happened. I think in some ways the movie is great. Well, the story and theme are.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
