<filme>
 <id>
  1179
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0113755
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Homem da Casa
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  4.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Ben Archer is not happy. His mother, Sandy, has just met a man, and it looks like things are pretty serious. Driven by a fear of abandonment, Ben tries anything and everything to ruin the "... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Ben Archer is not happy. His mother, Sandy, has just met a man, and it looks like things are pretty serious. Driven by a fear of abandonment, Ben tries anything and everything to ruin the "love bubble" which surrounds his mom. However, after Ben and Jack's experiences in the Indian Guides, the two become much closer.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   indian guide
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   divorce
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   family disapproval
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   revenge
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   camping
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   James Orr
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   David E. Peckinpah
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Richard Jefferies
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Chevy Chase
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Farrah Fawcett
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jonathan Taylor Thomas
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mildly hokey but wildly underrated Disney film. Certainly one of the very few Hollywood films I can personally relate with.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tootsielover68
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I understand the problems many people have with this movie. There are a few ridiculous subplots and hokey slapstick violence in a little over 90 minutes that seems redundant and ridiculous. But when I heard how underrated this movie actually really is I must say I was shocked. OK so there are some stupid subplots in the movie but so what? A lot of pre-teenagers (as well as early teenagers) can really learn a lot from this movie especially if they have experienced a family event like a divorce and having to deal with a step-parent. I am one who has had to deal with a divorce and a step-parent and they both are no day at the beach whatsoever. But the Jonathan Taylor Thomas character in this movie really reminded me of being younger and how I thought it was fun to do silly tricks and manipulations to get my step-parent to go away. And with all the hype of Farrah Fawcett recently passing away I think a lot of people who are interested in her career should look back at this movie as this was one of her very few Hollywood theatrical films. She had much more success on the smaller screen as we all know. I think a lot of people also had trouble with this movie because it tried to make Chevy Chase into more of a heartwarming character unlike his "Caddyshack" and "National Lampoon's Vacation" series characters. Why people had a bad reaction to that is a mystery to me. Comedians like Chase should not be playing silly oafs their whole career. Sometimes it is OK to change characters if you are going in the right direction and for the most part I think Chase was doing so here. And George Wendt's supporting performance as the Indian Guide leader I thought was very good and made him into a more endearing and heartwarming character unlike his Norm Peterson fame on "Cheers". As aforementioned a few things in this film do not work. For instance on the camping trip that Chase and Thomas attend in the woods with the Indian Guides and Chase tells a campfire story it is supposed to be funny but it really isn't.At least that monologue could have been written better for Chase. The supporting charactersmake that scene more interesting. I also don't like the subplot of the man who wants to kill Chase because he sent his father to prison as a prosecutor for committing a crime. We get some hokey dialog once again there and then it turns into a semi "Home Alone" rip off trying to scare away the bad guys with "Home Alone" like booby traps. But aside from those flaws I think "Man of the House" on the whole is a good film that parents and kids alike can enjoy and learn a lesson from. And with all the parents complaining about content in films today and how "family films don't exist" I think this one blows that theory. There is only one mild discussion about sex (it is a pre-teenager film what else do you expect?) profanity is very mild, and the violence is done on such a slapstick level that you cannot take it seriously at all. By the end of the film Thomas likes having Chase for a stepfather and now life will be great with his mom and Chase. I only wish the ending of this movie could have happened with the situation in my parents divorce and my later teenage years. All I am saying is ignore this movies flaws and go along for the ride. If you have experienced something like this in real life this will be a movie you will be glad you didn't miss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Man of the House Needs A Woman's Touch **12
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is basically a story of trust and building family relationships. When mom, the late Farrah Fawcett brings Chevy Chase in the house to live, obvious problems shall result when her 11 year old son rebels at the prospect of having to share his mother with this man. The situation is not helped by the fact that at the age of 5, the boy saw his father walk out on his mother and wave goodbye. Chase hopes to build this trust by introducing the child to a club of fathers emulating Indian chiefs with their sons. This becomes rather corny at best. Fawcett was given very little to do here and I wonder why she accepted this part. Chase, a prosecuting attorney, incurs the wrath of a mobster's son by putting the father away for 50 years. The son vows vengeance which interferes with Chase trying to establish a relationship with the boy. The last part of the film is inane since the son and his crew plot to do Chase in while the latter is on a camping trip with the boy and others. The attempt at turning this into a home alone type does not work and George Wendt, who portrays a shop teacher and member of the tribe, looks more like Friar Tuck. How the group turns the table on the mobster's son and his group is brief and ridiculous. More could have been made of this in a missed opportunity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comic inanities served up to families as something unique and gut-busting...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mind-bogglingly bad Disney comedy pits middle-aged sweethearts Chevy Chase and Farrah Fawcett against Fawcett's prankish pre-teen son Jonathan Taylor Thomas (that smug Keebler elf from the TV sitcom "Home Improvement"). After single mom Farrah brings new love-interest Chevy home to meet her kid, Taylor resorts to juvenile tomfoolery to scare the suitor away...sound familiar? Taking its cue from "The Parent Trap", but blessedly giving us only one child at the helm, this lame-duck script has nowhere to go after the initial set-up. Nice to see Chase and Fawcett together (the original choices for "Foul Play"), but the comic chaos which erupts here is only for undiscriminating viewers. * from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, Heartwarming, and Genuinely Sweet.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fiendish_Dramaturgy
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As usual, I'm in the minority. I love this movie. Chevy is so funny as the step dad to Jonathan Taylor Thomas and would-be husband to Farrah Fawcet. I loved Chevy in this. He plays characters completely off the cuff, and I found his character endearing, but what I really liked about this movie was Farrah. She still shines after all those years, in a completely engaging performance. Jonathan Taylor Thomas is perfectly precocious in his role as Fawcett's son, a boy who lost his father, and refuses to accept Chevy as an adequate substitute. It's funny, heartwarming, and genuinely sweet. It rates a 6.7/10 from... the Fiend :.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pearlangel2291
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie. It's been a favorite of mine since I was a little kid, and I love it to this day. Jonathan Taylor Thomas is hysterical as Ben, Chevy Chase truly embodies Jack, and Farrah Fawcett is great as Sandy. I love the Indian Guides characters; the kids and their fathers have great chemistry. For anyone who doesn't like this movie, I have to wonder if you were watching the same one I was. If you're ever looking for a funny, heartfelt family comedy, then this movie is definitely for you. I highly recommend it to everyone. P.S. I actually learned the rain dance. What does that tell you (apart from me being slightly obsessed)?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chevy Chase, he fell from grace...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some events are just so ironic that they just seem too weird to be true. One of the best examples, at least in my opinion, is what happened to Chevy Chase. You see, in the '80s he was one of the top stars, with movies like "Vacation" and "Fletch". Now, he was not friends with the president during that period, nor with the next president, but he was friends with Bill Clinton. That's where it gets bizarre: a few months after Slick Willie took the oath of office, Chase got his own TV show...and it failed miserably, turning Chase into a laughingstock. In short, Chevy Chase went from a star under his enemies to a joke under his friend. To compound this, the show's failure was followed by embarrassing movies like "Cops and Robbersons" and "Man of the House". I will say that the latter isn't god-awful, but it's not really worth much. Mostly just another story about a son and stepfather trying to bond. If nothing else, I guess that it just seems sad that Chase went from "SNL" to this (maybe it's also the flick's status as a Disney movie). But really, Chase has done better than this, as have Farrah Fawcett and George Wendt. Don't make it your first choice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you haven't seen this movie, you should!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephanie_brewer928
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the best movie to watch is you are feeling down. The Man of the House is just so funny, I could watch this movie over and over, and never get tired of watching it. Even now, just writing about it, makes me smile. You have to watch this movie if you haven't seen it yet! Just for fun, if you have seen, watch it again! I relate to J.T.T. in this movie, I have done some pretty mean things to my step-dad, but never anything like making him join an Indian Guide club. The actors in this movie, just crack me up. Also, the songs picked out for this movie just fit so perfectly. I love all the songs on this movie! The parts with music playing, just makes the movie even funnier some how! All I have left to say is, I love this movie! It is great!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Worth It!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Friesen_471
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a terrible waste of 96 min. A story of a boy (Johnathan Taylor Thomas)and how his dad leaves his mother (Farrah Fawcett) for his secretary. Then Johnathan and his mother have wonderful times together skipping on the beach and collecting shells and junk. Then Chevy Chase comes along and the movie get's more boring than it already was to begin with. In my opinion, Chevy is altogether not funny enough to make this movie at least a mediocre comedy. It's a comedy with hardly any laughs throughout the entire movie. You start to get bored with how not funny the movie is after the first 20 min. Chevy Chase is dull and amazingly unfunny. Johnathan Taylor Thomas is alright, but hey it's Johnathan Taylor Thomas... can he be any better than alright? Farrah Fawcett is probably the best part of this movie, everything else seems to fail miserably. All in all, not recommended in the least. Go spend your money on a better movie like 'Howard the Duck'. 1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Goey Rating: GFF (Great Family Film)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    goey312
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great movie for families to watch together. This is a story about a boy who is trying to stop h is mom form being with her new boyfriend. Of course nothing is ever easy and things never go as planned. To add to everything the new boyfriend has a dark secret. One that he doesn't want the boy or his mother to know. When the secret does get out everything blows up and the story gets very interesting. Jonathan Taylor Thomas does a great job playing a kid who whats to keep things with just himself and his mother. I was really impressed with this movie and was really entertained by it. It is definitely worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't understand...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hogwarts814
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why this film is so harshly rated. I viewed it in English class, and can truly refer to the phrase "I laughed, I cried." I was deeply touched by the stepfather's urge to become closer to his stepson, and the Indian Guides were full of humor. I like two particular songs in this movie; "Gonna make you sweat (Everybody dance now)" and "Enya" from Pure Moods. I can't believe I went a whole decade without seeing this. I really don't think it's a waste, and I don't think that it "stunk". Sure, some things were a little cheesy, but there are hardly any movies today without a few cheesy things. It seemed very funny to me, and should at least be ranked a 7.5, I think.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mildly hokey but wildly underrated Disney film. Certainly one of the very few Hollywood films I can personally relate with.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tootsielover68
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I understand the problems many people have with this movie. There are a few ridiculous subplots and hokey slapstick violence in a little over 90 minutes that seems redundant and ridiculous. But when I heard how underrated this movie actually really is I must say I was shocked. OK so there are some stupid subplots in the movie but so what? A lot of pre-teenagers (as well as early teenagers) can really learn a lot from this movie especially if they have experienced a family event like a divorce and having to deal with a step-parent. I am one who has had to deal with a divorce and a step-parent and they both are no day at the beach whatsoever. But the Jonathan Taylor Thomas character in this movie really reminded me of being younger and how I thought it was fun to do silly tricks and manipulations to get my step-parent to go away. And with all the hype of Farrah Fawcett recently passing away I think a lot of people who are interested in her career should look back at this movie as this was one of her very few Hollywood theatrical films. She had much more success on the smaller screen as we all know. I think a lot of people also had trouble with this movie because it tried to make Chevy Chase into more of a heartwarming character unlike his "Caddyshack" and "National Lampoon's Vacation" series characters. Why people had a bad reaction to that is a mystery to me. Comedians like Chase should not be playing silly oafs their whole career. Sometimes it is OK to change characters if you are going in the right direction and for the most part I think Chase was doing so here. And George Wendt's supporting performance as the Indian Guide leader I thought was very good and made him into a more endearing and heartwarming character unlike his Norm Peterson fame on "Cheers". As aforementioned a few things in this film do not work. For instance on the camping trip that Chase and Thomas attend in the woods with the Indian Guides and Chase tells a campfire story it is supposed to be funny but it really isn't.At least that monologue could have been written better for Chase. The supporting charactersmake that scene more interesting. I also don't like the subplot of the man who wants to kill Chase because he sent his father to prison as a prosecutor for committing a crime. We get some hokey dialog once again there and then it turns into a semi "Home Alone" rip off trying to scare away the bad guys with "Home Alone" like booby traps. But aside from those flaws I think "Man of the House" on the whole is a good film that parents and kids alike can enjoy and learn a lesson from. And with all the parents complaining about content in films today and how "family films don't exist" I think this one blows that theory. There is only one mild discussion about sex (it is a pre-teenager film what else do you expect?) profanity is very mild, and the violence is done on such a slapstick level that you cannot take it seriously at all. By the end of the film Thomas likes having Chase for a stepfather and now life will be great with his mom and Chase. I only wish the ending of this movie could have happened with the situation in my parents divorce and my later teenage years. All I am saying is ignore this movies flaws and go along for the ride. If you have experienced something like this in real life this will be a movie you will be glad you didn't miss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Man of the House Needs A Woman's Touch **12
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is basically a story of trust and building family relationships. When mom, the late Farrah Fawcett brings Chevy Chase in the house to live, obvious problems shall result when her 11 year old son rebels at the prospect of having to share his mother with this man. The situation is not helped by the fact that at the age of 5, the boy saw his father walk out on his mother and wave goodbye. Chase hopes to build this trust by introducing the child to a club of fathers emulating Indian chiefs with their sons. This becomes rather corny at best. Fawcett was given very little to do here and I wonder why she accepted this part. Chase, a prosecuting attorney, incurs the wrath of a mobster's son by putting the father away for 50 years. The son vows vengeance which interferes with Chase trying to establish a relationship with the boy. The last part of the film is inane since the son and his crew plot to do Chase in while the latter is on a camping trip with the boy and others. The attempt at turning this into a home alone type does not work and George Wendt, who portrays a shop teacher and member of the tribe, looks more like Friar Tuck. How the group turns the table on the mobster's son and his group is brief and ridiculous. More could have been made of this in a missed opportunity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comic inanities served up to families as something unique and gut-busting...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mind-bogglingly bad Disney comedy pits middle-aged sweethearts Chevy Chase and Farrah Fawcett against Fawcett's prankish pre-teen son Jonathan Taylor Thomas (that smug Keebler elf from the TV sitcom "Home Improvement"). After single mom Farrah brings new love-interest Chevy home to meet her kid, Taylor resorts to juvenile tomfoolery to scare the suitor away...sound familiar? Taking its cue from "The Parent Trap", but blessedly giving us only one child at the helm, this lame-duck script has nowhere to go after the initial set-up. Nice to see Chase and Fawcett together (the original choices for "Foul Play"), but the comic chaos which erupts here is only for undiscriminating viewers. * from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, Heartwarming, and Genuinely Sweet.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fiendish_Dramaturgy
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As usual, I'm in the minority. I love this movie. Chevy is so funny as the step dad to Jonathan Taylor Thomas and would-be husband to Farrah Fawcet. I loved Chevy in this. He plays characters completely off the cuff, and I found his character endearing, but what I really liked about this movie was Farrah. She still shines after all those years, in a completely engaging performance. Jonathan Taylor Thomas is perfectly precocious in his role as Fawcett's son, a boy who lost his father, and refuses to accept Chevy as an adequate substitute. It's funny, heartwarming, and genuinely sweet. It rates a 6.7/10 from... the Fiend :.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pearlangel2291
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie. It's been a favorite of mine since I was a little kid, and I love it to this day. Jonathan Taylor Thomas is hysterical as Ben, Chevy Chase truly embodies Jack, and Farrah Fawcett is great as Sandy. I love the Indian Guides characters; the kids and their fathers have great chemistry. For anyone who doesn't like this movie, I have to wonder if you were watching the same one I was. If you're ever looking for a funny, heartfelt family comedy, then this movie is definitely for you. I highly recommend it to everyone. P.S. I actually learned the rain dance. What does that tell you (apart from me being slightly obsessed)?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chevy Chase, he fell from grace...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some events are just so ironic that they just seem too weird to be true. One of the best examples, at least in my opinion, is what happened to Chevy Chase. You see, in the '80s he was one of the top stars, with movies like "Vacation" and "Fletch". Now, he was not friends with the president during that period, nor with the next president, but he was friends with Bill Clinton. That's where it gets bizarre: a few months after Slick Willie took the oath of office, Chase got his own TV show...and it failed miserably, turning Chase into a laughingstock. In short, Chevy Chase went from a star under his enemies to a joke under his friend. To compound this, the show's failure was followed by embarrassing movies like "Cops and Robbersons" and "Man of the House". I will say that the latter isn't god-awful, but it's not really worth much. Mostly just another story about a son and stepfather trying to bond. If nothing else, I guess that it just seems sad that Chase went from "SNL" to this (maybe it's also the flick's status as a Disney movie). But really, Chase has done better than this, as have Farrah Fawcett and George Wendt. Don't make it your first choice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you haven't seen this movie, you should!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephanie_brewer928
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the best movie to watch is you are feeling down. The Man of the House is just so funny, I could watch this movie over and over, and never get tired of watching it. Even now, just writing about it, makes me smile. You have to watch this movie if you haven't seen it yet! Just for fun, if you have seen, watch it again! I relate to J.T.T. in this movie, I have done some pretty mean things to my step-dad, but never anything like making him join an Indian Guide club. The actors in this movie, just crack me up. Also, the songs picked out for this movie just fit so perfectly. I love all the songs on this movie! The parts with music playing, just makes the movie even funnier some how! All I have left to say is, I love this movie! It is great!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Worth It!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Friesen_471
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a terrible waste of 96 min. A story of a boy (Johnathan Taylor Thomas)and how his dad leaves his mother (Farrah Fawcett) for his secretary. Then Johnathan and his mother have wonderful times together skipping on the beach and collecting shells and junk. Then Chevy Chase comes along and the movie get's more boring than it already was to begin with. In my opinion, Chevy is altogether not funny enough to make this movie at least a mediocre comedy. It's a comedy with hardly any laughs throughout the entire movie. You start to get bored with how not funny the movie is after the first 20 min. Chevy Chase is dull and amazingly unfunny. Johnathan Taylor Thomas is alright, but hey it's Johnathan Taylor Thomas... can he be any better than alright? Farrah Fawcett is probably the best part of this movie, everything else seems to fail miserably. All in all, not recommended in the least. Go spend your money on a better movie like 'Howard the Duck'. 1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Goey Rating: GFF (Great Family Film)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    goey312
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great movie for families to watch together. This is a story about a boy who is trying to stop h is mom form being with her new boyfriend. Of course nothing is ever easy and things never go as planned. To add to everything the new boyfriend has a dark secret. One that he doesn't want the boy or his mother to know. When the secret does get out everything blows up and the story gets very interesting. Jonathan Taylor Thomas does a great job playing a kid who whats to keep things with just himself and his mother. I was really impressed with this movie and was really entertained by it. It is definitely worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't understand...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hogwarts814
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why this film is so harshly rated. I viewed it in English class, and can truly refer to the phrase "I laughed, I cried." I was deeply touched by the stepfather's urge to become closer to his stepson, and the Indian Guides were full of humor. I like two particular songs in this movie; "Gonna make you sweat (Everybody dance now)" and "Enya" from Pure Moods. I can't believe I went a whole decade without seeing this. I really don't think it's a waste, and I don't think that it "stunk". Sure, some things were a little cheesy, but there are hardly any movies today without a few cheesy things. It seemed very funny to me, and should at least be ranked a 7.5, I think.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mildly hokey but wildly underrated Disney film. Certainly one of the very few Hollywood films I can personally relate with.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tootsielover68
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I understand the problems many people have with this movie. There are a few ridiculous subplots and hokey slapstick violence in a little over 90 minutes that seems redundant and ridiculous. But when I heard how underrated this movie actually really is I must say I was shocked. OK so there are some stupid subplots in the movie but so what? A lot of pre-teenagers (as well as early teenagers) can really learn a lot from this movie especially if they have experienced a family event like a divorce and having to deal with a step-parent. I am one who has had to deal with a divorce and a step-parent and they both are no day at the beach whatsoever. But the Jonathan Taylor Thomas character in this movie really reminded me of being younger and how I thought it was fun to do silly tricks and manipulations to get my step-parent to go away. And with all the hype of Farrah Fawcett recently passing away I think a lot of people who are interested in her career should look back at this movie as this was one of her very few Hollywood theatrical films. She had much more success on the smaller screen as we all know. I think a lot of people also had trouble with this movie because it tried to make Chevy Chase into more of a heartwarming character unlike his "Caddyshack" and "National Lampoon's Vacation" series characters. Why people had a bad reaction to that is a mystery to me. Comedians like Chase should not be playing silly oafs their whole career. Sometimes it is OK to change characters if you are going in the right direction and for the most part I think Chase was doing so here. And George Wendt's supporting performance as the Indian Guide leader I thought was very good and made him into a more endearing and heartwarming character unlike his Norm Peterson fame on "Cheers". As aforementioned a few things in this film do not work. For instance on the camping trip that Chase and Thomas attend in the woods with the Indian Guides and Chase tells a campfire story it is supposed to be funny but it really isn't.At least that monologue could have been written better for Chase. The supporting charactersmake that scene more interesting. I also don't like the subplot of the man who wants to kill Chase because he sent his father to prison as a prosecutor for committing a crime. We get some hokey dialog once again there and then it turns into a semi "Home Alone" rip off trying to scare away the bad guys with "Home Alone" like booby traps. But aside from those flaws I think "Man of the House" on the whole is a good film that parents and kids alike can enjoy and learn a lesson from. And with all the parents complaining about content in films today and how "family films don't exist" I think this one blows that theory. There is only one mild discussion about sex (it is a pre-teenager film what else do you expect?) profanity is very mild, and the violence is done on such a slapstick level that you cannot take it seriously at all. By the end of the film Thomas likes having Chase for a stepfather and now life will be great with his mom and Chase. I only wish the ending of this movie could have happened with the situation in my parents divorce and my later teenage years. All I am saying is ignore this movies flaws and go along for the ride. If you have experienced something like this in real life this will be a movie you will be glad you didn't miss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Man of the House Needs A Woman's Touch **12
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is basically a story of trust and building family relationships. When mom, the late Farrah Fawcett brings Chevy Chase in the house to live, obvious problems shall result when her 11 year old son rebels at the prospect of having to share his mother with this man. The situation is not helped by the fact that at the age of 5, the boy saw his father walk out on his mother and wave goodbye. Chase hopes to build this trust by introducing the child to a club of fathers emulating Indian chiefs with their sons. This becomes rather corny at best. Fawcett was given very little to do here and I wonder why she accepted this part. Chase, a prosecuting attorney, incurs the wrath of a mobster's son by putting the father away for 50 years. The son vows vengeance which interferes with Chase trying to establish a relationship with the boy. The last part of the film is inane since the son and his crew plot to do Chase in while the latter is on a camping trip with the boy and others. The attempt at turning this into a home alone type does not work and George Wendt, who portrays a shop teacher and member of the tribe, looks more like Friar Tuck. How the group turns the table on the mobster's son and his group is brief and ridiculous. More could have been made of this in a missed opportunity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comic inanities served up to families as something unique and gut-busting...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mind-bogglingly bad Disney comedy pits middle-aged sweethearts Chevy Chase and Farrah Fawcett against Fawcett's prankish pre-teen son Jonathan Taylor Thomas (that smug Keebler elf from the TV sitcom "Home Improvement"). After single mom Farrah brings new love-interest Chevy home to meet her kid, Taylor resorts to juvenile tomfoolery to scare the suitor away...sound familiar? Taking its cue from "The Parent Trap", but blessedly giving us only one child at the helm, this lame-duck script has nowhere to go after the initial set-up. Nice to see Chase and Fawcett together (the original choices for "Foul Play"), but the comic chaos which erupts here is only for undiscriminating viewers. * from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, Heartwarming, and Genuinely Sweet.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fiendish_Dramaturgy
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As usual, I'm in the minority. I love this movie. Chevy is so funny as the step dad to Jonathan Taylor Thomas and would-be husband to Farrah Fawcet. I loved Chevy in this. He plays characters completely off the cuff, and I found his character endearing, but what I really liked about this movie was Farrah. She still shines after all those years, in a completely engaging performance. Jonathan Taylor Thomas is perfectly precocious in his role as Fawcett's son, a boy who lost his father, and refuses to accept Chevy as an adequate substitute. It's funny, heartwarming, and genuinely sweet. It rates a 6.7/10 from... the Fiend :.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pearlangel2291
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie. It's been a favorite of mine since I was a little kid, and I love it to this day. Jonathan Taylor Thomas is hysterical as Ben, Chevy Chase truly embodies Jack, and Farrah Fawcett is great as Sandy. I love the Indian Guides characters; the kids and their fathers have great chemistry. For anyone who doesn't like this movie, I have to wonder if you were watching the same one I was. If you're ever looking for a funny, heartfelt family comedy, then this movie is definitely for you. I highly recommend it to everyone. P.S. I actually learned the rain dance. What does that tell you (apart from me being slightly obsessed)?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chevy Chase, he fell from grace...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some events are just so ironic that they just seem too weird to be true. One of the best examples, at least in my opinion, is what happened to Chevy Chase. You see, in the '80s he was one of the top stars, with movies like "Vacation" and "Fletch". Now, he was not friends with the president during that period, nor with the next president, but he was friends with Bill Clinton. That's where it gets bizarre: a few months after Slick Willie took the oath of office, Chase got his own TV show...and it failed miserably, turning Chase into a laughingstock. In short, Chevy Chase went from a star under his enemies to a joke under his friend. To compound this, the show's failure was followed by embarrassing movies like "Cops and Robbersons" and "Man of the House". I will say that the latter isn't god-awful, but it's not really worth much. Mostly just another story about a son and stepfather trying to bond. If nothing else, I guess that it just seems sad that Chase went from "SNL" to this (maybe it's also the flick's status as a Disney movie). But really, Chase has done better than this, as have Farrah Fawcett and George Wendt. Don't make it your first choice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you haven't seen this movie, you should!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephanie_brewer928
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the best movie to watch is you are feeling down. The Man of the House is just so funny, I could watch this movie over and over, and never get tired of watching it. Even now, just writing about it, makes me smile. You have to watch this movie if you haven't seen it yet! Just for fun, if you have seen, watch it again! I relate to J.T.T. in this movie, I have done some pretty mean things to my step-dad, but never anything like making him join an Indian Guide club. The actors in this movie, just crack me up. Also, the songs picked out for this movie just fit so perfectly. I love all the songs on this movie! The parts with music playing, just makes the movie even funnier some how! All I have left to say is, I love this movie! It is great!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Worth It!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Friesen_471
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a terrible waste of 96 min. A story of a boy (Johnathan Taylor Thomas)and how his dad leaves his mother (Farrah Fawcett) for his secretary. Then Johnathan and his mother have wonderful times together skipping on the beach and collecting shells and junk. Then Chevy Chase comes along and the movie get's more boring than it already was to begin with. In my opinion, Chevy is altogether not funny enough to make this movie at least a mediocre comedy. It's a comedy with hardly any laughs throughout the entire movie. You start to get bored with how not funny the movie is after the first 20 min. Chevy Chase is dull and amazingly unfunny. Johnathan Taylor Thomas is alright, but hey it's Johnathan Taylor Thomas... can he be any better than alright? Farrah Fawcett is probably the best part of this movie, everything else seems to fail miserably. All in all, not recommended in the least. Go spend your money on a better movie like 'Howard the Duck'. 1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Goey Rating: GFF (Great Family Film)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    goey312
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great movie for families to watch together. This is a story about a boy who is trying to stop h is mom form being with her new boyfriend. Of course nothing is ever easy and things never go as planned. To add to everything the new boyfriend has a dark secret. One that he doesn't want the boy or his mother to know. When the secret does get out everything blows up and the story gets very interesting. Jonathan Taylor Thomas does a great job playing a kid who whats to keep things with just himself and his mother. I was really impressed with this movie and was really entertained by it. It is definitely worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't understand...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hogwarts814
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why this film is so harshly rated. I viewed it in English class, and can truly refer to the phrase "I laughed, I cried." I was deeply touched by the stepfather's urge to become closer to his stepson, and the Indian Guides were full of humor. I like two particular songs in this movie; "Gonna make you sweat (Everybody dance now)" and "Enya" from Pure Moods. I can't believe I went a whole decade without seeing this. I really don't think it's a waste, and I don't think that it "stunk". Sure, some things were a little cheesy, but there are hardly any movies today without a few cheesy things. It seemed very funny to me, and should at least be ranked a 7.5, I think.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
