<filme>
 <id>
  118
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0117998
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Twister
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Bill and Jo Harding, advanced storm chasers on the brink of divorce, must join together to create an advanced weather alert system by putting themselves in the cross-hairs of extremely violent tornadoes.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  TV weatherman Bill Harding is trying to get his tornado-hunter wife, Jo, to sign divorce papers so he can marry his girlfriend Melissa. But Mother Nature, in the form of a series of intense storms sweeping across Oklahoma, has other plans. Soon the three have joined the team of stormchasers as they attempt to insert a revolutionary measuring device into the very heart of several extremely violent tornados.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   divorce
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   tornado
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   storm
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   divorce papers
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   storm chaser
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Jan de Bont
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Michael Crichton
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Anne-Marie Martin
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Helen Hunt
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Bill Paxton
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Cary Elwes
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Helen Hunt & Tornadoes.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Helen Hunt is Dr. Jo Harding, a storm chaser in Oklahoma tracking a series of violent tornadoes sweeping through the state. Bill Paxton is Bill Harding, her soon-to-be ex-husband(and TV weatherman) who is trying to get Jo to sign divorce papers so that he can marry his girlfriend Melissa(played by Jamie Gertz) They soon team up to chase the storms, because of a hated rival Dr. Jonas Miller(played by Carey Elwes) who is also following the storms. Jo wants to close to a tornado in order to test a new weather measuring device that could revolutionize tornado detection, but the trick is in getting near one without being killed... Highly entertaining film is well directed by Jan De Bont, who creates a breathless feel to the story, and has a fine cast of characters, especially Helen Hunt, who is a knockout. May stretch credibility at times, but not enough to matter. This is a fun movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loads of flying fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bill Harding (Bill Paxton) is trying to get his tornado-hunter wife Dr. Jo Harding (Helen Hunt) to sign the divorce papers, marry his girlfriend Melissa (Jami Gertz), and start his new job as a TV weatherman. But forgetting the divorce papers, a chance to use their latest contraption Dorothy, and an old nemesis Dr. Jonas Miller (Cary Elwes) pushes Bill to come along for a ride to hunt tornadoes. This is a fun wild thrill ride worthy of all the popcorn. The characters are all straight forward. There isn't much subtlety. They do some fun jokes. It's all about the roller coaster ride. The CG is pretty good for its times. The action is big fun whether it's a falling truck or a flying cow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Plain Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grade: B+. Twister is always better then I remember. The film is very fun with its chase sequences, but I always think down on it then watch it and change my mind. Bill Harding, a former twister chasing legend who is starting a new life with a new fianc&eacute;e, goes back to see the old gang to get divorce papers signed, but sees his old project finished called Dorothy to put twister reading devices inside a twister to read how stable it is for better preparation for tornadoes. When a twister hits, he tags along and is slowly drawing away from his fianc&eacute;e and to his ex Jo. He meets old friends like Dustin and Aunt Meg and also enemies like Jonas, a rival group of twister chasers who also are doing the same thing but do it for the money, not science but have better gear. After chasing for a while, they are resting at a theater when a F5 twister hits on them and nearly destroys the area but they survive but it hits Meg. His fianc&eacute;e also leaves him because she sees he still loves Jo and she needs him and the film ends with Jonas dying and them being successful but also they go inside the center of a tornado and live. Totally unrealistic, but freaking awesome to see. The film has things that don't work well with the story and characters that are annoying, but there are ones that are funny (Dustin, Meg) and the twisters are impressive and seem to be grabbed every time they chase one. It is just a lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cow?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    first off the flying cow. wow that is like one of my favorite scenes in any movie period and the tag lines that were presented in the movie,, after seeing the Cow for the first and subsequent times. Bill Paxton and Helen Hunt play off of each other very well in this picture.. The director was about 15 years ahead of his time.. look what we have today in the 2010's , the weather channel storm-chaser's several programs about that. I love the idea that in this movie you have dueling teams of Storm Chaser's the other team is headed up by a cocky Jake Busey. throughout the movie you will see some of the most horrifying scenes of twisters that can be put on film,, the funnel clouds , the wall the spinning rotation,, the vortex,, you can tell i'm a weather junkie can't you.. I live in the Midwest now and I have seen one tornado high up in the sky once right over my house,, thank god it didn't touch down,, found out later it was a F1 but still, I think that if people would stop and watch Twister seriously maybe some people in the country especially the Midwest would be better suited to deal with a tragedy like this, see you can actually learn a few things from watching a movie these days,, I loved this movie,, it is my "perfect storm".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Film with Great CGI (for it's time)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike48128
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of course today's CGI is more realistic, but this film was made in 1996! That's why I prefer my old VHS version. The pan & scan is annoying but the slight "fuzziness" makes the CGI appear more convincing. The DVD is too clear! Otherwise, turn down your sharpness and enjoy maybe the best definitive tornado movie ever made! Stormchasers in Oklahoma at the peak of the May season. The plot, at times, is cloying and slows down the action. However, Jo (Helen Hunt) believes that the tornadoes are stalking her and Bill (Paxton) is great as the "human barometer". So much eerie similarity to this year's real disaster: It's set in Oklahoma. It's a "F5" storm. Are the storms technically accurate? Probably not. I still love that poor flying cow. The gasoline tanker that almost seems to explode twice? Driving through a house turned on it's side?--both impossible, of course. I don't like the sub-plots: Bill's annoying sex therapist fianc&eacute; and the "Dorothy" telemetry tracking gizmos don't seen logical. Was this based on an actual invention? A lot of little "Spielberg" touches. The storms seem to "growl". Intentionally humorous scenes and dialog. Jo seems to "see" her family standing in the rubble of her Aunt's town, which of course is impossible. It's a great roller coaster ride all the way, even on the home "screen". The whirligigs were designed by that famous artist who just died. Today, we have almost a 15 min. tornado warning because of Doppler Radar, but it still isn't enough time to evacuate. This year in Oklahoma (2013), thousands were injured, displaced, and many died. This movie needs to be re-released on the big screen with IMAX 3D and updated special effects.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK but not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesgustina
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overall not that bad of a movie, even with the gross inaccuracies that come with the portrayal of storm chasing in it. I always enjoy watching Twister when it's on because its just a simple summer blockbuster with some cool special effects. As other people have pointed out, the science is a good ways off, but unless you're a meteorologist or weather enthusiast it shouldn't be particularly bothersome. As a chaser, I'm able to enjoy this movie because it does get the feeling of a chase almost dead on. The excitement on a day before the first storms go up is caught pretty well. Now to the science part, while Twister has many flaws (the preliminary ratings before the tornado has even dissipated to name one), some of the issues listed below are totally false. Violent tornadoes can and do happen at night. Boundary layer cooling does not mean violent tornadoes cannot occur at night (a la Greensburg, Kansas EF5 in 2007 or the Super Tuesday Outbreak in 2008). Next, while tornadoes do not usually last for hours, tornadoes can and have lasted for more than 75 minutes (Tuscaloosa EF4 April 27, 2011. Lasted from 3:40 CDT to 5:50 CDT).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    godzillaman631
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a huge Michael Crichton fan ever since Jurassic Park, Timeline, and The Lost World. After watching this movie I saw a Michael Crichton novel brought to life. Every character is fleshed out and memorable from Dusty to Beltzer and Bill. If you are a Michael Crichton you will love this movie. This movie is well acted by Bill Paxton and Helen Hunt. The scenarios they are in a very realistic with real tension there and as well some moments where there are character moments. This movie makes you feel for them and feel like part of the group. Twister has beautiful visual effects by ILM and they still hold up today. I was surprised when I saw the score for the movie as a 6.1. I give this movie a 10/10. A great 90's movie to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun and Exciting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Uriah43
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Bill Harding" (Bill Paxton) has just become a television weatherman and he wants a divorce. So he takes his new fianc&eacute; "Melissa Reeves" (Jami Gertz) with him to ask his soon-to-be ex-wife "Jo Harding" (Helen Hunt) to sign the divorce papers. Since she and her group of colleagues are in the field trying to chase tornadoes, that's where he and Melissa have to go as well. Now, prior to becoming a weatherman he and Jo were working on a recently completed project they named "Dorothy" which was a device capable of measuring scientific data within a twister. But in order for it to work they have to put it directly in front of a tornado as it is bearing down on them. If that wasn't bad enough, a former co-worker named "Jonas Miller" (Cary Elwes) has stolen their idea and has formed his own group. However, unlike Jo's group, Jonas and his group have corporate sponsorship. This has enabled them to build their own version of "Dorothy" which he has named "D.O.T. 3". Jonas and his group also have more sophisticated equipment. But Jo's group now has Bill and his instincts are superior to any man or machine. At any rate, rather than spoiling the movie for those who haven't seen it, I won't go any further with the plot. However, I will say that this film is fun and exciting. The special effects were excellent and I liked the supporting cast of characters. And if it wasn't for some of the incredibly preposterous scenarios, I probably would have rated it higher. Even so, it's still an enjoyable movie all the same.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Keating
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching this film is genuinely one of the worst things that has ever happened to me. I was warned but went ahead and did it. I could spend hours explaining why this is so bad in almost every possible way, but can't be bothered. Its the films fault. It has actually sucked all meaning out of my life. Why would a film do this? I mean Mac and me was bad, as was Howard the duck, but this is one of those films that was marginally successful. I don't like giving films a 1 out of 10, just as I'm reluctant to give a film a 10 out of 10, but this film should be quarantined it is so bad. It is a danger to people with high blood pressure or who may be suicidal. There should be a health warning. People should be made aware that swine flu is nothing compared to this. I even had that novovirus thing and that was fun compared to this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disaster leads to Romance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    katiemck44
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film Twister, written by Michael Crichton and Anne-Marie Martin and later directed by Jan De Bont was the second highest grossing film of 1996. The heavily anticipated disaster drama was action packed much like Bont's other films. Bont created Twister for anyone who loves to watch natural disasters unfold on the big screen. The movie had quite a few unrealistic scenes; however there were realistic ideas behind the actions. The script as well as acting is what lead to a very popular and exciting film. Twister in a nutshell is about two scientist/ storm chasers meeting up to get divorce papers finalized. While husband Bill Harding is more concerned with ending his marriage to start another with fianc&eacute;e, Dr. Melissa Reeves, wife Dr. Jo Harding is focused on launching a dangerous scientific machine (Dorothy) that will provide the scientist with never before developed tornado data. With the understanding of internal structures of tornados the scientist will be able to create an advanced tornado warning system. Along the way fianc&eacute;e Melissa can't handle the exciting life Bill leads leaving husband and wife to tackle the storms together. After close calls and deadly storms the couple ends up sending sensors straight into the eye of the storm and rekindling a lost relationship. While parts of this action packed film are unrealistic the film is overall enjoyable for families, adults and children. Twister, in relation to director Bont's other film Speed had action unfolding during the opening of the film and never letting up, keeping audiences on the edge of their seats in anticipation. The film producers were able to produce new cinematography never seen before. The realism of the tornados created by new technology lead to this movie placing in one of the top ranked movies of its day. Compared to the graphic of today there is a noticeable improvement, but in the 1990's the realism of a natural disaster was unheard of. Director Bont creates moods and tornadic environments with the green, blue, and blackish coloring. Not only do the colors help the audience know its storm time but the wide verity of up tempo music leads into the scene as well. On the tail of one giant tornado the film's music ranges all the way from rock to classic, all setting the mode for the adventure filled chase. A tornado film had never been done before so at the time the technology seemed amazing, but if you exclude the graphics the film follows a pretty unrealistic path. Events such as a Dodge Ram truck staying grounded and surviving high velocity winds, while a semi barreled out of the tornado made me question the realism of the movie. During the film, lead actor Bill Paxton (Bill Harding) climbs into the back of a moving pickup while hail the size of golf balls come crashing down on top of him. Anyone who has ever been hit by hail knows just how much that hurts and standing in it for a period of time would be painful for him to stand. While the film contains unrealistic events it still has some realistic aspects that can be found in most movies. The films main characters whose job is to follow the tornados in order to collect helpful data do just that. The directors and producers worked hard at making their fast chases seem natural. The cast played these scenes particularly well and it seemed as if they were true scientist excited for the challenge. This film also contains a rivalry between two group of scientist and rivalry between two women pining for a man's love. The scripted bickering was completely believable and left the audiences rooting for scientist Bill and Jo. Not only does the script work in favor of a plausible story line, the main characters Helen Hunt and Bill Paxton create a chemistry that is also very believable. These actors played the parts to their fullest potential and if I had the choice to recast this movie none of the actors would have been replaced. Every part, major of minor played a role in creating the atmosphere and they were all spot on. Everyone was excited to see this kind of destruction on the big screen and the directors and producers exceeded expectations. In my opinion the unrealistic aspects didn't affect the quality of the movie and I think those who helped it reach second highest grossing film would have to agree as well. This movie will forever pop into my mind and the minds of others who watched when they hear tornado sirens blaring. Overall the film is enjoyable and one that everyone should see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Helen Hunt & Tornadoes.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Helen Hunt is Dr. Jo Harding, a storm chaser in Oklahoma tracking a series of violent tornadoes sweeping through the state. Bill Paxton is Bill Harding, her soon-to-be ex-husband(and TV weatherman) who is trying to get Jo to sign divorce papers so that he can marry his girlfriend Melissa(played by Jamie Gertz) They soon team up to chase the storms, because of a hated rival Dr. Jonas Miller(played by Carey Elwes) who is also following the storms. Jo wants to close to a tornado in order to test a new weather measuring device that could revolutionize tornado detection, but the trick is in getting near one without being killed... Highly entertaining film is well directed by Jan De Bont, who creates a breathless feel to the story, and has a fine cast of characters, especially Helen Hunt, who is a knockout. May stretch credibility at times, but not enough to matter. This is a fun movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loads of flying fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bill Harding (Bill Paxton) is trying to get his tornado-hunter wife Dr. Jo Harding (Helen Hunt) to sign the divorce papers, marry his girlfriend Melissa (Jami Gertz), and start his new job as a TV weatherman. But forgetting the divorce papers, a chance to use their latest contraption Dorothy, and an old nemesis Dr. Jonas Miller (Cary Elwes) pushes Bill to come along for a ride to hunt tornadoes. This is a fun wild thrill ride worthy of all the popcorn. The characters are all straight forward. There isn't much subtlety. They do some fun jokes. It's all about the roller coaster ride. The CG is pretty good for its times. The action is big fun whether it's a falling truck or a flying cow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Plain Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grade: B+. Twister is always better then I remember. The film is very fun with its chase sequences, but I always think down on it then watch it and change my mind. Bill Harding, a former twister chasing legend who is starting a new life with a new fianc&eacute;e, goes back to see the old gang to get divorce papers signed, but sees his old project finished called Dorothy to put twister reading devices inside a twister to read how stable it is for better preparation for tornadoes. When a twister hits, he tags along and is slowly drawing away from his fianc&eacute;e and to his ex Jo. He meets old friends like Dustin and Aunt Meg and also enemies like Jonas, a rival group of twister chasers who also are doing the same thing but do it for the money, not science but have better gear. After chasing for a while, they are resting at a theater when a F5 twister hits on them and nearly destroys the area but they survive but it hits Meg. His fianc&eacute;e also leaves him because she sees he still loves Jo and she needs him and the film ends with Jonas dying and them being successful but also they go inside the center of a tornado and live. Totally unrealistic, but freaking awesome to see. The film has things that don't work well with the story and characters that are annoying, but there are ones that are funny (Dustin, Meg) and the twisters are impressive and seem to be grabbed every time they chase one. It is just a lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cow?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    first off the flying cow. wow that is like one of my favorite scenes in any movie period and the tag lines that were presented in the movie,, after seeing the Cow for the first and subsequent times. Bill Paxton and Helen Hunt play off of each other very well in this picture.. The director was about 15 years ahead of his time.. look what we have today in the 2010's , the weather channel storm-chaser's several programs about that. I love the idea that in this movie you have dueling teams of Storm Chaser's the other team is headed up by a cocky Jake Busey. throughout the movie you will see some of the most horrifying scenes of twisters that can be put on film,, the funnel clouds , the wall the spinning rotation,, the vortex,, you can tell i'm a weather junkie can't you.. I live in the Midwest now and I have seen one tornado high up in the sky once right over my house,, thank god it didn't touch down,, found out later it was a F1 but still, I think that if people would stop and watch Twister seriously maybe some people in the country especially the Midwest would be better suited to deal with a tragedy like this, see you can actually learn a few things from watching a movie these days,, I loved this movie,, it is my "perfect storm".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Film with Great CGI (for it's time)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike48128
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of course today's CGI is more realistic, but this film was made in 1996! That's why I prefer my old VHS version. The pan & scan is annoying but the slight "fuzziness" makes the CGI appear more convincing. The DVD is too clear! Otherwise, turn down your sharpness and enjoy maybe the best definitive tornado movie ever made! Stormchasers in Oklahoma at the peak of the May season. The plot, at times, is cloying and slows down the action. However, Jo (Helen Hunt) believes that the tornadoes are stalking her and Bill (Paxton) is great as the "human barometer". So much eerie similarity to this year's real disaster: It's set in Oklahoma. It's a "F5" storm. Are the storms technically accurate? Probably not. I still love that poor flying cow. The gasoline tanker that almost seems to explode twice? Driving through a house turned on it's side?--both impossible, of course. I don't like the sub-plots: Bill's annoying sex therapist fianc&eacute; and the "Dorothy" telemetry tracking gizmos don't seen logical. Was this based on an actual invention? A lot of little "Spielberg" touches. The storms seem to "growl". Intentionally humorous scenes and dialog. Jo seems to "see" her family standing in the rubble of her Aunt's town, which of course is impossible. It's a great roller coaster ride all the way, even on the home "screen". The whirligigs were designed by that famous artist who just died. Today, we have almost a 15 min. tornado warning because of Doppler Radar, but it still isn't enough time to evacuate. This year in Oklahoma (2013), thousands were injured, displaced, and many died. This movie needs to be re-released on the big screen with IMAX 3D and updated special effects.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK but not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesgustina
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overall not that bad of a movie, even with the gross inaccuracies that come with the portrayal of storm chasing in it. I always enjoy watching Twister when it's on because its just a simple summer blockbuster with some cool special effects. As other people have pointed out, the science is a good ways off, but unless you're a meteorologist or weather enthusiast it shouldn't be particularly bothersome. As a chaser, I'm able to enjoy this movie because it does get the feeling of a chase almost dead on. The excitement on a day before the first storms go up is caught pretty well. Now to the science part, while Twister has many flaws (the preliminary ratings before the tornado has even dissipated to name one), some of the issues listed below are totally false. Violent tornadoes can and do happen at night. Boundary layer cooling does not mean violent tornadoes cannot occur at night (a la Greensburg, Kansas EF5 in 2007 or the Super Tuesday Outbreak in 2008). Next, while tornadoes do not usually last for hours, tornadoes can and have lasted for more than 75 minutes (Tuscaloosa EF4 April 27, 2011. Lasted from 3:40 CDT to 5:50 CDT).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    godzillaman631
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a huge Michael Crichton fan ever since Jurassic Park, Timeline, and The Lost World. After watching this movie I saw a Michael Crichton novel brought to life. Every character is fleshed out and memorable from Dusty to Beltzer and Bill. If you are a Michael Crichton you will love this movie. This movie is well acted by Bill Paxton and Helen Hunt. The scenarios they are in a very realistic with real tension there and as well some moments where there are character moments. This movie makes you feel for them and feel like part of the group. Twister has beautiful visual effects by ILM and they still hold up today. I was surprised when I saw the score for the movie as a 6.1. I give this movie a 10/10. A great 90's movie to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun and Exciting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Uriah43
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Bill Harding" (Bill Paxton) has just become a television weatherman and he wants a divorce. So he takes his new fianc&eacute; "Melissa Reeves" (Jami Gertz) with him to ask his soon-to-be ex-wife "Jo Harding" (Helen Hunt) to sign the divorce papers. Since she and her group of colleagues are in the field trying to chase tornadoes, that's where he and Melissa have to go as well. Now, prior to becoming a weatherman he and Jo were working on a recently completed project they named "Dorothy" which was a device capable of measuring scientific data within a twister. But in order for it to work they have to put it directly in front of a tornado as it is bearing down on them. If that wasn't bad enough, a former co-worker named "Jonas Miller" (Cary Elwes) has stolen their idea and has formed his own group. However, unlike Jo's group, Jonas and his group have corporate sponsorship. This has enabled them to build their own version of "Dorothy" which he has named "D.O.T. 3". Jonas and his group also have more sophisticated equipment. But Jo's group now has Bill and his instincts are superior to any man or machine. At any rate, rather than spoiling the movie for those who haven't seen it, I won't go any further with the plot. However, I will say that this film is fun and exciting. The special effects were excellent and I liked the supporting cast of characters. And if it wasn't for some of the incredibly preposterous scenarios, I probably would have rated it higher. Even so, it's still an enjoyable movie all the same.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Keating
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching this film is genuinely one of the worst things that has ever happened to me. I was warned but went ahead and did it. I could spend hours explaining why this is so bad in almost every possible way, but can't be bothered. Its the films fault. It has actually sucked all meaning out of my life. Why would a film do this? I mean Mac and me was bad, as was Howard the duck, but this is one of those films that was marginally successful. I don't like giving films a 1 out of 10, just as I'm reluctant to give a film a 10 out of 10, but this film should be quarantined it is so bad. It is a danger to people with high blood pressure or who may be suicidal. There should be a health warning. People should be made aware that swine flu is nothing compared to this. I even had that novovirus thing and that was fun compared to this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disaster leads to Romance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    katiemck44
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film Twister, written by Michael Crichton and Anne-Marie Martin and later directed by Jan De Bont was the second highest grossing film of 1996. The heavily anticipated disaster drama was action packed much like Bont's other films. Bont created Twister for anyone who loves to watch natural disasters unfold on the big screen. The movie had quite a few unrealistic scenes; however there were realistic ideas behind the actions. The script as well as acting is what lead to a very popular and exciting film. Twister in a nutshell is about two scientist/ storm chasers meeting up to get divorce papers finalized. While husband Bill Harding is more concerned with ending his marriage to start another with fianc&eacute;e, Dr. Melissa Reeves, wife Dr. Jo Harding is focused on launching a dangerous scientific machine (Dorothy) that will provide the scientist with never before developed tornado data. With the understanding of internal structures of tornados the scientist will be able to create an advanced tornado warning system. Along the way fianc&eacute;e Melissa can't handle the exciting life Bill leads leaving husband and wife to tackle the storms together. After close calls and deadly storms the couple ends up sending sensors straight into the eye of the storm and rekindling a lost relationship. While parts of this action packed film are unrealistic the film is overall enjoyable for families, adults and children. Twister, in relation to director Bont's other film Speed had action unfolding during the opening of the film and never letting up, keeping audiences on the edge of their seats in anticipation. The film producers were able to produce new cinematography never seen before. The realism of the tornados created by new technology lead to this movie placing in one of the top ranked movies of its day. Compared to the graphic of today there is a noticeable improvement, but in the 1990's the realism of a natural disaster was unheard of. Director Bont creates moods and tornadic environments with the green, blue, and blackish coloring. Not only do the colors help the audience know its storm time but the wide verity of up tempo music leads into the scene as well. On the tail of one giant tornado the film's music ranges all the way from rock to classic, all setting the mode for the adventure filled chase. A tornado film had never been done before so at the time the technology seemed amazing, but if you exclude the graphics the film follows a pretty unrealistic path. Events such as a Dodge Ram truck staying grounded and surviving high velocity winds, while a semi barreled out of the tornado made me question the realism of the movie. During the film, lead actor Bill Paxton (Bill Harding) climbs into the back of a moving pickup while hail the size of golf balls come crashing down on top of him. Anyone who has ever been hit by hail knows just how much that hurts and standing in it for a period of time would be painful for him to stand. While the film contains unrealistic events it still has some realistic aspects that can be found in most movies. The films main characters whose job is to follow the tornados in order to collect helpful data do just that. The directors and producers worked hard at making their fast chases seem natural. The cast played these scenes particularly well and it seemed as if they were true scientist excited for the challenge. This film also contains a rivalry between two group of scientist and rivalry between two women pining for a man's love. The scripted bickering was completely believable and left the audiences rooting for scientist Bill and Jo. Not only does the script work in favor of a plausible story line, the main characters Helen Hunt and Bill Paxton create a chemistry that is also very believable. These actors played the parts to their fullest potential and if I had the choice to recast this movie none of the actors would have been replaced. Every part, major of minor played a role in creating the atmosphere and they were all spot on. Everyone was excited to see this kind of destruction on the big screen and the directors and producers exceeded expectations. In my opinion the unrealistic aspects didn't affect the quality of the movie and I think those who helped it reach second highest grossing film would have to agree as well. This movie will forever pop into my mind and the minds of others who watched when they hear tornado sirens blaring. Overall the film is enjoyable and one that everyone should see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Helen Hunt & Tornadoes.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Helen Hunt is Dr. Jo Harding, a storm chaser in Oklahoma tracking a series of violent tornadoes sweeping through the state. Bill Paxton is Bill Harding, her soon-to-be ex-husband(and TV weatherman) who is trying to get Jo to sign divorce papers so that he can marry his girlfriend Melissa(played by Jamie Gertz) They soon team up to chase the storms, because of a hated rival Dr. Jonas Miller(played by Carey Elwes) who is also following the storms. Jo wants to close to a tornado in order to test a new weather measuring device that could revolutionize tornado detection, but the trick is in getting near one without being killed... Highly entertaining film is well directed by Jan De Bont, who creates a breathless feel to the story, and has a fine cast of characters, especially Helen Hunt, who is a knockout. May stretch credibility at times, but not enough to matter. This is a fun movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loads of flying fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bill Harding (Bill Paxton) is trying to get his tornado-hunter wife Dr. Jo Harding (Helen Hunt) to sign the divorce papers, marry his girlfriend Melissa (Jami Gertz), and start his new job as a TV weatherman. But forgetting the divorce papers, a chance to use their latest contraption Dorothy, and an old nemesis Dr. Jonas Miller (Cary Elwes) pushes Bill to come along for a ride to hunt tornadoes. This is a fun wild thrill ride worthy of all the popcorn. The characters are all straight forward. There isn't much subtlety. They do some fun jokes. It's all about the roller coaster ride. The CG is pretty good for its times. The action is big fun whether it's a falling truck or a flying cow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Plain Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grade: B+. Twister is always better then I remember. The film is very fun with its chase sequences, but I always think down on it then watch it and change my mind. Bill Harding, a former twister chasing legend who is starting a new life with a new fianc&eacute;e, goes back to see the old gang to get divorce papers signed, but sees his old project finished called Dorothy to put twister reading devices inside a twister to read how stable it is for better preparation for tornadoes. When a twister hits, he tags along and is slowly drawing away from his fianc&eacute;e and to his ex Jo. He meets old friends like Dustin and Aunt Meg and also enemies like Jonas, a rival group of twister chasers who also are doing the same thing but do it for the money, not science but have better gear. After chasing for a while, they are resting at a theater when a F5 twister hits on them and nearly destroys the area but they survive but it hits Meg. His fianc&eacute;e also leaves him because she sees he still loves Jo and she needs him and the film ends with Jonas dying and them being successful but also they go inside the center of a tornado and live. Totally unrealistic, but freaking awesome to see. The film has things that don't work well with the story and characters that are annoying, but there are ones that are funny (Dustin, Meg) and the twisters are impressive and seem to be grabbed every time they chase one. It is just a lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cow?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    first off the flying cow. wow that is like one of my favorite scenes in any movie period and the tag lines that were presented in the movie,, after seeing the Cow for the first and subsequent times. Bill Paxton and Helen Hunt play off of each other very well in this picture.. The director was about 15 years ahead of his time.. look what we have today in the 2010's , the weather channel storm-chaser's several programs about that. I love the idea that in this movie you have dueling teams of Storm Chaser's the other team is headed up by a cocky Jake Busey. throughout the movie you will see some of the most horrifying scenes of twisters that can be put on film,, the funnel clouds , the wall the spinning rotation,, the vortex,, you can tell i'm a weather junkie can't you.. I live in the Midwest now and I have seen one tornado high up in the sky once right over my house,, thank god it didn't touch down,, found out later it was a F1 but still, I think that if people would stop and watch Twister seriously maybe some people in the country especially the Midwest would be better suited to deal with a tragedy like this, see you can actually learn a few things from watching a movie these days,, I loved this movie,, it is my "perfect storm".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Film with Great CGI (for it's time)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike48128
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of course today's CGI is more realistic, but this film was made in 1996! That's why I prefer my old VHS version. The pan & scan is annoying but the slight "fuzziness" makes the CGI appear more convincing. The DVD is too clear! Otherwise, turn down your sharpness and enjoy maybe the best definitive tornado movie ever made! Stormchasers in Oklahoma at the peak of the May season. The plot, at times, is cloying and slows down the action. However, Jo (Helen Hunt) believes that the tornadoes are stalking her and Bill (Paxton) is great as the "human barometer". So much eerie similarity to this year's real disaster: It's set in Oklahoma. It's a "F5" storm. Are the storms technically accurate? Probably not. I still love that poor flying cow. The gasoline tanker that almost seems to explode twice? Driving through a house turned on it's side?--both impossible, of course. I don't like the sub-plots: Bill's annoying sex therapist fianc&eacute; and the "Dorothy" telemetry tracking gizmos don't seen logical. Was this based on an actual invention? A lot of little "Spielberg" touches. The storms seem to "growl". Intentionally humorous scenes and dialog. Jo seems to "see" her family standing in the rubble of her Aunt's town, which of course is impossible. It's a great roller coaster ride all the way, even on the home "screen". The whirligigs were designed by that famous artist who just died. Today, we have almost a 15 min. tornado warning because of Doppler Radar, but it still isn't enough time to evacuate. This year in Oklahoma (2013), thousands were injured, displaced, and many died. This movie needs to be re-released on the big screen with IMAX 3D and updated special effects.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK but not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesgustina
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overall not that bad of a movie, even with the gross inaccuracies that come with the portrayal of storm chasing in it. I always enjoy watching Twister when it's on because its just a simple summer blockbuster with some cool special effects. As other people have pointed out, the science is a good ways off, but unless you're a meteorologist or weather enthusiast it shouldn't be particularly bothersome. As a chaser, I'm able to enjoy this movie because it does get the feeling of a chase almost dead on. The excitement on a day before the first storms go up is caught pretty well. Now to the science part, while Twister has many flaws (the preliminary ratings before the tornado has even dissipated to name one), some of the issues listed below are totally false. Violent tornadoes can and do happen at night. Boundary layer cooling does not mean violent tornadoes cannot occur at night (a la Greensburg, Kansas EF5 in 2007 or the Super Tuesday Outbreak in 2008). Next, while tornadoes do not usually last for hours, tornadoes can and have lasted for more than 75 minutes (Tuscaloosa EF4 April 27, 2011. Lasted from 3:40 CDT to 5:50 CDT).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    godzillaman631
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a huge Michael Crichton fan ever since Jurassic Park, Timeline, and The Lost World. After watching this movie I saw a Michael Crichton novel brought to life. Every character is fleshed out and memorable from Dusty to Beltzer and Bill. If you are a Michael Crichton you will love this movie. This movie is well acted by Bill Paxton and Helen Hunt. The scenarios they are in a very realistic with real tension there and as well some moments where there are character moments. This movie makes you feel for them and feel like part of the group. Twister has beautiful visual effects by ILM and they still hold up today. I was surprised when I saw the score for the movie as a 6.1. I give this movie a 10/10. A great 90's movie to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun and Exciting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Uriah43
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Bill Harding" (Bill Paxton) has just become a television weatherman and he wants a divorce. So he takes his new fianc&eacute; "Melissa Reeves" (Jami Gertz) with him to ask his soon-to-be ex-wife "Jo Harding" (Helen Hunt) to sign the divorce papers. Since she and her group of colleagues are in the field trying to chase tornadoes, that's where he and Melissa have to go as well. Now, prior to becoming a weatherman he and Jo were working on a recently completed project they named "Dorothy" which was a device capable of measuring scientific data within a twister. But in order for it to work they have to put it directly in front of a tornado as it is bearing down on them. If that wasn't bad enough, a former co-worker named "Jonas Miller" (Cary Elwes) has stolen their idea and has formed his own group. However, unlike Jo's group, Jonas and his group have corporate sponsorship. This has enabled them to build their own version of "Dorothy" which he has named "D.O.T. 3". Jonas and his group also have more sophisticated equipment. But Jo's group now has Bill and his instincts are superior to any man or machine. At any rate, rather than spoiling the movie for those who haven't seen it, I won't go any further with the plot. However, I will say that this film is fun and exciting. The special effects were excellent and I liked the supporting cast of characters. And if it wasn't for some of the incredibly preposterous scenarios, I probably would have rated it higher. Even so, it's still an enjoyable movie all the same.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Keating
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching this film is genuinely one of the worst things that has ever happened to me. I was warned but went ahead and did it. I could spend hours explaining why this is so bad in almost every possible way, but can't be bothered. Its the films fault. It has actually sucked all meaning out of my life. Why would a film do this? I mean Mac and me was bad, as was Howard the duck, but this is one of those films that was marginally successful. I don't like giving films a 1 out of 10, just as I'm reluctant to give a film a 10 out of 10, but this film should be quarantined it is so bad. It is a danger to people with high blood pressure or who may be suicidal. There should be a health warning. People should be made aware that swine flu is nothing compared to this. I even had that novovirus thing and that was fun compared to this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disaster leads to Romance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    katiemck44
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film Twister, written by Michael Crichton and Anne-Marie Martin and later directed by Jan De Bont was the second highest grossing film of 1996. The heavily anticipated disaster drama was action packed much like Bont's other films. Bont created Twister for anyone who loves to watch natural disasters unfold on the big screen. The movie had quite a few unrealistic scenes; however there were realistic ideas behind the actions. The script as well as acting is what lead to a very popular and exciting film. Twister in a nutshell is about two scientist/ storm chasers meeting up to get divorce papers finalized. While husband Bill Harding is more concerned with ending his marriage to start another with fianc&eacute;e, Dr. Melissa Reeves, wife Dr. Jo Harding is focused on launching a dangerous scientific machine (Dorothy) that will provide the scientist with never before developed tornado data. With the understanding of internal structures of tornados the scientist will be able to create an advanced tornado warning system. Along the way fianc&eacute;e Melissa can't handle the exciting life Bill leads leaving husband and wife to tackle the storms together. After close calls and deadly storms the couple ends up sending sensors straight into the eye of the storm and rekindling a lost relationship. While parts of this action packed film are unrealistic the film is overall enjoyable for families, adults and children. Twister, in relation to director Bont's other film Speed had action unfolding during the opening of the film and never letting up, keeping audiences on the edge of their seats in anticipation. The film producers were able to produce new cinematography never seen before. The realism of the tornados created by new technology lead to this movie placing in one of the top ranked movies of its day. Compared to the graphic of today there is a noticeable improvement, but in the 1990's the realism of a natural disaster was unheard of. Director Bont creates moods and tornadic environments with the green, blue, and blackish coloring. Not only do the colors help the audience know its storm time but the wide verity of up tempo music leads into the scene as well. On the tail of one giant tornado the film's music ranges all the way from rock to classic, all setting the mode for the adventure filled chase. A tornado film had never been done before so at the time the technology seemed amazing, but if you exclude the graphics the film follows a pretty unrealistic path. Events such as a Dodge Ram truck staying grounded and surviving high velocity winds, while a semi barreled out of the tornado made me question the realism of the movie. During the film, lead actor Bill Paxton (Bill Harding) climbs into the back of a moving pickup while hail the size of golf balls come crashing down on top of him. Anyone who has ever been hit by hail knows just how much that hurts and standing in it for a period of time would be painful for him to stand. While the film contains unrealistic events it still has some realistic aspects that can be found in most movies. The films main characters whose job is to follow the tornados in order to collect helpful data do just that. The directors and producers worked hard at making their fast chases seem natural. The cast played these scenes particularly well and it seemed as if they were true scientist excited for the challenge. This film also contains a rivalry between two group of scientist and rivalry between two women pining for a man's love. The scripted bickering was completely believable and left the audiences rooting for scientist Bill and Jo. Not only does the script work in favor of a plausible story line, the main characters Helen Hunt and Bill Paxton create a chemistry that is also very believable. These actors played the parts to their fullest potential and if I had the choice to recast this movie none of the actors would have been replaced. Every part, major of minor played a role in creating the atmosphere and they were all spot on. Everyone was excited to see this kind of destruction on the big screen and the directors and producers exceeded expectations. In my opinion the unrealistic aspects didn't affect the quality of the movie and I think those who helped it reach second highest grossing film would have to agree as well. This movie will forever pop into my mind and the minds of others who watched when they hear tornado sirens blaring. Overall the film is enjoyable and one that everyone should see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Helen Hunt & Tornadoes.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Helen Hunt is Dr. Jo Harding, a storm chaser in Oklahoma tracking a series of violent tornadoes sweeping through the state. Bill Paxton is Bill Harding, her soon-to-be ex-husband(and TV weatherman) who is trying to get Jo to sign divorce papers so that he can marry his girlfriend Melissa(played by Jamie Gertz) They soon team up to chase the storms, because of a hated rival Dr. Jonas Miller(played by Carey Elwes) who is also following the storms. Jo wants to close to a tornado in order to test a new weather measuring device that could revolutionize tornado detection, but the trick is in getting near one without being killed... Highly entertaining film is well directed by Jan De Bont, who creates a breathless feel to the story, and has a fine cast of characters, especially Helen Hunt, who is a knockout. May stretch credibility at times, but not enough to matter. This is a fun movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loads of flying fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bill Harding (Bill Paxton) is trying to get his tornado-hunter wife Dr. Jo Harding (Helen Hunt) to sign the divorce papers, marry his girlfriend Melissa (Jami Gertz), and start his new job as a TV weatherman. But forgetting the divorce papers, a chance to use their latest contraption Dorothy, and an old nemesis Dr. Jonas Miller (Cary Elwes) pushes Bill to come along for a ride to hunt tornadoes. This is a fun wild thrill ride worthy of all the popcorn. The characters are all straight forward. There isn't much subtlety. They do some fun jokes. It's all about the roller coaster ride. The CG is pretty good for its times. The action is big fun whether it's a falling truck or a flying cow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Plain Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grade: B+. Twister is always better then I remember. The film is very fun with its chase sequences, but I always think down on it then watch it and change my mind. Bill Harding, a former twister chasing legend who is starting a new life with a new fianc&eacute;e, goes back to see the old gang to get divorce papers signed, but sees his old project finished called Dorothy to put twister reading devices inside a twister to read how stable it is for better preparation for tornadoes. When a twister hits, he tags along and is slowly drawing away from his fianc&eacute;e and to his ex Jo. He meets old friends like Dustin and Aunt Meg and also enemies like Jonas, a rival group of twister chasers who also are doing the same thing but do it for the money, not science but have better gear. After chasing for a while, they are resting at a theater when a F5 twister hits on them and nearly destroys the area but they survive but it hits Meg. His fianc&eacute;e also leaves him because she sees he still loves Jo and she needs him and the film ends with Jonas dying and them being successful but also they go inside the center of a tornado and live. Totally unrealistic, but freaking awesome to see. The film has things that don't work well with the story and characters that are annoying, but there are ones that are funny (Dustin, Meg) and the twisters are impressive and seem to be grabbed every time they chase one. It is just a lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cow?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    first off the flying cow. wow that is like one of my favorite scenes in any movie period and the tag lines that were presented in the movie,, after seeing the Cow for the first and subsequent times. Bill Paxton and Helen Hunt play off of each other very well in this picture.. The director was about 15 years ahead of his time.. look what we have today in the 2010's , the weather channel storm-chaser's several programs about that. I love the idea that in this movie you have dueling teams of Storm Chaser's the other team is headed up by a cocky Jake Busey. throughout the movie you will see some of the most horrifying scenes of twisters that can be put on film,, the funnel clouds , the wall the spinning rotation,, the vortex,, you can tell i'm a weather junkie can't you.. I live in the Midwest now and I have seen one tornado high up in the sky once right over my house,, thank god it didn't touch down,, found out later it was a F1 but still, I think that if people would stop and watch Twister seriously maybe some people in the country especially the Midwest would be better suited to deal with a tragedy like this, see you can actually learn a few things from watching a movie these days,, I loved this movie,, it is my "perfect storm".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Film with Great CGI (for it's time)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike48128
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of course today's CGI is more realistic, but this film was made in 1996! That's why I prefer my old VHS version. The pan & scan is annoying but the slight "fuzziness" makes the CGI appear more convincing. The DVD is too clear! Otherwise, turn down your sharpness and enjoy maybe the best definitive tornado movie ever made! Stormchasers in Oklahoma at the peak of the May season. The plot, at times, is cloying and slows down the action. However, Jo (Helen Hunt) believes that the tornadoes are stalking her and Bill (Paxton) is great as the "human barometer". So much eerie similarity to this year's real disaster: It's set in Oklahoma. It's a "F5" storm. Are the storms technically accurate? Probably not. I still love that poor flying cow. The gasoline tanker that almost seems to explode twice? Driving through a house turned on it's side?--both impossible, of course. I don't like the sub-plots: Bill's annoying sex therapist fianc&eacute; and the "Dorothy" telemetry tracking gizmos don't seen logical. Was this based on an actual invention? A lot of little "Spielberg" touches. The storms seem to "growl". Intentionally humorous scenes and dialog. Jo seems to "see" her family standing in the rubble of her Aunt's town, which of course is impossible. It's a great roller coaster ride all the way, even on the home "screen". The whirligigs were designed by that famous artist who just died. Today, we have almost a 15 min. tornado warning because of Doppler Radar, but it still isn't enough time to evacuate. This year in Oklahoma (2013), thousands were injured, displaced, and many died. This movie needs to be re-released on the big screen with IMAX 3D and updated special effects.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK but not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesgustina
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overall not that bad of a movie, even with the gross inaccuracies that come with the portrayal of storm chasing in it. I always enjoy watching Twister when it's on because its just a simple summer blockbuster with some cool special effects. As other people have pointed out, the science is a good ways off, but unless you're a meteorologist or weather enthusiast it shouldn't be particularly bothersome. As a chaser, I'm able to enjoy this movie because it does get the feeling of a chase almost dead on. The excitement on a day before the first storms go up is caught pretty well. Now to the science part, while Twister has many flaws (the preliminary ratings before the tornado has even dissipated to name one), some of the issues listed below are totally false. Violent tornadoes can and do happen at night. Boundary layer cooling does not mean violent tornadoes cannot occur at night (a la Greensburg, Kansas EF5 in 2007 or the Super Tuesday Outbreak in 2008). Next, while tornadoes do not usually last for hours, tornadoes can and have lasted for more than 75 minutes (Tuscaloosa EF4 April 27, 2011. Lasted from 3:40 CDT to 5:50 CDT).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    godzillaman631
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a huge Michael Crichton fan ever since Jurassic Park, Timeline, and The Lost World. After watching this movie I saw a Michael Crichton novel brought to life. Every character is fleshed out and memorable from Dusty to Beltzer and Bill. If you are a Michael Crichton you will love this movie. This movie is well acted by Bill Paxton and Helen Hunt. The scenarios they are in a very realistic with real tension there and as well some moments where there are character moments. This movie makes you feel for them and feel like part of the group. Twister has beautiful visual effects by ILM and they still hold up today. I was surprised when I saw the score for the movie as a 6.1. I give this movie a 10/10. A great 90's movie to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun and Exciting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Uriah43
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Bill Harding" (Bill Paxton) has just become a television weatherman and he wants a divorce. So he takes his new fianc&eacute; "Melissa Reeves" (Jami Gertz) with him to ask his soon-to-be ex-wife "Jo Harding" (Helen Hunt) to sign the divorce papers. Since she and her group of colleagues are in the field trying to chase tornadoes, that's where he and Melissa have to go as well. Now, prior to becoming a weatherman he and Jo were working on a recently completed project they named "Dorothy" which was a device capable of measuring scientific data within a twister. But in order for it to work they have to put it directly in front of a tornado as it is bearing down on them. If that wasn't bad enough, a former co-worker named "Jonas Miller" (Cary Elwes) has stolen their idea and has formed his own group. However, unlike Jo's group, Jonas and his group have corporate sponsorship. This has enabled them to build their own version of "Dorothy" which he has named "D.O.T. 3". Jonas and his group also have more sophisticated equipment. But Jo's group now has Bill and his instincts are superior to any man or machine. At any rate, rather than spoiling the movie for those who haven't seen it, I won't go any further with the plot. However, I will say that this film is fun and exciting. The special effects were excellent and I liked the supporting cast of characters. And if it wasn't for some of the incredibly preposterous scenarios, I probably would have rated it higher. Even so, it's still an enjoyable movie all the same.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Keating
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching this film is genuinely one of the worst things that has ever happened to me. I was warned but went ahead and did it. I could spend hours explaining why this is so bad in almost every possible way, but can't be bothered. Its the films fault. It has actually sucked all meaning out of my life. Why would a film do this? I mean Mac and me was bad, as was Howard the duck, but this is one of those films that was marginally successful. I don't like giving films a 1 out of 10, just as I'm reluctant to give a film a 10 out of 10, but this film should be quarantined it is so bad. It is a danger to people with high blood pressure or who may be suicidal. There should be a health warning. People should be made aware that swine flu is nothing compared to this. I even had that novovirus thing and that was fun compared to this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disaster leads to Romance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    katiemck44
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film Twister, written by Michael Crichton and Anne-Marie Martin and later directed by Jan De Bont was the second highest grossing film of 1996. The heavily anticipated disaster drama was action packed much like Bont's other films. Bont created Twister for anyone who loves to watch natural disasters unfold on the big screen. The movie had quite a few unrealistic scenes; however there were realistic ideas behind the actions. The script as well as acting is what lead to a very popular and exciting film. Twister in a nutshell is about two scientist/ storm chasers meeting up to get divorce papers finalized. While husband Bill Harding is more concerned with ending his marriage to start another with fianc&eacute;e, Dr. Melissa Reeves, wife Dr. Jo Harding is focused on launching a dangerous scientific machine (Dorothy) that will provide the scientist with never before developed tornado data. With the understanding of internal structures of tornados the scientist will be able to create an advanced tornado warning system. Along the way fianc&eacute;e Melissa can't handle the exciting life Bill leads leaving husband and wife to tackle the storms together. After close calls and deadly storms the couple ends up sending sensors straight into the eye of the storm and rekindling a lost relationship. While parts of this action packed film are unrealistic the film is overall enjoyable for families, adults and children. Twister, in relation to director Bont's other film Speed had action unfolding during the opening of the film and never letting up, keeping audiences on the edge of their seats in anticipation. The film producers were able to produce new cinematography never seen before. The realism of the tornados created by new technology lead to this movie placing in one of the top ranked movies of its day. Compared to the graphic of today there is a noticeable improvement, but in the 1990's the realism of a natural disaster was unheard of. Director Bont creates moods and tornadic environments with the green, blue, and blackish coloring. Not only do the colors help the audience know its storm time but the wide verity of up tempo music leads into the scene as well. On the tail of one giant tornado the film's music ranges all the way from rock to classic, all setting the mode for the adventure filled chase. A tornado film had never been done before so at the time the technology seemed amazing, but if you exclude the graphics the film follows a pretty unrealistic path. Events such as a Dodge Ram truck staying grounded and surviving high velocity winds, while a semi barreled out of the tornado made me question the realism of the movie. During the film, lead actor Bill Paxton (Bill Harding) climbs into the back of a moving pickup while hail the size of golf balls come crashing down on top of him. Anyone who has ever been hit by hail knows just how much that hurts and standing in it for a period of time would be painful for him to stand. While the film contains unrealistic events it still has some realistic aspects that can be found in most movies. The films main characters whose job is to follow the tornados in order to collect helpful data do just that. The directors and producers worked hard at making their fast chases seem natural. The cast played these scenes particularly well and it seemed as if they were true scientist excited for the challenge. This film also contains a rivalry between two group of scientist and rivalry between two women pining for a man's love. The scripted bickering was completely believable and left the audiences rooting for scientist Bill and Jo. Not only does the script work in favor of a plausible story line, the main characters Helen Hunt and Bill Paxton create a chemistry that is also very believable. These actors played the parts to their fullest potential and if I had the choice to recast this movie none of the actors would have been replaced. Every part, major of minor played a role in creating the atmosphere and they were all spot on. Everyone was excited to see this kind of destruction on the big screen and the directors and producers exceeded expectations. In my opinion the unrealistic aspects didn't affect the quality of the movie and I think those who helped it reach second highest grossing film would have to agree as well. This movie will forever pop into my mind and the minds of others who watched when they hear tornado sirens blaring. Overall the film is enjoyable and one that everyone should see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Helen Hunt & Tornadoes.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Helen Hunt is Dr. Jo Harding, a storm chaser in Oklahoma tracking a series of violent tornadoes sweeping through the state. Bill Paxton is Bill Harding, her soon-to-be ex-husband(and TV weatherman) who is trying to get Jo to sign divorce papers so that he can marry his girlfriend Melissa(played by Jamie Gertz) They soon team up to chase the storms, because of a hated rival Dr. Jonas Miller(played by Carey Elwes) who is also following the storms. Jo wants to close to a tornado in order to test a new weather measuring device that could revolutionize tornado detection, but the trick is in getting near one without being killed... Highly entertaining film is well directed by Jan De Bont, who creates a breathless feel to the story, and has a fine cast of characters, especially Helen Hunt, who is a knockout. May stretch credibility at times, but not enough to matter. This is a fun movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loads of flying fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bill Harding (Bill Paxton) is trying to get his tornado-hunter wife Dr. Jo Harding (Helen Hunt) to sign the divorce papers, marry his girlfriend Melissa (Jami Gertz), and start his new job as a TV weatherman. But forgetting the divorce papers, a chance to use their latest contraption Dorothy, and an old nemesis Dr. Jonas Miller (Cary Elwes) pushes Bill to come along for a ride to hunt tornadoes. This is a fun wild thrill ride worthy of all the popcorn. The characters are all straight forward. There isn't much subtlety. They do some fun jokes. It's all about the roller coaster ride. The CG is pretty good for its times. The action is big fun whether it's a falling truck or a flying cow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Plain Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grade: B+. Twister is always better then I remember. The film is very fun with its chase sequences, but I always think down on it then watch it and change my mind. Bill Harding, a former twister chasing legend who is starting a new life with a new fianc&eacute;e, goes back to see the old gang to get divorce papers signed, but sees his old project finished called Dorothy to put twister reading devices inside a twister to read how stable it is for better preparation for tornadoes. When a twister hits, he tags along and is slowly drawing away from his fianc&eacute;e and to his ex Jo. He meets old friends like Dustin and Aunt Meg and also enemies like Jonas, a rival group of twister chasers who also are doing the same thing but do it for the money, not science but have better gear. After chasing for a while, they are resting at a theater when a F5 twister hits on them and nearly destroys the area but they survive but it hits Meg. His fianc&eacute;e also leaves him because she sees he still loves Jo and she needs him and the film ends with Jonas dying and them being successful but also they go inside the center of a tornado and live. Totally unrealistic, but freaking awesome to see. The film has things that don't work well with the story and characters that are annoying, but there are ones that are funny (Dustin, Meg) and the twisters are impressive and seem to be grabbed every time they chase one. It is just a lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cow?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    first off the flying cow. wow that is like one of my favorite scenes in any movie period and the tag lines that were presented in the movie,, after seeing the Cow for the first and subsequent times. Bill Paxton and Helen Hunt play off of each other very well in this picture.. The director was about 15 years ahead of his time.. look what we have today in the 2010's , the weather channel storm-chaser's several programs about that. I love the idea that in this movie you have dueling teams of Storm Chaser's the other team is headed up by a cocky Jake Busey. throughout the movie you will see some of the most horrifying scenes of twisters that can be put on film,, the funnel clouds , the wall the spinning rotation,, the vortex,, you can tell i'm a weather junkie can't you.. I live in the Midwest now and I have seen one tornado high up in the sky once right over my house,, thank god it didn't touch down,, found out later it was a F1 but still, I think that if people would stop and watch Twister seriously maybe some people in the country especially the Midwest would be better suited to deal with a tragedy like this, see you can actually learn a few things from watching a movie these days,, I loved this movie,, it is my "perfect storm".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Film with Great CGI (for it's time)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike48128
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of course today's CGI is more realistic, but this film was made in 1996! That's why I prefer my old VHS version. The pan & scan is annoying but the slight "fuzziness" makes the CGI appear more convincing. The DVD is too clear! Otherwise, turn down your sharpness and enjoy maybe the best definitive tornado movie ever made! Stormchasers in Oklahoma at the peak of the May season. The plot, at times, is cloying and slows down the action. However, Jo (Helen Hunt) believes that the tornadoes are stalking her and Bill (Paxton) is great as the "human barometer". So much eerie similarity to this year's real disaster: It's set in Oklahoma. It's a "F5" storm. Are the storms technically accurate? Probably not. I still love that poor flying cow. The gasoline tanker that almost seems to explode twice? Driving through a house turned on it's side?--both impossible, of course. I don't like the sub-plots: Bill's annoying sex therapist fianc&eacute; and the "Dorothy" telemetry tracking gizmos don't seen logical. Was this based on an actual invention? A lot of little "Spielberg" touches. The storms seem to "growl". Intentionally humorous scenes and dialog. Jo seems to "see" her family standing in the rubble of her Aunt's town, which of course is impossible. It's a great roller coaster ride all the way, even on the home "screen". The whirligigs were designed by that famous artist who just died. Today, we have almost a 15 min. tornado warning because of Doppler Radar, but it still isn't enough time to evacuate. This year in Oklahoma (2013), thousands were injured, displaced, and many died. This movie needs to be re-released on the big screen with IMAX 3D and updated special effects.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK but not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesgustina
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overall not that bad of a movie, even with the gross inaccuracies that come with the portrayal of storm chasing in it. I always enjoy watching Twister when it's on because its just a simple summer blockbuster with some cool special effects. As other people have pointed out, the science is a good ways off, but unless you're a meteorologist or weather enthusiast it shouldn't be particularly bothersome. As a chaser, I'm able to enjoy this movie because it does get the feeling of a chase almost dead on. The excitement on a day before the first storms go up is caught pretty well. Now to the science part, while Twister has many flaws (the preliminary ratings before the tornado has even dissipated to name one), some of the issues listed below are totally false. Violent tornadoes can and do happen at night. Boundary layer cooling does not mean violent tornadoes cannot occur at night (a la Greensburg, Kansas EF5 in 2007 or the Super Tuesday Outbreak in 2008). Next, while tornadoes do not usually last for hours, tornadoes can and have lasted for more than 75 minutes (Tuscaloosa EF4 April 27, 2011. Lasted from 3:40 CDT to 5:50 CDT).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    godzillaman631
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a huge Michael Crichton fan ever since Jurassic Park, Timeline, and The Lost World. After watching this movie I saw a Michael Crichton novel brought to life. Every character is fleshed out and memorable from Dusty to Beltzer and Bill. If you are a Michael Crichton you will love this movie. This movie is well acted by Bill Paxton and Helen Hunt. The scenarios they are in a very realistic with real tension there and as well some moments where there are character moments. This movie makes you feel for them and feel like part of the group. Twister has beautiful visual effects by ILM and they still hold up today. I was surprised when I saw the score for the movie as a 6.1. I give this movie a 10/10. A great 90's movie to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun and Exciting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Uriah43
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Bill Harding" (Bill Paxton) has just become a television weatherman and he wants a divorce. So he takes his new fianc&eacute; "Melissa Reeves" (Jami Gertz) with him to ask his soon-to-be ex-wife "Jo Harding" (Helen Hunt) to sign the divorce papers. Since she and her group of colleagues are in the field trying to chase tornadoes, that's where he and Melissa have to go as well. Now, prior to becoming a weatherman he and Jo were working on a recently completed project they named "Dorothy" which was a device capable of measuring scientific data within a twister. But in order for it to work they have to put it directly in front of a tornado as it is bearing down on them. If that wasn't bad enough, a former co-worker named "Jonas Miller" (Cary Elwes) has stolen their idea and has formed his own group. However, unlike Jo's group, Jonas and his group have corporate sponsorship. This has enabled them to build their own version of "Dorothy" which he has named "D.O.T. 3". Jonas and his group also have more sophisticated equipment. But Jo's group now has Bill and his instincts are superior to any man or machine. At any rate, rather than spoiling the movie for those who haven't seen it, I won't go any further with the plot. However, I will say that this film is fun and exciting. The special effects were excellent and I liked the supporting cast of characters. And if it wasn't for some of the incredibly preposterous scenarios, I probably would have rated it higher. Even so, it's still an enjoyable movie all the same.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Keating
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching this film is genuinely one of the worst things that has ever happened to me. I was warned but went ahead and did it. I could spend hours explaining why this is so bad in almost every possible way, but can't be bothered. Its the films fault. It has actually sucked all meaning out of my life. Why would a film do this? I mean Mac and me was bad, as was Howard the duck, but this is one of those films that was marginally successful. I don't like giving films a 1 out of 10, just as I'm reluctant to give a film a 10 out of 10, but this film should be quarantined it is so bad. It is a danger to people with high blood pressure or who may be suicidal. There should be a health warning. People should be made aware that swine flu is nothing compared to this. I even had that novovirus thing and that was fun compared to this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disaster leads to Romance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    katiemck44
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film Twister, written by Michael Crichton and Anne-Marie Martin and later directed by Jan De Bont was the second highest grossing film of 1996. The heavily anticipated disaster drama was action packed much like Bont's other films. Bont created Twister for anyone who loves to watch natural disasters unfold on the big screen. The movie had quite a few unrealistic scenes; however there were realistic ideas behind the actions. The script as well as acting is what lead to a very popular and exciting film. Twister in a nutshell is about two scientist/ storm chasers meeting up to get divorce papers finalized. While husband Bill Harding is more concerned with ending his marriage to start another with fianc&eacute;e, Dr. Melissa Reeves, wife Dr. Jo Harding is focused on launching a dangerous scientific machine (Dorothy) that will provide the scientist with never before developed tornado data. With the understanding of internal structures of tornados the scientist will be able to create an advanced tornado warning system. Along the way fianc&eacute;e Melissa can't handle the exciting life Bill leads leaving husband and wife to tackle the storms together. After close calls and deadly storms the couple ends up sending sensors straight into the eye of the storm and rekindling a lost relationship. While parts of this action packed film are unrealistic the film is overall enjoyable for families, adults and children. Twister, in relation to director Bont's other film Speed had action unfolding during the opening of the film and never letting up, keeping audiences on the edge of their seats in anticipation. The film producers were able to produce new cinematography never seen before. The realism of the tornados created by new technology lead to this movie placing in one of the top ranked movies of its day. Compared to the graphic of today there is a noticeable improvement, but in the 1990's the realism of a natural disaster was unheard of. Director Bont creates moods and tornadic environments with the green, blue, and blackish coloring. Not only do the colors help the audience know its storm time but the wide verity of up tempo music leads into the scene as well. On the tail of one giant tornado the film's music ranges all the way from rock to classic, all setting the mode for the adventure filled chase. A tornado film had never been done before so at the time the technology seemed amazing, but if you exclude the graphics the film follows a pretty unrealistic path. Events such as a Dodge Ram truck staying grounded and surviving high velocity winds, while a semi barreled out of the tornado made me question the realism of the movie. During the film, lead actor Bill Paxton (Bill Harding) climbs into the back of a moving pickup while hail the size of golf balls come crashing down on top of him. Anyone who has ever been hit by hail knows just how much that hurts and standing in it for a period of time would be painful for him to stand. While the film contains unrealistic events it still has some realistic aspects that can be found in most movies. The films main characters whose job is to follow the tornados in order to collect helpful data do just that. The directors and producers worked hard at making their fast chases seem natural. The cast played these scenes particularly well and it seemed as if they were true scientist excited for the challenge. This film also contains a rivalry between two group of scientist and rivalry between two women pining for a man's love. The scripted bickering was completely believable and left the audiences rooting for scientist Bill and Jo. Not only does the script work in favor of a plausible story line, the main characters Helen Hunt and Bill Paxton create a chemistry that is also very believable. These actors played the parts to their fullest potential and if I had the choice to recast this movie none of the actors would have been replaced. Every part, major of minor played a role in creating the atmosphere and they were all spot on. Everyone was excited to see this kind of destruction on the big screen and the directors and producers exceeded expectations. In my opinion the unrealistic aspects didn't affect the quality of the movie and I think those who helped it reach second highest grossing film would have to agree as well. This movie will forever pop into my mind and the minds of others who watched when they hear tornado sirens blaring. Overall the film is enjoyable and one that everyone should see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Helen Hunt & Tornadoes.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Helen Hunt is Dr. Jo Harding, a storm chaser in Oklahoma tracking a series of violent tornadoes sweeping through the state. Bill Paxton is Bill Harding, her soon-to-be ex-husband(and TV weatherman) who is trying to get Jo to sign divorce papers so that he can marry his girlfriend Melissa(played by Jamie Gertz) They soon team up to chase the storms, because of a hated rival Dr. Jonas Miller(played by Carey Elwes) who is also following the storms. Jo wants to close to a tornado in order to test a new weather measuring device that could revolutionize tornado detection, but the trick is in getting near one without being killed... Highly entertaining film is well directed by Jan De Bont, who creates a breathless feel to the story, and has a fine cast of characters, especially Helen Hunt, who is a knockout. May stretch credibility at times, but not enough to matter. This is a fun movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loads of flying fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bill Harding (Bill Paxton) is trying to get his tornado-hunter wife Dr. Jo Harding (Helen Hunt) to sign the divorce papers, marry his girlfriend Melissa (Jami Gertz), and start his new job as a TV weatherman. But forgetting the divorce papers, a chance to use their latest contraption Dorothy, and an old nemesis Dr. Jonas Miller (Cary Elwes) pushes Bill to come along for a ride to hunt tornadoes. This is a fun wild thrill ride worthy of all the popcorn. The characters are all straight forward. There isn't much subtlety. They do some fun jokes. It's all about the roller coaster ride. The CG is pretty good for its times. The action is big fun whether it's a falling truck or a flying cow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Plain Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grade: B+. Twister is always better then I remember. The film is very fun with its chase sequences, but I always think down on it then watch it and change my mind. Bill Harding, a former twister chasing legend who is starting a new life with a new fianc&eacute;e, goes back to see the old gang to get divorce papers signed, but sees his old project finished called Dorothy to put twister reading devices inside a twister to read how stable it is for better preparation for tornadoes. When a twister hits, he tags along and is slowly drawing away from his fianc&eacute;e and to his ex Jo. He meets old friends like Dustin and Aunt Meg and also enemies like Jonas, a rival group of twister chasers who also are doing the same thing but do it for the money, not science but have better gear. After chasing for a while, they are resting at a theater when a F5 twister hits on them and nearly destroys the area but they survive but it hits Meg. His fianc&eacute;e also leaves him because she sees he still loves Jo and she needs him and the film ends with Jonas dying and them being successful but also they go inside the center of a tornado and live. Totally unrealistic, but freaking awesome to see. The film has things that don't work well with the story and characters that are annoying, but there are ones that are funny (Dustin, Meg) and the twisters are impressive and seem to be grabbed every time they chase one. It is just a lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cow?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    first off the flying cow. wow that is like one of my favorite scenes in any movie period and the tag lines that were presented in the movie,, after seeing the Cow for the first and subsequent times. Bill Paxton and Helen Hunt play off of each other very well in this picture.. The director was about 15 years ahead of his time.. look what we have today in the 2010's , the weather channel storm-chaser's several programs about that. I love the idea that in this movie you have dueling teams of Storm Chaser's the other team is headed up by a cocky Jake Busey. throughout the movie you will see some of the most horrifying scenes of twisters that can be put on film,, the funnel clouds , the wall the spinning rotation,, the vortex,, you can tell i'm a weather junkie can't you.. I live in the Midwest now and I have seen one tornado high up in the sky once right over my house,, thank god it didn't touch down,, found out later it was a F1 but still, I think that if people would stop and watch Twister seriously maybe some people in the country especially the Midwest would be better suited to deal with a tragedy like this, see you can actually learn a few things from watching a movie these days,, I loved this movie,, it is my "perfect storm".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Film with Great CGI (for it's time)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike48128
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of course today's CGI is more realistic, but this film was made in 1996! That's why I prefer my old VHS version. The pan & scan is annoying but the slight "fuzziness" makes the CGI appear more convincing. The DVD is too clear! Otherwise, turn down your sharpness and enjoy maybe the best definitive tornado movie ever made! Stormchasers in Oklahoma at the peak of the May season. The plot, at times, is cloying and slows down the action. However, Jo (Helen Hunt) believes that the tornadoes are stalking her and Bill (Paxton) is great as the "human barometer". So much eerie similarity to this year's real disaster: It's set in Oklahoma. It's a "F5" storm. Are the storms technically accurate? Probably not. I still love that poor flying cow. The gasoline tanker that almost seems to explode twice? Driving through a house turned on it's side?--both impossible, of course. I don't like the sub-plots: Bill's annoying sex therapist fianc&eacute; and the "Dorothy" telemetry tracking gizmos don't seen logical. Was this based on an actual invention? A lot of little "Spielberg" touches. The storms seem to "growl". Intentionally humorous scenes and dialog. Jo seems to "see" her family standing in the rubble of her Aunt's town, which of course is impossible. It's a great roller coaster ride all the way, even on the home "screen". The whirligigs were designed by that famous artist who just died. Today, we have almost a 15 min. tornado warning because of Doppler Radar, but it still isn't enough time to evacuate. This year in Oklahoma (2013), thousands were injured, displaced, and many died. This movie needs to be re-released on the big screen with IMAX 3D and updated special effects.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK but not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesgustina
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overall not that bad of a movie, even with the gross inaccuracies that come with the portrayal of storm chasing in it. I always enjoy watching Twister when it's on because its just a simple summer blockbuster with some cool special effects. As other people have pointed out, the science is a good ways off, but unless you're a meteorologist or weather enthusiast it shouldn't be particularly bothersome. As a chaser, I'm able to enjoy this movie because it does get the feeling of a chase almost dead on. The excitement on a day before the first storms go up is caught pretty well. Now to the science part, while Twister has many flaws (the preliminary ratings before the tornado has even dissipated to name one), some of the issues listed below are totally false. Violent tornadoes can and do happen at night. Boundary layer cooling does not mean violent tornadoes cannot occur at night (a la Greensburg, Kansas EF5 in 2007 or the Super Tuesday Outbreak in 2008). Next, while tornadoes do not usually last for hours, tornadoes can and have lasted for more than 75 minutes (Tuscaloosa EF4 April 27, 2011. Lasted from 3:40 CDT to 5:50 CDT).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    godzillaman631
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a huge Michael Crichton fan ever since Jurassic Park, Timeline, and The Lost World. After watching this movie I saw a Michael Crichton novel brought to life. Every character is fleshed out and memorable from Dusty to Beltzer and Bill. If you are a Michael Crichton you will love this movie. This movie is well acted by Bill Paxton and Helen Hunt. The scenarios they are in a very realistic with real tension there and as well some moments where there are character moments. This movie makes you feel for them and feel like part of the group. Twister has beautiful visual effects by ILM and they still hold up today. I was surprised when I saw the score for the movie as a 6.1. I give this movie a 10/10. A great 90's movie to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun and Exciting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Uriah43
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Bill Harding" (Bill Paxton) has just become a television weatherman and he wants a divorce. So he takes his new fianc&eacute; "Melissa Reeves" (Jami Gertz) with him to ask his soon-to-be ex-wife "Jo Harding" (Helen Hunt) to sign the divorce papers. Since she and her group of colleagues are in the field trying to chase tornadoes, that's where he and Melissa have to go as well. Now, prior to becoming a weatherman he and Jo were working on a recently completed project they named "Dorothy" which was a device capable of measuring scientific data within a twister. But in order for it to work they have to put it directly in front of a tornado as it is bearing down on them. If that wasn't bad enough, a former co-worker named "Jonas Miller" (Cary Elwes) has stolen their idea and has formed his own group. However, unlike Jo's group, Jonas and his group have corporate sponsorship. This has enabled them to build their own version of "Dorothy" which he has named "D.O.T. 3". Jonas and his group also have more sophisticated equipment. But Jo's group now has Bill and his instincts are superior to any man or machine. At any rate, rather than spoiling the movie for those who haven't seen it, I won't go any further with the plot. However, I will say that this film is fun and exciting. The special effects were excellent and I liked the supporting cast of characters. And if it wasn't for some of the incredibly preposterous scenarios, I probably would have rated it higher. Even so, it's still an enjoyable movie all the same.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Keating
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching this film is genuinely one of the worst things that has ever happened to me. I was warned but went ahead and did it. I could spend hours explaining why this is so bad in almost every possible way, but can't be bothered. Its the films fault. It has actually sucked all meaning out of my life. Why would a film do this? I mean Mac and me was bad, as was Howard the duck, but this is one of those films that was marginally successful. I don't like giving films a 1 out of 10, just as I'm reluctant to give a film a 10 out of 10, but this film should be quarantined it is so bad. It is a danger to people with high blood pressure or who may be suicidal. There should be a health warning. People should be made aware that swine flu is nothing compared to this. I even had that novovirus thing and that was fun compared to this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disaster leads to Romance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    katiemck44
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film Twister, written by Michael Crichton and Anne-Marie Martin and later directed by Jan De Bont was the second highest grossing film of 1996. The heavily anticipated disaster drama was action packed much like Bont's other films. Bont created Twister for anyone who loves to watch natural disasters unfold on the big screen. The movie had quite a few unrealistic scenes; however there were realistic ideas behind the actions. The script as well as acting is what lead to a very popular and exciting film. Twister in a nutshell is about two scientist/ storm chasers meeting up to get divorce papers finalized. While husband Bill Harding is more concerned with ending his marriage to start another with fianc&eacute;e, Dr. Melissa Reeves, wife Dr. Jo Harding is focused on launching a dangerous scientific machine (Dorothy) that will provide the scientist with never before developed tornado data. With the understanding of internal structures of tornados the scientist will be able to create an advanced tornado warning system. Along the way fianc&eacute;e Melissa can't handle the exciting life Bill leads leaving husband and wife to tackle the storms together. After close calls and deadly storms the couple ends up sending sensors straight into the eye of the storm and rekindling a lost relationship. While parts of this action packed film are unrealistic the film is overall enjoyable for families, adults and children. Twister, in relation to director Bont's other film Speed had action unfolding during the opening of the film and never letting up, keeping audiences on the edge of their seats in anticipation. The film producers were able to produce new cinematography never seen before. The realism of the tornados created by new technology lead to this movie placing in one of the top ranked movies of its day. Compared to the graphic of today there is a noticeable improvement, but in the 1990's the realism of a natural disaster was unheard of. Director Bont creates moods and tornadic environments with the green, blue, and blackish coloring. Not only do the colors help the audience know its storm time but the wide verity of up tempo music leads into the scene as well. On the tail of one giant tornado the film's music ranges all the way from rock to classic, all setting the mode for the adventure filled chase. A tornado film had never been done before so at the time the technology seemed amazing, but if you exclude the graphics the film follows a pretty unrealistic path. Events such as a Dodge Ram truck staying grounded and surviving high velocity winds, while a semi barreled out of the tornado made me question the realism of the movie. During the film, lead actor Bill Paxton (Bill Harding) climbs into the back of a moving pickup while hail the size of golf balls come crashing down on top of him. Anyone who has ever been hit by hail knows just how much that hurts and standing in it for a period of time would be painful for him to stand. While the film contains unrealistic events it still has some realistic aspects that can be found in most movies. The films main characters whose job is to follow the tornados in order to collect helpful data do just that. The directors and producers worked hard at making their fast chases seem natural. The cast played these scenes particularly well and it seemed as if they were true scientist excited for the challenge. This film also contains a rivalry between two group of scientist and rivalry between two women pining for a man's love. The scripted bickering was completely believable and left the audiences rooting for scientist Bill and Jo. Not only does the script work in favor of a plausible story line, the main characters Helen Hunt and Bill Paxton create a chemistry that is also very believable. These actors played the parts to their fullest potential and if I had the choice to recast this movie none of the actors would have been replaced. Every part, major of minor played a role in creating the atmosphere and they were all spot on. Everyone was excited to see this kind of destruction on the big screen and the directors and producers exceeded expectations. In my opinion the unrealistic aspects didn't affect the quality of the movie and I think those who helped it reach second highest grossing film would have to agree as well. This movie will forever pop into my mind and the minds of others who watched when they hear tornado sirens blaring. Overall the film is enjoyable and one that everyone should see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Helen Hunt & Tornadoes.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Helen Hunt is Dr. Jo Harding, a storm chaser in Oklahoma tracking a series of violent tornadoes sweeping through the state. Bill Paxton is Bill Harding, her soon-to-be ex-husband(and TV weatherman) who is trying to get Jo to sign divorce papers so that he can marry his girlfriend Melissa(played by Jamie Gertz) They soon team up to chase the storms, because of a hated rival Dr. Jonas Miller(played by Carey Elwes) who is also following the storms. Jo wants to close to a tornado in order to test a new weather measuring device that could revolutionize tornado detection, but the trick is in getting near one without being killed... Highly entertaining film is well directed by Jan De Bont, who creates a breathless feel to the story, and has a fine cast of characters, especially Helen Hunt, who is a knockout. May stretch credibility at times, but not enough to matter. This is a fun movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loads of flying fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bill Harding (Bill Paxton) is trying to get his tornado-hunter wife Dr. Jo Harding (Helen Hunt) to sign the divorce papers, marry his girlfriend Melissa (Jami Gertz), and start his new job as a TV weatherman. But forgetting the divorce papers, a chance to use their latest contraption Dorothy, and an old nemesis Dr. Jonas Miller (Cary Elwes) pushes Bill to come along for a ride to hunt tornadoes. This is a fun wild thrill ride worthy of all the popcorn. The characters are all straight forward. There isn't much subtlety. They do some fun jokes. It's all about the roller coaster ride. The CG is pretty good for its times. The action is big fun whether it's a falling truck or a flying cow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Plain Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grade: B+. Twister is always better then I remember. The film is very fun with its chase sequences, but I always think down on it then watch it and change my mind. Bill Harding, a former twister chasing legend who is starting a new life with a new fianc&eacute;e, goes back to see the old gang to get divorce papers signed, but sees his old project finished called Dorothy to put twister reading devices inside a twister to read how stable it is for better preparation for tornadoes. When a twister hits, he tags along and is slowly drawing away from his fianc&eacute;e and to his ex Jo. He meets old friends like Dustin and Aunt Meg and also enemies like Jonas, a rival group of twister chasers who also are doing the same thing but do it for the money, not science but have better gear. After chasing for a while, they are resting at a theater when a F5 twister hits on them and nearly destroys the area but they survive but it hits Meg. His fianc&eacute;e also leaves him because she sees he still loves Jo and she needs him and the film ends with Jonas dying and them being successful but also they go inside the center of a tornado and live. Totally unrealistic, but freaking awesome to see. The film has things that don't work well with the story and characters that are annoying, but there are ones that are funny (Dustin, Meg) and the twisters are impressive and seem to be grabbed every time they chase one. It is just a lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cow?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    first off the flying cow. wow that is like one of my favorite scenes in any movie period and the tag lines that were presented in the movie,, after seeing the Cow for the first and subsequent times. Bill Paxton and Helen Hunt play off of each other very well in this picture.. The director was about 15 years ahead of his time.. look what we have today in the 2010's , the weather channel storm-chaser's several programs about that. I love the idea that in this movie you have dueling teams of Storm Chaser's the other team is headed up by a cocky Jake Busey. throughout the movie you will see some of the most horrifying scenes of twisters that can be put on film,, the funnel clouds , the wall the spinning rotation,, the vortex,, you can tell i'm a weather junkie can't you.. I live in the Midwest now and I have seen one tornado high up in the sky once right over my house,, thank god it didn't touch down,, found out later it was a F1 but still, I think that if people would stop and watch Twister seriously maybe some people in the country especially the Midwest would be better suited to deal with a tragedy like this, see you can actually learn a few things from watching a movie these days,, I loved this movie,, it is my "perfect storm".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Film with Great CGI (for it's time)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike48128
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of course today's CGI is more realistic, but this film was made in 1996! That's why I prefer my old VHS version. The pan & scan is annoying but the slight "fuzziness" makes the CGI appear more convincing. The DVD is too clear! Otherwise, turn down your sharpness and enjoy maybe the best definitive tornado movie ever made! Stormchasers in Oklahoma at the peak of the May season. The plot, at times, is cloying and slows down the action. However, Jo (Helen Hunt) believes that the tornadoes are stalking her and Bill (Paxton) is great as the "human barometer". So much eerie similarity to this year's real disaster: It's set in Oklahoma. It's a "F5" storm. Are the storms technically accurate? Probably not. I still love that poor flying cow. The gasoline tanker that almost seems to explode twice? Driving through a house turned on it's side?--both impossible, of course. I don't like the sub-plots: Bill's annoying sex therapist fianc&eacute; and the "Dorothy" telemetry tracking gizmos don't seen logical. Was this based on an actual invention? A lot of little "Spielberg" touches. The storms seem to "growl". Intentionally humorous scenes and dialog. Jo seems to "see" her family standing in the rubble of her Aunt's town, which of course is impossible. It's a great roller coaster ride all the way, even on the home "screen". The whirligigs were designed by that famous artist who just died. Today, we have almost a 15 min. tornado warning because of Doppler Radar, but it still isn't enough time to evacuate. This year in Oklahoma (2013), thousands were injured, displaced, and many died. This movie needs to be re-released on the big screen with IMAX 3D and updated special effects.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK but not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesgustina
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overall not that bad of a movie, even with the gross inaccuracies that come with the portrayal of storm chasing in it. I always enjoy watching Twister when it's on because its just a simple summer blockbuster with some cool special effects. As other people have pointed out, the science is a good ways off, but unless you're a meteorologist or weather enthusiast it shouldn't be particularly bothersome. As a chaser, I'm able to enjoy this movie because it does get the feeling of a chase almost dead on. The excitement on a day before the first storms go up is caught pretty well. Now to the science part, while Twister has many flaws (the preliminary ratings before the tornado has even dissipated to name one), some of the issues listed below are totally false. Violent tornadoes can and do happen at night. Boundary layer cooling does not mean violent tornadoes cannot occur at night (a la Greensburg, Kansas EF5 in 2007 or the Super Tuesday Outbreak in 2008). Next, while tornadoes do not usually last for hours, tornadoes can and have lasted for more than 75 minutes (Tuscaloosa EF4 April 27, 2011. Lasted from 3:40 CDT to 5:50 CDT).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    godzillaman631
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a huge Michael Crichton fan ever since Jurassic Park, Timeline, and The Lost World. After watching this movie I saw a Michael Crichton novel brought to life. Every character is fleshed out and memorable from Dusty to Beltzer and Bill. If you are a Michael Crichton you will love this movie. This movie is well acted by Bill Paxton and Helen Hunt. The scenarios they are in a very realistic with real tension there and as well some moments where there are character moments. This movie makes you feel for them and feel like part of the group. Twister has beautiful visual effects by ILM and they still hold up today. I was surprised when I saw the score for the movie as a 6.1. I give this movie a 10/10. A great 90's movie to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun and Exciting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Uriah43
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Bill Harding" (Bill Paxton) has just become a television weatherman and he wants a divorce. So he takes his new fianc&eacute; "Melissa Reeves" (Jami Gertz) with him to ask his soon-to-be ex-wife "Jo Harding" (Helen Hunt) to sign the divorce papers. Since she and her group of colleagues are in the field trying to chase tornadoes, that's where he and Melissa have to go as well. Now, prior to becoming a weatherman he and Jo were working on a recently completed project they named "Dorothy" which was a device capable of measuring scientific data within a twister. But in order for it to work they have to put it directly in front of a tornado as it is bearing down on them. If that wasn't bad enough, a former co-worker named "Jonas Miller" (Cary Elwes) has stolen their idea and has formed his own group. However, unlike Jo's group, Jonas and his group have corporate sponsorship. This has enabled them to build their own version of "Dorothy" which he has named "D.O.T. 3". Jonas and his group also have more sophisticated equipment. But Jo's group now has Bill and his instincts are superior to any man or machine. At any rate, rather than spoiling the movie for those who haven't seen it, I won't go any further with the plot. However, I will say that this film is fun and exciting. The special effects were excellent and I liked the supporting cast of characters. And if it wasn't for some of the incredibly preposterous scenarios, I probably would have rated it higher. Even so, it's still an enjoyable movie all the same.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Keating
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching this film is genuinely one of the worst things that has ever happened to me. I was warned but went ahead and did it. I could spend hours explaining why this is so bad in almost every possible way, but can't be bothered. Its the films fault. It has actually sucked all meaning out of my life. Why would a film do this? I mean Mac and me was bad, as was Howard the duck, but this is one of those films that was marginally successful. I don't like giving films a 1 out of 10, just as I'm reluctant to give a film a 10 out of 10, but this film should be quarantined it is so bad. It is a danger to people with high blood pressure or who may be suicidal. There should be a health warning. People should be made aware that swine flu is nothing compared to this. I even had that novovirus thing and that was fun compared to this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disaster leads to Romance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    katiemck44
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film Twister, written by Michael Crichton and Anne-Marie Martin and later directed by Jan De Bont was the second highest grossing film of 1996. The heavily anticipated disaster drama was action packed much like Bont's other films. Bont created Twister for anyone who loves to watch natural disasters unfold on the big screen. The movie had quite a few unrealistic scenes; however there were realistic ideas behind the actions. The script as well as acting is what lead to a very popular and exciting film. Twister in a nutshell is about two scientist/ storm chasers meeting up to get divorce papers finalized. While husband Bill Harding is more concerned with ending his marriage to start another with fianc&eacute;e, Dr. Melissa Reeves, wife Dr. Jo Harding is focused on launching a dangerous scientific machine (Dorothy) that will provide the scientist with never before developed tornado data. With the understanding of internal structures of tornados the scientist will be able to create an advanced tornado warning system. Along the way fianc&eacute;e Melissa can't handle the exciting life Bill leads leaving husband and wife to tackle the storms together. After close calls and deadly storms the couple ends up sending sensors straight into the eye of the storm and rekindling a lost relationship. While parts of this action packed film are unrealistic the film is overall enjoyable for families, adults and children. Twister, in relation to director Bont's other film Speed had action unfolding during the opening of the film and never letting up, keeping audiences on the edge of their seats in anticipation. The film producers were able to produce new cinematography never seen before. The realism of the tornados created by new technology lead to this movie placing in one of the top ranked movies of its day. Compared to the graphic of today there is a noticeable improvement, but in the 1990's the realism of a natural disaster was unheard of. Director Bont creates moods and tornadic environments with the green, blue, and blackish coloring. Not only do the colors help the audience know its storm time but the wide verity of up tempo music leads into the scene as well. On the tail of one giant tornado the film's music ranges all the way from rock to classic, all setting the mode for the adventure filled chase. A tornado film had never been done before so at the time the technology seemed amazing, but if you exclude the graphics the film follows a pretty unrealistic path. Events such as a Dodge Ram truck staying grounded and surviving high velocity winds, while a semi barreled out of the tornado made me question the realism of the movie. During the film, lead actor Bill Paxton (Bill Harding) climbs into the back of a moving pickup while hail the size of golf balls come crashing down on top of him. Anyone who has ever been hit by hail knows just how much that hurts and standing in it for a period of time would be painful for him to stand. While the film contains unrealistic events it still has some realistic aspects that can be found in most movies. The films main characters whose job is to follow the tornados in order to collect helpful data do just that. The directors and producers worked hard at making their fast chases seem natural. The cast played these scenes particularly well and it seemed as if they were true scientist excited for the challenge. This film also contains a rivalry between two group of scientist and rivalry between two women pining for a man's love. The scripted bickering was completely believable and left the audiences rooting for scientist Bill and Jo. Not only does the script work in favor of a plausible story line, the main characters Helen Hunt and Bill Paxton create a chemistry that is also very believable. These actors played the parts to their fullest potential and if I had the choice to recast this movie none of the actors would have been replaced. Every part, major of minor played a role in creating the atmosphere and they were all spot on. Everyone was excited to see this kind of destruction on the big screen and the directors and producers exceeded expectations. In my opinion the unrealistic aspects didn't affect the quality of the movie and I think those who helped it reach second highest grossing film would have to agree as well. This movie will forever pop into my mind and the minds of others who watched when they hear tornado sirens blaring. Overall the film is enjoyable and one that everyone should see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Helen Hunt & Tornadoes.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Helen Hunt is Dr. Jo Harding, a storm chaser in Oklahoma tracking a series of violent tornadoes sweeping through the state. Bill Paxton is Bill Harding, her soon-to-be ex-husband(and TV weatherman) who is trying to get Jo to sign divorce papers so that he can marry his girlfriend Melissa(played by Jamie Gertz) They soon team up to chase the storms, because of a hated rival Dr. Jonas Miller(played by Carey Elwes) who is also following the storms. Jo wants to close to a tornado in order to test a new weather measuring device that could revolutionize tornado detection, but the trick is in getting near one without being killed... Highly entertaining film is well directed by Jan De Bont, who creates a breathless feel to the story, and has a fine cast of characters, especially Helen Hunt, who is a knockout. May stretch credibility at times, but not enough to matter. This is a fun movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loads of flying fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bill Harding (Bill Paxton) is trying to get his tornado-hunter wife Dr. Jo Harding (Helen Hunt) to sign the divorce papers, marry his girlfriend Melissa (Jami Gertz), and start his new job as a TV weatherman. But forgetting the divorce papers, a chance to use their latest contraption Dorothy, and an old nemesis Dr. Jonas Miller (Cary Elwes) pushes Bill to come along for a ride to hunt tornadoes. This is a fun wild thrill ride worthy of all the popcorn. The characters are all straight forward. There isn't much subtlety. They do some fun jokes. It's all about the roller coaster ride. The CG is pretty good for its times. The action is big fun whether it's a falling truck or a flying cow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Plain Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grade: B+. Twister is always better then I remember. The film is very fun with its chase sequences, but I always think down on it then watch it and change my mind. Bill Harding, a former twister chasing legend who is starting a new life with a new fianc&eacute;e, goes back to see the old gang to get divorce papers signed, but sees his old project finished called Dorothy to put twister reading devices inside a twister to read how stable it is for better preparation for tornadoes. When a twister hits, he tags along and is slowly drawing away from his fianc&eacute;e and to his ex Jo. He meets old friends like Dustin and Aunt Meg and also enemies like Jonas, a rival group of twister chasers who also are doing the same thing but do it for the money, not science but have better gear. After chasing for a while, they are resting at a theater when a F5 twister hits on them and nearly destroys the area but they survive but it hits Meg. His fianc&eacute;e also leaves him because she sees he still loves Jo and she needs him and the film ends with Jonas dying and them being successful but also they go inside the center of a tornado and live. Totally unrealistic, but freaking awesome to see. The film has things that don't work well with the story and characters that are annoying, but there are ones that are funny (Dustin, Meg) and the twisters are impressive and seem to be grabbed every time they chase one. It is just a lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cow?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    first off the flying cow. wow that is like one of my favorite scenes in any movie period and the tag lines that were presented in the movie,, after seeing the Cow for the first and subsequent times. Bill Paxton and Helen Hunt play off of each other very well in this picture.. The director was about 15 years ahead of his time.. look what we have today in the 2010's , the weather channel storm-chaser's several programs about that. I love the idea that in this movie you have dueling teams of Storm Chaser's the other team is headed up by a cocky Jake Busey. throughout the movie you will see some of the most horrifying scenes of twisters that can be put on film,, the funnel clouds , the wall the spinning rotation,, the vortex,, you can tell i'm a weather junkie can't you.. I live in the Midwest now and I have seen one tornado high up in the sky once right over my house,, thank god it didn't touch down,, found out later it was a F1 but still, I think that if people would stop and watch Twister seriously maybe some people in the country especially the Midwest would be better suited to deal with a tragedy like this, see you can actually learn a few things from watching a movie these days,, I loved this movie,, it is my "perfect storm".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Film with Great CGI (for it's time)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike48128
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of course today's CGI is more realistic, but this film was made in 1996! That's why I prefer my old VHS version. The pan & scan is annoying but the slight "fuzziness" makes the CGI appear more convincing. The DVD is too clear! Otherwise, turn down your sharpness and enjoy maybe the best definitive tornado movie ever made! Stormchasers in Oklahoma at the peak of the May season. The plot, at times, is cloying and slows down the action. However, Jo (Helen Hunt) believes that the tornadoes are stalking her and Bill (Paxton) is great as the "human barometer". So much eerie similarity to this year's real disaster: It's set in Oklahoma. It's a "F5" storm. Are the storms technically accurate? Probably not. I still love that poor flying cow. The gasoline tanker that almost seems to explode twice? Driving through a house turned on it's side?--both impossible, of course. I don't like the sub-plots: Bill's annoying sex therapist fianc&eacute; and the "Dorothy" telemetry tracking gizmos don't seen logical. Was this based on an actual invention? A lot of little "Spielberg" touches. The storms seem to "growl". Intentionally humorous scenes and dialog. Jo seems to "see" her family standing in the rubble of her Aunt's town, which of course is impossible. It's a great roller coaster ride all the way, even on the home "screen". The whirligigs were designed by that famous artist who just died. Today, we have almost a 15 min. tornado warning because of Doppler Radar, but it still isn't enough time to evacuate. This year in Oklahoma (2013), thousands were injured, displaced, and many died. This movie needs to be re-released on the big screen with IMAX 3D and updated special effects.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK but not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesgustina
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overall not that bad of a movie, even with the gross inaccuracies that come with the portrayal of storm chasing in it. I always enjoy watching Twister when it's on because its just a simple summer blockbuster with some cool special effects. As other people have pointed out, the science is a good ways off, but unless you're a meteorologist or weather enthusiast it shouldn't be particularly bothersome. As a chaser, I'm able to enjoy this movie because it does get the feeling of a chase almost dead on. The excitement on a day before the first storms go up is caught pretty well. Now to the science part, while Twister has many flaws (the preliminary ratings before the tornado has even dissipated to name one), some of the issues listed below are totally false. Violent tornadoes can and do happen at night. Boundary layer cooling does not mean violent tornadoes cannot occur at night (a la Greensburg, Kansas EF5 in 2007 or the Super Tuesday Outbreak in 2008). Next, while tornadoes do not usually last for hours, tornadoes can and have lasted for more than 75 minutes (Tuscaloosa EF4 April 27, 2011. Lasted from 3:40 CDT to 5:50 CDT).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    godzillaman631
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a huge Michael Crichton fan ever since Jurassic Park, Timeline, and The Lost World. After watching this movie I saw a Michael Crichton novel brought to life. Every character is fleshed out and memorable from Dusty to Beltzer and Bill. If you are a Michael Crichton you will love this movie. This movie is well acted by Bill Paxton and Helen Hunt. The scenarios they are in a very realistic with real tension there and as well some moments where there are character moments. This movie makes you feel for them and feel like part of the group. Twister has beautiful visual effects by ILM and they still hold up today. I was surprised when I saw the score for the movie as a 6.1. I give this movie a 10/10. A great 90's movie to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun and Exciting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Uriah43
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Bill Harding" (Bill Paxton) has just become a television weatherman and he wants a divorce. So he takes his new fianc&eacute; "Melissa Reeves" (Jami Gertz) with him to ask his soon-to-be ex-wife "Jo Harding" (Helen Hunt) to sign the divorce papers. Since she and her group of colleagues are in the field trying to chase tornadoes, that's where he and Melissa have to go as well. Now, prior to becoming a weatherman he and Jo were working on a recently completed project they named "Dorothy" which was a device capable of measuring scientific data within a twister. But in order for it to work they have to put it directly in front of a tornado as it is bearing down on them. If that wasn't bad enough, a former co-worker named "Jonas Miller" (Cary Elwes) has stolen their idea and has formed his own group. However, unlike Jo's group, Jonas and his group have corporate sponsorship. This has enabled them to build their own version of "Dorothy" which he has named "D.O.T. 3". Jonas and his group also have more sophisticated equipment. But Jo's group now has Bill and his instincts are superior to any man or machine. At any rate, rather than spoiling the movie for those who haven't seen it, I won't go any further with the plot. However, I will say that this film is fun and exciting. The special effects were excellent and I liked the supporting cast of characters. And if it wasn't for some of the incredibly preposterous scenarios, I probably would have rated it higher. Even so, it's still an enjoyable movie all the same.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Keating
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching this film is genuinely one of the worst things that has ever happened to me. I was warned but went ahead and did it. I could spend hours explaining why this is so bad in almost every possible way, but can't be bothered. Its the films fault. It has actually sucked all meaning out of my life. Why would a film do this? I mean Mac and me was bad, as was Howard the duck, but this is one of those films that was marginally successful. I don't like giving films a 1 out of 10, just as I'm reluctant to give a film a 10 out of 10, but this film should be quarantined it is so bad. It is a danger to people with high blood pressure or who may be suicidal. There should be a health warning. People should be made aware that swine flu is nothing compared to this. I even had that novovirus thing and that was fun compared to this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disaster leads to Romance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    katiemck44
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film Twister, written by Michael Crichton and Anne-Marie Martin and later directed by Jan De Bont was the second highest grossing film of 1996. The heavily anticipated disaster drama was action packed much like Bont's other films. Bont created Twister for anyone who loves to watch natural disasters unfold on the big screen. The movie had quite a few unrealistic scenes; however there were realistic ideas behind the actions. The script as well as acting is what lead to a very popular and exciting film. Twister in a nutshell is about two scientist/ storm chasers meeting up to get divorce papers finalized. While husband Bill Harding is more concerned with ending his marriage to start another with fianc&eacute;e, Dr. Melissa Reeves, wife Dr. Jo Harding is focused on launching a dangerous scientific machine (Dorothy) that will provide the scientist with never before developed tornado data. With the understanding of internal structures of tornados the scientist will be able to create an advanced tornado warning system. Along the way fianc&eacute;e Melissa can't handle the exciting life Bill leads leaving husband and wife to tackle the storms together. After close calls and deadly storms the couple ends up sending sensors straight into the eye of the storm and rekindling a lost relationship. While parts of this action packed film are unrealistic the film is overall enjoyable for families, adults and children. Twister, in relation to director Bont's other film Speed had action unfolding during the opening of the film and never letting up, keeping audiences on the edge of their seats in anticipation. The film producers were able to produce new cinematography never seen before. The realism of the tornados created by new technology lead to this movie placing in one of the top ranked movies of its day. Compared to the graphic of today there is a noticeable improvement, but in the 1990's the realism of a natural disaster was unheard of. Director Bont creates moods and tornadic environments with the green, blue, and blackish coloring. Not only do the colors help the audience know its storm time but the wide verity of up tempo music leads into the scene as well. On the tail of one giant tornado the film's music ranges all the way from rock to classic, all setting the mode for the adventure filled chase. A tornado film had never been done before so at the time the technology seemed amazing, but if you exclude the graphics the film follows a pretty unrealistic path. Events such as a Dodge Ram truck staying grounded and surviving high velocity winds, while a semi barreled out of the tornado made me question the realism of the movie. During the film, lead actor Bill Paxton (Bill Harding) climbs into the back of a moving pickup while hail the size of golf balls come crashing down on top of him. Anyone who has ever been hit by hail knows just how much that hurts and standing in it for a period of time would be painful for him to stand. While the film contains unrealistic events it still has some realistic aspects that can be found in most movies. The films main characters whose job is to follow the tornados in order to collect helpful data do just that. The directors and producers worked hard at making their fast chases seem natural. The cast played these scenes particularly well and it seemed as if they were true scientist excited for the challenge. This film also contains a rivalry between two group of scientist and rivalry between two women pining for a man's love. The scripted bickering was completely believable and left the audiences rooting for scientist Bill and Jo. Not only does the script work in favor of a plausible story line, the main characters Helen Hunt and Bill Paxton create a chemistry that is also very believable. These actors played the parts to their fullest potential and if I had the choice to recast this movie none of the actors would have been replaced. Every part, major of minor played a role in creating the atmosphere and they were all spot on. Everyone was excited to see this kind of destruction on the big screen and the directors and producers exceeded expectations. In my opinion the unrealistic aspects didn't affect the quality of the movie and I think those who helped it reach second highest grossing film would have to agree as well. This movie will forever pop into my mind and the minds of others who watched when they hear tornado sirens blaring. Overall the film is enjoyable and one that everyone should see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Helen Hunt & Tornadoes.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Helen Hunt is Dr. Jo Harding, a storm chaser in Oklahoma tracking a series of violent tornadoes sweeping through the state. Bill Paxton is Bill Harding, her soon-to-be ex-husband(and TV weatherman) who is trying to get Jo to sign divorce papers so that he can marry his girlfriend Melissa(played by Jamie Gertz) They soon team up to chase the storms, because of a hated rival Dr. Jonas Miller(played by Carey Elwes) who is also following the storms. Jo wants to close to a tornado in order to test a new weather measuring device that could revolutionize tornado detection, but the trick is in getting near one without being killed... Highly entertaining film is well directed by Jan De Bont, who creates a breathless feel to the story, and has a fine cast of characters, especially Helen Hunt, who is a knockout. May stretch credibility at times, but not enough to matter. This is a fun movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loads of flying fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bill Harding (Bill Paxton) is trying to get his tornado-hunter wife Dr. Jo Harding (Helen Hunt) to sign the divorce papers, marry his girlfriend Melissa (Jami Gertz), and start his new job as a TV weatherman. But forgetting the divorce papers, a chance to use their latest contraption Dorothy, and an old nemesis Dr. Jonas Miller (Cary Elwes) pushes Bill to come along for a ride to hunt tornadoes. This is a fun wild thrill ride worthy of all the popcorn. The characters are all straight forward. There isn't much subtlety. They do some fun jokes. It's all about the roller coaster ride. The CG is pretty good for its times. The action is big fun whether it's a falling truck or a flying cow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Plain Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grade: B+. Twister is always better then I remember. The film is very fun with its chase sequences, but I always think down on it then watch it and change my mind. Bill Harding, a former twister chasing legend who is starting a new life with a new fianc&eacute;e, goes back to see the old gang to get divorce papers signed, but sees his old project finished called Dorothy to put twister reading devices inside a twister to read how stable it is for better preparation for tornadoes. When a twister hits, he tags along and is slowly drawing away from his fianc&eacute;e and to his ex Jo. He meets old friends like Dustin and Aunt Meg and also enemies like Jonas, a rival group of twister chasers who also are doing the same thing but do it for the money, not science but have better gear. After chasing for a while, they are resting at a theater when a F5 twister hits on them and nearly destroys the area but they survive but it hits Meg. His fianc&eacute;e also leaves him because she sees he still loves Jo and she needs him and the film ends with Jonas dying and them being successful but also they go inside the center of a tornado and live. Totally unrealistic, but freaking awesome to see. The film has things that don't work well with the story and characters that are annoying, but there are ones that are funny (Dustin, Meg) and the twisters are impressive and seem to be grabbed every time they chase one. It is just a lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cow?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    first off the flying cow. wow that is like one of my favorite scenes in any movie period and the tag lines that were presented in the movie,, after seeing the Cow for the first and subsequent times. Bill Paxton and Helen Hunt play off of each other very well in this picture.. The director was about 15 years ahead of his time.. look what we have today in the 2010's , the weather channel storm-chaser's several programs about that. I love the idea that in this movie you have dueling teams of Storm Chaser's the other team is headed up by a cocky Jake Busey. throughout the movie you will see some of the most horrifying scenes of twisters that can be put on film,, the funnel clouds , the wall the spinning rotation,, the vortex,, you can tell i'm a weather junkie can't you.. I live in the Midwest now and I have seen one tornado high up in the sky once right over my house,, thank god it didn't touch down,, found out later it was a F1 but still, I think that if people would stop and watch Twister seriously maybe some people in the country especially the Midwest would be better suited to deal with a tragedy like this, see you can actually learn a few things from watching a movie these days,, I loved this movie,, it is my "perfect storm".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Film with Great CGI (for it's time)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike48128
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of course today's CGI is more realistic, but this film was made in 1996! That's why I prefer my old VHS version. The pan & scan is annoying but the slight "fuzziness" makes the CGI appear more convincing. The DVD is too clear! Otherwise, turn down your sharpness and enjoy maybe the best definitive tornado movie ever made! Stormchasers in Oklahoma at the peak of the May season. The plot, at times, is cloying and slows down the action. However, Jo (Helen Hunt) believes that the tornadoes are stalking her and Bill (Paxton) is great as the "human barometer". So much eerie similarity to this year's real disaster: It's set in Oklahoma. It's a "F5" storm. Are the storms technically accurate? Probably not. I still love that poor flying cow. The gasoline tanker that almost seems to explode twice? Driving through a house turned on it's side?--both impossible, of course. I don't like the sub-plots: Bill's annoying sex therapist fianc&eacute; and the "Dorothy" telemetry tracking gizmos don't seen logical. Was this based on an actual invention? A lot of little "Spielberg" touches. The storms seem to "growl". Intentionally humorous scenes and dialog. Jo seems to "see" her family standing in the rubble of her Aunt's town, which of course is impossible. It's a great roller coaster ride all the way, even on the home "screen". The whirligigs were designed by that famous artist who just died. Today, we have almost a 15 min. tornado warning because of Doppler Radar, but it still isn't enough time to evacuate. This year in Oklahoma (2013), thousands were injured, displaced, and many died. This movie needs to be re-released on the big screen with IMAX 3D and updated special effects.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK but not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesgustina
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overall not that bad of a movie, even with the gross inaccuracies that come with the portrayal of storm chasing in it. I always enjoy watching Twister when it's on because its just a simple summer blockbuster with some cool special effects. As other people have pointed out, the science is a good ways off, but unless you're a meteorologist or weather enthusiast it shouldn't be particularly bothersome. As a chaser, I'm able to enjoy this movie because it does get the feeling of a chase almost dead on. The excitement on a day before the first storms go up is caught pretty well. Now to the science part, while Twister has many flaws (the preliminary ratings before the tornado has even dissipated to name one), some of the issues listed below are totally false. Violent tornadoes can and do happen at night. Boundary layer cooling does not mean violent tornadoes cannot occur at night (a la Greensburg, Kansas EF5 in 2007 or the Super Tuesday Outbreak in 2008). Next, while tornadoes do not usually last for hours, tornadoes can and have lasted for more than 75 minutes (Tuscaloosa EF4 April 27, 2011. Lasted from 3:40 CDT to 5:50 CDT).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    godzillaman631
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a huge Michael Crichton fan ever since Jurassic Park, Timeline, and The Lost World. After watching this movie I saw a Michael Crichton novel brought to life. Every character is fleshed out and memorable from Dusty to Beltzer and Bill. If you are a Michael Crichton you will love this movie. This movie is well acted by Bill Paxton and Helen Hunt. The scenarios they are in a very realistic with real tension there and as well some moments where there are character moments. This movie makes you feel for them and feel like part of the group. Twister has beautiful visual effects by ILM and they still hold up today. I was surprised when I saw the score for the movie as a 6.1. I give this movie a 10/10. A great 90's movie to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun and Exciting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Uriah43
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Bill Harding" (Bill Paxton) has just become a television weatherman and he wants a divorce. So he takes his new fianc&eacute; "Melissa Reeves" (Jami Gertz) with him to ask his soon-to-be ex-wife "Jo Harding" (Helen Hunt) to sign the divorce papers. Since she and her group of colleagues are in the field trying to chase tornadoes, that's where he and Melissa have to go as well. Now, prior to becoming a weatherman he and Jo were working on a recently completed project they named "Dorothy" which was a device capable of measuring scientific data within a twister. But in order for it to work they have to put it directly in front of a tornado as it is bearing down on them. If that wasn't bad enough, a former co-worker named "Jonas Miller" (Cary Elwes) has stolen their idea and has formed his own group. However, unlike Jo's group, Jonas and his group have corporate sponsorship. This has enabled them to build their own version of "Dorothy" which he has named "D.O.T. 3". Jonas and his group also have more sophisticated equipment. But Jo's group now has Bill and his instincts are superior to any man or machine. At any rate, rather than spoiling the movie for those who haven't seen it, I won't go any further with the plot. However, I will say that this film is fun and exciting. The special effects were excellent and I liked the supporting cast of characters. And if it wasn't for some of the incredibly preposterous scenarios, I probably would have rated it higher. Even so, it's still an enjoyable movie all the same.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Keating
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching this film is genuinely one of the worst things that has ever happened to me. I was warned but went ahead and did it. I could spend hours explaining why this is so bad in almost every possible way, but can't be bothered. Its the films fault. It has actually sucked all meaning out of my life. Why would a film do this? I mean Mac and me was bad, as was Howard the duck, but this is one of those films that was marginally successful. I don't like giving films a 1 out of 10, just as I'm reluctant to give a film a 10 out of 10, but this film should be quarantined it is so bad. It is a danger to people with high blood pressure or who may be suicidal. There should be a health warning. People should be made aware that swine flu is nothing compared to this. I even had that novovirus thing and that was fun compared to this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disaster leads to Romance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    katiemck44
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film Twister, written by Michael Crichton and Anne-Marie Martin and later directed by Jan De Bont was the second highest grossing film of 1996. The heavily anticipated disaster drama was action packed much like Bont's other films. Bont created Twister for anyone who loves to watch natural disasters unfold on the big screen. The movie had quite a few unrealistic scenes; however there were realistic ideas behind the actions. The script as well as acting is what lead to a very popular and exciting film. Twister in a nutshell is about two scientist/ storm chasers meeting up to get divorce papers finalized. While husband Bill Harding is more concerned with ending his marriage to start another with fianc&eacute;e, Dr. Melissa Reeves, wife Dr. Jo Harding is focused on launching a dangerous scientific machine (Dorothy) that will provide the scientist with never before developed tornado data. With the understanding of internal structures of tornados the scientist will be able to create an advanced tornado warning system. Along the way fianc&eacute;e Melissa can't handle the exciting life Bill leads leaving husband and wife to tackle the storms together. After close calls and deadly storms the couple ends up sending sensors straight into the eye of the storm and rekindling a lost relationship. While parts of this action packed film are unrealistic the film is overall enjoyable for families, adults and children. Twister, in relation to director Bont's other film Speed had action unfolding during the opening of the film and never letting up, keeping audiences on the edge of their seats in anticipation. The film producers were able to produce new cinematography never seen before. The realism of the tornados created by new technology lead to this movie placing in one of the top ranked movies of its day. Compared to the graphic of today there is a noticeable improvement, but in the 1990's the realism of a natural disaster was unheard of. Director Bont creates moods and tornadic environments with the green, blue, and blackish coloring. Not only do the colors help the audience know its storm time but the wide verity of up tempo music leads into the scene as well. On the tail of one giant tornado the film's music ranges all the way from rock to classic, all setting the mode for the adventure filled chase. A tornado film had never been done before so at the time the technology seemed amazing, but if you exclude the graphics the film follows a pretty unrealistic path. Events such as a Dodge Ram truck staying grounded and surviving high velocity winds, while a semi barreled out of the tornado made me question the realism of the movie. During the film, lead actor Bill Paxton (Bill Harding) climbs into the back of a moving pickup while hail the size of golf balls come crashing down on top of him. Anyone who has ever been hit by hail knows just how much that hurts and standing in it for a period of time would be painful for him to stand. While the film contains unrealistic events it still has some realistic aspects that can be found in most movies. The films main characters whose job is to follow the tornados in order to collect helpful data do just that. The directors and producers worked hard at making their fast chases seem natural. The cast played these scenes particularly well and it seemed as if they were true scientist excited for the challenge. This film also contains a rivalry between two group of scientist and rivalry between two women pining for a man's love. The scripted bickering was completely believable and left the audiences rooting for scientist Bill and Jo. Not only does the script work in favor of a plausible story line, the main characters Helen Hunt and Bill Paxton create a chemistry that is also very believable. These actors played the parts to their fullest potential and if I had the choice to recast this movie none of the actors would have been replaced. Every part, major of minor played a role in creating the atmosphere and they were all spot on. Everyone was excited to see this kind of destruction on the big screen and the directors and producers exceeded expectations. In my opinion the unrealistic aspects didn't affect the quality of the movie and I think those who helped it reach second highest grossing film would have to agree as well. This movie will forever pop into my mind and the minds of others who watched when they hear tornado sirens blaring. Overall the film is enjoyable and one that everyone should see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Helen Hunt & Tornadoes.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Helen Hunt is Dr. Jo Harding, a storm chaser in Oklahoma tracking a series of violent tornadoes sweeping through the state. Bill Paxton is Bill Harding, her soon-to-be ex-husband(and TV weatherman) who is trying to get Jo to sign divorce papers so that he can marry his girlfriend Melissa(played by Jamie Gertz) They soon team up to chase the storms, because of a hated rival Dr. Jonas Miller(played by Carey Elwes) who is also following the storms. Jo wants to close to a tornado in order to test a new weather measuring device that could revolutionize tornado detection, but the trick is in getting near one without being killed... Highly entertaining film is well directed by Jan De Bont, who creates a breathless feel to the story, and has a fine cast of characters, especially Helen Hunt, who is a knockout. May stretch credibility at times, but not enough to matter. This is a fun movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loads of flying fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bill Harding (Bill Paxton) is trying to get his tornado-hunter wife Dr. Jo Harding (Helen Hunt) to sign the divorce papers, marry his girlfriend Melissa (Jami Gertz), and start his new job as a TV weatherman. But forgetting the divorce papers, a chance to use their latest contraption Dorothy, and an old nemesis Dr. Jonas Miller (Cary Elwes) pushes Bill to come along for a ride to hunt tornadoes. This is a fun wild thrill ride worthy of all the popcorn. The characters are all straight forward. There isn't much subtlety. They do some fun jokes. It's all about the roller coaster ride. The CG is pretty good for its times. The action is big fun whether it's a falling truck or a flying cow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Plain Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grade: B+. Twister is always better then I remember. The film is very fun with its chase sequences, but I always think down on it then watch it and change my mind. Bill Harding, a former twister chasing legend who is starting a new life with a new fianc&eacute;e, goes back to see the old gang to get divorce papers signed, but sees his old project finished called Dorothy to put twister reading devices inside a twister to read how stable it is for better preparation for tornadoes. When a twister hits, he tags along and is slowly drawing away from his fianc&eacute;e and to his ex Jo. He meets old friends like Dustin and Aunt Meg and also enemies like Jonas, a rival group of twister chasers who also are doing the same thing but do it for the money, not science but have better gear. After chasing for a while, they are resting at a theater when a F5 twister hits on them and nearly destroys the area but they survive but it hits Meg. His fianc&eacute;e also leaves him because she sees he still loves Jo and she needs him and the film ends with Jonas dying and them being successful but also they go inside the center of a tornado and live. Totally unrealistic, but freaking awesome to see. The film has things that don't work well with the story and characters that are annoying, but there are ones that are funny (Dustin, Meg) and the twisters are impressive and seem to be grabbed every time they chase one. It is just a lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cow?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    first off the flying cow. wow that is like one of my favorite scenes in any movie period and the tag lines that were presented in the movie,, after seeing the Cow for the first and subsequent times. Bill Paxton and Helen Hunt play off of each other very well in this picture.. The director was about 15 years ahead of his time.. look what we have today in the 2010's , the weather channel storm-chaser's several programs about that. I love the idea that in this movie you have dueling teams of Storm Chaser's the other team is headed up by a cocky Jake Busey. throughout the movie you will see some of the most horrifying scenes of twisters that can be put on film,, the funnel clouds , the wall the spinning rotation,, the vortex,, you can tell i'm a weather junkie can't you.. I live in the Midwest now and I have seen one tornado high up in the sky once right over my house,, thank god it didn't touch down,, found out later it was a F1 but still, I think that if people would stop and watch Twister seriously maybe some people in the country especially the Midwest would be better suited to deal with a tragedy like this, see you can actually learn a few things from watching a movie these days,, I loved this movie,, it is my "perfect storm".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Film with Great CGI (for it's time)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike48128
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of course today's CGI is more realistic, but this film was made in 1996! That's why I prefer my old VHS version. The pan & scan is annoying but the slight "fuzziness" makes the CGI appear more convincing. The DVD is too clear! Otherwise, turn down your sharpness and enjoy maybe the best definitive tornado movie ever made! Stormchasers in Oklahoma at the peak of the May season. The plot, at times, is cloying and slows down the action. However, Jo (Helen Hunt) believes that the tornadoes are stalking her and Bill (Paxton) is great as the "human barometer". So much eerie similarity to this year's real disaster: It's set in Oklahoma. It's a "F5" storm. Are the storms technically accurate? Probably not. I still love that poor flying cow. The gasoline tanker that almost seems to explode twice? Driving through a house turned on it's side?--both impossible, of course. I don't like the sub-plots: Bill's annoying sex therapist fianc&eacute; and the "Dorothy" telemetry tracking gizmos don't seen logical. Was this based on an actual invention? A lot of little "Spielberg" touches. The storms seem to "growl". Intentionally humorous scenes and dialog. Jo seems to "see" her family standing in the rubble of her Aunt's town, which of course is impossible. It's a great roller coaster ride all the way, even on the home "screen". The whirligigs were designed by that famous artist who just died. Today, we have almost a 15 min. tornado warning because of Doppler Radar, but it still isn't enough time to evacuate. This year in Oklahoma (2013), thousands were injured, displaced, and many died. This movie needs to be re-released on the big screen with IMAX 3D and updated special effects.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK but not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesgustina
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overall not that bad of a movie, even with the gross inaccuracies that come with the portrayal of storm chasing in it. I always enjoy watching Twister when it's on because its just a simple summer blockbuster with some cool special effects. As other people have pointed out, the science is a good ways off, but unless you're a meteorologist or weather enthusiast it shouldn't be particularly bothersome. As a chaser, I'm able to enjoy this movie because it does get the feeling of a chase almost dead on. The excitement on a day before the first storms go up is caught pretty well. Now to the science part, while Twister has many flaws (the preliminary ratings before the tornado has even dissipated to name one), some of the issues listed below are totally false. Violent tornadoes can and do happen at night. Boundary layer cooling does not mean violent tornadoes cannot occur at night (a la Greensburg, Kansas EF5 in 2007 or the Super Tuesday Outbreak in 2008). Next, while tornadoes do not usually last for hours, tornadoes can and have lasted for more than 75 minutes (Tuscaloosa EF4 April 27, 2011. Lasted from 3:40 CDT to 5:50 CDT).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    godzillaman631
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a huge Michael Crichton fan ever since Jurassic Park, Timeline, and The Lost World. After watching this movie I saw a Michael Crichton novel brought to life. Every character is fleshed out and memorable from Dusty to Beltzer and Bill. If you are a Michael Crichton you will love this movie. This movie is well acted by Bill Paxton and Helen Hunt. The scenarios they are in a very realistic with real tension there and as well some moments where there are character moments. This movie makes you feel for them and feel like part of the group. Twister has beautiful visual effects by ILM and they still hold up today. I was surprised when I saw the score for the movie as a 6.1. I give this movie a 10/10. A great 90's movie to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun and Exciting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Uriah43
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Bill Harding" (Bill Paxton) has just become a television weatherman and he wants a divorce. So he takes his new fianc&eacute; "Melissa Reeves" (Jami Gertz) with him to ask his soon-to-be ex-wife "Jo Harding" (Helen Hunt) to sign the divorce papers. Since she and her group of colleagues are in the field trying to chase tornadoes, that's where he and Melissa have to go as well. Now, prior to becoming a weatherman he and Jo were working on a recently completed project they named "Dorothy" which was a device capable of measuring scientific data within a twister. But in order for it to work they have to put it directly in front of a tornado as it is bearing down on them. If that wasn't bad enough, a former co-worker named "Jonas Miller" (Cary Elwes) has stolen their idea and has formed his own group. However, unlike Jo's group, Jonas and his group have corporate sponsorship. This has enabled them to build their own version of "Dorothy" which he has named "D.O.T. 3". Jonas and his group also have more sophisticated equipment. But Jo's group now has Bill and his instincts are superior to any man or machine. At any rate, rather than spoiling the movie for those who haven't seen it, I won't go any further with the plot. However, I will say that this film is fun and exciting. The special effects were excellent and I liked the supporting cast of characters. And if it wasn't for some of the incredibly preposterous scenarios, I probably would have rated it higher. Even so, it's still an enjoyable movie all the same.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Keating
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching this film is genuinely one of the worst things that has ever happened to me. I was warned but went ahead and did it. I could spend hours explaining why this is so bad in almost every possible way, but can't be bothered. Its the films fault. It has actually sucked all meaning out of my life. Why would a film do this? I mean Mac and me was bad, as was Howard the duck, but this is one of those films that was marginally successful. I don't like giving films a 1 out of 10, just as I'm reluctant to give a film a 10 out of 10, but this film should be quarantined it is so bad. It is a danger to people with high blood pressure or who may be suicidal. There should be a health warning. People should be made aware that swine flu is nothing compared to this. I even had that novovirus thing and that was fun compared to this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disaster leads to Romance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    katiemck44
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film Twister, written by Michael Crichton and Anne-Marie Martin and later directed by Jan De Bont was the second highest grossing film of 1996. The heavily anticipated disaster drama was action packed much like Bont's other films. Bont created Twister for anyone who loves to watch natural disasters unfold on the big screen. The movie had quite a few unrealistic scenes; however there were realistic ideas behind the actions. The script as well as acting is what lead to a very popular and exciting film. Twister in a nutshell is about two scientist/ storm chasers meeting up to get divorce papers finalized. While husband Bill Harding is more concerned with ending his marriage to start another with fianc&eacute;e, Dr. Melissa Reeves, wife Dr. Jo Harding is focused on launching a dangerous scientific machine (Dorothy) that will provide the scientist with never before developed tornado data. With the understanding of internal structures of tornados the scientist will be able to create an advanced tornado warning system. Along the way fianc&eacute;e Melissa can't handle the exciting life Bill leads leaving husband and wife to tackle the storms together. After close calls and deadly storms the couple ends up sending sensors straight into the eye of the storm and rekindling a lost relationship. While parts of this action packed film are unrealistic the film is overall enjoyable for families, adults and children. Twister, in relation to director Bont's other film Speed had action unfolding during the opening of the film and never letting up, keeping audiences on the edge of their seats in anticipation. The film producers were able to produce new cinematography never seen before. The realism of the tornados created by new technology lead to this movie placing in one of the top ranked movies of its day. Compared to the graphic of today there is a noticeable improvement, but in the 1990's the realism of a natural disaster was unheard of. Director Bont creates moods and tornadic environments with the green, blue, and blackish coloring. Not only do the colors help the audience know its storm time but the wide verity of up tempo music leads into the scene as well. On the tail of one giant tornado the film's music ranges all the way from rock to classic, all setting the mode for the adventure filled chase. A tornado film had never been done before so at the time the technology seemed amazing, but if you exclude the graphics the film follows a pretty unrealistic path. Events such as a Dodge Ram truck staying grounded and surviving high velocity winds, while a semi barreled out of the tornado made me question the realism of the movie. During the film, lead actor Bill Paxton (Bill Harding) climbs into the back of a moving pickup while hail the size of golf balls come crashing down on top of him. Anyone who has ever been hit by hail knows just how much that hurts and standing in it for a period of time would be painful for him to stand. While the film contains unrealistic events it still has some realistic aspects that can be found in most movies. The films main characters whose job is to follow the tornados in order to collect helpful data do just that. The directors and producers worked hard at making their fast chases seem natural. The cast played these scenes particularly well and it seemed as if they were true scientist excited for the challenge. This film also contains a rivalry between two group of scientist and rivalry between two women pining for a man's love. The scripted bickering was completely believable and left the audiences rooting for scientist Bill and Jo. Not only does the script work in favor of a plausible story line, the main characters Helen Hunt and Bill Paxton create a chemistry that is also very believable. These actors played the parts to their fullest potential and if I had the choice to recast this movie none of the actors would have been replaced. Every part, major of minor played a role in creating the atmosphere and they were all spot on. Everyone was excited to see this kind of destruction on the big screen and the directors and producers exceeded expectations. In my opinion the unrealistic aspects didn't affect the quality of the movie and I think those who helped it reach second highest grossing film would have to agree as well. This movie will forever pop into my mind and the minds of others who watched when they hear tornado sirens blaring. Overall the film is enjoyable and one that everyone should see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
