<filme>
 <id>
  1180
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110093
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Adoro Problemas
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Peter Brackett and Sabrina Peterson are two competing Chicago newspaper reporters who join forces to unravel the mystery behind a train derailment.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  She's green and eager. He's seasoned and jaded. They're reporters for rival Chicago newspapers assigned to cover the same story. He offers tips and advice; she scoops him. Then, their snappy patter, repartee, and ripostes get romantic even as their competitive juices overflow. Will corrupt scientists at a chemical company whose goats give cancer-causing milk kill the cub and the columnist, or will they escape with their lives and their by-lines to hear wedding bells?
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   reporter
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   scoop
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   train
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   finger crossing
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Charles Shyer
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Nancy Meyers
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Charles Shyer
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Nick Nolte
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Julia Roberts
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Saul Rubinek
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bury the leads and below the fold
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjnxn-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bland and unimaginative but many films are that what really drags this down is not the lack of chemistry between the leads but the transparent loathing they have for each other. The production of this was notoriously contentious between Roberts and Nolte and their utter abhorrence is something that seeps out of every frame of the movie. Sometimes that can fuel a set and make the picture better, as it did on I Married a Witch where Veronica Lake and Fredric March's mutual animosity somehow translated into a kinetic on screen chemistry, such is not the case here however it just makes an already weak picture that much worse. A good supporting cast and decent production values aren't enough to save this turkey. It stinks!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Movie Review! - http://tss5078.blogspot.com
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tss5078
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen I Love Trouble several times and it never gets old. It is from the early 90s but is a story that is still entertaining today. Nick Nolte and Julia Roberts play competing reporters at different newspapers in Chicago. When a major story breaks, they both compete to scoop each other, but ultimately decide to team up when it becomes clear that their lives are endangered. Julia Roberts shines in one of her first leading roles, showing us what got her to be known as America's sweetheart. Nick Nolte is also fantastic. He is a very good actor who doesn't get many good roles anymore, because of his past. It's good to see him playing a likable character instead of making a cameo as a psychotic drunk. I Love Trouble, and I love this movie. It's a great story with an excellent cast and thoroughly entertaining.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One-Time Watch!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'I Love Trouble' is a fairly entertaining film, that offers some interesting moments in the goings-on. What really stands tall in this film, are the performances by it's popular cast. 'I Love Trouble' tells the story of how 2 Competing journalists at rival papers fall in love, while exposing a government-involved scandal. Written by the husband-and-wife team of Nancy Meyers and Charles Shyer, The writing in the first-hour is convincing & moves easily. But, in the second hour it falters and dips for quite some time, but the culmination is nicely done. Charles Shyer's direction is fair. Cinematography & Editing are functional. The Action Sequences are interesting. Performance-Wise: Nick Nolte is terrific, as always. Julia Roberts is equally superb too. In the supporting cast, Olympia Dukakis, Robert Loggia & Saul Rubinek are noticeable. On the whole, A One-Time Watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Love Trouble-This Trouble Hasn't Been So Good ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Had this film been made in the 1930s, William Powell and Myrna Loy certainly would have had the parts of Nick Nolte and Julia Roberts. The film is fast paced and provides plenty of interest as 2 competing reporters vie for a major news story regarding the derailment of a rear car of a passenger train, resulting in the deaths of 5 people. Nolte and Roberts soon discover that there is much more to this accident than anyone can believe. When they make their discovery, they are pursued by the culprits. In a very hilarious scene, the chased into a Vegas wedding chapel and wed in a quick ceremony with Nolte wearing a skull cap. Olympia Dukakis, Marsha Mason and Robert Loggia are wasted in this film. They briefly appear and don't have exciting parts at all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Love Julia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sabrina Peterson is a rising young journalist with a Chicago newspaper. Peter Brackett is a veteran columnist for a rival paper. After they are assigned by their respective editors to cover a major train accident they stumble upon a dangerous conspiracy (involving wrongdoing by a big chemical company). This could have been the plot of a standard thriller, something like Julia Roberts' previous film, "The Pelican Brief", in which a rising young lawyer teams up with a journalist to expose a dangerous conspiracy involving wrongdoing by a big oil company. "I Love Trouble," however, is not a standard thriller, but rather a light-hearted romantic comedy with thriller elements. A strong influence seems to have been the "screwball" comedies of the thirties and forties; one can imagine the role of Sabrina being taken by Katharine Hepburn with Cary Grant or Spencer Tracy as Peter. A common feature of these films is an element of friction between the male and female leads; they quarrel throughout but nevertheless end up falling in love. Perhaps the best modern example of a screwball comedy is the Coen brothers' "Intolerable Cruelty" in which George Clooney plays a cynical, manipulative divorce lawyer and Catherine Zeta Jones plays the mercenary, gold-digging ex-wife of one of his clients. In "I Love Trouble" the element of friction is provided by the rivalry between the two newspapers, which turns into rivalry between the two journalists. Peter initially takes a patronising attitude to Sabrina, whom he sees as raw and inexperienced, but she starts to win his respect when she scoops him over the train crash story. When they uncover the conspiracy they are forced to work together in order to survive, but nevertheless still continually try to outwit one another to get scoops for their papers. Since 1994 Roberts has become one of Hollywood's most successful romantic comedy actresses, but this was only her second film in the genre. The first, of course, was "Pretty Woman", the film which first made her a major star, and like the earlier film, "I Love Trouble" is heavily dependent on Roberts. She not only looks lovely but also brings her brand of star quality, the ability to seize hold of a film and to make it her own personal property. Nick Nolte is not an actor whom I would necessarily have associated with romantic comedy, but here as Peter he makes a likable hero, even if at 53 (twice Roberts' age) he is perhaps rather too old for the part. Roberts and Nolte bring out the contrast between their two characters; she bright and enthusiastic, he cynical, hard-bitten and more laid back. "I Love Trouble" is a film which has largely been overlooked; even Roberts' greatest admirers would rarely rank it among her greatest achievements, and its current rating on this board is only 4.9. This is an attitude which I find difficult to understand. The film is not perhaps as complex as "Pretty Woman" or "Notting Hill", or as funny as "America's Sweethearts", but I would certainly prefer it to something like the over-formulaic and predictable "Runaway Bride". Like most rom-coms it is a lightweight film, but it is an amusing and entertaining one which moves along at a good pace. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    enjoyable 1940s throwback
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pmcguireumc
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, once you get past the age difference of nolte and roberts, the film is enjoyable. I would have rather seen someone a little younger in Nolte's role, but other than that, i found the film enjoyable and well written. Where the film struggles however is editing. I actually think the film is about 20 minutes too long. There are a lot of traveling too and fro scenes that could have been edited out. Where the film succeeds is the acting quality. As I said above, the age difference in the leads is distracting, the chemistry in the actors is very likable (including a nice set of guest spots in the beginning, including Robert Loggia). Many of the montages used to illustrate the developing rivalry are well done and the clues in the film are very intelligent. Ultimately though, the best part of the movie is the fact that it is clean. A nice tribute to the tracy/hepburn days.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nick Nolte and Julia Roberts together in the same movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I Love Trouble" is an okay romantic comedy with some charm in certain points. But that's all. As a movie, it is generally watchable (at least during its first half). However, in the second half the movie seems to become way more slow, lame, goofy and with a notorious lack of interest and entertainment. Only the &laquo;crazy speed at the rain in the car&raquo; scene, the forced wedding scene and the thrilling ending (with some good action) are the good things about the second half. Other than that, not really. Why? Because before the thrilling ending, that sequence starts by taking too long to finally win some "life". Besides, there is a scene in a bar with dancing or country music, which is one of the most boring things for me in a movie. Not to mention that I don't see what's the point of both Peter Brackett and Sabrina Peterson keeping out-scooping each other. Nevertheless, until the first hour the movie is okay and contains some good humor. Besides, Nick Nolte is great as Peter Brackett and Julia Roberts is not bad as Sabrina Peterson. Overall, not a great movie, but certainly not as bad as they make it sound.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Opposites Attract
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George&Deolene Catsicadellis
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a wonderfully entertaining love story, spiced up with adventure and intrigue. Nick Nolte plays the rough, tough male chauvinist while Julia Roberts charms us with her usual warm and attractive personality. The two are competing newspaper reporters who while chasing after the same headline story stumble upon a government and corporate conspiracy to conceal the truth about genetically enhanced milk producing cows. The director has beautifully combined the excitement of uncovering the conspiracy with the excitement of Nolte and Roberts falling in love. The interaction and chemistry between Nolte and Roberts is acted out superbly, never too much, never too little just enough to keep you excited with them to the very end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    o.k. movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    krelll
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I HAVE SEEN THIS MOVIE,and I have to tell you the plot is really like something out of the 1970's.Although there is one good scene in it that I like.It is the scene were Julia Roberts character is getting out of the water at a lake dripping wet and naked,she is confronted by an entire group of boy scouts. Nick Nolty's character is the only thing standing between her and the boys about 10 to 14 years old.Julia Roberts begs him with everything inside her, not for him to move,he ask the boys,"ANYBODY GOT A CAMERA",then he grabs a very short towel she's managed to get hold of that cant even cover her,and snatches it off of her body stripping leaving her completely wet and naked, at the same time he runs away from her leaving her in absolute and complete shock!!! She is so shocked that if you slow this part down and look,she only tries to cover her boobs leaving her totally and completely wet and naked,and her privates and belly totally exposed to the boys who have her surrounded,allowing them to take pictures of her instantly!!She cant do anything from being in shock,but to stand there, trying to cover her boobs, and gasping loudly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mindless fun, a romance of bickering journalists
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    roghache
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I wouldn't exactly describe this as a timeless classic, a thought provoking movie, or one of the legendary love stories of the silver screen. Still, it's a fun romance and an entertaining way to spend a couple of hours. The tale revolves around two rival Chicago reporters, one relatively novice, Sabrina Peterson, the other the more seasoned, well known Peter Brackett, who are both hot on the trail of a train derailment story. Of course competition between them is intense (and so at times is the chemistry) as the two exchange false leads, fibs, barbs, and witty repartee. Lots of predictable action, chases, and mystery as to the identity of the bad guys. The lovely, always endearing Julia Roberts plays the journalistic sharp cookie, Sabrina, with Nick Nolte convincing in the role of her rival, Brackett. At least the pair are not hopping into bed within the first half hour (in refreshing contrast to most modern films), leaving a little time for storytelling and character development. This is definitely describable as a "flick" (for guys or chicks); its spirit is in keeping with its title. Personally, I'm a great Julia Roberts fan. This isn't her best picture but, nevertheless, it's quite watchable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bury the leads and below the fold
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjnxn-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bland and unimaginative but many films are that what really drags this down is not the lack of chemistry between the leads but the transparent loathing they have for each other. The production of this was notoriously contentious between Roberts and Nolte and their utter abhorrence is something that seeps out of every frame of the movie. Sometimes that can fuel a set and make the picture better, as it did on I Married a Witch where Veronica Lake and Fredric March's mutual animosity somehow translated into a kinetic on screen chemistry, such is not the case here however it just makes an already weak picture that much worse. A good supporting cast and decent production values aren't enough to save this turkey. It stinks!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Movie Review! - http://tss5078.blogspot.com
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tss5078
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen I Love Trouble several times and it never gets old. It is from the early 90s but is a story that is still entertaining today. Nick Nolte and Julia Roberts play competing reporters at different newspapers in Chicago. When a major story breaks, they both compete to scoop each other, but ultimately decide to team up when it becomes clear that their lives are endangered. Julia Roberts shines in one of her first leading roles, showing us what got her to be known as America's sweetheart. Nick Nolte is also fantastic. He is a very good actor who doesn't get many good roles anymore, because of his past. It's good to see him playing a likable character instead of making a cameo as a psychotic drunk. I Love Trouble, and I love this movie. It's a great story with an excellent cast and thoroughly entertaining.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One-Time Watch!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'I Love Trouble' is a fairly entertaining film, that offers some interesting moments in the goings-on. What really stands tall in this film, are the performances by it's popular cast. 'I Love Trouble' tells the story of how 2 Competing journalists at rival papers fall in love, while exposing a government-involved scandal. Written by the husband-and-wife team of Nancy Meyers and Charles Shyer, The writing in the first-hour is convincing & moves easily. But, in the second hour it falters and dips for quite some time, but the culmination is nicely done. Charles Shyer's direction is fair. Cinematography & Editing are functional. The Action Sequences are interesting. Performance-Wise: Nick Nolte is terrific, as always. Julia Roberts is equally superb too. In the supporting cast, Olympia Dukakis, Robert Loggia & Saul Rubinek are noticeable. On the whole, A One-Time Watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Love Trouble-This Trouble Hasn't Been So Good ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Had this film been made in the 1930s, William Powell and Myrna Loy certainly would have had the parts of Nick Nolte and Julia Roberts. The film is fast paced and provides plenty of interest as 2 competing reporters vie for a major news story regarding the derailment of a rear car of a passenger train, resulting in the deaths of 5 people. Nolte and Roberts soon discover that there is much more to this accident than anyone can believe. When they make their discovery, they are pursued by the culprits. In a very hilarious scene, the chased into a Vegas wedding chapel and wed in a quick ceremony with Nolte wearing a skull cap. Olympia Dukakis, Marsha Mason and Robert Loggia are wasted in this film. They briefly appear and don't have exciting parts at all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Love Julia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sabrina Peterson is a rising young journalist with a Chicago newspaper. Peter Brackett is a veteran columnist for a rival paper. After they are assigned by their respective editors to cover a major train accident they stumble upon a dangerous conspiracy (involving wrongdoing by a big chemical company). This could have been the plot of a standard thriller, something like Julia Roberts' previous film, "The Pelican Brief", in which a rising young lawyer teams up with a journalist to expose a dangerous conspiracy involving wrongdoing by a big oil company. "I Love Trouble," however, is not a standard thriller, but rather a light-hearted romantic comedy with thriller elements. A strong influence seems to have been the "screwball" comedies of the thirties and forties; one can imagine the role of Sabrina being taken by Katharine Hepburn with Cary Grant or Spencer Tracy as Peter. A common feature of these films is an element of friction between the male and female leads; they quarrel throughout but nevertheless end up falling in love. Perhaps the best modern example of a screwball comedy is the Coen brothers' "Intolerable Cruelty" in which George Clooney plays a cynical, manipulative divorce lawyer and Catherine Zeta Jones plays the mercenary, gold-digging ex-wife of one of his clients. In "I Love Trouble" the element of friction is provided by the rivalry between the two newspapers, which turns into rivalry between the two journalists. Peter initially takes a patronising attitude to Sabrina, whom he sees as raw and inexperienced, but she starts to win his respect when she scoops him over the train crash story. When they uncover the conspiracy they are forced to work together in order to survive, but nevertheless still continually try to outwit one another to get scoops for their papers. Since 1994 Roberts has become one of Hollywood's most successful romantic comedy actresses, but this was only her second film in the genre. The first, of course, was "Pretty Woman", the film which first made her a major star, and like the earlier film, "I Love Trouble" is heavily dependent on Roberts. She not only looks lovely but also brings her brand of star quality, the ability to seize hold of a film and to make it her own personal property. Nick Nolte is not an actor whom I would necessarily have associated with romantic comedy, but here as Peter he makes a likable hero, even if at 53 (twice Roberts' age) he is perhaps rather too old for the part. Roberts and Nolte bring out the contrast between their two characters; she bright and enthusiastic, he cynical, hard-bitten and more laid back. "I Love Trouble" is a film which has largely been overlooked; even Roberts' greatest admirers would rarely rank it among her greatest achievements, and its current rating on this board is only 4.9. This is an attitude which I find difficult to understand. The film is not perhaps as complex as "Pretty Woman" or "Notting Hill", or as funny as "America's Sweethearts", but I would certainly prefer it to something like the over-formulaic and predictable "Runaway Bride". Like most rom-coms it is a lightweight film, but it is an amusing and entertaining one which moves along at a good pace. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    enjoyable 1940s throwback
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pmcguireumc
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, once you get past the age difference of nolte and roberts, the film is enjoyable. I would have rather seen someone a little younger in Nolte's role, but other than that, i found the film enjoyable and well written. Where the film struggles however is editing. I actually think the film is about 20 minutes too long. There are a lot of traveling too and fro scenes that could have been edited out. Where the film succeeds is the acting quality. As I said above, the age difference in the leads is distracting, the chemistry in the actors is very likable (including a nice set of guest spots in the beginning, including Robert Loggia). Many of the montages used to illustrate the developing rivalry are well done and the clues in the film are very intelligent. Ultimately though, the best part of the movie is the fact that it is clean. A nice tribute to the tracy/hepburn days.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nick Nolte and Julia Roberts together in the same movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I Love Trouble" is an okay romantic comedy with some charm in certain points. But that's all. As a movie, it is generally watchable (at least during its first half). However, in the second half the movie seems to become way more slow, lame, goofy and with a notorious lack of interest and entertainment. Only the &laquo;crazy speed at the rain in the car&raquo; scene, the forced wedding scene and the thrilling ending (with some good action) are the good things about the second half. Other than that, not really. Why? Because before the thrilling ending, that sequence starts by taking too long to finally win some "life". Besides, there is a scene in a bar with dancing or country music, which is one of the most boring things for me in a movie. Not to mention that I don't see what's the point of both Peter Brackett and Sabrina Peterson keeping out-scooping each other. Nevertheless, until the first hour the movie is okay and contains some good humor. Besides, Nick Nolte is great as Peter Brackett and Julia Roberts is not bad as Sabrina Peterson. Overall, not a great movie, but certainly not as bad as they make it sound.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Opposites Attract
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George&Deolene Catsicadellis
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a wonderfully entertaining love story, spiced up with adventure and intrigue. Nick Nolte plays the rough, tough male chauvinist while Julia Roberts charms us with her usual warm and attractive personality. The two are competing newspaper reporters who while chasing after the same headline story stumble upon a government and corporate conspiracy to conceal the truth about genetically enhanced milk producing cows. The director has beautifully combined the excitement of uncovering the conspiracy with the excitement of Nolte and Roberts falling in love. The interaction and chemistry between Nolte and Roberts is acted out superbly, never too much, never too little just enough to keep you excited with them to the very end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    o.k. movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    krelll
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I HAVE SEEN THIS MOVIE,and I have to tell you the plot is really like something out of the 1970's.Although there is one good scene in it that I like.It is the scene were Julia Roberts character is getting out of the water at a lake dripping wet and naked,she is confronted by an entire group of boy scouts. Nick Nolty's character is the only thing standing between her and the boys about 10 to 14 years old.Julia Roberts begs him with everything inside her, not for him to move,he ask the boys,"ANYBODY GOT A CAMERA",then he grabs a very short towel she's managed to get hold of that cant even cover her,and snatches it off of her body stripping leaving her completely wet and naked, at the same time he runs away from her leaving her in absolute and complete shock!!! She is so shocked that if you slow this part down and look,she only tries to cover her boobs leaving her totally and completely wet and naked,and her privates and belly totally exposed to the boys who have her surrounded,allowing them to take pictures of her instantly!!She cant do anything from being in shock,but to stand there, trying to cover her boobs, and gasping loudly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mindless fun, a romance of bickering journalists
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    roghache
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I wouldn't exactly describe this as a timeless classic, a thought provoking movie, or one of the legendary love stories of the silver screen. Still, it's a fun romance and an entertaining way to spend a couple of hours. The tale revolves around two rival Chicago reporters, one relatively novice, Sabrina Peterson, the other the more seasoned, well known Peter Brackett, who are both hot on the trail of a train derailment story. Of course competition between them is intense (and so at times is the chemistry) as the two exchange false leads, fibs, barbs, and witty repartee. Lots of predictable action, chases, and mystery as to the identity of the bad guys. The lovely, always endearing Julia Roberts plays the journalistic sharp cookie, Sabrina, with Nick Nolte convincing in the role of her rival, Brackett. At least the pair are not hopping into bed within the first half hour (in refreshing contrast to most modern films), leaving a little time for storytelling and character development. This is definitely describable as a "flick" (for guys or chicks); its spirit is in keeping with its title. Personally, I'm a great Julia Roberts fan. This isn't her best picture but, nevertheless, it's quite watchable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bury the leads and below the fold
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjnxn-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bland and unimaginative but many films are that what really drags this down is not the lack of chemistry between the leads but the transparent loathing they have for each other. The production of this was notoriously contentious between Roberts and Nolte and their utter abhorrence is something that seeps out of every frame of the movie. Sometimes that can fuel a set and make the picture better, as it did on I Married a Witch where Veronica Lake and Fredric March's mutual animosity somehow translated into a kinetic on screen chemistry, such is not the case here however it just makes an already weak picture that much worse. A good supporting cast and decent production values aren't enough to save this turkey. It stinks!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Movie Review! - http://tss5078.blogspot.com
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tss5078
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen I Love Trouble several times and it never gets old. It is from the early 90s but is a story that is still entertaining today. Nick Nolte and Julia Roberts play competing reporters at different newspapers in Chicago. When a major story breaks, they both compete to scoop each other, but ultimately decide to team up when it becomes clear that their lives are endangered. Julia Roberts shines in one of her first leading roles, showing us what got her to be known as America's sweetheart. Nick Nolte is also fantastic. He is a very good actor who doesn't get many good roles anymore, because of his past. It's good to see him playing a likable character instead of making a cameo as a psychotic drunk. I Love Trouble, and I love this movie. It's a great story with an excellent cast and thoroughly entertaining.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One-Time Watch!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'I Love Trouble' is a fairly entertaining film, that offers some interesting moments in the goings-on. What really stands tall in this film, are the performances by it's popular cast. 'I Love Trouble' tells the story of how 2 Competing journalists at rival papers fall in love, while exposing a government-involved scandal. Written by the husband-and-wife team of Nancy Meyers and Charles Shyer, The writing in the first-hour is convincing & moves easily. But, in the second hour it falters and dips for quite some time, but the culmination is nicely done. Charles Shyer's direction is fair. Cinematography & Editing are functional. The Action Sequences are interesting. Performance-Wise: Nick Nolte is terrific, as always. Julia Roberts is equally superb too. In the supporting cast, Olympia Dukakis, Robert Loggia & Saul Rubinek are noticeable. On the whole, A One-Time Watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Love Trouble-This Trouble Hasn't Been So Good ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Had this film been made in the 1930s, William Powell and Myrna Loy certainly would have had the parts of Nick Nolte and Julia Roberts. The film is fast paced and provides plenty of interest as 2 competing reporters vie for a major news story regarding the derailment of a rear car of a passenger train, resulting in the deaths of 5 people. Nolte and Roberts soon discover that there is much more to this accident than anyone can believe. When they make their discovery, they are pursued by the culprits. In a very hilarious scene, the chased into a Vegas wedding chapel and wed in a quick ceremony with Nolte wearing a skull cap. Olympia Dukakis, Marsha Mason and Robert Loggia are wasted in this film. They briefly appear and don't have exciting parts at all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Love Julia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sabrina Peterson is a rising young journalist with a Chicago newspaper. Peter Brackett is a veteran columnist for a rival paper. After they are assigned by their respective editors to cover a major train accident they stumble upon a dangerous conspiracy (involving wrongdoing by a big chemical company). This could have been the plot of a standard thriller, something like Julia Roberts' previous film, "The Pelican Brief", in which a rising young lawyer teams up with a journalist to expose a dangerous conspiracy involving wrongdoing by a big oil company. "I Love Trouble," however, is not a standard thriller, but rather a light-hearted romantic comedy with thriller elements. A strong influence seems to have been the "screwball" comedies of the thirties and forties; one can imagine the role of Sabrina being taken by Katharine Hepburn with Cary Grant or Spencer Tracy as Peter. A common feature of these films is an element of friction between the male and female leads; they quarrel throughout but nevertheless end up falling in love. Perhaps the best modern example of a screwball comedy is the Coen brothers' "Intolerable Cruelty" in which George Clooney plays a cynical, manipulative divorce lawyer and Catherine Zeta Jones plays the mercenary, gold-digging ex-wife of one of his clients. In "I Love Trouble" the element of friction is provided by the rivalry between the two newspapers, which turns into rivalry between the two journalists. Peter initially takes a patronising attitude to Sabrina, whom he sees as raw and inexperienced, but she starts to win his respect when she scoops him over the train crash story. When they uncover the conspiracy they are forced to work together in order to survive, but nevertheless still continually try to outwit one another to get scoops for their papers. Since 1994 Roberts has become one of Hollywood's most successful romantic comedy actresses, but this was only her second film in the genre. The first, of course, was "Pretty Woman", the film which first made her a major star, and like the earlier film, "I Love Trouble" is heavily dependent on Roberts. She not only looks lovely but also brings her brand of star quality, the ability to seize hold of a film and to make it her own personal property. Nick Nolte is not an actor whom I would necessarily have associated with romantic comedy, but here as Peter he makes a likable hero, even if at 53 (twice Roberts' age) he is perhaps rather too old for the part. Roberts and Nolte bring out the contrast between their two characters; she bright and enthusiastic, he cynical, hard-bitten and more laid back. "I Love Trouble" is a film which has largely been overlooked; even Roberts' greatest admirers would rarely rank it among her greatest achievements, and its current rating on this board is only 4.9. This is an attitude which I find difficult to understand. The film is not perhaps as complex as "Pretty Woman" or "Notting Hill", or as funny as "America's Sweethearts", but I would certainly prefer it to something like the over-formulaic and predictable "Runaway Bride". Like most rom-coms it is a lightweight film, but it is an amusing and entertaining one which moves along at a good pace. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    enjoyable 1940s throwback
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pmcguireumc
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, once you get past the age difference of nolte and roberts, the film is enjoyable. I would have rather seen someone a little younger in Nolte's role, but other than that, i found the film enjoyable and well written. Where the film struggles however is editing. I actually think the film is about 20 minutes too long. There are a lot of traveling too and fro scenes that could have been edited out. Where the film succeeds is the acting quality. As I said above, the age difference in the leads is distracting, the chemistry in the actors is very likable (including a nice set of guest spots in the beginning, including Robert Loggia). Many of the montages used to illustrate the developing rivalry are well done and the clues in the film are very intelligent. Ultimately though, the best part of the movie is the fact that it is clean. A nice tribute to the tracy/hepburn days.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nick Nolte and Julia Roberts together in the same movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I Love Trouble" is an okay romantic comedy with some charm in certain points. But that's all. As a movie, it is generally watchable (at least during its first half). However, in the second half the movie seems to become way more slow, lame, goofy and with a notorious lack of interest and entertainment. Only the &laquo;crazy speed at the rain in the car&raquo; scene, the forced wedding scene and the thrilling ending (with some good action) are the good things about the second half. Other than that, not really. Why? Because before the thrilling ending, that sequence starts by taking too long to finally win some "life". Besides, there is a scene in a bar with dancing or country music, which is one of the most boring things for me in a movie. Not to mention that I don't see what's the point of both Peter Brackett and Sabrina Peterson keeping out-scooping each other. Nevertheless, until the first hour the movie is okay and contains some good humor. Besides, Nick Nolte is great as Peter Brackett and Julia Roberts is not bad as Sabrina Peterson. Overall, not a great movie, but certainly not as bad as they make it sound.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Opposites Attract
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George&Deolene Catsicadellis
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a wonderfully entertaining love story, spiced up with adventure and intrigue. Nick Nolte plays the rough, tough male chauvinist while Julia Roberts charms us with her usual warm and attractive personality. The two are competing newspaper reporters who while chasing after the same headline story stumble upon a government and corporate conspiracy to conceal the truth about genetically enhanced milk producing cows. The director has beautifully combined the excitement of uncovering the conspiracy with the excitement of Nolte and Roberts falling in love. The interaction and chemistry between Nolte and Roberts is acted out superbly, never too much, never too little just enough to keep you excited with them to the very end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    o.k. movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    krelll
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I HAVE SEEN THIS MOVIE,and I have to tell you the plot is really like something out of the 1970's.Although there is one good scene in it that I like.It is the scene were Julia Roberts character is getting out of the water at a lake dripping wet and naked,she is confronted by an entire group of boy scouts. Nick Nolty's character is the only thing standing between her and the boys about 10 to 14 years old.Julia Roberts begs him with everything inside her, not for him to move,he ask the boys,"ANYBODY GOT A CAMERA",then he grabs a very short towel she's managed to get hold of that cant even cover her,and snatches it off of her body stripping leaving her completely wet and naked, at the same time he runs away from her leaving her in absolute and complete shock!!! She is so shocked that if you slow this part down and look,she only tries to cover her boobs leaving her totally and completely wet and naked,and her privates and belly totally exposed to the boys who have her surrounded,allowing them to take pictures of her instantly!!She cant do anything from being in shock,but to stand there, trying to cover her boobs, and gasping loudly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mindless fun, a romance of bickering journalists
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    roghache
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I wouldn't exactly describe this as a timeless classic, a thought provoking movie, or one of the legendary love stories of the silver screen. Still, it's a fun romance and an entertaining way to spend a couple of hours. The tale revolves around two rival Chicago reporters, one relatively novice, Sabrina Peterson, the other the more seasoned, well known Peter Brackett, who are both hot on the trail of a train derailment story. Of course competition between them is intense (and so at times is the chemistry) as the two exchange false leads, fibs, barbs, and witty repartee. Lots of predictable action, chases, and mystery as to the identity of the bad guys. The lovely, always endearing Julia Roberts plays the journalistic sharp cookie, Sabrina, with Nick Nolte convincing in the role of her rival, Brackett. At least the pair are not hopping into bed within the first half hour (in refreshing contrast to most modern films), leaving a little time for storytelling and character development. This is definitely describable as a "flick" (for guys or chicks); its spirit is in keeping with its title. Personally, I'm a great Julia Roberts fan. This isn't her best picture but, nevertheless, it's quite watchable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bury the leads and below the fold
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjnxn-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bland and unimaginative but many films are that what really drags this down is not the lack of chemistry between the leads but the transparent loathing they have for each other. The production of this was notoriously contentious between Roberts and Nolte and their utter abhorrence is something that seeps out of every frame of the movie. Sometimes that can fuel a set and make the picture better, as it did on I Married a Witch where Veronica Lake and Fredric March's mutual animosity somehow translated into a kinetic on screen chemistry, such is not the case here however it just makes an already weak picture that much worse. A good supporting cast and decent production values aren't enough to save this turkey. It stinks!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Movie Review! - http://tss5078.blogspot.com
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tss5078
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen I Love Trouble several times and it never gets old. It is from the early 90s but is a story that is still entertaining today. Nick Nolte and Julia Roberts play competing reporters at different newspapers in Chicago. When a major story breaks, they both compete to scoop each other, but ultimately decide to team up when it becomes clear that their lives are endangered. Julia Roberts shines in one of her first leading roles, showing us what got her to be known as America's sweetheart. Nick Nolte is also fantastic. He is a very good actor who doesn't get many good roles anymore, because of his past. It's good to see him playing a likable character instead of making a cameo as a psychotic drunk. I Love Trouble, and I love this movie. It's a great story with an excellent cast and thoroughly entertaining.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One-Time Watch!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'I Love Trouble' is a fairly entertaining film, that offers some interesting moments in the goings-on. What really stands tall in this film, are the performances by it's popular cast. 'I Love Trouble' tells the story of how 2 Competing journalists at rival papers fall in love, while exposing a government-involved scandal. Written by the husband-and-wife team of Nancy Meyers and Charles Shyer, The writing in the first-hour is convincing & moves easily. But, in the second hour it falters and dips for quite some time, but the culmination is nicely done. Charles Shyer's direction is fair. Cinematography & Editing are functional. The Action Sequences are interesting. Performance-Wise: Nick Nolte is terrific, as always. Julia Roberts is equally superb too. In the supporting cast, Olympia Dukakis, Robert Loggia & Saul Rubinek are noticeable. On the whole, A One-Time Watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Love Trouble-This Trouble Hasn't Been So Good ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Had this film been made in the 1930s, William Powell and Myrna Loy certainly would have had the parts of Nick Nolte and Julia Roberts. The film is fast paced and provides plenty of interest as 2 competing reporters vie for a major news story regarding the derailment of a rear car of a passenger train, resulting in the deaths of 5 people. Nolte and Roberts soon discover that there is much more to this accident than anyone can believe. When they make their discovery, they are pursued by the culprits. In a very hilarious scene, the chased into a Vegas wedding chapel and wed in a quick ceremony with Nolte wearing a skull cap. Olympia Dukakis, Marsha Mason and Robert Loggia are wasted in this film. They briefly appear and don't have exciting parts at all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Love Julia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sabrina Peterson is a rising young journalist with a Chicago newspaper. Peter Brackett is a veteran columnist for a rival paper. After they are assigned by their respective editors to cover a major train accident they stumble upon a dangerous conspiracy (involving wrongdoing by a big chemical company). This could have been the plot of a standard thriller, something like Julia Roberts' previous film, "The Pelican Brief", in which a rising young lawyer teams up with a journalist to expose a dangerous conspiracy involving wrongdoing by a big oil company. "I Love Trouble," however, is not a standard thriller, but rather a light-hearted romantic comedy with thriller elements. A strong influence seems to have been the "screwball" comedies of the thirties and forties; one can imagine the role of Sabrina being taken by Katharine Hepburn with Cary Grant or Spencer Tracy as Peter. A common feature of these films is an element of friction between the male and female leads; they quarrel throughout but nevertheless end up falling in love. Perhaps the best modern example of a screwball comedy is the Coen brothers' "Intolerable Cruelty" in which George Clooney plays a cynical, manipulative divorce lawyer and Catherine Zeta Jones plays the mercenary, gold-digging ex-wife of one of his clients. In "I Love Trouble" the element of friction is provided by the rivalry between the two newspapers, which turns into rivalry between the two journalists. Peter initially takes a patronising attitude to Sabrina, whom he sees as raw and inexperienced, but she starts to win his respect when she scoops him over the train crash story. When they uncover the conspiracy they are forced to work together in order to survive, but nevertheless still continually try to outwit one another to get scoops for their papers. Since 1994 Roberts has become one of Hollywood's most successful romantic comedy actresses, but this was only her second film in the genre. The first, of course, was "Pretty Woman", the film which first made her a major star, and like the earlier film, "I Love Trouble" is heavily dependent on Roberts. She not only looks lovely but also brings her brand of star quality, the ability to seize hold of a film and to make it her own personal property. Nick Nolte is not an actor whom I would necessarily have associated with romantic comedy, but here as Peter he makes a likable hero, even if at 53 (twice Roberts' age) he is perhaps rather too old for the part. Roberts and Nolte bring out the contrast between their two characters; she bright and enthusiastic, he cynical, hard-bitten and more laid back. "I Love Trouble" is a film which has largely been overlooked; even Roberts' greatest admirers would rarely rank it among her greatest achievements, and its current rating on this board is only 4.9. This is an attitude which I find difficult to understand. The film is not perhaps as complex as "Pretty Woman" or "Notting Hill", or as funny as "America's Sweethearts", but I would certainly prefer it to something like the over-formulaic and predictable "Runaway Bride". Like most rom-coms it is a lightweight film, but it is an amusing and entertaining one which moves along at a good pace. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    enjoyable 1940s throwback
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pmcguireumc
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, once you get past the age difference of nolte and roberts, the film is enjoyable. I would have rather seen someone a little younger in Nolte's role, but other than that, i found the film enjoyable and well written. Where the film struggles however is editing. I actually think the film is about 20 minutes too long. There are a lot of traveling too and fro scenes that could have been edited out. Where the film succeeds is the acting quality. As I said above, the age difference in the leads is distracting, the chemistry in the actors is very likable (including a nice set of guest spots in the beginning, including Robert Loggia). Many of the montages used to illustrate the developing rivalry are well done and the clues in the film are very intelligent. Ultimately though, the best part of the movie is the fact that it is clean. A nice tribute to the tracy/hepburn days.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nick Nolte and Julia Roberts together in the same movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I Love Trouble" is an okay romantic comedy with some charm in certain points. But that's all. As a movie, it is generally watchable (at least during its first half). However, in the second half the movie seems to become way more slow, lame, goofy and with a notorious lack of interest and entertainment. Only the &laquo;crazy speed at the rain in the car&raquo; scene, the forced wedding scene and the thrilling ending (with some good action) are the good things about the second half. Other than that, not really. Why? Because before the thrilling ending, that sequence starts by taking too long to finally win some "life". Besides, there is a scene in a bar with dancing or country music, which is one of the most boring things for me in a movie. Not to mention that I don't see what's the point of both Peter Brackett and Sabrina Peterson keeping out-scooping each other. Nevertheless, until the first hour the movie is okay and contains some good humor. Besides, Nick Nolte is great as Peter Brackett and Julia Roberts is not bad as Sabrina Peterson. Overall, not a great movie, but certainly not as bad as they make it sound.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Opposites Attract
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George&Deolene Catsicadellis
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a wonderfully entertaining love story, spiced up with adventure and intrigue. Nick Nolte plays the rough, tough male chauvinist while Julia Roberts charms us with her usual warm and attractive personality. The two are competing newspaper reporters who while chasing after the same headline story stumble upon a government and corporate conspiracy to conceal the truth about genetically enhanced milk producing cows. The director has beautifully combined the excitement of uncovering the conspiracy with the excitement of Nolte and Roberts falling in love. The interaction and chemistry between Nolte and Roberts is acted out superbly, never too much, never too little just enough to keep you excited with them to the very end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    o.k. movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    krelll
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I HAVE SEEN THIS MOVIE,and I have to tell you the plot is really like something out of the 1970's.Although there is one good scene in it that I like.It is the scene were Julia Roberts character is getting out of the water at a lake dripping wet and naked,she is confronted by an entire group of boy scouts. Nick Nolty's character is the only thing standing between her and the boys about 10 to 14 years old.Julia Roberts begs him with everything inside her, not for him to move,he ask the boys,"ANYBODY GOT A CAMERA",then he grabs a very short towel she's managed to get hold of that cant even cover her,and snatches it off of her body stripping leaving her completely wet and naked, at the same time he runs away from her leaving her in absolute and complete shock!!! She is so shocked that if you slow this part down and look,she only tries to cover her boobs leaving her totally and completely wet and naked,and her privates and belly totally exposed to the boys who have her surrounded,allowing them to take pictures of her instantly!!She cant do anything from being in shock,but to stand there, trying to cover her boobs, and gasping loudly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mindless fun, a romance of bickering journalists
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    roghache
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I wouldn't exactly describe this as a timeless classic, a thought provoking movie, or one of the legendary love stories of the silver screen. Still, it's a fun romance and an entertaining way to spend a couple of hours. The tale revolves around two rival Chicago reporters, one relatively novice, Sabrina Peterson, the other the more seasoned, well known Peter Brackett, who are both hot on the trail of a train derailment story. Of course competition between them is intense (and so at times is the chemistry) as the two exchange false leads, fibs, barbs, and witty repartee. Lots of predictable action, chases, and mystery as to the identity of the bad guys. The lovely, always endearing Julia Roberts plays the journalistic sharp cookie, Sabrina, with Nick Nolte convincing in the role of her rival, Brackett. At least the pair are not hopping into bed within the first half hour (in refreshing contrast to most modern films), leaving a little time for storytelling and character development. This is definitely describable as a "flick" (for guys or chicks); its spirit is in keeping with its title. Personally, I'm a great Julia Roberts fan. This isn't her best picture but, nevertheless, it's quite watchable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
