<filme>
 <id>
  1181
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110399
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Low Down Dirty Shame
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A black detective becomes embroiled in a web of danger while searching for a fortune in missing drug money.During the course of his investigation, he encounters various old connections, ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A black detective becomes embroiled in a web of danger while searching for a fortune in missing drug money.During the course of his investigation, he encounters various old connections, ultimately confronting the criminal responsible for Shame's expulsion from the force. He must also deal with two women, Angela, a beautiful old flame, and Peaches, his energetic but annoying sidekick.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   drugs
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   homosexual
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hitman
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   private detective
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   white supremacy
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Keenen Ivory Wayans
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Keenen Ivory Wayans
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Keenen Ivory Wayans
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Charles S. Dutton
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jada Pinkett Smith
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Low Down Dirty Waste of Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I hired thus movie because I thought a scene on the previews where he sings James Brown to three vicious dogs and pacifies them was cool, but now I wish I didn't. Basically Low-Down-Dirty Shame is a boring clich&eacute;d movie that is just full of black jive. This is a movie where the cool black dude is not just stereotypical, but everywhere. Not only is Shame (Keenan Ivory Wayans) a cool black guy, but so is his secretary Peaches. What really annoyed me is that at the end those two got together and basically it was a relationship that just didn't seem right. When I create relationships, there is just something about them that make them seem right (not that they will work, rather just seem realistic). Low Down Dirty Shame is about an ex-cop who has become a private detective but his work is a little slow and he has a habit of losing his pay because he causes too much damage. The down and out detective is just too clich&eacute;d to be believable. Yet even though he is almost bankrupt, somehow he still has a cool car, heaps of guns, and a nice suit. Seriously this movie is just stretches the imagination too far. The plot is also too clich&eacute;d. He is after a Mexican drug-lord which seems to be the focus of every pointless cop movie these days. The twist is that this drug-lord is supposed to be dead, killed by Shame a few years earlier. Not only is this clich&eacute;d but the annoying Lieutenant is just as bad because he keeps on telling Shame off for just being there. He even tries to arrest Shame but Shame is just way too cool for that. As far as I am concerned, this movie can stay on the shelves.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you loved "Shaft", you will like this modernized flick that is a retrospect of it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charlessmith702210
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When everyone in the 1970s was introduced to the film "Shaft", it gave a great example of the African-American action hero--a cop or ex-cop who is destined to take out the bad guys. All of this inspiration from "Shaft" comes in "A Low Down Dirty Shame". Like "Shaft", "Low Down" has a cop or ex-cop, as well as action-packed sequences, like gunfights and fist fights, and this modernization from the former flick made "A Low Down Dirty Shame" make its positive impact. But there are a few twists. Keanon Ivory Wayans plays the role of Shame, who is actually an investigator who has ties to the DEA and retired as a cop. And instead of the common .38 revolver, his favorite service weapon is the 9mm Beretta. He has his sidekick, a friend named Peaches (played by Jada Pinkett at that time before she became Jada Pinkett-Smith). Shame runs his own private investigation business. So, as the story unfolds, a DEA mole named Sonny invites Shame to take on a mission to capture Ernesto Mendoza, a Mexican narcotrafficker who had a strong romance interest with character Angela Flowers, who was attempting to try to beckon Mendoza to turn himself in. The start of this focused on Shame's remembrances with Angela in the past. He mentions that she wears Covenant perfume, and basically goes on the mend to find her exactly. He does find her in one of the apartments with a bit of a police trick, and calls Sonny to try to get her to turn Mendoza in to the authorities, but regrettably, Angela said that she was on the run because a potential hit by a drug gang is imminent. This is when Sonny drops the ball but not at her...Angela was tipped, and Shame knows this. They escape the apartment as the drug gang comes in to try the death wish attempt...they confront the armed gang, and was able to escape with their lives. At Ernesto Mendoza's compound, the gang comes back home along with Sonny, and Ernesto gets upset. Sonny then rails at Ernesto that what he did will put Ernesto in trouble...and Shame was the main fly in the ointment for all of the trouble. Ernesto then does a knife slash on one of the gang members--the one who messed up the hit on Shame and Angela, and orders Sonny to get Shame. Then, Shame arms himself to the death to try to reverse the tide. He starts by forcing a low-level member of Ernesto's drug gang, Luis, to tell where Mendoza is. Little did Luis did not know that he ran into a White Supremacist rally to find that out. With that psychological torture, Luis was able to tell Shame where he was--at a nightclub. And he does. He likes to do tricks to get what he wants. Another scene I liked was the confrontation between Sonny and Angela at the shopping mall. Sonny had his gun drawn at him after Angela found the drug money. She is forced to step away and Sonny realizes that the money was real. Then, taking out of a page from the "James Bond" movies, Angela undresses her top, and reveals a full-figured black bra. But Sonny was smart, deciding not to take Angela's trick, but despite that, another ugly surprise..Angela then displays a gun from her back but Sonny did not even realize it...he gets hit several times as Sonny was about to use his gun to fire him back. Then a coup-de-grace shot by her finishes him off. So she killed Sonny so she can get the money. The final fight between Mendoza and Shame was something. Shame finally brings Mendoza down after a fight that resembled a dirty street fight and Muay Thai martial arts....and arrests him but the loud bang from a bullet kills Mendoza...but it was Angela who did it, not Shame. Now, she is going to kill Shame but from behind, Peaches, with her karate skills, was able to finish off Angela before Angela could kill off Shame. Then, you hear Peaches' love for soap operas as the movie is about to approach the final credits. So basically, when I flash back, Peaches loves television so much--that's the reason why she loves soap operas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    2 Comments in One !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wrote about this movie lately. Then I discovered an old review I wrote about it 10 years ago. Here's the 2. Emetic ! --------- It is, and for generations and generations to come. I don't know how the 1994's Razzie of the worst picture went to (Color of Night) ?! In comparison with (A Low Down..), (Color of Night) is a classic masterpiece !! It's violent comic action without any comedy or action. And its only violence is in its mammoth silliness of each and every factor in it; the cast, the way they act, the dialog, the characters, the situations...etc. (Keenen Ivory Wayans) isn't remotely funny at all; his comic scenes seemed horrible. He didn't impress anybody in his action scenes too. (Keenen Ivory Wayans)'s plot got nothing to be remembered after watching (or during watching !). And (Keenen Ivory Wayans)'s directing wasn't less low ! Did I forget to tell you that Mr. Wayans starred, wrote, and directed the whole thing? It isn't related to the fact that he's a cinematic genius or something, it's maybe because no decent moviemaker could bear working with him ! I'm a fan of (Charles S. Dutton); however I hated seeing him in here. (Jada Pinkett Smith) was incredibly unsightly and stupidly annoying. True (Salli Richardson-Whitfield) was kind of sexy, but not preferentially, or for long, or in a way could compensate for the endless ugly matters that this movie is crowded with ! The climax of its torturing crap is the lead's too gay sidekick "Wayman" (or women ?!). He can't do anything, even making laughs as he's supposed to. The only thing he succeeded to do is forcing you to throw up continually. The black try of making fun of black stereotypes wasn't filthier before! It's one naked movie, which has nothing  and I mean NOTHING  entertaining or else to present. Definitely the worst Blaxploitation movie is more interesting and memorable than this. However (A Low Down Dirty Shame) is a movie that my stomach won't forget. Works like this invented "The worst 10 movies list" ! It is a "dirty shame" only ! Written in 20/4/2010 =========================================== Flood of Filthiness ! ---------------------- This is Dirty Harry meets a dirty rap song. It goes like this : a black lead between Shaft and Martin Lawrence + logicless plot + the filthiest language ever recorded on film + countless rap songs for more than what any endurance could stand = mean outcome which's too paltry to remember. Man. Did I hate it? Well, it makes itself impossible to love. I hated the scene of seeing the great lead preparing to fight, wearing the best of what he has of clothes and weapons; I have seen this moment for at least 1000 times before! I hated (Jada Pinkett Smith) as the secretary. I may go to hell if I ever put "beautiful" and her name in one sentence anytime! The way she looks and talks is extremely sickening. What epithet she deserves the most ? The most detestable cartoon character, the silliest girl even been in an action, or the ugliest thing I have ever seen ! Having none sense of humor was better than having the worst kind; as this movie does ! From totally unfunny scenes for (Wayans), to such a contumely to the 1960s star (James Brown) as if only dogs that listen to his songs now, ending up with the hellish dialog. Most of the time I felt my ears getting flayed. Just recall : the numerous "ass", "penis", "fucking" terminologies. I believe this movie is a fine reference book for all the squalid phrases that use these words (the tabloid speaks about decreasing the size of asses, shoot my ass, don't make me spank your black ass, promise me to burn his ass...) Ahh, there is no end and nothing else. It assures not only that (Wayans) knows nothing about writing comedy but by using these terms, he rather knows nothing from the English language but them too! Let alone the free pure filth: The conversation about the beauty of a crippled girl's butt, or the joy of making love with the crippled girls in general (!!!!!). Or the awful story of (Jada Pinkett Smith) about her dog that shits a lot. Things like these, and I'm not sorry to say, made the movie as a huge pile of excrement itself ! But still, to add more vomit, here you are; the lead's sissy sidekick "Wayman". 3 scenes, just 3, got this thing in it. Nevertheless the repugnant effect of it can't be forgotten. What alien from outer space, or a demon from inferno, can actually bear this "Wayman" for a second ?? He's, without a doubt, the dirtiest of whatever this movie has ! In Egypt, its commercial title as a video stood for (The Professional and The Beauties), while I saw no Professional, Beauties, or a "Beauty" of any kind ! Written in 3/10/2000 =========================================== Not much of a difference, huh ?!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Do Not Believe The CRAP "uppity" People Say About This Movie...IT IS AWESOOOOME!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stumaczter1
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm sure this movie wasn't done with "we're gonna win an academy award with this one!" intentions it doesn't take itself too seriously & was done to entertain & it did just that! Trust me all the negative criticism & unnecessary flack this movie got was totally unwarranted & was done by people who have NO taste for GREAT entertainment! That being said this movie is one of my favourite comedy/action flicks..it is FUNNNNNNNNNY & the ACTION is steadily paced & EXPLOSIVE there isn't a dull moment in this one guys.Jada Pinkett was too cute not to mention hilarious in this movie & her personality amped this film up nicely.The guy who played Louise was very funny & of course the oldest Wayans brother Keenan (the star)delivered too.Lol the guy who played Wayman was a riot as well. In my head I'm trying to pick out a favourite moment from this movie & I can't!..the whole movie was a BLAST & if you haven't seen it yet you're wasting time..seriously! It's one of the best films in the comedy/action genre & fans of both individual genres WON'T be disappointed either..so if you haven't seen it yet do yourself a favour & check it out you won't regret it! 10 out of 10 stars!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You Might Like It, You Might Not
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ichocolat
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some films that you can't decide whether the film is good or bad. On whether the film is worth the watch or you're better off doing some other more meaningful things. This film is one of it. As I said, you might like it, you might not. The acting a little bit over the top, but I think that's what the producer intended to do. The jokes may at times be quite crude, but maybe it's exactly the way it was suppose to be. Worth a mention here is Jada Pinkett acting. She's quite good ! And I like her hairstyle too. Not that it has any bearing of the quality of acting though, just wanted to let you guys know. Over all, the film is nice to watch, if you don't take it seriously.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fromer cop turns private eye and catches a case from his past
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brooklynjymmah
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie does what it set out to do,make the the people watching this movie laugh. A Low Down Dirty Shame characters make this an enjoyable movie. Jada Pinkett is perfectly cast as Peaches Shame's (Wayans' character) Assistant.She's funny and likable in this role the action does not come with overly done, loud, explosive, costly Hollywood production. what it does come with is humor and that's why this movie is solid..When I first saw this movie I couldn't stop laughing. When Peaches has the scene with the Geri-Curled,Gold Toothed Mailman. The scene when Shane wakes up next to Peaches'roommate I'm still waiting for Shame 2. Heck,I have seen worst movies make a sequel. My suggestion to anyone who is interested in seeing this movie is go into it with an open mind and you will love it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good watch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    NLC-Rasta
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fun movie not to be taken seriously and nice to see actors/actresses that are not afraid of trying something different. I cant compare this movie to any other, its a movie just for pure comedy/action entertainment and not aimed at any particular group, genre, race or religion, or political issues. Although there are some race/sexual orientated material, i'm sure its strictly just for the story/plot and not meant to degrade, harm or single out any one. I enjoy the odd laugh now and then and this movie has its very funny moments, i like it... very good. There maybe negative ratings/comments out there which balances out the whole and everyone has the right to there own views, I've watched far worse movies with thinner plots and story lines even poor acting but i'l give them credit for at least trying to play the part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shaft with humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (winner55)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed this film, and it holds up fairly well with repeated viewings. But more importantly, this film has historical importance. First of all, this film is drawing very heavily on Hong Kong action thrillers at a time when these were just getting attention in the US. Secondly, compare this film very carefully with the Samuel Jackson "remake" of "Shaft", released - with enormous hype - in 2000. I don't know why Wayans didn't sue for plagiarism. Samuel Jackson's Shaft is Shame without humor. Unfortunately, the humor is absolutely essential to this story. For one thing, it creates a "black" identity that is capable of rising above any Hollywood appropriation of it. Shame's secretary - and real romantic interest - is a strong black woman - a character type that Hollywood has finally admitted actually exists only very recently, since about 2001. So Samuel Jackson's Shaft gets a x-million dollars promo, and still can't come up with an interesting story (although it was nice to see Richard roundtree on the screen again). Meanwhile, let's talk about entertainment - alright, there are some bits that don't work; but enough do to keep the film moving. I had good time; what the heck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I loved this MOVIE!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ct162926
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    WOW! this movie was great filled with action and comedy. The Action was from start to end! And the comedy is what makes this movie good peaches (Jada Pinkett Smith) was so funny in this one go rent it its worth 3 or 4 bucks! Don't Listen To The Top Comment hes a negative person and it has different people in it that surprisingly does a very good job! There's boy fights and guess what Jada fights in it to she is so ghetto in this film she hasn't done a lot of films but this one is definitely top 5. if u have any comments on my thoughts please e-mail me at get_over_it@now.com OK I'm done with this one on to the next films. gosh they make you write a minimum number of ten lines.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you take this seriously then you're totally missing the point!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Low Down Dirty Shame is really no more than all the most familiar Cop movie clich&eacute;s arranged in an order that makes a barely cohesive story. But it's all the fun and silly action that occurs in between that really matters! It's a bit like The Last Boy Scout from a spoof-blaxploitation angle. Shame (Keenan Ivory Wayans) is a former cop who has been blackballed after a major drugs bust went awry, leaving several DEA agents dead. He now works as a private detective, taking on suicide missions for peanuts and barely scraping by. His disapproving secretary Peaches (a very funny and very, very small Jada Pinkett) wants him to get his act together but he's too busy wallowing in self-pity. His old pal from the DEA shows up and offers him a side mission to help get back at the Drug Kingpin who ruined his career. And so, with only a few clues, Shame begins his search and soon all roads lead to lies and deception. Like I said, the plot is certainly nothing special. But it does contain a helluva lot of laughs and decent action. The one thing I can complain of is that the production design is kind of dated now. Action films have evolved so much in the past decade that watching ALDDS 12 years on can be a bit distracting. Wayans (who also directs as well as writing and starring) too often shoots non-actions scenes like a sitcom and his light-hearted editing may help remind you that this totally AIN'T a serious film but it's a little TV-ish if you know what I mean. If you find ALDDS for cheap somewhere or if it's showing on TV then don't con yourself out of a fun movie. High art is not what this film aims to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Low Down Dirty Waste of Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I hired thus movie because I thought a scene on the previews where he sings James Brown to three vicious dogs and pacifies them was cool, but now I wish I didn't. Basically Low-Down-Dirty Shame is a boring clich&eacute;d movie that is just full of black jive. This is a movie where the cool black dude is not just stereotypical, but everywhere. Not only is Shame (Keenan Ivory Wayans) a cool black guy, but so is his secretary Peaches. What really annoyed me is that at the end those two got together and basically it was a relationship that just didn't seem right. When I create relationships, there is just something about them that make them seem right (not that they will work, rather just seem realistic). Low Down Dirty Shame is about an ex-cop who has become a private detective but his work is a little slow and he has a habit of losing his pay because he causes too much damage. The down and out detective is just too clich&eacute;d to be believable. Yet even though he is almost bankrupt, somehow he still has a cool car, heaps of guns, and a nice suit. Seriously this movie is just stretches the imagination too far. The plot is also too clich&eacute;d. He is after a Mexican drug-lord which seems to be the focus of every pointless cop movie these days. The twist is that this drug-lord is supposed to be dead, killed by Shame a few years earlier. Not only is this clich&eacute;d but the annoying Lieutenant is just as bad because he keeps on telling Shame off for just being there. He even tries to arrest Shame but Shame is just way too cool for that. As far as I am concerned, this movie can stay on the shelves.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you loved "Shaft", you will like this modernized flick that is a retrospect of it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charlessmith702210
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When everyone in the 1970s was introduced to the film "Shaft", it gave a great example of the African-American action hero--a cop or ex-cop who is destined to take out the bad guys. All of this inspiration from "Shaft" comes in "A Low Down Dirty Shame". Like "Shaft", "Low Down" has a cop or ex-cop, as well as action-packed sequences, like gunfights and fist fights, and this modernization from the former flick made "A Low Down Dirty Shame" make its positive impact. But there are a few twists. Keanon Ivory Wayans plays the role of Shame, who is actually an investigator who has ties to the DEA and retired as a cop. And instead of the common .38 revolver, his favorite service weapon is the 9mm Beretta. He has his sidekick, a friend named Peaches (played by Jada Pinkett at that time before she became Jada Pinkett-Smith). Shame runs his own private investigation business. So, as the story unfolds, a DEA mole named Sonny invites Shame to take on a mission to capture Ernesto Mendoza, a Mexican narcotrafficker who had a strong romance interest with character Angela Flowers, who was attempting to try to beckon Mendoza to turn himself in. The start of this focused on Shame's remembrances with Angela in the past. He mentions that she wears Covenant perfume, and basically goes on the mend to find her exactly. He does find her in one of the apartments with a bit of a police trick, and calls Sonny to try to get her to turn Mendoza in to the authorities, but regrettably, Angela said that she was on the run because a potential hit by a drug gang is imminent. This is when Sonny drops the ball but not at her...Angela was tipped, and Shame knows this. They escape the apartment as the drug gang comes in to try the death wish attempt...they confront the armed gang, and was able to escape with their lives. At Ernesto Mendoza's compound, the gang comes back home along with Sonny, and Ernesto gets upset. Sonny then rails at Ernesto that what he did will put Ernesto in trouble...and Shame was the main fly in the ointment for all of the trouble. Ernesto then does a knife slash on one of the gang members--the one who messed up the hit on Shame and Angela, and orders Sonny to get Shame. Then, Shame arms himself to the death to try to reverse the tide. He starts by forcing a low-level member of Ernesto's drug gang, Luis, to tell where Mendoza is. Little did Luis did not know that he ran into a White Supremacist rally to find that out. With that psychological torture, Luis was able to tell Shame where he was--at a nightclub. And he does. He likes to do tricks to get what he wants. Another scene I liked was the confrontation between Sonny and Angela at the shopping mall. Sonny had his gun drawn at him after Angela found the drug money. She is forced to step away and Sonny realizes that the money was real. Then, taking out of a page from the "James Bond" movies, Angela undresses her top, and reveals a full-figured black bra. But Sonny was smart, deciding not to take Angela's trick, but despite that, another ugly surprise..Angela then displays a gun from her back but Sonny did not even realize it...he gets hit several times as Sonny was about to use his gun to fire him back. Then a coup-de-grace shot by her finishes him off. So she killed Sonny so she can get the money. The final fight between Mendoza and Shame was something. Shame finally brings Mendoza down after a fight that resembled a dirty street fight and Muay Thai martial arts....and arrests him but the loud bang from a bullet kills Mendoza...but it was Angela who did it, not Shame. Now, she is going to kill Shame but from behind, Peaches, with her karate skills, was able to finish off Angela before Angela could kill off Shame. Then, you hear Peaches' love for soap operas as the movie is about to approach the final credits. So basically, when I flash back, Peaches loves television so much--that's the reason why she loves soap operas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    2 Comments in One !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wrote about this movie lately. Then I discovered an old review I wrote about it 10 years ago. Here's the 2. Emetic ! --------- It is, and for generations and generations to come. I don't know how the 1994's Razzie of the worst picture went to (Color of Night) ?! In comparison with (A Low Down..), (Color of Night) is a classic masterpiece !! It's violent comic action without any comedy or action. And its only violence is in its mammoth silliness of each and every factor in it; the cast, the way they act, the dialog, the characters, the situations...etc. (Keenen Ivory Wayans) isn't remotely funny at all; his comic scenes seemed horrible. He didn't impress anybody in his action scenes too. (Keenen Ivory Wayans)'s plot got nothing to be remembered after watching (or during watching !). And (Keenen Ivory Wayans)'s directing wasn't less low ! Did I forget to tell you that Mr. Wayans starred, wrote, and directed the whole thing? It isn't related to the fact that he's a cinematic genius or something, it's maybe because no decent moviemaker could bear working with him ! I'm a fan of (Charles S. Dutton); however I hated seeing him in here. (Jada Pinkett Smith) was incredibly unsightly and stupidly annoying. True (Salli Richardson-Whitfield) was kind of sexy, but not preferentially, or for long, or in a way could compensate for the endless ugly matters that this movie is crowded with ! The climax of its torturing crap is the lead's too gay sidekick "Wayman" (or women ?!). He can't do anything, even making laughs as he's supposed to. The only thing he succeeded to do is forcing you to throw up continually. The black try of making fun of black stereotypes wasn't filthier before! It's one naked movie, which has nothing  and I mean NOTHING  entertaining or else to present. Definitely the worst Blaxploitation movie is more interesting and memorable than this. However (A Low Down Dirty Shame) is a movie that my stomach won't forget. Works like this invented "The worst 10 movies list" ! It is a "dirty shame" only ! Written in 20/4/2010 =========================================== Flood of Filthiness ! ---------------------- This is Dirty Harry meets a dirty rap song. It goes like this : a black lead between Shaft and Martin Lawrence + logicless plot + the filthiest language ever recorded on film + countless rap songs for more than what any endurance could stand = mean outcome which's too paltry to remember. Man. Did I hate it? Well, it makes itself impossible to love. I hated the scene of seeing the great lead preparing to fight, wearing the best of what he has of clothes and weapons; I have seen this moment for at least 1000 times before! I hated (Jada Pinkett Smith) as the secretary. I may go to hell if I ever put "beautiful" and her name in one sentence anytime! The way she looks and talks is extremely sickening. What epithet she deserves the most ? The most detestable cartoon character, the silliest girl even been in an action, or the ugliest thing I have ever seen ! Having none sense of humor was better than having the worst kind; as this movie does ! From totally unfunny scenes for (Wayans), to such a contumely to the 1960s star (James Brown) as if only dogs that listen to his songs now, ending up with the hellish dialog. Most of the time I felt my ears getting flayed. Just recall : the numerous "ass", "penis", "fucking" terminologies. I believe this movie is a fine reference book for all the squalid phrases that use these words (the tabloid speaks about decreasing the size of asses, shoot my ass, don't make me spank your black ass, promise me to burn his ass...) Ahh, there is no end and nothing else. It assures not only that (Wayans) knows nothing about writing comedy but by using these terms, he rather knows nothing from the English language but them too! Let alone the free pure filth: The conversation about the beauty of a crippled girl's butt, or the joy of making love with the crippled girls in general (!!!!!). Or the awful story of (Jada Pinkett Smith) about her dog that shits a lot. Things like these, and I'm not sorry to say, made the movie as a huge pile of excrement itself ! But still, to add more vomit, here you are; the lead's sissy sidekick "Wayman". 3 scenes, just 3, got this thing in it. Nevertheless the repugnant effect of it can't be forgotten. What alien from outer space, or a demon from inferno, can actually bear this "Wayman" for a second ?? He's, without a doubt, the dirtiest of whatever this movie has ! In Egypt, its commercial title as a video stood for (The Professional and The Beauties), while I saw no Professional, Beauties, or a "Beauty" of any kind ! Written in 3/10/2000 =========================================== Not much of a difference, huh ?!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Do Not Believe The CRAP "uppity" People Say About This Movie...IT IS AWESOOOOME!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stumaczter1
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm sure this movie wasn't done with "we're gonna win an academy award with this one!" intentions it doesn't take itself too seriously & was done to entertain & it did just that! Trust me all the negative criticism & unnecessary flack this movie got was totally unwarranted & was done by people who have NO taste for GREAT entertainment! That being said this movie is one of my favourite comedy/action flicks..it is FUNNNNNNNNNY & the ACTION is steadily paced & EXPLOSIVE there isn't a dull moment in this one guys.Jada Pinkett was too cute not to mention hilarious in this movie & her personality amped this film up nicely.The guy who played Louise was very funny & of course the oldest Wayans brother Keenan (the star)delivered too.Lol the guy who played Wayman was a riot as well. In my head I'm trying to pick out a favourite moment from this movie & I can't!..the whole movie was a BLAST & if you haven't seen it yet you're wasting time..seriously! It's one of the best films in the comedy/action genre & fans of both individual genres WON'T be disappointed either..so if you haven't seen it yet do yourself a favour & check it out you won't regret it! 10 out of 10 stars!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You Might Like It, You Might Not
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ichocolat
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some films that you can't decide whether the film is good or bad. On whether the film is worth the watch or you're better off doing some other more meaningful things. This film is one of it. As I said, you might like it, you might not. The acting a little bit over the top, but I think that's what the producer intended to do. The jokes may at times be quite crude, but maybe it's exactly the way it was suppose to be. Worth a mention here is Jada Pinkett acting. She's quite good ! And I like her hairstyle too. Not that it has any bearing of the quality of acting though, just wanted to let you guys know. Over all, the film is nice to watch, if you don't take it seriously.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fromer cop turns private eye and catches a case from his past
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brooklynjymmah
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie does what it set out to do,make the the people watching this movie laugh. A Low Down Dirty Shame characters make this an enjoyable movie. Jada Pinkett is perfectly cast as Peaches Shame's (Wayans' character) Assistant.She's funny and likable in this role the action does not come with overly done, loud, explosive, costly Hollywood production. what it does come with is humor and that's why this movie is solid..When I first saw this movie I couldn't stop laughing. When Peaches has the scene with the Geri-Curled,Gold Toothed Mailman. The scene when Shane wakes up next to Peaches'roommate I'm still waiting for Shame 2. Heck,I have seen worst movies make a sequel. My suggestion to anyone who is interested in seeing this movie is go into it with an open mind and you will love it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good watch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    NLC-Rasta
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fun movie not to be taken seriously and nice to see actors/actresses that are not afraid of trying something different. I cant compare this movie to any other, its a movie just for pure comedy/action entertainment and not aimed at any particular group, genre, race or religion, or political issues. Although there are some race/sexual orientated material, i'm sure its strictly just for the story/plot and not meant to degrade, harm or single out any one. I enjoy the odd laugh now and then and this movie has its very funny moments, i like it... very good. There maybe negative ratings/comments out there which balances out the whole and everyone has the right to there own views, I've watched far worse movies with thinner plots and story lines even poor acting but i'l give them credit for at least trying to play the part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shaft with humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (winner55)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed this film, and it holds up fairly well with repeated viewings. But more importantly, this film has historical importance. First of all, this film is drawing very heavily on Hong Kong action thrillers at a time when these were just getting attention in the US. Secondly, compare this film very carefully with the Samuel Jackson "remake" of "Shaft", released - with enormous hype - in 2000. I don't know why Wayans didn't sue for plagiarism. Samuel Jackson's Shaft is Shame without humor. Unfortunately, the humor is absolutely essential to this story. For one thing, it creates a "black" identity that is capable of rising above any Hollywood appropriation of it. Shame's secretary - and real romantic interest - is a strong black woman - a character type that Hollywood has finally admitted actually exists only very recently, since about 2001. So Samuel Jackson's Shaft gets a x-million dollars promo, and still can't come up with an interesting story (although it was nice to see Richard roundtree on the screen again). Meanwhile, let's talk about entertainment - alright, there are some bits that don't work; but enough do to keep the film moving. I had good time; what the heck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I loved this MOVIE!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ct162926
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    WOW! this movie was great filled with action and comedy. The Action was from start to end! And the comedy is what makes this movie good peaches (Jada Pinkett Smith) was so funny in this one go rent it its worth 3 or 4 bucks! Don't Listen To The Top Comment hes a negative person and it has different people in it that surprisingly does a very good job! There's boy fights and guess what Jada fights in it to she is so ghetto in this film she hasn't done a lot of films but this one is definitely top 5. if u have any comments on my thoughts please e-mail me at get_over_it@now.com OK I'm done with this one on to the next films. gosh they make you write a minimum number of ten lines.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you take this seriously then you're totally missing the point!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Low Down Dirty Shame is really no more than all the most familiar Cop movie clich&eacute;s arranged in an order that makes a barely cohesive story. But it's all the fun and silly action that occurs in between that really matters! It's a bit like The Last Boy Scout from a spoof-blaxploitation angle. Shame (Keenan Ivory Wayans) is a former cop who has been blackballed after a major drugs bust went awry, leaving several DEA agents dead. He now works as a private detective, taking on suicide missions for peanuts and barely scraping by. His disapproving secretary Peaches (a very funny and very, very small Jada Pinkett) wants him to get his act together but he's too busy wallowing in self-pity. His old pal from the DEA shows up and offers him a side mission to help get back at the Drug Kingpin who ruined his career. And so, with only a few clues, Shame begins his search and soon all roads lead to lies and deception. Like I said, the plot is certainly nothing special. But it does contain a helluva lot of laughs and decent action. The one thing I can complain of is that the production design is kind of dated now. Action films have evolved so much in the past decade that watching ALDDS 12 years on can be a bit distracting. Wayans (who also directs as well as writing and starring) too often shoots non-actions scenes like a sitcom and his light-hearted editing may help remind you that this totally AIN'T a serious film but it's a little TV-ish if you know what I mean. If you find ALDDS for cheap somewhere or if it's showing on TV then don't con yourself out of a fun movie. High art is not what this film aims to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Low Down Dirty Waste of Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I hired thus movie because I thought a scene on the previews where he sings James Brown to three vicious dogs and pacifies them was cool, but now I wish I didn't. Basically Low-Down-Dirty Shame is a boring clich&eacute;d movie that is just full of black jive. This is a movie where the cool black dude is not just stereotypical, but everywhere. Not only is Shame (Keenan Ivory Wayans) a cool black guy, but so is his secretary Peaches. What really annoyed me is that at the end those two got together and basically it was a relationship that just didn't seem right. When I create relationships, there is just something about them that make them seem right (not that they will work, rather just seem realistic). Low Down Dirty Shame is about an ex-cop who has become a private detective but his work is a little slow and he has a habit of losing his pay because he causes too much damage. The down and out detective is just too clich&eacute;d to be believable. Yet even though he is almost bankrupt, somehow he still has a cool car, heaps of guns, and a nice suit. Seriously this movie is just stretches the imagination too far. The plot is also too clich&eacute;d. He is after a Mexican drug-lord which seems to be the focus of every pointless cop movie these days. The twist is that this drug-lord is supposed to be dead, killed by Shame a few years earlier. Not only is this clich&eacute;d but the annoying Lieutenant is just as bad because he keeps on telling Shame off for just being there. He even tries to arrest Shame but Shame is just way too cool for that. As far as I am concerned, this movie can stay on the shelves.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you loved "Shaft", you will like this modernized flick that is a retrospect of it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charlessmith702210
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When everyone in the 1970s was introduced to the film "Shaft", it gave a great example of the African-American action hero--a cop or ex-cop who is destined to take out the bad guys. All of this inspiration from "Shaft" comes in "A Low Down Dirty Shame". Like "Shaft", "Low Down" has a cop or ex-cop, as well as action-packed sequences, like gunfights and fist fights, and this modernization from the former flick made "A Low Down Dirty Shame" make its positive impact. But there are a few twists. Keanon Ivory Wayans plays the role of Shame, who is actually an investigator who has ties to the DEA and retired as a cop. And instead of the common .38 revolver, his favorite service weapon is the 9mm Beretta. He has his sidekick, a friend named Peaches (played by Jada Pinkett at that time before she became Jada Pinkett-Smith). Shame runs his own private investigation business. So, as the story unfolds, a DEA mole named Sonny invites Shame to take on a mission to capture Ernesto Mendoza, a Mexican narcotrafficker who had a strong romance interest with character Angela Flowers, who was attempting to try to beckon Mendoza to turn himself in. The start of this focused on Shame's remembrances with Angela in the past. He mentions that she wears Covenant perfume, and basically goes on the mend to find her exactly. He does find her in one of the apartments with a bit of a police trick, and calls Sonny to try to get her to turn Mendoza in to the authorities, but regrettably, Angela said that she was on the run because a potential hit by a drug gang is imminent. This is when Sonny drops the ball but not at her...Angela was tipped, and Shame knows this. They escape the apartment as the drug gang comes in to try the death wish attempt...they confront the armed gang, and was able to escape with their lives. At Ernesto Mendoza's compound, the gang comes back home along with Sonny, and Ernesto gets upset. Sonny then rails at Ernesto that what he did will put Ernesto in trouble...and Shame was the main fly in the ointment for all of the trouble. Ernesto then does a knife slash on one of the gang members--the one who messed up the hit on Shame and Angela, and orders Sonny to get Shame. Then, Shame arms himself to the death to try to reverse the tide. He starts by forcing a low-level member of Ernesto's drug gang, Luis, to tell where Mendoza is. Little did Luis did not know that he ran into a White Supremacist rally to find that out. With that psychological torture, Luis was able to tell Shame where he was--at a nightclub. And he does. He likes to do tricks to get what he wants. Another scene I liked was the confrontation between Sonny and Angela at the shopping mall. Sonny had his gun drawn at him after Angela found the drug money. She is forced to step away and Sonny realizes that the money was real. Then, taking out of a page from the "James Bond" movies, Angela undresses her top, and reveals a full-figured black bra. But Sonny was smart, deciding not to take Angela's trick, but despite that, another ugly surprise..Angela then displays a gun from her back but Sonny did not even realize it...he gets hit several times as Sonny was about to use his gun to fire him back. Then a coup-de-grace shot by her finishes him off. So she killed Sonny so she can get the money. The final fight between Mendoza and Shame was something. Shame finally brings Mendoza down after a fight that resembled a dirty street fight and Muay Thai martial arts....and arrests him but the loud bang from a bullet kills Mendoza...but it was Angela who did it, not Shame. Now, she is going to kill Shame but from behind, Peaches, with her karate skills, was able to finish off Angela before Angela could kill off Shame. Then, you hear Peaches' love for soap operas as the movie is about to approach the final credits. So basically, when I flash back, Peaches loves television so much--that's the reason why she loves soap operas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    2 Comments in One !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wrote about this movie lately. Then I discovered an old review I wrote about it 10 years ago. Here's the 2. Emetic ! --------- It is, and for generations and generations to come. I don't know how the 1994's Razzie of the worst picture went to (Color of Night) ?! In comparison with (A Low Down..), (Color of Night) is a classic masterpiece !! It's violent comic action without any comedy or action. And its only violence is in its mammoth silliness of each and every factor in it; the cast, the way they act, the dialog, the characters, the situations...etc. (Keenen Ivory Wayans) isn't remotely funny at all; his comic scenes seemed horrible. He didn't impress anybody in his action scenes too. (Keenen Ivory Wayans)'s plot got nothing to be remembered after watching (or during watching !). And (Keenen Ivory Wayans)'s directing wasn't less low ! Did I forget to tell you that Mr. Wayans starred, wrote, and directed the whole thing? It isn't related to the fact that he's a cinematic genius or something, it's maybe because no decent moviemaker could bear working with him ! I'm a fan of (Charles S. Dutton); however I hated seeing him in here. (Jada Pinkett Smith) was incredibly unsightly and stupidly annoying. True (Salli Richardson-Whitfield) was kind of sexy, but not preferentially, or for long, or in a way could compensate for the endless ugly matters that this movie is crowded with ! The climax of its torturing crap is the lead's too gay sidekick "Wayman" (or women ?!). He can't do anything, even making laughs as he's supposed to. The only thing he succeeded to do is forcing you to throw up continually. The black try of making fun of black stereotypes wasn't filthier before! It's one naked movie, which has nothing  and I mean NOTHING  entertaining or else to present. Definitely the worst Blaxploitation movie is more interesting and memorable than this. However (A Low Down Dirty Shame) is a movie that my stomach won't forget. Works like this invented "The worst 10 movies list" ! It is a "dirty shame" only ! Written in 20/4/2010 =========================================== Flood of Filthiness ! ---------------------- This is Dirty Harry meets a dirty rap song. It goes like this : a black lead between Shaft and Martin Lawrence + logicless plot + the filthiest language ever recorded on film + countless rap songs for more than what any endurance could stand = mean outcome which's too paltry to remember. Man. Did I hate it? Well, it makes itself impossible to love. I hated the scene of seeing the great lead preparing to fight, wearing the best of what he has of clothes and weapons; I have seen this moment for at least 1000 times before! I hated (Jada Pinkett Smith) as the secretary. I may go to hell if I ever put "beautiful" and her name in one sentence anytime! The way she looks and talks is extremely sickening. What epithet she deserves the most ? The most detestable cartoon character, the silliest girl even been in an action, or the ugliest thing I have ever seen ! Having none sense of humor was better than having the worst kind; as this movie does ! From totally unfunny scenes for (Wayans), to such a contumely to the 1960s star (James Brown) as if only dogs that listen to his songs now, ending up with the hellish dialog. Most of the time I felt my ears getting flayed. Just recall : the numerous "ass", "penis", "fucking" terminologies. I believe this movie is a fine reference book for all the squalid phrases that use these words (the tabloid speaks about decreasing the size of asses, shoot my ass, don't make me spank your black ass, promise me to burn his ass...) Ahh, there is no end and nothing else. It assures not only that (Wayans) knows nothing about writing comedy but by using these terms, he rather knows nothing from the English language but them too! Let alone the free pure filth: The conversation about the beauty of a crippled girl's butt, or the joy of making love with the crippled girls in general (!!!!!). Or the awful story of (Jada Pinkett Smith) about her dog that shits a lot. Things like these, and I'm not sorry to say, made the movie as a huge pile of excrement itself ! But still, to add more vomit, here you are; the lead's sissy sidekick "Wayman". 3 scenes, just 3, got this thing in it. Nevertheless the repugnant effect of it can't be forgotten. What alien from outer space, or a demon from inferno, can actually bear this "Wayman" for a second ?? He's, without a doubt, the dirtiest of whatever this movie has ! In Egypt, its commercial title as a video stood for (The Professional and The Beauties), while I saw no Professional, Beauties, or a "Beauty" of any kind ! Written in 3/10/2000 =========================================== Not much of a difference, huh ?!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Do Not Believe The CRAP "uppity" People Say About This Movie...IT IS AWESOOOOME!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stumaczter1
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm sure this movie wasn't done with "we're gonna win an academy award with this one!" intentions it doesn't take itself too seriously & was done to entertain & it did just that! Trust me all the negative criticism & unnecessary flack this movie got was totally unwarranted & was done by people who have NO taste for GREAT entertainment! That being said this movie is one of my favourite comedy/action flicks..it is FUNNNNNNNNNY & the ACTION is steadily paced & EXPLOSIVE there isn't a dull moment in this one guys.Jada Pinkett was too cute not to mention hilarious in this movie & her personality amped this film up nicely.The guy who played Louise was very funny & of course the oldest Wayans brother Keenan (the star)delivered too.Lol the guy who played Wayman was a riot as well. In my head I'm trying to pick out a favourite moment from this movie & I can't!..the whole movie was a BLAST & if you haven't seen it yet you're wasting time..seriously! It's one of the best films in the comedy/action genre & fans of both individual genres WON'T be disappointed either..so if you haven't seen it yet do yourself a favour & check it out you won't regret it! 10 out of 10 stars!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You Might Like It, You Might Not
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ichocolat
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some films that you can't decide whether the film is good or bad. On whether the film is worth the watch or you're better off doing some other more meaningful things. This film is one of it. As I said, you might like it, you might not. The acting a little bit over the top, but I think that's what the producer intended to do. The jokes may at times be quite crude, but maybe it's exactly the way it was suppose to be. Worth a mention here is Jada Pinkett acting. She's quite good ! And I like her hairstyle too. Not that it has any bearing of the quality of acting though, just wanted to let you guys know. Over all, the film is nice to watch, if you don't take it seriously.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fromer cop turns private eye and catches a case from his past
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brooklynjymmah
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie does what it set out to do,make the the people watching this movie laugh. A Low Down Dirty Shame characters make this an enjoyable movie. Jada Pinkett is perfectly cast as Peaches Shame's (Wayans' character) Assistant.She's funny and likable in this role the action does not come with overly done, loud, explosive, costly Hollywood production. what it does come with is humor and that's why this movie is solid..When I first saw this movie I couldn't stop laughing. When Peaches has the scene with the Geri-Curled,Gold Toothed Mailman. The scene when Shane wakes up next to Peaches'roommate I'm still waiting for Shame 2. Heck,I have seen worst movies make a sequel. My suggestion to anyone who is interested in seeing this movie is go into it with an open mind and you will love it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good watch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    NLC-Rasta
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fun movie not to be taken seriously and nice to see actors/actresses that are not afraid of trying something different. I cant compare this movie to any other, its a movie just for pure comedy/action entertainment and not aimed at any particular group, genre, race or religion, or political issues. Although there are some race/sexual orientated material, i'm sure its strictly just for the story/plot and not meant to degrade, harm or single out any one. I enjoy the odd laugh now and then and this movie has its very funny moments, i like it... very good. There maybe negative ratings/comments out there which balances out the whole and everyone has the right to there own views, I've watched far worse movies with thinner plots and story lines even poor acting but i'l give them credit for at least trying to play the part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shaft with humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (winner55)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed this film, and it holds up fairly well with repeated viewings. But more importantly, this film has historical importance. First of all, this film is drawing very heavily on Hong Kong action thrillers at a time when these were just getting attention in the US. Secondly, compare this film very carefully with the Samuel Jackson "remake" of "Shaft", released - with enormous hype - in 2000. I don't know why Wayans didn't sue for plagiarism. Samuel Jackson's Shaft is Shame without humor. Unfortunately, the humor is absolutely essential to this story. For one thing, it creates a "black" identity that is capable of rising above any Hollywood appropriation of it. Shame's secretary - and real romantic interest - is a strong black woman - a character type that Hollywood has finally admitted actually exists only very recently, since about 2001. So Samuel Jackson's Shaft gets a x-million dollars promo, and still can't come up with an interesting story (although it was nice to see Richard roundtree on the screen again). Meanwhile, let's talk about entertainment - alright, there are some bits that don't work; but enough do to keep the film moving. I had good time; what the heck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I loved this MOVIE!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ct162926
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    WOW! this movie was great filled with action and comedy. The Action was from start to end! And the comedy is what makes this movie good peaches (Jada Pinkett Smith) was so funny in this one go rent it its worth 3 or 4 bucks! Don't Listen To The Top Comment hes a negative person and it has different people in it that surprisingly does a very good job! There's boy fights and guess what Jada fights in it to she is so ghetto in this film she hasn't done a lot of films but this one is definitely top 5. if u have any comments on my thoughts please e-mail me at get_over_it@now.com OK I'm done with this one on to the next films. gosh they make you write a minimum number of ten lines.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you take this seriously then you're totally missing the point!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Low Down Dirty Shame is really no more than all the most familiar Cop movie clich&eacute;s arranged in an order that makes a barely cohesive story. But it's all the fun and silly action that occurs in between that really matters! It's a bit like The Last Boy Scout from a spoof-blaxploitation angle. Shame (Keenan Ivory Wayans) is a former cop who has been blackballed after a major drugs bust went awry, leaving several DEA agents dead. He now works as a private detective, taking on suicide missions for peanuts and barely scraping by. His disapproving secretary Peaches (a very funny and very, very small Jada Pinkett) wants him to get his act together but he's too busy wallowing in self-pity. His old pal from the DEA shows up and offers him a side mission to help get back at the Drug Kingpin who ruined his career. And so, with only a few clues, Shame begins his search and soon all roads lead to lies and deception. Like I said, the plot is certainly nothing special. But it does contain a helluva lot of laughs and decent action. The one thing I can complain of is that the production design is kind of dated now. Action films have evolved so much in the past decade that watching ALDDS 12 years on can be a bit distracting. Wayans (who also directs as well as writing and starring) too often shoots non-actions scenes like a sitcom and his light-hearted editing may help remind you that this totally AIN'T a serious film but it's a little TV-ish if you know what I mean. If you find ALDDS for cheap somewhere or if it's showing on TV then don't con yourself out of a fun movie. High art is not what this film aims to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
