<filme>
 <id>
  1185
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110123
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Um Maluco no Ex&eacute;rcito
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  4.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Two misguided youths join the reserves to make some money for their entrepreneurial dreams. No sooner than they finish basic training are they called up to do their part to save the free world.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Bones and Jack are two guys with very little going right in their lives. The two decide to join the Army as part of the water purification team and eventually find themselves on the front lines in the conflict between the northern African countries of Chad and Libya. The two men, along with a few companions, have it upon themselves to save the day in combat, something they know little about.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   War
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   water purification
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   army
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   training
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   tomboy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   persian gulf
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Daniel Petrie Jr.
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Steve Zacharias
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Jeff Buhai
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Pauly Shore
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Lori Petty
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Andy Dick
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shore puts on a fair performance, but very inferior to "Bio-Dome"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the Army Now reminds me a little of the Corey Haim/Corey Feldman film Last Resort. Both came out in the year 1994, and both have potential to be very enjoyable works of farce, they fail in taking themselves seriously. In In the Army Now and Last Resort the films have a few parts that are really funny, but then they are followed by dull and laughless jokes that don't go anywhere and make you want the film over as soon as possible. What a perfectly good waste of Shore and Dick's talent. My favorite work of Pauly Shore was in the 1996 film Bio-Dome. I don't think we'll ever get something as good as Pauly Shore's work in that film. The first half of In the Army Now is very entertaining, but the funniest stuff is in the electronic store where Shore and Dick work in the beginning. If that was made into a film it would be a Clerks style film which would be very impressive. Instead the film thinks it will be funny to ship them off, well, in the army. Now. The plot revolves around Bones Conway (Shore) and Jack Kaufman (Dick) who, after a matter of minutes, are fired from their job at an electronic store for wrecking a stack of TV sets. In an effort for quick money, Bones and Kaufman join The United States Army Reserves. The boys sign up for water purification as their field, and after passing the training, they meet a tomboyish woman named Christine Jones (Pretty) and a dentist named Fred Ostroff (Grier). The four nickname their group "the waterboys". What they do not realize is that Libya is attacking Chad, and Bones and Jack get called into duty. They now must survive out in the army, with their new group. I caught this on TV and thought "this may be good for a farce laugh." While I did laugh a few times, the jokes weren't original or clever for that matter. I still have three Pauly Shore films I need to watch (Encino Man, Adopted, and Jury Duty), and I hope at least one is better or surpasses Bio-Dome There has to be one. Andy Dick managed to squeeze some awkward, yet appropriate laughs out of this film which is surprising. I never really found Andy Dick too amusing, but this film taught me he isn't all bad. Thats pretty much all I learned from In the Army Now. That may be an accomplishment. I don't think anyone else learns a damn thing from a slapstick fest. Starring: Pauly Shore, Andy Dick, Lori Petty, David Alan Grier, and Brendan Fraser. Directed by: Daniel Petrie, Jr.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Being All That They Can Be?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although there's a lot of people who don't like Pauly Shore, apparently you either love him or hate him, I have to say that I found this film quite amusing. It takes me back to my younger days when I was a weekend warrior. The group I hung out with I'm afraid, all people who were trying to get out of the real army and Vietnam joined the reserves as I did. We were about as military a group as Pauly Shore, Andy Dick, and David Alan Grier. Back then though we were not side by side with Lori Petty. The Army in its infinite wisdom knew better than to activate our crowd for Vietnam. But that's not what happens here. Pauly Shore and Andy Dick are a pair of misfits in civilian life and find they have a cash flow problem. That extra money for attending those Army Reserve drills sounds pretty enticing so they decide to be all that they can be on the weekends and two weeks in the summer. But Libya and Chad go to war and like the Iraqi Desert Storm, the reserves are called up for a United Nations multi-national force. Actually Libya and Chad did have border conflicts for many years with the French attacking as protectors for Chad. Pauly, Andy, and their new friends David Alan Grier and Lori Petty are in the Sahara Desert as part of a water purification team, water boys as they're derisively called by those in the real army. In The Army Now revives all the basic service comedy situations going all the way back to Abbott&Costello in Buck Privates. Especially in the training sequences. Pauly Shore and Andy Dick probably grew up on Bud&Lou, but they do the routines with a Generation X twist. I liked the film and thanked God I was not in the situations that Pauly and the rest were in.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not too bad representation of the Army
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daniel-ambia
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I trained in the exact same bases that Pauly Shore does in the movie, and we did pretty much the same things that he does. I know some movies portray army training as being incredibly intense. and it is, but there's always room for humor. I got a drill sgt to laugh the first day by running past him nude into the shower because someone had stolen my towel. Anyway if people take this movie for more then it is supposed to be they should be checked for their mental health. These actors do stupid things to make you laugh. You watch a movie, you drink some beer and you laugh your ass off when Pauly Shore talks. That's all it's great. Love it or leave it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is Pauley Shore Dead?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whatever happened to Pauley Shore? I guess he's still around but you didn't hear much from him after this movie, which was a decent success. It was a surprisingly-good lightweight comedy with a bunch of likable goofs and weirdos from Glendale, California, and their adventures after they join the Army Reserves. The language was pretty tame in here but there were a lot of sexual innuendos, too many for a PG rating but not surprising in a modern-day comedy. That comedy overall is good with some laugh-out-loud scenes. Also, as with many films, the ending gets carried away. It was really dumb, but for most of this movie it was entertaining enough to certainly recommend if you need a laugh.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    this movie is gonna be a cult classic someday
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    arun aravind
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    how can anyone berate a movie so funny., give me a break. If u ar looking for a thought provik film this wont be film for you. I watched this film in college , that was around 1995, I saw it again in 1999, I laughed my ass off ( at certain places) thats like more than some films can do. I feel this movie delivers what it promises. It is undoubtedly one of my favorite film. I was disappointed with paulys other works ( jury duty etc) I guess it was shear magic watching the four main characters coming together., some of my fav lines were " christine,( if I got it right)she will drink anything !! and " is the snake done yet". The movie is slap stick at certain places but mostly its genuine comedy. I m shocked this movie has got only 4 stars. I wish the director of this movie makes lots of money someday, cos he sure made me happy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    well, there's one bright spot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trey-e-carter
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's Pauly Shore. It is what it is. However, i do have one, personally infamous issue with this movie. Oh sure, i can laugh about it now b/c it was so long ago, but at the time, i could have beat Pauly Shore with any number of garden tools. you see... I was going through basic training for the Army at Ft. Sill in 1994 and was "asked" by my drill sergeant's to be one of the unwittingly captive extras out there running in place in the "EXTEND TO THE LEFT---MARCH!!!" scene. That's right, sports fans, i was one of those poor souls kept out of bed until the wee hours of the morning so that Mr. Shore could have his early morning Army PT scene. Only it wasn't early morning. It was filmed in about three takes between the hours of 2000 and 2400. That's 9:00p.m. 'til midnight. For those or us who know, sleep in basic training is a rare and valued commodity and Mr. Shore took about four of the six hours i got away that night. So, needless to say, my fellow recruits and I didn't much care for Mr. Shore, especially at 0300 the next morning when the training day started. we somehow got through it but never really got over it. It wasn't until a few years later that I finally got to watch the movie. That infamous scene comes on and guess what I see. I see my bald-headed self out there running in place clear as day...well, night. It's only for maybe three seconds, but it's long enough to be confirmed by a number of people. So, there it is, three seconds of my fifteen minutes of fame used in a Pauly Shore movie. wow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Accidentally Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ray-280
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What must have started out as a one-liner: "Hey, let's put Pauly Shore in the Army!" -- turned into a full-fledged classic that will be as funny a century from now as it was when it was released. The humor is original, the stereotypes (and knocking them down a peg) are present in abundance, and Art LeFleur as the first Sargent could have squeaked out an Oscar nomination had the film starred anyone else. The dramatic elements are also stronger than generally recognized. The plot: Chad has chemical warheads pointed at US targets, and it's up to Pauly Shore (Bones), Andy Dick, Lori Petty, and the black guy from McHale's Navy to save the world, six weeks after they completed basic training for the Army Reserves. Need I say more? Watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pauly Shore sucks, but this movie doesn't.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    the-jerk
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am not a fan of Pauly Shore movies. I didn't like "Encino Man", I didn't like "Son-in-Law", and I didn't like "Jury Duty". I thought he was occasionally funny on MTV (he did one bit as Kennedy that had me rolling once), but I don't think he made the transition to movies well. He's made some real stinkers. Okay. That being said, I actually DID like this movie. I even liked Pauly Shore in it. And although it probably wasn't a good movie by any standards, it had some extremely funny parts, like the part where Shore dropped the grenade and threw the pin in basic training. The premise (Shore joins the army as a water treatment specialist thinking he'll never have to go to war, but...) was an engaging one, and the foursome at the center (Shore, Lori Petty, Andy Dick, and David Alan Grier) worked well together, and seemed to be having a good time. I especially liked David Alan Grier as the dentist who was afraid of everything, and Petty was appropriately hammy as the butch girl who couldn't wait to go to war. Overall, a decent movie, but a masterpiece by Pauly Shore movie standards.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent movie, as good as Bio Dome.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kraal93
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved the movie for a lot of reasons. Pauly Shore and David Alan Grier, for example. My ONE small gripe; the fighter jets used in the movie. At first, it seemed as if the planes were Tornado Marines, single-tail, single-engine fighters. In other scenes, if you're into military aircraft, or have seen Top Gun, you can clearly see that they are F-14 Tomcats, dual-tail (or split-fin, as Luke Air Force Base pilots refer to them), dual-engine fighters. I'm guessing that since the Tornado and the Tomcat share a lot of similarities (swing-wings, similar forward fuselages, and near-cockpit intake vents), that only a person, or persons, familiar with aircraft would be able to tell the difference. Otherwise, I rank In The Army Now with Stripes, Sgt. Bilko, McHale's Navy, Down Periscope, Hot Shots Pts 1 and 2, and Major Payne, all funny military comedies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jessi4sale
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pauly Shore is amazing. His outrageous personality and unique take on humor make this movie very entertaining and irresistible This movie is the kind that every time you watch it it gets better. The story line is new and refreshing because it is like no movie I have ever seen before. This movie is good for people of all ages. Pauly Shore deserves more credit for his films and recognition for his comedy style. Pauly shore is without doubt my favorite actor. I will recommend In The Army Now to everyone I know .I give this movie a well deserved 10 out of 10 for being so clever. Other great movies with Pauly Shore are Son In Law and Encino Man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shore puts on a fair performance, but very inferior to "Bio-Dome"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the Army Now reminds me a little of the Corey Haim/Corey Feldman film Last Resort. Both came out in the year 1994, and both have potential to be very enjoyable works of farce, they fail in taking themselves seriously. In In the Army Now and Last Resort the films have a few parts that are really funny, but then they are followed by dull and laughless jokes that don't go anywhere and make you want the film over as soon as possible. What a perfectly good waste of Shore and Dick's talent. My favorite work of Pauly Shore was in the 1996 film Bio-Dome. I don't think we'll ever get something as good as Pauly Shore's work in that film. The first half of In the Army Now is very entertaining, but the funniest stuff is in the electronic store where Shore and Dick work in the beginning. If that was made into a film it would be a Clerks style film which would be very impressive. Instead the film thinks it will be funny to ship them off, well, in the army. Now. The plot revolves around Bones Conway (Shore) and Jack Kaufman (Dick) who, after a matter of minutes, are fired from their job at an electronic store for wrecking a stack of TV sets. In an effort for quick money, Bones and Kaufman join The United States Army Reserves. The boys sign up for water purification as their field, and after passing the training, they meet a tomboyish woman named Christine Jones (Pretty) and a dentist named Fred Ostroff (Grier). The four nickname their group "the waterboys". What they do not realize is that Libya is attacking Chad, and Bones and Jack get called into duty. They now must survive out in the army, with their new group. I caught this on TV and thought "this may be good for a farce laugh." While I did laugh a few times, the jokes weren't original or clever for that matter. I still have three Pauly Shore films I need to watch (Encino Man, Adopted, and Jury Duty), and I hope at least one is better or surpasses Bio-Dome There has to be one. Andy Dick managed to squeeze some awkward, yet appropriate laughs out of this film which is surprising. I never really found Andy Dick too amusing, but this film taught me he isn't all bad. Thats pretty much all I learned from In the Army Now. That may be an accomplishment. I don't think anyone else learns a damn thing from a slapstick fest. Starring: Pauly Shore, Andy Dick, Lori Petty, David Alan Grier, and Brendan Fraser. Directed by: Daniel Petrie, Jr.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Being All That They Can Be?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although there's a lot of people who don't like Pauly Shore, apparently you either love him or hate him, I have to say that I found this film quite amusing. It takes me back to my younger days when I was a weekend warrior. The group I hung out with I'm afraid, all people who were trying to get out of the real army and Vietnam joined the reserves as I did. We were about as military a group as Pauly Shore, Andy Dick, and David Alan Grier. Back then though we were not side by side with Lori Petty. The Army in its infinite wisdom knew better than to activate our crowd for Vietnam. But that's not what happens here. Pauly Shore and Andy Dick are a pair of misfits in civilian life and find they have a cash flow problem. That extra money for attending those Army Reserve drills sounds pretty enticing so they decide to be all that they can be on the weekends and two weeks in the summer. But Libya and Chad go to war and like the Iraqi Desert Storm, the reserves are called up for a United Nations multi-national force. Actually Libya and Chad did have border conflicts for many years with the French attacking as protectors for Chad. Pauly, Andy, and their new friends David Alan Grier and Lori Petty are in the Sahara Desert as part of a water purification team, water boys as they're derisively called by those in the real army. In The Army Now revives all the basic service comedy situations going all the way back to Abbott&Costello in Buck Privates. Especially in the training sequences. Pauly Shore and Andy Dick probably grew up on Bud&Lou, but they do the routines with a Generation X twist. I liked the film and thanked God I was not in the situations that Pauly and the rest were in.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not too bad representation of the Army
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daniel-ambia
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I trained in the exact same bases that Pauly Shore does in the movie, and we did pretty much the same things that he does. I know some movies portray army training as being incredibly intense. and it is, but there's always room for humor. I got a drill sgt to laugh the first day by running past him nude into the shower because someone had stolen my towel. Anyway if people take this movie for more then it is supposed to be they should be checked for their mental health. These actors do stupid things to make you laugh. You watch a movie, you drink some beer and you laugh your ass off when Pauly Shore talks. That's all it's great. Love it or leave it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is Pauley Shore Dead?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whatever happened to Pauley Shore? I guess he's still around but you didn't hear much from him after this movie, which was a decent success. It was a surprisingly-good lightweight comedy with a bunch of likable goofs and weirdos from Glendale, California, and their adventures after they join the Army Reserves. The language was pretty tame in here but there were a lot of sexual innuendos, too many for a PG rating but not surprising in a modern-day comedy. That comedy overall is good with some laugh-out-loud scenes. Also, as with many films, the ending gets carried away. It was really dumb, but for most of this movie it was entertaining enough to certainly recommend if you need a laugh.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    this movie is gonna be a cult classic someday
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    arun aravind
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    how can anyone berate a movie so funny., give me a break. If u ar looking for a thought provik film this wont be film for you. I watched this film in college , that was around 1995, I saw it again in 1999, I laughed my ass off ( at certain places) thats like more than some films can do. I feel this movie delivers what it promises. It is undoubtedly one of my favorite film. I was disappointed with paulys other works ( jury duty etc) I guess it was shear magic watching the four main characters coming together., some of my fav lines were " christine,( if I got it right)she will drink anything !! and " is the snake done yet". The movie is slap stick at certain places but mostly its genuine comedy. I m shocked this movie has got only 4 stars. I wish the director of this movie makes lots of money someday, cos he sure made me happy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    well, there's one bright spot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trey-e-carter
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's Pauly Shore. It is what it is. However, i do have one, personally infamous issue with this movie. Oh sure, i can laugh about it now b/c it was so long ago, but at the time, i could have beat Pauly Shore with any number of garden tools. you see... I was going through basic training for the Army at Ft. Sill in 1994 and was "asked" by my drill sergeant's to be one of the unwittingly captive extras out there running in place in the "EXTEND TO THE LEFT---MARCH!!!" scene. That's right, sports fans, i was one of those poor souls kept out of bed until the wee hours of the morning so that Mr. Shore could have his early morning Army PT scene. Only it wasn't early morning. It was filmed in about three takes between the hours of 2000 and 2400. That's 9:00p.m. 'til midnight. For those or us who know, sleep in basic training is a rare and valued commodity and Mr. Shore took about four of the six hours i got away that night. So, needless to say, my fellow recruits and I didn't much care for Mr. Shore, especially at 0300 the next morning when the training day started. we somehow got through it but never really got over it. It wasn't until a few years later that I finally got to watch the movie. That infamous scene comes on and guess what I see. I see my bald-headed self out there running in place clear as day...well, night. It's only for maybe three seconds, but it's long enough to be confirmed by a number of people. So, there it is, three seconds of my fifteen minutes of fame used in a Pauly Shore movie. wow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Accidentally Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ray-280
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What must have started out as a one-liner: "Hey, let's put Pauly Shore in the Army!" -- turned into a full-fledged classic that will be as funny a century from now as it was when it was released. The humor is original, the stereotypes (and knocking them down a peg) are present in abundance, and Art LeFleur as the first Sargent could have squeaked out an Oscar nomination had the film starred anyone else. The dramatic elements are also stronger than generally recognized. The plot: Chad has chemical warheads pointed at US targets, and it's up to Pauly Shore (Bones), Andy Dick, Lori Petty, and the black guy from McHale's Navy to save the world, six weeks after they completed basic training for the Army Reserves. Need I say more? Watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pauly Shore sucks, but this movie doesn't.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    the-jerk
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am not a fan of Pauly Shore movies. I didn't like "Encino Man", I didn't like "Son-in-Law", and I didn't like "Jury Duty". I thought he was occasionally funny on MTV (he did one bit as Kennedy that had me rolling once), but I don't think he made the transition to movies well. He's made some real stinkers. Okay. That being said, I actually DID like this movie. I even liked Pauly Shore in it. And although it probably wasn't a good movie by any standards, it had some extremely funny parts, like the part where Shore dropped the grenade and threw the pin in basic training. The premise (Shore joins the army as a water treatment specialist thinking he'll never have to go to war, but...) was an engaging one, and the foursome at the center (Shore, Lori Petty, Andy Dick, and David Alan Grier) worked well together, and seemed to be having a good time. I especially liked David Alan Grier as the dentist who was afraid of everything, and Petty was appropriately hammy as the butch girl who couldn't wait to go to war. Overall, a decent movie, but a masterpiece by Pauly Shore movie standards.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent movie, as good as Bio Dome.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kraal93
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved the movie for a lot of reasons. Pauly Shore and David Alan Grier, for example. My ONE small gripe; the fighter jets used in the movie. At first, it seemed as if the planes were Tornado Marines, single-tail, single-engine fighters. In other scenes, if you're into military aircraft, or have seen Top Gun, you can clearly see that they are F-14 Tomcats, dual-tail (or split-fin, as Luke Air Force Base pilots refer to them), dual-engine fighters. I'm guessing that since the Tornado and the Tomcat share a lot of similarities (swing-wings, similar forward fuselages, and near-cockpit intake vents), that only a person, or persons, familiar with aircraft would be able to tell the difference. Otherwise, I rank In The Army Now with Stripes, Sgt. Bilko, McHale's Navy, Down Periscope, Hot Shots Pts 1 and 2, and Major Payne, all funny military comedies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jessi4sale
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pauly Shore is amazing. His outrageous personality and unique take on humor make this movie very entertaining and irresistible This movie is the kind that every time you watch it it gets better. The story line is new and refreshing because it is like no movie I have ever seen before. This movie is good for people of all ages. Pauly Shore deserves more credit for his films and recognition for his comedy style. Pauly shore is without doubt my favorite actor. I will recommend In The Army Now to everyone I know .I give this movie a well deserved 10 out of 10 for being so clever. Other great movies with Pauly Shore are Son In Law and Encino Man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shore puts on a fair performance, but very inferior to "Bio-Dome"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the Army Now reminds me a little of the Corey Haim/Corey Feldman film Last Resort. Both came out in the year 1994, and both have potential to be very enjoyable works of farce, they fail in taking themselves seriously. In In the Army Now and Last Resort the films have a few parts that are really funny, but then they are followed by dull and laughless jokes that don't go anywhere and make you want the film over as soon as possible. What a perfectly good waste of Shore and Dick's talent. My favorite work of Pauly Shore was in the 1996 film Bio-Dome. I don't think we'll ever get something as good as Pauly Shore's work in that film. The first half of In the Army Now is very entertaining, but the funniest stuff is in the electronic store where Shore and Dick work in the beginning. If that was made into a film it would be a Clerks style film which would be very impressive. Instead the film thinks it will be funny to ship them off, well, in the army. Now. The plot revolves around Bones Conway (Shore) and Jack Kaufman (Dick) who, after a matter of minutes, are fired from their job at an electronic store for wrecking a stack of TV sets. In an effort for quick money, Bones and Kaufman join The United States Army Reserves. The boys sign up for water purification as their field, and after passing the training, they meet a tomboyish woman named Christine Jones (Pretty) and a dentist named Fred Ostroff (Grier). The four nickname their group "the waterboys". What they do not realize is that Libya is attacking Chad, and Bones and Jack get called into duty. They now must survive out in the army, with their new group. I caught this on TV and thought "this may be good for a farce laugh." While I did laugh a few times, the jokes weren't original or clever for that matter. I still have three Pauly Shore films I need to watch (Encino Man, Adopted, and Jury Duty), and I hope at least one is better or surpasses Bio-Dome There has to be one. Andy Dick managed to squeeze some awkward, yet appropriate laughs out of this film which is surprising. I never really found Andy Dick too amusing, but this film taught me he isn't all bad. Thats pretty much all I learned from In the Army Now. That may be an accomplishment. I don't think anyone else learns a damn thing from a slapstick fest. Starring: Pauly Shore, Andy Dick, Lori Petty, David Alan Grier, and Brendan Fraser. Directed by: Daniel Petrie, Jr.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Being All That They Can Be?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although there's a lot of people who don't like Pauly Shore, apparently you either love him or hate him, I have to say that I found this film quite amusing. It takes me back to my younger days when I was a weekend warrior. The group I hung out with I'm afraid, all people who were trying to get out of the real army and Vietnam joined the reserves as I did. We were about as military a group as Pauly Shore, Andy Dick, and David Alan Grier. Back then though we were not side by side with Lori Petty. The Army in its infinite wisdom knew better than to activate our crowd for Vietnam. But that's not what happens here. Pauly Shore and Andy Dick are a pair of misfits in civilian life and find they have a cash flow problem. That extra money for attending those Army Reserve drills sounds pretty enticing so they decide to be all that they can be on the weekends and two weeks in the summer. But Libya and Chad go to war and like the Iraqi Desert Storm, the reserves are called up for a United Nations multi-national force. Actually Libya and Chad did have border conflicts for many years with the French attacking as protectors for Chad. Pauly, Andy, and their new friends David Alan Grier and Lori Petty are in the Sahara Desert as part of a water purification team, water boys as they're derisively called by those in the real army. In The Army Now revives all the basic service comedy situations going all the way back to Abbott&Costello in Buck Privates. Especially in the training sequences. Pauly Shore and Andy Dick probably grew up on Bud&Lou, but they do the routines with a Generation X twist. I liked the film and thanked God I was not in the situations that Pauly and the rest were in.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not too bad representation of the Army
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daniel-ambia
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I trained in the exact same bases that Pauly Shore does in the movie, and we did pretty much the same things that he does. I know some movies portray army training as being incredibly intense. and it is, but there's always room for humor. I got a drill sgt to laugh the first day by running past him nude into the shower because someone had stolen my towel. Anyway if people take this movie for more then it is supposed to be they should be checked for their mental health. These actors do stupid things to make you laugh. You watch a movie, you drink some beer and you laugh your ass off when Pauly Shore talks. That's all it's great. Love it or leave it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is Pauley Shore Dead?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whatever happened to Pauley Shore? I guess he's still around but you didn't hear much from him after this movie, which was a decent success. It was a surprisingly-good lightweight comedy with a bunch of likable goofs and weirdos from Glendale, California, and their adventures after they join the Army Reserves. The language was pretty tame in here but there were a lot of sexual innuendos, too many for a PG rating but not surprising in a modern-day comedy. That comedy overall is good with some laugh-out-loud scenes. Also, as with many films, the ending gets carried away. It was really dumb, but for most of this movie it was entertaining enough to certainly recommend if you need a laugh.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    this movie is gonna be a cult classic someday
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    arun aravind
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    how can anyone berate a movie so funny., give me a break. If u ar looking for a thought provik film this wont be film for you. I watched this film in college , that was around 1995, I saw it again in 1999, I laughed my ass off ( at certain places) thats like more than some films can do. I feel this movie delivers what it promises. It is undoubtedly one of my favorite film. I was disappointed with paulys other works ( jury duty etc) I guess it was shear magic watching the four main characters coming together., some of my fav lines were " christine,( if I got it right)she will drink anything !! and " is the snake done yet". The movie is slap stick at certain places but mostly its genuine comedy. I m shocked this movie has got only 4 stars. I wish the director of this movie makes lots of money someday, cos he sure made me happy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    well, there's one bright spot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trey-e-carter
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's Pauly Shore. It is what it is. However, i do have one, personally infamous issue with this movie. Oh sure, i can laugh about it now b/c it was so long ago, but at the time, i could have beat Pauly Shore with any number of garden tools. you see... I was going through basic training for the Army at Ft. Sill in 1994 and was "asked" by my drill sergeant's to be one of the unwittingly captive extras out there running in place in the "EXTEND TO THE LEFT---MARCH!!!" scene. That's right, sports fans, i was one of those poor souls kept out of bed until the wee hours of the morning so that Mr. Shore could have his early morning Army PT scene. Only it wasn't early morning. It was filmed in about three takes between the hours of 2000 and 2400. That's 9:00p.m. 'til midnight. For those or us who know, sleep in basic training is a rare and valued commodity and Mr. Shore took about four of the six hours i got away that night. So, needless to say, my fellow recruits and I didn't much care for Mr. Shore, especially at 0300 the next morning when the training day started. we somehow got through it but never really got over it. It wasn't until a few years later that I finally got to watch the movie. That infamous scene comes on and guess what I see. I see my bald-headed self out there running in place clear as day...well, night. It's only for maybe three seconds, but it's long enough to be confirmed by a number of people. So, there it is, three seconds of my fifteen minutes of fame used in a Pauly Shore movie. wow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Accidentally Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ray-280
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What must have started out as a one-liner: "Hey, let's put Pauly Shore in the Army!" -- turned into a full-fledged classic that will be as funny a century from now as it was when it was released. The humor is original, the stereotypes (and knocking them down a peg) are present in abundance, and Art LeFleur as the first Sargent could have squeaked out an Oscar nomination had the film starred anyone else. The dramatic elements are also stronger than generally recognized. The plot: Chad has chemical warheads pointed at US targets, and it's up to Pauly Shore (Bones), Andy Dick, Lori Petty, and the black guy from McHale's Navy to save the world, six weeks after they completed basic training for the Army Reserves. Need I say more? Watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pauly Shore sucks, but this movie doesn't.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    the-jerk
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am not a fan of Pauly Shore movies. I didn't like "Encino Man", I didn't like "Son-in-Law", and I didn't like "Jury Duty". I thought he was occasionally funny on MTV (he did one bit as Kennedy that had me rolling once), but I don't think he made the transition to movies well. He's made some real stinkers. Okay. That being said, I actually DID like this movie. I even liked Pauly Shore in it. And although it probably wasn't a good movie by any standards, it had some extremely funny parts, like the part where Shore dropped the grenade and threw the pin in basic training. The premise (Shore joins the army as a water treatment specialist thinking he'll never have to go to war, but...) was an engaging one, and the foursome at the center (Shore, Lori Petty, Andy Dick, and David Alan Grier) worked well together, and seemed to be having a good time. I especially liked David Alan Grier as the dentist who was afraid of everything, and Petty was appropriately hammy as the butch girl who couldn't wait to go to war. Overall, a decent movie, but a masterpiece by Pauly Shore movie standards.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent movie, as good as Bio Dome.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kraal93
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved the movie for a lot of reasons. Pauly Shore and David Alan Grier, for example. My ONE small gripe; the fighter jets used in the movie. At first, it seemed as if the planes were Tornado Marines, single-tail, single-engine fighters. In other scenes, if you're into military aircraft, or have seen Top Gun, you can clearly see that they are F-14 Tomcats, dual-tail (or split-fin, as Luke Air Force Base pilots refer to them), dual-engine fighters. I'm guessing that since the Tornado and the Tomcat share a lot of similarities (swing-wings, similar forward fuselages, and near-cockpit intake vents), that only a person, or persons, familiar with aircraft would be able to tell the difference. Otherwise, I rank In The Army Now with Stripes, Sgt. Bilko, McHale's Navy, Down Periscope, Hot Shots Pts 1 and 2, and Major Payne, all funny military comedies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jessi4sale
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pauly Shore is amazing. His outrageous personality and unique take on humor make this movie very entertaining and irresistible This movie is the kind that every time you watch it it gets better. The story line is new and refreshing because it is like no movie I have ever seen before. This movie is good for people of all ages. Pauly Shore deserves more credit for his films and recognition for his comedy style. Pauly shore is without doubt my favorite actor. I will recommend In The Army Now to everyone I know .I give this movie a well deserved 10 out of 10 for being so clever. Other great movies with Pauly Shore are Son In Law and Encino Man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
