<filme>
 <id>
  1193
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110882
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Antes da Chuva
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The circularity of violence seen in a story that circles on itself. In Macedonia, during war in Bosnia, Christians hunt an ethnic Albanian girl who may have murdered one of their own. A ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  The circularity of violence seen in a story that circles on itself. In Macedonia, during war in Bosnia, Christians hunt an ethnic Albanian girl who may have murdered one of their own. A young monk who's taken a vow of silence offers her protection. In London, a photographic editor who's pregnant needs to talk it out with her estranged husband and chooses a toney restaurant. She wants permanence with her lover, a prize-winning Macedonian photographer just back from Bosnia, changed by the violence. He leaves abruptly for his village; he's not visited it in 16 years. There he tries to ignore bitter divisions between his Orthodox brethren and local Albanians, then tries to transcend them.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   War
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   albanian
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   monk
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   macedonia
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bosnia
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   violence
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Milcho Manchevski
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Milcho Manchevski
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Katrin Cartlidge
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Rade Serbedzija
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Gr&eacute;goire Colin
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    gray circles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    it is a film about the dust of words. about power of self definition. about death. and hate. about courage. and a deformed universe. each character is letter of a testimony. each testimony is another cold circle of ash.and nothing else. a monk, a girl, a photographer. a village as scene of a profound crime. sure, it is slice from a war. but this war has not end. it is expectation, desire, ladder. a seed as demolition of another old order. for this cause the film is touching and impressive. because it is clear. and honest. because is a picture. the places, the dialogs, the borders of circles are only shadows of events. three stories. and the cruel silence. that is all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gripping Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the Rain has a similar format to Babel, with three separate stories which come together at the end. In the first, a young monk has taken a vow of silence and is protecting Zamira, an Aobanian girl on the run from the mob. He leaves the monastery and travels throughout Macedonia with her, attempting to escape. The second chapter involves a photo editor in London, having to choose between her husband, Nick, and a war photographer, Aleksandar. She gets caught up in a series of tragic events, beginning with a shoot out at a restaurant. The third segment ties the first two together through somewhat confusing flashbacks, and one scene, in particular is a definite timeline mistake. I sent an email to the director, and he says that it was intentional. Poetic license was is reasoning. The movie is a violent but realistic depiction of the war in the former Yugoslavia. There are no winners, only victims of another stupid and pointless conflict. Before the Rain is an excellent drama.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beautifully done movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sutapanaki66
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I liked the movie quite a lot. Well done, with clear story line and conveying the ideas perfectly. I gave it 7 instead of 10 stars because of some incorrect historic statements. For example, one of the characters says that the Byzantines poked the eyes of 14000 "Macedonian" soldiers. This refers to the battle at Klyuch in 1014 where the Byzantine emperor Basil II won the battle and because of what he did to the soldiers he was called Basil the Bulgar-slayer (Boulgaroktonos Greek: Βουλγαροκτόνος) - obviously no mention of any Macedonian soldiers. Oh, well, what can one do - that's the present day Macedonian view on history. I just thought that a movie of this scale should be correct in every aspect - both what concerns present day events and facts from the past.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sublime Work of Manchevski. A must too see
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vedette69
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    BEFORE THE RAIN is a reality Life story Movie of Macedonia it's a very original Movie and have so many in it History, War, politic, faith, power, real life..... The actors are really good, The Music is great in the film And the Camera work is One of the BEST ever seen Sublime Work of Milcho Manchevski the movie won a lot of prizes but not the big ones? Maybe of cause it's a movie from Macedonia and not American I Don't understand That i don't find the movie on DVD to buy if someone can't help my to find it Please let me now THANKS Have a Good Time This movie is also a must too see for photographers. Greetings Patrick
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Timeline Was Too Dischordant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony_retford
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Obviously most people are enthralled with this movie. I wasn't. The music was good but the cinematography was lacking - too many shots shown over again. I watch a lot of foreign movies and, I guess, unfortunately had just watched "A Very Long Engagement" with cinematography that excelled. I suppose the message in Before The Rain was that time may not have been circular but it certainly comes back onto itself. The feeling I had was that the writer wanted to paint this little universe, which always repeated itself. Was this plot anything to do with the reality we all live in? No! We live in a linear reality and we don't see pictures of things that haven't happened yet. I thought it was more than depressing that the cycle the writer chose was punctuated with fusillades of gunfire from start to end. I thought "Dark Country" made better use of an enclosed circular universe. I also found the likelihood that someone could return to his old home after 16 years false, especially with the tribality and backwardness of the inhabitants which he had outgrown shortly after leaving. I have been traveling for 7 years and things are different. I could not go back to what was and be a part of those I knew. So the idea that Rade, world-wise traveler thought he could just enter his old stomping grounds did not make sense. He would have had more sense, particularly when he was met by a gun-toting guard. When he first arrived he saw his house had been abandoned so how could he not understand his old life had also been abandoned?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Time never dies, the circle is not round.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stodruza
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    But this film's construction is, like the cycle of war. Brilliant, as of course is the film. Gotta do ten lines. This is one of the best anti-war films ever made, on par with Bardov's Prisoner of the Mountains, which I recommend to you, along side Susan Beir's Brothers. Should be required viewing for all politicians...The art in this film is immense, from the film stock, to the lighting, acting, story, in essence, a perfect film. Have to wonder about people who don't appreciate it, much less enjoy it on some level. Brutally honest film about the consequences of war.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inrteresting - but why the middle section
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike B
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a 3 part film depicting events during the complex civil war in what use to be Yugoslavia. The first and third parts are set in the Balkans and for the most part are touching and authentic. A photographer returns to his homeland to witness the fracturing of it into war. This is well depicted in the movie - how communities that use to co-exist peacefully can somehow, through a tortured religious history,group pressure.. . gradually fracture into warring tribes. Another centerpiece of this story is a young girl forced to leave her village to try and save her life. The second part is mostly disconnected from part 1 and 3. The English woman is pregnant and having marital problems, there is a mafia style shoot-up in a bar. It is entirely irrelevant to the themes presented in 1 and 3. Part 2 should have been edited to coalesce with 1 and 3. The only reason for the second installment is to provide a back-drop for the photographer to return, after a long absence, to his native land and witness the fissures developing. Also in part 2 we see photographs of the execution of the fleeing young woman,but at this stage the photographer was already dead!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let the Circle be Broken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MacAindrais
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the Rain (1994) **** After only being available on bootlegged or used but extremely rare DVDs, the originals of which were released only in Macedonia and Turkey (given away for free in limited number), Milcho Manchevski's poetic and soulful examination of the futility of war and circularity of violence is set to be released on DVD proper through Criterion this June. Given that the film won the Oscar for best foreign film and earned numerous accolades from the major critics (Siskel and Ebert raved about the film on their show), one would have expected to see it on DVD a long time ago, but alas, it's coming now and getting the proper treatment. The film is set in Macedonia in the early 90s, as tensions between the 'native' Macedonians and Muslim Albanians flare. The story is broken into 3 parts  words, faces, and pictures. Words follows a young monk, on a vow of silence for the last 2 years. He finds to his shock one evening in his quarters a young boy hiding in his bed. He runs to tell one of the monastery heads, but decides against telling after seeing the fear in the boy's eyes. The next day, armed men show up looking for an Albanian girl who allegedly killed a sheep herder. No one knows of the girl, but the armed men refuse to leave and keep watch in case she turns up. That night, the young Monk, Kiril, wakes to see the boy again, but this time in the light of the moon, and realizes that it is not a boy, but a girl with her hair chopped off. She is Zamira. He allows her to hide with him, only to be discovered later in the night by the other priests. The two are forced out under the cover of darkness, wished well on their way. The two seem to be heading for love, but that love will be swiftly and brutally taken away from them before it is allowed to materialize. Part 2, faces, takes us into the modern hubbub of London, where a woman at a photo agency, Anne, is embroiled in pregnancy and an affair with her Macedonian Co-worker, Aleksander (Rade Serbedzija). He has just returned from an expedition which has apparently traumatized him. His camera has killed a man he says. He asks her to come back to Macedonia with him, where he remembers life as peaceful and safe, despite her warnings and knowledge of the Balkan conflicts. Being pregnant, she cannot go, she must meet with her husband. Aleksander leaves alone to return to his homeland. While the war seems far away from bustling London, violence and hatred are never as far as they seem. Over dinner, Anne first tells her husband she is pregnant, it's his, and she wants a divorce. Meanwhile, a waiter and a patron, both speaking Macedonian, bicker. The tension in the scene is wrought, as Anne struggles to get the right words out and express her feelings and the two men head toward a devastating act of violence for Anne and her Husband. Part 3, pictures, returns us to Macedonia, and to Aleksander. He arrives home and finds his old home a disaster, and finds that his Albanian neighbours are fearful of him. Childhood friends are now bitter enemies, hatred runs hot between Macedonians and Albanians. Some in his family seem to be somewhat sympathetic, others militant, such as his cousin, Mitre, one of the armed men at the church in the beginning of the film. Aleksander inquires about Hana, a woman he used to love, and apparently still does. She is Albanian, widowed, and off limits. He goes to visit her, and finds that he must pass a roadblock, where he is suspiciously questioned by armed villagers. He is allowed in only after Hana's father confirms his identity. We discover that the man is Zamira's grandfather, and she is Hana's daughter. Aleksander will be asked later by Hana to help protect Zamira. I will not reveal here the interconnectedness of the film, as it is impossible to do so without revealing major spoilers. We come to realize however that the film is not linear in nature, but circular, a style employed in a much different film at the same time, Pulp Fiction. We also come to realize that there a number of subtle incongruence's in the plot. People who should be dead are alive - timing and events seem to be off. Manchevski was purposeful in his editing, and the inconsistencies are not simply goofs. Rather they fit the theme of the film, spoken or seen numerous times throughout the film  "The circle is not round. Time never dies." The circularity of violence is manifested through the circularity of the plot: things don't always look the same but the result always is: destruction of life. Before the Rain is a film about our humanity and how it is destroyed by hate; how we are not only willing to destroy those we hate because we hate them, but that we will destroy those we love when they stand in the way of our hatreds. The film is a scathing indictment of the policies of war and hate, rendered through the heart and soul of art. I implore anyone reading this to seek out the film, which thankfully will be far more available come this June.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A predictably intense and depressing film about nationalism in Macedonia.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fedor8
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The London segments, i.e. the segments in English, though relatively short, drag the film down somewhat; the dialogue here is clumsy. The scene with the restaurant shoot-out is absurd and stupid: a Balkan mobster starts shooting at people randomly, a place where Cartlidge - a photographer or journalist - just happens to be, telling her husband she wants a divorce. (How conveniently her problem is solved, by him getting killed there moments later!). A little too far-fetched. Serbedjija is upset with Cartlidge because she refuses to follow him to Macedonia, him having given her very short notice! What is this, kindergarten?... The rest of BTR, which revolves around a couple of small villages, is much better, but suffers from a bad case of premonitia: we know Serbedjija will get killed; it's just a matter of time. The acting and the dialogue is solid. The film's main statement - that all sides in such a conflict are equally guilty - was a wise choice for the director to make. This decision is not to be taken for granted because most directors - particularly left-wing Western ones - aren't capable of approaching any political issue in a movie in a constructive, logical, fair, intelligent, and unbiased manner. Frankly, I saw this quite a while ago, hence am not sure what I'd think about it now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Balkan witness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kalala
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cannot praise this film highly enough. It is one of my all time favorites. This is an exquisite, haunting film that does not get shown enough. The three interlocking parts of the story slant time and recast different characters in parallel tales that form a wreath, not a sequence or circle. Each story follows a similar arc and includes similar elements: a hidden impregnation; an agonizing choice that reaches out to one that has already passed out of reach; an unexpected victim of violence; and the tragic back story of attack and retribution that dates back at least a thousand years to a late Byzantine reprisal. The elements map to the Christ story as if it had been compressed in a black hole, the virgin birth and sacrificial death compacted together and exploding out of a dazzling collage of violently mindless brutality and mindful attention--to prayer, to craft, to shepherdry. Where is the viewer? A tragedy that is so alive in current events calls to action. If we are mute witnesses, then the story will reach a point where we must testify to the tragedy(so the photographer's stills tell us). But what words could have stopped what happened? If we stand by and are glad that the story is not ours we may yet find ourselves in the story. It doesn't matter if the face is Balkan or Palestinian--ejecting the combatants fails as policy. In the end and ending, reentering the picture as participant, not witness, repossessing the ruins of home and taking responsibility for the fruit of love, means giving up personal immortality (the European illusion of celebrity) in exchange for a blood-soaked collective eternity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    gray circles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    it is a film about the dust of words. about power of self definition. about death. and hate. about courage. and a deformed universe. each character is letter of a testimony. each testimony is another cold circle of ash.and nothing else. a monk, a girl, a photographer. a village as scene of a profound crime. sure, it is slice from a war. but this war has not end. it is expectation, desire, ladder. a seed as demolition of another old order. for this cause the film is touching and impressive. because it is clear. and honest. because is a picture. the places, the dialogs, the borders of circles are only shadows of events. three stories. and the cruel silence. that is all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gripping Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the Rain has a similar format to Babel, with three separate stories which come together at the end. In the first, a young monk has taken a vow of silence and is protecting Zamira, an Aobanian girl on the run from the mob. He leaves the monastery and travels throughout Macedonia with her, attempting to escape. The second chapter involves a photo editor in London, having to choose between her husband, Nick, and a war photographer, Aleksandar. She gets caught up in a series of tragic events, beginning with a shoot out at a restaurant. The third segment ties the first two together through somewhat confusing flashbacks, and one scene, in particular is a definite timeline mistake. I sent an email to the director, and he says that it was intentional. Poetic license was is reasoning. The movie is a violent but realistic depiction of the war in the former Yugoslavia. There are no winners, only victims of another stupid and pointless conflict. Before the Rain is an excellent drama.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beautifully done movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sutapanaki66
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I liked the movie quite a lot. Well done, with clear story line and conveying the ideas perfectly. I gave it 7 instead of 10 stars because of some incorrect historic statements. For example, one of the characters says that the Byzantines poked the eyes of 14000 "Macedonian" soldiers. This refers to the battle at Klyuch in 1014 where the Byzantine emperor Basil II won the battle and because of what he did to the soldiers he was called Basil the Bulgar-slayer (Boulgaroktonos Greek: Βουλγαροκτόνος) - obviously no mention of any Macedonian soldiers. Oh, well, what can one do - that's the present day Macedonian view on history. I just thought that a movie of this scale should be correct in every aspect - both what concerns present day events and facts from the past.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sublime Work of Manchevski. A must too see
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vedette69
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    BEFORE THE RAIN is a reality Life story Movie of Macedonia it's a very original Movie and have so many in it History, War, politic, faith, power, real life..... The actors are really good, The Music is great in the film And the Camera work is One of the BEST ever seen Sublime Work of Milcho Manchevski the movie won a lot of prizes but not the big ones? Maybe of cause it's a movie from Macedonia and not American I Don't understand That i don't find the movie on DVD to buy if someone can't help my to find it Please let me now THANKS Have a Good Time This movie is also a must too see for photographers. Greetings Patrick
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Timeline Was Too Dischordant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony_retford
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Obviously most people are enthralled with this movie. I wasn't. The music was good but the cinematography was lacking - too many shots shown over again. I watch a lot of foreign movies and, I guess, unfortunately had just watched "A Very Long Engagement" with cinematography that excelled. I suppose the message in Before The Rain was that time may not have been circular but it certainly comes back onto itself. The feeling I had was that the writer wanted to paint this little universe, which always repeated itself. Was this plot anything to do with the reality we all live in? No! We live in a linear reality and we don't see pictures of things that haven't happened yet. I thought it was more than depressing that the cycle the writer chose was punctuated with fusillades of gunfire from start to end. I thought "Dark Country" made better use of an enclosed circular universe. I also found the likelihood that someone could return to his old home after 16 years false, especially with the tribality and backwardness of the inhabitants which he had outgrown shortly after leaving. I have been traveling for 7 years and things are different. I could not go back to what was and be a part of those I knew. So the idea that Rade, world-wise traveler thought he could just enter his old stomping grounds did not make sense. He would have had more sense, particularly when he was met by a gun-toting guard. When he first arrived he saw his house had been abandoned so how could he not understand his old life had also been abandoned?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Time never dies, the circle is not round.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stodruza
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    But this film's construction is, like the cycle of war. Brilliant, as of course is the film. Gotta do ten lines. This is one of the best anti-war films ever made, on par with Bardov's Prisoner of the Mountains, which I recommend to you, along side Susan Beir's Brothers. Should be required viewing for all politicians...The art in this film is immense, from the film stock, to the lighting, acting, story, in essence, a perfect film. Have to wonder about people who don't appreciate it, much less enjoy it on some level. Brutally honest film about the consequences of war.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inrteresting - but why the middle section
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike B
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a 3 part film depicting events during the complex civil war in what use to be Yugoslavia. The first and third parts are set in the Balkans and for the most part are touching and authentic. A photographer returns to his homeland to witness the fracturing of it into war. This is well depicted in the movie - how communities that use to co-exist peacefully can somehow, through a tortured religious history,group pressure.. . gradually fracture into warring tribes. Another centerpiece of this story is a young girl forced to leave her village to try and save her life. The second part is mostly disconnected from part 1 and 3. The English woman is pregnant and having marital problems, there is a mafia style shoot-up in a bar. It is entirely irrelevant to the themes presented in 1 and 3. Part 2 should have been edited to coalesce with 1 and 3. The only reason for the second installment is to provide a back-drop for the photographer to return, after a long absence, to his native land and witness the fissures developing. Also in part 2 we see photographs of the execution of the fleeing young woman,but at this stage the photographer was already dead!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let the Circle be Broken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MacAindrais
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the Rain (1994) **** After only being available on bootlegged or used but extremely rare DVDs, the originals of which were released only in Macedonia and Turkey (given away for free in limited number), Milcho Manchevski's poetic and soulful examination of the futility of war and circularity of violence is set to be released on DVD proper through Criterion this June. Given that the film won the Oscar for best foreign film and earned numerous accolades from the major critics (Siskel and Ebert raved about the film on their show), one would have expected to see it on DVD a long time ago, but alas, it's coming now and getting the proper treatment. The film is set in Macedonia in the early 90s, as tensions between the 'native' Macedonians and Muslim Albanians flare. The story is broken into 3 parts  words, faces, and pictures. Words follows a young monk, on a vow of silence for the last 2 years. He finds to his shock one evening in his quarters a young boy hiding in his bed. He runs to tell one of the monastery heads, but decides against telling after seeing the fear in the boy's eyes. The next day, armed men show up looking for an Albanian girl who allegedly killed a sheep herder. No one knows of the girl, but the armed men refuse to leave and keep watch in case she turns up. That night, the young Monk, Kiril, wakes to see the boy again, but this time in the light of the moon, and realizes that it is not a boy, but a girl with her hair chopped off. She is Zamira. He allows her to hide with him, only to be discovered later in the night by the other priests. The two are forced out under the cover of darkness, wished well on their way. The two seem to be heading for love, but that love will be swiftly and brutally taken away from them before it is allowed to materialize. Part 2, faces, takes us into the modern hubbub of London, where a woman at a photo agency, Anne, is embroiled in pregnancy and an affair with her Macedonian Co-worker, Aleksander (Rade Serbedzija). He has just returned from an expedition which has apparently traumatized him. His camera has killed a man he says. He asks her to come back to Macedonia with him, where he remembers life as peaceful and safe, despite her warnings and knowledge of the Balkan conflicts. Being pregnant, she cannot go, she must meet with her husband. Aleksander leaves alone to return to his homeland. While the war seems far away from bustling London, violence and hatred are never as far as they seem. Over dinner, Anne first tells her husband she is pregnant, it's his, and she wants a divorce. Meanwhile, a waiter and a patron, both speaking Macedonian, bicker. The tension in the scene is wrought, as Anne struggles to get the right words out and express her feelings and the two men head toward a devastating act of violence for Anne and her Husband. Part 3, pictures, returns us to Macedonia, and to Aleksander. He arrives home and finds his old home a disaster, and finds that his Albanian neighbours are fearful of him. Childhood friends are now bitter enemies, hatred runs hot between Macedonians and Albanians. Some in his family seem to be somewhat sympathetic, others militant, such as his cousin, Mitre, one of the armed men at the church in the beginning of the film. Aleksander inquires about Hana, a woman he used to love, and apparently still does. She is Albanian, widowed, and off limits. He goes to visit her, and finds that he must pass a roadblock, where he is suspiciously questioned by armed villagers. He is allowed in only after Hana's father confirms his identity. We discover that the man is Zamira's grandfather, and she is Hana's daughter. Aleksander will be asked later by Hana to help protect Zamira. I will not reveal here the interconnectedness of the film, as it is impossible to do so without revealing major spoilers. We come to realize however that the film is not linear in nature, but circular, a style employed in a much different film at the same time, Pulp Fiction. We also come to realize that there a number of subtle incongruence's in the plot. People who should be dead are alive - timing and events seem to be off. Manchevski was purposeful in his editing, and the inconsistencies are not simply goofs. Rather they fit the theme of the film, spoken or seen numerous times throughout the film  "The circle is not round. Time never dies." The circularity of violence is manifested through the circularity of the plot: things don't always look the same but the result always is: destruction of life. Before the Rain is a film about our humanity and how it is destroyed by hate; how we are not only willing to destroy those we hate because we hate them, but that we will destroy those we love when they stand in the way of our hatreds. The film is a scathing indictment of the policies of war and hate, rendered through the heart and soul of art. I implore anyone reading this to seek out the film, which thankfully will be far more available come this June.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A predictably intense and depressing film about nationalism in Macedonia.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fedor8
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The London segments, i.e. the segments in English, though relatively short, drag the film down somewhat; the dialogue here is clumsy. The scene with the restaurant shoot-out is absurd and stupid: a Balkan mobster starts shooting at people randomly, a place where Cartlidge - a photographer or journalist - just happens to be, telling her husband she wants a divorce. (How conveniently her problem is solved, by him getting killed there moments later!). A little too far-fetched. Serbedjija is upset with Cartlidge because she refuses to follow him to Macedonia, him having given her very short notice! What is this, kindergarten?... The rest of BTR, which revolves around a couple of small villages, is much better, but suffers from a bad case of premonitia: we know Serbedjija will get killed; it's just a matter of time. The acting and the dialogue is solid. The film's main statement - that all sides in such a conflict are equally guilty - was a wise choice for the director to make. This decision is not to be taken for granted because most directors - particularly left-wing Western ones - aren't capable of approaching any political issue in a movie in a constructive, logical, fair, intelligent, and unbiased manner. Frankly, I saw this quite a while ago, hence am not sure what I'd think about it now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Balkan witness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kalala
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cannot praise this film highly enough. It is one of my all time favorites. This is an exquisite, haunting film that does not get shown enough. The three interlocking parts of the story slant time and recast different characters in parallel tales that form a wreath, not a sequence or circle. Each story follows a similar arc and includes similar elements: a hidden impregnation; an agonizing choice that reaches out to one that has already passed out of reach; an unexpected victim of violence; and the tragic back story of attack and retribution that dates back at least a thousand years to a late Byzantine reprisal. The elements map to the Christ story as if it had been compressed in a black hole, the virgin birth and sacrificial death compacted together and exploding out of a dazzling collage of violently mindless brutality and mindful attention--to prayer, to craft, to shepherdry. Where is the viewer? A tragedy that is so alive in current events calls to action. If we are mute witnesses, then the story will reach a point where we must testify to the tragedy(so the photographer's stills tell us). But what words could have stopped what happened? If we stand by and are glad that the story is not ours we may yet find ourselves in the story. It doesn't matter if the face is Balkan or Palestinian--ejecting the combatants fails as policy. In the end and ending, reentering the picture as participant, not witness, repossessing the ruins of home and taking responsibility for the fruit of love, means giving up personal immortality (the European illusion of celebrity) in exchange for a blood-soaked collective eternity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    gray circles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    it is a film about the dust of words. about power of self definition. about death. and hate. about courage. and a deformed universe. each character is letter of a testimony. each testimony is another cold circle of ash.and nothing else. a monk, a girl, a photographer. a village as scene of a profound crime. sure, it is slice from a war. but this war has not end. it is expectation, desire, ladder. a seed as demolition of another old order. for this cause the film is touching and impressive. because it is clear. and honest. because is a picture. the places, the dialogs, the borders of circles are only shadows of events. three stories. and the cruel silence. that is all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gripping Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the Rain has a similar format to Babel, with three separate stories which come together at the end. In the first, a young monk has taken a vow of silence and is protecting Zamira, an Aobanian girl on the run from the mob. He leaves the monastery and travels throughout Macedonia with her, attempting to escape. The second chapter involves a photo editor in London, having to choose between her husband, Nick, and a war photographer, Aleksandar. She gets caught up in a series of tragic events, beginning with a shoot out at a restaurant. The third segment ties the first two together through somewhat confusing flashbacks, and one scene, in particular is a definite timeline mistake. I sent an email to the director, and he says that it was intentional. Poetic license was is reasoning. The movie is a violent but realistic depiction of the war in the former Yugoslavia. There are no winners, only victims of another stupid and pointless conflict. Before the Rain is an excellent drama.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beautifully done movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sutapanaki66
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I liked the movie quite a lot. Well done, with clear story line and conveying the ideas perfectly. I gave it 7 instead of 10 stars because of some incorrect historic statements. For example, one of the characters says that the Byzantines poked the eyes of 14000 "Macedonian" soldiers. This refers to the battle at Klyuch in 1014 where the Byzantine emperor Basil II won the battle and because of what he did to the soldiers he was called Basil the Bulgar-slayer (Boulgaroktonos Greek: Βουλγαροκτόνος) - obviously no mention of any Macedonian soldiers. Oh, well, what can one do - that's the present day Macedonian view on history. I just thought that a movie of this scale should be correct in every aspect - both what concerns present day events and facts from the past.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sublime Work of Manchevski. A must too see
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vedette69
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    BEFORE THE RAIN is a reality Life story Movie of Macedonia it's a very original Movie and have so many in it History, War, politic, faith, power, real life..... The actors are really good, The Music is great in the film And the Camera work is One of the BEST ever seen Sublime Work of Milcho Manchevski the movie won a lot of prizes but not the big ones? Maybe of cause it's a movie from Macedonia and not American I Don't understand That i don't find the movie on DVD to buy if someone can't help my to find it Please let me now THANKS Have a Good Time This movie is also a must too see for photographers. Greetings Patrick
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Timeline Was Too Dischordant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony_retford
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Obviously most people are enthralled with this movie. I wasn't. The music was good but the cinematography was lacking - too many shots shown over again. I watch a lot of foreign movies and, I guess, unfortunately had just watched "A Very Long Engagement" with cinematography that excelled. I suppose the message in Before The Rain was that time may not have been circular but it certainly comes back onto itself. The feeling I had was that the writer wanted to paint this little universe, which always repeated itself. Was this plot anything to do with the reality we all live in? No! We live in a linear reality and we don't see pictures of things that haven't happened yet. I thought it was more than depressing that the cycle the writer chose was punctuated with fusillades of gunfire from start to end. I thought "Dark Country" made better use of an enclosed circular universe. I also found the likelihood that someone could return to his old home after 16 years false, especially with the tribality and backwardness of the inhabitants which he had outgrown shortly after leaving. I have been traveling for 7 years and things are different. I could not go back to what was and be a part of those I knew. So the idea that Rade, world-wise traveler thought he could just enter his old stomping grounds did not make sense. He would have had more sense, particularly when he was met by a gun-toting guard. When he first arrived he saw his house had been abandoned so how could he not understand his old life had also been abandoned?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Time never dies, the circle is not round.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stodruza
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    But this film's construction is, like the cycle of war. Brilliant, as of course is the film. Gotta do ten lines. This is one of the best anti-war films ever made, on par with Bardov's Prisoner of the Mountains, which I recommend to you, along side Susan Beir's Brothers. Should be required viewing for all politicians...The art in this film is immense, from the film stock, to the lighting, acting, story, in essence, a perfect film. Have to wonder about people who don't appreciate it, much less enjoy it on some level. Brutally honest film about the consequences of war.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inrteresting - but why the middle section
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike B
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a 3 part film depicting events during the complex civil war in what use to be Yugoslavia. The first and third parts are set in the Balkans and for the most part are touching and authentic. A photographer returns to his homeland to witness the fracturing of it into war. This is well depicted in the movie - how communities that use to co-exist peacefully can somehow, through a tortured religious history,group pressure.. . gradually fracture into warring tribes. Another centerpiece of this story is a young girl forced to leave her village to try and save her life. The second part is mostly disconnected from part 1 and 3. The English woman is pregnant and having marital problems, there is a mafia style shoot-up in a bar. It is entirely irrelevant to the themes presented in 1 and 3. Part 2 should have been edited to coalesce with 1 and 3. The only reason for the second installment is to provide a back-drop for the photographer to return, after a long absence, to his native land and witness the fissures developing. Also in part 2 we see photographs of the execution of the fleeing young woman,but at this stage the photographer was already dead!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let the Circle be Broken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MacAindrais
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the Rain (1994) **** After only being available on bootlegged or used but extremely rare DVDs, the originals of which were released only in Macedonia and Turkey (given away for free in limited number), Milcho Manchevski's poetic and soulful examination of the futility of war and circularity of violence is set to be released on DVD proper through Criterion this June. Given that the film won the Oscar for best foreign film and earned numerous accolades from the major critics (Siskel and Ebert raved about the film on their show), one would have expected to see it on DVD a long time ago, but alas, it's coming now and getting the proper treatment. The film is set in Macedonia in the early 90s, as tensions between the 'native' Macedonians and Muslim Albanians flare. The story is broken into 3 parts  words, faces, and pictures. Words follows a young monk, on a vow of silence for the last 2 years. He finds to his shock one evening in his quarters a young boy hiding in his bed. He runs to tell one of the monastery heads, but decides against telling after seeing the fear in the boy's eyes. The next day, armed men show up looking for an Albanian girl who allegedly killed a sheep herder. No one knows of the girl, but the armed men refuse to leave and keep watch in case she turns up. That night, the young Monk, Kiril, wakes to see the boy again, but this time in the light of the moon, and realizes that it is not a boy, but a girl with her hair chopped off. She is Zamira. He allows her to hide with him, only to be discovered later in the night by the other priests. The two are forced out under the cover of darkness, wished well on their way. The two seem to be heading for love, but that love will be swiftly and brutally taken away from them before it is allowed to materialize. Part 2, faces, takes us into the modern hubbub of London, where a woman at a photo agency, Anne, is embroiled in pregnancy and an affair with her Macedonian Co-worker, Aleksander (Rade Serbedzija). He has just returned from an expedition which has apparently traumatized him. His camera has killed a man he says. He asks her to come back to Macedonia with him, where he remembers life as peaceful and safe, despite her warnings and knowledge of the Balkan conflicts. Being pregnant, she cannot go, she must meet with her husband. Aleksander leaves alone to return to his homeland. While the war seems far away from bustling London, violence and hatred are never as far as they seem. Over dinner, Anne first tells her husband she is pregnant, it's his, and she wants a divorce. Meanwhile, a waiter and a patron, both speaking Macedonian, bicker. The tension in the scene is wrought, as Anne struggles to get the right words out and express her feelings and the two men head toward a devastating act of violence for Anne and her Husband. Part 3, pictures, returns us to Macedonia, and to Aleksander. He arrives home and finds his old home a disaster, and finds that his Albanian neighbours are fearful of him. Childhood friends are now bitter enemies, hatred runs hot between Macedonians and Albanians. Some in his family seem to be somewhat sympathetic, others militant, such as his cousin, Mitre, one of the armed men at the church in the beginning of the film. Aleksander inquires about Hana, a woman he used to love, and apparently still does. She is Albanian, widowed, and off limits. He goes to visit her, and finds that he must pass a roadblock, where he is suspiciously questioned by armed villagers. He is allowed in only after Hana's father confirms his identity. We discover that the man is Zamira's grandfather, and she is Hana's daughter. Aleksander will be asked later by Hana to help protect Zamira. I will not reveal here the interconnectedness of the film, as it is impossible to do so without revealing major spoilers. We come to realize however that the film is not linear in nature, but circular, a style employed in a much different film at the same time, Pulp Fiction. We also come to realize that there a number of subtle incongruence's in the plot. People who should be dead are alive - timing and events seem to be off. Manchevski was purposeful in his editing, and the inconsistencies are not simply goofs. Rather they fit the theme of the film, spoken or seen numerous times throughout the film  "The circle is not round. Time never dies." The circularity of violence is manifested through the circularity of the plot: things don't always look the same but the result always is: destruction of life. Before the Rain is a film about our humanity and how it is destroyed by hate; how we are not only willing to destroy those we hate because we hate them, but that we will destroy those we love when they stand in the way of our hatreds. The film is a scathing indictment of the policies of war and hate, rendered through the heart and soul of art. I implore anyone reading this to seek out the film, which thankfully will be far more available come this June.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A predictably intense and depressing film about nationalism in Macedonia.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fedor8
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The London segments, i.e. the segments in English, though relatively short, drag the film down somewhat; the dialogue here is clumsy. The scene with the restaurant shoot-out is absurd and stupid: a Balkan mobster starts shooting at people randomly, a place where Cartlidge - a photographer or journalist - just happens to be, telling her husband she wants a divorce. (How conveniently her problem is solved, by him getting killed there moments later!). A little too far-fetched. Serbedjija is upset with Cartlidge because she refuses to follow him to Macedonia, him having given her very short notice! What is this, kindergarten?... The rest of BTR, which revolves around a couple of small villages, is much better, but suffers from a bad case of premonitia: we know Serbedjija will get killed; it's just a matter of time. The acting and the dialogue is solid. The film's main statement - that all sides in such a conflict are equally guilty - was a wise choice for the director to make. This decision is not to be taken for granted because most directors - particularly left-wing Western ones - aren't capable of approaching any political issue in a movie in a constructive, logical, fair, intelligent, and unbiased manner. Frankly, I saw this quite a while ago, hence am not sure what I'd think about it now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Balkan witness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kalala
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cannot praise this film highly enough. It is one of my all time favorites. This is an exquisite, haunting film that does not get shown enough. The three interlocking parts of the story slant time and recast different characters in parallel tales that form a wreath, not a sequence or circle. Each story follows a similar arc and includes similar elements: a hidden impregnation; an agonizing choice that reaches out to one that has already passed out of reach; an unexpected victim of violence; and the tragic back story of attack and retribution that dates back at least a thousand years to a late Byzantine reprisal. The elements map to the Christ story as if it had been compressed in a black hole, the virgin birth and sacrificial death compacted together and exploding out of a dazzling collage of violently mindless brutality and mindful attention--to prayer, to craft, to shepherdry. Where is the viewer? A tragedy that is so alive in current events calls to action. If we are mute witnesses, then the story will reach a point where we must testify to the tragedy(so the photographer's stills tell us). But what words could have stopped what happened? If we stand by and are glad that the story is not ours we may yet find ourselves in the story. It doesn't matter if the face is Balkan or Palestinian--ejecting the combatants fails as policy. In the end and ending, reentering the picture as participant, not witness, repossessing the ruins of home and taking responsibility for the fruit of love, means giving up personal immortality (the European illusion of celebrity) in exchange for a blood-soaked collective eternity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    gray circles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    it is a film about the dust of words. about power of self definition. about death. and hate. about courage. and a deformed universe. each character is letter of a testimony. each testimony is another cold circle of ash.and nothing else. a monk, a girl, a photographer. a village as scene of a profound crime. sure, it is slice from a war. but this war has not end. it is expectation, desire, ladder. a seed as demolition of another old order. for this cause the film is touching and impressive. because it is clear. and honest. because is a picture. the places, the dialogs, the borders of circles are only shadows of events. three stories. and the cruel silence. that is all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gripping Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the Rain has a similar format to Babel, with three separate stories which come together at the end. In the first, a young monk has taken a vow of silence and is protecting Zamira, an Aobanian girl on the run from the mob. He leaves the monastery and travels throughout Macedonia with her, attempting to escape. The second chapter involves a photo editor in London, having to choose between her husband, Nick, and a war photographer, Aleksandar. She gets caught up in a series of tragic events, beginning with a shoot out at a restaurant. The third segment ties the first two together through somewhat confusing flashbacks, and one scene, in particular is a definite timeline mistake. I sent an email to the director, and he says that it was intentional. Poetic license was is reasoning. The movie is a violent but realistic depiction of the war in the former Yugoslavia. There are no winners, only victims of another stupid and pointless conflict. Before the Rain is an excellent drama.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beautifully done movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sutapanaki66
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I liked the movie quite a lot. Well done, with clear story line and conveying the ideas perfectly. I gave it 7 instead of 10 stars because of some incorrect historic statements. For example, one of the characters says that the Byzantines poked the eyes of 14000 "Macedonian" soldiers. This refers to the battle at Klyuch in 1014 where the Byzantine emperor Basil II won the battle and because of what he did to the soldiers he was called Basil the Bulgar-slayer (Boulgaroktonos Greek: Βουλγαροκτόνος) - obviously no mention of any Macedonian soldiers. Oh, well, what can one do - that's the present day Macedonian view on history. I just thought that a movie of this scale should be correct in every aspect - both what concerns present day events and facts from the past.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sublime Work of Manchevski. A must too see
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vedette69
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    BEFORE THE RAIN is a reality Life story Movie of Macedonia it's a very original Movie and have so many in it History, War, politic, faith, power, real life..... The actors are really good, The Music is great in the film And the Camera work is One of the BEST ever seen Sublime Work of Milcho Manchevski the movie won a lot of prizes but not the big ones? Maybe of cause it's a movie from Macedonia and not American I Don't understand That i don't find the movie on DVD to buy if someone can't help my to find it Please let me now THANKS Have a Good Time This movie is also a must too see for photographers. Greetings Patrick
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Timeline Was Too Dischordant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony_retford
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Obviously most people are enthralled with this movie. I wasn't. The music was good but the cinematography was lacking - too many shots shown over again. I watch a lot of foreign movies and, I guess, unfortunately had just watched "A Very Long Engagement" with cinematography that excelled. I suppose the message in Before The Rain was that time may not have been circular but it certainly comes back onto itself. The feeling I had was that the writer wanted to paint this little universe, which always repeated itself. Was this plot anything to do with the reality we all live in? No! We live in a linear reality and we don't see pictures of things that haven't happened yet. I thought it was more than depressing that the cycle the writer chose was punctuated with fusillades of gunfire from start to end. I thought "Dark Country" made better use of an enclosed circular universe. I also found the likelihood that someone could return to his old home after 16 years false, especially with the tribality and backwardness of the inhabitants which he had outgrown shortly after leaving. I have been traveling for 7 years and things are different. I could not go back to what was and be a part of those I knew. So the idea that Rade, world-wise traveler thought he could just enter his old stomping grounds did not make sense. He would have had more sense, particularly when he was met by a gun-toting guard. When he first arrived he saw his house had been abandoned so how could he not understand his old life had also been abandoned?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Time never dies, the circle is not round.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stodruza
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    But this film's construction is, like the cycle of war. Brilliant, as of course is the film. Gotta do ten lines. This is one of the best anti-war films ever made, on par with Bardov's Prisoner of the Mountains, which I recommend to you, along side Susan Beir's Brothers. Should be required viewing for all politicians...The art in this film is immense, from the film stock, to the lighting, acting, story, in essence, a perfect film. Have to wonder about people who don't appreciate it, much less enjoy it on some level. Brutally honest film about the consequences of war.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inrteresting - but why the middle section
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike B
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a 3 part film depicting events during the complex civil war in what use to be Yugoslavia. The first and third parts are set in the Balkans and for the most part are touching and authentic. A photographer returns to his homeland to witness the fracturing of it into war. This is well depicted in the movie - how communities that use to co-exist peacefully can somehow, through a tortured religious history,group pressure.. . gradually fracture into warring tribes. Another centerpiece of this story is a young girl forced to leave her village to try and save her life. The second part is mostly disconnected from part 1 and 3. The English woman is pregnant and having marital problems, there is a mafia style shoot-up in a bar. It is entirely irrelevant to the themes presented in 1 and 3. Part 2 should have been edited to coalesce with 1 and 3. The only reason for the second installment is to provide a back-drop for the photographer to return, after a long absence, to his native land and witness the fissures developing. Also in part 2 we see photographs of the execution of the fleeing young woman,but at this stage the photographer was already dead!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let the Circle be Broken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MacAindrais
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the Rain (1994) **** After only being available on bootlegged or used but extremely rare DVDs, the originals of which were released only in Macedonia and Turkey (given away for free in limited number), Milcho Manchevski's poetic and soulful examination of the futility of war and circularity of violence is set to be released on DVD proper through Criterion this June. Given that the film won the Oscar for best foreign film and earned numerous accolades from the major critics (Siskel and Ebert raved about the film on their show), one would have expected to see it on DVD a long time ago, but alas, it's coming now and getting the proper treatment. The film is set in Macedonia in the early 90s, as tensions between the 'native' Macedonians and Muslim Albanians flare. The story is broken into 3 parts  words, faces, and pictures. Words follows a young monk, on a vow of silence for the last 2 years. He finds to his shock one evening in his quarters a young boy hiding in his bed. He runs to tell one of the monastery heads, but decides against telling after seeing the fear in the boy's eyes. The next day, armed men show up looking for an Albanian girl who allegedly killed a sheep herder. No one knows of the girl, but the armed men refuse to leave and keep watch in case she turns up. That night, the young Monk, Kiril, wakes to see the boy again, but this time in the light of the moon, and realizes that it is not a boy, but a girl with her hair chopped off. She is Zamira. He allows her to hide with him, only to be discovered later in the night by the other priests. The two are forced out under the cover of darkness, wished well on their way. The two seem to be heading for love, but that love will be swiftly and brutally taken away from them before it is allowed to materialize. Part 2, faces, takes us into the modern hubbub of London, where a woman at a photo agency, Anne, is embroiled in pregnancy and an affair with her Macedonian Co-worker, Aleksander (Rade Serbedzija). He has just returned from an expedition which has apparently traumatized him. His camera has killed a man he says. He asks her to come back to Macedonia with him, where he remembers life as peaceful and safe, despite her warnings and knowledge of the Balkan conflicts. Being pregnant, she cannot go, she must meet with her husband. Aleksander leaves alone to return to his homeland. While the war seems far away from bustling London, violence and hatred are never as far as they seem. Over dinner, Anne first tells her husband she is pregnant, it's his, and she wants a divorce. Meanwhile, a waiter and a patron, both speaking Macedonian, bicker. The tension in the scene is wrought, as Anne struggles to get the right words out and express her feelings and the two men head toward a devastating act of violence for Anne and her Husband. Part 3, pictures, returns us to Macedonia, and to Aleksander. He arrives home and finds his old home a disaster, and finds that his Albanian neighbours are fearful of him. Childhood friends are now bitter enemies, hatred runs hot between Macedonians and Albanians. Some in his family seem to be somewhat sympathetic, others militant, such as his cousin, Mitre, one of the armed men at the church in the beginning of the film. Aleksander inquires about Hana, a woman he used to love, and apparently still does. She is Albanian, widowed, and off limits. He goes to visit her, and finds that he must pass a roadblock, where he is suspiciously questioned by armed villagers. He is allowed in only after Hana's father confirms his identity. We discover that the man is Zamira's grandfather, and she is Hana's daughter. Aleksander will be asked later by Hana to help protect Zamira. I will not reveal here the interconnectedness of the film, as it is impossible to do so without revealing major spoilers. We come to realize however that the film is not linear in nature, but circular, a style employed in a much different film at the same time, Pulp Fiction. We also come to realize that there a number of subtle incongruence's in the plot. People who should be dead are alive - timing and events seem to be off. Manchevski was purposeful in his editing, and the inconsistencies are not simply goofs. Rather they fit the theme of the film, spoken or seen numerous times throughout the film  "The circle is not round. Time never dies." The circularity of violence is manifested through the circularity of the plot: things don't always look the same but the result always is: destruction of life. Before the Rain is a film about our humanity and how it is destroyed by hate; how we are not only willing to destroy those we hate because we hate them, but that we will destroy those we love when they stand in the way of our hatreds. The film is a scathing indictment of the policies of war and hate, rendered through the heart and soul of art. I implore anyone reading this to seek out the film, which thankfully will be far more available come this June.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A predictably intense and depressing film about nationalism in Macedonia.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fedor8
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The London segments, i.e. the segments in English, though relatively short, drag the film down somewhat; the dialogue here is clumsy. The scene with the restaurant shoot-out is absurd and stupid: a Balkan mobster starts shooting at people randomly, a place where Cartlidge - a photographer or journalist - just happens to be, telling her husband she wants a divorce. (How conveniently her problem is solved, by him getting killed there moments later!). A little too far-fetched. Serbedjija is upset with Cartlidge because she refuses to follow him to Macedonia, him having given her very short notice! What is this, kindergarten?... The rest of BTR, which revolves around a couple of small villages, is much better, but suffers from a bad case of premonitia: we know Serbedjija will get killed; it's just a matter of time. The acting and the dialogue is solid. The film's main statement - that all sides in such a conflict are equally guilty - was a wise choice for the director to make. This decision is not to be taken for granted because most directors - particularly left-wing Western ones - aren't capable of approaching any political issue in a movie in a constructive, logical, fair, intelligent, and unbiased manner. Frankly, I saw this quite a while ago, hence am not sure what I'd think about it now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Balkan witness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kalala
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cannot praise this film highly enough. It is one of my all time favorites. This is an exquisite, haunting film that does not get shown enough. The three interlocking parts of the story slant time and recast different characters in parallel tales that form a wreath, not a sequence or circle. Each story follows a similar arc and includes similar elements: a hidden impregnation; an agonizing choice that reaches out to one that has already passed out of reach; an unexpected victim of violence; and the tragic back story of attack and retribution that dates back at least a thousand years to a late Byzantine reprisal. The elements map to the Christ story as if it had been compressed in a black hole, the virgin birth and sacrificial death compacted together and exploding out of a dazzling collage of violently mindless brutality and mindful attention--to prayer, to craft, to shepherdry. Where is the viewer? A tragedy that is so alive in current events calls to action. If we are mute witnesses, then the story will reach a point where we must testify to the tragedy(so the photographer's stills tell us). But what words could have stopped what happened? If we stand by and are glad that the story is not ours we may yet find ourselves in the story. It doesn't matter if the face is Balkan or Palestinian--ejecting the combatants fails as policy. In the end and ending, reentering the picture as participant, not witness, repossessing the ruins of home and taking responsibility for the fruit of love, means giving up personal immortality (the European illusion of celebrity) in exchange for a blood-soaked collective eternity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    gray circles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    it is a film about the dust of words. about power of self definition. about death. and hate. about courage. and a deformed universe. each character is letter of a testimony. each testimony is another cold circle of ash.and nothing else. a monk, a girl, a photographer. a village as scene of a profound crime. sure, it is slice from a war. but this war has not end. it is expectation, desire, ladder. a seed as demolition of another old order. for this cause the film is touching and impressive. because it is clear. and honest. because is a picture. the places, the dialogs, the borders of circles are only shadows of events. three stories. and the cruel silence. that is all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gripping Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the Rain has a similar format to Babel, with three separate stories which come together at the end. In the first, a young monk has taken a vow of silence and is protecting Zamira, an Aobanian girl on the run from the mob. He leaves the monastery and travels throughout Macedonia with her, attempting to escape. The second chapter involves a photo editor in London, having to choose between her husband, Nick, and a war photographer, Aleksandar. She gets caught up in a series of tragic events, beginning with a shoot out at a restaurant. The third segment ties the first two together through somewhat confusing flashbacks, and one scene, in particular is a definite timeline mistake. I sent an email to the director, and he says that it was intentional. Poetic license was is reasoning. The movie is a violent but realistic depiction of the war in the former Yugoslavia. There are no winners, only victims of another stupid and pointless conflict. Before the Rain is an excellent drama.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beautifully done movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sutapanaki66
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I liked the movie quite a lot. Well done, with clear story line and conveying the ideas perfectly. I gave it 7 instead of 10 stars because of some incorrect historic statements. For example, one of the characters says that the Byzantines poked the eyes of 14000 "Macedonian" soldiers. This refers to the battle at Klyuch in 1014 where the Byzantine emperor Basil II won the battle and because of what he did to the soldiers he was called Basil the Bulgar-slayer (Boulgaroktonos Greek: Βουλγαροκτόνος) - obviously no mention of any Macedonian soldiers. Oh, well, what can one do - that's the present day Macedonian view on history. I just thought that a movie of this scale should be correct in every aspect - both what concerns present day events and facts from the past.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sublime Work of Manchevski. A must too see
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vedette69
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    BEFORE THE RAIN is a reality Life story Movie of Macedonia it's a very original Movie and have so many in it History, War, politic, faith, power, real life..... The actors are really good, The Music is great in the film And the Camera work is One of the BEST ever seen Sublime Work of Milcho Manchevski the movie won a lot of prizes but not the big ones? Maybe of cause it's a movie from Macedonia and not American I Don't understand That i don't find the movie on DVD to buy if someone can't help my to find it Please let me now THANKS Have a Good Time This movie is also a must too see for photographers. Greetings Patrick
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Timeline Was Too Dischordant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony_retford
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Obviously most people are enthralled with this movie. I wasn't. The music was good but the cinematography was lacking - too many shots shown over again. I watch a lot of foreign movies and, I guess, unfortunately had just watched "A Very Long Engagement" with cinematography that excelled. I suppose the message in Before The Rain was that time may not have been circular but it certainly comes back onto itself. The feeling I had was that the writer wanted to paint this little universe, which always repeated itself. Was this plot anything to do with the reality we all live in? No! We live in a linear reality and we don't see pictures of things that haven't happened yet. I thought it was more than depressing that the cycle the writer chose was punctuated with fusillades of gunfire from start to end. I thought "Dark Country" made better use of an enclosed circular universe. I also found the likelihood that someone could return to his old home after 16 years false, especially with the tribality and backwardness of the inhabitants which he had outgrown shortly after leaving. I have been traveling for 7 years and things are different. I could not go back to what was and be a part of those I knew. So the idea that Rade, world-wise traveler thought he could just enter his old stomping grounds did not make sense. He would have had more sense, particularly when he was met by a gun-toting guard. When he first arrived he saw his house had been abandoned so how could he not understand his old life had also been abandoned?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Time never dies, the circle is not round.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stodruza
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    But this film's construction is, like the cycle of war. Brilliant, as of course is the film. Gotta do ten lines. This is one of the best anti-war films ever made, on par with Bardov's Prisoner of the Mountains, which I recommend to you, along side Susan Beir's Brothers. Should be required viewing for all politicians...The art in this film is immense, from the film stock, to the lighting, acting, story, in essence, a perfect film. Have to wonder about people who don't appreciate it, much less enjoy it on some level. Brutally honest film about the consequences of war.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inrteresting - but why the middle section
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike B
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a 3 part film depicting events during the complex civil war in what use to be Yugoslavia. The first and third parts are set in the Balkans and for the most part are touching and authentic. A photographer returns to his homeland to witness the fracturing of it into war. This is well depicted in the movie - how communities that use to co-exist peacefully can somehow, through a tortured religious history,group pressure.. . gradually fracture into warring tribes. Another centerpiece of this story is a young girl forced to leave her village to try and save her life. The second part is mostly disconnected from part 1 and 3. The English woman is pregnant and having marital problems, there is a mafia style shoot-up in a bar. It is entirely irrelevant to the themes presented in 1 and 3. Part 2 should have been edited to coalesce with 1 and 3. The only reason for the second installment is to provide a back-drop for the photographer to return, after a long absence, to his native land and witness the fissures developing. Also in part 2 we see photographs of the execution of the fleeing young woman,but at this stage the photographer was already dead!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let the Circle be Broken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MacAindrais
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the Rain (1994) **** After only being available on bootlegged or used but extremely rare DVDs, the originals of which were released only in Macedonia and Turkey (given away for free in limited number), Milcho Manchevski's poetic and soulful examination of the futility of war and circularity of violence is set to be released on DVD proper through Criterion this June. Given that the film won the Oscar for best foreign film and earned numerous accolades from the major critics (Siskel and Ebert raved about the film on their show), one would have expected to see it on DVD a long time ago, but alas, it's coming now and getting the proper treatment. The film is set in Macedonia in the early 90s, as tensions between the 'native' Macedonians and Muslim Albanians flare. The story is broken into 3 parts  words, faces, and pictures. Words follows a young monk, on a vow of silence for the last 2 years. He finds to his shock one evening in his quarters a young boy hiding in his bed. He runs to tell one of the monastery heads, but decides against telling after seeing the fear in the boy's eyes. The next day, armed men show up looking for an Albanian girl who allegedly killed a sheep herder. No one knows of the girl, but the armed men refuse to leave and keep watch in case she turns up. That night, the young Monk, Kiril, wakes to see the boy again, but this time in the light of the moon, and realizes that it is not a boy, but a girl with her hair chopped off. She is Zamira. He allows her to hide with him, only to be discovered later in the night by the other priests. The two are forced out under the cover of darkness, wished well on their way. The two seem to be heading for love, but that love will be swiftly and brutally taken away from them before it is allowed to materialize. Part 2, faces, takes us into the modern hubbub of London, where a woman at a photo agency, Anne, is embroiled in pregnancy and an affair with her Macedonian Co-worker, Aleksander (Rade Serbedzija). He has just returned from an expedition which has apparently traumatized him. His camera has killed a man he says. He asks her to come back to Macedonia with him, where he remembers life as peaceful and safe, despite her warnings and knowledge of the Balkan conflicts. Being pregnant, she cannot go, she must meet with her husband. Aleksander leaves alone to return to his homeland. While the war seems far away from bustling London, violence and hatred are never as far as they seem. Over dinner, Anne first tells her husband she is pregnant, it's his, and she wants a divorce. Meanwhile, a waiter and a patron, both speaking Macedonian, bicker. The tension in the scene is wrought, as Anne struggles to get the right words out and express her feelings and the two men head toward a devastating act of violence for Anne and her Husband. Part 3, pictures, returns us to Macedonia, and to Aleksander. He arrives home and finds his old home a disaster, and finds that his Albanian neighbours are fearful of him. Childhood friends are now bitter enemies, hatred runs hot between Macedonians and Albanians. Some in his family seem to be somewhat sympathetic, others militant, such as his cousin, Mitre, one of the armed men at the church in the beginning of the film. Aleksander inquires about Hana, a woman he used to love, and apparently still does. She is Albanian, widowed, and off limits. He goes to visit her, and finds that he must pass a roadblock, where he is suspiciously questioned by armed villagers. He is allowed in only after Hana's father confirms his identity. We discover that the man is Zamira's grandfather, and she is Hana's daughter. Aleksander will be asked later by Hana to help protect Zamira. I will not reveal here the interconnectedness of the film, as it is impossible to do so without revealing major spoilers. We come to realize however that the film is not linear in nature, but circular, a style employed in a much different film at the same time, Pulp Fiction. We also come to realize that there a number of subtle incongruence's in the plot. People who should be dead are alive - timing and events seem to be off. Manchevski was purposeful in his editing, and the inconsistencies are not simply goofs. Rather they fit the theme of the film, spoken or seen numerous times throughout the film  "The circle is not round. Time never dies." The circularity of violence is manifested through the circularity of the plot: things don't always look the same but the result always is: destruction of life. Before the Rain is a film about our humanity and how it is destroyed by hate; how we are not only willing to destroy those we hate because we hate them, but that we will destroy those we love when they stand in the way of our hatreds. The film is a scathing indictment of the policies of war and hate, rendered through the heart and soul of art. I implore anyone reading this to seek out the film, which thankfully will be far more available come this June.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A predictably intense and depressing film about nationalism in Macedonia.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fedor8
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The London segments, i.e. the segments in English, though relatively short, drag the film down somewhat; the dialogue here is clumsy. The scene with the restaurant shoot-out is absurd and stupid: a Balkan mobster starts shooting at people randomly, a place where Cartlidge - a photographer or journalist - just happens to be, telling her husband she wants a divorce. (How conveniently her problem is solved, by him getting killed there moments later!). A little too far-fetched. Serbedjija is upset with Cartlidge because she refuses to follow him to Macedonia, him having given her very short notice! What is this, kindergarten?... The rest of BTR, which revolves around a couple of small villages, is much better, but suffers from a bad case of premonitia: we know Serbedjija will get killed; it's just a matter of time. The acting and the dialogue is solid. The film's main statement - that all sides in such a conflict are equally guilty - was a wise choice for the director to make. This decision is not to be taken for granted because most directors - particularly left-wing Western ones - aren't capable of approaching any political issue in a movie in a constructive, logical, fair, intelligent, and unbiased manner. Frankly, I saw this quite a while ago, hence am not sure what I'd think about it now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Balkan witness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kalala
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cannot praise this film highly enough. It is one of my all time favorites. This is an exquisite, haunting film that does not get shown enough. The three interlocking parts of the story slant time and recast different characters in parallel tales that form a wreath, not a sequence or circle. Each story follows a similar arc and includes similar elements: a hidden impregnation; an agonizing choice that reaches out to one that has already passed out of reach; an unexpected victim of violence; and the tragic back story of attack and retribution that dates back at least a thousand years to a late Byzantine reprisal. The elements map to the Christ story as if it had been compressed in a black hole, the virgin birth and sacrificial death compacted together and exploding out of a dazzling collage of violently mindless brutality and mindful attention--to prayer, to craft, to shepherdry. Where is the viewer? A tragedy that is so alive in current events calls to action. If we are mute witnesses, then the story will reach a point where we must testify to the tragedy(so the photographer's stills tell us). But what words could have stopped what happened? If we stand by and are glad that the story is not ours we may yet find ourselves in the story. It doesn't matter if the face is Balkan or Palestinian--ejecting the combatants fails as policy. In the end and ending, reentering the picture as participant, not witness, repossessing the ruins of home and taking responsibility for the fruit of love, means giving up personal immortality (the European illusion of celebrity) in exchange for a blood-soaked collective eternity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    gray circles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    it is a film about the dust of words. about power of self definition. about death. and hate. about courage. and a deformed universe. each character is letter of a testimony. each testimony is another cold circle of ash.and nothing else. a monk, a girl, a photographer. a village as scene of a profound crime. sure, it is slice from a war. but this war has not end. it is expectation, desire, ladder. a seed as demolition of another old order. for this cause the film is touching and impressive. because it is clear. and honest. because is a picture. the places, the dialogs, the borders of circles are only shadows of events. three stories. and the cruel silence. that is all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gripping Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the Rain has a similar format to Babel, with three separate stories which come together at the end. In the first, a young monk has taken a vow of silence and is protecting Zamira, an Aobanian girl on the run from the mob. He leaves the monastery and travels throughout Macedonia with her, attempting to escape. The second chapter involves a photo editor in London, having to choose between her husband, Nick, and a war photographer, Aleksandar. She gets caught up in a series of tragic events, beginning with a shoot out at a restaurant. The third segment ties the first two together through somewhat confusing flashbacks, and one scene, in particular is a definite timeline mistake. I sent an email to the director, and he says that it was intentional. Poetic license was is reasoning. The movie is a violent but realistic depiction of the war in the former Yugoslavia. There are no winners, only victims of another stupid and pointless conflict. Before the Rain is an excellent drama.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beautifully done movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sutapanaki66
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I liked the movie quite a lot. Well done, with clear story line and conveying the ideas perfectly. I gave it 7 instead of 10 stars because of some incorrect historic statements. For example, one of the characters says that the Byzantines poked the eyes of 14000 "Macedonian" soldiers. This refers to the battle at Klyuch in 1014 where the Byzantine emperor Basil II won the battle and because of what he did to the soldiers he was called Basil the Bulgar-slayer (Boulgaroktonos Greek: Βουλγαροκτόνος) - obviously no mention of any Macedonian soldiers. Oh, well, what can one do - that's the present day Macedonian view on history. I just thought that a movie of this scale should be correct in every aspect - both what concerns present day events and facts from the past.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sublime Work of Manchevski. A must too see
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vedette69
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    BEFORE THE RAIN is a reality Life story Movie of Macedonia it's a very original Movie and have so many in it History, War, politic, faith, power, real life..... The actors are really good, The Music is great in the film And the Camera work is One of the BEST ever seen Sublime Work of Milcho Manchevski the movie won a lot of prizes but not the big ones? Maybe of cause it's a movie from Macedonia and not American I Don't understand That i don't find the movie on DVD to buy if someone can't help my to find it Please let me now THANKS Have a Good Time This movie is also a must too see for photographers. Greetings Patrick
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Timeline Was Too Dischordant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony_retford
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Obviously most people are enthralled with this movie. I wasn't. The music was good but the cinematography was lacking - too many shots shown over again. I watch a lot of foreign movies and, I guess, unfortunately had just watched "A Very Long Engagement" with cinematography that excelled. I suppose the message in Before The Rain was that time may not have been circular but it certainly comes back onto itself. The feeling I had was that the writer wanted to paint this little universe, which always repeated itself. Was this plot anything to do with the reality we all live in? No! We live in a linear reality and we don't see pictures of things that haven't happened yet. I thought it was more than depressing that the cycle the writer chose was punctuated with fusillades of gunfire from start to end. I thought "Dark Country" made better use of an enclosed circular universe. I also found the likelihood that someone could return to his old home after 16 years false, especially with the tribality and backwardness of the inhabitants which he had outgrown shortly after leaving. I have been traveling for 7 years and things are different. I could not go back to what was and be a part of those I knew. So the idea that Rade, world-wise traveler thought he could just enter his old stomping grounds did not make sense. He would have had more sense, particularly when he was met by a gun-toting guard. When he first arrived he saw his house had been abandoned so how could he not understand his old life had also been abandoned?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Time never dies, the circle is not round.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stodruza
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    But this film's construction is, like the cycle of war. Brilliant, as of course is the film. Gotta do ten lines. This is one of the best anti-war films ever made, on par with Bardov's Prisoner of the Mountains, which I recommend to you, along side Susan Beir's Brothers. Should be required viewing for all politicians...The art in this film is immense, from the film stock, to the lighting, acting, story, in essence, a perfect film. Have to wonder about people who don't appreciate it, much less enjoy it on some level. Brutally honest film about the consequences of war.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inrteresting - but why the middle section
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike B
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a 3 part film depicting events during the complex civil war in what use to be Yugoslavia. The first and third parts are set in the Balkans and for the most part are touching and authentic. A photographer returns to his homeland to witness the fracturing of it into war. This is well depicted in the movie - how communities that use to co-exist peacefully can somehow, through a tortured religious history,group pressure.. . gradually fracture into warring tribes. Another centerpiece of this story is a young girl forced to leave her village to try and save her life. The second part is mostly disconnected from part 1 and 3. The English woman is pregnant and having marital problems, there is a mafia style shoot-up in a bar. It is entirely irrelevant to the themes presented in 1 and 3. Part 2 should have been edited to coalesce with 1 and 3. The only reason for the second installment is to provide a back-drop for the photographer to return, after a long absence, to his native land and witness the fissures developing. Also in part 2 we see photographs of the execution of the fleeing young woman,but at this stage the photographer was already dead!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let the Circle be Broken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MacAindrais
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the Rain (1994) **** After only being available on bootlegged or used but extremely rare DVDs, the originals of which were released only in Macedonia and Turkey (given away for free in limited number), Milcho Manchevski's poetic and soulful examination of the futility of war and circularity of violence is set to be released on DVD proper through Criterion this June. Given that the film won the Oscar for best foreign film and earned numerous accolades from the major critics (Siskel and Ebert raved about the film on their show), one would have expected to see it on DVD a long time ago, but alas, it's coming now and getting the proper treatment. The film is set in Macedonia in the early 90s, as tensions between the 'native' Macedonians and Muslim Albanians flare. The story is broken into 3 parts  words, faces, and pictures. Words follows a young monk, on a vow of silence for the last 2 years. He finds to his shock one evening in his quarters a young boy hiding in his bed. He runs to tell one of the monastery heads, but decides against telling after seeing the fear in the boy's eyes. The next day, armed men show up looking for an Albanian girl who allegedly killed a sheep herder. No one knows of the girl, but the armed men refuse to leave and keep watch in case she turns up. That night, the young Monk, Kiril, wakes to see the boy again, but this time in the light of the moon, and realizes that it is not a boy, but a girl with her hair chopped off. She is Zamira. He allows her to hide with him, only to be discovered later in the night by the other priests. The two are forced out under the cover of darkness, wished well on their way. The two seem to be heading for love, but that love will be swiftly and brutally taken away from them before it is allowed to materialize. Part 2, faces, takes us into the modern hubbub of London, where a woman at a photo agency, Anne, is embroiled in pregnancy and an affair with her Macedonian Co-worker, Aleksander (Rade Serbedzija). He has just returned from an expedition which has apparently traumatized him. His camera has killed a man he says. He asks her to come back to Macedonia with him, where he remembers life as peaceful and safe, despite her warnings and knowledge of the Balkan conflicts. Being pregnant, she cannot go, she must meet with her husband. Aleksander leaves alone to return to his homeland. While the war seems far away from bustling London, violence and hatred are never as far as they seem. Over dinner, Anne first tells her husband she is pregnant, it's his, and she wants a divorce. Meanwhile, a waiter and a patron, both speaking Macedonian, bicker. The tension in the scene is wrought, as Anne struggles to get the right words out and express her feelings and the two men head toward a devastating act of violence for Anne and her Husband. Part 3, pictures, returns us to Macedonia, and to Aleksander. He arrives home and finds his old home a disaster, and finds that his Albanian neighbours are fearful of him. Childhood friends are now bitter enemies, hatred runs hot between Macedonians and Albanians. Some in his family seem to be somewhat sympathetic, others militant, such as his cousin, Mitre, one of the armed men at the church in the beginning of the film. Aleksander inquires about Hana, a woman he used to love, and apparently still does. She is Albanian, widowed, and off limits. He goes to visit her, and finds that he must pass a roadblock, where he is suspiciously questioned by armed villagers. He is allowed in only after Hana's father confirms his identity. We discover that the man is Zamira's grandfather, and she is Hana's daughter. Aleksander will be asked later by Hana to help protect Zamira. I will not reveal here the interconnectedness of the film, as it is impossible to do so without revealing major spoilers. We come to realize however that the film is not linear in nature, but circular, a style employed in a much different film at the same time, Pulp Fiction. We also come to realize that there a number of subtle incongruence's in the plot. People who should be dead are alive - timing and events seem to be off. Manchevski was purposeful in his editing, and the inconsistencies are not simply goofs. Rather they fit the theme of the film, spoken or seen numerous times throughout the film  "The circle is not round. Time never dies." The circularity of violence is manifested through the circularity of the plot: things don't always look the same but the result always is: destruction of life. Before the Rain is a film about our humanity and how it is destroyed by hate; how we are not only willing to destroy those we hate because we hate them, but that we will destroy those we love when they stand in the way of our hatreds. The film is a scathing indictment of the policies of war and hate, rendered through the heart and soul of art. I implore anyone reading this to seek out the film, which thankfully will be far more available come this June.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A predictably intense and depressing film about nationalism in Macedonia.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fedor8
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The London segments, i.e. the segments in English, though relatively short, drag the film down somewhat; the dialogue here is clumsy. The scene with the restaurant shoot-out is absurd and stupid: a Balkan mobster starts shooting at people randomly, a place where Cartlidge - a photographer or journalist - just happens to be, telling her husband she wants a divorce. (How conveniently her problem is solved, by him getting killed there moments later!). A little too far-fetched. Serbedjija is upset with Cartlidge because she refuses to follow him to Macedonia, him having given her very short notice! What is this, kindergarten?... The rest of BTR, which revolves around a couple of small villages, is much better, but suffers from a bad case of premonitia: we know Serbedjija will get killed; it's just a matter of time. The acting and the dialogue is solid. The film's main statement - that all sides in such a conflict are equally guilty - was a wise choice for the director to make. This decision is not to be taken for granted because most directors - particularly left-wing Western ones - aren't capable of approaching any political issue in a movie in a constructive, logical, fair, intelligent, and unbiased manner. Frankly, I saw this quite a while ago, hence am not sure what I'd think about it now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Balkan witness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kalala
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cannot praise this film highly enough. It is one of my all time favorites. This is an exquisite, haunting film that does not get shown enough. The three interlocking parts of the story slant time and recast different characters in parallel tales that form a wreath, not a sequence or circle. Each story follows a similar arc and includes similar elements: a hidden impregnation; an agonizing choice that reaches out to one that has already passed out of reach; an unexpected victim of violence; and the tragic back story of attack and retribution that dates back at least a thousand years to a late Byzantine reprisal. The elements map to the Christ story as if it had been compressed in a black hole, the virgin birth and sacrificial death compacted together and exploding out of a dazzling collage of violently mindless brutality and mindful attention--to prayer, to craft, to shepherdry. Where is the viewer? A tragedy that is so alive in current events calls to action. If we are mute witnesses, then the story will reach a point where we must testify to the tragedy(so the photographer's stills tell us). But what words could have stopped what happened? If we stand by and are glad that the story is not ours we may yet find ourselves in the story. It doesn't matter if the face is Balkan or Palestinian--ejecting the combatants fails as policy. In the end and ending, reentering the picture as participant, not witness, repossessing the ruins of home and taking responsibility for the fruit of love, means giving up personal immortality (the European illusion of celebrity) in exchange for a blood-soaked collective eternity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    gray circles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    it is a film about the dust of words. about power of self definition. about death. and hate. about courage. and a deformed universe. each character is letter of a testimony. each testimony is another cold circle of ash.and nothing else. a monk, a girl, a photographer. a village as scene of a profound crime. sure, it is slice from a war. but this war has not end. it is expectation, desire, ladder. a seed as demolition of another old order. for this cause the film is touching and impressive. because it is clear. and honest. because is a picture. the places, the dialogs, the borders of circles are only shadows of events. three stories. and the cruel silence. that is all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gripping Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the Rain has a similar format to Babel, with three separate stories which come together at the end. In the first, a young monk has taken a vow of silence and is protecting Zamira, an Aobanian girl on the run from the mob. He leaves the monastery and travels throughout Macedonia with her, attempting to escape. The second chapter involves a photo editor in London, having to choose between her husband, Nick, and a war photographer, Aleksandar. She gets caught up in a series of tragic events, beginning with a shoot out at a restaurant. The third segment ties the first two together through somewhat confusing flashbacks, and one scene, in particular is a definite timeline mistake. I sent an email to the director, and he says that it was intentional. Poetic license was is reasoning. The movie is a violent but realistic depiction of the war in the former Yugoslavia. There are no winners, only victims of another stupid and pointless conflict. Before the Rain is an excellent drama.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beautifully done movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sutapanaki66
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I liked the movie quite a lot. Well done, with clear story line and conveying the ideas perfectly. I gave it 7 instead of 10 stars because of some incorrect historic statements. For example, one of the characters says that the Byzantines poked the eyes of 14000 "Macedonian" soldiers. This refers to the battle at Klyuch in 1014 where the Byzantine emperor Basil II won the battle and because of what he did to the soldiers he was called Basil the Bulgar-slayer (Boulgaroktonos Greek: Βουλγαροκτόνος) - obviously no mention of any Macedonian soldiers. Oh, well, what can one do - that's the present day Macedonian view on history. I just thought that a movie of this scale should be correct in every aspect - both what concerns present day events and facts from the past.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sublime Work of Manchevski. A must too see
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vedette69
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    BEFORE THE RAIN is a reality Life story Movie of Macedonia it's a very original Movie and have so many in it History, War, politic, faith, power, real life..... The actors are really good, The Music is great in the film And the Camera work is One of the BEST ever seen Sublime Work of Milcho Manchevski the movie won a lot of prizes but not the big ones? Maybe of cause it's a movie from Macedonia and not American I Don't understand That i don't find the movie on DVD to buy if someone can't help my to find it Please let me now THANKS Have a Good Time This movie is also a must too see for photographers. Greetings Patrick
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Timeline Was Too Dischordant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony_retford
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Obviously most people are enthralled with this movie. I wasn't. The music was good but the cinematography was lacking - too many shots shown over again. I watch a lot of foreign movies and, I guess, unfortunately had just watched "A Very Long Engagement" with cinematography that excelled. I suppose the message in Before The Rain was that time may not have been circular but it certainly comes back onto itself. The feeling I had was that the writer wanted to paint this little universe, which always repeated itself. Was this plot anything to do with the reality we all live in? No! We live in a linear reality and we don't see pictures of things that haven't happened yet. I thought it was more than depressing that the cycle the writer chose was punctuated with fusillades of gunfire from start to end. I thought "Dark Country" made better use of an enclosed circular universe. I also found the likelihood that someone could return to his old home after 16 years false, especially with the tribality and backwardness of the inhabitants which he had outgrown shortly after leaving. I have been traveling for 7 years and things are different. I could not go back to what was and be a part of those I knew. So the idea that Rade, world-wise traveler thought he could just enter his old stomping grounds did not make sense. He would have had more sense, particularly when he was met by a gun-toting guard. When he first arrived he saw his house had been abandoned so how could he not understand his old life had also been abandoned?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Time never dies, the circle is not round.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stodruza
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    But this film's construction is, like the cycle of war. Brilliant, as of course is the film. Gotta do ten lines. This is one of the best anti-war films ever made, on par with Bardov's Prisoner of the Mountains, which I recommend to you, along side Susan Beir's Brothers. Should be required viewing for all politicians...The art in this film is immense, from the film stock, to the lighting, acting, story, in essence, a perfect film. Have to wonder about people who don't appreciate it, much less enjoy it on some level. Brutally honest film about the consequences of war.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inrteresting - but why the middle section
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike B
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a 3 part film depicting events during the complex civil war in what use to be Yugoslavia. The first and third parts are set in the Balkans and for the most part are touching and authentic. A photographer returns to his homeland to witness the fracturing of it into war. This is well depicted in the movie - how communities that use to co-exist peacefully can somehow, through a tortured religious history,group pressure.. . gradually fracture into warring tribes. Another centerpiece of this story is a young girl forced to leave her village to try and save her life. The second part is mostly disconnected from part 1 and 3. The English woman is pregnant and having marital problems, there is a mafia style shoot-up in a bar. It is entirely irrelevant to the themes presented in 1 and 3. Part 2 should have been edited to coalesce with 1 and 3. The only reason for the second installment is to provide a back-drop for the photographer to return, after a long absence, to his native land and witness the fissures developing. Also in part 2 we see photographs of the execution of the fleeing young woman,but at this stage the photographer was already dead!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let the Circle be Broken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MacAindrais
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the Rain (1994) **** After only being available on bootlegged or used but extremely rare DVDs, the originals of which were released only in Macedonia and Turkey (given away for free in limited number), Milcho Manchevski's poetic and soulful examination of the futility of war and circularity of violence is set to be released on DVD proper through Criterion this June. Given that the film won the Oscar for best foreign film and earned numerous accolades from the major critics (Siskel and Ebert raved about the film on their show), one would have expected to see it on DVD a long time ago, but alas, it's coming now and getting the proper treatment. The film is set in Macedonia in the early 90s, as tensions between the 'native' Macedonians and Muslim Albanians flare. The story is broken into 3 parts  words, faces, and pictures. Words follows a young monk, on a vow of silence for the last 2 years. He finds to his shock one evening in his quarters a young boy hiding in his bed. He runs to tell one of the monastery heads, but decides against telling after seeing the fear in the boy's eyes. The next day, armed men show up looking for an Albanian girl who allegedly killed a sheep herder. No one knows of the girl, but the armed men refuse to leave and keep watch in case she turns up. That night, the young Monk, Kiril, wakes to see the boy again, but this time in the light of the moon, and realizes that it is not a boy, but a girl with her hair chopped off. She is Zamira. He allows her to hide with him, only to be discovered later in the night by the other priests. The two are forced out under the cover of darkness, wished well on their way. The two seem to be heading for love, but that love will be swiftly and brutally taken away from them before it is allowed to materialize. Part 2, faces, takes us into the modern hubbub of London, where a woman at a photo agency, Anne, is embroiled in pregnancy and an affair with her Macedonian Co-worker, Aleksander (Rade Serbedzija). He has just returned from an expedition which has apparently traumatized him. His camera has killed a man he says. He asks her to come back to Macedonia with him, where he remembers life as peaceful and safe, despite her warnings and knowledge of the Balkan conflicts. Being pregnant, she cannot go, she must meet with her husband. Aleksander leaves alone to return to his homeland. While the war seems far away from bustling London, violence and hatred are never as far as they seem. Over dinner, Anne first tells her husband she is pregnant, it's his, and she wants a divorce. Meanwhile, a waiter and a patron, both speaking Macedonian, bicker. The tension in the scene is wrought, as Anne struggles to get the right words out and express her feelings and the two men head toward a devastating act of violence for Anne and her Husband. Part 3, pictures, returns us to Macedonia, and to Aleksander. He arrives home and finds his old home a disaster, and finds that his Albanian neighbours are fearful of him. Childhood friends are now bitter enemies, hatred runs hot between Macedonians and Albanians. Some in his family seem to be somewhat sympathetic, others militant, such as his cousin, Mitre, one of the armed men at the church in the beginning of the film. Aleksander inquires about Hana, a woman he used to love, and apparently still does. She is Albanian, widowed, and off limits. He goes to visit her, and finds that he must pass a roadblock, where he is suspiciously questioned by armed villagers. He is allowed in only after Hana's father confirms his identity. We discover that the man is Zamira's grandfather, and she is Hana's daughter. Aleksander will be asked later by Hana to help protect Zamira. I will not reveal here the interconnectedness of the film, as it is impossible to do so without revealing major spoilers. We come to realize however that the film is not linear in nature, but circular, a style employed in a much different film at the same time, Pulp Fiction. We also come to realize that there a number of subtle incongruence's in the plot. People who should be dead are alive - timing and events seem to be off. Manchevski was purposeful in his editing, and the inconsistencies are not simply goofs. Rather they fit the theme of the film, spoken or seen numerous times throughout the film  "The circle is not round. Time never dies." The circularity of violence is manifested through the circularity of the plot: things don't always look the same but the result always is: destruction of life. Before the Rain is a film about our humanity and how it is destroyed by hate; how we are not only willing to destroy those we hate because we hate them, but that we will destroy those we love when they stand in the way of our hatreds. The film is a scathing indictment of the policies of war and hate, rendered through the heart and soul of art. I implore anyone reading this to seek out the film, which thankfully will be far more available come this June.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A predictably intense and depressing film about nationalism in Macedonia.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fedor8
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The London segments, i.e. the segments in English, though relatively short, drag the film down somewhat; the dialogue here is clumsy. The scene with the restaurant shoot-out is absurd and stupid: a Balkan mobster starts shooting at people randomly, a place where Cartlidge - a photographer or journalist - just happens to be, telling her husband she wants a divorce. (How conveniently her problem is solved, by him getting killed there moments later!). A little too far-fetched. Serbedjija is upset with Cartlidge because she refuses to follow him to Macedonia, him having given her very short notice! What is this, kindergarten?... The rest of BTR, which revolves around a couple of small villages, is much better, but suffers from a bad case of premonitia: we know Serbedjija will get killed; it's just a matter of time. The acting and the dialogue is solid. The film's main statement - that all sides in such a conflict are equally guilty - was a wise choice for the director to make. This decision is not to be taken for granted because most directors - particularly left-wing Western ones - aren't capable of approaching any political issue in a movie in a constructive, logical, fair, intelligent, and unbiased manner. Frankly, I saw this quite a while ago, hence am not sure what I'd think about it now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Balkan witness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kalala
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cannot praise this film highly enough. It is one of my all time favorites. This is an exquisite, haunting film that does not get shown enough. The three interlocking parts of the story slant time and recast different characters in parallel tales that form a wreath, not a sequence or circle. Each story follows a similar arc and includes similar elements: a hidden impregnation; an agonizing choice that reaches out to one that has already passed out of reach; an unexpected victim of violence; and the tragic back story of attack and retribution that dates back at least a thousand years to a late Byzantine reprisal. The elements map to the Christ story as if it had been compressed in a black hole, the virgin birth and sacrificial death compacted together and exploding out of a dazzling collage of violently mindless brutality and mindful attention--to prayer, to craft, to shepherdry. Where is the viewer? A tragedy that is so alive in current events calls to action. If we are mute witnesses, then the story will reach a point where we must testify to the tragedy(so the photographer's stills tell us). But what words could have stopped what happened? If we stand by and are glad that the story is not ours we may yet find ourselves in the story. It doesn't matter if the face is Balkan or Palestinian--ejecting the combatants fails as policy. In the end and ending, reentering the picture as participant, not witness, repossessing the ruins of home and taking responsibility for the fruit of love, means giving up personal immortality (the European illusion of celebrity) in exchange for a blood-soaked collective eternity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
