<filme>
 <id>
  1195
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0106966
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1993
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Morango E Chocolate
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Diego, a cultivated, homosexual and skeptical young man, falls in love with a young heterosexual communist full of prejudices and doctrinary ideas. First come rejection and suspicion, but ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Diego, a cultivated, homosexual and skeptical young man, falls in love with a young heterosexual communist full of prejudices and doctrinary ideas. First come rejection and suspicion, but also fascination. Fresa y chocolate is the story of a great friendship, that is, a great love between two men, which overcomes incomprehension and intolerance.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   friendship
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   communist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   homosexual
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   chocolate
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Tom&aacute;s Guti&eacute;rrez Alea
  </diretor>
  <diretor>
   Juan Carlos Tab&iacute;o
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Tom&aacute;s Guti&eacute;rrez Alea
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Senel Paz
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jorge Perugorr&iacute;a
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Vladimir Cruz
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Mirta Ibarra
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly enjoyable whether or not you are gay or straight or a communist or whatever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Strawberry and Chocolate" is a Cuban film that was nominated for the Best Foreign Language Oscar--losing to "Burnt By the Sun" (my personal favorite was "Eat, Drink, Man, Woman"). And, although the film is set in communist Cuba and is about a gay man, you can enjoy the film regardless of your orientation (political or sexual). It's simply well made and interesting. David is a very straight young man who is an unquestioning lover of the Cuban revolution. One day, he's approached by Diego and lured to Diego's apartment. However, because David is certainly not gay, Diego's conquest never occurs and David leaves. When David tells a friend about this, this friend encourages David to return to spy on Diego. After all, he's a gay religious man and has international ideas--and MUST be an enemy of the state. Something strange happens, however, and Diego and David become friends--something that challenges both of them. Diego must learn to deal with a non-sexual male friend and David must realize that you can still love your country without being straight or having a love of life outside Cuba. The film works mostly because the acting is quite nice and the story universal. Even with a few anti-American remarks at one point, the film is one anyone can enjoy. And, I was surprised that this Cuban film was willing to question what it is to be patriotic--and how Cuba in 1993 was not exactly tolerant when it came to homosexuality. Fascinating. By the way, there is a reasonable amount of nudity in this one, so you may want to think twice about having younger folks watch the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No chocolate, please
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Edgar Sober&oacute;n Torchia (estorchia@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fresa y chocolate" has more historical significance than cinematic merits: for the first time, a film from revolutionary Cuba openly treated homosexuality, from a point of view that it's too "safe" to create a controversy. It was greeted with great enthusiasm by Cuban homosexuals, including those that were victims of persecution during the 1970. But I am sorry to say that, being myself a mature homosexual from the Capitalist world who has gone through all kind of persecutions in life --literal and symbolic-- I find the story too clich&eacute;d and manipulative, and the main character a sad figure from the past, trapped in time and space. When it was made Tom&aacute;s Guti&eacute;rrez Alea, whose masterpiece "Memorias del subdesarrollo" (1968) is among the best films of world cinema of all times, was terminally ill, so Juan Carlos Tab&iacute;o (whose forte is comedy, including the classic "Demasiado miedo a la vida o Plaf") had to share the direction. The script by Senel Paz is tame, Vladimir Cruz is miscast and the whole affair is a bit boring and demod&eacute;.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A refreshing non-formulaic movie with an effective approach about a sensitive Cuban subject.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a rather good and surprising Cuban movie, focusing on homosexuality in Communist Cuba. It's not the sort of movie you expect coming from Cuba and on top of that it also isn't a movie that stays on the surface but goes in into the subject real deep. It's not a movie that focuses on the physical relationship between the two main characters but more between the spiritual relationship of the two, which is a surprising approach. So, it's not a 'standard' movie about two man falling in love with each other, as you at first might expect when watching this movie. It's a movie that goes much deeper and therefor gets more layered, interesting and compelling to watch. It's great to see how the two of them grow toward each other, in a non-forced or formulaic way. It feels like a warm and very realistic movie, since it never chooses to diverse from its main plot-line and mainly focuses purely on the two main characters of the movie. Vladimir Cruz gives a good and realistic performance. But one thing that bothered me about him was that he was very popular in both male and female camp, which seemed weird and funny to me, since he really didn't looked like an handsome guy. But who knows, maybe this is the Cuban's idea of a pretty looking man. Jorge Perugorr&iacute;a also did a good job, although he performance as an homosexual character seemed a bit too feminine and over-the-top to me at certain points. He played the character like an obvious stereotype of a gay person but he did it in such a good and sincere way that it wasn't always a problem. I was also surprised by the look and overall atmosphere of the movie. Foreign movies, made outside of Cuba, always focus- and shows its visual beauty, of wide beaches, palms, beautiful music and people living there. It's a sort of an almost surreal and alternate world if you look at it. This movie is however more dark and gritty and shows the ugly side of Havana, both visually as with its themes and underlying comments. Some of the symbolism and underlying messages in the dialog are a bit too obvious, as if they were trying too hard, but this is perhaps the only real flaw in the movie its excellent story and directing of the movie. Don't know why the movie is often being regarded and treated as a comedy. It's above all an heavy drama but done in a light and more pleasant sort of way, but those are no reasons for me to regard this movie as a comedy. The movie uses the more European style and approach of the story and characters. So be sure what to expect when watching this movie. A great and relevant movie because of its themes, and I assume also a big step forward for gay-right and tolerance in Cuba. 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A charming film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    little_rhody
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How often do we get to see Cuban films here in America? How many Cuban films have a gay protagonist? Strawberry and Chocolate is a wonderful Cuban film that features a glimpse into Havana and the Cuban gay subculture juxtaposed against dedicated, communist college students. David is the college student who believes in the system. Diego is a gay writer who has friends in the art world. Nancy is stuck between the two worlds, and having difficulty coping. Through his association with the others, David receives an education he wouldn't get at the university. The film is about love and desire: love of country; love of art; love between men and women; love between men - romantic and platonic. Thank you Robert Redford and Miramax for bringing this to the States
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How did this ever get past the censor?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danngil
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At first I thought that this was a Latin version of a typical gay film that comes out of the U.S. I couldn't have been more wrong. It's really a charming film about friendship that's difficult to achieve. "Why does sex always get in the way?" David asks. In other words, it's as difficult for a gay and straight man to develop a friendship as it is for a straight man and woman. Sounds a bit like dating and marriage, doesn't it? It's even more difficult when a government and friends interfere. At the beginning I was afraid that Diego would actually seduce David and voil&agrave; we have the usual gay film that I find boring. Instead, I really got to like Diego, much the same way he eventually charms David. That's getting involved with characters in a movie. Excellent performances by the two leads. The other performance that is compelling is that of Nancy (Mirtha Ibarra). I first saw Mirtha Ibarra in Guantanamara, a film that followed this by a year. In both films, she plays the older woman that every young man fantasizes about. Where was Mirtha Ibarra when I was David's age? I don't know how, if the Cuban regime is supposed to be so oppressive that they allowed this film to be made. Perhaps they wanted to show the "Yanquis" that it's possible to be critical of the government and still love one's country. This is a film that I will see twice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    getting out to the street
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ruiresende84 (ruiresende84@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cinema is an art in itself and not a sum of arts. That is because it has specific things that can't be made alone by any other art. Now, what exactly can make cinema an art of its own is arguable but will always have something to do with passing anything through moving images: . storytelling . a mood, an atmosphere . fact all three are worth exploring. In Fresa y chocolate, the problem is there is an apparent mixture of all three, which can exist, but not like exposed in here. The device was clear and apparently effective: a simple story inside Story. never mind the simple story, it's the least important. The Story is the whole Cuba context. Go to the general, pick up an episode (that may represent or not, fact) and from there build the mood, the atmosphere. This last step was what failed. And it was for a non definition on the "eye" of the camera. By giving all the ingredients, all the passwords to the contained world (island) and to its specific context, it should have been shown. I've been to Cuba, there was not much lacking for me, i know what i didn't see in the picture, but by focusing on dialog (that could for its meaning come embedded on the mood) and by not having an eye for the street, for the people, for the city, the project lost a big deal. It had everything to be a film about a city. Story inside space, since the story we are told is clearly typical, one in many. it may have been political issues behind, and it is of great importance that this film could have been made, versing such locally heavy themes. But that's my main critic, Guti&eacute;rrez Alea had an excellent eye for portrait, and for placing stories in context, but he lacked the sense of the place, in terms of senses (modd, atmosphere). Even though a good document, worth watching, excellent character development, excellent performances also. Diego's house (and the dialogs that go with it) contain excellent underline thoughts, the dialogs are filled (i didn't read the original story) with messages, in a not so subtle way. Also a note for the excellent use of the color (very Cuban). My evaluation: 3/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    High sensitivity at the sight!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaffar-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is undoubtedly one of the greatest Cuban films of the last two decades, Tomas Gutierrez Alea "tit&oacute;n" was an excellent film director that took part in many of Cuban most awarded films ever and he's for so much in Cuban top 10 directors list. About Perugorria "Pichi" he's one Cuban most largely known actors of the time and has proved to be a never static actor, never stereotyped actor, ... The film aboard one big truth, not just a Cuban one but a latinamerican one, the macho men thinking way that has to do with everyone's way of interacting in society. The film captures a particular stage on Cuban history when homosexuality was mistreated even at high levels and the prejudice set against homosexuals was really strong, even more on men because of the imperant Latin "machismo". This is just a gift both for cinema lovers and for those that loves Cuba and Cubans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    it is a friendship between two different men in spite of their sexuality difference. Around 1979 Cuban governments's oppressions toward homosexuals.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    steuern
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fresa y chocolate I liked to watch Fresa y Chocolate; this is first Cuban movie I've seen. Fresa y Chocolate is a product of two directors, Tom&aacute;s Guti&eacute;rrez Alea and Juan Carlos Tab&iacute;o in 1993. Fresa y Chocolate was nominated in 1995 the best foreign film. During the production of this film the director Alea had cancer and for this reason Tab&iacute;o had to help him to complete the movie. Later 1996 Alea die. This movie expresses the oppression of Cuban government toward the homosexual and the conflict also the friendship within two different men. Around 1997 in Cuba,Diego (Jorge Perugorria ) the main character is a cultured gay and David (Vldimir Cruz) a young revolutionary college student. He is a naive and dogmatic. The story begins at a cheap hotel room where David and his sweetheart, Vivian tried to have first intimate experience together but ended up angry at each other, later Vivian marries to a much older man who is in the government office position. David, the wedding day feeling low come to an Ice cream shop near by school and over there David and Diego meet. At the begging, it was Diego's attempt to allure David but soon it change and in spite of their sexuality, these two different men establish a true friendship. Most of story take a place at Diego's apartment where full of things (art work, forbidden books, pictures...) for David's eye. It is a new and different world for David, a dogmatic and in a way an ignorant. Diego tells David about his anguish and problem toward the government. For him being homosexual hinder his work in Cuba and also his well being, too. However, David learns much about art and literature from Diego and moreover, he learn how to enjoy and savor life. The message of this movie is tolerance. No matter what is one's sexuality people have genuine heart. They have hope, dreams, and frustration that life brings us. I think this movie is worth to watch because Fresa y Chocolate gave me a chance to give a glance to Cuba, the country that I don't know yet. To me watching a good film lessens a tension of life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fresa y Chocolate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Adair
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Homosexuality is something that is not accepted in many countries, and this Cuban movie is based in this sentiment. The dramatic-comedy Strawberry and Chocolate was directed by Tom&aacute;s Guti&eacute;rrez Alea and Juan Carlos Tab&iacute;o, and was an adaptation of the story "The wolf, the forest, and the new man" by Senel Paz. This movie represents very well the sentiment against homosexuality that still exists. Vladimir Cruz plays the part of David, the protagonist (the "new man" in Paz's words), and Jorge Perugorr&iacute;a plays the part of Diego (the wolf). The plot begins in Havana with David and his failed attempt to make love to his girlfriend, Vivian. It continues later on Vivian's wedding day with another man, while David watches them from the background. Depressed, David goes to the ice cream stand and meets Diego, who is clearly homosexual. Diego invites him to his apartment, but David flees suddenly because Diego is very strange. He later returns to the apartment because he is under the pressure of his roommate, Manuel, to investigate "the queer." Friendship begins to grow between David and Diego. Diego is smart, knows a lot about art and culture, and teaches these things to his friend. The friendship between David and Nancy, one of Diego's friends, grows as well and they make love at the end of the movie. But, Diego is in trouble after sending a letter that ridicules the government for not accepting his art exhibition and, for this reason, the government kicks him out and he has to leave the country. The movie ends with a touching hug between Diego and David. I like the plot because it uses elements of comedy to demonstrate a serious theme, and I thing that this works well. There are two themes that clearly exist in this movie: friendship and tolerance. True friendship can only exist when two people accept each other as they are; not only physically, but on the inside as well. For example, friendship is nonexistent between Manuel and David because Manuel doesn't care about David's personality, rather his actions. By the end, David and Diego adore each other for all the qualities they have, and do not worry about physical things. Tolerance is something different and is important as well. Many people in Cuba (demonstrated in Manuel) and other countries can't change their thoughts about homosexuality because they are too strong and unmovable. David's tolerance for Diego grows during the progression of the movie and it is realized at the end with a hug between friends. The use of light works well to show the mood of the movie. The darkness at the beginning shows the feeling that they are doing something bad or dirty, and the brightness when David and Diego are in the hideout (Diego's apartment) at the end of the movie shows that things will be fine. The acting is good and adds to the movie. Sometimes, Perugorr&iacute;a's acting is too cheesy, but it works to show his strange character. Through Cruz's good acting, one can clearly see David's emotional growth with his new friendship with Diego, the strange guy. In reality, people do not accept a change from the norm, and this is true especially with homosexuality. Homosexuals still fight today in many countries for their rights, but many people still don't accept them. This movie shows us very well this feeling through drama but also with a few moments of humor. I would recommend this to my friends because it isn't too serious, but nonetheless has a moving message for the viewer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a good look at homosexuality in Cuba
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Knowing how the Cuban government suppressed homosexuality for so long, it's sort of surprising that they allowed a movie about it. But the movie ended up being quite good. Diego (Jorge Perugorria) is a student in 1979 Havana who hooks up with the aesthetic David (Vladimir Cruz), who turns out to be gay. Naturally, Diego is a little unnerved by this, but over time, he and David come to respect each other. One reason that "Strawberry and Chocolate" is especially good is because they never go overboard in trying to portray gay people. David is attracted to men, certainly, but he never does something like start dancing to a disco song suddenly. Quite an impressive movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly enjoyable whether or not you are gay or straight or a communist or whatever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Strawberry and Chocolate" is a Cuban film that was nominated for the Best Foreign Language Oscar--losing to "Burnt By the Sun" (my personal favorite was "Eat, Drink, Man, Woman"). And, although the film is set in communist Cuba and is about a gay man, you can enjoy the film regardless of your orientation (political or sexual). It's simply well made and interesting. David is a very straight young man who is an unquestioning lover of the Cuban revolution. One day, he's approached by Diego and lured to Diego's apartment. However, because David is certainly not gay, Diego's conquest never occurs and David leaves. When David tells a friend about this, this friend encourages David to return to spy on Diego. After all, he's a gay religious man and has international ideas--and MUST be an enemy of the state. Something strange happens, however, and Diego and David become friends--something that challenges both of them. Diego must learn to deal with a non-sexual male friend and David must realize that you can still love your country without being straight or having a love of life outside Cuba. The film works mostly because the acting is quite nice and the story universal. Even with a few anti-American remarks at one point, the film is one anyone can enjoy. And, I was surprised that this Cuban film was willing to question what it is to be patriotic--and how Cuba in 1993 was not exactly tolerant when it came to homosexuality. Fascinating. By the way, there is a reasonable amount of nudity in this one, so you may want to think twice about having younger folks watch the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No chocolate, please
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Edgar Sober&oacute;n Torchia (estorchia@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fresa y chocolate" has more historical significance than cinematic merits: for the first time, a film from revolutionary Cuba openly treated homosexuality, from a point of view that it's too "safe" to create a controversy. It was greeted with great enthusiasm by Cuban homosexuals, including those that were victims of persecution during the 1970. But I am sorry to say that, being myself a mature homosexual from the Capitalist world who has gone through all kind of persecutions in life --literal and symbolic-- I find the story too clich&eacute;d and manipulative, and the main character a sad figure from the past, trapped in time and space. When it was made Tom&aacute;s Guti&eacute;rrez Alea, whose masterpiece "Memorias del subdesarrollo" (1968) is among the best films of world cinema of all times, was terminally ill, so Juan Carlos Tab&iacute;o (whose forte is comedy, including the classic "Demasiado miedo a la vida o Plaf") had to share the direction. The script by Senel Paz is tame, Vladimir Cruz is miscast and the whole affair is a bit boring and demod&eacute;.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A refreshing non-formulaic movie with an effective approach about a sensitive Cuban subject.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a rather good and surprising Cuban movie, focusing on homosexuality in Communist Cuba. It's not the sort of movie you expect coming from Cuba and on top of that it also isn't a movie that stays on the surface but goes in into the subject real deep. It's not a movie that focuses on the physical relationship between the two main characters but more between the spiritual relationship of the two, which is a surprising approach. So, it's not a 'standard' movie about two man falling in love with each other, as you at first might expect when watching this movie. It's a movie that goes much deeper and therefor gets more layered, interesting and compelling to watch. It's great to see how the two of them grow toward each other, in a non-forced or formulaic way. It feels like a warm and very realistic movie, since it never chooses to diverse from its main plot-line and mainly focuses purely on the two main characters of the movie. Vladimir Cruz gives a good and realistic performance. But one thing that bothered me about him was that he was very popular in both male and female camp, which seemed weird and funny to me, since he really didn't looked like an handsome guy. But who knows, maybe this is the Cuban's idea of a pretty looking man. Jorge Perugorr&iacute;a also did a good job, although he performance as an homosexual character seemed a bit too feminine and over-the-top to me at certain points. He played the character like an obvious stereotype of a gay person but he did it in such a good and sincere way that it wasn't always a problem. I was also surprised by the look and overall atmosphere of the movie. Foreign movies, made outside of Cuba, always focus- and shows its visual beauty, of wide beaches, palms, beautiful music and people living there. It's a sort of an almost surreal and alternate world if you look at it. This movie is however more dark and gritty and shows the ugly side of Havana, both visually as with its themes and underlying comments. Some of the symbolism and underlying messages in the dialog are a bit too obvious, as if they were trying too hard, but this is perhaps the only real flaw in the movie its excellent story and directing of the movie. Don't know why the movie is often being regarded and treated as a comedy. It's above all an heavy drama but done in a light and more pleasant sort of way, but those are no reasons for me to regard this movie as a comedy. The movie uses the more European style and approach of the story and characters. So be sure what to expect when watching this movie. A great and relevant movie because of its themes, and I assume also a big step forward for gay-right and tolerance in Cuba. 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A charming film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    little_rhody
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How often do we get to see Cuban films here in America? How many Cuban films have a gay protagonist? Strawberry and Chocolate is a wonderful Cuban film that features a glimpse into Havana and the Cuban gay subculture juxtaposed against dedicated, communist college students. David is the college student who believes in the system. Diego is a gay writer who has friends in the art world. Nancy is stuck between the two worlds, and having difficulty coping. Through his association with the others, David receives an education he wouldn't get at the university. The film is about love and desire: love of country; love of art; love between men and women; love between men - romantic and platonic. Thank you Robert Redford and Miramax for bringing this to the States
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How did this ever get past the censor?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danngil
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At first I thought that this was a Latin version of a typical gay film that comes out of the U.S. I couldn't have been more wrong. It's really a charming film about friendship that's difficult to achieve. "Why does sex always get in the way?" David asks. In other words, it's as difficult for a gay and straight man to develop a friendship as it is for a straight man and woman. Sounds a bit like dating and marriage, doesn't it? It's even more difficult when a government and friends interfere. At the beginning I was afraid that Diego would actually seduce David and voil&agrave; we have the usual gay film that I find boring. Instead, I really got to like Diego, much the same way he eventually charms David. That's getting involved with characters in a movie. Excellent performances by the two leads. The other performance that is compelling is that of Nancy (Mirtha Ibarra). I first saw Mirtha Ibarra in Guantanamara, a film that followed this by a year. In both films, she plays the older woman that every young man fantasizes about. Where was Mirtha Ibarra when I was David's age? I don't know how, if the Cuban regime is supposed to be so oppressive that they allowed this film to be made. Perhaps they wanted to show the "Yanquis" that it's possible to be critical of the government and still love one's country. This is a film that I will see twice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    getting out to the street
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ruiresende84 (ruiresende84@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cinema is an art in itself and not a sum of arts. That is because it has specific things that can't be made alone by any other art. Now, what exactly can make cinema an art of its own is arguable but will always have something to do with passing anything through moving images: . storytelling . a mood, an atmosphere . fact all three are worth exploring. In Fresa y chocolate, the problem is there is an apparent mixture of all three, which can exist, but not like exposed in here. The device was clear and apparently effective: a simple story inside Story. never mind the simple story, it's the least important. The Story is the whole Cuba context. Go to the general, pick up an episode (that may represent or not, fact) and from there build the mood, the atmosphere. This last step was what failed. And it was for a non definition on the "eye" of the camera. By giving all the ingredients, all the passwords to the contained world (island) and to its specific context, it should have been shown. I've been to Cuba, there was not much lacking for me, i know what i didn't see in the picture, but by focusing on dialog (that could for its meaning come embedded on the mood) and by not having an eye for the street, for the people, for the city, the project lost a big deal. It had everything to be a film about a city. Story inside space, since the story we are told is clearly typical, one in many. it may have been political issues behind, and it is of great importance that this film could have been made, versing such locally heavy themes. But that's my main critic, Guti&eacute;rrez Alea had an excellent eye for portrait, and for placing stories in context, but he lacked the sense of the place, in terms of senses (modd, atmosphere). Even though a good document, worth watching, excellent character development, excellent performances also. Diego's house (and the dialogs that go with it) contain excellent underline thoughts, the dialogs are filled (i didn't read the original story) with messages, in a not so subtle way. Also a note for the excellent use of the color (very Cuban). My evaluation: 3/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    High sensitivity at the sight!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaffar-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is undoubtedly one of the greatest Cuban films of the last two decades, Tomas Gutierrez Alea "tit&oacute;n" was an excellent film director that took part in many of Cuban most awarded films ever and he's for so much in Cuban top 10 directors list. About Perugorria "Pichi" he's one Cuban most largely known actors of the time and has proved to be a never static actor, never stereotyped actor, ... The film aboard one big truth, not just a Cuban one but a latinamerican one, the macho men thinking way that has to do with everyone's way of interacting in society. The film captures a particular stage on Cuban history when homosexuality was mistreated even at high levels and the prejudice set against homosexuals was really strong, even more on men because of the imperant Latin "machismo". This is just a gift both for cinema lovers and for those that loves Cuba and Cubans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    it is a friendship between two different men in spite of their sexuality difference. Around 1979 Cuban governments's oppressions toward homosexuals.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    steuern
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fresa y chocolate I liked to watch Fresa y Chocolate; this is first Cuban movie I've seen. Fresa y Chocolate is a product of two directors, Tom&aacute;s Guti&eacute;rrez Alea and Juan Carlos Tab&iacute;o in 1993. Fresa y Chocolate was nominated in 1995 the best foreign film. During the production of this film the director Alea had cancer and for this reason Tab&iacute;o had to help him to complete the movie. Later 1996 Alea die. This movie expresses the oppression of Cuban government toward the homosexual and the conflict also the friendship within two different men. Around 1997 in Cuba,Diego (Jorge Perugorria ) the main character is a cultured gay and David (Vldimir Cruz) a young revolutionary college student. He is a naive and dogmatic. The story begins at a cheap hotel room where David and his sweetheart, Vivian tried to have first intimate experience together but ended up angry at each other, later Vivian marries to a much older man who is in the government office position. David, the wedding day feeling low come to an Ice cream shop near by school and over there David and Diego meet. At the begging, it was Diego's attempt to allure David but soon it change and in spite of their sexuality, these two different men establish a true friendship. Most of story take a place at Diego's apartment where full of things (art work, forbidden books, pictures...) for David's eye. It is a new and different world for David, a dogmatic and in a way an ignorant. Diego tells David about his anguish and problem toward the government. For him being homosexual hinder his work in Cuba and also his well being, too. However, David learns much about art and literature from Diego and moreover, he learn how to enjoy and savor life. The message of this movie is tolerance. No matter what is one's sexuality people have genuine heart. They have hope, dreams, and frustration that life brings us. I think this movie is worth to watch because Fresa y Chocolate gave me a chance to give a glance to Cuba, the country that I don't know yet. To me watching a good film lessens a tension of life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fresa y Chocolate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Adair
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Homosexuality is something that is not accepted in many countries, and this Cuban movie is based in this sentiment. The dramatic-comedy Strawberry and Chocolate was directed by Tom&aacute;s Guti&eacute;rrez Alea and Juan Carlos Tab&iacute;o, and was an adaptation of the story "The wolf, the forest, and the new man" by Senel Paz. This movie represents very well the sentiment against homosexuality that still exists. Vladimir Cruz plays the part of David, the protagonist (the "new man" in Paz's words), and Jorge Perugorr&iacute;a plays the part of Diego (the wolf). The plot begins in Havana with David and his failed attempt to make love to his girlfriend, Vivian. It continues later on Vivian's wedding day with another man, while David watches them from the background. Depressed, David goes to the ice cream stand and meets Diego, who is clearly homosexual. Diego invites him to his apartment, but David flees suddenly because Diego is very strange. He later returns to the apartment because he is under the pressure of his roommate, Manuel, to investigate "the queer." Friendship begins to grow between David and Diego. Diego is smart, knows a lot about art and culture, and teaches these things to his friend. The friendship between David and Nancy, one of Diego's friends, grows as well and they make love at the end of the movie. But, Diego is in trouble after sending a letter that ridicules the government for not accepting his art exhibition and, for this reason, the government kicks him out and he has to leave the country. The movie ends with a touching hug between Diego and David. I like the plot because it uses elements of comedy to demonstrate a serious theme, and I thing that this works well. There are two themes that clearly exist in this movie: friendship and tolerance. True friendship can only exist when two people accept each other as they are; not only physically, but on the inside as well. For example, friendship is nonexistent between Manuel and David because Manuel doesn't care about David's personality, rather his actions. By the end, David and Diego adore each other for all the qualities they have, and do not worry about physical things. Tolerance is something different and is important as well. Many people in Cuba (demonstrated in Manuel) and other countries can't change their thoughts about homosexuality because they are too strong and unmovable. David's tolerance for Diego grows during the progression of the movie and it is realized at the end with a hug between friends. The use of light works well to show the mood of the movie. The darkness at the beginning shows the feeling that they are doing something bad or dirty, and the brightness when David and Diego are in the hideout (Diego's apartment) at the end of the movie shows that things will be fine. The acting is good and adds to the movie. Sometimes, Perugorr&iacute;a's acting is too cheesy, but it works to show his strange character. Through Cruz's good acting, one can clearly see David's emotional growth with his new friendship with Diego, the strange guy. In reality, people do not accept a change from the norm, and this is true especially with homosexuality. Homosexuals still fight today in many countries for their rights, but many people still don't accept them. This movie shows us very well this feeling through drama but also with a few moments of humor. I would recommend this to my friends because it isn't too serious, but nonetheless has a moving message for the viewer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a good look at homosexuality in Cuba
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Knowing how the Cuban government suppressed homosexuality for so long, it's sort of surprising that they allowed a movie about it. But the movie ended up being quite good. Diego (Jorge Perugorria) is a student in 1979 Havana who hooks up with the aesthetic David (Vladimir Cruz), who turns out to be gay. Naturally, Diego is a little unnerved by this, but over time, he and David come to respect each other. One reason that "Strawberry and Chocolate" is especially good is because they never go overboard in trying to portray gay people. David is attracted to men, certainly, but he never does something like start dancing to a disco song suddenly. Quite an impressive movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly enjoyable whether or not you are gay or straight or a communist or whatever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Strawberry and Chocolate" is a Cuban film that was nominated for the Best Foreign Language Oscar--losing to "Burnt By the Sun" (my personal favorite was "Eat, Drink, Man, Woman"). And, although the film is set in communist Cuba and is about a gay man, you can enjoy the film regardless of your orientation (political or sexual). It's simply well made and interesting. David is a very straight young man who is an unquestioning lover of the Cuban revolution. One day, he's approached by Diego and lured to Diego's apartment. However, because David is certainly not gay, Diego's conquest never occurs and David leaves. When David tells a friend about this, this friend encourages David to return to spy on Diego. After all, he's a gay religious man and has international ideas--and MUST be an enemy of the state. Something strange happens, however, and Diego and David become friends--something that challenges both of them. Diego must learn to deal with a non-sexual male friend and David must realize that you can still love your country without being straight or having a love of life outside Cuba. The film works mostly because the acting is quite nice and the story universal. Even with a few anti-American remarks at one point, the film is one anyone can enjoy. And, I was surprised that this Cuban film was willing to question what it is to be patriotic--and how Cuba in 1993 was not exactly tolerant when it came to homosexuality. Fascinating. By the way, there is a reasonable amount of nudity in this one, so you may want to think twice about having younger folks watch the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No chocolate, please
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Edgar Sober&oacute;n Torchia (estorchia@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fresa y chocolate" has more historical significance than cinematic merits: for the first time, a film from revolutionary Cuba openly treated homosexuality, from a point of view that it's too "safe" to create a controversy. It was greeted with great enthusiasm by Cuban homosexuals, including those that were victims of persecution during the 1970. But I am sorry to say that, being myself a mature homosexual from the Capitalist world who has gone through all kind of persecutions in life --literal and symbolic-- I find the story too clich&eacute;d and manipulative, and the main character a sad figure from the past, trapped in time and space. When it was made Tom&aacute;s Guti&eacute;rrez Alea, whose masterpiece "Memorias del subdesarrollo" (1968) is among the best films of world cinema of all times, was terminally ill, so Juan Carlos Tab&iacute;o (whose forte is comedy, including the classic "Demasiado miedo a la vida o Plaf") had to share the direction. The script by Senel Paz is tame, Vladimir Cruz is miscast and the whole affair is a bit boring and demod&eacute;.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A refreshing non-formulaic movie with an effective approach about a sensitive Cuban subject.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a rather good and surprising Cuban movie, focusing on homosexuality in Communist Cuba. It's not the sort of movie you expect coming from Cuba and on top of that it also isn't a movie that stays on the surface but goes in into the subject real deep. It's not a movie that focuses on the physical relationship between the two main characters but more between the spiritual relationship of the two, which is a surprising approach. So, it's not a 'standard' movie about two man falling in love with each other, as you at first might expect when watching this movie. It's a movie that goes much deeper and therefor gets more layered, interesting and compelling to watch. It's great to see how the two of them grow toward each other, in a non-forced or formulaic way. It feels like a warm and very realistic movie, since it never chooses to diverse from its main plot-line and mainly focuses purely on the two main characters of the movie. Vladimir Cruz gives a good and realistic performance. But one thing that bothered me about him was that he was very popular in both male and female camp, which seemed weird and funny to me, since he really didn't looked like an handsome guy. But who knows, maybe this is the Cuban's idea of a pretty looking man. Jorge Perugorr&iacute;a also did a good job, although he performance as an homosexual character seemed a bit too feminine and over-the-top to me at certain points. He played the character like an obvious stereotype of a gay person but he did it in such a good and sincere way that it wasn't always a problem. I was also surprised by the look and overall atmosphere of the movie. Foreign movies, made outside of Cuba, always focus- and shows its visual beauty, of wide beaches, palms, beautiful music and people living there. It's a sort of an almost surreal and alternate world if you look at it. This movie is however more dark and gritty and shows the ugly side of Havana, both visually as with its themes and underlying comments. Some of the symbolism and underlying messages in the dialog are a bit too obvious, as if they were trying too hard, but this is perhaps the only real flaw in the movie its excellent story and directing of the movie. Don't know why the movie is often being regarded and treated as a comedy. It's above all an heavy drama but done in a light and more pleasant sort of way, but those are no reasons for me to regard this movie as a comedy. The movie uses the more European style and approach of the story and characters. So be sure what to expect when watching this movie. A great and relevant movie because of its themes, and I assume also a big step forward for gay-right and tolerance in Cuba. 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A charming film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    little_rhody
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How often do we get to see Cuban films here in America? How many Cuban films have a gay protagonist? Strawberry and Chocolate is a wonderful Cuban film that features a glimpse into Havana and the Cuban gay subculture juxtaposed against dedicated, communist college students. David is the college student who believes in the system. Diego is a gay writer who has friends in the art world. Nancy is stuck between the two worlds, and having difficulty coping. Through his association with the others, David receives an education he wouldn't get at the university. The film is about love and desire: love of country; love of art; love between men and women; love between men - romantic and platonic. Thank you Robert Redford and Miramax for bringing this to the States
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How did this ever get past the censor?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danngil
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At first I thought that this was a Latin version of a typical gay film that comes out of the U.S. I couldn't have been more wrong. It's really a charming film about friendship that's difficult to achieve. "Why does sex always get in the way?" David asks. In other words, it's as difficult for a gay and straight man to develop a friendship as it is for a straight man and woman. Sounds a bit like dating and marriage, doesn't it? It's even more difficult when a government and friends interfere. At the beginning I was afraid that Diego would actually seduce David and voil&agrave; we have the usual gay film that I find boring. Instead, I really got to like Diego, much the same way he eventually charms David. That's getting involved with characters in a movie. Excellent performances by the two leads. The other performance that is compelling is that of Nancy (Mirtha Ibarra). I first saw Mirtha Ibarra in Guantanamara, a film that followed this by a year. In both films, she plays the older woman that every young man fantasizes about. Where was Mirtha Ibarra when I was David's age? I don't know how, if the Cuban regime is supposed to be so oppressive that they allowed this film to be made. Perhaps they wanted to show the "Yanquis" that it's possible to be critical of the government and still love one's country. This is a film that I will see twice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    getting out to the street
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ruiresende84 (ruiresende84@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cinema is an art in itself and not a sum of arts. That is because it has specific things that can't be made alone by any other art. Now, what exactly can make cinema an art of its own is arguable but will always have something to do with passing anything through moving images: . storytelling . a mood, an atmosphere . fact all three are worth exploring. In Fresa y chocolate, the problem is there is an apparent mixture of all three, which can exist, but not like exposed in here. The device was clear and apparently effective: a simple story inside Story. never mind the simple story, it's the least important. The Story is the whole Cuba context. Go to the general, pick up an episode (that may represent or not, fact) and from there build the mood, the atmosphere. This last step was what failed. And it was for a non definition on the "eye" of the camera. By giving all the ingredients, all the passwords to the contained world (island) and to its specific context, it should have been shown. I've been to Cuba, there was not much lacking for me, i know what i didn't see in the picture, but by focusing on dialog (that could for its meaning come embedded on the mood) and by not having an eye for the street, for the people, for the city, the project lost a big deal. It had everything to be a film about a city. Story inside space, since the story we are told is clearly typical, one in many. it may have been political issues behind, and it is of great importance that this film could have been made, versing such locally heavy themes. But that's my main critic, Guti&eacute;rrez Alea had an excellent eye for portrait, and for placing stories in context, but he lacked the sense of the place, in terms of senses (modd, atmosphere). Even though a good document, worth watching, excellent character development, excellent performances also. Diego's house (and the dialogs that go with it) contain excellent underline thoughts, the dialogs are filled (i didn't read the original story) with messages, in a not so subtle way. Also a note for the excellent use of the color (very Cuban). My evaluation: 3/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    High sensitivity at the sight!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaffar-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is undoubtedly one of the greatest Cuban films of the last two decades, Tomas Gutierrez Alea "tit&oacute;n" was an excellent film director that took part in many of Cuban most awarded films ever and he's for so much in Cuban top 10 directors list. About Perugorria "Pichi" he's one Cuban most largely known actors of the time and has proved to be a never static actor, never stereotyped actor, ... The film aboard one big truth, not just a Cuban one but a latinamerican one, the macho men thinking way that has to do with everyone's way of interacting in society. The film captures a particular stage on Cuban history when homosexuality was mistreated even at high levels and the prejudice set against homosexuals was really strong, even more on men because of the imperant Latin "machismo". This is just a gift both for cinema lovers and for those that loves Cuba and Cubans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    it is a friendship between two different men in spite of their sexuality difference. Around 1979 Cuban governments's oppressions toward homosexuals.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    steuern
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fresa y chocolate I liked to watch Fresa y Chocolate; this is first Cuban movie I've seen. Fresa y Chocolate is a product of two directors, Tom&aacute;s Guti&eacute;rrez Alea and Juan Carlos Tab&iacute;o in 1993. Fresa y Chocolate was nominated in 1995 the best foreign film. During the production of this film the director Alea had cancer and for this reason Tab&iacute;o had to help him to complete the movie. Later 1996 Alea die. This movie expresses the oppression of Cuban government toward the homosexual and the conflict also the friendship within two different men. Around 1997 in Cuba,Diego (Jorge Perugorria ) the main character is a cultured gay and David (Vldimir Cruz) a young revolutionary college student. He is a naive and dogmatic. The story begins at a cheap hotel room where David and his sweetheart, Vivian tried to have first intimate experience together but ended up angry at each other, later Vivian marries to a much older man who is in the government office position. David, the wedding day feeling low come to an Ice cream shop near by school and over there David and Diego meet. At the begging, it was Diego's attempt to allure David but soon it change and in spite of their sexuality, these two different men establish a true friendship. Most of story take a place at Diego's apartment where full of things (art work, forbidden books, pictures...) for David's eye. It is a new and different world for David, a dogmatic and in a way an ignorant. Diego tells David about his anguish and problem toward the government. For him being homosexual hinder his work in Cuba and also his well being, too. However, David learns much about art and literature from Diego and moreover, he learn how to enjoy and savor life. The message of this movie is tolerance. No matter what is one's sexuality people have genuine heart. They have hope, dreams, and frustration that life brings us. I think this movie is worth to watch because Fresa y Chocolate gave me a chance to give a glance to Cuba, the country that I don't know yet. To me watching a good film lessens a tension of life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fresa y Chocolate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Adair
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Homosexuality is something that is not accepted in many countries, and this Cuban movie is based in this sentiment. The dramatic-comedy Strawberry and Chocolate was directed by Tom&aacute;s Guti&eacute;rrez Alea and Juan Carlos Tab&iacute;o, and was an adaptation of the story "The wolf, the forest, and the new man" by Senel Paz. This movie represents very well the sentiment against homosexuality that still exists. Vladimir Cruz plays the part of David, the protagonist (the "new man" in Paz's words), and Jorge Perugorr&iacute;a plays the part of Diego (the wolf). The plot begins in Havana with David and his failed attempt to make love to his girlfriend, Vivian. It continues later on Vivian's wedding day with another man, while David watches them from the background. Depressed, David goes to the ice cream stand and meets Diego, who is clearly homosexual. Diego invites him to his apartment, but David flees suddenly because Diego is very strange. He later returns to the apartment because he is under the pressure of his roommate, Manuel, to investigate "the queer." Friendship begins to grow between David and Diego. Diego is smart, knows a lot about art and culture, and teaches these things to his friend. The friendship between David and Nancy, one of Diego's friends, grows as well and they make love at the end of the movie. But, Diego is in trouble after sending a letter that ridicules the government for not accepting his art exhibition and, for this reason, the government kicks him out and he has to leave the country. The movie ends with a touching hug between Diego and David. I like the plot because it uses elements of comedy to demonstrate a serious theme, and I thing that this works well. There are two themes that clearly exist in this movie: friendship and tolerance. True friendship can only exist when two people accept each other as they are; not only physically, but on the inside as well. For example, friendship is nonexistent between Manuel and David because Manuel doesn't care about David's personality, rather his actions. By the end, David and Diego adore each other for all the qualities they have, and do not worry about physical things. Tolerance is something different and is important as well. Many people in Cuba (demonstrated in Manuel) and other countries can't change their thoughts about homosexuality because they are too strong and unmovable. David's tolerance for Diego grows during the progression of the movie and it is realized at the end with a hug between friends. The use of light works well to show the mood of the movie. The darkness at the beginning shows the feeling that they are doing something bad or dirty, and the brightness when David and Diego are in the hideout (Diego's apartment) at the end of the movie shows that things will be fine. The acting is good and adds to the movie. Sometimes, Perugorr&iacute;a's acting is too cheesy, but it works to show his strange character. Through Cruz's good acting, one can clearly see David's emotional growth with his new friendship with Diego, the strange guy. In reality, people do not accept a change from the norm, and this is true especially with homosexuality. Homosexuals still fight today in many countries for their rights, but many people still don't accept them. This movie shows us very well this feeling through drama but also with a few moments of humor. I would recommend this to my friends because it isn't too serious, but nonetheless has a moving message for the viewer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a good look at homosexuality in Cuba
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Knowing how the Cuban government suppressed homosexuality for so long, it's sort of surprising that they allowed a movie about it. But the movie ended up being quite good. Diego (Jorge Perugorria) is a student in 1979 Havana who hooks up with the aesthetic David (Vladimir Cruz), who turns out to be gay. Naturally, Diego is a little unnerved by this, but over time, he and David come to respect each other. One reason that "Strawberry and Chocolate" is especially good is because they never go overboard in trying to portray gay people. David is attracted to men, certainly, but he never does something like start dancing to a disco song suddenly. Quite an impressive movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
