<filme>
 <id>
  1201
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116992
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Marlene Dietrich: Shadow and Light (TV Movi
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Following the life of Marlene Dietrich through her films (including home movies) and interviews with family, friends, co-workers, acquaintances, and presumed lovers. From the cabaret scene ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Following the life of Marlene Dietrich through her films (including home movies) and interviews with family, friends, co-workers, acquaintances, and presumed lovers. From the cabaret scene in 1920's Berlin, silent films in Germany, her triumph in _The Blue Angel_ in 1930 (for which her screen test is included in this film), to Hollywood with Josef von Sternberg . The highest paid female star of her time, the luster dimmed by 1935. and in the later part of the decade she might be the most valuable actress in the world but also the most unemployable. But with _Destry Rides Again_ Marlene became a sex symbol who could play comedy and the most remarkable comeback in Hollywood was a reality. She was one of the most active entertainers of the allied troops during WW II. After the war movies were infrequent, but a new career on the stage continued for another 20 years, until she retired into seclusion for the last decade of her life.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Documentary
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   actress
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   five word title
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   colon in title
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   female singer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   german woman
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Chris Hunt
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   American Movie Classics (AMC)
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Marlene Dietrich
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Maria Riva
  </ator>
  <ator>
   David Riva
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews></reviews>
</filme>
