<filme>
 <id>
  1204
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0035446
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1942
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Ser ou N&atilde;o Ser
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  During the Nazi occupation of Poland, an acting troupe becomes embroiled in a Polish soldier's efforts to track down a German spy.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  In occupied Poland during WWII, a troupe of ham stage actors (led by Joseph Tura and his wife Maria) match wits with the Nazis. A spy has information which would be very damaging to the Polish resistance and they must prevent it's being delivered to the Germans.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   War
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   nazi
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   poland
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   acting troupe
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   actor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   polish resistance
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Ernst Lubitsch
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Melchior Lengyel
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Edwin Justus Mayer
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Carole Lombard
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jack Benny
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Robert Stack
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film that never should have been made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Applause Meter
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some topics lend themselves to satire; genocidal military dictatorships do not. This is perhaps one of the most offensive, ill-conceived movies ever produced in the name of public "entertainment." To portray Nazis as idiotic buffoons and to script in dialogue and insert one- liners about the comedic aspects of concentration campswell that's got to just be a laugh a minute. And here Jack Benny portrays a pretentious Polish actor, Joseph Tura, which gives Benny full license to present us with his comedy persona in full form. Tura, who craves greatness as Shakespeare's Hamlet is prime Benny, the smug, mocking, self-satisfied comedic fool only satisfied when he can make everyone else look foolish. So guess what?! THAT makes him smart. Got it? Hilarious! This film, Carole Lombard's last, is a sad coda to her sparkling career. Purportedly her husband Clark Gable urged her not to take the part of Maria Tura, but she liked the script?! The esteemed director Fritz Lang, half-Jewish, (his Jewish mother had converted to Catholicism) and an &eacute;migr&eacute; from Nazi Germany who fled that country just in time, should have known better. This movie was a disaster when it was made at the height of World War II, and more than 70 years later is still, to put it mildly, an embarrassment. No matter what Leonard Maltin thinks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Starts Well But Fizzles Out
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie begins in Warsaw, Poland in 1939, in the days just before the invasion by Germany and the USSR (though the movie disregards the latter). Though the threat of war is in the air, a theater company's actors and staff spend their time worrying and arguing over theatrical roles and their status in the company. Also, a young bomber pilot has his eye upon an actor's wife (who is an actress herself), and tries to enter an affair with her. The invasion comes. Most of the company has fled Poland, including the pilot, who has joined the Polish exile forces in Britain. However, the actor and his actress wife remain. A professor is sent from Britain to Poland to help the resistance there...but he becomes suspected as a double agent, and the pilot is sent to Poland to stop the professor's intended treachery. He warns the actors who are still there, and they in turn impersonate various Gestapo members to try to foil the professor. Unfortunately for the pilot, the husband he tried to cuckold is upset with him, which complicates things. And unfortunately, it makes everything too complicated and confusing, and ruins the rest of the movie. Also not helping was the joke about "Concentration Camp Gerhardt" which became irritating after being repeated a dozen times. Also, many scenes went on for far too long after they made their point. The movie is notable mainly for being a period piece; as a farce it dropped the ball.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hamlet in Holocaust !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Diya Dutta
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is perhaps one of the greatest Satire movie I've ever seen on this war genre. Jack Benny was hilarious and superb in this movie, and not to mention about the great work of the director who succeeded in kept you anticipating through out the movie without any chance of taking eyes off. The only sad parts I came to know that the Star couple of this movie as played Mr & Mrs Taura expired even before the Premiere of this movie. This one is a very old classic but wont appear to be slow or boring at any point of time during the play. I highly recommend viewers with a taste for World War or Holocaust to go for a change and enjoy this Satire which you wont regret ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shakespeare Does Hitler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A troupe of Polish actors impersonate Nazis in order to prevent the Polish underground from being captured. Jack Benny used to joke on radio and TV about his movie career, especially The Horn Blows at Midnight (1945). But he never joked about this film. Though it's got a serious subject right on the eve of WWII, it's still pretty funny, especially when Jack pulls his egotistical, great actor bit. With all the Heil Hitlers and Gestapo boys running around, it's sometimes hard to keep up with who's who. Nonetheless, it's a clever screenplay having an actors' troupe impersonate Nazi's. Aside from TV's Hogan's Heroes (1965-1971), I don't know of any other show that risked making fun of the murderous Third Reich. It's a pretty tricky topic to begin with, but the production crew pulls it off. Then there's Carole Lombard, on the eve of her tragic plane ride. But she's still delicious as heck. Plus, I could swear that silken gown she's got on for her tryst is all she's got on. My eyes were glued. Also, it's easy to catch a young, love-struck Robert Stack before he got out of the movie's second row and moved into the hard case cop on TV's The Untouchables (1959-1963). Note too, the unspoken Jewish subtext, with the names of many of the victims and Shylock's moving plea from Shakespeare. I don't know why the script made do with inference rather than a single overt mention of Nazism's virulent anti-Semitism. Maybe it's because that might sound like special pleading, regardless of the merits. Anyway, it's still a pretty funny movie, and remains an offbeat one-of-a-kind. Besides Benny had a much better film career than he wanted to admit.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To Be is To Be- To Be or Not to Be ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're looking for comedy, the 1983 remake of this film with Mel Brooks, Tim Mathieson, Anne Bancroft and Charles Durning is the film for you. That was absolutely hilarious. As for the original 1942 version, it is humorous, especially when you have Jack Benny playing the lead, but there are some moments of serious overtones. As the smitten lover, Robert Stack was incredibly wooden here. Perhaps, we can blame it on the fact that he was just beginning his career and given very little to say here. Sig Ruman is a standout as usual as Concentration Camp Earhardt, eagerly ready to blame his failings on Schultz. Benny and Carole Lombard provide the right chemistry as the Polish acting couple who eventually outwit the Nazis.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deft Delightful & Dangerously Hilarious Nazi Satire
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amplexuslotus
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one else but Ernst Lubitsch could have made To Be or Not to Be. That it's superb and sublime and witty and ingeniously funny cannot be emphasized enough. The film has a great script, direction and cinematography (Rudolph Mat&eacute;). While the entire cast shines, Lombard and Benny are absolutely stellar. It's a shame that Benny did not get matched with similarly genius director post-TBONTB is a real shame because with the right director and script he could have gone on to be a film star. Perhaps the fact that much of the story takes place in a theatre and then on the many theatre troupe's "stages" as they foil the Nazis throughout the story, nurtured Benny's own natural unique comedic talent in a way that his other films could not. And then there's Lombard. Carole Lombard was and still is imho, the best comedic actor other than Chaplin-Lloyd-Keaton-Dressler-Stanwyck. I don't find that the comedians of today can even come close to the previously mentioned comedians. Lombard and Benny play the most perfectly narcissistic clever power-couple seen anywhere in film or real life. That this was Lomabrd's final film before her tragic death (plane crash during a war bond tour) is sad for all of us. Her seduction of the dashing young Robert Stack's Lt. Sobinski and the evil double-agent, Professor Siletski (Stanley Ridges)is wonderful to watch. The petty banter between the egomaniacal husband and wife acting team, the Turas (Lombard and Benny) is equally delightful. Also worth mentioning is Lombard's maid, Anna (Maude Eburne) who has some great lines like, "What a husband doesn't know won't hurt his wife." While audiences in 1941/42 may not have been able to appreciate this satire,it's worth noting that Roberto Benigni's film Life Is Beautiful (which has a higher IMDb rating) was also criticized for mixing humor in a story about the holocaust when screened at Cannes in 1997. Some people were outraged that Benigni would include comedy in the concentration camp scenes. But the film went on to win several top awards. Another film which comes to mind mixing war/genocide with comedy in a very skillful way is Arthur Penn's, Little Big Man (1970-based on a novel of the same name by Thomas Berger). I don't know if there were any criticisms of comedy being used in a movie about the genocide of Native Americans but in my opinion, Little Big Man, although a different style than TBONTB, is a superior comedy about a very serious and tragic time in America's history. I believe these knee jerk reactions to films which show or allude to barbaric shameful historic events are without merit. For it's art which brings light to not only these man-made horrors but illuminates the beauty and power of the human spirit. Lubitsch's To Be or Not to Be should not be over-looked. It's one of the finest examples of comedy from any era. Plus you get to watch Lombard and Benny at their most sublime.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " A laugh is nothing to be sneezed at ".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Recently reading an article on the Timeout website about movies which failed badly on there original release that deserve to be re-appraise,I noticed in amongst the more recent titles was a Screwball Comedy from the 40's involving Nazi's.Being interested in seeing how a movie made during WWII could look at the then current events in a comedic light,I decided to import the only DVD edition of the film I could find,and get set to find out how LOL got put together with Nazi. The plot: As a Polish theatre company starts to gather ideas for a new production called "Gastarpo",that along with being a satirical play about the Nazis,is also going to be lead by the company's lead actor Joseph Tura playing a lookalike version of Hitler.With only a few more performances of Hamlet to go before Gastrarpo enters production,Tura starts to experience terrible anxiety attacks due to his wife, (fellow stage performer Maria Tura) getting bundles of flowers from a secret admirer and also due to one individual always being in the audience and each time publicly stepping out as soon as Joseph gets on stage.Unbeknownst to Joseph,the man who is sending his wife flowers and the audience member who keeps walking out are both the same person:Lieut. Stanislav Sobinski.Since setting their eyes on each other for the first time,Maria and Sobinski have both fallen deeply head over heels for each other.As Maria and Stanislav's affair intensifies,and the theatre company also starts its countdown for the premier of Gastarpo,Hitler invades Poland and destroys anything which threatens to mock the authority of the Nazis.Whilst Joseph,Maria and the rest of the actors go into hiding to join the resistances,Sobinski rushes to join the British Polish division of the RAF to do everything he can to fight for his country.Returning to London after a recent raid,Sobinski and a group of fellow solider's meet a leading polish Resistance leader called Prof. Siletsky.Proudly saying that he is about to return to Poland to continue his support for the Resistance,Siletsky offers all of the soldiers a chance to each give him a message that he can pass on to their love ones.Thinking that this may be his only chance to give her a message,Sobinski ask Siletsky to give a message to Poland's most famous actress,who Siletsky has never heard of before!..After having given him the message,Sobinski begins to fear that Siletsky may not be all that he seems. View on the film: Writing the screenplay a few months before America got fully involved in WWII,screenwriter's Melchior Lengyel,Edwin Justus Mayer and Ernst Lubitsch strike a remarkable balance of never playing down the grim situation that the characters are involved in,whilst also having each of the cast members deliver still-razor sharp satirical dialogue,that is truly ahead of its time in its design to prick the pompous,authoritarian image of Hitler and the Nazis.From the moment that Hitler cancel's the production of Gastarpo,the writer's show act-or Joseph Tura, (played by a great,egotistical Jack Benny) to be a two bit old ham,whose dream is to use the role of Hitler so that he can soon become a Lawrance Oliveria style legend in the theatre world.Allowing the tremendous,screwball dialogue to move at lightning speed,co-writer/director Ernst Lubitsch also displays real skill in knowing when to slow the exchanges down,to focus on the troubles that the character's are caught in,with the scenes that revel Prof. Siletsky, (played by a wonderfully deranged Stanley Ridgers) true intension being filmed in tight angles,amped up in tension Werner R. Heymann's terrific score.For what would tragically be her final role,stunning Carole Lombard gives a blistering performance as Joseph's less than faithful wife Maria.Along with smoothly handling the film's dramatic moments,as Maria begins to get closer to finding out Siletsky's true intension's,Lombard also clearly displays a true joy for delivering zingers left,right and centre,from doing everything to keep her husband's suspicion's of an affair at bay,to wooing everyone in sight of her figure-hugging dress in an attempt to escape from a Nazi bedroom,which all help to make Lombard's curtain call performance one that will continue to be applauded for years to come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1942, this comedy is set in Warsaw, during the Polish occupation by the Nazis. It unashamedly pokes fun both at Hitler and the Nazi regime, and also the vanity of actors. It tells the story of a Polish acting troupe, including husband and wife couple Joseph and Maria Tura (Jack Benny and Carole Lombard, in her last film), who find themselves tangled up in a plot to stop the Nazis obtaining valuable information. It does not sound like a recipe for a hilarious comedybut that is what this film is. Joseph Tura considers himself an acclaimed Shakespearean actor, and during the film he plays Hamlet (badly!) Maria, his beautiful and feisty wife, catches the eye of Lieutenant Stanislav Sobinski. Joseph is suspicious and jealous, but they soon have greater problems to worry about By the time this film was released, Germany was sweeping across Europe. Also, tragically, Carole Lombard had died in a plane crash, and possibly as a result, the film was initially seen as being in bad taste, and was not appreciated by audiences. Over the years however, it has gained a reputation as a classic comedy, and I think the humour still stands up well for modern viewers. The story is convoluted, but easy enough to follow. The real joy in this film however, is the incredibly funny script and the way that the cast (even the minor players are terrific) deliver their lines. The dialogue fizzes along nicely and there is also plenty of visual comedy. The tragedy and heartache caused by the occupation of Poland is duly acknowledged, and I don't think the film was attempting to make light of the situation at all. One scene in particular shows members of the Nazi army jumping out of a plane to their certain death, on the orders of Hitler, given by radio transmission. The film also shows the burning buildings and the many homeless and grieving families who suffered as a result of Hitler's regime. The subplot is great  concerning Joseph's vexation at his wife's flirtation with a handsome Lieutenant; and said Lieutenant's infatuation with the slightly Maria (flightly she may be, but she is also possessed of a great bravery). Carole Lombard looks beautiful and so full of life and vitality throughout  which in hindsight underlines the sadness of her death at such terrible circumstances at the age of 33. Still, this is how she should be remembered  at her very best. It's a shame that this film turned out to be her swan song, but what a swan song it is. Benny is also terrific; I have never seen any of his work before, but will certainly be searching out more of it! This is one of the American Film Institute's 100 Funniest Comedies, and it deserves its place on that list. Despite the sombre subject matter, this is a film well worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's often overshadowed by The Great Dictator, which preceded it by two years and was technically the first American WW-II themed comedy, but To Be Or Not To Be deserves the honor both for being the first comedy to refer to Hitler and Nazi Germany by name, and also for being made while the US was very much an active side in the war. It's still incredibly funny, but it's much more impressive, almost shockingly so, when you realize that it was made while Hitler was alive, and just how powerful it was back then. Carole Lombard is show-stoppingly terrific, and it's probably the best place to see her talent on display, since sadly it was her final performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Have you seen The Great Dictator or The Producers? Watch this and you'll see where they got the idea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nomoons11
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one is just one funny farce all the way through. Doeesn't hurt Jack Benny is as good as he's ever been on film. To me this was his film. Lombard is in this a lot but she's not near as good as Jack Benny. This film is about 90% comedy and 10% serious. The opening scene comes up and immediately you start to see where Charlie Chaplin and Mel brooks got their inspiration. They got it from a fictitious Polish acting troop trying to put on a farcical play about Hitler (of course Mr. Brooks remade this but it's not in the same league). Not a lot has to be said about this, you just have to watch it and see. An all around funny film. I can see why it has high user ratings in here. Really good stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film that never should have been made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Applause Meter
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some topics lend themselves to satire; genocidal military dictatorships do not. This is perhaps one of the most offensive, ill-conceived movies ever produced in the name of public "entertainment." To portray Nazis as idiotic buffoons and to script in dialogue and insert one- liners about the comedic aspects of concentration campswell that's got to just be a laugh a minute. And here Jack Benny portrays a pretentious Polish actor, Joseph Tura, which gives Benny full license to present us with his comedy persona in full form. Tura, who craves greatness as Shakespeare's Hamlet is prime Benny, the smug, mocking, self-satisfied comedic fool only satisfied when he can make everyone else look foolish. So guess what?! THAT makes him smart. Got it? Hilarious! This film, Carole Lombard's last, is a sad coda to her sparkling career. Purportedly her husband Clark Gable urged her not to take the part of Maria Tura, but she liked the script?! The esteemed director Fritz Lang, half-Jewish, (his Jewish mother had converted to Catholicism) and an &eacute;migr&eacute; from Nazi Germany who fled that country just in time, should have known better. This movie was a disaster when it was made at the height of World War II, and more than 70 years later is still, to put it mildly, an embarrassment. No matter what Leonard Maltin thinks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Starts Well But Fizzles Out
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie begins in Warsaw, Poland in 1939, in the days just before the invasion by Germany and the USSR (though the movie disregards the latter). Though the threat of war is in the air, a theater company's actors and staff spend their time worrying and arguing over theatrical roles and their status in the company. Also, a young bomber pilot has his eye upon an actor's wife (who is an actress herself), and tries to enter an affair with her. The invasion comes. Most of the company has fled Poland, including the pilot, who has joined the Polish exile forces in Britain. However, the actor and his actress wife remain. A professor is sent from Britain to Poland to help the resistance there...but he becomes suspected as a double agent, and the pilot is sent to Poland to stop the professor's intended treachery. He warns the actors who are still there, and they in turn impersonate various Gestapo members to try to foil the professor. Unfortunately for the pilot, the husband he tried to cuckold is upset with him, which complicates things. And unfortunately, it makes everything too complicated and confusing, and ruins the rest of the movie. Also not helping was the joke about "Concentration Camp Gerhardt" which became irritating after being repeated a dozen times. Also, many scenes went on for far too long after they made their point. The movie is notable mainly for being a period piece; as a farce it dropped the ball.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hamlet in Holocaust !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Diya Dutta
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is perhaps one of the greatest Satire movie I've ever seen on this war genre. Jack Benny was hilarious and superb in this movie, and not to mention about the great work of the director who succeeded in kept you anticipating through out the movie without any chance of taking eyes off. The only sad parts I came to know that the Star couple of this movie as played Mr & Mrs Taura expired even before the Premiere of this movie. This one is a very old classic but wont appear to be slow or boring at any point of time during the play. I highly recommend viewers with a taste for World War or Holocaust to go for a change and enjoy this Satire which you wont regret ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shakespeare Does Hitler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A troupe of Polish actors impersonate Nazis in order to prevent the Polish underground from being captured. Jack Benny used to joke on radio and TV about his movie career, especially The Horn Blows at Midnight (1945). But he never joked about this film. Though it's got a serious subject right on the eve of WWII, it's still pretty funny, especially when Jack pulls his egotistical, great actor bit. With all the Heil Hitlers and Gestapo boys running around, it's sometimes hard to keep up with who's who. Nonetheless, it's a clever screenplay having an actors' troupe impersonate Nazi's. Aside from TV's Hogan's Heroes (1965-1971), I don't know of any other show that risked making fun of the murderous Third Reich. It's a pretty tricky topic to begin with, but the production crew pulls it off. Then there's Carole Lombard, on the eve of her tragic plane ride. But she's still delicious as heck. Plus, I could swear that silken gown she's got on for her tryst is all she's got on. My eyes were glued. Also, it's easy to catch a young, love-struck Robert Stack before he got out of the movie's second row and moved into the hard case cop on TV's The Untouchables (1959-1963). Note too, the unspoken Jewish subtext, with the names of many of the victims and Shylock's moving plea from Shakespeare. I don't know why the script made do with inference rather than a single overt mention of Nazism's virulent anti-Semitism. Maybe it's because that might sound like special pleading, regardless of the merits. Anyway, it's still a pretty funny movie, and remains an offbeat one-of-a-kind. Besides Benny had a much better film career than he wanted to admit.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To Be is To Be- To Be or Not to Be ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're looking for comedy, the 1983 remake of this film with Mel Brooks, Tim Mathieson, Anne Bancroft and Charles Durning is the film for you. That was absolutely hilarious. As for the original 1942 version, it is humorous, especially when you have Jack Benny playing the lead, but there are some moments of serious overtones. As the smitten lover, Robert Stack was incredibly wooden here. Perhaps, we can blame it on the fact that he was just beginning his career and given very little to say here. Sig Ruman is a standout as usual as Concentration Camp Earhardt, eagerly ready to blame his failings on Schultz. Benny and Carole Lombard provide the right chemistry as the Polish acting couple who eventually outwit the Nazis.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deft Delightful & Dangerously Hilarious Nazi Satire
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amplexuslotus
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one else but Ernst Lubitsch could have made To Be or Not to Be. That it's superb and sublime and witty and ingeniously funny cannot be emphasized enough. The film has a great script, direction and cinematography (Rudolph Mat&eacute;). While the entire cast shines, Lombard and Benny are absolutely stellar. It's a shame that Benny did not get matched with similarly genius director post-TBONTB is a real shame because with the right director and script he could have gone on to be a film star. Perhaps the fact that much of the story takes place in a theatre and then on the many theatre troupe's "stages" as they foil the Nazis throughout the story, nurtured Benny's own natural unique comedic talent in a way that his other films could not. And then there's Lombard. Carole Lombard was and still is imho, the best comedic actor other than Chaplin-Lloyd-Keaton-Dressler-Stanwyck. I don't find that the comedians of today can even come close to the previously mentioned comedians. Lombard and Benny play the most perfectly narcissistic clever power-couple seen anywhere in film or real life. That this was Lomabrd's final film before her tragic death (plane crash during a war bond tour) is sad for all of us. Her seduction of the dashing young Robert Stack's Lt. Sobinski and the evil double-agent, Professor Siletski (Stanley Ridges)is wonderful to watch. The petty banter between the egomaniacal husband and wife acting team, the Turas (Lombard and Benny) is equally delightful. Also worth mentioning is Lombard's maid, Anna (Maude Eburne) who has some great lines like, "What a husband doesn't know won't hurt his wife." While audiences in 1941/42 may not have been able to appreciate this satire,it's worth noting that Roberto Benigni's film Life Is Beautiful (which has a higher IMDb rating) was also criticized for mixing humor in a story about the holocaust when screened at Cannes in 1997. Some people were outraged that Benigni would include comedy in the concentration camp scenes. But the film went on to win several top awards. Another film which comes to mind mixing war/genocide with comedy in a very skillful way is Arthur Penn's, Little Big Man (1970-based on a novel of the same name by Thomas Berger). I don't know if there were any criticisms of comedy being used in a movie about the genocide of Native Americans but in my opinion, Little Big Man, although a different style than TBONTB, is a superior comedy about a very serious and tragic time in America's history. I believe these knee jerk reactions to films which show or allude to barbaric shameful historic events are without merit. For it's art which brings light to not only these man-made horrors but illuminates the beauty and power of the human spirit. Lubitsch's To Be or Not to Be should not be over-looked. It's one of the finest examples of comedy from any era. Plus you get to watch Lombard and Benny at their most sublime.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " A laugh is nothing to be sneezed at ".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Recently reading an article on the Timeout website about movies which failed badly on there original release that deserve to be re-appraise,I noticed in amongst the more recent titles was a Screwball Comedy from the 40's involving Nazi's.Being interested in seeing how a movie made during WWII could look at the then current events in a comedic light,I decided to import the only DVD edition of the film I could find,and get set to find out how LOL got put together with Nazi. The plot: As a Polish theatre company starts to gather ideas for a new production called "Gastarpo",that along with being a satirical play about the Nazis,is also going to be lead by the company's lead actor Joseph Tura playing a lookalike version of Hitler.With only a few more performances of Hamlet to go before Gastrarpo enters production,Tura starts to experience terrible anxiety attacks due to his wife, (fellow stage performer Maria Tura) getting bundles of flowers from a secret admirer and also due to one individual always being in the audience and each time publicly stepping out as soon as Joseph gets on stage.Unbeknownst to Joseph,the man who is sending his wife flowers and the audience member who keeps walking out are both the same person:Lieut. Stanislav Sobinski.Since setting their eyes on each other for the first time,Maria and Sobinski have both fallen deeply head over heels for each other.As Maria and Stanislav's affair intensifies,and the theatre company also starts its countdown for the premier of Gastarpo,Hitler invades Poland and destroys anything which threatens to mock the authority of the Nazis.Whilst Joseph,Maria and the rest of the actors go into hiding to join the resistances,Sobinski rushes to join the British Polish division of the RAF to do everything he can to fight for his country.Returning to London after a recent raid,Sobinski and a group of fellow solider's meet a leading polish Resistance leader called Prof. Siletsky.Proudly saying that he is about to return to Poland to continue his support for the Resistance,Siletsky offers all of the soldiers a chance to each give him a message that he can pass on to their love ones.Thinking that this may be his only chance to give her a message,Sobinski ask Siletsky to give a message to Poland's most famous actress,who Siletsky has never heard of before!..After having given him the message,Sobinski begins to fear that Siletsky may not be all that he seems. View on the film: Writing the screenplay a few months before America got fully involved in WWII,screenwriter's Melchior Lengyel,Edwin Justus Mayer and Ernst Lubitsch strike a remarkable balance of never playing down the grim situation that the characters are involved in,whilst also having each of the cast members deliver still-razor sharp satirical dialogue,that is truly ahead of its time in its design to prick the pompous,authoritarian image of Hitler and the Nazis.From the moment that Hitler cancel's the production of Gastarpo,the writer's show act-or Joseph Tura, (played by a great,egotistical Jack Benny) to be a two bit old ham,whose dream is to use the role of Hitler so that he can soon become a Lawrance Oliveria style legend in the theatre world.Allowing the tremendous,screwball dialogue to move at lightning speed,co-writer/director Ernst Lubitsch also displays real skill in knowing when to slow the exchanges down,to focus on the troubles that the character's are caught in,with the scenes that revel Prof. Siletsky, (played by a wonderfully deranged Stanley Ridgers) true intension being filmed in tight angles,amped up in tension Werner R. Heymann's terrific score.For what would tragically be her final role,stunning Carole Lombard gives a blistering performance as Joseph's less than faithful wife Maria.Along with smoothly handling the film's dramatic moments,as Maria begins to get closer to finding out Siletsky's true intension's,Lombard also clearly displays a true joy for delivering zingers left,right and centre,from doing everything to keep her husband's suspicion's of an affair at bay,to wooing everyone in sight of her figure-hugging dress in an attempt to escape from a Nazi bedroom,which all help to make Lombard's curtain call performance one that will continue to be applauded for years to come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1942, this comedy is set in Warsaw, during the Polish occupation by the Nazis. It unashamedly pokes fun both at Hitler and the Nazi regime, and also the vanity of actors. It tells the story of a Polish acting troupe, including husband and wife couple Joseph and Maria Tura (Jack Benny and Carole Lombard, in her last film), who find themselves tangled up in a plot to stop the Nazis obtaining valuable information. It does not sound like a recipe for a hilarious comedybut that is what this film is. Joseph Tura considers himself an acclaimed Shakespearean actor, and during the film he plays Hamlet (badly!) Maria, his beautiful and feisty wife, catches the eye of Lieutenant Stanislav Sobinski. Joseph is suspicious and jealous, but they soon have greater problems to worry about By the time this film was released, Germany was sweeping across Europe. Also, tragically, Carole Lombard had died in a plane crash, and possibly as a result, the film was initially seen as being in bad taste, and was not appreciated by audiences. Over the years however, it has gained a reputation as a classic comedy, and I think the humour still stands up well for modern viewers. The story is convoluted, but easy enough to follow. The real joy in this film however, is the incredibly funny script and the way that the cast (even the minor players are terrific) deliver their lines. The dialogue fizzes along nicely and there is also plenty of visual comedy. The tragedy and heartache caused by the occupation of Poland is duly acknowledged, and I don't think the film was attempting to make light of the situation at all. One scene in particular shows members of the Nazi army jumping out of a plane to their certain death, on the orders of Hitler, given by radio transmission. The film also shows the burning buildings and the many homeless and grieving families who suffered as a result of Hitler's regime. The subplot is great  concerning Joseph's vexation at his wife's flirtation with a handsome Lieutenant; and said Lieutenant's infatuation with the slightly Maria (flightly she may be, but she is also possessed of a great bravery). Carole Lombard looks beautiful and so full of life and vitality throughout  which in hindsight underlines the sadness of her death at such terrible circumstances at the age of 33. Still, this is how she should be remembered  at her very best. It's a shame that this film turned out to be her swan song, but what a swan song it is. Benny is also terrific; I have never seen any of his work before, but will certainly be searching out more of it! This is one of the American Film Institute's 100 Funniest Comedies, and it deserves its place on that list. Despite the sombre subject matter, this is a film well worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's often overshadowed by The Great Dictator, which preceded it by two years and was technically the first American WW-II themed comedy, but To Be Or Not To Be deserves the honor both for being the first comedy to refer to Hitler and Nazi Germany by name, and also for being made while the US was very much an active side in the war. It's still incredibly funny, but it's much more impressive, almost shockingly so, when you realize that it was made while Hitler was alive, and just how powerful it was back then. Carole Lombard is show-stoppingly terrific, and it's probably the best place to see her talent on display, since sadly it was her final performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Have you seen The Great Dictator or The Producers? Watch this and you'll see where they got the idea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nomoons11
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one is just one funny farce all the way through. Doeesn't hurt Jack Benny is as good as he's ever been on film. To me this was his film. Lombard is in this a lot but she's not near as good as Jack Benny. This film is about 90% comedy and 10% serious. The opening scene comes up and immediately you start to see where Charlie Chaplin and Mel brooks got their inspiration. They got it from a fictitious Polish acting troop trying to put on a farcical play about Hitler (of course Mr. Brooks remade this but it's not in the same league). Not a lot has to be said about this, you just have to watch it and see. An all around funny film. I can see why it has high user ratings in here. Really good stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film that never should have been made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Applause Meter
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some topics lend themselves to satire; genocidal military dictatorships do not. This is perhaps one of the most offensive, ill-conceived movies ever produced in the name of public "entertainment." To portray Nazis as idiotic buffoons and to script in dialogue and insert one- liners about the comedic aspects of concentration campswell that's got to just be a laugh a minute. And here Jack Benny portrays a pretentious Polish actor, Joseph Tura, which gives Benny full license to present us with his comedy persona in full form. Tura, who craves greatness as Shakespeare's Hamlet is prime Benny, the smug, mocking, self-satisfied comedic fool only satisfied when he can make everyone else look foolish. So guess what?! THAT makes him smart. Got it? Hilarious! This film, Carole Lombard's last, is a sad coda to her sparkling career. Purportedly her husband Clark Gable urged her not to take the part of Maria Tura, but she liked the script?! The esteemed director Fritz Lang, half-Jewish, (his Jewish mother had converted to Catholicism) and an &eacute;migr&eacute; from Nazi Germany who fled that country just in time, should have known better. This movie was a disaster when it was made at the height of World War II, and more than 70 years later is still, to put it mildly, an embarrassment. No matter what Leonard Maltin thinks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Starts Well But Fizzles Out
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie begins in Warsaw, Poland in 1939, in the days just before the invasion by Germany and the USSR (though the movie disregards the latter). Though the threat of war is in the air, a theater company's actors and staff spend their time worrying and arguing over theatrical roles and their status in the company. Also, a young bomber pilot has his eye upon an actor's wife (who is an actress herself), and tries to enter an affair with her. The invasion comes. Most of the company has fled Poland, including the pilot, who has joined the Polish exile forces in Britain. However, the actor and his actress wife remain. A professor is sent from Britain to Poland to help the resistance there...but he becomes suspected as a double agent, and the pilot is sent to Poland to stop the professor's intended treachery. He warns the actors who are still there, and they in turn impersonate various Gestapo members to try to foil the professor. Unfortunately for the pilot, the husband he tried to cuckold is upset with him, which complicates things. And unfortunately, it makes everything too complicated and confusing, and ruins the rest of the movie. Also not helping was the joke about "Concentration Camp Gerhardt" which became irritating after being repeated a dozen times. Also, many scenes went on for far too long after they made their point. The movie is notable mainly for being a period piece; as a farce it dropped the ball.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hamlet in Holocaust !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Diya Dutta
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is perhaps one of the greatest Satire movie I've ever seen on this war genre. Jack Benny was hilarious and superb in this movie, and not to mention about the great work of the director who succeeded in kept you anticipating through out the movie without any chance of taking eyes off. The only sad parts I came to know that the Star couple of this movie as played Mr & Mrs Taura expired even before the Premiere of this movie. This one is a very old classic but wont appear to be slow or boring at any point of time during the play. I highly recommend viewers with a taste for World War or Holocaust to go for a change and enjoy this Satire which you wont regret ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shakespeare Does Hitler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A troupe of Polish actors impersonate Nazis in order to prevent the Polish underground from being captured. Jack Benny used to joke on radio and TV about his movie career, especially The Horn Blows at Midnight (1945). But he never joked about this film. Though it's got a serious subject right on the eve of WWII, it's still pretty funny, especially when Jack pulls his egotistical, great actor bit. With all the Heil Hitlers and Gestapo boys running around, it's sometimes hard to keep up with who's who. Nonetheless, it's a clever screenplay having an actors' troupe impersonate Nazi's. Aside from TV's Hogan's Heroes (1965-1971), I don't know of any other show that risked making fun of the murderous Third Reich. It's a pretty tricky topic to begin with, but the production crew pulls it off. Then there's Carole Lombard, on the eve of her tragic plane ride. But she's still delicious as heck. Plus, I could swear that silken gown she's got on for her tryst is all she's got on. My eyes were glued. Also, it's easy to catch a young, love-struck Robert Stack before he got out of the movie's second row and moved into the hard case cop on TV's The Untouchables (1959-1963). Note too, the unspoken Jewish subtext, with the names of many of the victims and Shylock's moving plea from Shakespeare. I don't know why the script made do with inference rather than a single overt mention of Nazism's virulent anti-Semitism. Maybe it's because that might sound like special pleading, regardless of the merits. Anyway, it's still a pretty funny movie, and remains an offbeat one-of-a-kind. Besides Benny had a much better film career than he wanted to admit.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To Be is To Be- To Be or Not to Be ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're looking for comedy, the 1983 remake of this film with Mel Brooks, Tim Mathieson, Anne Bancroft and Charles Durning is the film for you. That was absolutely hilarious. As for the original 1942 version, it is humorous, especially when you have Jack Benny playing the lead, but there are some moments of serious overtones. As the smitten lover, Robert Stack was incredibly wooden here. Perhaps, we can blame it on the fact that he was just beginning his career and given very little to say here. Sig Ruman is a standout as usual as Concentration Camp Earhardt, eagerly ready to blame his failings on Schultz. Benny and Carole Lombard provide the right chemistry as the Polish acting couple who eventually outwit the Nazis.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deft Delightful & Dangerously Hilarious Nazi Satire
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amplexuslotus
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one else but Ernst Lubitsch could have made To Be or Not to Be. That it's superb and sublime and witty and ingeniously funny cannot be emphasized enough. The film has a great script, direction and cinematography (Rudolph Mat&eacute;). While the entire cast shines, Lombard and Benny are absolutely stellar. It's a shame that Benny did not get matched with similarly genius director post-TBONTB is a real shame because with the right director and script he could have gone on to be a film star. Perhaps the fact that much of the story takes place in a theatre and then on the many theatre troupe's "stages" as they foil the Nazis throughout the story, nurtured Benny's own natural unique comedic talent in a way that his other films could not. And then there's Lombard. Carole Lombard was and still is imho, the best comedic actor other than Chaplin-Lloyd-Keaton-Dressler-Stanwyck. I don't find that the comedians of today can even come close to the previously mentioned comedians. Lombard and Benny play the most perfectly narcissistic clever power-couple seen anywhere in film or real life. That this was Lomabrd's final film before her tragic death (plane crash during a war bond tour) is sad for all of us. Her seduction of the dashing young Robert Stack's Lt. Sobinski and the evil double-agent, Professor Siletski (Stanley Ridges)is wonderful to watch. The petty banter between the egomaniacal husband and wife acting team, the Turas (Lombard and Benny) is equally delightful. Also worth mentioning is Lombard's maid, Anna (Maude Eburne) who has some great lines like, "What a husband doesn't know won't hurt his wife." While audiences in 1941/42 may not have been able to appreciate this satire,it's worth noting that Roberto Benigni's film Life Is Beautiful (which has a higher IMDb rating) was also criticized for mixing humor in a story about the holocaust when screened at Cannes in 1997. Some people were outraged that Benigni would include comedy in the concentration camp scenes. But the film went on to win several top awards. Another film which comes to mind mixing war/genocide with comedy in a very skillful way is Arthur Penn's, Little Big Man (1970-based on a novel of the same name by Thomas Berger). I don't know if there were any criticisms of comedy being used in a movie about the genocide of Native Americans but in my opinion, Little Big Man, although a different style than TBONTB, is a superior comedy about a very serious and tragic time in America's history. I believe these knee jerk reactions to films which show or allude to barbaric shameful historic events are without merit. For it's art which brings light to not only these man-made horrors but illuminates the beauty and power of the human spirit. Lubitsch's To Be or Not to Be should not be over-looked. It's one of the finest examples of comedy from any era. Plus you get to watch Lombard and Benny at their most sublime.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " A laugh is nothing to be sneezed at ".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Recently reading an article on the Timeout website about movies which failed badly on there original release that deserve to be re-appraise,I noticed in amongst the more recent titles was a Screwball Comedy from the 40's involving Nazi's.Being interested in seeing how a movie made during WWII could look at the then current events in a comedic light,I decided to import the only DVD edition of the film I could find,and get set to find out how LOL got put together with Nazi. The plot: As a Polish theatre company starts to gather ideas for a new production called "Gastarpo",that along with being a satirical play about the Nazis,is also going to be lead by the company's lead actor Joseph Tura playing a lookalike version of Hitler.With only a few more performances of Hamlet to go before Gastrarpo enters production,Tura starts to experience terrible anxiety attacks due to his wife, (fellow stage performer Maria Tura) getting bundles of flowers from a secret admirer and also due to one individual always being in the audience and each time publicly stepping out as soon as Joseph gets on stage.Unbeknownst to Joseph,the man who is sending his wife flowers and the audience member who keeps walking out are both the same person:Lieut. Stanislav Sobinski.Since setting their eyes on each other for the first time,Maria and Sobinski have both fallen deeply head over heels for each other.As Maria and Stanislav's affair intensifies,and the theatre company also starts its countdown for the premier of Gastarpo,Hitler invades Poland and destroys anything which threatens to mock the authority of the Nazis.Whilst Joseph,Maria and the rest of the actors go into hiding to join the resistances,Sobinski rushes to join the British Polish division of the RAF to do everything he can to fight for his country.Returning to London after a recent raid,Sobinski and a group of fellow solider's meet a leading polish Resistance leader called Prof. Siletsky.Proudly saying that he is about to return to Poland to continue his support for the Resistance,Siletsky offers all of the soldiers a chance to each give him a message that he can pass on to their love ones.Thinking that this may be his only chance to give her a message,Sobinski ask Siletsky to give a message to Poland's most famous actress,who Siletsky has never heard of before!..After having given him the message,Sobinski begins to fear that Siletsky may not be all that he seems. View on the film: Writing the screenplay a few months before America got fully involved in WWII,screenwriter's Melchior Lengyel,Edwin Justus Mayer and Ernst Lubitsch strike a remarkable balance of never playing down the grim situation that the characters are involved in,whilst also having each of the cast members deliver still-razor sharp satirical dialogue,that is truly ahead of its time in its design to prick the pompous,authoritarian image of Hitler and the Nazis.From the moment that Hitler cancel's the production of Gastarpo,the writer's show act-or Joseph Tura, (played by a great,egotistical Jack Benny) to be a two bit old ham,whose dream is to use the role of Hitler so that he can soon become a Lawrance Oliveria style legend in the theatre world.Allowing the tremendous,screwball dialogue to move at lightning speed,co-writer/director Ernst Lubitsch also displays real skill in knowing when to slow the exchanges down,to focus on the troubles that the character's are caught in,with the scenes that revel Prof. Siletsky, (played by a wonderfully deranged Stanley Ridgers) true intension being filmed in tight angles,amped up in tension Werner R. Heymann's terrific score.For what would tragically be her final role,stunning Carole Lombard gives a blistering performance as Joseph's less than faithful wife Maria.Along with smoothly handling the film's dramatic moments,as Maria begins to get closer to finding out Siletsky's true intension's,Lombard also clearly displays a true joy for delivering zingers left,right and centre,from doing everything to keep her husband's suspicion's of an affair at bay,to wooing everyone in sight of her figure-hugging dress in an attempt to escape from a Nazi bedroom,which all help to make Lombard's curtain call performance one that will continue to be applauded for years to come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1942, this comedy is set in Warsaw, during the Polish occupation by the Nazis. It unashamedly pokes fun both at Hitler and the Nazi regime, and also the vanity of actors. It tells the story of a Polish acting troupe, including husband and wife couple Joseph and Maria Tura (Jack Benny and Carole Lombard, in her last film), who find themselves tangled up in a plot to stop the Nazis obtaining valuable information. It does not sound like a recipe for a hilarious comedybut that is what this film is. Joseph Tura considers himself an acclaimed Shakespearean actor, and during the film he plays Hamlet (badly!) Maria, his beautiful and feisty wife, catches the eye of Lieutenant Stanislav Sobinski. Joseph is suspicious and jealous, but they soon have greater problems to worry about By the time this film was released, Germany was sweeping across Europe. Also, tragically, Carole Lombard had died in a plane crash, and possibly as a result, the film was initially seen as being in bad taste, and was not appreciated by audiences. Over the years however, it has gained a reputation as a classic comedy, and I think the humour still stands up well for modern viewers. The story is convoluted, but easy enough to follow. The real joy in this film however, is the incredibly funny script and the way that the cast (even the minor players are terrific) deliver their lines. The dialogue fizzes along nicely and there is also plenty of visual comedy. The tragedy and heartache caused by the occupation of Poland is duly acknowledged, and I don't think the film was attempting to make light of the situation at all. One scene in particular shows members of the Nazi army jumping out of a plane to their certain death, on the orders of Hitler, given by radio transmission. The film also shows the burning buildings and the many homeless and grieving families who suffered as a result of Hitler's regime. The subplot is great  concerning Joseph's vexation at his wife's flirtation with a handsome Lieutenant; and said Lieutenant's infatuation with the slightly Maria (flightly she may be, but she is also possessed of a great bravery). Carole Lombard looks beautiful and so full of life and vitality throughout  which in hindsight underlines the sadness of her death at such terrible circumstances at the age of 33. Still, this is how she should be remembered  at her very best. It's a shame that this film turned out to be her swan song, but what a swan song it is. Benny is also terrific; I have never seen any of his work before, but will certainly be searching out more of it! This is one of the American Film Institute's 100 Funniest Comedies, and it deserves its place on that list. Despite the sombre subject matter, this is a film well worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's often overshadowed by The Great Dictator, which preceded it by two years and was technically the first American WW-II themed comedy, but To Be Or Not To Be deserves the honor both for being the first comedy to refer to Hitler and Nazi Germany by name, and also for being made while the US was very much an active side in the war. It's still incredibly funny, but it's much more impressive, almost shockingly so, when you realize that it was made while Hitler was alive, and just how powerful it was back then. Carole Lombard is show-stoppingly terrific, and it's probably the best place to see her talent on display, since sadly it was her final performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Have you seen The Great Dictator or The Producers? Watch this and you'll see where they got the idea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nomoons11
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one is just one funny farce all the way through. Doeesn't hurt Jack Benny is as good as he's ever been on film. To me this was his film. Lombard is in this a lot but she's not near as good as Jack Benny. This film is about 90% comedy and 10% serious. The opening scene comes up and immediately you start to see where Charlie Chaplin and Mel brooks got their inspiration. They got it from a fictitious Polish acting troop trying to put on a farcical play about Hitler (of course Mr. Brooks remade this but it's not in the same league). Not a lot has to be said about this, you just have to watch it and see. An all around funny film. I can see why it has high user ratings in here. Really good stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film that never should have been made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Applause Meter
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some topics lend themselves to satire; genocidal military dictatorships do not. This is perhaps one of the most offensive, ill-conceived movies ever produced in the name of public "entertainment." To portray Nazis as idiotic buffoons and to script in dialogue and insert one- liners about the comedic aspects of concentration campswell that's got to just be a laugh a minute. And here Jack Benny portrays a pretentious Polish actor, Joseph Tura, which gives Benny full license to present us with his comedy persona in full form. Tura, who craves greatness as Shakespeare's Hamlet is prime Benny, the smug, mocking, self-satisfied comedic fool only satisfied when he can make everyone else look foolish. So guess what?! THAT makes him smart. Got it? Hilarious! This film, Carole Lombard's last, is a sad coda to her sparkling career. Purportedly her husband Clark Gable urged her not to take the part of Maria Tura, but she liked the script?! The esteemed director Fritz Lang, half-Jewish, (his Jewish mother had converted to Catholicism) and an &eacute;migr&eacute; from Nazi Germany who fled that country just in time, should have known better. This movie was a disaster when it was made at the height of World War II, and more than 70 years later is still, to put it mildly, an embarrassment. No matter what Leonard Maltin thinks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Starts Well But Fizzles Out
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie begins in Warsaw, Poland in 1939, in the days just before the invasion by Germany and the USSR (though the movie disregards the latter). Though the threat of war is in the air, a theater company's actors and staff spend their time worrying and arguing over theatrical roles and their status in the company. Also, a young bomber pilot has his eye upon an actor's wife (who is an actress herself), and tries to enter an affair with her. The invasion comes. Most of the company has fled Poland, including the pilot, who has joined the Polish exile forces in Britain. However, the actor and his actress wife remain. A professor is sent from Britain to Poland to help the resistance there...but he becomes suspected as a double agent, and the pilot is sent to Poland to stop the professor's intended treachery. He warns the actors who are still there, and they in turn impersonate various Gestapo members to try to foil the professor. Unfortunately for the pilot, the husband he tried to cuckold is upset with him, which complicates things. And unfortunately, it makes everything too complicated and confusing, and ruins the rest of the movie. Also not helping was the joke about "Concentration Camp Gerhardt" which became irritating after being repeated a dozen times. Also, many scenes went on for far too long after they made their point. The movie is notable mainly for being a period piece; as a farce it dropped the ball.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hamlet in Holocaust !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Diya Dutta
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is perhaps one of the greatest Satire movie I've ever seen on this war genre. Jack Benny was hilarious and superb in this movie, and not to mention about the great work of the director who succeeded in kept you anticipating through out the movie without any chance of taking eyes off. The only sad parts I came to know that the Star couple of this movie as played Mr & Mrs Taura expired even before the Premiere of this movie. This one is a very old classic but wont appear to be slow or boring at any point of time during the play. I highly recommend viewers with a taste for World War or Holocaust to go for a change and enjoy this Satire which you wont regret ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shakespeare Does Hitler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A troupe of Polish actors impersonate Nazis in order to prevent the Polish underground from being captured. Jack Benny used to joke on radio and TV about his movie career, especially The Horn Blows at Midnight (1945). But he never joked about this film. Though it's got a serious subject right on the eve of WWII, it's still pretty funny, especially when Jack pulls his egotistical, great actor bit. With all the Heil Hitlers and Gestapo boys running around, it's sometimes hard to keep up with who's who. Nonetheless, it's a clever screenplay having an actors' troupe impersonate Nazi's. Aside from TV's Hogan's Heroes (1965-1971), I don't know of any other show that risked making fun of the murderous Third Reich. It's a pretty tricky topic to begin with, but the production crew pulls it off. Then there's Carole Lombard, on the eve of her tragic plane ride. But she's still delicious as heck. Plus, I could swear that silken gown she's got on for her tryst is all she's got on. My eyes were glued. Also, it's easy to catch a young, love-struck Robert Stack before he got out of the movie's second row and moved into the hard case cop on TV's The Untouchables (1959-1963). Note too, the unspoken Jewish subtext, with the names of many of the victims and Shylock's moving plea from Shakespeare. I don't know why the script made do with inference rather than a single overt mention of Nazism's virulent anti-Semitism. Maybe it's because that might sound like special pleading, regardless of the merits. Anyway, it's still a pretty funny movie, and remains an offbeat one-of-a-kind. Besides Benny had a much better film career than he wanted to admit.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To Be is To Be- To Be or Not to Be ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're looking for comedy, the 1983 remake of this film with Mel Brooks, Tim Mathieson, Anne Bancroft and Charles Durning is the film for you. That was absolutely hilarious. As for the original 1942 version, it is humorous, especially when you have Jack Benny playing the lead, but there are some moments of serious overtones. As the smitten lover, Robert Stack was incredibly wooden here. Perhaps, we can blame it on the fact that he was just beginning his career and given very little to say here. Sig Ruman is a standout as usual as Concentration Camp Earhardt, eagerly ready to blame his failings on Schultz. Benny and Carole Lombard provide the right chemistry as the Polish acting couple who eventually outwit the Nazis.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deft Delightful & Dangerously Hilarious Nazi Satire
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amplexuslotus
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one else but Ernst Lubitsch could have made To Be or Not to Be. That it's superb and sublime and witty and ingeniously funny cannot be emphasized enough. The film has a great script, direction and cinematography (Rudolph Mat&eacute;). While the entire cast shines, Lombard and Benny are absolutely stellar. It's a shame that Benny did not get matched with similarly genius director post-TBONTB is a real shame because with the right director and script he could have gone on to be a film star. Perhaps the fact that much of the story takes place in a theatre and then on the many theatre troupe's "stages" as they foil the Nazis throughout the story, nurtured Benny's own natural unique comedic talent in a way that his other films could not. And then there's Lombard. Carole Lombard was and still is imho, the best comedic actor other than Chaplin-Lloyd-Keaton-Dressler-Stanwyck. I don't find that the comedians of today can even come close to the previously mentioned comedians. Lombard and Benny play the most perfectly narcissistic clever power-couple seen anywhere in film or real life. That this was Lomabrd's final film before her tragic death (plane crash during a war bond tour) is sad for all of us. Her seduction of the dashing young Robert Stack's Lt. Sobinski and the evil double-agent, Professor Siletski (Stanley Ridges)is wonderful to watch. The petty banter between the egomaniacal husband and wife acting team, the Turas (Lombard and Benny) is equally delightful. Also worth mentioning is Lombard's maid, Anna (Maude Eburne) who has some great lines like, "What a husband doesn't know won't hurt his wife." While audiences in 1941/42 may not have been able to appreciate this satire,it's worth noting that Roberto Benigni's film Life Is Beautiful (which has a higher IMDb rating) was also criticized for mixing humor in a story about the holocaust when screened at Cannes in 1997. Some people were outraged that Benigni would include comedy in the concentration camp scenes. But the film went on to win several top awards. Another film which comes to mind mixing war/genocide with comedy in a very skillful way is Arthur Penn's, Little Big Man (1970-based on a novel of the same name by Thomas Berger). I don't know if there were any criticisms of comedy being used in a movie about the genocide of Native Americans but in my opinion, Little Big Man, although a different style than TBONTB, is a superior comedy about a very serious and tragic time in America's history. I believe these knee jerk reactions to films which show or allude to barbaric shameful historic events are without merit. For it's art which brings light to not only these man-made horrors but illuminates the beauty and power of the human spirit. Lubitsch's To Be or Not to Be should not be over-looked. It's one of the finest examples of comedy from any era. Plus you get to watch Lombard and Benny at their most sublime.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " A laugh is nothing to be sneezed at ".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Recently reading an article on the Timeout website about movies which failed badly on there original release that deserve to be re-appraise,I noticed in amongst the more recent titles was a Screwball Comedy from the 40's involving Nazi's.Being interested in seeing how a movie made during WWII could look at the then current events in a comedic light,I decided to import the only DVD edition of the film I could find,and get set to find out how LOL got put together with Nazi. The plot: As a Polish theatre company starts to gather ideas for a new production called "Gastarpo",that along with being a satirical play about the Nazis,is also going to be lead by the company's lead actor Joseph Tura playing a lookalike version of Hitler.With only a few more performances of Hamlet to go before Gastrarpo enters production,Tura starts to experience terrible anxiety attacks due to his wife, (fellow stage performer Maria Tura) getting bundles of flowers from a secret admirer and also due to one individual always being in the audience and each time publicly stepping out as soon as Joseph gets on stage.Unbeknownst to Joseph,the man who is sending his wife flowers and the audience member who keeps walking out are both the same person:Lieut. Stanislav Sobinski.Since setting their eyes on each other for the first time,Maria and Sobinski have both fallen deeply head over heels for each other.As Maria and Stanislav's affair intensifies,and the theatre company also starts its countdown for the premier of Gastarpo,Hitler invades Poland and destroys anything which threatens to mock the authority of the Nazis.Whilst Joseph,Maria and the rest of the actors go into hiding to join the resistances,Sobinski rushes to join the British Polish division of the RAF to do everything he can to fight for his country.Returning to London after a recent raid,Sobinski and a group of fellow solider's meet a leading polish Resistance leader called Prof. Siletsky.Proudly saying that he is about to return to Poland to continue his support for the Resistance,Siletsky offers all of the soldiers a chance to each give him a message that he can pass on to their love ones.Thinking that this may be his only chance to give her a message,Sobinski ask Siletsky to give a message to Poland's most famous actress,who Siletsky has never heard of before!..After having given him the message,Sobinski begins to fear that Siletsky may not be all that he seems. View on the film: Writing the screenplay a few months before America got fully involved in WWII,screenwriter's Melchior Lengyel,Edwin Justus Mayer and Ernst Lubitsch strike a remarkable balance of never playing down the grim situation that the characters are involved in,whilst also having each of the cast members deliver still-razor sharp satirical dialogue,that is truly ahead of its time in its design to prick the pompous,authoritarian image of Hitler and the Nazis.From the moment that Hitler cancel's the production of Gastarpo,the writer's show act-or Joseph Tura, (played by a great,egotistical Jack Benny) to be a two bit old ham,whose dream is to use the role of Hitler so that he can soon become a Lawrance Oliveria style legend in the theatre world.Allowing the tremendous,screwball dialogue to move at lightning speed,co-writer/director Ernst Lubitsch also displays real skill in knowing when to slow the exchanges down,to focus on the troubles that the character's are caught in,with the scenes that revel Prof. Siletsky, (played by a wonderfully deranged Stanley Ridgers) true intension being filmed in tight angles,amped up in tension Werner R. Heymann's terrific score.For what would tragically be her final role,stunning Carole Lombard gives a blistering performance as Joseph's less than faithful wife Maria.Along with smoothly handling the film's dramatic moments,as Maria begins to get closer to finding out Siletsky's true intension's,Lombard also clearly displays a true joy for delivering zingers left,right and centre,from doing everything to keep her husband's suspicion's of an affair at bay,to wooing everyone in sight of her figure-hugging dress in an attempt to escape from a Nazi bedroom,which all help to make Lombard's curtain call performance one that will continue to be applauded for years to come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1942, this comedy is set in Warsaw, during the Polish occupation by the Nazis. It unashamedly pokes fun both at Hitler and the Nazi regime, and also the vanity of actors. It tells the story of a Polish acting troupe, including husband and wife couple Joseph and Maria Tura (Jack Benny and Carole Lombard, in her last film), who find themselves tangled up in a plot to stop the Nazis obtaining valuable information. It does not sound like a recipe for a hilarious comedybut that is what this film is. Joseph Tura considers himself an acclaimed Shakespearean actor, and during the film he plays Hamlet (badly!) Maria, his beautiful and feisty wife, catches the eye of Lieutenant Stanislav Sobinski. Joseph is suspicious and jealous, but they soon have greater problems to worry about By the time this film was released, Germany was sweeping across Europe. Also, tragically, Carole Lombard had died in a plane crash, and possibly as a result, the film was initially seen as being in bad taste, and was not appreciated by audiences. Over the years however, it has gained a reputation as a classic comedy, and I think the humour still stands up well for modern viewers. The story is convoluted, but easy enough to follow. The real joy in this film however, is the incredibly funny script and the way that the cast (even the minor players are terrific) deliver their lines. The dialogue fizzes along nicely and there is also plenty of visual comedy. The tragedy and heartache caused by the occupation of Poland is duly acknowledged, and I don't think the film was attempting to make light of the situation at all. One scene in particular shows members of the Nazi army jumping out of a plane to their certain death, on the orders of Hitler, given by radio transmission. The film also shows the burning buildings and the many homeless and grieving families who suffered as a result of Hitler's regime. The subplot is great  concerning Joseph's vexation at his wife's flirtation with a handsome Lieutenant; and said Lieutenant's infatuation with the slightly Maria (flightly she may be, but she is also possessed of a great bravery). Carole Lombard looks beautiful and so full of life and vitality throughout  which in hindsight underlines the sadness of her death at such terrible circumstances at the age of 33. Still, this is how she should be remembered  at her very best. It's a shame that this film turned out to be her swan song, but what a swan song it is. Benny is also terrific; I have never seen any of his work before, but will certainly be searching out more of it! This is one of the American Film Institute's 100 Funniest Comedies, and it deserves its place on that list. Despite the sombre subject matter, this is a film well worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's often overshadowed by The Great Dictator, which preceded it by two years and was technically the first American WW-II themed comedy, but To Be Or Not To Be deserves the honor both for being the first comedy to refer to Hitler and Nazi Germany by name, and also for being made while the US was very much an active side in the war. It's still incredibly funny, but it's much more impressive, almost shockingly so, when you realize that it was made while Hitler was alive, and just how powerful it was back then. Carole Lombard is show-stoppingly terrific, and it's probably the best place to see her talent on display, since sadly it was her final performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Have you seen The Great Dictator or The Producers? Watch this and you'll see where they got the idea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nomoons11
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one is just one funny farce all the way through. Doeesn't hurt Jack Benny is as good as he's ever been on film. To me this was his film. Lombard is in this a lot but she's not near as good as Jack Benny. This film is about 90% comedy and 10% serious. The opening scene comes up and immediately you start to see where Charlie Chaplin and Mel brooks got their inspiration. They got it from a fictitious Polish acting troop trying to put on a farcical play about Hitler (of course Mr. Brooks remade this but it's not in the same league). Not a lot has to be said about this, you just have to watch it and see. An all around funny film. I can see why it has high user ratings in here. Really good stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film that never should have been made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Applause Meter
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some topics lend themselves to satire; genocidal military dictatorships do not. This is perhaps one of the most offensive, ill-conceived movies ever produced in the name of public "entertainment." To portray Nazis as idiotic buffoons and to script in dialogue and insert one- liners about the comedic aspects of concentration campswell that's got to just be a laugh a minute. And here Jack Benny portrays a pretentious Polish actor, Joseph Tura, which gives Benny full license to present us with his comedy persona in full form. Tura, who craves greatness as Shakespeare's Hamlet is prime Benny, the smug, mocking, self-satisfied comedic fool only satisfied when he can make everyone else look foolish. So guess what?! THAT makes him smart. Got it? Hilarious! This film, Carole Lombard's last, is a sad coda to her sparkling career. Purportedly her husband Clark Gable urged her not to take the part of Maria Tura, but she liked the script?! The esteemed director Fritz Lang, half-Jewish, (his Jewish mother had converted to Catholicism) and an &eacute;migr&eacute; from Nazi Germany who fled that country just in time, should have known better. This movie was a disaster when it was made at the height of World War II, and more than 70 years later is still, to put it mildly, an embarrassment. No matter what Leonard Maltin thinks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Starts Well But Fizzles Out
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie begins in Warsaw, Poland in 1939, in the days just before the invasion by Germany and the USSR (though the movie disregards the latter). Though the threat of war is in the air, a theater company's actors and staff spend their time worrying and arguing over theatrical roles and their status in the company. Also, a young bomber pilot has his eye upon an actor's wife (who is an actress herself), and tries to enter an affair with her. The invasion comes. Most of the company has fled Poland, including the pilot, who has joined the Polish exile forces in Britain. However, the actor and his actress wife remain. A professor is sent from Britain to Poland to help the resistance there...but he becomes suspected as a double agent, and the pilot is sent to Poland to stop the professor's intended treachery. He warns the actors who are still there, and they in turn impersonate various Gestapo members to try to foil the professor. Unfortunately for the pilot, the husband he tried to cuckold is upset with him, which complicates things. And unfortunately, it makes everything too complicated and confusing, and ruins the rest of the movie. Also not helping was the joke about "Concentration Camp Gerhardt" which became irritating after being repeated a dozen times. Also, many scenes went on for far too long after they made their point. The movie is notable mainly for being a period piece; as a farce it dropped the ball.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hamlet in Holocaust !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Diya Dutta
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is perhaps one of the greatest Satire movie I've ever seen on this war genre. Jack Benny was hilarious and superb in this movie, and not to mention about the great work of the director who succeeded in kept you anticipating through out the movie without any chance of taking eyes off. The only sad parts I came to know that the Star couple of this movie as played Mr & Mrs Taura expired even before the Premiere of this movie. This one is a very old classic but wont appear to be slow or boring at any point of time during the play. I highly recommend viewers with a taste for World War or Holocaust to go for a change and enjoy this Satire which you wont regret ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shakespeare Does Hitler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A troupe of Polish actors impersonate Nazis in order to prevent the Polish underground from being captured. Jack Benny used to joke on radio and TV about his movie career, especially The Horn Blows at Midnight (1945). But he never joked about this film. Though it's got a serious subject right on the eve of WWII, it's still pretty funny, especially when Jack pulls his egotistical, great actor bit. With all the Heil Hitlers and Gestapo boys running around, it's sometimes hard to keep up with who's who. Nonetheless, it's a clever screenplay having an actors' troupe impersonate Nazi's. Aside from TV's Hogan's Heroes (1965-1971), I don't know of any other show that risked making fun of the murderous Third Reich. It's a pretty tricky topic to begin with, but the production crew pulls it off. Then there's Carole Lombard, on the eve of her tragic plane ride. But she's still delicious as heck. Plus, I could swear that silken gown she's got on for her tryst is all she's got on. My eyes were glued. Also, it's easy to catch a young, love-struck Robert Stack before he got out of the movie's second row and moved into the hard case cop on TV's The Untouchables (1959-1963). Note too, the unspoken Jewish subtext, with the names of many of the victims and Shylock's moving plea from Shakespeare. I don't know why the script made do with inference rather than a single overt mention of Nazism's virulent anti-Semitism. Maybe it's because that might sound like special pleading, regardless of the merits. Anyway, it's still a pretty funny movie, and remains an offbeat one-of-a-kind. Besides Benny had a much better film career than he wanted to admit.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To Be is To Be- To Be or Not to Be ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're looking for comedy, the 1983 remake of this film with Mel Brooks, Tim Mathieson, Anne Bancroft and Charles Durning is the film for you. That was absolutely hilarious. As for the original 1942 version, it is humorous, especially when you have Jack Benny playing the lead, but there are some moments of serious overtones. As the smitten lover, Robert Stack was incredibly wooden here. Perhaps, we can blame it on the fact that he was just beginning his career and given very little to say here. Sig Ruman is a standout as usual as Concentration Camp Earhardt, eagerly ready to blame his failings on Schultz. Benny and Carole Lombard provide the right chemistry as the Polish acting couple who eventually outwit the Nazis.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deft Delightful & Dangerously Hilarious Nazi Satire
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amplexuslotus
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one else but Ernst Lubitsch could have made To Be or Not to Be. That it's superb and sublime and witty and ingeniously funny cannot be emphasized enough. The film has a great script, direction and cinematography (Rudolph Mat&eacute;). While the entire cast shines, Lombard and Benny are absolutely stellar. It's a shame that Benny did not get matched with similarly genius director post-TBONTB is a real shame because with the right director and script he could have gone on to be a film star. Perhaps the fact that much of the story takes place in a theatre and then on the many theatre troupe's "stages" as they foil the Nazis throughout the story, nurtured Benny's own natural unique comedic talent in a way that his other films could not. And then there's Lombard. Carole Lombard was and still is imho, the best comedic actor other than Chaplin-Lloyd-Keaton-Dressler-Stanwyck. I don't find that the comedians of today can even come close to the previously mentioned comedians. Lombard and Benny play the most perfectly narcissistic clever power-couple seen anywhere in film or real life. That this was Lomabrd's final film before her tragic death (plane crash during a war bond tour) is sad for all of us. Her seduction of the dashing young Robert Stack's Lt. Sobinski and the evil double-agent, Professor Siletski (Stanley Ridges)is wonderful to watch. The petty banter between the egomaniacal husband and wife acting team, the Turas (Lombard and Benny) is equally delightful. Also worth mentioning is Lombard's maid, Anna (Maude Eburne) who has some great lines like, "What a husband doesn't know won't hurt his wife." While audiences in 1941/42 may not have been able to appreciate this satire,it's worth noting that Roberto Benigni's film Life Is Beautiful (which has a higher IMDb rating) was also criticized for mixing humor in a story about the holocaust when screened at Cannes in 1997. Some people were outraged that Benigni would include comedy in the concentration camp scenes. But the film went on to win several top awards. Another film which comes to mind mixing war/genocide with comedy in a very skillful way is Arthur Penn's, Little Big Man (1970-based on a novel of the same name by Thomas Berger). I don't know if there were any criticisms of comedy being used in a movie about the genocide of Native Americans but in my opinion, Little Big Man, although a different style than TBONTB, is a superior comedy about a very serious and tragic time in America's history. I believe these knee jerk reactions to films which show or allude to barbaric shameful historic events are without merit. For it's art which brings light to not only these man-made horrors but illuminates the beauty and power of the human spirit. Lubitsch's To Be or Not to Be should not be over-looked. It's one of the finest examples of comedy from any era. Plus you get to watch Lombard and Benny at their most sublime.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " A laugh is nothing to be sneezed at ".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Recently reading an article on the Timeout website about movies which failed badly on there original release that deserve to be re-appraise,I noticed in amongst the more recent titles was a Screwball Comedy from the 40's involving Nazi's.Being interested in seeing how a movie made during WWII could look at the then current events in a comedic light,I decided to import the only DVD edition of the film I could find,and get set to find out how LOL got put together with Nazi. The plot: As a Polish theatre company starts to gather ideas for a new production called "Gastarpo",that along with being a satirical play about the Nazis,is also going to be lead by the company's lead actor Joseph Tura playing a lookalike version of Hitler.With only a few more performances of Hamlet to go before Gastrarpo enters production,Tura starts to experience terrible anxiety attacks due to his wife, (fellow stage performer Maria Tura) getting bundles of flowers from a secret admirer and also due to one individual always being in the audience and each time publicly stepping out as soon as Joseph gets on stage.Unbeknownst to Joseph,the man who is sending his wife flowers and the audience member who keeps walking out are both the same person:Lieut. Stanislav Sobinski.Since setting their eyes on each other for the first time,Maria and Sobinski have both fallen deeply head over heels for each other.As Maria and Stanislav's affair intensifies,and the theatre company also starts its countdown for the premier of Gastarpo,Hitler invades Poland and destroys anything which threatens to mock the authority of the Nazis.Whilst Joseph,Maria and the rest of the actors go into hiding to join the resistances,Sobinski rushes to join the British Polish division of the RAF to do everything he can to fight for his country.Returning to London after a recent raid,Sobinski and a group of fellow solider's meet a leading polish Resistance leader called Prof. Siletsky.Proudly saying that he is about to return to Poland to continue his support for the Resistance,Siletsky offers all of the soldiers a chance to each give him a message that he can pass on to their love ones.Thinking that this may be his only chance to give her a message,Sobinski ask Siletsky to give a message to Poland's most famous actress,who Siletsky has never heard of before!..After having given him the message,Sobinski begins to fear that Siletsky may not be all that he seems. View on the film: Writing the screenplay a few months before America got fully involved in WWII,screenwriter's Melchior Lengyel,Edwin Justus Mayer and Ernst Lubitsch strike a remarkable balance of never playing down the grim situation that the characters are involved in,whilst also having each of the cast members deliver still-razor sharp satirical dialogue,that is truly ahead of its time in its design to prick the pompous,authoritarian image of Hitler and the Nazis.From the moment that Hitler cancel's the production of Gastarpo,the writer's show act-or Joseph Tura, (played by a great,egotistical Jack Benny) to be a two bit old ham,whose dream is to use the role of Hitler so that he can soon become a Lawrance Oliveria style legend in the theatre world.Allowing the tremendous,screwball dialogue to move at lightning speed,co-writer/director Ernst Lubitsch also displays real skill in knowing when to slow the exchanges down,to focus on the troubles that the character's are caught in,with the scenes that revel Prof. Siletsky, (played by a wonderfully deranged Stanley Ridgers) true intension being filmed in tight angles,amped up in tension Werner R. Heymann's terrific score.For what would tragically be her final role,stunning Carole Lombard gives a blistering performance as Joseph's less than faithful wife Maria.Along with smoothly handling the film's dramatic moments,as Maria begins to get closer to finding out Siletsky's true intension's,Lombard also clearly displays a true joy for delivering zingers left,right and centre,from doing everything to keep her husband's suspicion's of an affair at bay,to wooing everyone in sight of her figure-hugging dress in an attempt to escape from a Nazi bedroom,which all help to make Lombard's curtain call performance one that will continue to be applauded for years to come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1942, this comedy is set in Warsaw, during the Polish occupation by the Nazis. It unashamedly pokes fun both at Hitler and the Nazi regime, and also the vanity of actors. It tells the story of a Polish acting troupe, including husband and wife couple Joseph and Maria Tura (Jack Benny and Carole Lombard, in her last film), who find themselves tangled up in a plot to stop the Nazis obtaining valuable information. It does not sound like a recipe for a hilarious comedybut that is what this film is. Joseph Tura considers himself an acclaimed Shakespearean actor, and during the film he plays Hamlet (badly!) Maria, his beautiful and feisty wife, catches the eye of Lieutenant Stanislav Sobinski. Joseph is suspicious and jealous, but they soon have greater problems to worry about By the time this film was released, Germany was sweeping across Europe. Also, tragically, Carole Lombard had died in a plane crash, and possibly as a result, the film was initially seen as being in bad taste, and was not appreciated by audiences. Over the years however, it has gained a reputation as a classic comedy, and I think the humour still stands up well for modern viewers. The story is convoluted, but easy enough to follow. The real joy in this film however, is the incredibly funny script and the way that the cast (even the minor players are terrific) deliver their lines. The dialogue fizzes along nicely and there is also plenty of visual comedy. The tragedy and heartache caused by the occupation of Poland is duly acknowledged, and I don't think the film was attempting to make light of the situation at all. One scene in particular shows members of the Nazi army jumping out of a plane to their certain death, on the orders of Hitler, given by radio transmission. The film also shows the burning buildings and the many homeless and grieving families who suffered as a result of Hitler's regime. The subplot is great  concerning Joseph's vexation at his wife's flirtation with a handsome Lieutenant; and said Lieutenant's infatuation with the slightly Maria (flightly she may be, but she is also possessed of a great bravery). Carole Lombard looks beautiful and so full of life and vitality throughout  which in hindsight underlines the sadness of her death at such terrible circumstances at the age of 33. Still, this is how she should be remembered  at her very best. It's a shame that this film turned out to be her swan song, but what a swan song it is. Benny is also terrific; I have never seen any of his work before, but will certainly be searching out more of it! This is one of the American Film Institute's 100 Funniest Comedies, and it deserves its place on that list. Despite the sombre subject matter, this is a film well worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's often overshadowed by The Great Dictator, which preceded it by two years and was technically the first American WW-II themed comedy, but To Be Or Not To Be deserves the honor both for being the first comedy to refer to Hitler and Nazi Germany by name, and also for being made while the US was very much an active side in the war. It's still incredibly funny, but it's much more impressive, almost shockingly so, when you realize that it was made while Hitler was alive, and just how powerful it was back then. Carole Lombard is show-stoppingly terrific, and it's probably the best place to see her talent on display, since sadly it was her final performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Have you seen The Great Dictator or The Producers? Watch this and you'll see where they got the idea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nomoons11
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one is just one funny farce all the way through. Doeesn't hurt Jack Benny is as good as he's ever been on film. To me this was his film. Lombard is in this a lot but she's not near as good as Jack Benny. This film is about 90% comedy and 10% serious. The opening scene comes up and immediately you start to see where Charlie Chaplin and Mel brooks got their inspiration. They got it from a fictitious Polish acting troop trying to put on a farcical play about Hitler (of course Mr. Brooks remade this but it's not in the same league). Not a lot has to be said about this, you just have to watch it and see. An all around funny film. I can see why it has high user ratings in here. Really good stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film that never should have been made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Applause Meter
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some topics lend themselves to satire; genocidal military dictatorships do not. This is perhaps one of the most offensive, ill-conceived movies ever produced in the name of public "entertainment." To portray Nazis as idiotic buffoons and to script in dialogue and insert one- liners about the comedic aspects of concentration campswell that's got to just be a laugh a minute. And here Jack Benny portrays a pretentious Polish actor, Joseph Tura, which gives Benny full license to present us with his comedy persona in full form. Tura, who craves greatness as Shakespeare's Hamlet is prime Benny, the smug, mocking, self-satisfied comedic fool only satisfied when he can make everyone else look foolish. So guess what?! THAT makes him smart. Got it? Hilarious! This film, Carole Lombard's last, is a sad coda to her sparkling career. Purportedly her husband Clark Gable urged her not to take the part of Maria Tura, but she liked the script?! The esteemed director Fritz Lang, half-Jewish, (his Jewish mother had converted to Catholicism) and an &eacute;migr&eacute; from Nazi Germany who fled that country just in time, should have known better. This movie was a disaster when it was made at the height of World War II, and more than 70 years later is still, to put it mildly, an embarrassment. No matter what Leonard Maltin thinks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Starts Well But Fizzles Out
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie begins in Warsaw, Poland in 1939, in the days just before the invasion by Germany and the USSR (though the movie disregards the latter). Though the threat of war is in the air, a theater company's actors and staff spend their time worrying and arguing over theatrical roles and their status in the company. Also, a young bomber pilot has his eye upon an actor's wife (who is an actress herself), and tries to enter an affair with her. The invasion comes. Most of the company has fled Poland, including the pilot, who has joined the Polish exile forces in Britain. However, the actor and his actress wife remain. A professor is sent from Britain to Poland to help the resistance there...but he becomes suspected as a double agent, and the pilot is sent to Poland to stop the professor's intended treachery. He warns the actors who are still there, and they in turn impersonate various Gestapo members to try to foil the professor. Unfortunately for the pilot, the husband he tried to cuckold is upset with him, which complicates things. And unfortunately, it makes everything too complicated and confusing, and ruins the rest of the movie. Also not helping was the joke about "Concentration Camp Gerhardt" which became irritating after being repeated a dozen times. Also, many scenes went on for far too long after they made their point. The movie is notable mainly for being a period piece; as a farce it dropped the ball.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hamlet in Holocaust !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Diya Dutta
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is perhaps one of the greatest Satire movie I've ever seen on this war genre. Jack Benny was hilarious and superb in this movie, and not to mention about the great work of the director who succeeded in kept you anticipating through out the movie without any chance of taking eyes off. The only sad parts I came to know that the Star couple of this movie as played Mr & Mrs Taura expired even before the Premiere of this movie. This one is a very old classic but wont appear to be slow or boring at any point of time during the play. I highly recommend viewers with a taste for World War or Holocaust to go for a change and enjoy this Satire which you wont regret ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shakespeare Does Hitler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A troupe of Polish actors impersonate Nazis in order to prevent the Polish underground from being captured. Jack Benny used to joke on radio and TV about his movie career, especially The Horn Blows at Midnight (1945). But he never joked about this film. Though it's got a serious subject right on the eve of WWII, it's still pretty funny, especially when Jack pulls his egotistical, great actor bit. With all the Heil Hitlers and Gestapo boys running around, it's sometimes hard to keep up with who's who. Nonetheless, it's a clever screenplay having an actors' troupe impersonate Nazi's. Aside from TV's Hogan's Heroes (1965-1971), I don't know of any other show that risked making fun of the murderous Third Reich. It's a pretty tricky topic to begin with, but the production crew pulls it off. Then there's Carole Lombard, on the eve of her tragic plane ride. But she's still delicious as heck. Plus, I could swear that silken gown she's got on for her tryst is all she's got on. My eyes were glued. Also, it's easy to catch a young, love-struck Robert Stack before he got out of the movie's second row and moved into the hard case cop on TV's The Untouchables (1959-1963). Note too, the unspoken Jewish subtext, with the names of many of the victims and Shylock's moving plea from Shakespeare. I don't know why the script made do with inference rather than a single overt mention of Nazism's virulent anti-Semitism. Maybe it's because that might sound like special pleading, regardless of the merits. Anyway, it's still a pretty funny movie, and remains an offbeat one-of-a-kind. Besides Benny had a much better film career than he wanted to admit.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To Be is To Be- To Be or Not to Be ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're looking for comedy, the 1983 remake of this film with Mel Brooks, Tim Mathieson, Anne Bancroft and Charles Durning is the film for you. That was absolutely hilarious. As for the original 1942 version, it is humorous, especially when you have Jack Benny playing the lead, but there are some moments of serious overtones. As the smitten lover, Robert Stack was incredibly wooden here. Perhaps, we can blame it on the fact that he was just beginning his career and given very little to say here. Sig Ruman is a standout as usual as Concentration Camp Earhardt, eagerly ready to blame his failings on Schultz. Benny and Carole Lombard provide the right chemistry as the Polish acting couple who eventually outwit the Nazis.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deft Delightful & Dangerously Hilarious Nazi Satire
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amplexuslotus
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one else but Ernst Lubitsch could have made To Be or Not to Be. That it's superb and sublime and witty and ingeniously funny cannot be emphasized enough. The film has a great script, direction and cinematography (Rudolph Mat&eacute;). While the entire cast shines, Lombard and Benny are absolutely stellar. It's a shame that Benny did not get matched with similarly genius director post-TBONTB is a real shame because with the right director and script he could have gone on to be a film star. Perhaps the fact that much of the story takes place in a theatre and then on the many theatre troupe's "stages" as they foil the Nazis throughout the story, nurtured Benny's own natural unique comedic talent in a way that his other films could not. And then there's Lombard. Carole Lombard was and still is imho, the best comedic actor other than Chaplin-Lloyd-Keaton-Dressler-Stanwyck. I don't find that the comedians of today can even come close to the previously mentioned comedians. Lombard and Benny play the most perfectly narcissistic clever power-couple seen anywhere in film or real life. That this was Lomabrd's final film before her tragic death (plane crash during a war bond tour) is sad for all of us. Her seduction of the dashing young Robert Stack's Lt. Sobinski and the evil double-agent, Professor Siletski (Stanley Ridges)is wonderful to watch. The petty banter between the egomaniacal husband and wife acting team, the Turas (Lombard and Benny) is equally delightful. Also worth mentioning is Lombard's maid, Anna (Maude Eburne) who has some great lines like, "What a husband doesn't know won't hurt his wife." While audiences in 1941/42 may not have been able to appreciate this satire,it's worth noting that Roberto Benigni's film Life Is Beautiful (which has a higher IMDb rating) was also criticized for mixing humor in a story about the holocaust when screened at Cannes in 1997. Some people were outraged that Benigni would include comedy in the concentration camp scenes. But the film went on to win several top awards. Another film which comes to mind mixing war/genocide with comedy in a very skillful way is Arthur Penn's, Little Big Man (1970-based on a novel of the same name by Thomas Berger). I don't know if there were any criticisms of comedy being used in a movie about the genocide of Native Americans but in my opinion, Little Big Man, although a different style than TBONTB, is a superior comedy about a very serious and tragic time in America's history. I believe these knee jerk reactions to films which show or allude to barbaric shameful historic events are without merit. For it's art which brings light to not only these man-made horrors but illuminates the beauty and power of the human spirit. Lubitsch's To Be or Not to Be should not be over-looked. It's one of the finest examples of comedy from any era. Plus you get to watch Lombard and Benny at their most sublime.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " A laugh is nothing to be sneezed at ".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Recently reading an article on the Timeout website about movies which failed badly on there original release that deserve to be re-appraise,I noticed in amongst the more recent titles was a Screwball Comedy from the 40's involving Nazi's.Being interested in seeing how a movie made during WWII could look at the then current events in a comedic light,I decided to import the only DVD edition of the film I could find,and get set to find out how LOL got put together with Nazi. The plot: As a Polish theatre company starts to gather ideas for a new production called "Gastarpo",that along with being a satirical play about the Nazis,is also going to be lead by the company's lead actor Joseph Tura playing a lookalike version of Hitler.With only a few more performances of Hamlet to go before Gastrarpo enters production,Tura starts to experience terrible anxiety attacks due to his wife, (fellow stage performer Maria Tura) getting bundles of flowers from a secret admirer and also due to one individual always being in the audience and each time publicly stepping out as soon as Joseph gets on stage.Unbeknownst to Joseph,the man who is sending his wife flowers and the audience member who keeps walking out are both the same person:Lieut. Stanislav Sobinski.Since setting their eyes on each other for the first time,Maria and Sobinski have both fallen deeply head over heels for each other.As Maria and Stanislav's affair intensifies,and the theatre company also starts its countdown for the premier of Gastarpo,Hitler invades Poland and destroys anything which threatens to mock the authority of the Nazis.Whilst Joseph,Maria and the rest of the actors go into hiding to join the resistances,Sobinski rushes to join the British Polish division of the RAF to do everything he can to fight for his country.Returning to London after a recent raid,Sobinski and a group of fellow solider's meet a leading polish Resistance leader called Prof. Siletsky.Proudly saying that he is about to return to Poland to continue his support for the Resistance,Siletsky offers all of the soldiers a chance to each give him a message that he can pass on to their love ones.Thinking that this may be his only chance to give her a message,Sobinski ask Siletsky to give a message to Poland's most famous actress,who Siletsky has never heard of before!..After having given him the message,Sobinski begins to fear that Siletsky may not be all that he seems. View on the film: Writing the screenplay a few months before America got fully involved in WWII,screenwriter's Melchior Lengyel,Edwin Justus Mayer and Ernst Lubitsch strike a remarkable balance of never playing down the grim situation that the characters are involved in,whilst also having each of the cast members deliver still-razor sharp satirical dialogue,that is truly ahead of its time in its design to prick the pompous,authoritarian image of Hitler and the Nazis.From the moment that Hitler cancel's the production of Gastarpo,the writer's show act-or Joseph Tura, (played by a great,egotistical Jack Benny) to be a two bit old ham,whose dream is to use the role of Hitler so that he can soon become a Lawrance Oliveria style legend in the theatre world.Allowing the tremendous,screwball dialogue to move at lightning speed,co-writer/director Ernst Lubitsch also displays real skill in knowing when to slow the exchanges down,to focus on the troubles that the character's are caught in,with the scenes that revel Prof. Siletsky, (played by a wonderfully deranged Stanley Ridgers) true intension being filmed in tight angles,amped up in tension Werner R. Heymann's terrific score.For what would tragically be her final role,stunning Carole Lombard gives a blistering performance as Joseph's less than faithful wife Maria.Along with smoothly handling the film's dramatic moments,as Maria begins to get closer to finding out Siletsky's true intension's,Lombard also clearly displays a true joy for delivering zingers left,right and centre,from doing everything to keep her husband's suspicion's of an affair at bay,to wooing everyone in sight of her figure-hugging dress in an attempt to escape from a Nazi bedroom,which all help to make Lombard's curtain call performance one that will continue to be applauded for years to come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1942, this comedy is set in Warsaw, during the Polish occupation by the Nazis. It unashamedly pokes fun both at Hitler and the Nazi regime, and also the vanity of actors. It tells the story of a Polish acting troupe, including husband and wife couple Joseph and Maria Tura (Jack Benny and Carole Lombard, in her last film), who find themselves tangled up in a plot to stop the Nazis obtaining valuable information. It does not sound like a recipe for a hilarious comedybut that is what this film is. Joseph Tura considers himself an acclaimed Shakespearean actor, and during the film he plays Hamlet (badly!) Maria, his beautiful and feisty wife, catches the eye of Lieutenant Stanislav Sobinski. Joseph is suspicious and jealous, but they soon have greater problems to worry about By the time this film was released, Germany was sweeping across Europe. Also, tragically, Carole Lombard had died in a plane crash, and possibly as a result, the film was initially seen as being in bad taste, and was not appreciated by audiences. Over the years however, it has gained a reputation as a classic comedy, and I think the humour still stands up well for modern viewers. The story is convoluted, but easy enough to follow. The real joy in this film however, is the incredibly funny script and the way that the cast (even the minor players are terrific) deliver their lines. The dialogue fizzes along nicely and there is also plenty of visual comedy. The tragedy and heartache caused by the occupation of Poland is duly acknowledged, and I don't think the film was attempting to make light of the situation at all. One scene in particular shows members of the Nazi army jumping out of a plane to their certain death, on the orders of Hitler, given by radio transmission. The film also shows the burning buildings and the many homeless and grieving families who suffered as a result of Hitler's regime. The subplot is great  concerning Joseph's vexation at his wife's flirtation with a handsome Lieutenant; and said Lieutenant's infatuation with the slightly Maria (flightly she may be, but she is also possessed of a great bravery). Carole Lombard looks beautiful and so full of life and vitality throughout  which in hindsight underlines the sadness of her death at such terrible circumstances at the age of 33. Still, this is how she should be remembered  at her very best. It's a shame that this film turned out to be her swan song, but what a swan song it is. Benny is also terrific; I have never seen any of his work before, but will certainly be searching out more of it! This is one of the American Film Institute's 100 Funniest Comedies, and it deserves its place on that list. Despite the sombre subject matter, this is a film well worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's often overshadowed by The Great Dictator, which preceded it by two years and was technically the first American WW-II themed comedy, but To Be Or Not To Be deserves the honor both for being the first comedy to refer to Hitler and Nazi Germany by name, and also for being made while the US was very much an active side in the war. It's still incredibly funny, but it's much more impressive, almost shockingly so, when you realize that it was made while Hitler was alive, and just how powerful it was back then. Carole Lombard is show-stoppingly terrific, and it's probably the best place to see her talent on display, since sadly it was her final performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Have you seen The Great Dictator or The Producers? Watch this and you'll see where they got the idea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nomoons11
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one is just one funny farce all the way through. Doeesn't hurt Jack Benny is as good as he's ever been on film. To me this was his film. Lombard is in this a lot but she's not near as good as Jack Benny. This film is about 90% comedy and 10% serious. The opening scene comes up and immediately you start to see where Charlie Chaplin and Mel brooks got their inspiration. They got it from a fictitious Polish acting troop trying to put on a farcical play about Hitler (of course Mr. Brooks remade this but it's not in the same league). Not a lot has to be said about this, you just have to watch it and see. An all around funny film. I can see why it has high user ratings in here. Really good stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film that never should have been made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Applause Meter
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some topics lend themselves to satire; genocidal military dictatorships do not. This is perhaps one of the most offensive, ill-conceived movies ever produced in the name of public "entertainment." To portray Nazis as idiotic buffoons and to script in dialogue and insert one- liners about the comedic aspects of concentration campswell that's got to just be a laugh a minute. And here Jack Benny portrays a pretentious Polish actor, Joseph Tura, which gives Benny full license to present us with his comedy persona in full form. Tura, who craves greatness as Shakespeare's Hamlet is prime Benny, the smug, mocking, self-satisfied comedic fool only satisfied when he can make everyone else look foolish. So guess what?! THAT makes him smart. Got it? Hilarious! This film, Carole Lombard's last, is a sad coda to her sparkling career. Purportedly her husband Clark Gable urged her not to take the part of Maria Tura, but she liked the script?! The esteemed director Fritz Lang, half-Jewish, (his Jewish mother had converted to Catholicism) and an &eacute;migr&eacute; from Nazi Germany who fled that country just in time, should have known better. This movie was a disaster when it was made at the height of World War II, and more than 70 years later is still, to put it mildly, an embarrassment. No matter what Leonard Maltin thinks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Starts Well But Fizzles Out
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie begins in Warsaw, Poland in 1939, in the days just before the invasion by Germany and the USSR (though the movie disregards the latter). Though the threat of war is in the air, a theater company's actors and staff spend their time worrying and arguing over theatrical roles and their status in the company. Also, a young bomber pilot has his eye upon an actor's wife (who is an actress herself), and tries to enter an affair with her. The invasion comes. Most of the company has fled Poland, including the pilot, who has joined the Polish exile forces in Britain. However, the actor and his actress wife remain. A professor is sent from Britain to Poland to help the resistance there...but he becomes suspected as a double agent, and the pilot is sent to Poland to stop the professor's intended treachery. He warns the actors who are still there, and they in turn impersonate various Gestapo members to try to foil the professor. Unfortunately for the pilot, the husband he tried to cuckold is upset with him, which complicates things. And unfortunately, it makes everything too complicated and confusing, and ruins the rest of the movie. Also not helping was the joke about "Concentration Camp Gerhardt" which became irritating after being repeated a dozen times. Also, many scenes went on for far too long after they made their point. The movie is notable mainly for being a period piece; as a farce it dropped the ball.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hamlet in Holocaust !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Diya Dutta
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is perhaps one of the greatest Satire movie I've ever seen on this war genre. Jack Benny was hilarious and superb in this movie, and not to mention about the great work of the director who succeeded in kept you anticipating through out the movie without any chance of taking eyes off. The only sad parts I came to know that the Star couple of this movie as played Mr & Mrs Taura expired even before the Premiere of this movie. This one is a very old classic but wont appear to be slow or boring at any point of time during the play. I highly recommend viewers with a taste for World War or Holocaust to go for a change and enjoy this Satire which you wont regret ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shakespeare Does Hitler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A troupe of Polish actors impersonate Nazis in order to prevent the Polish underground from being captured. Jack Benny used to joke on radio and TV about his movie career, especially The Horn Blows at Midnight (1945). But he never joked about this film. Though it's got a serious subject right on the eve of WWII, it's still pretty funny, especially when Jack pulls his egotistical, great actor bit. With all the Heil Hitlers and Gestapo boys running around, it's sometimes hard to keep up with who's who. Nonetheless, it's a clever screenplay having an actors' troupe impersonate Nazi's. Aside from TV's Hogan's Heroes (1965-1971), I don't know of any other show that risked making fun of the murderous Third Reich. It's a pretty tricky topic to begin with, but the production crew pulls it off. Then there's Carole Lombard, on the eve of her tragic plane ride. But she's still delicious as heck. Plus, I could swear that silken gown she's got on for her tryst is all she's got on. My eyes were glued. Also, it's easy to catch a young, love-struck Robert Stack before he got out of the movie's second row and moved into the hard case cop on TV's The Untouchables (1959-1963). Note too, the unspoken Jewish subtext, with the names of many of the victims and Shylock's moving plea from Shakespeare. I don't know why the script made do with inference rather than a single overt mention of Nazism's virulent anti-Semitism. Maybe it's because that might sound like special pleading, regardless of the merits. Anyway, it's still a pretty funny movie, and remains an offbeat one-of-a-kind. Besides Benny had a much better film career than he wanted to admit.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To Be is To Be- To Be or Not to Be ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're looking for comedy, the 1983 remake of this film with Mel Brooks, Tim Mathieson, Anne Bancroft and Charles Durning is the film for you. That was absolutely hilarious. As for the original 1942 version, it is humorous, especially when you have Jack Benny playing the lead, but there are some moments of serious overtones. As the smitten lover, Robert Stack was incredibly wooden here. Perhaps, we can blame it on the fact that he was just beginning his career and given very little to say here. Sig Ruman is a standout as usual as Concentration Camp Earhardt, eagerly ready to blame his failings on Schultz. Benny and Carole Lombard provide the right chemistry as the Polish acting couple who eventually outwit the Nazis.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deft Delightful & Dangerously Hilarious Nazi Satire
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amplexuslotus
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one else but Ernst Lubitsch could have made To Be or Not to Be. That it's superb and sublime and witty and ingeniously funny cannot be emphasized enough. The film has a great script, direction and cinematography (Rudolph Mat&eacute;). While the entire cast shines, Lombard and Benny are absolutely stellar. It's a shame that Benny did not get matched with similarly genius director post-TBONTB is a real shame because with the right director and script he could have gone on to be a film star. Perhaps the fact that much of the story takes place in a theatre and then on the many theatre troupe's "stages" as they foil the Nazis throughout the story, nurtured Benny's own natural unique comedic talent in a way that his other films could not. And then there's Lombard. Carole Lombard was and still is imho, the best comedic actor other than Chaplin-Lloyd-Keaton-Dressler-Stanwyck. I don't find that the comedians of today can even come close to the previously mentioned comedians. Lombard and Benny play the most perfectly narcissistic clever power-couple seen anywhere in film or real life. That this was Lomabrd's final film before her tragic death (plane crash during a war bond tour) is sad for all of us. Her seduction of the dashing young Robert Stack's Lt. Sobinski and the evil double-agent, Professor Siletski (Stanley Ridges)is wonderful to watch. The petty banter between the egomaniacal husband and wife acting team, the Turas (Lombard and Benny) is equally delightful. Also worth mentioning is Lombard's maid, Anna (Maude Eburne) who has some great lines like, "What a husband doesn't know won't hurt his wife." While audiences in 1941/42 may not have been able to appreciate this satire,it's worth noting that Roberto Benigni's film Life Is Beautiful (which has a higher IMDb rating) was also criticized for mixing humor in a story about the holocaust when screened at Cannes in 1997. Some people were outraged that Benigni would include comedy in the concentration camp scenes. But the film went on to win several top awards. Another film which comes to mind mixing war/genocide with comedy in a very skillful way is Arthur Penn's, Little Big Man (1970-based on a novel of the same name by Thomas Berger). I don't know if there were any criticisms of comedy being used in a movie about the genocide of Native Americans but in my opinion, Little Big Man, although a different style than TBONTB, is a superior comedy about a very serious and tragic time in America's history. I believe these knee jerk reactions to films which show or allude to barbaric shameful historic events are without merit. For it's art which brings light to not only these man-made horrors but illuminates the beauty and power of the human spirit. Lubitsch's To Be or Not to Be should not be over-looked. It's one of the finest examples of comedy from any era. Plus you get to watch Lombard and Benny at their most sublime.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " A laugh is nothing to be sneezed at ".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Recently reading an article on the Timeout website about movies which failed badly on there original release that deserve to be re-appraise,I noticed in amongst the more recent titles was a Screwball Comedy from the 40's involving Nazi's.Being interested in seeing how a movie made during WWII could look at the then current events in a comedic light,I decided to import the only DVD edition of the film I could find,and get set to find out how LOL got put together with Nazi. The plot: As a Polish theatre company starts to gather ideas for a new production called "Gastarpo",that along with being a satirical play about the Nazis,is also going to be lead by the company's lead actor Joseph Tura playing a lookalike version of Hitler.With only a few more performances of Hamlet to go before Gastrarpo enters production,Tura starts to experience terrible anxiety attacks due to his wife, (fellow stage performer Maria Tura) getting bundles of flowers from a secret admirer and also due to one individual always being in the audience and each time publicly stepping out as soon as Joseph gets on stage.Unbeknownst to Joseph,the man who is sending his wife flowers and the audience member who keeps walking out are both the same person:Lieut. Stanislav Sobinski.Since setting their eyes on each other for the first time,Maria and Sobinski have both fallen deeply head over heels for each other.As Maria and Stanislav's affair intensifies,and the theatre company also starts its countdown for the premier of Gastarpo,Hitler invades Poland and destroys anything which threatens to mock the authority of the Nazis.Whilst Joseph,Maria and the rest of the actors go into hiding to join the resistances,Sobinski rushes to join the British Polish division of the RAF to do everything he can to fight for his country.Returning to London after a recent raid,Sobinski and a group of fellow solider's meet a leading polish Resistance leader called Prof. Siletsky.Proudly saying that he is about to return to Poland to continue his support for the Resistance,Siletsky offers all of the soldiers a chance to each give him a message that he can pass on to their love ones.Thinking that this may be his only chance to give her a message,Sobinski ask Siletsky to give a message to Poland's most famous actress,who Siletsky has never heard of before!..After having given him the message,Sobinski begins to fear that Siletsky may not be all that he seems. View on the film: Writing the screenplay a few months before America got fully involved in WWII,screenwriter's Melchior Lengyel,Edwin Justus Mayer and Ernst Lubitsch strike a remarkable balance of never playing down the grim situation that the characters are involved in,whilst also having each of the cast members deliver still-razor sharp satirical dialogue,that is truly ahead of its time in its design to prick the pompous,authoritarian image of Hitler and the Nazis.From the moment that Hitler cancel's the production of Gastarpo,the writer's show act-or Joseph Tura, (played by a great,egotistical Jack Benny) to be a two bit old ham,whose dream is to use the role of Hitler so that he can soon become a Lawrance Oliveria style legend in the theatre world.Allowing the tremendous,screwball dialogue to move at lightning speed,co-writer/director Ernst Lubitsch also displays real skill in knowing when to slow the exchanges down,to focus on the troubles that the character's are caught in,with the scenes that revel Prof. Siletsky, (played by a wonderfully deranged Stanley Ridgers) true intension being filmed in tight angles,amped up in tension Werner R. Heymann's terrific score.For what would tragically be her final role,stunning Carole Lombard gives a blistering performance as Joseph's less than faithful wife Maria.Along with smoothly handling the film's dramatic moments,as Maria begins to get closer to finding out Siletsky's true intension's,Lombard also clearly displays a true joy for delivering zingers left,right and centre,from doing everything to keep her husband's suspicion's of an affair at bay,to wooing everyone in sight of her figure-hugging dress in an attempt to escape from a Nazi bedroom,which all help to make Lombard's curtain call performance one that will continue to be applauded for years to come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1942, this comedy is set in Warsaw, during the Polish occupation by the Nazis. It unashamedly pokes fun both at Hitler and the Nazi regime, and also the vanity of actors. It tells the story of a Polish acting troupe, including husband and wife couple Joseph and Maria Tura (Jack Benny and Carole Lombard, in her last film), who find themselves tangled up in a plot to stop the Nazis obtaining valuable information. It does not sound like a recipe for a hilarious comedybut that is what this film is. Joseph Tura considers himself an acclaimed Shakespearean actor, and during the film he plays Hamlet (badly!) Maria, his beautiful and feisty wife, catches the eye of Lieutenant Stanislav Sobinski. Joseph is suspicious and jealous, but they soon have greater problems to worry about By the time this film was released, Germany was sweeping across Europe. Also, tragically, Carole Lombard had died in a plane crash, and possibly as a result, the film was initially seen as being in bad taste, and was not appreciated by audiences. Over the years however, it has gained a reputation as a classic comedy, and I think the humour still stands up well for modern viewers. The story is convoluted, but easy enough to follow. The real joy in this film however, is the incredibly funny script and the way that the cast (even the minor players are terrific) deliver their lines. The dialogue fizzes along nicely and there is also plenty of visual comedy. The tragedy and heartache caused by the occupation of Poland is duly acknowledged, and I don't think the film was attempting to make light of the situation at all. One scene in particular shows members of the Nazi army jumping out of a plane to their certain death, on the orders of Hitler, given by radio transmission. The film also shows the burning buildings and the many homeless and grieving families who suffered as a result of Hitler's regime. The subplot is great  concerning Joseph's vexation at his wife's flirtation with a handsome Lieutenant; and said Lieutenant's infatuation with the slightly Maria (flightly she may be, but she is also possessed of a great bravery). Carole Lombard looks beautiful and so full of life and vitality throughout  which in hindsight underlines the sadness of her death at such terrible circumstances at the age of 33. Still, this is how she should be remembered  at her very best. It's a shame that this film turned out to be her swan song, but what a swan song it is. Benny is also terrific; I have never seen any of his work before, but will certainly be searching out more of it! This is one of the American Film Institute's 100 Funniest Comedies, and it deserves its place on that list. Despite the sombre subject matter, this is a film well worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's often overshadowed by The Great Dictator, which preceded it by two years and was technically the first American WW-II themed comedy, but To Be Or Not To Be deserves the honor both for being the first comedy to refer to Hitler and Nazi Germany by name, and also for being made while the US was very much an active side in the war. It's still incredibly funny, but it's much more impressive, almost shockingly so, when you realize that it was made while Hitler was alive, and just how powerful it was back then. Carole Lombard is show-stoppingly terrific, and it's probably the best place to see her talent on display, since sadly it was her final performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Have you seen The Great Dictator or The Producers? Watch this and you'll see where they got the idea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nomoons11
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one is just one funny farce all the way through. Doeesn't hurt Jack Benny is as good as he's ever been on film. To me this was his film. Lombard is in this a lot but she's not near as good as Jack Benny. This film is about 90% comedy and 10% serious. The opening scene comes up and immediately you start to see where Charlie Chaplin and Mel brooks got their inspiration. They got it from a fictitious Polish acting troop trying to put on a farcical play about Hitler (of course Mr. Brooks remade this but it's not in the same league). Not a lot has to be said about this, you just have to watch it and see. An all around funny film. I can see why it has high user ratings in here. Really good stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film that never should have been made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Applause Meter
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some topics lend themselves to satire; genocidal military dictatorships do not. This is perhaps one of the most offensive, ill-conceived movies ever produced in the name of public "entertainment." To portray Nazis as idiotic buffoons and to script in dialogue and insert one- liners about the comedic aspects of concentration campswell that's got to just be a laugh a minute. And here Jack Benny portrays a pretentious Polish actor, Joseph Tura, which gives Benny full license to present us with his comedy persona in full form. Tura, who craves greatness as Shakespeare's Hamlet is prime Benny, the smug, mocking, self-satisfied comedic fool only satisfied when he can make everyone else look foolish. So guess what?! THAT makes him smart. Got it? Hilarious! This film, Carole Lombard's last, is a sad coda to her sparkling career. Purportedly her husband Clark Gable urged her not to take the part of Maria Tura, but she liked the script?! The esteemed director Fritz Lang, half-Jewish, (his Jewish mother had converted to Catholicism) and an &eacute;migr&eacute; from Nazi Germany who fled that country just in time, should have known better. This movie was a disaster when it was made at the height of World War II, and more than 70 years later is still, to put it mildly, an embarrassment. No matter what Leonard Maltin thinks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Starts Well But Fizzles Out
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie begins in Warsaw, Poland in 1939, in the days just before the invasion by Germany and the USSR (though the movie disregards the latter). Though the threat of war is in the air, a theater company's actors and staff spend their time worrying and arguing over theatrical roles and their status in the company. Also, a young bomber pilot has his eye upon an actor's wife (who is an actress herself), and tries to enter an affair with her. The invasion comes. Most of the company has fled Poland, including the pilot, who has joined the Polish exile forces in Britain. However, the actor and his actress wife remain. A professor is sent from Britain to Poland to help the resistance there...but he becomes suspected as a double agent, and the pilot is sent to Poland to stop the professor's intended treachery. He warns the actors who are still there, and they in turn impersonate various Gestapo members to try to foil the professor. Unfortunately for the pilot, the husband he tried to cuckold is upset with him, which complicates things. And unfortunately, it makes everything too complicated and confusing, and ruins the rest of the movie. Also not helping was the joke about "Concentration Camp Gerhardt" which became irritating after being repeated a dozen times. Also, many scenes went on for far too long after they made their point. The movie is notable mainly for being a period piece; as a farce it dropped the ball.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hamlet in Holocaust !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Diya Dutta
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is perhaps one of the greatest Satire movie I've ever seen on this war genre. Jack Benny was hilarious and superb in this movie, and not to mention about the great work of the director who succeeded in kept you anticipating through out the movie without any chance of taking eyes off. The only sad parts I came to know that the Star couple of this movie as played Mr & Mrs Taura expired even before the Premiere of this movie. This one is a very old classic but wont appear to be slow or boring at any point of time during the play. I highly recommend viewers with a taste for World War or Holocaust to go for a change and enjoy this Satire which you wont regret ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shakespeare Does Hitler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A troupe of Polish actors impersonate Nazis in order to prevent the Polish underground from being captured. Jack Benny used to joke on radio and TV about his movie career, especially The Horn Blows at Midnight (1945). But he never joked about this film. Though it's got a serious subject right on the eve of WWII, it's still pretty funny, especially when Jack pulls his egotistical, great actor bit. With all the Heil Hitlers and Gestapo boys running around, it's sometimes hard to keep up with who's who. Nonetheless, it's a clever screenplay having an actors' troupe impersonate Nazi's. Aside from TV's Hogan's Heroes (1965-1971), I don't know of any other show that risked making fun of the murderous Third Reich. It's a pretty tricky topic to begin with, but the production crew pulls it off. Then there's Carole Lombard, on the eve of her tragic plane ride. But she's still delicious as heck. Plus, I could swear that silken gown she's got on for her tryst is all she's got on. My eyes were glued. Also, it's easy to catch a young, love-struck Robert Stack before he got out of the movie's second row and moved into the hard case cop on TV's The Untouchables (1959-1963). Note too, the unspoken Jewish subtext, with the names of many of the victims and Shylock's moving plea from Shakespeare. I don't know why the script made do with inference rather than a single overt mention of Nazism's virulent anti-Semitism. Maybe it's because that might sound like special pleading, regardless of the merits. Anyway, it's still a pretty funny movie, and remains an offbeat one-of-a-kind. Besides Benny had a much better film career than he wanted to admit.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To Be is To Be- To Be or Not to Be ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're looking for comedy, the 1983 remake of this film with Mel Brooks, Tim Mathieson, Anne Bancroft and Charles Durning is the film for you. That was absolutely hilarious. As for the original 1942 version, it is humorous, especially when you have Jack Benny playing the lead, but there are some moments of serious overtones. As the smitten lover, Robert Stack was incredibly wooden here. Perhaps, we can blame it on the fact that he was just beginning his career and given very little to say here. Sig Ruman is a standout as usual as Concentration Camp Earhardt, eagerly ready to blame his failings on Schultz. Benny and Carole Lombard provide the right chemistry as the Polish acting couple who eventually outwit the Nazis.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deft Delightful & Dangerously Hilarious Nazi Satire
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amplexuslotus
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one else but Ernst Lubitsch could have made To Be or Not to Be. That it's superb and sublime and witty and ingeniously funny cannot be emphasized enough. The film has a great script, direction and cinematography (Rudolph Mat&eacute;). While the entire cast shines, Lombard and Benny are absolutely stellar. It's a shame that Benny did not get matched with similarly genius director post-TBONTB is a real shame because with the right director and script he could have gone on to be a film star. Perhaps the fact that much of the story takes place in a theatre and then on the many theatre troupe's "stages" as they foil the Nazis throughout the story, nurtured Benny's own natural unique comedic talent in a way that his other films could not. And then there's Lombard. Carole Lombard was and still is imho, the best comedic actor other than Chaplin-Lloyd-Keaton-Dressler-Stanwyck. I don't find that the comedians of today can even come close to the previously mentioned comedians. Lombard and Benny play the most perfectly narcissistic clever power-couple seen anywhere in film or real life. That this was Lomabrd's final film before her tragic death (plane crash during a war bond tour) is sad for all of us. Her seduction of the dashing young Robert Stack's Lt. Sobinski and the evil double-agent, Professor Siletski (Stanley Ridges)is wonderful to watch. The petty banter between the egomaniacal husband and wife acting team, the Turas (Lombard and Benny) is equally delightful. Also worth mentioning is Lombard's maid, Anna (Maude Eburne) who has some great lines like, "What a husband doesn't know won't hurt his wife." While audiences in 1941/42 may not have been able to appreciate this satire,it's worth noting that Roberto Benigni's film Life Is Beautiful (which has a higher IMDb rating) was also criticized for mixing humor in a story about the holocaust when screened at Cannes in 1997. Some people were outraged that Benigni would include comedy in the concentration camp scenes. But the film went on to win several top awards. Another film which comes to mind mixing war/genocide with comedy in a very skillful way is Arthur Penn's, Little Big Man (1970-based on a novel of the same name by Thomas Berger). I don't know if there were any criticisms of comedy being used in a movie about the genocide of Native Americans but in my opinion, Little Big Man, although a different style than TBONTB, is a superior comedy about a very serious and tragic time in America's history. I believe these knee jerk reactions to films which show or allude to barbaric shameful historic events are without merit. For it's art which brings light to not only these man-made horrors but illuminates the beauty and power of the human spirit. Lubitsch's To Be or Not to Be should not be over-looked. It's one of the finest examples of comedy from any era. Plus you get to watch Lombard and Benny at their most sublime.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " A laugh is nothing to be sneezed at ".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Recently reading an article on the Timeout website about movies which failed badly on there original release that deserve to be re-appraise,I noticed in amongst the more recent titles was a Screwball Comedy from the 40's involving Nazi's.Being interested in seeing how a movie made during WWII could look at the then current events in a comedic light,I decided to import the only DVD edition of the film I could find,and get set to find out how LOL got put together with Nazi. The plot: As a Polish theatre company starts to gather ideas for a new production called "Gastarpo",that along with being a satirical play about the Nazis,is also going to be lead by the company's lead actor Joseph Tura playing a lookalike version of Hitler.With only a few more performances of Hamlet to go before Gastrarpo enters production,Tura starts to experience terrible anxiety attacks due to his wife, (fellow stage performer Maria Tura) getting bundles of flowers from a secret admirer and also due to one individual always being in the audience and each time publicly stepping out as soon as Joseph gets on stage.Unbeknownst to Joseph,the man who is sending his wife flowers and the audience member who keeps walking out are both the same person:Lieut. Stanislav Sobinski.Since setting their eyes on each other for the first time,Maria and Sobinski have both fallen deeply head over heels for each other.As Maria and Stanislav's affair intensifies,and the theatre company also starts its countdown for the premier of Gastarpo,Hitler invades Poland and destroys anything which threatens to mock the authority of the Nazis.Whilst Joseph,Maria and the rest of the actors go into hiding to join the resistances,Sobinski rushes to join the British Polish division of the RAF to do everything he can to fight for his country.Returning to London after a recent raid,Sobinski and a group of fellow solider's meet a leading polish Resistance leader called Prof. Siletsky.Proudly saying that he is about to return to Poland to continue his support for the Resistance,Siletsky offers all of the soldiers a chance to each give him a message that he can pass on to their love ones.Thinking that this may be his only chance to give her a message,Sobinski ask Siletsky to give a message to Poland's most famous actress,who Siletsky has never heard of before!..After having given him the message,Sobinski begins to fear that Siletsky may not be all that he seems. View on the film: Writing the screenplay a few months before America got fully involved in WWII,screenwriter's Melchior Lengyel,Edwin Justus Mayer and Ernst Lubitsch strike a remarkable balance of never playing down the grim situation that the characters are involved in,whilst also having each of the cast members deliver still-razor sharp satirical dialogue,that is truly ahead of its time in its design to prick the pompous,authoritarian image of Hitler and the Nazis.From the moment that Hitler cancel's the production of Gastarpo,the writer's show act-or Joseph Tura, (played by a great,egotistical Jack Benny) to be a two bit old ham,whose dream is to use the role of Hitler so that he can soon become a Lawrance Oliveria style legend in the theatre world.Allowing the tremendous,screwball dialogue to move at lightning speed,co-writer/director Ernst Lubitsch also displays real skill in knowing when to slow the exchanges down,to focus on the troubles that the character's are caught in,with the scenes that revel Prof. Siletsky, (played by a wonderfully deranged Stanley Ridgers) true intension being filmed in tight angles,amped up in tension Werner R. Heymann's terrific score.For what would tragically be her final role,stunning Carole Lombard gives a blistering performance as Joseph's less than faithful wife Maria.Along with smoothly handling the film's dramatic moments,as Maria begins to get closer to finding out Siletsky's true intension's,Lombard also clearly displays a true joy for delivering zingers left,right and centre,from doing everything to keep her husband's suspicion's of an affair at bay,to wooing everyone in sight of her figure-hugging dress in an attempt to escape from a Nazi bedroom,which all help to make Lombard's curtain call performance one that will continue to be applauded for years to come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1942, this comedy is set in Warsaw, during the Polish occupation by the Nazis. It unashamedly pokes fun both at Hitler and the Nazi regime, and also the vanity of actors. It tells the story of a Polish acting troupe, including husband and wife couple Joseph and Maria Tura (Jack Benny and Carole Lombard, in her last film), who find themselves tangled up in a plot to stop the Nazis obtaining valuable information. It does not sound like a recipe for a hilarious comedybut that is what this film is. Joseph Tura considers himself an acclaimed Shakespearean actor, and during the film he plays Hamlet (badly!) Maria, his beautiful and feisty wife, catches the eye of Lieutenant Stanislav Sobinski. Joseph is suspicious and jealous, but they soon have greater problems to worry about By the time this film was released, Germany was sweeping across Europe. Also, tragically, Carole Lombard had died in a plane crash, and possibly as a result, the film was initially seen as being in bad taste, and was not appreciated by audiences. Over the years however, it has gained a reputation as a classic comedy, and I think the humour still stands up well for modern viewers. The story is convoluted, but easy enough to follow. The real joy in this film however, is the incredibly funny script and the way that the cast (even the minor players are terrific) deliver their lines. The dialogue fizzes along nicely and there is also plenty of visual comedy. The tragedy and heartache caused by the occupation of Poland is duly acknowledged, and I don't think the film was attempting to make light of the situation at all. One scene in particular shows members of the Nazi army jumping out of a plane to their certain death, on the orders of Hitler, given by radio transmission. The film also shows the burning buildings and the many homeless and grieving families who suffered as a result of Hitler's regime. The subplot is great  concerning Joseph's vexation at his wife's flirtation with a handsome Lieutenant; and said Lieutenant's infatuation with the slightly Maria (flightly she may be, but she is also possessed of a great bravery). Carole Lombard looks beautiful and so full of life and vitality throughout  which in hindsight underlines the sadness of her death at such terrible circumstances at the age of 33. Still, this is how she should be remembered  at her very best. It's a shame that this film turned out to be her swan song, but what a swan song it is. Benny is also terrific; I have never seen any of his work before, but will certainly be searching out more of it! This is one of the American Film Institute's 100 Funniest Comedies, and it deserves its place on that list. Despite the sombre subject matter, this is a film well worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's often overshadowed by The Great Dictator, which preceded it by two years and was technically the first American WW-II themed comedy, but To Be Or Not To Be deserves the honor both for being the first comedy to refer to Hitler and Nazi Germany by name, and also for being made while the US was very much an active side in the war. It's still incredibly funny, but it's much more impressive, almost shockingly so, when you realize that it was made while Hitler was alive, and just how powerful it was back then. Carole Lombard is show-stoppingly terrific, and it's probably the best place to see her talent on display, since sadly it was her final performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Have you seen The Great Dictator or The Producers? Watch this and you'll see where they got the idea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nomoons11
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one is just one funny farce all the way through. Doeesn't hurt Jack Benny is as good as he's ever been on film. To me this was his film. Lombard is in this a lot but she's not near as good as Jack Benny. This film is about 90% comedy and 10% serious. The opening scene comes up and immediately you start to see where Charlie Chaplin and Mel brooks got their inspiration. They got it from a fictitious Polish acting troop trying to put on a farcical play about Hitler (of course Mr. Brooks remade this but it's not in the same league). Not a lot has to be said about this, you just have to watch it and see. An all around funny film. I can see why it has high user ratings in here. Really good stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film that never should have been made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Applause Meter
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some topics lend themselves to satire; genocidal military dictatorships do not. This is perhaps one of the most offensive, ill-conceived movies ever produced in the name of public "entertainment." To portray Nazis as idiotic buffoons and to script in dialogue and insert one- liners about the comedic aspects of concentration campswell that's got to just be a laugh a minute. And here Jack Benny portrays a pretentious Polish actor, Joseph Tura, which gives Benny full license to present us with his comedy persona in full form. Tura, who craves greatness as Shakespeare's Hamlet is prime Benny, the smug, mocking, self-satisfied comedic fool only satisfied when he can make everyone else look foolish. So guess what?! THAT makes him smart. Got it? Hilarious! This film, Carole Lombard's last, is a sad coda to her sparkling career. Purportedly her husband Clark Gable urged her not to take the part of Maria Tura, but she liked the script?! The esteemed director Fritz Lang, half-Jewish, (his Jewish mother had converted to Catholicism) and an &eacute;migr&eacute; from Nazi Germany who fled that country just in time, should have known better. This movie was a disaster when it was made at the height of World War II, and more than 70 years later is still, to put it mildly, an embarrassment. No matter what Leonard Maltin thinks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Starts Well But Fizzles Out
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie begins in Warsaw, Poland in 1939, in the days just before the invasion by Germany and the USSR (though the movie disregards the latter). Though the threat of war is in the air, a theater company's actors and staff spend their time worrying and arguing over theatrical roles and their status in the company. Also, a young bomber pilot has his eye upon an actor's wife (who is an actress herself), and tries to enter an affair with her. The invasion comes. Most of the company has fled Poland, including the pilot, who has joined the Polish exile forces in Britain. However, the actor and his actress wife remain. A professor is sent from Britain to Poland to help the resistance there...but he becomes suspected as a double agent, and the pilot is sent to Poland to stop the professor's intended treachery. He warns the actors who are still there, and they in turn impersonate various Gestapo members to try to foil the professor. Unfortunately for the pilot, the husband he tried to cuckold is upset with him, which complicates things. And unfortunately, it makes everything too complicated and confusing, and ruins the rest of the movie. Also not helping was the joke about "Concentration Camp Gerhardt" which became irritating after being repeated a dozen times. Also, many scenes went on for far too long after they made their point. The movie is notable mainly for being a period piece; as a farce it dropped the ball.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hamlet in Holocaust !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Diya Dutta
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is perhaps one of the greatest Satire movie I've ever seen on this war genre. Jack Benny was hilarious and superb in this movie, and not to mention about the great work of the director who succeeded in kept you anticipating through out the movie without any chance of taking eyes off. The only sad parts I came to know that the Star couple of this movie as played Mr & Mrs Taura expired even before the Premiere of this movie. This one is a very old classic but wont appear to be slow or boring at any point of time during the play. I highly recommend viewers with a taste for World War or Holocaust to go for a change and enjoy this Satire which you wont regret ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shakespeare Does Hitler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A troupe of Polish actors impersonate Nazis in order to prevent the Polish underground from being captured. Jack Benny used to joke on radio and TV about his movie career, especially The Horn Blows at Midnight (1945). But he never joked about this film. Though it's got a serious subject right on the eve of WWII, it's still pretty funny, especially when Jack pulls his egotistical, great actor bit. With all the Heil Hitlers and Gestapo boys running around, it's sometimes hard to keep up with who's who. Nonetheless, it's a clever screenplay having an actors' troupe impersonate Nazi's. Aside from TV's Hogan's Heroes (1965-1971), I don't know of any other show that risked making fun of the murderous Third Reich. It's a pretty tricky topic to begin with, but the production crew pulls it off. Then there's Carole Lombard, on the eve of her tragic plane ride. But she's still delicious as heck. Plus, I could swear that silken gown she's got on for her tryst is all she's got on. My eyes were glued. Also, it's easy to catch a young, love-struck Robert Stack before he got out of the movie's second row and moved into the hard case cop on TV's The Untouchables (1959-1963). Note too, the unspoken Jewish subtext, with the names of many of the victims and Shylock's moving plea from Shakespeare. I don't know why the script made do with inference rather than a single overt mention of Nazism's virulent anti-Semitism. Maybe it's because that might sound like special pleading, regardless of the merits. Anyway, it's still a pretty funny movie, and remains an offbeat one-of-a-kind. Besides Benny had a much better film career than he wanted to admit.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To Be is To Be- To Be or Not to Be ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're looking for comedy, the 1983 remake of this film with Mel Brooks, Tim Mathieson, Anne Bancroft and Charles Durning is the film for you. That was absolutely hilarious. As for the original 1942 version, it is humorous, especially when you have Jack Benny playing the lead, but there are some moments of serious overtones. As the smitten lover, Robert Stack was incredibly wooden here. Perhaps, we can blame it on the fact that he was just beginning his career and given very little to say here. Sig Ruman is a standout as usual as Concentration Camp Earhardt, eagerly ready to blame his failings on Schultz. Benny and Carole Lombard provide the right chemistry as the Polish acting couple who eventually outwit the Nazis.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deft Delightful & Dangerously Hilarious Nazi Satire
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amplexuslotus
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one else but Ernst Lubitsch could have made To Be or Not to Be. That it's superb and sublime and witty and ingeniously funny cannot be emphasized enough. The film has a great script, direction and cinematography (Rudolph Mat&eacute;). While the entire cast shines, Lombard and Benny are absolutely stellar. It's a shame that Benny did not get matched with similarly genius director post-TBONTB is a real shame because with the right director and script he could have gone on to be a film star. Perhaps the fact that much of the story takes place in a theatre and then on the many theatre troupe's "stages" as they foil the Nazis throughout the story, nurtured Benny's own natural unique comedic talent in a way that his other films could not. And then there's Lombard. Carole Lombard was and still is imho, the best comedic actor other than Chaplin-Lloyd-Keaton-Dressler-Stanwyck. I don't find that the comedians of today can even come close to the previously mentioned comedians. Lombard and Benny play the most perfectly narcissistic clever power-couple seen anywhere in film or real life. That this was Lomabrd's final film before her tragic death (plane crash during a war bond tour) is sad for all of us. Her seduction of the dashing young Robert Stack's Lt. Sobinski and the evil double-agent, Professor Siletski (Stanley Ridges)is wonderful to watch. The petty banter between the egomaniacal husband and wife acting team, the Turas (Lombard and Benny) is equally delightful. Also worth mentioning is Lombard's maid, Anna (Maude Eburne) who has some great lines like, "What a husband doesn't know won't hurt his wife." While audiences in 1941/42 may not have been able to appreciate this satire,it's worth noting that Roberto Benigni's film Life Is Beautiful (which has a higher IMDb rating) was also criticized for mixing humor in a story about the holocaust when screened at Cannes in 1997. Some people were outraged that Benigni would include comedy in the concentration camp scenes. But the film went on to win several top awards. Another film which comes to mind mixing war/genocide with comedy in a very skillful way is Arthur Penn's, Little Big Man (1970-based on a novel of the same name by Thomas Berger). I don't know if there were any criticisms of comedy being used in a movie about the genocide of Native Americans but in my opinion, Little Big Man, although a different style than TBONTB, is a superior comedy about a very serious and tragic time in America's history. I believe these knee jerk reactions to films which show or allude to barbaric shameful historic events are without merit. For it's art which brings light to not only these man-made horrors but illuminates the beauty and power of the human spirit. Lubitsch's To Be or Not to Be should not be over-looked. It's one of the finest examples of comedy from any era. Plus you get to watch Lombard and Benny at their most sublime.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " A laugh is nothing to be sneezed at ".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Recently reading an article on the Timeout website about movies which failed badly on there original release that deserve to be re-appraise,I noticed in amongst the more recent titles was a Screwball Comedy from the 40's involving Nazi's.Being interested in seeing how a movie made during WWII could look at the then current events in a comedic light,I decided to import the only DVD edition of the film I could find,and get set to find out how LOL got put together with Nazi. The plot: As a Polish theatre company starts to gather ideas for a new production called "Gastarpo",that along with being a satirical play about the Nazis,is also going to be lead by the company's lead actor Joseph Tura playing a lookalike version of Hitler.With only a few more performances of Hamlet to go before Gastrarpo enters production,Tura starts to experience terrible anxiety attacks due to his wife, (fellow stage performer Maria Tura) getting bundles of flowers from a secret admirer and also due to one individual always being in the audience and each time publicly stepping out as soon as Joseph gets on stage.Unbeknownst to Joseph,the man who is sending his wife flowers and the audience member who keeps walking out are both the same person:Lieut. Stanislav Sobinski.Since setting their eyes on each other for the first time,Maria and Sobinski have both fallen deeply head over heels for each other.As Maria and Stanislav's affair intensifies,and the theatre company also starts its countdown for the premier of Gastarpo,Hitler invades Poland and destroys anything which threatens to mock the authority of the Nazis.Whilst Joseph,Maria and the rest of the actors go into hiding to join the resistances,Sobinski rushes to join the British Polish division of the RAF to do everything he can to fight for his country.Returning to London after a recent raid,Sobinski and a group of fellow solider's meet a leading polish Resistance leader called Prof. Siletsky.Proudly saying that he is about to return to Poland to continue his support for the Resistance,Siletsky offers all of the soldiers a chance to each give him a message that he can pass on to their love ones.Thinking that this may be his only chance to give her a message,Sobinski ask Siletsky to give a message to Poland's most famous actress,who Siletsky has never heard of before!..After having given him the message,Sobinski begins to fear that Siletsky may not be all that he seems. View on the film: Writing the screenplay a few months before America got fully involved in WWII,screenwriter's Melchior Lengyel,Edwin Justus Mayer and Ernst Lubitsch strike a remarkable balance of never playing down the grim situation that the characters are involved in,whilst also having each of the cast members deliver still-razor sharp satirical dialogue,that is truly ahead of its time in its design to prick the pompous,authoritarian image of Hitler and the Nazis.From the moment that Hitler cancel's the production of Gastarpo,the writer's show act-or Joseph Tura, (played by a great,egotistical Jack Benny) to be a two bit old ham,whose dream is to use the role of Hitler so that he can soon become a Lawrance Oliveria style legend in the theatre world.Allowing the tremendous,screwball dialogue to move at lightning speed,co-writer/director Ernst Lubitsch also displays real skill in knowing when to slow the exchanges down,to focus on the troubles that the character's are caught in,with the scenes that revel Prof. Siletsky, (played by a wonderfully deranged Stanley Ridgers) true intension being filmed in tight angles,amped up in tension Werner R. Heymann's terrific score.For what would tragically be her final role,stunning Carole Lombard gives a blistering performance as Joseph's less than faithful wife Maria.Along with smoothly handling the film's dramatic moments,as Maria begins to get closer to finding out Siletsky's true intension's,Lombard also clearly displays a true joy for delivering zingers left,right and centre,from doing everything to keep her husband's suspicion's of an affair at bay,to wooing everyone in sight of her figure-hugging dress in an attempt to escape from a Nazi bedroom,which all help to make Lombard's curtain call performance one that will continue to be applauded for years to come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1942, this comedy is set in Warsaw, during the Polish occupation by the Nazis. It unashamedly pokes fun both at Hitler and the Nazi regime, and also the vanity of actors. It tells the story of a Polish acting troupe, including husband and wife couple Joseph and Maria Tura (Jack Benny and Carole Lombard, in her last film), who find themselves tangled up in a plot to stop the Nazis obtaining valuable information. It does not sound like a recipe for a hilarious comedybut that is what this film is. Joseph Tura considers himself an acclaimed Shakespearean actor, and during the film he plays Hamlet (badly!) Maria, his beautiful and feisty wife, catches the eye of Lieutenant Stanislav Sobinski. Joseph is suspicious and jealous, but they soon have greater problems to worry about By the time this film was released, Germany was sweeping across Europe. Also, tragically, Carole Lombard had died in a plane crash, and possibly as a result, the film was initially seen as being in bad taste, and was not appreciated by audiences. Over the years however, it has gained a reputation as a classic comedy, and I think the humour still stands up well for modern viewers. The story is convoluted, but easy enough to follow. The real joy in this film however, is the incredibly funny script and the way that the cast (even the minor players are terrific) deliver their lines. The dialogue fizzes along nicely and there is also plenty of visual comedy. The tragedy and heartache caused by the occupation of Poland is duly acknowledged, and I don't think the film was attempting to make light of the situation at all. One scene in particular shows members of the Nazi army jumping out of a plane to their certain death, on the orders of Hitler, given by radio transmission. The film also shows the burning buildings and the many homeless and grieving families who suffered as a result of Hitler's regime. The subplot is great  concerning Joseph's vexation at his wife's flirtation with a handsome Lieutenant; and said Lieutenant's infatuation with the slightly Maria (flightly she may be, but she is also possessed of a great bravery). Carole Lombard looks beautiful and so full of life and vitality throughout  which in hindsight underlines the sadness of her death at such terrible circumstances at the age of 33. Still, this is how she should be remembered  at her very best. It's a shame that this film turned out to be her swan song, but what a swan song it is. Benny is also terrific; I have never seen any of his work before, but will certainly be searching out more of it! This is one of the American Film Institute's 100 Funniest Comedies, and it deserves its place on that list. Despite the sombre subject matter, this is a film well worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's often overshadowed by The Great Dictator, which preceded it by two years and was technically the first American WW-II themed comedy, but To Be Or Not To Be deserves the honor both for being the first comedy to refer to Hitler and Nazi Germany by name, and also for being made while the US was very much an active side in the war. It's still incredibly funny, but it's much more impressive, almost shockingly so, when you realize that it was made while Hitler was alive, and just how powerful it was back then. Carole Lombard is show-stoppingly terrific, and it's probably the best place to see her talent on display, since sadly it was her final performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Have you seen The Great Dictator or The Producers? Watch this and you'll see where they got the idea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nomoons11
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one is just one funny farce all the way through. Doeesn't hurt Jack Benny is as good as he's ever been on film. To me this was his film. Lombard is in this a lot but she's not near as good as Jack Benny. This film is about 90% comedy and 10% serious. The opening scene comes up and immediately you start to see where Charlie Chaplin and Mel brooks got their inspiration. They got it from a fictitious Polish acting troop trying to put on a farcical play about Hitler (of course Mr. Brooks remade this but it's not in the same league). Not a lot has to be said about this, you just have to watch it and see. An all around funny film. I can see why it has high user ratings in here. Really good stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
