<filme>
 <id>
  1213
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0107057
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1993
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Culpado Como o Pecado
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A female lawyer takes an accused wife-murderer as a client, but finds herself morally compelled to betray him one way or another.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A man accused of murdering his wife approaches a hotshot female criminal attorney to take his case. The man is a self-professed womaniser, and his alleged motive would be the large sum of money his wife left him. The attorney begins to have second thoughts about representing him when he starts making it look like they're having an affair and tells her things she can't reveal because of lawyer/client privilege, so she starts her own investigation of him, which threatens her career and the safety of her friends and herself.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   investigation
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   female lawyer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   lawyer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   pantyhose
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   womanizer
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Sidney Lumet
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Larry Cohen
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Rebecca De Mornay
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Don Johnson
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Stephen Lang
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Courting the Lady Killer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Chicago, beautiful blue-eyed defense attorney Rebecca De Mornay (as Jennifer "Jen" Haines) celebrates a courtroom victory by stripping to her tight underwear and arousing boyfriend Stephen Lang (as Philip "Phil" Garson). Looking very sexy, Ms. De Mornay wins another round. Another handsome man, gigolo Don Johnson (as David Edgar Greenhill), is also interested in De Mornay. Accused of throwing his wealthy wife to her death from a window, Mr. Johnson has decided De Mornay is just the woman to get him off... This slick thriller exemplifies adept direction by Sidney Lumet, photography by Andrzej Bartkowiak and editing by Evan Lottman. The landscape includes some beautifully presented apartments, office buildings and parking structures. Much of the story is involving, but therein are some fault lines. An interesting mix of clich&eacute;s and surprises doesn't mix entirely well. Good is stock character Jack Warden (as Moe), who runs a familiar course. Bad are a couple of plot developments which nonsensically undermine the proceedings. ****** Guilty as Sin (6/4/93) Sidney Lumet ~ Rebecca De Mornay, Don Johnson, Jack Warden, Stephen Lang
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murderer Don Johnson outwits his attorney and himself
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After seeing Don Johnson in "Dead Bang" and especially "The Hot Spot", I've become something of a fan. He again delivered the goods in "Guilty as Sin", an entertaining neo-noir. I give it an extra point for Johnson's performance. In one or two places, I was reminded of how Bruno ensnares and manipulates Guy in "Strangers on a Train." This movie is like "Strangers on a Train" with Guy being instead female. Johnson is a womanizer who lives off women and sometimes kills them for the money. He throws his current wife out a window after arranging an alibi for himself, one that at least raises reasonable doubt. He has pre-planned to get a crack lawyer (Rebecca de Mornay) to defend him and get him off. This she can do and she does. But in the course of the preparation of the trial, Johnson puts into motion a larger scheme, one whose motivation we must figure out. He interferes with his lawyer's personal life and attempts to break up her relationship with her lover who has proposed to her and whom she loves. He wants to seduce her. He wants to share his murderous past with her under conditions where she can reveal nothing due to lawyer-client confidentiality. He tells de Mornay that the defect with perfect murders is not being able to tell anyone. He wants to remedy that defect. Associated with that motive is more. Johnson wants to control her. Getting off for this crime is not enough for him. His motives go deeper. Johnson is psychopathic. He really hates women. He is a repressed homosexual, as Bruno was in "Strangers on a Train." In one scene in which he tries to get de Mornay's sympathy, he portrays himself as being dropped by the women and their plaything. He wonders why men are not seen as the victims. What about his feelings? His whole tone and manner in this outburst are decidedly a feminine or catty parody. Johnson in his acting walked a fine line here and managed this scene well. He accidentally cuts his thumb and then several times sucks his thumb. In another scene with a role reversal, he allows a stranger to him, a woman, to buy him a drink. He is a dandy with his clothes. He stands up in court to show this off when a witness mentions this. If the scripting of de Mornay's character and if her acting had measured up to Johnson's, this picture would have been much better. As it stands, her part was not very deep and her performance was rather bland. She didn't particularly arouse my sympathy. Her role called for a hard-driving lawyer, to be sure, and even when she had sex with her boy friend, she initiated it and was rather cold. However, even taking the role into account, de Mornay seemed to me to belong to that category of acting (or non-acting) that I call "staring". This is when the actor or actress stares but the stare conveys no emotion and the acting fails to use other body language or devices to deepen the characterization. This is not fatal to a performance or a movie usually, not unless the whole cast is doing the zombie routine. There are frequently other things going on that liven up the show. In this case, as long as Johnson was carrying on, de Mornay really didn't have to do much more than become part of the scenery.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder, Mind Games & The Importance of Winning
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Guilty As Sin" is an entertaining courtroom drama with a plot which is very reminiscent of "Jagged Edge". In this story, however, it's the interaction between a defence lawyer and her client that provides the most interesting moments as both parties are very successful at what they do as well as being extremely ruthless. They both share a powerful determination to be winners and it's this compulsion that leads them both, at different times, to take actions which they know to be ill judged and reckless. Jennifer Haines (Rebecca DeMornay), a young criminal lawyer who's made quick progress to the top of her profession, is on a high after winning her latest court case when she's approached by David Greenhill (Don Johnson). Greenhill's a suave ladies' man who's been accused of murdering his rich wife by throwing her out of the window of their apartment and he wants Haines to represent him. At first she doesn't want to take the case but gradually she starts to find him interesting and convinces her superiors that she'd enjoy the challenge of defending Greenhill in what is guaranteed to be a high profile trial. Soon after agreeing to defend her new client, his behaviour becomes more threatening, he starts to get involved in her personal life and also Haines' private investigator, Moe (Jack Warden) begins to uncover some information about Greenhill's past which makes her believe that he is guilty of his wife's murder. Her attempts to drop her client are blocked by a judge and her professional obligations to respect attorney/client confidentiality prevent her from being able to use what she knows against him. With no legal or orthodox way out of her predicament, Haines plants some incriminating evidence in Greenhill's apartment. He immediately guesses that she's responsible and responds by taking some equally unscrupulous action to provide some compelling proof of his innocence. After the trial, Haines and Greenhill continue to play their dangerous mind games right up until the movie's violent denouement. At the outset, both Haines and Greenhill are very confident people but during their association, the psychological battles in which they indulge lead to Haines becoming more and more intimidated, especially when she starts to believe that her own life might be in danger. Rebecca DeMornay portrays Jennifer Haines' courtroom swagger and her addiction to the thrill of winning with the same ability she brings to conveying her growing uncertainty and fear as she realises that she's bitten off more than she can chew and is powerless to put things right. Don Johnson clearly revels in his role as the smarmy gigolo who's arrogant and very dangerous. His transparently insincere charm and his psychopathic behaviour make him a despicable villain who is nevertheless, amusing to watch. Jack Warden also provides good support as Haines' trusted old friend and adviser. "Guilty As Sin" isn't highly original or the type of movie that garners great accolades from the critics, however, for pure entertainment, it fits the bill nicely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Derivative of Hitchcock, obvious but okay...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MarieGabrielle
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film often on The Movie Channel was made in the early 90's when there was a lack of new suspense films...audiences were ready for something more. Also at this time was when "Silence of the Lambs" came out, and for that time was groundbreaking. So for what this is, it is a good TV film. DeMornay as ambitious criminal attorney (she was very good in "The Hand That Rocks the Cradle") wonder what she is filming these days. Anyway, Don Johnson as ladies man who is accused of killing his wife. There is a cameo with Jack Warden (excellenet veteran actor who was also in Lumet's "And Justice for All" and "The Verdict" with Paul Newman an excellent courtroom drama). Overall we have seen the story before, Johnson as conceited narcissist taunting his attorney...there is a twist at the end. There are several familiar scenes which Hitchcock aficionados will pick up on, including the "North by Northwest" cliffhanger ending. It's been done before, but worth watching for a few decent performances. 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's no denying Lumet's experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MovieGuy109
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Did I love the Sidney Lumet film Guilty as Sin? No. Did I enjoy it? You bet. Compared to Lumet's previous films like 12 Angry Men or The Verdict, it's weak, but as entertainment it works. Lumet is always making us question the nature of his characters, are they good or evil? Are they guilty? There's no denying that Lumet is a master of creating questions and letting us slowly receive the answers. The acting is serviceable, Johnson is good as a woman-killing madman, DiMurray makes the grade as a lawyer that loves the smell of victory. Is the dialouge masterful? No. Just like the whole film, it just makes the grade; no more, no less. Yet when you contrast this film with other killer-oriented films, it's honorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Help! Rich Woman In Jeopardy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Usually, before the woman in jeopardy discovers that her client or her handyman or gardener is guilty of murder, she has to fall in love and have an affair with him. The examples are too numerous to list but "Jagged Edge" can serve. In this case, Rebecca De Mornay is a lawyer at a high-end Chicago firm. She's hired by the narcissistic Don Johnson to defend him when he's accused of tossing his wealthy wife out a fourteen-story window. The odd thing -- almost the ONLY unpredictable feature of the movie -- is that she is wary of him from the beginning. She accepts the retainer, gets him out on bail, and defends him in court, with the assistance of the usual flawed investigator. Sometimes the assistant is a drunk -- Robert Loggia or Morgan Freeman -- and sometimes just well meaning but old and a little out of it. Here, it's Jack Warden, who played a similar role in "Verdict," a much better film. This is one hoary suspense device after another. A hand may reach in from off screen at a particularly spooky moment and shock the heroine. It soon becomes clear that Don Johnson is a homicidal maniac and we get scene after scene of people alone at night in deserted urban spaces like empty offices, dark hotel corridors, and those horrible multi-level parking lots with lots of shadows and distant blue neon. I don't know how Sidney Lumet -- a fine director -- could wrap his mind around a story like this. I don't know how he could have coped with it except by dozing off in his director's chair. The plot seems to have been ground out by a computer. Any questions about it could have been answered by a Magic Eight Ball. The art director certainly knew what he wanted. The settings are all sterile and the walls festooned with tasteful paintings. There's never any doubt that we're in greenback territory, although most of the supporting players speak with Canadian accents. There is nothing shabby about the settings, nor should there be. Jack Warden is his reliable self. And Rebecca De Mornay, thoroughly glamorized, has rarely looked so attractive. I thought she was more appealing as the raggedy, freckled, rosy-cheeked stowaway in "Runaway Train," but that's my perversion. She turns in a decent, textured performance too. The same can't be said for Don Johnson. Part of it must be the role as written, slimy and repulsive. But part is also Don Johnson, who has never convinced me that he's a good actor, though he's often cast as some masculine type who carries a cloud of pheromones around with him wherever he goes. This is strictly routine suspense, but if that's what you're looking for, the film delivers it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aside from the good acting and great conclusion this is pretty stupid
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **SPOILERS THROUGHOUT THE REVIEW** High powered attorney Jennifer Haines (Rebecca DeMorany) is seduced by handsome, smooth (and obviously sociopathic) David Greenhill (Don Johnson) into defending him over a charge that he killed his wife. As she gets to know him she discovers that he DID kill his wife and is slowly destroying her life. She gets old friend Moe (Jack Warden is wasted) to help her but David isn't above killing to get his way. It starts off good with great acting by DeMornay and Johnson but the story gets sillier as the movie goes on. Some VERY questionable legal technicalities are bought up and DeMorany goes to truly ridiculous lengths to get Johnson convicted WHILE she's defending him! Also there are huge loopholes in the script and DeMornay overreacts (and overacts) when she realizes what's going on. Seriously, wouldn't an intelligent attorney like her see that Greenhill is a raging sociopath AND extremely dangerous? Still all the acting is good and it leads up to a bloody and satisfying conclusion. I give this a 6 but (unless you're a fan of any of the stars) you're not missing anything. I originally saw it back in 1993 in a theatre and I wasn't thrilled with it then either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stalking and talking ..........
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalking and talking seems to be what "Guilty as Sin" is all about. Don Johnson does the stalking of his lawyer, Rebecca De Mornay, and everyone in the film talks and talks. Unfortunately, the womanizing Johnson, comes across as an almost unreal villain. He assaults Stephen Lang, yet no police are ever involved. He produces a surprise witness, who's motivation for giving him an alibi for his wife's murder borders on ridiculous. The only redeeming factor about Don Johnson is that his character is so despicable, you have to hang around for the ending, simply to see him get what's due. Don't blink however because the end when it finally does come is both swift and a real stretch of reality. Watchable, but not much more. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Very Underrated Courtroom thriller that deserves more attention
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    med_1978
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen this movie numerous times and it has become one of my favourites. Rebecca DeMornay gives a convincing portrayal of slick Chicago Lawyer Jennifer Haines, who is looking to "feel her oats" as she puts it by taking on the toughest cases she can find. Enter the completely psychotic David Greenhill played extremely smoothly and surprisingly convincingly by Don Johnson. He is a compulsive womaniser and has lived off of women most of his life. He is cold calculating but also incredibly charming and attractive to women. He is accused of throwing his wife from an 18 storey window and makes a good case for his own innocence. DeMornay though initially reluctant eventually decides to take on his case and here begins a nerve shredding game of Cat and Mouse that will ultimately end badly for one of them. I really enjoyed the photography and the top drawer performances from the two leads, in particular Don Johnson who totally surprised me in his ability to portray a truly psychotic individual. Stephen Lang's role as DeMornay's boyfriend is small and ultimately inconsequential in the film, Jack Warden's part is also fairly small but he does okay as an investigative aide to DeMornay. Ultimately though your eyes will be firmly glued on the two leads, to see how this plays out. The ending although a little unbelievable does not detract much from the film which for me is worth 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unexpected comedy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Wolfe
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don Johnson is...guilty of sin. Some people have already been offended by my critique of "Guilty as Sin"(1993) and a few others might disagree, with my take on big daddy Don as an over privileged man(murderer). But millions will agree, due to the lack of big ticket sales. The funny part is, that I really have enjoyed many of his performances. This is not as if I'm just looking to sort of stall out on a movie he did because I don't like him. Stephen Lang, is in the cast as well and he really is one heck of a versatile character actor, Sydney (the Director) should have switched the two actors roles.... Johnson's David Greenhill, was a smart-Alec twerp of a womanizer. Sitting at that bar telling that woman she could pay for his drink and that "Women take care of me." was one of the most ridiculously delivered lines I have heard. He, for me didn't come off as a suave lady killer, he came across as a man that you would like to take out to an alleyway and beat the socks off of em'. It was quite a spectacle the way that David dressed in black and a stocking cap and met the lawyer in the parking garage and beat him and his car phone to bits! That was a solid action / drama piece in the story that segue-way-ed nicely into the next place... Don has been in quite a few really 'great' roles, in which he was the only one that you could see there. It would be a crime to put in a different actor, they never would have filled his shoes. But, not here. On the out, the ending in this was 'pure' Hollywood in bad scripted form. Falling off the ledge on top of him, as she makes it out, alive and he dies. Sure. That's just one of the reasons (of many) why I gave this a 5/10 .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Courting the Lady Killer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Chicago, beautiful blue-eyed defense attorney Rebecca De Mornay (as Jennifer "Jen" Haines) celebrates a courtroom victory by stripping to her tight underwear and arousing boyfriend Stephen Lang (as Philip "Phil" Garson). Looking very sexy, Ms. De Mornay wins another round. Another handsome man, gigolo Don Johnson (as David Edgar Greenhill), is also interested in De Mornay. Accused of throwing his wealthy wife to her death from a window, Mr. Johnson has decided De Mornay is just the woman to get him off... This slick thriller exemplifies adept direction by Sidney Lumet, photography by Andrzej Bartkowiak and editing by Evan Lottman. The landscape includes some beautifully presented apartments, office buildings and parking structures. Much of the story is involving, but therein are some fault lines. An interesting mix of clich&eacute;s and surprises doesn't mix entirely well. Good is stock character Jack Warden (as Moe), who runs a familiar course. Bad are a couple of plot developments which nonsensically undermine the proceedings. ****** Guilty as Sin (6/4/93) Sidney Lumet ~ Rebecca De Mornay, Don Johnson, Jack Warden, Stephen Lang
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murderer Don Johnson outwits his attorney and himself
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After seeing Don Johnson in "Dead Bang" and especially "The Hot Spot", I've become something of a fan. He again delivered the goods in "Guilty as Sin", an entertaining neo-noir. I give it an extra point for Johnson's performance. In one or two places, I was reminded of how Bruno ensnares and manipulates Guy in "Strangers on a Train." This movie is like "Strangers on a Train" with Guy being instead female. Johnson is a womanizer who lives off women and sometimes kills them for the money. He throws his current wife out a window after arranging an alibi for himself, one that at least raises reasonable doubt. He has pre-planned to get a crack lawyer (Rebecca de Mornay) to defend him and get him off. This she can do and she does. But in the course of the preparation of the trial, Johnson puts into motion a larger scheme, one whose motivation we must figure out. He interferes with his lawyer's personal life and attempts to break up her relationship with her lover who has proposed to her and whom she loves. He wants to seduce her. He wants to share his murderous past with her under conditions where she can reveal nothing due to lawyer-client confidentiality. He tells de Mornay that the defect with perfect murders is not being able to tell anyone. He wants to remedy that defect. Associated with that motive is more. Johnson wants to control her. Getting off for this crime is not enough for him. His motives go deeper. Johnson is psychopathic. He really hates women. He is a repressed homosexual, as Bruno was in "Strangers on a Train." In one scene in which he tries to get de Mornay's sympathy, he portrays himself as being dropped by the women and their plaything. He wonders why men are not seen as the victims. What about his feelings? His whole tone and manner in this outburst are decidedly a feminine or catty parody. Johnson in his acting walked a fine line here and managed this scene well. He accidentally cuts his thumb and then several times sucks his thumb. In another scene with a role reversal, he allows a stranger to him, a woman, to buy him a drink. He is a dandy with his clothes. He stands up in court to show this off when a witness mentions this. If the scripting of de Mornay's character and if her acting had measured up to Johnson's, this picture would have been much better. As it stands, her part was not very deep and her performance was rather bland. She didn't particularly arouse my sympathy. Her role called for a hard-driving lawyer, to be sure, and even when she had sex with her boy friend, she initiated it and was rather cold. However, even taking the role into account, de Mornay seemed to me to belong to that category of acting (or non-acting) that I call "staring". This is when the actor or actress stares but the stare conveys no emotion and the acting fails to use other body language or devices to deepen the characterization. This is not fatal to a performance or a movie usually, not unless the whole cast is doing the zombie routine. There are frequently other things going on that liven up the show. In this case, as long as Johnson was carrying on, de Mornay really didn't have to do much more than become part of the scenery.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder, Mind Games & The Importance of Winning
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Guilty As Sin" is an entertaining courtroom drama with a plot which is very reminiscent of "Jagged Edge". In this story, however, it's the interaction between a defence lawyer and her client that provides the most interesting moments as both parties are very successful at what they do as well as being extremely ruthless. They both share a powerful determination to be winners and it's this compulsion that leads them both, at different times, to take actions which they know to be ill judged and reckless. Jennifer Haines (Rebecca DeMornay), a young criminal lawyer who's made quick progress to the top of her profession, is on a high after winning her latest court case when she's approached by David Greenhill (Don Johnson). Greenhill's a suave ladies' man who's been accused of murdering his rich wife by throwing her out of the window of their apartment and he wants Haines to represent him. At first she doesn't want to take the case but gradually she starts to find him interesting and convinces her superiors that she'd enjoy the challenge of defending Greenhill in what is guaranteed to be a high profile trial. Soon after agreeing to defend her new client, his behaviour becomes more threatening, he starts to get involved in her personal life and also Haines' private investigator, Moe (Jack Warden) begins to uncover some information about Greenhill's past which makes her believe that he is guilty of his wife's murder. Her attempts to drop her client are blocked by a judge and her professional obligations to respect attorney/client confidentiality prevent her from being able to use what she knows against him. With no legal or orthodox way out of her predicament, Haines plants some incriminating evidence in Greenhill's apartment. He immediately guesses that she's responsible and responds by taking some equally unscrupulous action to provide some compelling proof of his innocence. After the trial, Haines and Greenhill continue to play their dangerous mind games right up until the movie's violent denouement. At the outset, both Haines and Greenhill are very confident people but during their association, the psychological battles in which they indulge lead to Haines becoming more and more intimidated, especially when she starts to believe that her own life might be in danger. Rebecca DeMornay portrays Jennifer Haines' courtroom swagger and her addiction to the thrill of winning with the same ability she brings to conveying her growing uncertainty and fear as she realises that she's bitten off more than she can chew and is powerless to put things right. Don Johnson clearly revels in his role as the smarmy gigolo who's arrogant and very dangerous. His transparently insincere charm and his psychopathic behaviour make him a despicable villain who is nevertheless, amusing to watch. Jack Warden also provides good support as Haines' trusted old friend and adviser. "Guilty As Sin" isn't highly original or the type of movie that garners great accolades from the critics, however, for pure entertainment, it fits the bill nicely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Derivative of Hitchcock, obvious but okay...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MarieGabrielle
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film often on The Movie Channel was made in the early 90's when there was a lack of new suspense films...audiences were ready for something more. Also at this time was when "Silence of the Lambs" came out, and for that time was groundbreaking. So for what this is, it is a good TV film. DeMornay as ambitious criminal attorney (she was very good in "The Hand That Rocks the Cradle") wonder what she is filming these days. Anyway, Don Johnson as ladies man who is accused of killing his wife. There is a cameo with Jack Warden (excellenet veteran actor who was also in Lumet's "And Justice for All" and "The Verdict" with Paul Newman an excellent courtroom drama). Overall we have seen the story before, Johnson as conceited narcissist taunting his attorney...there is a twist at the end. There are several familiar scenes which Hitchcock aficionados will pick up on, including the "North by Northwest" cliffhanger ending. It's been done before, but worth watching for a few decent performances. 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's no denying Lumet's experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MovieGuy109
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Did I love the Sidney Lumet film Guilty as Sin? No. Did I enjoy it? You bet. Compared to Lumet's previous films like 12 Angry Men or The Verdict, it's weak, but as entertainment it works. Lumet is always making us question the nature of his characters, are they good or evil? Are they guilty? There's no denying that Lumet is a master of creating questions and letting us slowly receive the answers. The acting is serviceable, Johnson is good as a woman-killing madman, DiMurray makes the grade as a lawyer that loves the smell of victory. Is the dialouge masterful? No. Just like the whole film, it just makes the grade; no more, no less. Yet when you contrast this film with other killer-oriented films, it's honorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Help! Rich Woman In Jeopardy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Usually, before the woman in jeopardy discovers that her client or her handyman or gardener is guilty of murder, she has to fall in love and have an affair with him. The examples are too numerous to list but "Jagged Edge" can serve. In this case, Rebecca De Mornay is a lawyer at a high-end Chicago firm. She's hired by the narcissistic Don Johnson to defend him when he's accused of tossing his wealthy wife out a fourteen-story window. The odd thing -- almost the ONLY unpredictable feature of the movie -- is that she is wary of him from the beginning. She accepts the retainer, gets him out on bail, and defends him in court, with the assistance of the usual flawed investigator. Sometimes the assistant is a drunk -- Robert Loggia or Morgan Freeman -- and sometimes just well meaning but old and a little out of it. Here, it's Jack Warden, who played a similar role in "Verdict," a much better film. This is one hoary suspense device after another. A hand may reach in from off screen at a particularly spooky moment and shock the heroine. It soon becomes clear that Don Johnson is a homicidal maniac and we get scene after scene of people alone at night in deserted urban spaces like empty offices, dark hotel corridors, and those horrible multi-level parking lots with lots of shadows and distant blue neon. I don't know how Sidney Lumet -- a fine director -- could wrap his mind around a story like this. I don't know how he could have coped with it except by dozing off in his director's chair. The plot seems to have been ground out by a computer. Any questions about it could have been answered by a Magic Eight Ball. The art director certainly knew what he wanted. The settings are all sterile and the walls festooned with tasteful paintings. There's never any doubt that we're in greenback territory, although most of the supporting players speak with Canadian accents. There is nothing shabby about the settings, nor should there be. Jack Warden is his reliable self. And Rebecca De Mornay, thoroughly glamorized, has rarely looked so attractive. I thought she was more appealing as the raggedy, freckled, rosy-cheeked stowaway in "Runaway Train," but that's my perversion. She turns in a decent, textured performance too. The same can't be said for Don Johnson. Part of it must be the role as written, slimy and repulsive. But part is also Don Johnson, who has never convinced me that he's a good actor, though he's often cast as some masculine type who carries a cloud of pheromones around with him wherever he goes. This is strictly routine suspense, but if that's what you're looking for, the film delivers it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aside from the good acting and great conclusion this is pretty stupid
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **SPOILERS THROUGHOUT THE REVIEW** High powered attorney Jennifer Haines (Rebecca DeMorany) is seduced by handsome, smooth (and obviously sociopathic) David Greenhill (Don Johnson) into defending him over a charge that he killed his wife. As she gets to know him she discovers that he DID kill his wife and is slowly destroying her life. She gets old friend Moe (Jack Warden is wasted) to help her but David isn't above killing to get his way. It starts off good with great acting by DeMornay and Johnson but the story gets sillier as the movie goes on. Some VERY questionable legal technicalities are bought up and DeMorany goes to truly ridiculous lengths to get Johnson convicted WHILE she's defending him! Also there are huge loopholes in the script and DeMornay overreacts (and overacts) when she realizes what's going on. Seriously, wouldn't an intelligent attorney like her see that Greenhill is a raging sociopath AND extremely dangerous? Still all the acting is good and it leads up to a bloody and satisfying conclusion. I give this a 6 but (unless you're a fan of any of the stars) you're not missing anything. I originally saw it back in 1993 in a theatre and I wasn't thrilled with it then either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stalking and talking ..........
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalking and talking seems to be what "Guilty as Sin" is all about. Don Johnson does the stalking of his lawyer, Rebecca De Mornay, and everyone in the film talks and talks. Unfortunately, the womanizing Johnson, comes across as an almost unreal villain. He assaults Stephen Lang, yet no police are ever involved. He produces a surprise witness, who's motivation for giving him an alibi for his wife's murder borders on ridiculous. The only redeeming factor about Don Johnson is that his character is so despicable, you have to hang around for the ending, simply to see him get what's due. Don't blink however because the end when it finally does come is both swift and a real stretch of reality. Watchable, but not much more. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Very Underrated Courtroom thriller that deserves more attention
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    med_1978
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen this movie numerous times and it has become one of my favourites. Rebecca DeMornay gives a convincing portrayal of slick Chicago Lawyer Jennifer Haines, who is looking to "feel her oats" as she puts it by taking on the toughest cases she can find. Enter the completely psychotic David Greenhill played extremely smoothly and surprisingly convincingly by Don Johnson. He is a compulsive womaniser and has lived off of women most of his life. He is cold calculating but also incredibly charming and attractive to women. He is accused of throwing his wife from an 18 storey window and makes a good case for his own innocence. DeMornay though initially reluctant eventually decides to take on his case and here begins a nerve shredding game of Cat and Mouse that will ultimately end badly for one of them. I really enjoyed the photography and the top drawer performances from the two leads, in particular Don Johnson who totally surprised me in his ability to portray a truly psychotic individual. Stephen Lang's role as DeMornay's boyfriend is small and ultimately inconsequential in the film, Jack Warden's part is also fairly small but he does okay as an investigative aide to DeMornay. Ultimately though your eyes will be firmly glued on the two leads, to see how this plays out. The ending although a little unbelievable does not detract much from the film which for me is worth 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unexpected comedy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Wolfe
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don Johnson is...guilty of sin. Some people have already been offended by my critique of "Guilty as Sin"(1993) and a few others might disagree, with my take on big daddy Don as an over privileged man(murderer). But millions will agree, due to the lack of big ticket sales. The funny part is, that I really have enjoyed many of his performances. This is not as if I'm just looking to sort of stall out on a movie he did because I don't like him. Stephen Lang, is in the cast as well and he really is one heck of a versatile character actor, Sydney (the Director) should have switched the two actors roles.... Johnson's David Greenhill, was a smart-Alec twerp of a womanizer. Sitting at that bar telling that woman she could pay for his drink and that "Women take care of me." was one of the most ridiculously delivered lines I have heard. He, for me didn't come off as a suave lady killer, he came across as a man that you would like to take out to an alleyway and beat the socks off of em'. It was quite a spectacle the way that David dressed in black and a stocking cap and met the lawyer in the parking garage and beat him and his car phone to bits! That was a solid action / drama piece in the story that segue-way-ed nicely into the next place... Don has been in quite a few really 'great' roles, in which he was the only one that you could see there. It would be a crime to put in a different actor, they never would have filled his shoes. But, not here. On the out, the ending in this was 'pure' Hollywood in bad scripted form. Falling off the ledge on top of him, as she makes it out, alive and he dies. Sure. That's just one of the reasons (of many) why I gave this a 5/10 .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Courting the Lady Killer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Chicago, beautiful blue-eyed defense attorney Rebecca De Mornay (as Jennifer "Jen" Haines) celebrates a courtroom victory by stripping to her tight underwear and arousing boyfriend Stephen Lang (as Philip "Phil" Garson). Looking very sexy, Ms. De Mornay wins another round. Another handsome man, gigolo Don Johnson (as David Edgar Greenhill), is also interested in De Mornay. Accused of throwing his wealthy wife to her death from a window, Mr. Johnson has decided De Mornay is just the woman to get him off... This slick thriller exemplifies adept direction by Sidney Lumet, photography by Andrzej Bartkowiak and editing by Evan Lottman. The landscape includes some beautifully presented apartments, office buildings and parking structures. Much of the story is involving, but therein are some fault lines. An interesting mix of clich&eacute;s and surprises doesn't mix entirely well. Good is stock character Jack Warden (as Moe), who runs a familiar course. Bad are a couple of plot developments which nonsensically undermine the proceedings. ****** Guilty as Sin (6/4/93) Sidney Lumet ~ Rebecca De Mornay, Don Johnson, Jack Warden, Stephen Lang
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murderer Don Johnson outwits his attorney and himself
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After seeing Don Johnson in "Dead Bang" and especially "The Hot Spot", I've become something of a fan. He again delivered the goods in "Guilty as Sin", an entertaining neo-noir. I give it an extra point for Johnson's performance. In one or two places, I was reminded of how Bruno ensnares and manipulates Guy in "Strangers on a Train." This movie is like "Strangers on a Train" with Guy being instead female. Johnson is a womanizer who lives off women and sometimes kills them for the money. He throws his current wife out a window after arranging an alibi for himself, one that at least raises reasonable doubt. He has pre-planned to get a crack lawyer (Rebecca de Mornay) to defend him and get him off. This she can do and she does. But in the course of the preparation of the trial, Johnson puts into motion a larger scheme, one whose motivation we must figure out. He interferes with his lawyer's personal life and attempts to break up her relationship with her lover who has proposed to her and whom she loves. He wants to seduce her. He wants to share his murderous past with her under conditions where she can reveal nothing due to lawyer-client confidentiality. He tells de Mornay that the defect with perfect murders is not being able to tell anyone. He wants to remedy that defect. Associated with that motive is more. Johnson wants to control her. Getting off for this crime is not enough for him. His motives go deeper. Johnson is psychopathic. He really hates women. He is a repressed homosexual, as Bruno was in "Strangers on a Train." In one scene in which he tries to get de Mornay's sympathy, he portrays himself as being dropped by the women and their plaything. He wonders why men are not seen as the victims. What about his feelings? His whole tone and manner in this outburst are decidedly a feminine or catty parody. Johnson in his acting walked a fine line here and managed this scene well. He accidentally cuts his thumb and then several times sucks his thumb. In another scene with a role reversal, he allows a stranger to him, a woman, to buy him a drink. He is a dandy with his clothes. He stands up in court to show this off when a witness mentions this. If the scripting of de Mornay's character and if her acting had measured up to Johnson's, this picture would have been much better. As it stands, her part was not very deep and her performance was rather bland. She didn't particularly arouse my sympathy. Her role called for a hard-driving lawyer, to be sure, and even when she had sex with her boy friend, she initiated it and was rather cold. However, even taking the role into account, de Mornay seemed to me to belong to that category of acting (or non-acting) that I call "staring". This is when the actor or actress stares but the stare conveys no emotion and the acting fails to use other body language or devices to deepen the characterization. This is not fatal to a performance or a movie usually, not unless the whole cast is doing the zombie routine. There are frequently other things going on that liven up the show. In this case, as long as Johnson was carrying on, de Mornay really didn't have to do much more than become part of the scenery.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder, Mind Games & The Importance of Winning
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Guilty As Sin" is an entertaining courtroom drama with a plot which is very reminiscent of "Jagged Edge". In this story, however, it's the interaction between a defence lawyer and her client that provides the most interesting moments as both parties are very successful at what they do as well as being extremely ruthless. They both share a powerful determination to be winners and it's this compulsion that leads them both, at different times, to take actions which they know to be ill judged and reckless. Jennifer Haines (Rebecca DeMornay), a young criminal lawyer who's made quick progress to the top of her profession, is on a high after winning her latest court case when she's approached by David Greenhill (Don Johnson). Greenhill's a suave ladies' man who's been accused of murdering his rich wife by throwing her out of the window of their apartment and he wants Haines to represent him. At first she doesn't want to take the case but gradually she starts to find him interesting and convinces her superiors that she'd enjoy the challenge of defending Greenhill in what is guaranteed to be a high profile trial. Soon after agreeing to defend her new client, his behaviour becomes more threatening, he starts to get involved in her personal life and also Haines' private investigator, Moe (Jack Warden) begins to uncover some information about Greenhill's past which makes her believe that he is guilty of his wife's murder. Her attempts to drop her client are blocked by a judge and her professional obligations to respect attorney/client confidentiality prevent her from being able to use what she knows against him. With no legal or orthodox way out of her predicament, Haines plants some incriminating evidence in Greenhill's apartment. He immediately guesses that she's responsible and responds by taking some equally unscrupulous action to provide some compelling proof of his innocence. After the trial, Haines and Greenhill continue to play their dangerous mind games right up until the movie's violent denouement. At the outset, both Haines and Greenhill are very confident people but during their association, the psychological battles in which they indulge lead to Haines becoming more and more intimidated, especially when she starts to believe that her own life might be in danger. Rebecca DeMornay portrays Jennifer Haines' courtroom swagger and her addiction to the thrill of winning with the same ability she brings to conveying her growing uncertainty and fear as she realises that she's bitten off more than she can chew and is powerless to put things right. Don Johnson clearly revels in his role as the smarmy gigolo who's arrogant and very dangerous. His transparently insincere charm and his psychopathic behaviour make him a despicable villain who is nevertheless, amusing to watch. Jack Warden also provides good support as Haines' trusted old friend and adviser. "Guilty As Sin" isn't highly original or the type of movie that garners great accolades from the critics, however, for pure entertainment, it fits the bill nicely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Derivative of Hitchcock, obvious but okay...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MarieGabrielle
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film often on The Movie Channel was made in the early 90's when there was a lack of new suspense films...audiences were ready for something more. Also at this time was when "Silence of the Lambs" came out, and for that time was groundbreaking. So for what this is, it is a good TV film. DeMornay as ambitious criminal attorney (she was very good in "The Hand That Rocks the Cradle") wonder what she is filming these days. Anyway, Don Johnson as ladies man who is accused of killing his wife. There is a cameo with Jack Warden (excellenet veteran actor who was also in Lumet's "And Justice for All" and "The Verdict" with Paul Newman an excellent courtroom drama). Overall we have seen the story before, Johnson as conceited narcissist taunting his attorney...there is a twist at the end. There are several familiar scenes which Hitchcock aficionados will pick up on, including the "North by Northwest" cliffhanger ending. It's been done before, but worth watching for a few decent performances. 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's no denying Lumet's experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MovieGuy109
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Did I love the Sidney Lumet film Guilty as Sin? No. Did I enjoy it? You bet. Compared to Lumet's previous films like 12 Angry Men or The Verdict, it's weak, but as entertainment it works. Lumet is always making us question the nature of his characters, are they good or evil? Are they guilty? There's no denying that Lumet is a master of creating questions and letting us slowly receive the answers. The acting is serviceable, Johnson is good as a woman-killing madman, DiMurray makes the grade as a lawyer that loves the smell of victory. Is the dialouge masterful? No. Just like the whole film, it just makes the grade; no more, no less. Yet when you contrast this film with other killer-oriented films, it's honorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Help! Rich Woman In Jeopardy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Usually, before the woman in jeopardy discovers that her client or her handyman or gardener is guilty of murder, she has to fall in love and have an affair with him. The examples are too numerous to list but "Jagged Edge" can serve. In this case, Rebecca De Mornay is a lawyer at a high-end Chicago firm. She's hired by the narcissistic Don Johnson to defend him when he's accused of tossing his wealthy wife out a fourteen-story window. The odd thing -- almost the ONLY unpredictable feature of the movie -- is that she is wary of him from the beginning. She accepts the retainer, gets him out on bail, and defends him in court, with the assistance of the usual flawed investigator. Sometimes the assistant is a drunk -- Robert Loggia or Morgan Freeman -- and sometimes just well meaning but old and a little out of it. Here, it's Jack Warden, who played a similar role in "Verdict," a much better film. This is one hoary suspense device after another. A hand may reach in from off screen at a particularly spooky moment and shock the heroine. It soon becomes clear that Don Johnson is a homicidal maniac and we get scene after scene of people alone at night in deserted urban spaces like empty offices, dark hotel corridors, and those horrible multi-level parking lots with lots of shadows and distant blue neon. I don't know how Sidney Lumet -- a fine director -- could wrap his mind around a story like this. I don't know how he could have coped with it except by dozing off in his director's chair. The plot seems to have been ground out by a computer. Any questions about it could have been answered by a Magic Eight Ball. The art director certainly knew what he wanted. The settings are all sterile and the walls festooned with tasteful paintings. There's never any doubt that we're in greenback territory, although most of the supporting players speak with Canadian accents. There is nothing shabby about the settings, nor should there be. Jack Warden is his reliable self. And Rebecca De Mornay, thoroughly glamorized, has rarely looked so attractive. I thought she was more appealing as the raggedy, freckled, rosy-cheeked stowaway in "Runaway Train," but that's my perversion. She turns in a decent, textured performance too. The same can't be said for Don Johnson. Part of it must be the role as written, slimy and repulsive. But part is also Don Johnson, who has never convinced me that he's a good actor, though he's often cast as some masculine type who carries a cloud of pheromones around with him wherever he goes. This is strictly routine suspense, but if that's what you're looking for, the film delivers it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aside from the good acting and great conclusion this is pretty stupid
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **SPOILERS THROUGHOUT THE REVIEW** High powered attorney Jennifer Haines (Rebecca DeMorany) is seduced by handsome, smooth (and obviously sociopathic) David Greenhill (Don Johnson) into defending him over a charge that he killed his wife. As she gets to know him she discovers that he DID kill his wife and is slowly destroying her life. She gets old friend Moe (Jack Warden is wasted) to help her but David isn't above killing to get his way. It starts off good with great acting by DeMornay and Johnson but the story gets sillier as the movie goes on. Some VERY questionable legal technicalities are bought up and DeMorany goes to truly ridiculous lengths to get Johnson convicted WHILE she's defending him! Also there are huge loopholes in the script and DeMornay overreacts (and overacts) when she realizes what's going on. Seriously, wouldn't an intelligent attorney like her see that Greenhill is a raging sociopath AND extremely dangerous? Still all the acting is good and it leads up to a bloody and satisfying conclusion. I give this a 6 but (unless you're a fan of any of the stars) you're not missing anything. I originally saw it back in 1993 in a theatre and I wasn't thrilled with it then either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stalking and talking ..........
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalking and talking seems to be what "Guilty as Sin" is all about. Don Johnson does the stalking of his lawyer, Rebecca De Mornay, and everyone in the film talks and talks. Unfortunately, the womanizing Johnson, comes across as an almost unreal villain. He assaults Stephen Lang, yet no police are ever involved. He produces a surprise witness, who's motivation for giving him an alibi for his wife's murder borders on ridiculous. The only redeeming factor about Don Johnson is that his character is so despicable, you have to hang around for the ending, simply to see him get what's due. Don't blink however because the end when it finally does come is both swift and a real stretch of reality. Watchable, but not much more. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Very Underrated Courtroom thriller that deserves more attention
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    med_1978
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen this movie numerous times and it has become one of my favourites. Rebecca DeMornay gives a convincing portrayal of slick Chicago Lawyer Jennifer Haines, who is looking to "feel her oats" as she puts it by taking on the toughest cases she can find. Enter the completely psychotic David Greenhill played extremely smoothly and surprisingly convincingly by Don Johnson. He is a compulsive womaniser and has lived off of women most of his life. He is cold calculating but also incredibly charming and attractive to women. He is accused of throwing his wife from an 18 storey window and makes a good case for his own innocence. DeMornay though initially reluctant eventually decides to take on his case and here begins a nerve shredding game of Cat and Mouse that will ultimately end badly for one of them. I really enjoyed the photography and the top drawer performances from the two leads, in particular Don Johnson who totally surprised me in his ability to portray a truly psychotic individual. Stephen Lang's role as DeMornay's boyfriend is small and ultimately inconsequential in the film, Jack Warden's part is also fairly small but he does okay as an investigative aide to DeMornay. Ultimately though your eyes will be firmly glued on the two leads, to see how this plays out. The ending although a little unbelievable does not detract much from the film which for me is worth 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unexpected comedy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Wolfe
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don Johnson is...guilty of sin. Some people have already been offended by my critique of "Guilty as Sin"(1993) and a few others might disagree, with my take on big daddy Don as an over privileged man(murderer). But millions will agree, due to the lack of big ticket sales. The funny part is, that I really have enjoyed many of his performances. This is not as if I'm just looking to sort of stall out on a movie he did because I don't like him. Stephen Lang, is in the cast as well and he really is one heck of a versatile character actor, Sydney (the Director) should have switched the two actors roles.... Johnson's David Greenhill, was a smart-Alec twerp of a womanizer. Sitting at that bar telling that woman she could pay for his drink and that "Women take care of me." was one of the most ridiculously delivered lines I have heard. He, for me didn't come off as a suave lady killer, he came across as a man that you would like to take out to an alleyway and beat the socks off of em'. It was quite a spectacle the way that David dressed in black and a stocking cap and met the lawyer in the parking garage and beat him and his car phone to bits! That was a solid action / drama piece in the story that segue-way-ed nicely into the next place... Don has been in quite a few really 'great' roles, in which he was the only one that you could see there. It would be a crime to put in a different actor, they never would have filled his shoes. But, not here. On the out, the ending in this was 'pure' Hollywood in bad scripted form. Falling off the ledge on top of him, as she makes it out, alive and he dies. Sure. That's just one of the reasons (of many) why I gave this a 5/10 .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Courting the Lady Killer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Chicago, beautiful blue-eyed defense attorney Rebecca De Mornay (as Jennifer "Jen" Haines) celebrates a courtroom victory by stripping to her tight underwear and arousing boyfriend Stephen Lang (as Philip "Phil" Garson). Looking very sexy, Ms. De Mornay wins another round. Another handsome man, gigolo Don Johnson (as David Edgar Greenhill), is also interested in De Mornay. Accused of throwing his wealthy wife to her death from a window, Mr. Johnson has decided De Mornay is just the woman to get him off... This slick thriller exemplifies adept direction by Sidney Lumet, photography by Andrzej Bartkowiak and editing by Evan Lottman. The landscape includes some beautifully presented apartments, office buildings and parking structures. Much of the story is involving, but therein are some fault lines. An interesting mix of clich&eacute;s and surprises doesn't mix entirely well. Good is stock character Jack Warden (as Moe), who runs a familiar course. Bad are a couple of plot developments which nonsensically undermine the proceedings. ****** Guilty as Sin (6/4/93) Sidney Lumet ~ Rebecca De Mornay, Don Johnson, Jack Warden, Stephen Lang
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murderer Don Johnson outwits his attorney and himself
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After seeing Don Johnson in "Dead Bang" and especially "The Hot Spot", I've become something of a fan. He again delivered the goods in "Guilty as Sin", an entertaining neo-noir. I give it an extra point for Johnson's performance. In one or two places, I was reminded of how Bruno ensnares and manipulates Guy in "Strangers on a Train." This movie is like "Strangers on a Train" with Guy being instead female. Johnson is a womanizer who lives off women and sometimes kills them for the money. He throws his current wife out a window after arranging an alibi for himself, one that at least raises reasonable doubt. He has pre-planned to get a crack lawyer (Rebecca de Mornay) to defend him and get him off. This she can do and she does. But in the course of the preparation of the trial, Johnson puts into motion a larger scheme, one whose motivation we must figure out. He interferes with his lawyer's personal life and attempts to break up her relationship with her lover who has proposed to her and whom she loves. He wants to seduce her. He wants to share his murderous past with her under conditions where she can reveal nothing due to lawyer-client confidentiality. He tells de Mornay that the defect with perfect murders is not being able to tell anyone. He wants to remedy that defect. Associated with that motive is more. Johnson wants to control her. Getting off for this crime is not enough for him. His motives go deeper. Johnson is psychopathic. He really hates women. He is a repressed homosexual, as Bruno was in "Strangers on a Train." In one scene in which he tries to get de Mornay's sympathy, he portrays himself as being dropped by the women and their plaything. He wonders why men are not seen as the victims. What about his feelings? His whole tone and manner in this outburst are decidedly a feminine or catty parody. Johnson in his acting walked a fine line here and managed this scene well. He accidentally cuts his thumb and then several times sucks his thumb. In another scene with a role reversal, he allows a stranger to him, a woman, to buy him a drink. He is a dandy with his clothes. He stands up in court to show this off when a witness mentions this. If the scripting of de Mornay's character and if her acting had measured up to Johnson's, this picture would have been much better. As it stands, her part was not very deep and her performance was rather bland. She didn't particularly arouse my sympathy. Her role called for a hard-driving lawyer, to be sure, and even when she had sex with her boy friend, she initiated it and was rather cold. However, even taking the role into account, de Mornay seemed to me to belong to that category of acting (or non-acting) that I call "staring". This is when the actor or actress stares but the stare conveys no emotion and the acting fails to use other body language or devices to deepen the characterization. This is not fatal to a performance or a movie usually, not unless the whole cast is doing the zombie routine. There are frequently other things going on that liven up the show. In this case, as long as Johnson was carrying on, de Mornay really didn't have to do much more than become part of the scenery.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder, Mind Games & The Importance of Winning
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Guilty As Sin" is an entertaining courtroom drama with a plot which is very reminiscent of "Jagged Edge". In this story, however, it's the interaction between a defence lawyer and her client that provides the most interesting moments as both parties are very successful at what they do as well as being extremely ruthless. They both share a powerful determination to be winners and it's this compulsion that leads them both, at different times, to take actions which they know to be ill judged and reckless. Jennifer Haines (Rebecca DeMornay), a young criminal lawyer who's made quick progress to the top of her profession, is on a high after winning her latest court case when she's approached by David Greenhill (Don Johnson). Greenhill's a suave ladies' man who's been accused of murdering his rich wife by throwing her out of the window of their apartment and he wants Haines to represent him. At first she doesn't want to take the case but gradually she starts to find him interesting and convinces her superiors that she'd enjoy the challenge of defending Greenhill in what is guaranteed to be a high profile trial. Soon after agreeing to defend her new client, his behaviour becomes more threatening, he starts to get involved in her personal life and also Haines' private investigator, Moe (Jack Warden) begins to uncover some information about Greenhill's past which makes her believe that he is guilty of his wife's murder. Her attempts to drop her client are blocked by a judge and her professional obligations to respect attorney/client confidentiality prevent her from being able to use what she knows against him. With no legal or orthodox way out of her predicament, Haines plants some incriminating evidence in Greenhill's apartment. He immediately guesses that she's responsible and responds by taking some equally unscrupulous action to provide some compelling proof of his innocence. After the trial, Haines and Greenhill continue to play their dangerous mind games right up until the movie's violent denouement. At the outset, both Haines and Greenhill are very confident people but during their association, the psychological battles in which they indulge lead to Haines becoming more and more intimidated, especially when she starts to believe that her own life might be in danger. Rebecca DeMornay portrays Jennifer Haines' courtroom swagger and her addiction to the thrill of winning with the same ability she brings to conveying her growing uncertainty and fear as she realises that she's bitten off more than she can chew and is powerless to put things right. Don Johnson clearly revels in his role as the smarmy gigolo who's arrogant and very dangerous. His transparently insincere charm and his psychopathic behaviour make him a despicable villain who is nevertheless, amusing to watch. Jack Warden also provides good support as Haines' trusted old friend and adviser. "Guilty As Sin" isn't highly original or the type of movie that garners great accolades from the critics, however, for pure entertainment, it fits the bill nicely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Derivative of Hitchcock, obvious but okay...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MarieGabrielle
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film often on The Movie Channel was made in the early 90's when there was a lack of new suspense films...audiences were ready for something more. Also at this time was when "Silence of the Lambs" came out, and for that time was groundbreaking. So for what this is, it is a good TV film. DeMornay as ambitious criminal attorney (she was very good in "The Hand That Rocks the Cradle") wonder what she is filming these days. Anyway, Don Johnson as ladies man who is accused of killing his wife. There is a cameo with Jack Warden (excellenet veteran actor who was also in Lumet's "And Justice for All" and "The Verdict" with Paul Newman an excellent courtroom drama). Overall we have seen the story before, Johnson as conceited narcissist taunting his attorney...there is a twist at the end. There are several familiar scenes which Hitchcock aficionados will pick up on, including the "North by Northwest" cliffhanger ending. It's been done before, but worth watching for a few decent performances. 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's no denying Lumet's experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MovieGuy109
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Did I love the Sidney Lumet film Guilty as Sin? No. Did I enjoy it? You bet. Compared to Lumet's previous films like 12 Angry Men or The Verdict, it's weak, but as entertainment it works. Lumet is always making us question the nature of his characters, are they good or evil? Are they guilty? There's no denying that Lumet is a master of creating questions and letting us slowly receive the answers. The acting is serviceable, Johnson is good as a woman-killing madman, DiMurray makes the grade as a lawyer that loves the smell of victory. Is the dialouge masterful? No. Just like the whole film, it just makes the grade; no more, no less. Yet when you contrast this film with other killer-oriented films, it's honorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Help! Rich Woman In Jeopardy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Usually, before the woman in jeopardy discovers that her client or her handyman or gardener is guilty of murder, she has to fall in love and have an affair with him. The examples are too numerous to list but "Jagged Edge" can serve. In this case, Rebecca De Mornay is a lawyer at a high-end Chicago firm. She's hired by the narcissistic Don Johnson to defend him when he's accused of tossing his wealthy wife out a fourteen-story window. The odd thing -- almost the ONLY unpredictable feature of the movie -- is that she is wary of him from the beginning. She accepts the retainer, gets him out on bail, and defends him in court, with the assistance of the usual flawed investigator. Sometimes the assistant is a drunk -- Robert Loggia or Morgan Freeman -- and sometimes just well meaning but old and a little out of it. Here, it's Jack Warden, who played a similar role in "Verdict," a much better film. This is one hoary suspense device after another. A hand may reach in from off screen at a particularly spooky moment and shock the heroine. It soon becomes clear that Don Johnson is a homicidal maniac and we get scene after scene of people alone at night in deserted urban spaces like empty offices, dark hotel corridors, and those horrible multi-level parking lots with lots of shadows and distant blue neon. I don't know how Sidney Lumet -- a fine director -- could wrap his mind around a story like this. I don't know how he could have coped with it except by dozing off in his director's chair. The plot seems to have been ground out by a computer. Any questions about it could have been answered by a Magic Eight Ball. The art director certainly knew what he wanted. The settings are all sterile and the walls festooned with tasteful paintings. There's never any doubt that we're in greenback territory, although most of the supporting players speak with Canadian accents. There is nothing shabby about the settings, nor should there be. Jack Warden is his reliable self. And Rebecca De Mornay, thoroughly glamorized, has rarely looked so attractive. I thought she was more appealing as the raggedy, freckled, rosy-cheeked stowaway in "Runaway Train," but that's my perversion. She turns in a decent, textured performance too. The same can't be said for Don Johnson. Part of it must be the role as written, slimy and repulsive. But part is also Don Johnson, who has never convinced me that he's a good actor, though he's often cast as some masculine type who carries a cloud of pheromones around with him wherever he goes. This is strictly routine suspense, but if that's what you're looking for, the film delivers it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aside from the good acting and great conclusion this is pretty stupid
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **SPOILERS THROUGHOUT THE REVIEW** High powered attorney Jennifer Haines (Rebecca DeMorany) is seduced by handsome, smooth (and obviously sociopathic) David Greenhill (Don Johnson) into defending him over a charge that he killed his wife. As she gets to know him she discovers that he DID kill his wife and is slowly destroying her life. She gets old friend Moe (Jack Warden is wasted) to help her but David isn't above killing to get his way. It starts off good with great acting by DeMornay and Johnson but the story gets sillier as the movie goes on. Some VERY questionable legal technicalities are bought up and DeMorany goes to truly ridiculous lengths to get Johnson convicted WHILE she's defending him! Also there are huge loopholes in the script and DeMornay overreacts (and overacts) when she realizes what's going on. Seriously, wouldn't an intelligent attorney like her see that Greenhill is a raging sociopath AND extremely dangerous? Still all the acting is good and it leads up to a bloody and satisfying conclusion. I give this a 6 but (unless you're a fan of any of the stars) you're not missing anything. I originally saw it back in 1993 in a theatre and I wasn't thrilled with it then either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stalking and talking ..........
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stalking and talking seems to be what "Guilty as Sin" is all about. Don Johnson does the stalking of his lawyer, Rebecca De Mornay, and everyone in the film talks and talks. Unfortunately, the womanizing Johnson, comes across as an almost unreal villain. He assaults Stephen Lang, yet no police are ever involved. He produces a surprise witness, who's motivation for giving him an alibi for his wife's murder borders on ridiculous. The only redeeming factor about Don Johnson is that his character is so despicable, you have to hang around for the ending, simply to see him get what's due. Don't blink however because the end when it finally does come is both swift and a real stretch of reality. Watchable, but not much more. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Very Underrated Courtroom thriller that deserves more attention
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    med_1978
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen this movie numerous times and it has become one of my favourites. Rebecca DeMornay gives a convincing portrayal of slick Chicago Lawyer Jennifer Haines, who is looking to "feel her oats" as she puts it by taking on the toughest cases she can find. Enter the completely psychotic David Greenhill played extremely smoothly and surprisingly convincingly by Don Johnson. He is a compulsive womaniser and has lived off of women most of his life. He is cold calculating but also incredibly charming and attractive to women. He is accused of throwing his wife from an 18 storey window and makes a good case for his own innocence. DeMornay though initially reluctant eventually decides to take on his case and here begins a nerve shredding game of Cat and Mouse that will ultimately end badly for one of them. I really enjoyed the photography and the top drawer performances from the two leads, in particular Don Johnson who totally surprised me in his ability to portray a truly psychotic individual. Stephen Lang's role as DeMornay's boyfriend is small and ultimately inconsequential in the film, Jack Warden's part is also fairly small but he does okay as an investigative aide to DeMornay. Ultimately though your eyes will be firmly glued on the two leads, to see how this plays out. The ending although a little unbelievable does not detract much from the film which for me is worth 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unexpected comedy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Wolfe
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don Johnson is...guilty of sin. Some people have already been offended by my critique of "Guilty as Sin"(1993) and a few others might disagree, with my take on big daddy Don as an over privileged man(murderer). But millions will agree, due to the lack of big ticket sales. The funny part is, that I really have enjoyed many of his performances. This is not as if I'm just looking to sort of stall out on a movie he did because I don't like him. Stephen Lang, is in the cast as well and he really is one heck of a versatile character actor, Sydney (the Director) should have switched the two actors roles.... Johnson's David Greenhill, was a smart-Alec twerp of a womanizer. Sitting at that bar telling that woman she could pay for his drink and that "Women take care of me." was one of the most ridiculously delivered lines I have heard. He, for me didn't come off as a suave lady killer, he came across as a man that you would like to take out to an alleyway and beat the socks off of em'. It was quite a spectacle the way that David dressed in black and a stocking cap and met the lawyer in the parking garage and beat him and his car phone to bits! That was a solid action / drama piece in the story that segue-way-ed nicely into the next place... Don has been in quite a few really 'great' roles, in which he was the only one that you could see there. It would be a crime to put in a different actor, they never would have filled his shoes. But, not here. On the out, the ending in this was 'pure' Hollywood in bad scripted form. Falling off the ledge on top of him, as she makes it out, alive and he dies. Sure. That's just one of the reasons (of many) why I gave this a 5/10 .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
