<filme>
 <id>
  1215
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0115624
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Barb Wire - A Justiceira
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  3.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Post-Apocalyptic remake of "Casablanca" set in a strip club.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  21st century. USA. The second civil war. The whole country is in a state of emergency. What was formerly called the American Congress now rules with fascistic methods. There is only one free city left, Steel Harbor, headquarter for the resistance. This is the hometown of Barb Wire, owner of the night club Hammerhead. As times aren't good, Barb has a second job. She's a bounty hunter and you probably wouldn't want her after you. Barb's credo is to never take sides for anybody and that's the only way to survive these days. As her former lover Axel Hood appears asking for a favour, Barb suddenly finds herself to be key player on high political stage. Now she has to take sides...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   bounty hunter
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   scientist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bar
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   woman in leather jacket
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   fat man
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   David Hogan
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Chris Warner
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Ilene Chaiken
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Pamela Anderson
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Amir Aboulela
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Adriana Alexander
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the top ten worst films ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Jenkins
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's worth watching purely for the cringe factor. The acting is wooden. The story line is hardly existent, and the script writing is pretty poor too. Let's face it, Pam can't act. The number of cuts (with associated continuity errors) is testament to the number of takes it took to do some scenes. Even just the act of turning over a table seems beyond her and needs to be pieced together from multiple takes. Given the number of takes they had to do they really should have employed a human to manage continuity, rather than the chimpanzee they seem to have had doing the job. If sitting in the corner throwing their poo at passers by can be called "doing the job". And at least they could have picked a stunt double who at least looks vaguely like Pam. The one they chose barely fills the bodice Pam wears, and looks like a man to boot. I mean, Pam's breasts spill over the top of her bodice. Her stunt double has noticeable gaps where flesh (or rather silicone) should be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here's looking at you, Pammy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 2017 and the USA is in the middle of a second civil war. Top-heavy bar-owner Barb Wire lives in the country's only free city, supplementing her income as a mercenary/bounty hunter. When an old flame, freedom fighter Axel (Temuera Morrison), re-enters her life seeking assistance to help a wanted scientist escape to Canada, Barb is reluctant to get involved, but after her blind brother is killed by the Congressionals, she finds herself once again joining the cause. With her ridiculously large chest, tiny waist, massive pout and cascading peroxide blonde locks, 90s sex-symbol Pamela Anderson certainly looks the part, but that's about the only good thing I can bring myself to say about this otherwise miserable mid-90s movie adaptation of Dark Horse comic-book character Barb Wire. Clearly never intended to be anything other than a vehicle to exploit the former Baywatch star's plastic sex appeal, the film is a poorly scripted piece of near-futuristic drivel, a post-apocalyptic Casablanca (complete with thinly veiled Nazis!) that deals in well-worn clich&eacute;s and keeps costs to an absolute minimum by filming exclusively in derelict warehouses, junkyards and dock-lands. David Hogan's direction is uninspired, the 'drama' falls flat (unsurprisingly), and the action, when it eventually happens, is explosive but unexciting, the outcome a long foregone conclusion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well, it could've been worse.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aidiera
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At least they pretended to follow the plot of "Casablanca". Other than that, it's too strange for its own good. Anderson is deadpan throughout the entire movie but still manages to kick ass. Most of the characters were really insane. Charlie had really good vision for a blind guy, Big Fatso was pretty disgusting, and Curly seemed to only be there for comic relief, even though he provided none. It's still an entertaining movie, however. Watching Anderson beat up people was surprisingly funny, and the plot is /just/ crazy enough to be enjoyable. I'd recommend you listen to the "How Did This Get Made" episode for it as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plodding dystopian fluff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    djensen1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barb Wire looks good. Most of the important roles are acted competently, and its star is luminous. In the hands of someone like Paul Verhoeven, it could have been another Total Recall--silly fun that might have balanced Verhoeven's usual violence with a little T&A. Instead, the story plods along in drawn-out sequences that drain the life out of what little fun was written into the screenplay or available from the stylish sets and lighting. The kinky prostitution scam, for example, is a grueling, humorless 3+ minute setup for a lackluster action scene that is followed by a grueling, humorless payoff scene that's just as long. Worse, whole scenes are completely superfluous. The scenes where Axel and Cora get into the city are unnecessary and unexciting. The drunk who is taken care of by Camille is both valueless to the plot and totally unfunny. It's odd that the story was lifted almost entirely from Casablanca and then flubbed so badly by adding such dull scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    was made at a bad time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    15 years after it was made I finally bought this flick and even on Blu Ray, cheap of course. This is one of those flicks that always have got some bad reviews. I can't say anything about the script because I haven't seen the comic. But if I just have a look at the names appearing then you know that this isn't going to be a blockbuster. We have Udo Kier and Steven Railsback in it, for those into horror or exploitation those names are famous. And when I saw the name Rick Bota then I immediately must think of him being directing 3 Hellraisers. The story itself is post-apocalyptic so with those actors and the story we could add it into the grindhouse genre even as it wasn't attempt to be. Naturally the main lead was by Pamela Anderson Lee. Back then she was very hot on all aspects. Just made some nudity shots and a porn flick with her husband and of course Baywatch did the producers add her on the wanted list. But face it, she only in it as a teaser. Every time you see her, the most important things are her fake two penny worth breasts. I even has seen the unrated version and indeed, she goes naked now and then only showing tits and nipples. Did I enjoy it? Just looking towards the story and the actors and the gratuitous nudity I liked it and if it would have been made 20 years earlier or even nowadays (remember Bitch Slap also just made for the boys to watch girlies shooting around and posing) it could have been a bigger success. Naturally it was teared down due Pamela's performance. But Steve did good work as did the rest. But be honest, most flicks based on comics failed to deliver.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The only good thing about it is Pamela Anderson's cleavage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barb Wire isn't the worst movie of 1996(quite), Bio-Dome and Ed are worse, but it is a terrible movie with its only redeeming asset Pamela Anderson's cleavage. Anderson is very sexy and does better than expected in the action sequences, but the way she delivers her lines just for me amplifies her limitations as an actress. And the rest of the acting ranges to pretty poor to non-existent. The action sequences are in a way efficiently performed but choreographed in a generic way and some of the editing feels sloppy. I liked how catchy and how upbeat the soundtrack was but it got a bit too loud and too much after a while, the script is cheesy and weak and the story is so thin you have to watch closely to see if there is a story, and I have no better news about the direction. Overall, a terrible movie. 1/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "don't call me babe"...,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    and don't watch this movie either,unless you're really desperate for something to do.but trust me,you could always find something better to do.i mean wow,this was not good.i managed to get to the forty four minute mark before giving up and shutting it down.there's just no coherent plot here,and no real acting of any kind involved.plus,the music was awful,although that's just personal preference.the opening scene sets the bar pretty low and it just gets worse from there.for some strange reason,Xander Berkeley(who's a quality actor)decided to appear in this mess.oh,well,everybody is entitled to a bad movie once in a while.anyway,for me, because it's not the worse movie i've seen,Barb Wire is a 3/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's face it, if you're looking for depth and a meaning, you've put the wrong movie in your machine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some films that are bad, infamous bad and Barb Wire is one of those I have heard about. Some bad films are trashy but can be a bit fun, like Showgirls and some can just be wrong like Striptease. Barb Wire is a film I guess in some way I'm kind of undecided on, it has the making for just a bad movie with Pamela's bad acting but has the action scenes and cheesy lines that make it fun as well. This movie is a retelling of Cassablanca and isn't so quick to hide that fact, so I guess this is the exotic remake. Pam Anderson is a sexy female lead and isn't that hard to believe that at times she can be tough, she does wear that leather well I have to admit, but some of the way she delivers the lines was a little too Shaquil O'Neil, I think if you're going to do a movie like this, you might as well go over the top, go a little James Woods, it's all good. But we need a fun action film with the lead being female, just sad that this is a bad film that got overlooked. Set in 2017 during the "Second American Civil War", Barb Wire owns the Hammerhead, a nightclub in Steel Harbor "the last free city" in a United States ravaged by the civil war and she brings in extra cash by hiring out as a mercenary and bounty hunter. Her club is raided by Chief of Police Willis, who is looking for the fugitive Dr. Corrina "Cora" Devonshire. Devonshire, a former government scientist, has information about a bioweapon being developed by her former superior, Colonel Pryzer of the Congressional Directorate; she is trying to escape to Canada in order to make this information public. Meanwhile, Devonshire has turned up at the Hammerhead. She is accompanied by Axel Hood, a "freedom fighter" whom Barb had known at the outbreak of the war, but the two were separated soon afterward. Axel is now married to Cora, and is trying to help her get to Canada. They are trying to find a contraband pair of contact lenses which will allow Cora to evade the retinal scan at the Steel Harbor airport. The lenses pass through the hands of several lowlifes before also ending up at Barb's nightclub. Barb Wire really wasn't as bad as I was expecting, even though it's just a remake of a classic romantic movie, it does have some cool moments. I loved some of the action scenes, the fight on the fork lift was a lot of fun to watch and since the movie doesn't take itself too seriously, it's all good and makes the fight scenes that more exciting. I guess I could say that I enjoyed the movie a little bit, I suppose it's a new guilty pleasure. Pam Anderson may be an awful actress, but it's not like I was looking for an Oscar worth movie when I decided to watch it. But I have a feeling that the director has some serious sexual issues considering some of the strange erotic torture devices used in the film are a bit much, maybe I don't want to know. If you have an open mind and are looking for a good bad film, I think you'll get a kick out Barb Wire. However just think if you're looking for an actual action film with good acting, just look at the cover, enough said. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wham! Bam! Thank you Pam!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be perfectly honest with you, my appreciation of this movie is almost solely based on Pamela Anderson's breasts. I'm not going to waste your time and claim anything else. Take Pammy out of 'Barb Wire' and you are left with something highly mediocre. The story, action and other characters are simply by-the-numbers and I really cannot be bothered discussing them. It's Pamela's film pure and simple. It wouldn't be over-stating it to say that I thought the opening credit sequence was quite good. Pamela in tight black leather, half out of her top being soaked by a hose? I would say there's four good ideas in there, all in one. Unfortunately, this is where the film peaks and we are only two minutes in. Sadly, a story kicks in at this point and spoils things. But seriously Ms Anderson is perfect for this flick. Her pneumatic figure couldn't be any better for the role she's playing. She is quite ridiculously sexy throughout the entire picture and the film frankly flags when she is not on screen. She is more than serviceable in this action role too. It's worth pointing out here that I am a big Russ Meyer fan and, therefore, it's perhaps no surprise that I have a huge weakness for dangerous, sexy, buxom women. The biggest compliment I can pay Pammy, therefore, is that on this showing she would not have looked out of place as one of the lead bad girls in 'Faster Pussycat! Kill! Kill!' High praise but quite frankly true. The only criticism I can level at Pamela here is she doesn't get naked enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would have loved this if I saw it when it first came out.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt_Layden
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sort of remake of Casablanca set in the future and in a strip club? Pam Anderson is Barb Wire and she must help someone get on a plane to Canada, with contact lenses. Whatever else the plot is, do people really care? This film was made, marketing and watched because of one thing and one thing only, Pamela Anderson. This was her naked sci/fi Hollywood film, the opening of the movie shows her stripping, showing her breasts and getting hit with water. Ooooh, so sexy. This was probably the one scene many kids watched over and over. The film itself is regarded as one of those, it's so bad it's good. I can totally see that and once I got pass Anderson's wooden acting, I actually enjoyed myself. Guilty as charged. I said I would have loved this when it first came out. I say that because I was around 10 years old and a film like this, that is drenched in so called "sexiness" would have been imprinted on my mind. Seeing it for the first time in full when I'm 22, went to film school and have been on the internet since I was whatever age, the film doesn't strike me as sexy. Anderson does look good though and seeing her prance around in tight leather doesn't hurt either. Much better than what Halle Berry tried to do with Catwoman. Anderson became famous for her breasts and that was the focus of the film. Every other shot is of her massive cleavage. Am I complaining? Not really. But we have porno for that, the catch is that Anderson is someone "somewhat" famous. There is a special feature on the DVD called SEXY OUTTAKES. This is ten minutes long and it is of her stripping with the water. Basically the entire opening, but for ten minutes. Jango Fett from the Star Wars prequels is in this film, I found myself saying "Hey it's that guy" a lot every time a character came on screen. The film is campy, what else do I need to say? The acting is campy, the script is god-awful and taken from Casablanca, the nudity isn't even that good. I expected more, the film feels like a tease. Barb Wire is like Showgirls. Made to appeal to the perverted crowd, only this one has explosions. I'm giving this one a high rating, for it's campiness feel. It's trash, but golden trash.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the top ten worst films ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Jenkins
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's worth watching purely for the cringe factor. The acting is wooden. The story line is hardly existent, and the script writing is pretty poor too. Let's face it, Pam can't act. The number of cuts (with associated continuity errors) is testament to the number of takes it took to do some scenes. Even just the act of turning over a table seems beyond her and needs to be pieced together from multiple takes. Given the number of takes they had to do they really should have employed a human to manage continuity, rather than the chimpanzee they seem to have had doing the job. If sitting in the corner throwing their poo at passers by can be called "doing the job". And at least they could have picked a stunt double who at least looks vaguely like Pam. The one they chose barely fills the bodice Pam wears, and looks like a man to boot. I mean, Pam's breasts spill over the top of her bodice. Her stunt double has noticeable gaps where flesh (or rather silicone) should be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here's looking at you, Pammy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 2017 and the USA is in the middle of a second civil war. Top-heavy bar-owner Barb Wire lives in the country's only free city, supplementing her income as a mercenary/bounty hunter. When an old flame, freedom fighter Axel (Temuera Morrison), re-enters her life seeking assistance to help a wanted scientist escape to Canada, Barb is reluctant to get involved, but after her blind brother is killed by the Congressionals, she finds herself once again joining the cause. With her ridiculously large chest, tiny waist, massive pout and cascading peroxide blonde locks, 90s sex-symbol Pamela Anderson certainly looks the part, but that's about the only good thing I can bring myself to say about this otherwise miserable mid-90s movie adaptation of Dark Horse comic-book character Barb Wire. Clearly never intended to be anything other than a vehicle to exploit the former Baywatch star's plastic sex appeal, the film is a poorly scripted piece of near-futuristic drivel, a post-apocalyptic Casablanca (complete with thinly veiled Nazis!) that deals in well-worn clich&eacute;s and keeps costs to an absolute minimum by filming exclusively in derelict warehouses, junkyards and dock-lands. David Hogan's direction is uninspired, the 'drama' falls flat (unsurprisingly), and the action, when it eventually happens, is explosive but unexciting, the outcome a long foregone conclusion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well, it could've been worse.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aidiera
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At least they pretended to follow the plot of "Casablanca". Other than that, it's too strange for its own good. Anderson is deadpan throughout the entire movie but still manages to kick ass. Most of the characters were really insane. Charlie had really good vision for a blind guy, Big Fatso was pretty disgusting, and Curly seemed to only be there for comic relief, even though he provided none. It's still an entertaining movie, however. Watching Anderson beat up people was surprisingly funny, and the plot is /just/ crazy enough to be enjoyable. I'd recommend you listen to the "How Did This Get Made" episode for it as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plodding dystopian fluff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    djensen1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barb Wire looks good. Most of the important roles are acted competently, and its star is luminous. In the hands of someone like Paul Verhoeven, it could have been another Total Recall--silly fun that might have balanced Verhoeven's usual violence with a little T&A. Instead, the story plods along in drawn-out sequences that drain the life out of what little fun was written into the screenplay or available from the stylish sets and lighting. The kinky prostitution scam, for example, is a grueling, humorless 3+ minute setup for a lackluster action scene that is followed by a grueling, humorless payoff scene that's just as long. Worse, whole scenes are completely superfluous. The scenes where Axel and Cora get into the city are unnecessary and unexciting. The drunk who is taken care of by Camille is both valueless to the plot and totally unfunny. It's odd that the story was lifted almost entirely from Casablanca and then flubbed so badly by adding such dull scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    was made at a bad time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    15 years after it was made I finally bought this flick and even on Blu Ray, cheap of course. This is one of those flicks that always have got some bad reviews. I can't say anything about the script because I haven't seen the comic. But if I just have a look at the names appearing then you know that this isn't going to be a blockbuster. We have Udo Kier and Steven Railsback in it, for those into horror or exploitation those names are famous. And when I saw the name Rick Bota then I immediately must think of him being directing 3 Hellraisers. The story itself is post-apocalyptic so with those actors and the story we could add it into the grindhouse genre even as it wasn't attempt to be. Naturally the main lead was by Pamela Anderson Lee. Back then she was very hot on all aspects. Just made some nudity shots and a porn flick with her husband and of course Baywatch did the producers add her on the wanted list. But face it, she only in it as a teaser. Every time you see her, the most important things are her fake two penny worth breasts. I even has seen the unrated version and indeed, she goes naked now and then only showing tits and nipples. Did I enjoy it? Just looking towards the story and the actors and the gratuitous nudity I liked it and if it would have been made 20 years earlier or even nowadays (remember Bitch Slap also just made for the boys to watch girlies shooting around and posing) it could have been a bigger success. Naturally it was teared down due Pamela's performance. But Steve did good work as did the rest. But be honest, most flicks based on comics failed to deliver.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The only good thing about it is Pamela Anderson's cleavage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barb Wire isn't the worst movie of 1996(quite), Bio-Dome and Ed are worse, but it is a terrible movie with its only redeeming asset Pamela Anderson's cleavage. Anderson is very sexy and does better than expected in the action sequences, but the way she delivers her lines just for me amplifies her limitations as an actress. And the rest of the acting ranges to pretty poor to non-existent. The action sequences are in a way efficiently performed but choreographed in a generic way and some of the editing feels sloppy. I liked how catchy and how upbeat the soundtrack was but it got a bit too loud and too much after a while, the script is cheesy and weak and the story is so thin you have to watch closely to see if there is a story, and I have no better news about the direction. Overall, a terrible movie. 1/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "don't call me babe"...,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    and don't watch this movie either,unless you're really desperate for something to do.but trust me,you could always find something better to do.i mean wow,this was not good.i managed to get to the forty four minute mark before giving up and shutting it down.there's just no coherent plot here,and no real acting of any kind involved.plus,the music was awful,although that's just personal preference.the opening scene sets the bar pretty low and it just gets worse from there.for some strange reason,Xander Berkeley(who's a quality actor)decided to appear in this mess.oh,well,everybody is entitled to a bad movie once in a while.anyway,for me, because it's not the worse movie i've seen,Barb Wire is a 3/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's face it, if you're looking for depth and a meaning, you've put the wrong movie in your machine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some films that are bad, infamous bad and Barb Wire is one of those I have heard about. Some bad films are trashy but can be a bit fun, like Showgirls and some can just be wrong like Striptease. Barb Wire is a film I guess in some way I'm kind of undecided on, it has the making for just a bad movie with Pamela's bad acting but has the action scenes and cheesy lines that make it fun as well. This movie is a retelling of Cassablanca and isn't so quick to hide that fact, so I guess this is the exotic remake. Pam Anderson is a sexy female lead and isn't that hard to believe that at times she can be tough, she does wear that leather well I have to admit, but some of the way she delivers the lines was a little too Shaquil O'Neil, I think if you're going to do a movie like this, you might as well go over the top, go a little James Woods, it's all good. But we need a fun action film with the lead being female, just sad that this is a bad film that got overlooked. Set in 2017 during the "Second American Civil War", Barb Wire owns the Hammerhead, a nightclub in Steel Harbor "the last free city" in a United States ravaged by the civil war and she brings in extra cash by hiring out as a mercenary and bounty hunter. Her club is raided by Chief of Police Willis, who is looking for the fugitive Dr. Corrina "Cora" Devonshire. Devonshire, a former government scientist, has information about a bioweapon being developed by her former superior, Colonel Pryzer of the Congressional Directorate; she is trying to escape to Canada in order to make this information public. Meanwhile, Devonshire has turned up at the Hammerhead. She is accompanied by Axel Hood, a "freedom fighter" whom Barb had known at the outbreak of the war, but the two were separated soon afterward. Axel is now married to Cora, and is trying to help her get to Canada. They are trying to find a contraband pair of contact lenses which will allow Cora to evade the retinal scan at the Steel Harbor airport. The lenses pass through the hands of several lowlifes before also ending up at Barb's nightclub. Barb Wire really wasn't as bad as I was expecting, even though it's just a remake of a classic romantic movie, it does have some cool moments. I loved some of the action scenes, the fight on the fork lift was a lot of fun to watch and since the movie doesn't take itself too seriously, it's all good and makes the fight scenes that more exciting. I guess I could say that I enjoyed the movie a little bit, I suppose it's a new guilty pleasure. Pam Anderson may be an awful actress, but it's not like I was looking for an Oscar worth movie when I decided to watch it. But I have a feeling that the director has some serious sexual issues considering some of the strange erotic torture devices used in the film are a bit much, maybe I don't want to know. If you have an open mind and are looking for a good bad film, I think you'll get a kick out Barb Wire. However just think if you're looking for an actual action film with good acting, just look at the cover, enough said. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wham! Bam! Thank you Pam!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be perfectly honest with you, my appreciation of this movie is almost solely based on Pamela Anderson's breasts. I'm not going to waste your time and claim anything else. Take Pammy out of 'Barb Wire' and you are left with something highly mediocre. The story, action and other characters are simply by-the-numbers and I really cannot be bothered discussing them. It's Pamela's film pure and simple. It wouldn't be over-stating it to say that I thought the opening credit sequence was quite good. Pamela in tight black leather, half out of her top being soaked by a hose? I would say there's four good ideas in there, all in one. Unfortunately, this is where the film peaks and we are only two minutes in. Sadly, a story kicks in at this point and spoils things. But seriously Ms Anderson is perfect for this flick. Her pneumatic figure couldn't be any better for the role she's playing. She is quite ridiculously sexy throughout the entire picture and the film frankly flags when she is not on screen. She is more than serviceable in this action role too. It's worth pointing out here that I am a big Russ Meyer fan and, therefore, it's perhaps no surprise that I have a huge weakness for dangerous, sexy, buxom women. The biggest compliment I can pay Pammy, therefore, is that on this showing she would not have looked out of place as one of the lead bad girls in 'Faster Pussycat! Kill! Kill!' High praise but quite frankly true. The only criticism I can level at Pamela here is she doesn't get naked enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would have loved this if I saw it when it first came out.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt_Layden
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sort of remake of Casablanca set in the future and in a strip club? Pam Anderson is Barb Wire and she must help someone get on a plane to Canada, with contact lenses. Whatever else the plot is, do people really care? This film was made, marketing and watched because of one thing and one thing only, Pamela Anderson. This was her naked sci/fi Hollywood film, the opening of the movie shows her stripping, showing her breasts and getting hit with water. Ooooh, so sexy. This was probably the one scene many kids watched over and over. The film itself is regarded as one of those, it's so bad it's good. I can totally see that and once I got pass Anderson's wooden acting, I actually enjoyed myself. Guilty as charged. I said I would have loved this when it first came out. I say that because I was around 10 years old and a film like this, that is drenched in so called "sexiness" would have been imprinted on my mind. Seeing it for the first time in full when I'm 22, went to film school and have been on the internet since I was whatever age, the film doesn't strike me as sexy. Anderson does look good though and seeing her prance around in tight leather doesn't hurt either. Much better than what Halle Berry tried to do with Catwoman. Anderson became famous for her breasts and that was the focus of the film. Every other shot is of her massive cleavage. Am I complaining? Not really. But we have porno for that, the catch is that Anderson is someone "somewhat" famous. There is a special feature on the DVD called SEXY OUTTAKES. This is ten minutes long and it is of her stripping with the water. Basically the entire opening, but for ten minutes. Jango Fett from the Star Wars prequels is in this film, I found myself saying "Hey it's that guy" a lot every time a character came on screen. The film is campy, what else do I need to say? The acting is campy, the script is god-awful and taken from Casablanca, the nudity isn't even that good. I expected more, the film feels like a tease. Barb Wire is like Showgirls. Made to appeal to the perverted crowd, only this one has explosions. I'm giving this one a high rating, for it's campiness feel. It's trash, but golden trash.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the top ten worst films ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Jenkins
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's worth watching purely for the cringe factor. The acting is wooden. The story line is hardly existent, and the script writing is pretty poor too. Let's face it, Pam can't act. The number of cuts (with associated continuity errors) is testament to the number of takes it took to do some scenes. Even just the act of turning over a table seems beyond her and needs to be pieced together from multiple takes. Given the number of takes they had to do they really should have employed a human to manage continuity, rather than the chimpanzee they seem to have had doing the job. If sitting in the corner throwing their poo at passers by can be called "doing the job". And at least they could have picked a stunt double who at least looks vaguely like Pam. The one they chose barely fills the bodice Pam wears, and looks like a man to boot. I mean, Pam's breasts spill over the top of her bodice. Her stunt double has noticeable gaps where flesh (or rather silicone) should be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here's looking at you, Pammy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 2017 and the USA is in the middle of a second civil war. Top-heavy bar-owner Barb Wire lives in the country's only free city, supplementing her income as a mercenary/bounty hunter. When an old flame, freedom fighter Axel (Temuera Morrison), re-enters her life seeking assistance to help a wanted scientist escape to Canada, Barb is reluctant to get involved, but after her blind brother is killed by the Congressionals, she finds herself once again joining the cause. With her ridiculously large chest, tiny waist, massive pout and cascading peroxide blonde locks, 90s sex-symbol Pamela Anderson certainly looks the part, but that's about the only good thing I can bring myself to say about this otherwise miserable mid-90s movie adaptation of Dark Horse comic-book character Barb Wire. Clearly never intended to be anything other than a vehicle to exploit the former Baywatch star's plastic sex appeal, the film is a poorly scripted piece of near-futuristic drivel, a post-apocalyptic Casablanca (complete with thinly veiled Nazis!) that deals in well-worn clich&eacute;s and keeps costs to an absolute minimum by filming exclusively in derelict warehouses, junkyards and dock-lands. David Hogan's direction is uninspired, the 'drama' falls flat (unsurprisingly), and the action, when it eventually happens, is explosive but unexciting, the outcome a long foregone conclusion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well, it could've been worse.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aidiera
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At least they pretended to follow the plot of "Casablanca". Other than that, it's too strange for its own good. Anderson is deadpan throughout the entire movie but still manages to kick ass. Most of the characters were really insane. Charlie had really good vision for a blind guy, Big Fatso was pretty disgusting, and Curly seemed to only be there for comic relief, even though he provided none. It's still an entertaining movie, however. Watching Anderson beat up people was surprisingly funny, and the plot is /just/ crazy enough to be enjoyable. I'd recommend you listen to the "How Did This Get Made" episode for it as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plodding dystopian fluff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    djensen1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barb Wire looks good. Most of the important roles are acted competently, and its star is luminous. In the hands of someone like Paul Verhoeven, it could have been another Total Recall--silly fun that might have balanced Verhoeven's usual violence with a little T&A. Instead, the story plods along in drawn-out sequences that drain the life out of what little fun was written into the screenplay or available from the stylish sets and lighting. The kinky prostitution scam, for example, is a grueling, humorless 3+ minute setup for a lackluster action scene that is followed by a grueling, humorless payoff scene that's just as long. Worse, whole scenes are completely superfluous. The scenes where Axel and Cora get into the city are unnecessary and unexciting. The drunk who is taken care of by Camille is both valueless to the plot and totally unfunny. It's odd that the story was lifted almost entirely from Casablanca and then flubbed so badly by adding such dull scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    was made at a bad time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    15 years after it was made I finally bought this flick and even on Blu Ray, cheap of course. This is one of those flicks that always have got some bad reviews. I can't say anything about the script because I haven't seen the comic. But if I just have a look at the names appearing then you know that this isn't going to be a blockbuster. We have Udo Kier and Steven Railsback in it, for those into horror or exploitation those names are famous. And when I saw the name Rick Bota then I immediately must think of him being directing 3 Hellraisers. The story itself is post-apocalyptic so with those actors and the story we could add it into the grindhouse genre even as it wasn't attempt to be. Naturally the main lead was by Pamela Anderson Lee. Back then she was very hot on all aspects. Just made some nudity shots and a porn flick with her husband and of course Baywatch did the producers add her on the wanted list. But face it, she only in it as a teaser. Every time you see her, the most important things are her fake two penny worth breasts. I even has seen the unrated version and indeed, she goes naked now and then only showing tits and nipples. Did I enjoy it? Just looking towards the story and the actors and the gratuitous nudity I liked it and if it would have been made 20 years earlier or even nowadays (remember Bitch Slap also just made for the boys to watch girlies shooting around and posing) it could have been a bigger success. Naturally it was teared down due Pamela's performance. But Steve did good work as did the rest. But be honest, most flicks based on comics failed to deliver.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The only good thing about it is Pamela Anderson's cleavage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barb Wire isn't the worst movie of 1996(quite), Bio-Dome and Ed are worse, but it is a terrible movie with its only redeeming asset Pamela Anderson's cleavage. Anderson is very sexy and does better than expected in the action sequences, but the way she delivers her lines just for me amplifies her limitations as an actress. And the rest of the acting ranges to pretty poor to non-existent. The action sequences are in a way efficiently performed but choreographed in a generic way and some of the editing feels sloppy. I liked how catchy and how upbeat the soundtrack was but it got a bit too loud and too much after a while, the script is cheesy and weak and the story is so thin you have to watch closely to see if there is a story, and I have no better news about the direction. Overall, a terrible movie. 1/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "don't call me babe"...,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    and don't watch this movie either,unless you're really desperate for something to do.but trust me,you could always find something better to do.i mean wow,this was not good.i managed to get to the forty four minute mark before giving up and shutting it down.there's just no coherent plot here,and no real acting of any kind involved.plus,the music was awful,although that's just personal preference.the opening scene sets the bar pretty low and it just gets worse from there.for some strange reason,Xander Berkeley(who's a quality actor)decided to appear in this mess.oh,well,everybody is entitled to a bad movie once in a while.anyway,for me, because it's not the worse movie i've seen,Barb Wire is a 3/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's face it, if you're looking for depth and a meaning, you've put the wrong movie in your machine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some films that are bad, infamous bad and Barb Wire is one of those I have heard about. Some bad films are trashy but can be a bit fun, like Showgirls and some can just be wrong like Striptease. Barb Wire is a film I guess in some way I'm kind of undecided on, it has the making for just a bad movie with Pamela's bad acting but has the action scenes and cheesy lines that make it fun as well. This movie is a retelling of Cassablanca and isn't so quick to hide that fact, so I guess this is the exotic remake. Pam Anderson is a sexy female lead and isn't that hard to believe that at times she can be tough, she does wear that leather well I have to admit, but some of the way she delivers the lines was a little too Shaquil O'Neil, I think if you're going to do a movie like this, you might as well go over the top, go a little James Woods, it's all good. But we need a fun action film with the lead being female, just sad that this is a bad film that got overlooked. Set in 2017 during the "Second American Civil War", Barb Wire owns the Hammerhead, a nightclub in Steel Harbor "the last free city" in a United States ravaged by the civil war and she brings in extra cash by hiring out as a mercenary and bounty hunter. Her club is raided by Chief of Police Willis, who is looking for the fugitive Dr. Corrina "Cora" Devonshire. Devonshire, a former government scientist, has information about a bioweapon being developed by her former superior, Colonel Pryzer of the Congressional Directorate; she is trying to escape to Canada in order to make this information public. Meanwhile, Devonshire has turned up at the Hammerhead. She is accompanied by Axel Hood, a "freedom fighter" whom Barb had known at the outbreak of the war, but the two were separated soon afterward. Axel is now married to Cora, and is trying to help her get to Canada. They are trying to find a contraband pair of contact lenses which will allow Cora to evade the retinal scan at the Steel Harbor airport. The lenses pass through the hands of several lowlifes before also ending up at Barb's nightclub. Barb Wire really wasn't as bad as I was expecting, even though it's just a remake of a classic romantic movie, it does have some cool moments. I loved some of the action scenes, the fight on the fork lift was a lot of fun to watch and since the movie doesn't take itself too seriously, it's all good and makes the fight scenes that more exciting. I guess I could say that I enjoyed the movie a little bit, I suppose it's a new guilty pleasure. Pam Anderson may be an awful actress, but it's not like I was looking for an Oscar worth movie when I decided to watch it. But I have a feeling that the director has some serious sexual issues considering some of the strange erotic torture devices used in the film are a bit much, maybe I don't want to know. If you have an open mind and are looking for a good bad film, I think you'll get a kick out Barb Wire. However just think if you're looking for an actual action film with good acting, just look at the cover, enough said. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wham! Bam! Thank you Pam!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be perfectly honest with you, my appreciation of this movie is almost solely based on Pamela Anderson's breasts. I'm not going to waste your time and claim anything else. Take Pammy out of 'Barb Wire' and you are left with something highly mediocre. The story, action and other characters are simply by-the-numbers and I really cannot be bothered discussing them. It's Pamela's film pure and simple. It wouldn't be over-stating it to say that I thought the opening credit sequence was quite good. Pamela in tight black leather, half out of her top being soaked by a hose? I would say there's four good ideas in there, all in one. Unfortunately, this is where the film peaks and we are only two minutes in. Sadly, a story kicks in at this point and spoils things. But seriously Ms Anderson is perfect for this flick. Her pneumatic figure couldn't be any better for the role she's playing. She is quite ridiculously sexy throughout the entire picture and the film frankly flags when she is not on screen. She is more than serviceable in this action role too. It's worth pointing out here that I am a big Russ Meyer fan and, therefore, it's perhaps no surprise that I have a huge weakness for dangerous, sexy, buxom women. The biggest compliment I can pay Pammy, therefore, is that on this showing she would not have looked out of place as one of the lead bad girls in 'Faster Pussycat! Kill! Kill!' High praise but quite frankly true. The only criticism I can level at Pamela here is she doesn't get naked enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would have loved this if I saw it when it first came out.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt_Layden
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sort of remake of Casablanca set in the future and in a strip club? Pam Anderson is Barb Wire and she must help someone get on a plane to Canada, with contact lenses. Whatever else the plot is, do people really care? This film was made, marketing and watched because of one thing and one thing only, Pamela Anderson. This was her naked sci/fi Hollywood film, the opening of the movie shows her stripping, showing her breasts and getting hit with water. Ooooh, so sexy. This was probably the one scene many kids watched over and over. The film itself is regarded as one of those, it's so bad it's good. I can totally see that and once I got pass Anderson's wooden acting, I actually enjoyed myself. Guilty as charged. I said I would have loved this when it first came out. I say that because I was around 10 years old and a film like this, that is drenched in so called "sexiness" would have been imprinted on my mind. Seeing it for the first time in full when I'm 22, went to film school and have been on the internet since I was whatever age, the film doesn't strike me as sexy. Anderson does look good though and seeing her prance around in tight leather doesn't hurt either. Much better than what Halle Berry tried to do with Catwoman. Anderson became famous for her breasts and that was the focus of the film. Every other shot is of her massive cleavage. Am I complaining? Not really. But we have porno for that, the catch is that Anderson is someone "somewhat" famous. There is a special feature on the DVD called SEXY OUTTAKES. This is ten minutes long and it is of her stripping with the water. Basically the entire opening, but for ten minutes. Jango Fett from the Star Wars prequels is in this film, I found myself saying "Hey it's that guy" a lot every time a character came on screen. The film is campy, what else do I need to say? The acting is campy, the script is god-awful and taken from Casablanca, the nudity isn't even that good. I expected more, the film feels like a tease. Barb Wire is like Showgirls. Made to appeal to the perverted crowd, only this one has explosions. I'm giving this one a high rating, for it's campiness feel. It's trash, but golden trash.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the top ten worst films ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Jenkins
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's worth watching purely for the cringe factor. The acting is wooden. The story line is hardly existent, and the script writing is pretty poor too. Let's face it, Pam can't act. The number of cuts (with associated continuity errors) is testament to the number of takes it took to do some scenes. Even just the act of turning over a table seems beyond her and needs to be pieced together from multiple takes. Given the number of takes they had to do they really should have employed a human to manage continuity, rather than the chimpanzee they seem to have had doing the job. If sitting in the corner throwing their poo at passers by can be called "doing the job". And at least they could have picked a stunt double who at least looks vaguely like Pam. The one they chose barely fills the bodice Pam wears, and looks like a man to boot. I mean, Pam's breasts spill over the top of her bodice. Her stunt double has noticeable gaps where flesh (or rather silicone) should be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here's looking at you, Pammy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 2017 and the USA is in the middle of a second civil war. Top-heavy bar-owner Barb Wire lives in the country's only free city, supplementing her income as a mercenary/bounty hunter. When an old flame, freedom fighter Axel (Temuera Morrison), re-enters her life seeking assistance to help a wanted scientist escape to Canada, Barb is reluctant to get involved, but after her blind brother is killed by the Congressionals, she finds herself once again joining the cause. With her ridiculously large chest, tiny waist, massive pout and cascading peroxide blonde locks, 90s sex-symbol Pamela Anderson certainly looks the part, but that's about the only good thing I can bring myself to say about this otherwise miserable mid-90s movie adaptation of Dark Horse comic-book character Barb Wire. Clearly never intended to be anything other than a vehicle to exploit the former Baywatch star's plastic sex appeal, the film is a poorly scripted piece of near-futuristic drivel, a post-apocalyptic Casablanca (complete with thinly veiled Nazis!) that deals in well-worn clich&eacute;s and keeps costs to an absolute minimum by filming exclusively in derelict warehouses, junkyards and dock-lands. David Hogan's direction is uninspired, the 'drama' falls flat (unsurprisingly), and the action, when it eventually happens, is explosive but unexciting, the outcome a long foregone conclusion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well, it could've been worse.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aidiera
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At least they pretended to follow the plot of "Casablanca". Other than that, it's too strange for its own good. Anderson is deadpan throughout the entire movie but still manages to kick ass. Most of the characters were really insane. Charlie had really good vision for a blind guy, Big Fatso was pretty disgusting, and Curly seemed to only be there for comic relief, even though he provided none. It's still an entertaining movie, however. Watching Anderson beat up people was surprisingly funny, and the plot is /just/ crazy enough to be enjoyable. I'd recommend you listen to the "How Did This Get Made" episode for it as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plodding dystopian fluff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    djensen1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barb Wire looks good. Most of the important roles are acted competently, and its star is luminous. In the hands of someone like Paul Verhoeven, it could have been another Total Recall--silly fun that might have balanced Verhoeven's usual violence with a little T&A. Instead, the story plods along in drawn-out sequences that drain the life out of what little fun was written into the screenplay or available from the stylish sets and lighting. The kinky prostitution scam, for example, is a grueling, humorless 3+ minute setup for a lackluster action scene that is followed by a grueling, humorless payoff scene that's just as long. Worse, whole scenes are completely superfluous. The scenes where Axel and Cora get into the city are unnecessary and unexciting. The drunk who is taken care of by Camille is both valueless to the plot and totally unfunny. It's odd that the story was lifted almost entirely from Casablanca and then flubbed so badly by adding such dull scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    was made at a bad time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    15 years after it was made I finally bought this flick and even on Blu Ray, cheap of course. This is one of those flicks that always have got some bad reviews. I can't say anything about the script because I haven't seen the comic. But if I just have a look at the names appearing then you know that this isn't going to be a blockbuster. We have Udo Kier and Steven Railsback in it, for those into horror or exploitation those names are famous. And when I saw the name Rick Bota then I immediately must think of him being directing 3 Hellraisers. The story itself is post-apocalyptic so with those actors and the story we could add it into the grindhouse genre even as it wasn't attempt to be. Naturally the main lead was by Pamela Anderson Lee. Back then she was very hot on all aspects. Just made some nudity shots and a porn flick with her husband and of course Baywatch did the producers add her on the wanted list. But face it, she only in it as a teaser. Every time you see her, the most important things are her fake two penny worth breasts. I even has seen the unrated version and indeed, she goes naked now and then only showing tits and nipples. Did I enjoy it? Just looking towards the story and the actors and the gratuitous nudity I liked it and if it would have been made 20 years earlier or even nowadays (remember Bitch Slap also just made for the boys to watch girlies shooting around and posing) it could have been a bigger success. Naturally it was teared down due Pamela's performance. But Steve did good work as did the rest. But be honest, most flicks based on comics failed to deliver.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The only good thing about it is Pamela Anderson's cleavage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barb Wire isn't the worst movie of 1996(quite), Bio-Dome and Ed are worse, but it is a terrible movie with its only redeeming asset Pamela Anderson's cleavage. Anderson is very sexy and does better than expected in the action sequences, but the way she delivers her lines just for me amplifies her limitations as an actress. And the rest of the acting ranges to pretty poor to non-existent. The action sequences are in a way efficiently performed but choreographed in a generic way and some of the editing feels sloppy. I liked how catchy and how upbeat the soundtrack was but it got a bit too loud and too much after a while, the script is cheesy and weak and the story is so thin you have to watch closely to see if there is a story, and I have no better news about the direction. Overall, a terrible movie. 1/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "don't call me babe"...,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    and don't watch this movie either,unless you're really desperate for something to do.but trust me,you could always find something better to do.i mean wow,this was not good.i managed to get to the forty four minute mark before giving up and shutting it down.there's just no coherent plot here,and no real acting of any kind involved.plus,the music was awful,although that's just personal preference.the opening scene sets the bar pretty low and it just gets worse from there.for some strange reason,Xander Berkeley(who's a quality actor)decided to appear in this mess.oh,well,everybody is entitled to a bad movie once in a while.anyway,for me, because it's not the worse movie i've seen,Barb Wire is a 3/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's face it, if you're looking for depth and a meaning, you've put the wrong movie in your machine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some films that are bad, infamous bad and Barb Wire is one of those I have heard about. Some bad films are trashy but can be a bit fun, like Showgirls and some can just be wrong like Striptease. Barb Wire is a film I guess in some way I'm kind of undecided on, it has the making for just a bad movie with Pamela's bad acting but has the action scenes and cheesy lines that make it fun as well. This movie is a retelling of Cassablanca and isn't so quick to hide that fact, so I guess this is the exotic remake. Pam Anderson is a sexy female lead and isn't that hard to believe that at times she can be tough, she does wear that leather well I have to admit, but some of the way she delivers the lines was a little too Shaquil O'Neil, I think if you're going to do a movie like this, you might as well go over the top, go a little James Woods, it's all good. But we need a fun action film with the lead being female, just sad that this is a bad film that got overlooked. Set in 2017 during the "Second American Civil War", Barb Wire owns the Hammerhead, a nightclub in Steel Harbor "the last free city" in a United States ravaged by the civil war and she brings in extra cash by hiring out as a mercenary and bounty hunter. Her club is raided by Chief of Police Willis, who is looking for the fugitive Dr. Corrina "Cora" Devonshire. Devonshire, a former government scientist, has information about a bioweapon being developed by her former superior, Colonel Pryzer of the Congressional Directorate; she is trying to escape to Canada in order to make this information public. Meanwhile, Devonshire has turned up at the Hammerhead. She is accompanied by Axel Hood, a "freedom fighter" whom Barb had known at the outbreak of the war, but the two were separated soon afterward. Axel is now married to Cora, and is trying to help her get to Canada. They are trying to find a contraband pair of contact lenses which will allow Cora to evade the retinal scan at the Steel Harbor airport. The lenses pass through the hands of several lowlifes before also ending up at Barb's nightclub. Barb Wire really wasn't as bad as I was expecting, even though it's just a remake of a classic romantic movie, it does have some cool moments. I loved some of the action scenes, the fight on the fork lift was a lot of fun to watch and since the movie doesn't take itself too seriously, it's all good and makes the fight scenes that more exciting. I guess I could say that I enjoyed the movie a little bit, I suppose it's a new guilty pleasure. Pam Anderson may be an awful actress, but it's not like I was looking for an Oscar worth movie when I decided to watch it. But I have a feeling that the director has some serious sexual issues considering some of the strange erotic torture devices used in the film are a bit much, maybe I don't want to know. If you have an open mind and are looking for a good bad film, I think you'll get a kick out Barb Wire. However just think if you're looking for an actual action film with good acting, just look at the cover, enough said. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wham! Bam! Thank you Pam!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be perfectly honest with you, my appreciation of this movie is almost solely based on Pamela Anderson's breasts. I'm not going to waste your time and claim anything else. Take Pammy out of 'Barb Wire' and you are left with something highly mediocre. The story, action and other characters are simply by-the-numbers and I really cannot be bothered discussing them. It's Pamela's film pure and simple. It wouldn't be over-stating it to say that I thought the opening credit sequence was quite good. Pamela in tight black leather, half out of her top being soaked by a hose? I would say there's four good ideas in there, all in one. Unfortunately, this is where the film peaks and we are only two minutes in. Sadly, a story kicks in at this point and spoils things. But seriously Ms Anderson is perfect for this flick. Her pneumatic figure couldn't be any better for the role she's playing. She is quite ridiculously sexy throughout the entire picture and the film frankly flags when she is not on screen. She is more than serviceable in this action role too. It's worth pointing out here that I am a big Russ Meyer fan and, therefore, it's perhaps no surprise that I have a huge weakness for dangerous, sexy, buxom women. The biggest compliment I can pay Pammy, therefore, is that on this showing she would not have looked out of place as one of the lead bad girls in 'Faster Pussycat! Kill! Kill!' High praise but quite frankly true. The only criticism I can level at Pamela here is she doesn't get naked enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would have loved this if I saw it when it first came out.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt_Layden
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sort of remake of Casablanca set in the future and in a strip club? Pam Anderson is Barb Wire and she must help someone get on a plane to Canada, with contact lenses. Whatever else the plot is, do people really care? This film was made, marketing and watched because of one thing and one thing only, Pamela Anderson. This was her naked sci/fi Hollywood film, the opening of the movie shows her stripping, showing her breasts and getting hit with water. Ooooh, so sexy. This was probably the one scene many kids watched over and over. The film itself is regarded as one of those, it's so bad it's good. I can totally see that and once I got pass Anderson's wooden acting, I actually enjoyed myself. Guilty as charged. I said I would have loved this when it first came out. I say that because I was around 10 years old and a film like this, that is drenched in so called "sexiness" would have been imprinted on my mind. Seeing it for the first time in full when I'm 22, went to film school and have been on the internet since I was whatever age, the film doesn't strike me as sexy. Anderson does look good though and seeing her prance around in tight leather doesn't hurt either. Much better than what Halle Berry tried to do with Catwoman. Anderson became famous for her breasts and that was the focus of the film. Every other shot is of her massive cleavage. Am I complaining? Not really. But we have porno for that, the catch is that Anderson is someone "somewhat" famous. There is a special feature on the DVD called SEXY OUTTAKES. This is ten minutes long and it is of her stripping with the water. Basically the entire opening, but for ten minutes. Jango Fett from the Star Wars prequels is in this film, I found myself saying "Hey it's that guy" a lot every time a character came on screen. The film is campy, what else do I need to say? The acting is campy, the script is god-awful and taken from Casablanca, the nudity isn't even that good. I expected more, the film feels like a tease. Barb Wire is like Showgirls. Made to appeal to the perverted crowd, only this one has explosions. I'm giving this one a high rating, for it's campiness feel. It's trash, but golden trash.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the top ten worst films ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Jenkins
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's worth watching purely for the cringe factor. The acting is wooden. The story line is hardly existent, and the script writing is pretty poor too. Let's face it, Pam can't act. The number of cuts (with associated continuity errors) is testament to the number of takes it took to do some scenes. Even just the act of turning over a table seems beyond her and needs to be pieced together from multiple takes. Given the number of takes they had to do they really should have employed a human to manage continuity, rather than the chimpanzee they seem to have had doing the job. If sitting in the corner throwing their poo at passers by can be called "doing the job". And at least they could have picked a stunt double who at least looks vaguely like Pam. The one they chose barely fills the bodice Pam wears, and looks like a man to boot. I mean, Pam's breasts spill over the top of her bodice. Her stunt double has noticeable gaps where flesh (or rather silicone) should be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here's looking at you, Pammy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 2017 and the USA is in the middle of a second civil war. Top-heavy bar-owner Barb Wire lives in the country's only free city, supplementing her income as a mercenary/bounty hunter. When an old flame, freedom fighter Axel (Temuera Morrison), re-enters her life seeking assistance to help a wanted scientist escape to Canada, Barb is reluctant to get involved, but after her blind brother is killed by the Congressionals, she finds herself once again joining the cause. With her ridiculously large chest, tiny waist, massive pout and cascading peroxide blonde locks, 90s sex-symbol Pamela Anderson certainly looks the part, but that's about the only good thing I can bring myself to say about this otherwise miserable mid-90s movie adaptation of Dark Horse comic-book character Barb Wire. Clearly never intended to be anything other than a vehicle to exploit the former Baywatch star's plastic sex appeal, the film is a poorly scripted piece of near-futuristic drivel, a post-apocalyptic Casablanca (complete with thinly veiled Nazis!) that deals in well-worn clich&eacute;s and keeps costs to an absolute minimum by filming exclusively in derelict warehouses, junkyards and dock-lands. David Hogan's direction is uninspired, the 'drama' falls flat (unsurprisingly), and the action, when it eventually happens, is explosive but unexciting, the outcome a long foregone conclusion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well, it could've been worse.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aidiera
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At least they pretended to follow the plot of "Casablanca". Other than that, it's too strange for its own good. Anderson is deadpan throughout the entire movie but still manages to kick ass. Most of the characters were really insane. Charlie had really good vision for a blind guy, Big Fatso was pretty disgusting, and Curly seemed to only be there for comic relief, even though he provided none. It's still an entertaining movie, however. Watching Anderson beat up people was surprisingly funny, and the plot is /just/ crazy enough to be enjoyable. I'd recommend you listen to the "How Did This Get Made" episode for it as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plodding dystopian fluff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    djensen1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barb Wire looks good. Most of the important roles are acted competently, and its star is luminous. In the hands of someone like Paul Verhoeven, it could have been another Total Recall--silly fun that might have balanced Verhoeven's usual violence with a little T&A. Instead, the story plods along in drawn-out sequences that drain the life out of what little fun was written into the screenplay or available from the stylish sets and lighting. The kinky prostitution scam, for example, is a grueling, humorless 3+ minute setup for a lackluster action scene that is followed by a grueling, humorless payoff scene that's just as long. Worse, whole scenes are completely superfluous. The scenes where Axel and Cora get into the city are unnecessary and unexciting. The drunk who is taken care of by Camille is both valueless to the plot and totally unfunny. It's odd that the story was lifted almost entirely from Casablanca and then flubbed so badly by adding such dull scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    was made at a bad time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    15 years after it was made I finally bought this flick and even on Blu Ray, cheap of course. This is one of those flicks that always have got some bad reviews. I can't say anything about the script because I haven't seen the comic. But if I just have a look at the names appearing then you know that this isn't going to be a blockbuster. We have Udo Kier and Steven Railsback in it, for those into horror or exploitation those names are famous. And when I saw the name Rick Bota then I immediately must think of him being directing 3 Hellraisers. The story itself is post-apocalyptic so with those actors and the story we could add it into the grindhouse genre even as it wasn't attempt to be. Naturally the main lead was by Pamela Anderson Lee. Back then she was very hot on all aspects. Just made some nudity shots and a porn flick with her husband and of course Baywatch did the producers add her on the wanted list. But face it, she only in it as a teaser. Every time you see her, the most important things are her fake two penny worth breasts. I even has seen the unrated version and indeed, she goes naked now and then only showing tits and nipples. Did I enjoy it? Just looking towards the story and the actors and the gratuitous nudity I liked it and if it would have been made 20 years earlier or even nowadays (remember Bitch Slap also just made for the boys to watch girlies shooting around and posing) it could have been a bigger success. Naturally it was teared down due Pamela's performance. But Steve did good work as did the rest. But be honest, most flicks based on comics failed to deliver.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The only good thing about it is Pamela Anderson's cleavage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barb Wire isn't the worst movie of 1996(quite), Bio-Dome and Ed are worse, but it is a terrible movie with its only redeeming asset Pamela Anderson's cleavage. Anderson is very sexy and does better than expected in the action sequences, but the way she delivers her lines just for me amplifies her limitations as an actress. And the rest of the acting ranges to pretty poor to non-existent. The action sequences are in a way efficiently performed but choreographed in a generic way and some of the editing feels sloppy. I liked how catchy and how upbeat the soundtrack was but it got a bit too loud and too much after a while, the script is cheesy and weak and the story is so thin you have to watch closely to see if there is a story, and I have no better news about the direction. Overall, a terrible movie. 1/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "don't call me babe"...,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    and don't watch this movie either,unless you're really desperate for something to do.but trust me,you could always find something better to do.i mean wow,this was not good.i managed to get to the forty four minute mark before giving up and shutting it down.there's just no coherent plot here,and no real acting of any kind involved.plus,the music was awful,although that's just personal preference.the opening scene sets the bar pretty low and it just gets worse from there.for some strange reason,Xander Berkeley(who's a quality actor)decided to appear in this mess.oh,well,everybody is entitled to a bad movie once in a while.anyway,for me, because it's not the worse movie i've seen,Barb Wire is a 3/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's face it, if you're looking for depth and a meaning, you've put the wrong movie in your machine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some films that are bad, infamous bad and Barb Wire is one of those I have heard about. Some bad films are trashy but can be a bit fun, like Showgirls and some can just be wrong like Striptease. Barb Wire is a film I guess in some way I'm kind of undecided on, it has the making for just a bad movie with Pamela's bad acting but has the action scenes and cheesy lines that make it fun as well. This movie is a retelling of Cassablanca and isn't so quick to hide that fact, so I guess this is the exotic remake. Pam Anderson is a sexy female lead and isn't that hard to believe that at times she can be tough, she does wear that leather well I have to admit, but some of the way she delivers the lines was a little too Shaquil O'Neil, I think if you're going to do a movie like this, you might as well go over the top, go a little James Woods, it's all good. But we need a fun action film with the lead being female, just sad that this is a bad film that got overlooked. Set in 2017 during the "Second American Civil War", Barb Wire owns the Hammerhead, a nightclub in Steel Harbor "the last free city" in a United States ravaged by the civil war and she brings in extra cash by hiring out as a mercenary and bounty hunter. Her club is raided by Chief of Police Willis, who is looking for the fugitive Dr. Corrina "Cora" Devonshire. Devonshire, a former government scientist, has information about a bioweapon being developed by her former superior, Colonel Pryzer of the Congressional Directorate; she is trying to escape to Canada in order to make this information public. Meanwhile, Devonshire has turned up at the Hammerhead. She is accompanied by Axel Hood, a "freedom fighter" whom Barb had known at the outbreak of the war, but the two were separated soon afterward. Axel is now married to Cora, and is trying to help her get to Canada. They are trying to find a contraband pair of contact lenses which will allow Cora to evade the retinal scan at the Steel Harbor airport. The lenses pass through the hands of several lowlifes before also ending up at Barb's nightclub. Barb Wire really wasn't as bad as I was expecting, even though it's just a remake of a classic romantic movie, it does have some cool moments. I loved some of the action scenes, the fight on the fork lift was a lot of fun to watch and since the movie doesn't take itself too seriously, it's all good and makes the fight scenes that more exciting. I guess I could say that I enjoyed the movie a little bit, I suppose it's a new guilty pleasure. Pam Anderson may be an awful actress, but it's not like I was looking for an Oscar worth movie when I decided to watch it. But I have a feeling that the director has some serious sexual issues considering some of the strange erotic torture devices used in the film are a bit much, maybe I don't want to know. If you have an open mind and are looking for a good bad film, I think you'll get a kick out Barb Wire. However just think if you're looking for an actual action film with good acting, just look at the cover, enough said. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wham! Bam! Thank you Pam!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be perfectly honest with you, my appreciation of this movie is almost solely based on Pamela Anderson's breasts. I'm not going to waste your time and claim anything else. Take Pammy out of 'Barb Wire' and you are left with something highly mediocre. The story, action and other characters are simply by-the-numbers and I really cannot be bothered discussing them. It's Pamela's film pure and simple. It wouldn't be over-stating it to say that I thought the opening credit sequence was quite good. Pamela in tight black leather, half out of her top being soaked by a hose? I would say there's four good ideas in there, all in one. Unfortunately, this is where the film peaks and we are only two minutes in. Sadly, a story kicks in at this point and spoils things. But seriously Ms Anderson is perfect for this flick. Her pneumatic figure couldn't be any better for the role she's playing. She is quite ridiculously sexy throughout the entire picture and the film frankly flags when she is not on screen. She is more than serviceable in this action role too. It's worth pointing out here that I am a big Russ Meyer fan and, therefore, it's perhaps no surprise that I have a huge weakness for dangerous, sexy, buxom women. The biggest compliment I can pay Pammy, therefore, is that on this showing she would not have looked out of place as one of the lead bad girls in 'Faster Pussycat! Kill! Kill!' High praise but quite frankly true. The only criticism I can level at Pamela here is she doesn't get naked enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would have loved this if I saw it when it first came out.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt_Layden
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sort of remake of Casablanca set in the future and in a strip club? Pam Anderson is Barb Wire and she must help someone get on a plane to Canada, with contact lenses. Whatever else the plot is, do people really care? This film was made, marketing and watched because of one thing and one thing only, Pamela Anderson. This was her naked sci/fi Hollywood film, the opening of the movie shows her stripping, showing her breasts and getting hit with water. Ooooh, so sexy. This was probably the one scene many kids watched over and over. The film itself is regarded as one of those, it's so bad it's good. I can totally see that and once I got pass Anderson's wooden acting, I actually enjoyed myself. Guilty as charged. I said I would have loved this when it first came out. I say that because I was around 10 years old and a film like this, that is drenched in so called "sexiness" would have been imprinted on my mind. Seeing it for the first time in full when I'm 22, went to film school and have been on the internet since I was whatever age, the film doesn't strike me as sexy. Anderson does look good though and seeing her prance around in tight leather doesn't hurt either. Much better than what Halle Berry tried to do with Catwoman. Anderson became famous for her breasts and that was the focus of the film. Every other shot is of her massive cleavage. Am I complaining? Not really. But we have porno for that, the catch is that Anderson is someone "somewhat" famous. There is a special feature on the DVD called SEXY OUTTAKES. This is ten minutes long and it is of her stripping with the water. Basically the entire opening, but for ten minutes. Jango Fett from the Star Wars prequels is in this film, I found myself saying "Hey it's that guy" a lot every time a character came on screen. The film is campy, what else do I need to say? The acting is campy, the script is god-awful and taken from Casablanca, the nudity isn't even that good. I expected more, the film feels like a tease. Barb Wire is like Showgirls. Made to appeal to the perverted crowd, only this one has explosions. I'm giving this one a high rating, for it's campiness feel. It's trash, but golden trash.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the top ten worst films ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Jenkins
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's worth watching purely for the cringe factor. The acting is wooden. The story line is hardly existent, and the script writing is pretty poor too. Let's face it, Pam can't act. The number of cuts (with associated continuity errors) is testament to the number of takes it took to do some scenes. Even just the act of turning over a table seems beyond her and needs to be pieced together from multiple takes. Given the number of takes they had to do they really should have employed a human to manage continuity, rather than the chimpanzee they seem to have had doing the job. If sitting in the corner throwing their poo at passers by can be called "doing the job". And at least they could have picked a stunt double who at least looks vaguely like Pam. The one they chose barely fills the bodice Pam wears, and looks like a man to boot. I mean, Pam's breasts spill over the top of her bodice. Her stunt double has noticeable gaps where flesh (or rather silicone) should be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here's looking at you, Pammy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 2017 and the USA is in the middle of a second civil war. Top-heavy bar-owner Barb Wire lives in the country's only free city, supplementing her income as a mercenary/bounty hunter. When an old flame, freedom fighter Axel (Temuera Morrison), re-enters her life seeking assistance to help a wanted scientist escape to Canada, Barb is reluctant to get involved, but after her blind brother is killed by the Congressionals, she finds herself once again joining the cause. With her ridiculously large chest, tiny waist, massive pout and cascading peroxide blonde locks, 90s sex-symbol Pamela Anderson certainly looks the part, but that's about the only good thing I can bring myself to say about this otherwise miserable mid-90s movie adaptation of Dark Horse comic-book character Barb Wire. Clearly never intended to be anything other than a vehicle to exploit the former Baywatch star's plastic sex appeal, the film is a poorly scripted piece of near-futuristic drivel, a post-apocalyptic Casablanca (complete with thinly veiled Nazis!) that deals in well-worn clich&eacute;s and keeps costs to an absolute minimum by filming exclusively in derelict warehouses, junkyards and dock-lands. David Hogan's direction is uninspired, the 'drama' falls flat (unsurprisingly), and the action, when it eventually happens, is explosive but unexciting, the outcome a long foregone conclusion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well, it could've been worse.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aidiera
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At least they pretended to follow the plot of "Casablanca". Other than that, it's too strange for its own good. Anderson is deadpan throughout the entire movie but still manages to kick ass. Most of the characters were really insane. Charlie had really good vision for a blind guy, Big Fatso was pretty disgusting, and Curly seemed to only be there for comic relief, even though he provided none. It's still an entertaining movie, however. Watching Anderson beat up people was surprisingly funny, and the plot is /just/ crazy enough to be enjoyable. I'd recommend you listen to the "How Did This Get Made" episode for it as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plodding dystopian fluff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    djensen1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barb Wire looks good. Most of the important roles are acted competently, and its star is luminous. In the hands of someone like Paul Verhoeven, it could have been another Total Recall--silly fun that might have balanced Verhoeven's usual violence with a little T&A. Instead, the story plods along in drawn-out sequences that drain the life out of what little fun was written into the screenplay or available from the stylish sets and lighting. The kinky prostitution scam, for example, is a grueling, humorless 3+ minute setup for a lackluster action scene that is followed by a grueling, humorless payoff scene that's just as long. Worse, whole scenes are completely superfluous. The scenes where Axel and Cora get into the city are unnecessary and unexciting. The drunk who is taken care of by Camille is both valueless to the plot and totally unfunny. It's odd that the story was lifted almost entirely from Casablanca and then flubbed so badly by adding such dull scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    was made at a bad time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    15 years after it was made I finally bought this flick and even on Blu Ray, cheap of course. This is one of those flicks that always have got some bad reviews. I can't say anything about the script because I haven't seen the comic. But if I just have a look at the names appearing then you know that this isn't going to be a blockbuster. We have Udo Kier and Steven Railsback in it, for those into horror or exploitation those names are famous. And when I saw the name Rick Bota then I immediately must think of him being directing 3 Hellraisers. The story itself is post-apocalyptic so with those actors and the story we could add it into the grindhouse genre even as it wasn't attempt to be. Naturally the main lead was by Pamela Anderson Lee. Back then she was very hot on all aspects. Just made some nudity shots and a porn flick with her husband and of course Baywatch did the producers add her on the wanted list. But face it, she only in it as a teaser. Every time you see her, the most important things are her fake two penny worth breasts. I even has seen the unrated version and indeed, she goes naked now and then only showing tits and nipples. Did I enjoy it? Just looking towards the story and the actors and the gratuitous nudity I liked it and if it would have been made 20 years earlier or even nowadays (remember Bitch Slap also just made for the boys to watch girlies shooting around and posing) it could have been a bigger success. Naturally it was teared down due Pamela's performance. But Steve did good work as did the rest. But be honest, most flicks based on comics failed to deliver.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The only good thing about it is Pamela Anderson's cleavage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barb Wire isn't the worst movie of 1996(quite), Bio-Dome and Ed are worse, but it is a terrible movie with its only redeeming asset Pamela Anderson's cleavage. Anderson is very sexy and does better than expected in the action sequences, but the way she delivers her lines just for me amplifies her limitations as an actress. And the rest of the acting ranges to pretty poor to non-existent. The action sequences are in a way efficiently performed but choreographed in a generic way and some of the editing feels sloppy. I liked how catchy and how upbeat the soundtrack was but it got a bit too loud and too much after a while, the script is cheesy and weak and the story is so thin you have to watch closely to see if there is a story, and I have no better news about the direction. Overall, a terrible movie. 1/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "don't call me babe"...,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    and don't watch this movie either,unless you're really desperate for something to do.but trust me,you could always find something better to do.i mean wow,this was not good.i managed to get to the forty four minute mark before giving up and shutting it down.there's just no coherent plot here,and no real acting of any kind involved.plus,the music was awful,although that's just personal preference.the opening scene sets the bar pretty low and it just gets worse from there.for some strange reason,Xander Berkeley(who's a quality actor)decided to appear in this mess.oh,well,everybody is entitled to a bad movie once in a while.anyway,for me, because it's not the worse movie i've seen,Barb Wire is a 3/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's face it, if you're looking for depth and a meaning, you've put the wrong movie in your machine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some films that are bad, infamous bad and Barb Wire is one of those I have heard about. Some bad films are trashy but can be a bit fun, like Showgirls and some can just be wrong like Striptease. Barb Wire is a film I guess in some way I'm kind of undecided on, it has the making for just a bad movie with Pamela's bad acting but has the action scenes and cheesy lines that make it fun as well. This movie is a retelling of Cassablanca and isn't so quick to hide that fact, so I guess this is the exotic remake. Pam Anderson is a sexy female lead and isn't that hard to believe that at times she can be tough, she does wear that leather well I have to admit, but some of the way she delivers the lines was a little too Shaquil O'Neil, I think if you're going to do a movie like this, you might as well go over the top, go a little James Woods, it's all good. But we need a fun action film with the lead being female, just sad that this is a bad film that got overlooked. Set in 2017 during the "Second American Civil War", Barb Wire owns the Hammerhead, a nightclub in Steel Harbor "the last free city" in a United States ravaged by the civil war and she brings in extra cash by hiring out as a mercenary and bounty hunter. Her club is raided by Chief of Police Willis, who is looking for the fugitive Dr. Corrina "Cora" Devonshire. Devonshire, a former government scientist, has information about a bioweapon being developed by her former superior, Colonel Pryzer of the Congressional Directorate; she is trying to escape to Canada in order to make this information public. Meanwhile, Devonshire has turned up at the Hammerhead. She is accompanied by Axel Hood, a "freedom fighter" whom Barb had known at the outbreak of the war, but the two were separated soon afterward. Axel is now married to Cora, and is trying to help her get to Canada. They are trying to find a contraband pair of contact lenses which will allow Cora to evade the retinal scan at the Steel Harbor airport. The lenses pass through the hands of several lowlifes before also ending up at Barb's nightclub. Barb Wire really wasn't as bad as I was expecting, even though it's just a remake of a classic romantic movie, it does have some cool moments. I loved some of the action scenes, the fight on the fork lift was a lot of fun to watch and since the movie doesn't take itself too seriously, it's all good and makes the fight scenes that more exciting. I guess I could say that I enjoyed the movie a little bit, I suppose it's a new guilty pleasure. Pam Anderson may be an awful actress, but it's not like I was looking for an Oscar worth movie when I decided to watch it. But I have a feeling that the director has some serious sexual issues considering some of the strange erotic torture devices used in the film are a bit much, maybe I don't want to know. If you have an open mind and are looking for a good bad film, I think you'll get a kick out Barb Wire. However just think if you're looking for an actual action film with good acting, just look at the cover, enough said. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wham! Bam! Thank you Pam!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be perfectly honest with you, my appreciation of this movie is almost solely based on Pamela Anderson's breasts. I'm not going to waste your time and claim anything else. Take Pammy out of 'Barb Wire' and you are left with something highly mediocre. The story, action and other characters are simply by-the-numbers and I really cannot be bothered discussing them. It's Pamela's film pure and simple. It wouldn't be over-stating it to say that I thought the opening credit sequence was quite good. Pamela in tight black leather, half out of her top being soaked by a hose? I would say there's four good ideas in there, all in one. Unfortunately, this is where the film peaks and we are only two minutes in. Sadly, a story kicks in at this point and spoils things. But seriously Ms Anderson is perfect for this flick. Her pneumatic figure couldn't be any better for the role she's playing. She is quite ridiculously sexy throughout the entire picture and the film frankly flags when she is not on screen. She is more than serviceable in this action role too. It's worth pointing out here that I am a big Russ Meyer fan and, therefore, it's perhaps no surprise that I have a huge weakness for dangerous, sexy, buxom women. The biggest compliment I can pay Pammy, therefore, is that on this showing she would not have looked out of place as one of the lead bad girls in 'Faster Pussycat! Kill! Kill!' High praise but quite frankly true. The only criticism I can level at Pamela here is she doesn't get naked enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would have loved this if I saw it when it first came out.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt_Layden
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sort of remake of Casablanca set in the future and in a strip club? Pam Anderson is Barb Wire and she must help someone get on a plane to Canada, with contact lenses. Whatever else the plot is, do people really care? This film was made, marketing and watched because of one thing and one thing only, Pamela Anderson. This was her naked sci/fi Hollywood film, the opening of the movie shows her stripping, showing her breasts and getting hit with water. Ooooh, so sexy. This was probably the one scene many kids watched over and over. The film itself is regarded as one of those, it's so bad it's good. I can totally see that and once I got pass Anderson's wooden acting, I actually enjoyed myself. Guilty as charged. I said I would have loved this when it first came out. I say that because I was around 10 years old and a film like this, that is drenched in so called "sexiness" would have been imprinted on my mind. Seeing it for the first time in full when I'm 22, went to film school and have been on the internet since I was whatever age, the film doesn't strike me as sexy. Anderson does look good though and seeing her prance around in tight leather doesn't hurt either. Much better than what Halle Berry tried to do with Catwoman. Anderson became famous for her breasts and that was the focus of the film. Every other shot is of her massive cleavage. Am I complaining? Not really. But we have porno for that, the catch is that Anderson is someone "somewhat" famous. There is a special feature on the DVD called SEXY OUTTAKES. This is ten minutes long and it is of her stripping with the water. Basically the entire opening, but for ten minutes. Jango Fett from the Star Wars prequels is in this film, I found myself saying "Hey it's that guy" a lot every time a character came on screen. The film is campy, what else do I need to say? The acting is campy, the script is god-awful and taken from Casablanca, the nudity isn't even that good. I expected more, the film feels like a tease. Barb Wire is like Showgirls. Made to appeal to the perverted crowd, only this one has explosions. I'm giving this one a high rating, for it's campiness feel. It's trash, but golden trash.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the top ten worst films ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Jenkins
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's worth watching purely for the cringe factor. The acting is wooden. The story line is hardly existent, and the script writing is pretty poor too. Let's face it, Pam can't act. The number of cuts (with associated continuity errors) is testament to the number of takes it took to do some scenes. Even just the act of turning over a table seems beyond her and needs to be pieced together from multiple takes. Given the number of takes they had to do they really should have employed a human to manage continuity, rather than the chimpanzee they seem to have had doing the job. If sitting in the corner throwing their poo at passers by can be called "doing the job". And at least they could have picked a stunt double who at least looks vaguely like Pam. The one they chose barely fills the bodice Pam wears, and looks like a man to boot. I mean, Pam's breasts spill over the top of her bodice. Her stunt double has noticeable gaps where flesh (or rather silicone) should be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here's looking at you, Pammy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 2017 and the USA is in the middle of a second civil war. Top-heavy bar-owner Barb Wire lives in the country's only free city, supplementing her income as a mercenary/bounty hunter. When an old flame, freedom fighter Axel (Temuera Morrison), re-enters her life seeking assistance to help a wanted scientist escape to Canada, Barb is reluctant to get involved, but after her blind brother is killed by the Congressionals, she finds herself once again joining the cause. With her ridiculously large chest, tiny waist, massive pout and cascading peroxide blonde locks, 90s sex-symbol Pamela Anderson certainly looks the part, but that's about the only good thing I can bring myself to say about this otherwise miserable mid-90s movie adaptation of Dark Horse comic-book character Barb Wire. Clearly never intended to be anything other than a vehicle to exploit the former Baywatch star's plastic sex appeal, the film is a poorly scripted piece of near-futuristic drivel, a post-apocalyptic Casablanca (complete with thinly veiled Nazis!) that deals in well-worn clich&eacute;s and keeps costs to an absolute minimum by filming exclusively in derelict warehouses, junkyards and dock-lands. David Hogan's direction is uninspired, the 'drama' falls flat (unsurprisingly), and the action, when it eventually happens, is explosive but unexciting, the outcome a long foregone conclusion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well, it could've been worse.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aidiera
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At least they pretended to follow the plot of "Casablanca". Other than that, it's too strange for its own good. Anderson is deadpan throughout the entire movie but still manages to kick ass. Most of the characters were really insane. Charlie had really good vision for a blind guy, Big Fatso was pretty disgusting, and Curly seemed to only be there for comic relief, even though he provided none. It's still an entertaining movie, however. Watching Anderson beat up people was surprisingly funny, and the plot is /just/ crazy enough to be enjoyable. I'd recommend you listen to the "How Did This Get Made" episode for it as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plodding dystopian fluff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    djensen1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barb Wire looks good. Most of the important roles are acted competently, and its star is luminous. In the hands of someone like Paul Verhoeven, it could have been another Total Recall--silly fun that might have balanced Verhoeven's usual violence with a little T&A. Instead, the story plods along in drawn-out sequences that drain the life out of what little fun was written into the screenplay or available from the stylish sets and lighting. The kinky prostitution scam, for example, is a grueling, humorless 3+ minute setup for a lackluster action scene that is followed by a grueling, humorless payoff scene that's just as long. Worse, whole scenes are completely superfluous. The scenes where Axel and Cora get into the city are unnecessary and unexciting. The drunk who is taken care of by Camille is both valueless to the plot and totally unfunny. It's odd that the story was lifted almost entirely from Casablanca and then flubbed so badly by adding such dull scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    was made at a bad time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    15 years after it was made I finally bought this flick and even on Blu Ray, cheap of course. This is one of those flicks that always have got some bad reviews. I can't say anything about the script because I haven't seen the comic. But if I just have a look at the names appearing then you know that this isn't going to be a blockbuster. We have Udo Kier and Steven Railsback in it, for those into horror or exploitation those names are famous. And when I saw the name Rick Bota then I immediately must think of him being directing 3 Hellraisers. The story itself is post-apocalyptic so with those actors and the story we could add it into the grindhouse genre even as it wasn't attempt to be. Naturally the main lead was by Pamela Anderson Lee. Back then she was very hot on all aspects. Just made some nudity shots and a porn flick with her husband and of course Baywatch did the producers add her on the wanted list. But face it, she only in it as a teaser. Every time you see her, the most important things are her fake two penny worth breasts. I even has seen the unrated version and indeed, she goes naked now and then only showing tits and nipples. Did I enjoy it? Just looking towards the story and the actors and the gratuitous nudity I liked it and if it would have been made 20 years earlier or even nowadays (remember Bitch Slap also just made for the boys to watch girlies shooting around and posing) it could have been a bigger success. Naturally it was teared down due Pamela's performance. But Steve did good work as did the rest. But be honest, most flicks based on comics failed to deliver.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The only good thing about it is Pamela Anderson's cleavage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barb Wire isn't the worst movie of 1996(quite), Bio-Dome and Ed are worse, but it is a terrible movie with its only redeeming asset Pamela Anderson's cleavage. Anderson is very sexy and does better than expected in the action sequences, but the way she delivers her lines just for me amplifies her limitations as an actress. And the rest of the acting ranges to pretty poor to non-existent. The action sequences are in a way efficiently performed but choreographed in a generic way and some of the editing feels sloppy. I liked how catchy and how upbeat the soundtrack was but it got a bit too loud and too much after a while, the script is cheesy and weak and the story is so thin you have to watch closely to see if there is a story, and I have no better news about the direction. Overall, a terrible movie. 1/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "don't call me babe"...,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    and don't watch this movie either,unless you're really desperate for something to do.but trust me,you could always find something better to do.i mean wow,this was not good.i managed to get to the forty four minute mark before giving up and shutting it down.there's just no coherent plot here,and no real acting of any kind involved.plus,the music was awful,although that's just personal preference.the opening scene sets the bar pretty low and it just gets worse from there.for some strange reason,Xander Berkeley(who's a quality actor)decided to appear in this mess.oh,well,everybody is entitled to a bad movie once in a while.anyway,for me, because it's not the worse movie i've seen,Barb Wire is a 3/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's face it, if you're looking for depth and a meaning, you've put the wrong movie in your machine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some films that are bad, infamous bad and Barb Wire is one of those I have heard about. Some bad films are trashy but can be a bit fun, like Showgirls and some can just be wrong like Striptease. Barb Wire is a film I guess in some way I'm kind of undecided on, it has the making for just a bad movie with Pamela's bad acting but has the action scenes and cheesy lines that make it fun as well. This movie is a retelling of Cassablanca and isn't so quick to hide that fact, so I guess this is the exotic remake. Pam Anderson is a sexy female lead and isn't that hard to believe that at times she can be tough, she does wear that leather well I have to admit, but some of the way she delivers the lines was a little too Shaquil O'Neil, I think if you're going to do a movie like this, you might as well go over the top, go a little James Woods, it's all good. But we need a fun action film with the lead being female, just sad that this is a bad film that got overlooked. Set in 2017 during the "Second American Civil War", Barb Wire owns the Hammerhead, a nightclub in Steel Harbor "the last free city" in a United States ravaged by the civil war and she brings in extra cash by hiring out as a mercenary and bounty hunter. Her club is raided by Chief of Police Willis, who is looking for the fugitive Dr. Corrina "Cora" Devonshire. Devonshire, a former government scientist, has information about a bioweapon being developed by her former superior, Colonel Pryzer of the Congressional Directorate; she is trying to escape to Canada in order to make this information public. Meanwhile, Devonshire has turned up at the Hammerhead. She is accompanied by Axel Hood, a "freedom fighter" whom Barb had known at the outbreak of the war, but the two were separated soon afterward. Axel is now married to Cora, and is trying to help her get to Canada. They are trying to find a contraband pair of contact lenses which will allow Cora to evade the retinal scan at the Steel Harbor airport. The lenses pass through the hands of several lowlifes before also ending up at Barb's nightclub. Barb Wire really wasn't as bad as I was expecting, even though it's just a remake of a classic romantic movie, it does have some cool moments. I loved some of the action scenes, the fight on the fork lift was a lot of fun to watch and since the movie doesn't take itself too seriously, it's all good and makes the fight scenes that more exciting. I guess I could say that I enjoyed the movie a little bit, I suppose it's a new guilty pleasure. Pam Anderson may be an awful actress, but it's not like I was looking for an Oscar worth movie when I decided to watch it. But I have a feeling that the director has some serious sexual issues considering some of the strange erotic torture devices used in the film are a bit much, maybe I don't want to know. If you have an open mind and are looking for a good bad film, I think you'll get a kick out Barb Wire. However just think if you're looking for an actual action film with good acting, just look at the cover, enough said. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wham! Bam! Thank you Pam!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be perfectly honest with you, my appreciation of this movie is almost solely based on Pamela Anderson's breasts. I'm not going to waste your time and claim anything else. Take Pammy out of 'Barb Wire' and you are left with something highly mediocre. The story, action and other characters are simply by-the-numbers and I really cannot be bothered discussing them. It's Pamela's film pure and simple. It wouldn't be over-stating it to say that I thought the opening credit sequence was quite good. Pamela in tight black leather, half out of her top being soaked by a hose? I would say there's four good ideas in there, all in one. Unfortunately, this is where the film peaks and we are only two minutes in. Sadly, a story kicks in at this point and spoils things. But seriously Ms Anderson is perfect for this flick. Her pneumatic figure couldn't be any better for the role she's playing. She is quite ridiculously sexy throughout the entire picture and the film frankly flags when she is not on screen. She is more than serviceable in this action role too. It's worth pointing out here that I am a big Russ Meyer fan and, therefore, it's perhaps no surprise that I have a huge weakness for dangerous, sexy, buxom women. The biggest compliment I can pay Pammy, therefore, is that on this showing she would not have looked out of place as one of the lead bad girls in 'Faster Pussycat! Kill! Kill!' High praise but quite frankly true. The only criticism I can level at Pamela here is she doesn't get naked enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would have loved this if I saw it when it first came out.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt_Layden
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sort of remake of Casablanca set in the future and in a strip club? Pam Anderson is Barb Wire and she must help someone get on a plane to Canada, with contact lenses. Whatever else the plot is, do people really care? This film was made, marketing and watched because of one thing and one thing only, Pamela Anderson. This was her naked sci/fi Hollywood film, the opening of the movie shows her stripping, showing her breasts and getting hit with water. Ooooh, so sexy. This was probably the one scene many kids watched over and over. The film itself is regarded as one of those, it's so bad it's good. I can totally see that and once I got pass Anderson's wooden acting, I actually enjoyed myself. Guilty as charged. I said I would have loved this when it first came out. I say that because I was around 10 years old and a film like this, that is drenched in so called "sexiness" would have been imprinted on my mind. Seeing it for the first time in full when I'm 22, went to film school and have been on the internet since I was whatever age, the film doesn't strike me as sexy. Anderson does look good though and seeing her prance around in tight leather doesn't hurt either. Much better than what Halle Berry tried to do with Catwoman. Anderson became famous for her breasts and that was the focus of the film. Every other shot is of her massive cleavage. Am I complaining? Not really. But we have porno for that, the catch is that Anderson is someone "somewhat" famous. There is a special feature on the DVD called SEXY OUTTAKES. This is ten minutes long and it is of her stripping with the water. Basically the entire opening, but for ten minutes. Jango Fett from the Star Wars prequels is in this film, I found myself saying "Hey it's that guy" a lot every time a character came on screen. The film is campy, what else do I need to say? The acting is campy, the script is god-awful and taken from Casablanca, the nudity isn't even that good. I expected more, the film feels like a tease. Barb Wire is like Showgirls. Made to appeal to the perverted crowd, only this one has explosions. I'm giving this one a high rating, for it's campiness feel. It's trash, but golden trash.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the top ten worst films ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Jenkins
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's worth watching purely for the cringe factor. The acting is wooden. The story line is hardly existent, and the script writing is pretty poor too. Let's face it, Pam can't act. The number of cuts (with associated continuity errors) is testament to the number of takes it took to do some scenes. Even just the act of turning over a table seems beyond her and needs to be pieced together from multiple takes. Given the number of takes they had to do they really should have employed a human to manage continuity, rather than the chimpanzee they seem to have had doing the job. If sitting in the corner throwing their poo at passers by can be called "doing the job". And at least they could have picked a stunt double who at least looks vaguely like Pam. The one they chose barely fills the bodice Pam wears, and looks like a man to boot. I mean, Pam's breasts spill over the top of her bodice. Her stunt double has noticeable gaps where flesh (or rather silicone) should be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here's looking at you, Pammy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 2017 and the USA is in the middle of a second civil war. Top-heavy bar-owner Barb Wire lives in the country's only free city, supplementing her income as a mercenary/bounty hunter. When an old flame, freedom fighter Axel (Temuera Morrison), re-enters her life seeking assistance to help a wanted scientist escape to Canada, Barb is reluctant to get involved, but after her blind brother is killed by the Congressionals, she finds herself once again joining the cause. With her ridiculously large chest, tiny waist, massive pout and cascading peroxide blonde locks, 90s sex-symbol Pamela Anderson certainly looks the part, but that's about the only good thing I can bring myself to say about this otherwise miserable mid-90s movie adaptation of Dark Horse comic-book character Barb Wire. Clearly never intended to be anything other than a vehicle to exploit the former Baywatch star's plastic sex appeal, the film is a poorly scripted piece of near-futuristic drivel, a post-apocalyptic Casablanca (complete with thinly veiled Nazis!) that deals in well-worn clich&eacute;s and keeps costs to an absolute minimum by filming exclusively in derelict warehouses, junkyards and dock-lands. David Hogan's direction is uninspired, the 'drama' falls flat (unsurprisingly), and the action, when it eventually happens, is explosive but unexciting, the outcome a long foregone conclusion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well, it could've been worse.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aidiera
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At least they pretended to follow the plot of "Casablanca". Other than that, it's too strange for its own good. Anderson is deadpan throughout the entire movie but still manages to kick ass. Most of the characters were really insane. Charlie had really good vision for a blind guy, Big Fatso was pretty disgusting, and Curly seemed to only be there for comic relief, even though he provided none. It's still an entertaining movie, however. Watching Anderson beat up people was surprisingly funny, and the plot is /just/ crazy enough to be enjoyable. I'd recommend you listen to the "How Did This Get Made" episode for it as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plodding dystopian fluff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    djensen1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barb Wire looks good. Most of the important roles are acted competently, and its star is luminous. In the hands of someone like Paul Verhoeven, it could have been another Total Recall--silly fun that might have balanced Verhoeven's usual violence with a little T&A. Instead, the story plods along in drawn-out sequences that drain the life out of what little fun was written into the screenplay or available from the stylish sets and lighting. The kinky prostitution scam, for example, is a grueling, humorless 3+ minute setup for a lackluster action scene that is followed by a grueling, humorless payoff scene that's just as long. Worse, whole scenes are completely superfluous. The scenes where Axel and Cora get into the city are unnecessary and unexciting. The drunk who is taken care of by Camille is both valueless to the plot and totally unfunny. It's odd that the story was lifted almost entirely from Casablanca and then flubbed so badly by adding such dull scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    was made at a bad time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    15 years after it was made I finally bought this flick and even on Blu Ray, cheap of course. This is one of those flicks that always have got some bad reviews. I can't say anything about the script because I haven't seen the comic. But if I just have a look at the names appearing then you know that this isn't going to be a blockbuster. We have Udo Kier and Steven Railsback in it, for those into horror or exploitation those names are famous. And when I saw the name Rick Bota then I immediately must think of him being directing 3 Hellraisers. The story itself is post-apocalyptic so with those actors and the story we could add it into the grindhouse genre even as it wasn't attempt to be. Naturally the main lead was by Pamela Anderson Lee. Back then she was very hot on all aspects. Just made some nudity shots and a porn flick with her husband and of course Baywatch did the producers add her on the wanted list. But face it, she only in it as a teaser. Every time you see her, the most important things are her fake two penny worth breasts. I even has seen the unrated version and indeed, she goes naked now and then only showing tits and nipples. Did I enjoy it? Just looking towards the story and the actors and the gratuitous nudity I liked it and if it would have been made 20 years earlier or even nowadays (remember Bitch Slap also just made for the boys to watch girlies shooting around and posing) it could have been a bigger success. Naturally it was teared down due Pamela's performance. But Steve did good work as did the rest. But be honest, most flicks based on comics failed to deliver.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The only good thing about it is Pamela Anderson's cleavage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barb Wire isn't the worst movie of 1996(quite), Bio-Dome and Ed are worse, but it is a terrible movie with its only redeeming asset Pamela Anderson's cleavage. Anderson is very sexy and does better than expected in the action sequences, but the way she delivers her lines just for me amplifies her limitations as an actress. And the rest of the acting ranges to pretty poor to non-existent. The action sequences are in a way efficiently performed but choreographed in a generic way and some of the editing feels sloppy. I liked how catchy and how upbeat the soundtrack was but it got a bit too loud and too much after a while, the script is cheesy and weak and the story is so thin you have to watch closely to see if there is a story, and I have no better news about the direction. Overall, a terrible movie. 1/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "don't call me babe"...,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    and don't watch this movie either,unless you're really desperate for something to do.but trust me,you could always find something better to do.i mean wow,this was not good.i managed to get to the forty four minute mark before giving up and shutting it down.there's just no coherent plot here,and no real acting of any kind involved.plus,the music was awful,although that's just personal preference.the opening scene sets the bar pretty low and it just gets worse from there.for some strange reason,Xander Berkeley(who's a quality actor)decided to appear in this mess.oh,well,everybody is entitled to a bad movie once in a while.anyway,for me, because it's not the worse movie i've seen,Barb Wire is a 3/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's face it, if you're looking for depth and a meaning, you've put the wrong movie in your machine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some films that are bad, infamous bad and Barb Wire is one of those I have heard about. Some bad films are trashy but can be a bit fun, like Showgirls and some can just be wrong like Striptease. Barb Wire is a film I guess in some way I'm kind of undecided on, it has the making for just a bad movie with Pamela's bad acting but has the action scenes and cheesy lines that make it fun as well. This movie is a retelling of Cassablanca and isn't so quick to hide that fact, so I guess this is the exotic remake. Pam Anderson is a sexy female lead and isn't that hard to believe that at times she can be tough, she does wear that leather well I have to admit, but some of the way she delivers the lines was a little too Shaquil O'Neil, I think if you're going to do a movie like this, you might as well go over the top, go a little James Woods, it's all good. But we need a fun action film with the lead being female, just sad that this is a bad film that got overlooked. Set in 2017 during the "Second American Civil War", Barb Wire owns the Hammerhead, a nightclub in Steel Harbor "the last free city" in a United States ravaged by the civil war and she brings in extra cash by hiring out as a mercenary and bounty hunter. Her club is raided by Chief of Police Willis, who is looking for the fugitive Dr. Corrina "Cora" Devonshire. Devonshire, a former government scientist, has information about a bioweapon being developed by her former superior, Colonel Pryzer of the Congressional Directorate; she is trying to escape to Canada in order to make this information public. Meanwhile, Devonshire has turned up at the Hammerhead. She is accompanied by Axel Hood, a "freedom fighter" whom Barb had known at the outbreak of the war, but the two were separated soon afterward. Axel is now married to Cora, and is trying to help her get to Canada. They are trying to find a contraband pair of contact lenses which will allow Cora to evade the retinal scan at the Steel Harbor airport. The lenses pass through the hands of several lowlifes before also ending up at Barb's nightclub. Barb Wire really wasn't as bad as I was expecting, even though it's just a remake of a classic romantic movie, it does have some cool moments. I loved some of the action scenes, the fight on the fork lift was a lot of fun to watch and since the movie doesn't take itself too seriously, it's all good and makes the fight scenes that more exciting. I guess I could say that I enjoyed the movie a little bit, I suppose it's a new guilty pleasure. Pam Anderson may be an awful actress, but it's not like I was looking for an Oscar worth movie when I decided to watch it. But I have a feeling that the director has some serious sexual issues considering some of the strange erotic torture devices used in the film are a bit much, maybe I don't want to know. If you have an open mind and are looking for a good bad film, I think you'll get a kick out Barb Wire. However just think if you're looking for an actual action film with good acting, just look at the cover, enough said. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wham! Bam! Thank you Pam!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be perfectly honest with you, my appreciation of this movie is almost solely based on Pamela Anderson's breasts. I'm not going to waste your time and claim anything else. Take Pammy out of 'Barb Wire' and you are left with something highly mediocre. The story, action and other characters are simply by-the-numbers and I really cannot be bothered discussing them. It's Pamela's film pure and simple. It wouldn't be over-stating it to say that I thought the opening credit sequence was quite good. Pamela in tight black leather, half out of her top being soaked by a hose? I would say there's four good ideas in there, all in one. Unfortunately, this is where the film peaks and we are only two minutes in. Sadly, a story kicks in at this point and spoils things. But seriously Ms Anderson is perfect for this flick. Her pneumatic figure couldn't be any better for the role she's playing. She is quite ridiculously sexy throughout the entire picture and the film frankly flags when she is not on screen. She is more than serviceable in this action role too. It's worth pointing out here that I am a big Russ Meyer fan and, therefore, it's perhaps no surprise that I have a huge weakness for dangerous, sexy, buxom women. The biggest compliment I can pay Pammy, therefore, is that on this showing she would not have looked out of place as one of the lead bad girls in 'Faster Pussycat! Kill! Kill!' High praise but quite frankly true. The only criticism I can level at Pamela here is she doesn't get naked enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would have loved this if I saw it when it first came out.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt_Layden
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sort of remake of Casablanca set in the future and in a strip club? Pam Anderson is Barb Wire and she must help someone get on a plane to Canada, with contact lenses. Whatever else the plot is, do people really care? This film was made, marketing and watched because of one thing and one thing only, Pamela Anderson. This was her naked sci/fi Hollywood film, the opening of the movie shows her stripping, showing her breasts and getting hit with water. Ooooh, so sexy. This was probably the one scene many kids watched over and over. The film itself is regarded as one of those, it's so bad it's good. I can totally see that and once I got pass Anderson's wooden acting, I actually enjoyed myself. Guilty as charged. I said I would have loved this when it first came out. I say that because I was around 10 years old and a film like this, that is drenched in so called "sexiness" would have been imprinted on my mind. Seeing it for the first time in full when I'm 22, went to film school and have been on the internet since I was whatever age, the film doesn't strike me as sexy. Anderson does look good though and seeing her prance around in tight leather doesn't hurt either. Much better than what Halle Berry tried to do with Catwoman. Anderson became famous for her breasts and that was the focus of the film. Every other shot is of her massive cleavage. Am I complaining? Not really. But we have porno for that, the catch is that Anderson is someone "somewhat" famous. There is a special feature on the DVD called SEXY OUTTAKES. This is ten minutes long and it is of her stripping with the water. Basically the entire opening, but for ten minutes. Jango Fett from the Star Wars prequels is in this film, I found myself saying "Hey it's that guy" a lot every time a character came on screen. The film is campy, what else do I need to say? The acting is campy, the script is god-awful and taken from Casablanca, the nudity isn't even that good. I expected more, the film feels like a tease. Barb Wire is like Showgirls. Made to appeal to the perverted crowd, only this one has explosions. I'm giving this one a high rating, for it's campiness feel. It's trash, but golden trash.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the top ten worst films ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Jenkins
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's worth watching purely for the cringe factor. The acting is wooden. The story line is hardly existent, and the script writing is pretty poor too. Let's face it, Pam can't act. The number of cuts (with associated continuity errors) is testament to the number of takes it took to do some scenes. Even just the act of turning over a table seems beyond her and needs to be pieced together from multiple takes. Given the number of takes they had to do they really should have employed a human to manage continuity, rather than the chimpanzee they seem to have had doing the job. If sitting in the corner throwing their poo at passers by can be called "doing the job". And at least they could have picked a stunt double who at least looks vaguely like Pam. The one they chose barely fills the bodice Pam wears, and looks like a man to boot. I mean, Pam's breasts spill over the top of her bodice. Her stunt double has noticeable gaps where flesh (or rather silicone) should be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here's looking at you, Pammy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 2017 and the USA is in the middle of a second civil war. Top-heavy bar-owner Barb Wire lives in the country's only free city, supplementing her income as a mercenary/bounty hunter. When an old flame, freedom fighter Axel (Temuera Morrison), re-enters her life seeking assistance to help a wanted scientist escape to Canada, Barb is reluctant to get involved, but after her blind brother is killed by the Congressionals, she finds herself once again joining the cause. With her ridiculously large chest, tiny waist, massive pout and cascading peroxide blonde locks, 90s sex-symbol Pamela Anderson certainly looks the part, but that's about the only good thing I can bring myself to say about this otherwise miserable mid-90s movie adaptation of Dark Horse comic-book character Barb Wire. Clearly never intended to be anything other than a vehicle to exploit the former Baywatch star's plastic sex appeal, the film is a poorly scripted piece of near-futuristic drivel, a post-apocalyptic Casablanca (complete with thinly veiled Nazis!) that deals in well-worn clich&eacute;s and keeps costs to an absolute minimum by filming exclusively in derelict warehouses, junkyards and dock-lands. David Hogan's direction is uninspired, the 'drama' falls flat (unsurprisingly), and the action, when it eventually happens, is explosive but unexciting, the outcome a long foregone conclusion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well, it could've been worse.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aidiera
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At least they pretended to follow the plot of "Casablanca". Other than that, it's too strange for its own good. Anderson is deadpan throughout the entire movie but still manages to kick ass. Most of the characters were really insane. Charlie had really good vision for a blind guy, Big Fatso was pretty disgusting, and Curly seemed to only be there for comic relief, even though he provided none. It's still an entertaining movie, however. Watching Anderson beat up people was surprisingly funny, and the plot is /just/ crazy enough to be enjoyable. I'd recommend you listen to the "How Did This Get Made" episode for it as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plodding dystopian fluff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    djensen1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barb Wire looks good. Most of the important roles are acted competently, and its star is luminous. In the hands of someone like Paul Verhoeven, it could have been another Total Recall--silly fun that might have balanced Verhoeven's usual violence with a little T&A. Instead, the story plods along in drawn-out sequences that drain the life out of what little fun was written into the screenplay or available from the stylish sets and lighting. The kinky prostitution scam, for example, is a grueling, humorless 3+ minute setup for a lackluster action scene that is followed by a grueling, humorless payoff scene that's just as long. Worse, whole scenes are completely superfluous. The scenes where Axel and Cora get into the city are unnecessary and unexciting. The drunk who is taken care of by Camille is both valueless to the plot and totally unfunny. It's odd that the story was lifted almost entirely from Casablanca and then flubbed so badly by adding such dull scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    was made at a bad time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    15 years after it was made I finally bought this flick and even on Blu Ray, cheap of course. This is one of those flicks that always have got some bad reviews. I can't say anything about the script because I haven't seen the comic. But if I just have a look at the names appearing then you know that this isn't going to be a blockbuster. We have Udo Kier and Steven Railsback in it, for those into horror or exploitation those names are famous. And when I saw the name Rick Bota then I immediately must think of him being directing 3 Hellraisers. The story itself is post-apocalyptic so with those actors and the story we could add it into the grindhouse genre even as it wasn't attempt to be. Naturally the main lead was by Pamela Anderson Lee. Back then she was very hot on all aspects. Just made some nudity shots and a porn flick with her husband and of course Baywatch did the producers add her on the wanted list. But face it, she only in it as a teaser. Every time you see her, the most important things are her fake two penny worth breasts. I even has seen the unrated version and indeed, she goes naked now and then only showing tits and nipples. Did I enjoy it? Just looking towards the story and the actors and the gratuitous nudity I liked it and if it would have been made 20 years earlier or even nowadays (remember Bitch Slap also just made for the boys to watch girlies shooting around and posing) it could have been a bigger success. Naturally it was teared down due Pamela's performance. But Steve did good work as did the rest. But be honest, most flicks based on comics failed to deliver.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The only good thing about it is Pamela Anderson's cleavage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barb Wire isn't the worst movie of 1996(quite), Bio-Dome and Ed are worse, but it is a terrible movie with its only redeeming asset Pamela Anderson's cleavage. Anderson is very sexy and does better than expected in the action sequences, but the way she delivers her lines just for me amplifies her limitations as an actress. And the rest of the acting ranges to pretty poor to non-existent. The action sequences are in a way efficiently performed but choreographed in a generic way and some of the editing feels sloppy. I liked how catchy and how upbeat the soundtrack was but it got a bit too loud and too much after a while, the script is cheesy and weak and the story is so thin you have to watch closely to see if there is a story, and I have no better news about the direction. Overall, a terrible movie. 1/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "don't call me babe"...,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    and don't watch this movie either,unless you're really desperate for something to do.but trust me,you could always find something better to do.i mean wow,this was not good.i managed to get to the forty four minute mark before giving up and shutting it down.there's just no coherent plot here,and no real acting of any kind involved.plus,the music was awful,although that's just personal preference.the opening scene sets the bar pretty low and it just gets worse from there.for some strange reason,Xander Berkeley(who's a quality actor)decided to appear in this mess.oh,well,everybody is entitled to a bad movie once in a while.anyway,for me, because it's not the worse movie i've seen,Barb Wire is a 3/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's face it, if you're looking for depth and a meaning, you've put the wrong movie in your machine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some films that are bad, infamous bad and Barb Wire is one of those I have heard about. Some bad films are trashy but can be a bit fun, like Showgirls and some can just be wrong like Striptease. Barb Wire is a film I guess in some way I'm kind of undecided on, it has the making for just a bad movie with Pamela's bad acting but has the action scenes and cheesy lines that make it fun as well. This movie is a retelling of Cassablanca and isn't so quick to hide that fact, so I guess this is the exotic remake. Pam Anderson is a sexy female lead and isn't that hard to believe that at times she can be tough, she does wear that leather well I have to admit, but some of the way she delivers the lines was a little too Shaquil O'Neil, I think if you're going to do a movie like this, you might as well go over the top, go a little James Woods, it's all good. But we need a fun action film with the lead being female, just sad that this is a bad film that got overlooked. Set in 2017 during the "Second American Civil War", Barb Wire owns the Hammerhead, a nightclub in Steel Harbor "the last free city" in a United States ravaged by the civil war and she brings in extra cash by hiring out as a mercenary and bounty hunter. Her club is raided by Chief of Police Willis, who is looking for the fugitive Dr. Corrina "Cora" Devonshire. Devonshire, a former government scientist, has information about a bioweapon being developed by her former superior, Colonel Pryzer of the Congressional Directorate; she is trying to escape to Canada in order to make this information public. Meanwhile, Devonshire has turned up at the Hammerhead. She is accompanied by Axel Hood, a "freedom fighter" whom Barb had known at the outbreak of the war, but the two were separated soon afterward. Axel is now married to Cora, and is trying to help her get to Canada. They are trying to find a contraband pair of contact lenses which will allow Cora to evade the retinal scan at the Steel Harbor airport. The lenses pass through the hands of several lowlifes before also ending up at Barb's nightclub. Barb Wire really wasn't as bad as I was expecting, even though it's just a remake of a classic romantic movie, it does have some cool moments. I loved some of the action scenes, the fight on the fork lift was a lot of fun to watch and since the movie doesn't take itself too seriously, it's all good and makes the fight scenes that more exciting. I guess I could say that I enjoyed the movie a little bit, I suppose it's a new guilty pleasure. Pam Anderson may be an awful actress, but it's not like I was looking for an Oscar worth movie when I decided to watch it. But I have a feeling that the director has some serious sexual issues considering some of the strange erotic torture devices used in the film are a bit much, maybe I don't want to know. If you have an open mind and are looking for a good bad film, I think you'll get a kick out Barb Wire. However just think if you're looking for an actual action film with good acting, just look at the cover, enough said. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wham! Bam! Thank you Pam!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be perfectly honest with you, my appreciation of this movie is almost solely based on Pamela Anderson's breasts. I'm not going to waste your time and claim anything else. Take Pammy out of 'Barb Wire' and you are left with something highly mediocre. The story, action and other characters are simply by-the-numbers and I really cannot be bothered discussing them. It's Pamela's film pure and simple. It wouldn't be over-stating it to say that I thought the opening credit sequence was quite good. Pamela in tight black leather, half out of her top being soaked by a hose? I would say there's four good ideas in there, all in one. Unfortunately, this is where the film peaks and we are only two minutes in. Sadly, a story kicks in at this point and spoils things. But seriously Ms Anderson is perfect for this flick. Her pneumatic figure couldn't be any better for the role she's playing. She is quite ridiculously sexy throughout the entire picture and the film frankly flags when she is not on screen. She is more than serviceable in this action role too. It's worth pointing out here that I am a big Russ Meyer fan and, therefore, it's perhaps no surprise that I have a huge weakness for dangerous, sexy, buxom women. The biggest compliment I can pay Pammy, therefore, is that on this showing she would not have looked out of place as one of the lead bad girls in 'Faster Pussycat! Kill! Kill!' High praise but quite frankly true. The only criticism I can level at Pamela here is she doesn't get naked enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would have loved this if I saw it when it first came out.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt_Layden
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sort of remake of Casablanca set in the future and in a strip club? Pam Anderson is Barb Wire and she must help someone get on a plane to Canada, with contact lenses. Whatever else the plot is, do people really care? This film was made, marketing and watched because of one thing and one thing only, Pamela Anderson. This was her naked sci/fi Hollywood film, the opening of the movie shows her stripping, showing her breasts and getting hit with water. Ooooh, so sexy. This was probably the one scene many kids watched over and over. The film itself is regarded as one of those, it's so bad it's good. I can totally see that and once I got pass Anderson's wooden acting, I actually enjoyed myself. Guilty as charged. I said I would have loved this when it first came out. I say that because I was around 10 years old and a film like this, that is drenched in so called "sexiness" would have been imprinted on my mind. Seeing it for the first time in full when I'm 22, went to film school and have been on the internet since I was whatever age, the film doesn't strike me as sexy. Anderson does look good though and seeing her prance around in tight leather doesn't hurt either. Much better than what Halle Berry tried to do with Catwoman. Anderson became famous for her breasts and that was the focus of the film. Every other shot is of her massive cleavage. Am I complaining? Not really. But we have porno for that, the catch is that Anderson is someone "somewhat" famous. There is a special feature on the DVD called SEXY OUTTAKES. This is ten minutes long and it is of her stripping with the water. Basically the entire opening, but for ten minutes. Jango Fett from the Star Wars prequels is in this film, I found myself saying "Hey it's that guy" a lot every time a character came on screen. The film is campy, what else do I need to say? The acting is campy, the script is god-awful and taken from Casablanca, the nudity isn't even that good. I expected more, the film feels like a tease. Barb Wire is like Showgirls. Made to appeal to the perverted crowd, only this one has explosions. I'm giving this one a high rating, for it's campiness feel. It's trash, but golden trash.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
