<filme>
 <id>
  1216
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116783
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Kissed
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Over the years, a child's romantic ideals about death blossom into necrophilia, the study of embalming and the most profound relationship of her life.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Over the years, a child's romantic ideals about death blossom into necrophilia, the study of embalming and the most profound relationship of her life.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   funeral
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   funeral home
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   necrophilia
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   embalming
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   medical student
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Lynne Stopkewich
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Angus Fraser
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Lynne Stopkewich
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Molly Parker
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Peter Outerbridge
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jay Brazeau
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting subject matter; very poorly handled (some pun intended)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s k
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As some other reviewers have already pointed out, "Kissed" is not a bad film because it tries to tackle the taboo subject of necrophilia -- it's a bad film because it does a bad job of dealing with the subject matter. It's as if the writer and director wanted to make a "Lifetime" movie about necrophilia. (See how yucky that is? Well...that's pretty much the feeling throughout the movie as well.) As I stated in one of the board threads, what I found most disturbing about this film was not the subject matter of necrophilia, although that clearly IS something very disturbing in itself. What I found most disturbing is the fact that the film maker has attempted to somehow glorify that sick, twisted fetish and equate it with love. It is NOT LOVE. It is mental illness of the highest order. And to even begin to glamorize, beautify, or glorify it, as this film does, is even more offensive than the subject matter itself. IF the film had at least attempted to try to UNDERSTAND necrophilia -- which in and of itself would have been one hell of an undertaking -- that would be different. But it doesn't come close to doing that. What it does is titillate and obfuscate the issue(s), then paint some twisted variation of a Disney "ain't love grand" nonsensical ending over top of it. Kissed might arguably be a worthwhile film to watch if for nothing else than to see what necrophilia is NOT, and to stimulate some sort of thought process into what it might be. Aside from that, the film has little if any redeeming value.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as terrible or as brilliant as the extremes profess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mojochi
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a purposefully simple and obvious film, but good. Could it have been more complex or developed? Sure. Did it need to be? I think not. The goals were achieved. The mood was executed appropriately, and the performances were given well enough that additional development, while perhaps useful, was not necessary to the objective. Do we need to know why the little girl is attracted to dead things? Not really, unless you're doing a psyche profile on her. For dramatic purposes, it is simply enough to note that she has a life long relationship to it. In fact, in this case there is even a romanticism & perhaps myth centering around her obsession, such that overly defining how it came about would defeat its allure. That allure is what the film is embracing, the allure of necrophilia being more than just a sexual fetish, involving perhaps all four of the principal characters, the girl, her boyfriend, her mentor, & even the custodian, all of whom have varied, & uniquely unnatural fascinations with the subject. The story is direct, & it drives straight to the point without delay, & its characters all have a purpose & design, which conclude fittingly, even including the girl's undertaker mentor, who gets a glimpse into her truth at the end & leaves speechless, knowing all too well what is really happening, just as his custodian knows too well the truth of him. Anyway, onto the question everybody needs answered. Is this arousing? Well, in any well adjusted sense, of course the notion of making love to the dead is not supposed to be sexually arousing, but the film is, or at least alluring, if not in a fully sexual way. Truth be told, there is something arousing about this film, even if it's only arousing to the subject of necrophilia in a voyeuristic way. In short, it's not arousing such that it makes you want to go hump a corpse, but it does make you want to watch her do it. As such, the film is a success at pushing the artistic envelop. To understand the level of difficulty in achieving something like this, one need only reflect on how impossible it would be to make an equally enticing story about any other abominable fetish, like fecophilia. Sounds pretty tough doesn't it? A great deal of the success in making this story alluring was in how it was presented & by whom, & I mean specifically the well played performance given by the celestially beautiful Molly Parker, whose every square inch of freckled majesty I worship, so much so that I too would hang myself, sooner than look away from her glorious visage, or turn away from hearing the hushed tones of her sweet & transcendent voice I would feel myself bask in her radiance, even if it were a movie wherein she only sat at a bus stop & read from the phone book. I'll watch anything that woman is in, & in this case, I felt I spent my time wisely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What amazes me is that there are people that love and praise this film...I think I'm going to an alarm system for my house!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This story is about a lonely and twisted lady who has a fascination with dead people--so much so that she gets a job in a mortuary. However, she is not just fascinated but stimulated by the dead and begins to have her way with them. When she meets a seemingly nice guy who cares about her, she cannot give of herself to him...as he's alive. So, in a bizarre twist, he makes himself more attractive to her in a very sick but supposedly romantic finale. The acting is decent and the film is technically well done...but very, very unsettling and grotesque. Years ago, I saw this film and was hesitant to ever review it--after all, I'd hate my friends to know I've seen this! Plus, I tried very, very hard to erase the film from my memory because I regretted seeing such a sick and thoroughly nasty film--with almost nothing to recommend it. After all, the film glorifies and romanticizes necrophilia--yes, necrophilia (that's doing the nasty with dead folks for you less informed readers). If Lynne Stopkewich and Angus Fraser had made a movie glorifying pedophiles or serial rapists would people have praised it?! Probably not...or at least they wouldn't have done so publicly...after all, these are nasty and illegal. So, why, then, praise necrophilia?! It's illegal (in most but not all places) and really, really gross...yet to some, it's romantic or compelling?! Why not, then, make films about urophilics (people who like to tinkle on others for gratification) or copraphilics (people who like to defecate on others for gratification)?! By the way, if you notice I am using euphemisms and talking around things, IMDb won't allow certain key words in its reviews. The fact that people actually LIKED this film disturbs me more than the fact that the film was made in the first place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mediocre film veiled behind droning philosophy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dead_doll00
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally, I didn't so much get worked up over this movie as I found it rather...mediocre. Many times I was bored and I found that Sandra's constant notions of "light, energy, etc." were forced and unoriginal. So she slept with corpses and experienced a euphoric awakening? Sorry, I just couldn't buy that. I understand the movie was trying to convey a message about transcendence and the similarities between life/death and love/hate (and yes, I understood the point of Matt's suicide and the many progressive layers of his obsession/love for her), but for me, that message just didn't come through well at all. In the end, it felt like it was all about her growing sexual attraction to death more so than anything else, culminating with her finally going all the way with her cadavers, droning on philosophically while she diddled away as though to curtain the fact that if she wasn't the kind of character she was, the interpretation of this movie would have been far less kinder. I think, had they made her character less of the "ethereal, mysterious outcast" type they so desperately tried to convey her as being, the subject matter wouldn't have been seen as deep and artsy but rather just a bland movie about necrophilia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Parker is great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ellkew
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This had an odd film to it that reminded me of Harold and Maude in tone. It does not really fit in any category which is always a good thing in my book. That said it didn't work on a complete level. I had problems with the boyfriend and I found it hard to believe the way he responded to her sleeping with dead people from the start. I expected him to be a little more horrified. I also didn't believe his outcome but I suppose it was always going to happen. Molly Parker was simply great and it was such a difficult role to pull off but she does it admirably. I really believed her and this world she ventured into. It manages to make a taboo subject seem quite fascinating which in itself is groundbreaking. I think it does stand true that if the sexes were switched then audiences would indeed have trouble swallowing the story but this way round it is more acceptable. Well that's the double standard thing again. Thought provoking and sensual. I take away from this Parker's performance more than anything, without her I think the film would be consigned to the annals of history.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    interesting subject
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomnkiki
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had to give this movie 9 stars out of ten because, having some background in Abnormal Psychology, this subject was very interesting to me. It is not often the subject of necrophilia is presented in a film that is non-academic or a complete gore fest. The portrayal of the main character's abnormal obsession with dead corpses was presented in a very enlightened and informed manner which was surprising. This deviant behavior was portrayed as being right and normal in the psyche of the necrophiliac and that is exactly how this type of necrophilia is described by those who have this particular type of compulsion/attraction. The sensitive, almost spiritual, love that the main character feels toward these cadavers is portrayed in a very ethereal manner and it allows us, the viewers, to almost understand the attraction. The inability of the main character to have a healthy relationship with a living being is also very common with this type of deviancy. That two people who have something of the same infatuation should be attracted to each other is not uncommon, nor is the willingness to be a participant in such a relationship. These are abnormal personality disorders and as such, cannot be judged by normal behavioral measures. This is a film that successfully taps into the psyche of this type of necrophilia that can manifest itself for no apparent reason. It is difficult to know how such abnormal behavior develops but there has been discussion that it may have something to do with aberrant development of the pre-frontal cortex in the brain, although it is not completely limited to this region. This type of development is difficult to predict or to even map within the realm of science much less cinematography. The director showed an inspired understanding of early manifested behavioral patterns that created a realistic lead-in to increased aberrant behavior. Good show!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    convincingly conveyed mix of true innocence and corruption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    christopher-underwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Obviously not for everyone but I just love this little film. I am sure there are plot holes galore but I am persuaded by the film's inner truth. From those early shots of the young girl's ritualistic behaviour and the chilling/exciting manner in which she strokes herself with the little parcels, one is surely hooked and ready to explore the world of this young lady who wishes to cavort with the departed. There is just enough humour and masses of emotion. Molly Parker and Peter Outerbridge are most convincing in their difficult roles, his probably even more difficult than hers. She has to convince us of the attractiveness of the unthinkable but he has to convince us that he can go along with all this as her girlfriend, and does. It reminded me a bit of Peter Jackson's, Heavenly Creatures (back when he made real films!) and I think it was because of that rarely convincingly conveyed mix of true innocence and corruption. Heady stuff,
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much more than a necrophiliac girl
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rqwxyz
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe the greatest achievement of the film is that it was able to deal with an subject such as necrophilia without falling into tastelessness. It's easy getting horrified at the idea of people being sexually attracted for corpses, but the relationship of mankind with death (That primigenial and fascinating fear) can go that far and, if you think of it, it goes way far beyond . If you are not willing to get into any reflexions about how the dead are treated, you may fell uneasy about the film. The contrast between Sandra and the other people manipulating bodies (the teachers, the embalmer) is rather eloquent. But what I personally liked the best about it is how it figures relationships, elucidating the insane need of one not having the other have its own and private corner, the need of forcing the other to share it, and the woe that comes from not being able to stand it. In this line, necrophilia becomes just an excuse.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is the tackling of taboos a good enough reason to see a film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Howlin Wolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kissed" walks very close to the invisible line marked out by this question. I say this because it wasn't necessarily compositional quality that kept me watching; more instead the apparent 'shock factor' of its topic, because gratuity often has a tendency to overwhelm any nuances that may also be present. When dealing with such an 'underground' subject matter (excuse the pun!), then technical proficiency almost becomes irrelevant. If some of the film's images weren't so loudly sensationalistic, one is left thinking with chagrin that the honest speaking voice could more easily be heard... It's almost unfortunate that there is so much nudity, and that it's such an unusual topic, because the sympathetic quality underlying the script may well be overlooked by a lot of people. If you are the type who is able to put themselves in someone else's position without always agreeing with how they go about things; then the main character's struggle with her feelings may very well move you. I feel that certain shots contained within could well be construed as unnecessarily pandering to controversy, though. If this gets more people to give it a chance, then I guess it might well turn out to be a good thing. For the film-makers it must have been a case of being caught between the devil and the deep blue sea, and each individual person will resolve the decided final approach in their own way... The journey the audience take is an unsettling walk with a person longing to find a state where people don't judge, and it affected me far deeper emotionally when it was more reticent about what it revealed, not vice-versa. By holding back on what was shown and exercising just a little more subtlety, it's my opinion that a far stronger position would then be gained to concentrate entirely on this poor young woman and her inner torment. In fact, the more I think about it, not permitting her to give in to the temptation of the act would also lend more resonance to the moment when we finally learn how the people who love her deal with this issue, too. I think too much 'exposure' too soon unfortunately undermines a great deal of its potential impact at the cost of gaining the work a wider notoriety. Despite this hindrance that in my mind prevents it from being of even greater value, "Kissed" is a film which I would say still remains worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Song in Dance Scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fecalite
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie! It definitely encouraged my friend to pursue a career in death care. The soundtrack is awesome too, but one of my favorite songs from the movie is missing from it. Near the beginning of the movie when the young Sandra is playing with her only friend, Carol, Sandra discovers that her can has found a family of dead mice. Sandra tells Carol they will have a special ceremony to commemorate the mice and they find a place in the wood to bury them. After interment, Sandra plays a rather 70s style song on her tape recorder and she and Carol dance to it. Does anyone know what the title of the song is and who wrote it? It's not on the soundtrack. Thanks!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting subject matter; very poorly handled (some pun intended)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s k
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As some other reviewers have already pointed out, "Kissed" is not a bad film because it tries to tackle the taboo subject of necrophilia -- it's a bad film because it does a bad job of dealing with the subject matter. It's as if the writer and director wanted to make a "Lifetime" movie about necrophilia. (See how yucky that is? Well...that's pretty much the feeling throughout the movie as well.) As I stated in one of the board threads, what I found most disturbing about this film was not the subject matter of necrophilia, although that clearly IS something very disturbing in itself. What I found most disturbing is the fact that the film maker has attempted to somehow glorify that sick, twisted fetish and equate it with love. It is NOT LOVE. It is mental illness of the highest order. And to even begin to glamorize, beautify, or glorify it, as this film does, is even more offensive than the subject matter itself. IF the film had at least attempted to try to UNDERSTAND necrophilia -- which in and of itself would have been one hell of an undertaking -- that would be different. But it doesn't come close to doing that. What it does is titillate and obfuscate the issue(s), then paint some twisted variation of a Disney "ain't love grand" nonsensical ending over top of it. Kissed might arguably be a worthwhile film to watch if for nothing else than to see what necrophilia is NOT, and to stimulate some sort of thought process into what it might be. Aside from that, the film has little if any redeeming value.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as terrible or as brilliant as the extremes profess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mojochi
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a purposefully simple and obvious film, but good. Could it have been more complex or developed? Sure. Did it need to be? I think not. The goals were achieved. The mood was executed appropriately, and the performances were given well enough that additional development, while perhaps useful, was not necessary to the objective. Do we need to know why the little girl is attracted to dead things? Not really, unless you're doing a psyche profile on her. For dramatic purposes, it is simply enough to note that she has a life long relationship to it. In fact, in this case there is even a romanticism & perhaps myth centering around her obsession, such that overly defining how it came about would defeat its allure. That allure is what the film is embracing, the allure of necrophilia being more than just a sexual fetish, involving perhaps all four of the principal characters, the girl, her boyfriend, her mentor, & even the custodian, all of whom have varied, & uniquely unnatural fascinations with the subject. The story is direct, & it drives straight to the point without delay, & its characters all have a purpose & design, which conclude fittingly, even including the girl's undertaker mentor, who gets a glimpse into her truth at the end & leaves speechless, knowing all too well what is really happening, just as his custodian knows too well the truth of him. Anyway, onto the question everybody needs answered. Is this arousing? Well, in any well adjusted sense, of course the notion of making love to the dead is not supposed to be sexually arousing, but the film is, or at least alluring, if not in a fully sexual way. Truth be told, there is something arousing about this film, even if it's only arousing to the subject of necrophilia in a voyeuristic way. In short, it's not arousing such that it makes you want to go hump a corpse, but it does make you want to watch her do it. As such, the film is a success at pushing the artistic envelop. To understand the level of difficulty in achieving something like this, one need only reflect on how impossible it would be to make an equally enticing story about any other abominable fetish, like fecophilia. Sounds pretty tough doesn't it? A great deal of the success in making this story alluring was in how it was presented & by whom, & I mean specifically the well played performance given by the celestially beautiful Molly Parker, whose every square inch of freckled majesty I worship, so much so that I too would hang myself, sooner than look away from her glorious visage, or turn away from hearing the hushed tones of her sweet & transcendent voice I would feel myself bask in her radiance, even if it were a movie wherein she only sat at a bus stop & read from the phone book. I'll watch anything that woman is in, & in this case, I felt I spent my time wisely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What amazes me is that there are people that love and praise this film...I think I'm going to an alarm system for my house!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This story is about a lonely and twisted lady who has a fascination with dead people--so much so that she gets a job in a mortuary. However, she is not just fascinated but stimulated by the dead and begins to have her way with them. When she meets a seemingly nice guy who cares about her, she cannot give of herself to him...as he's alive. So, in a bizarre twist, he makes himself more attractive to her in a very sick but supposedly romantic finale. The acting is decent and the film is technically well done...but very, very unsettling and grotesque. Years ago, I saw this film and was hesitant to ever review it--after all, I'd hate my friends to know I've seen this! Plus, I tried very, very hard to erase the film from my memory because I regretted seeing such a sick and thoroughly nasty film--with almost nothing to recommend it. After all, the film glorifies and romanticizes necrophilia--yes, necrophilia (that's doing the nasty with dead folks for you less informed readers). If Lynne Stopkewich and Angus Fraser had made a movie glorifying pedophiles or serial rapists would people have praised it?! Probably not...or at least they wouldn't have done so publicly...after all, these are nasty and illegal. So, why, then, praise necrophilia?! It's illegal (in most but not all places) and really, really gross...yet to some, it's romantic or compelling?! Why not, then, make films about urophilics (people who like to tinkle on others for gratification) or copraphilics (people who like to defecate on others for gratification)?! By the way, if you notice I am using euphemisms and talking around things, IMDb won't allow certain key words in its reviews. The fact that people actually LIKED this film disturbs me more than the fact that the film was made in the first place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mediocre film veiled behind droning philosophy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dead_doll00
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally, I didn't so much get worked up over this movie as I found it rather...mediocre. Many times I was bored and I found that Sandra's constant notions of "light, energy, etc." were forced and unoriginal. So she slept with corpses and experienced a euphoric awakening? Sorry, I just couldn't buy that. I understand the movie was trying to convey a message about transcendence and the similarities between life/death and love/hate (and yes, I understood the point of Matt's suicide and the many progressive layers of his obsession/love for her), but for me, that message just didn't come through well at all. In the end, it felt like it was all about her growing sexual attraction to death more so than anything else, culminating with her finally going all the way with her cadavers, droning on philosophically while she diddled away as though to curtain the fact that if she wasn't the kind of character she was, the interpretation of this movie would have been far less kinder. I think, had they made her character less of the "ethereal, mysterious outcast" type they so desperately tried to convey her as being, the subject matter wouldn't have been seen as deep and artsy but rather just a bland movie about necrophilia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Parker is great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ellkew
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This had an odd film to it that reminded me of Harold and Maude in tone. It does not really fit in any category which is always a good thing in my book. That said it didn't work on a complete level. I had problems with the boyfriend and I found it hard to believe the way he responded to her sleeping with dead people from the start. I expected him to be a little more horrified. I also didn't believe his outcome but I suppose it was always going to happen. Molly Parker was simply great and it was such a difficult role to pull off but she does it admirably. I really believed her and this world she ventured into. It manages to make a taboo subject seem quite fascinating which in itself is groundbreaking. I think it does stand true that if the sexes were switched then audiences would indeed have trouble swallowing the story but this way round it is more acceptable. Well that's the double standard thing again. Thought provoking and sensual. I take away from this Parker's performance more than anything, without her I think the film would be consigned to the annals of history.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    interesting subject
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomnkiki
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had to give this movie 9 stars out of ten because, having some background in Abnormal Psychology, this subject was very interesting to me. It is not often the subject of necrophilia is presented in a film that is non-academic or a complete gore fest. The portrayal of the main character's abnormal obsession with dead corpses was presented in a very enlightened and informed manner which was surprising. This deviant behavior was portrayed as being right and normal in the psyche of the necrophiliac and that is exactly how this type of necrophilia is described by those who have this particular type of compulsion/attraction. The sensitive, almost spiritual, love that the main character feels toward these cadavers is portrayed in a very ethereal manner and it allows us, the viewers, to almost understand the attraction. The inability of the main character to have a healthy relationship with a living being is also very common with this type of deviancy. That two people who have something of the same infatuation should be attracted to each other is not uncommon, nor is the willingness to be a participant in such a relationship. These are abnormal personality disorders and as such, cannot be judged by normal behavioral measures. This is a film that successfully taps into the psyche of this type of necrophilia that can manifest itself for no apparent reason. It is difficult to know how such abnormal behavior develops but there has been discussion that it may have something to do with aberrant development of the pre-frontal cortex in the brain, although it is not completely limited to this region. This type of development is difficult to predict or to even map within the realm of science much less cinematography. The director showed an inspired understanding of early manifested behavioral patterns that created a realistic lead-in to increased aberrant behavior. Good show!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    convincingly conveyed mix of true innocence and corruption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    christopher-underwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Obviously not for everyone but I just love this little film. I am sure there are plot holes galore but I am persuaded by the film's inner truth. From those early shots of the young girl's ritualistic behaviour and the chilling/exciting manner in which she strokes herself with the little parcels, one is surely hooked and ready to explore the world of this young lady who wishes to cavort with the departed. There is just enough humour and masses of emotion. Molly Parker and Peter Outerbridge are most convincing in their difficult roles, his probably even more difficult than hers. She has to convince us of the attractiveness of the unthinkable but he has to convince us that he can go along with all this as her girlfriend, and does. It reminded me a bit of Peter Jackson's, Heavenly Creatures (back when he made real films!) and I think it was because of that rarely convincingly conveyed mix of true innocence and corruption. Heady stuff,
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much more than a necrophiliac girl
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rqwxyz
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe the greatest achievement of the film is that it was able to deal with an subject such as necrophilia without falling into tastelessness. It's easy getting horrified at the idea of people being sexually attracted for corpses, but the relationship of mankind with death (That primigenial and fascinating fear) can go that far and, if you think of it, it goes way far beyond . If you are not willing to get into any reflexions about how the dead are treated, you may fell uneasy about the film. The contrast between Sandra and the other people manipulating bodies (the teachers, the embalmer) is rather eloquent. But what I personally liked the best about it is how it figures relationships, elucidating the insane need of one not having the other have its own and private corner, the need of forcing the other to share it, and the woe that comes from not being able to stand it. In this line, necrophilia becomes just an excuse.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is the tackling of taboos a good enough reason to see a film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Howlin Wolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kissed" walks very close to the invisible line marked out by this question. I say this because it wasn't necessarily compositional quality that kept me watching; more instead the apparent 'shock factor' of its topic, because gratuity often has a tendency to overwhelm any nuances that may also be present. When dealing with such an 'underground' subject matter (excuse the pun!), then technical proficiency almost becomes irrelevant. If some of the film's images weren't so loudly sensationalistic, one is left thinking with chagrin that the honest speaking voice could more easily be heard... It's almost unfortunate that there is so much nudity, and that it's such an unusual topic, because the sympathetic quality underlying the script may well be overlooked by a lot of people. If you are the type who is able to put themselves in someone else's position without always agreeing with how they go about things; then the main character's struggle with her feelings may very well move you. I feel that certain shots contained within could well be construed as unnecessarily pandering to controversy, though. If this gets more people to give it a chance, then I guess it might well turn out to be a good thing. For the film-makers it must have been a case of being caught between the devil and the deep blue sea, and each individual person will resolve the decided final approach in their own way... The journey the audience take is an unsettling walk with a person longing to find a state where people don't judge, and it affected me far deeper emotionally when it was more reticent about what it revealed, not vice-versa. By holding back on what was shown and exercising just a little more subtlety, it's my opinion that a far stronger position would then be gained to concentrate entirely on this poor young woman and her inner torment. In fact, the more I think about it, not permitting her to give in to the temptation of the act would also lend more resonance to the moment when we finally learn how the people who love her deal with this issue, too. I think too much 'exposure' too soon unfortunately undermines a great deal of its potential impact at the cost of gaining the work a wider notoriety. Despite this hindrance that in my mind prevents it from being of even greater value, "Kissed" is a film which I would say still remains worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Song in Dance Scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fecalite
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie! It definitely encouraged my friend to pursue a career in death care. The soundtrack is awesome too, but one of my favorite songs from the movie is missing from it. Near the beginning of the movie when the young Sandra is playing with her only friend, Carol, Sandra discovers that her can has found a family of dead mice. Sandra tells Carol they will have a special ceremony to commemorate the mice and they find a place in the wood to bury them. After interment, Sandra plays a rather 70s style song on her tape recorder and she and Carol dance to it. Does anyone know what the title of the song is and who wrote it? It's not on the soundtrack. Thanks!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting subject matter; very poorly handled (some pun intended)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s k
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As some other reviewers have already pointed out, "Kissed" is not a bad film because it tries to tackle the taboo subject of necrophilia -- it's a bad film because it does a bad job of dealing with the subject matter. It's as if the writer and director wanted to make a "Lifetime" movie about necrophilia. (See how yucky that is? Well...that's pretty much the feeling throughout the movie as well.) As I stated in one of the board threads, what I found most disturbing about this film was not the subject matter of necrophilia, although that clearly IS something very disturbing in itself. What I found most disturbing is the fact that the film maker has attempted to somehow glorify that sick, twisted fetish and equate it with love. It is NOT LOVE. It is mental illness of the highest order. And to even begin to glamorize, beautify, or glorify it, as this film does, is even more offensive than the subject matter itself. IF the film had at least attempted to try to UNDERSTAND necrophilia -- which in and of itself would have been one hell of an undertaking -- that would be different. But it doesn't come close to doing that. What it does is titillate and obfuscate the issue(s), then paint some twisted variation of a Disney "ain't love grand" nonsensical ending over top of it. Kissed might arguably be a worthwhile film to watch if for nothing else than to see what necrophilia is NOT, and to stimulate some sort of thought process into what it might be. Aside from that, the film has little if any redeeming value.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as terrible or as brilliant as the extremes profess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mojochi
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a purposefully simple and obvious film, but good. Could it have been more complex or developed? Sure. Did it need to be? I think not. The goals were achieved. The mood was executed appropriately, and the performances were given well enough that additional development, while perhaps useful, was not necessary to the objective. Do we need to know why the little girl is attracted to dead things? Not really, unless you're doing a psyche profile on her. For dramatic purposes, it is simply enough to note that she has a life long relationship to it. In fact, in this case there is even a romanticism & perhaps myth centering around her obsession, such that overly defining how it came about would defeat its allure. That allure is what the film is embracing, the allure of necrophilia being more than just a sexual fetish, involving perhaps all four of the principal characters, the girl, her boyfriend, her mentor, & even the custodian, all of whom have varied, & uniquely unnatural fascinations with the subject. The story is direct, & it drives straight to the point without delay, & its characters all have a purpose & design, which conclude fittingly, even including the girl's undertaker mentor, who gets a glimpse into her truth at the end & leaves speechless, knowing all too well what is really happening, just as his custodian knows too well the truth of him. Anyway, onto the question everybody needs answered. Is this arousing? Well, in any well adjusted sense, of course the notion of making love to the dead is not supposed to be sexually arousing, but the film is, or at least alluring, if not in a fully sexual way. Truth be told, there is something arousing about this film, even if it's only arousing to the subject of necrophilia in a voyeuristic way. In short, it's not arousing such that it makes you want to go hump a corpse, but it does make you want to watch her do it. As such, the film is a success at pushing the artistic envelop. To understand the level of difficulty in achieving something like this, one need only reflect on how impossible it would be to make an equally enticing story about any other abominable fetish, like fecophilia. Sounds pretty tough doesn't it? A great deal of the success in making this story alluring was in how it was presented & by whom, & I mean specifically the well played performance given by the celestially beautiful Molly Parker, whose every square inch of freckled majesty I worship, so much so that I too would hang myself, sooner than look away from her glorious visage, or turn away from hearing the hushed tones of her sweet & transcendent voice I would feel myself bask in her radiance, even if it were a movie wherein she only sat at a bus stop & read from the phone book. I'll watch anything that woman is in, & in this case, I felt I spent my time wisely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What amazes me is that there are people that love and praise this film...I think I'm going to an alarm system for my house!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This story is about a lonely and twisted lady who has a fascination with dead people--so much so that she gets a job in a mortuary. However, she is not just fascinated but stimulated by the dead and begins to have her way with them. When she meets a seemingly nice guy who cares about her, she cannot give of herself to him...as he's alive. So, in a bizarre twist, he makes himself more attractive to her in a very sick but supposedly romantic finale. The acting is decent and the film is technically well done...but very, very unsettling and grotesque. Years ago, I saw this film and was hesitant to ever review it--after all, I'd hate my friends to know I've seen this! Plus, I tried very, very hard to erase the film from my memory because I regretted seeing such a sick and thoroughly nasty film--with almost nothing to recommend it. After all, the film glorifies and romanticizes necrophilia--yes, necrophilia (that's doing the nasty with dead folks for you less informed readers). If Lynne Stopkewich and Angus Fraser had made a movie glorifying pedophiles or serial rapists would people have praised it?! Probably not...or at least they wouldn't have done so publicly...after all, these are nasty and illegal. So, why, then, praise necrophilia?! It's illegal (in most but not all places) and really, really gross...yet to some, it's romantic or compelling?! Why not, then, make films about urophilics (people who like to tinkle on others for gratification) or copraphilics (people who like to defecate on others for gratification)?! By the way, if you notice I am using euphemisms and talking around things, IMDb won't allow certain key words in its reviews. The fact that people actually LIKED this film disturbs me more than the fact that the film was made in the first place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mediocre film veiled behind droning philosophy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dead_doll00
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally, I didn't so much get worked up over this movie as I found it rather...mediocre. Many times I was bored and I found that Sandra's constant notions of "light, energy, etc." were forced and unoriginal. So she slept with corpses and experienced a euphoric awakening? Sorry, I just couldn't buy that. I understand the movie was trying to convey a message about transcendence and the similarities between life/death and love/hate (and yes, I understood the point of Matt's suicide and the many progressive layers of his obsession/love for her), but for me, that message just didn't come through well at all. In the end, it felt like it was all about her growing sexual attraction to death more so than anything else, culminating with her finally going all the way with her cadavers, droning on philosophically while she diddled away as though to curtain the fact that if she wasn't the kind of character she was, the interpretation of this movie would have been far less kinder. I think, had they made her character less of the "ethereal, mysterious outcast" type they so desperately tried to convey her as being, the subject matter wouldn't have been seen as deep and artsy but rather just a bland movie about necrophilia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Parker is great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ellkew
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This had an odd film to it that reminded me of Harold and Maude in tone. It does not really fit in any category which is always a good thing in my book. That said it didn't work on a complete level. I had problems with the boyfriend and I found it hard to believe the way he responded to her sleeping with dead people from the start. I expected him to be a little more horrified. I also didn't believe his outcome but I suppose it was always going to happen. Molly Parker was simply great and it was such a difficult role to pull off but she does it admirably. I really believed her and this world she ventured into. It manages to make a taboo subject seem quite fascinating which in itself is groundbreaking. I think it does stand true that if the sexes were switched then audiences would indeed have trouble swallowing the story but this way round it is more acceptable. Well that's the double standard thing again. Thought provoking and sensual. I take away from this Parker's performance more than anything, without her I think the film would be consigned to the annals of history.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    interesting subject
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomnkiki
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had to give this movie 9 stars out of ten because, having some background in Abnormal Psychology, this subject was very interesting to me. It is not often the subject of necrophilia is presented in a film that is non-academic or a complete gore fest. The portrayal of the main character's abnormal obsession with dead corpses was presented in a very enlightened and informed manner which was surprising. This deviant behavior was portrayed as being right and normal in the psyche of the necrophiliac and that is exactly how this type of necrophilia is described by those who have this particular type of compulsion/attraction. The sensitive, almost spiritual, love that the main character feels toward these cadavers is portrayed in a very ethereal manner and it allows us, the viewers, to almost understand the attraction. The inability of the main character to have a healthy relationship with a living being is also very common with this type of deviancy. That two people who have something of the same infatuation should be attracted to each other is not uncommon, nor is the willingness to be a participant in such a relationship. These are abnormal personality disorders and as such, cannot be judged by normal behavioral measures. This is a film that successfully taps into the psyche of this type of necrophilia that can manifest itself for no apparent reason. It is difficult to know how such abnormal behavior develops but there has been discussion that it may have something to do with aberrant development of the pre-frontal cortex in the brain, although it is not completely limited to this region. This type of development is difficult to predict or to even map within the realm of science much less cinematography. The director showed an inspired understanding of early manifested behavioral patterns that created a realistic lead-in to increased aberrant behavior. Good show!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    convincingly conveyed mix of true innocence and corruption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    christopher-underwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Obviously not for everyone but I just love this little film. I am sure there are plot holes galore but I am persuaded by the film's inner truth. From those early shots of the young girl's ritualistic behaviour and the chilling/exciting manner in which she strokes herself with the little parcels, one is surely hooked and ready to explore the world of this young lady who wishes to cavort with the departed. There is just enough humour and masses of emotion. Molly Parker and Peter Outerbridge are most convincing in their difficult roles, his probably even more difficult than hers. She has to convince us of the attractiveness of the unthinkable but he has to convince us that he can go along with all this as her girlfriend, and does. It reminded me a bit of Peter Jackson's, Heavenly Creatures (back when he made real films!) and I think it was because of that rarely convincingly conveyed mix of true innocence and corruption. Heady stuff,
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much more than a necrophiliac girl
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rqwxyz
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe the greatest achievement of the film is that it was able to deal with an subject such as necrophilia without falling into tastelessness. It's easy getting horrified at the idea of people being sexually attracted for corpses, but the relationship of mankind with death (That primigenial and fascinating fear) can go that far and, if you think of it, it goes way far beyond . If you are not willing to get into any reflexions about how the dead are treated, you may fell uneasy about the film. The contrast between Sandra and the other people manipulating bodies (the teachers, the embalmer) is rather eloquent. But what I personally liked the best about it is how it figures relationships, elucidating the insane need of one not having the other have its own and private corner, the need of forcing the other to share it, and the woe that comes from not being able to stand it. In this line, necrophilia becomes just an excuse.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is the tackling of taboos a good enough reason to see a film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Howlin Wolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kissed" walks very close to the invisible line marked out by this question. I say this because it wasn't necessarily compositional quality that kept me watching; more instead the apparent 'shock factor' of its topic, because gratuity often has a tendency to overwhelm any nuances that may also be present. When dealing with such an 'underground' subject matter (excuse the pun!), then technical proficiency almost becomes irrelevant. If some of the film's images weren't so loudly sensationalistic, one is left thinking with chagrin that the honest speaking voice could more easily be heard... It's almost unfortunate that there is so much nudity, and that it's such an unusual topic, because the sympathetic quality underlying the script may well be overlooked by a lot of people. If you are the type who is able to put themselves in someone else's position without always agreeing with how they go about things; then the main character's struggle with her feelings may very well move you. I feel that certain shots contained within could well be construed as unnecessarily pandering to controversy, though. If this gets more people to give it a chance, then I guess it might well turn out to be a good thing. For the film-makers it must have been a case of being caught between the devil and the deep blue sea, and each individual person will resolve the decided final approach in their own way... The journey the audience take is an unsettling walk with a person longing to find a state where people don't judge, and it affected me far deeper emotionally when it was more reticent about what it revealed, not vice-versa. By holding back on what was shown and exercising just a little more subtlety, it's my opinion that a far stronger position would then be gained to concentrate entirely on this poor young woman and her inner torment. In fact, the more I think about it, not permitting her to give in to the temptation of the act would also lend more resonance to the moment when we finally learn how the people who love her deal with this issue, too. I think too much 'exposure' too soon unfortunately undermines a great deal of its potential impact at the cost of gaining the work a wider notoriety. Despite this hindrance that in my mind prevents it from being of even greater value, "Kissed" is a film which I would say still remains worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Song in Dance Scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fecalite
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie! It definitely encouraged my friend to pursue a career in death care. The soundtrack is awesome too, but one of my favorite songs from the movie is missing from it. Near the beginning of the movie when the young Sandra is playing with her only friend, Carol, Sandra discovers that her can has found a family of dead mice. Sandra tells Carol they will have a special ceremony to commemorate the mice and they find a place in the wood to bury them. After interment, Sandra plays a rather 70s style song on her tape recorder and she and Carol dance to it. Does anyone know what the title of the song is and who wrote it? It's not on the soundtrack. Thanks!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting subject matter; very poorly handled (some pun intended)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s k
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As some other reviewers have already pointed out, "Kissed" is not a bad film because it tries to tackle the taboo subject of necrophilia -- it's a bad film because it does a bad job of dealing with the subject matter. It's as if the writer and director wanted to make a "Lifetime" movie about necrophilia. (See how yucky that is? Well...that's pretty much the feeling throughout the movie as well.) As I stated in one of the board threads, what I found most disturbing about this film was not the subject matter of necrophilia, although that clearly IS something very disturbing in itself. What I found most disturbing is the fact that the film maker has attempted to somehow glorify that sick, twisted fetish and equate it with love. It is NOT LOVE. It is mental illness of the highest order. And to even begin to glamorize, beautify, or glorify it, as this film does, is even more offensive than the subject matter itself. IF the film had at least attempted to try to UNDERSTAND necrophilia -- which in and of itself would have been one hell of an undertaking -- that would be different. But it doesn't come close to doing that. What it does is titillate and obfuscate the issue(s), then paint some twisted variation of a Disney "ain't love grand" nonsensical ending over top of it. Kissed might arguably be a worthwhile film to watch if for nothing else than to see what necrophilia is NOT, and to stimulate some sort of thought process into what it might be. Aside from that, the film has little if any redeeming value.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as terrible or as brilliant as the extremes profess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mojochi
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a purposefully simple and obvious film, but good. Could it have been more complex or developed? Sure. Did it need to be? I think not. The goals were achieved. The mood was executed appropriately, and the performances were given well enough that additional development, while perhaps useful, was not necessary to the objective. Do we need to know why the little girl is attracted to dead things? Not really, unless you're doing a psyche profile on her. For dramatic purposes, it is simply enough to note that she has a life long relationship to it. In fact, in this case there is even a romanticism & perhaps myth centering around her obsession, such that overly defining how it came about would defeat its allure. That allure is what the film is embracing, the allure of necrophilia being more than just a sexual fetish, involving perhaps all four of the principal characters, the girl, her boyfriend, her mentor, & even the custodian, all of whom have varied, & uniquely unnatural fascinations with the subject. The story is direct, & it drives straight to the point without delay, & its characters all have a purpose & design, which conclude fittingly, even including the girl's undertaker mentor, who gets a glimpse into her truth at the end & leaves speechless, knowing all too well what is really happening, just as his custodian knows too well the truth of him. Anyway, onto the question everybody needs answered. Is this arousing? Well, in any well adjusted sense, of course the notion of making love to the dead is not supposed to be sexually arousing, but the film is, or at least alluring, if not in a fully sexual way. Truth be told, there is something arousing about this film, even if it's only arousing to the subject of necrophilia in a voyeuristic way. In short, it's not arousing such that it makes you want to go hump a corpse, but it does make you want to watch her do it. As such, the film is a success at pushing the artistic envelop. To understand the level of difficulty in achieving something like this, one need only reflect on how impossible it would be to make an equally enticing story about any other abominable fetish, like fecophilia. Sounds pretty tough doesn't it? A great deal of the success in making this story alluring was in how it was presented & by whom, & I mean specifically the well played performance given by the celestially beautiful Molly Parker, whose every square inch of freckled majesty I worship, so much so that I too would hang myself, sooner than look away from her glorious visage, or turn away from hearing the hushed tones of her sweet & transcendent voice I would feel myself bask in her radiance, even if it were a movie wherein she only sat at a bus stop & read from the phone book. I'll watch anything that woman is in, & in this case, I felt I spent my time wisely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What amazes me is that there are people that love and praise this film...I think I'm going to an alarm system for my house!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This story is about a lonely and twisted lady who has a fascination with dead people--so much so that she gets a job in a mortuary. However, she is not just fascinated but stimulated by the dead and begins to have her way with them. When she meets a seemingly nice guy who cares about her, she cannot give of herself to him...as he's alive. So, in a bizarre twist, he makes himself more attractive to her in a very sick but supposedly romantic finale. The acting is decent and the film is technically well done...but very, very unsettling and grotesque. Years ago, I saw this film and was hesitant to ever review it--after all, I'd hate my friends to know I've seen this! Plus, I tried very, very hard to erase the film from my memory because I regretted seeing such a sick and thoroughly nasty film--with almost nothing to recommend it. After all, the film glorifies and romanticizes necrophilia--yes, necrophilia (that's doing the nasty with dead folks for you less informed readers). If Lynne Stopkewich and Angus Fraser had made a movie glorifying pedophiles or serial rapists would people have praised it?! Probably not...or at least they wouldn't have done so publicly...after all, these are nasty and illegal. So, why, then, praise necrophilia?! It's illegal (in most but not all places) and really, really gross...yet to some, it's romantic or compelling?! Why not, then, make films about urophilics (people who like to tinkle on others for gratification) or copraphilics (people who like to defecate on others for gratification)?! By the way, if you notice I am using euphemisms and talking around things, IMDb won't allow certain key words in its reviews. The fact that people actually LIKED this film disturbs me more than the fact that the film was made in the first place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mediocre film veiled behind droning philosophy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dead_doll00
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally, I didn't so much get worked up over this movie as I found it rather...mediocre. Many times I was bored and I found that Sandra's constant notions of "light, energy, etc." were forced and unoriginal. So she slept with corpses and experienced a euphoric awakening? Sorry, I just couldn't buy that. I understand the movie was trying to convey a message about transcendence and the similarities between life/death and love/hate (and yes, I understood the point of Matt's suicide and the many progressive layers of his obsession/love for her), but for me, that message just didn't come through well at all. In the end, it felt like it was all about her growing sexual attraction to death more so than anything else, culminating with her finally going all the way with her cadavers, droning on philosophically while she diddled away as though to curtain the fact that if she wasn't the kind of character she was, the interpretation of this movie would have been far less kinder. I think, had they made her character less of the "ethereal, mysterious outcast" type they so desperately tried to convey her as being, the subject matter wouldn't have been seen as deep and artsy but rather just a bland movie about necrophilia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Parker is great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ellkew
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This had an odd film to it that reminded me of Harold and Maude in tone. It does not really fit in any category which is always a good thing in my book. That said it didn't work on a complete level. I had problems with the boyfriend and I found it hard to believe the way he responded to her sleeping with dead people from the start. I expected him to be a little more horrified. I also didn't believe his outcome but I suppose it was always going to happen. Molly Parker was simply great and it was such a difficult role to pull off but she does it admirably. I really believed her and this world she ventured into. It manages to make a taboo subject seem quite fascinating which in itself is groundbreaking. I think it does stand true that if the sexes were switched then audiences would indeed have trouble swallowing the story but this way round it is more acceptable. Well that's the double standard thing again. Thought provoking and sensual. I take away from this Parker's performance more than anything, without her I think the film would be consigned to the annals of history.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    interesting subject
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomnkiki
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had to give this movie 9 stars out of ten because, having some background in Abnormal Psychology, this subject was very interesting to me. It is not often the subject of necrophilia is presented in a film that is non-academic or a complete gore fest. The portrayal of the main character's abnormal obsession with dead corpses was presented in a very enlightened and informed manner which was surprising. This deviant behavior was portrayed as being right and normal in the psyche of the necrophiliac and that is exactly how this type of necrophilia is described by those who have this particular type of compulsion/attraction. The sensitive, almost spiritual, love that the main character feels toward these cadavers is portrayed in a very ethereal manner and it allows us, the viewers, to almost understand the attraction. The inability of the main character to have a healthy relationship with a living being is also very common with this type of deviancy. That two people who have something of the same infatuation should be attracted to each other is not uncommon, nor is the willingness to be a participant in such a relationship. These are abnormal personality disorders and as such, cannot be judged by normal behavioral measures. This is a film that successfully taps into the psyche of this type of necrophilia that can manifest itself for no apparent reason. It is difficult to know how such abnormal behavior develops but there has been discussion that it may have something to do with aberrant development of the pre-frontal cortex in the brain, although it is not completely limited to this region. This type of development is difficult to predict or to even map within the realm of science much less cinematography. The director showed an inspired understanding of early manifested behavioral patterns that created a realistic lead-in to increased aberrant behavior. Good show!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    convincingly conveyed mix of true innocence and corruption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    christopher-underwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Obviously not for everyone but I just love this little film. I am sure there are plot holes galore but I am persuaded by the film's inner truth. From those early shots of the young girl's ritualistic behaviour and the chilling/exciting manner in which she strokes herself with the little parcels, one is surely hooked and ready to explore the world of this young lady who wishes to cavort with the departed. There is just enough humour and masses of emotion. Molly Parker and Peter Outerbridge are most convincing in their difficult roles, his probably even more difficult than hers. She has to convince us of the attractiveness of the unthinkable but he has to convince us that he can go along with all this as her girlfriend, and does. It reminded me a bit of Peter Jackson's, Heavenly Creatures (back when he made real films!) and I think it was because of that rarely convincingly conveyed mix of true innocence and corruption. Heady stuff,
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much more than a necrophiliac girl
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rqwxyz
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe the greatest achievement of the film is that it was able to deal with an subject such as necrophilia without falling into tastelessness. It's easy getting horrified at the idea of people being sexually attracted for corpses, but the relationship of mankind with death (That primigenial and fascinating fear) can go that far and, if you think of it, it goes way far beyond . If you are not willing to get into any reflexions about how the dead are treated, you may fell uneasy about the film. The contrast between Sandra and the other people manipulating bodies (the teachers, the embalmer) is rather eloquent. But what I personally liked the best about it is how it figures relationships, elucidating the insane need of one not having the other have its own and private corner, the need of forcing the other to share it, and the woe that comes from not being able to stand it. In this line, necrophilia becomes just an excuse.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is the tackling of taboos a good enough reason to see a film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Howlin Wolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kissed" walks very close to the invisible line marked out by this question. I say this because it wasn't necessarily compositional quality that kept me watching; more instead the apparent 'shock factor' of its topic, because gratuity often has a tendency to overwhelm any nuances that may also be present. When dealing with such an 'underground' subject matter (excuse the pun!), then technical proficiency almost becomes irrelevant. If some of the film's images weren't so loudly sensationalistic, one is left thinking with chagrin that the honest speaking voice could more easily be heard... It's almost unfortunate that there is so much nudity, and that it's such an unusual topic, because the sympathetic quality underlying the script may well be overlooked by a lot of people. If you are the type who is able to put themselves in someone else's position without always agreeing with how they go about things; then the main character's struggle with her feelings may very well move you. I feel that certain shots contained within could well be construed as unnecessarily pandering to controversy, though. If this gets more people to give it a chance, then I guess it might well turn out to be a good thing. For the film-makers it must have been a case of being caught between the devil and the deep blue sea, and each individual person will resolve the decided final approach in their own way... The journey the audience take is an unsettling walk with a person longing to find a state where people don't judge, and it affected me far deeper emotionally when it was more reticent about what it revealed, not vice-versa. By holding back on what was shown and exercising just a little more subtlety, it's my opinion that a far stronger position would then be gained to concentrate entirely on this poor young woman and her inner torment. In fact, the more I think about it, not permitting her to give in to the temptation of the act would also lend more resonance to the moment when we finally learn how the people who love her deal with this issue, too. I think too much 'exposure' too soon unfortunately undermines a great deal of its potential impact at the cost of gaining the work a wider notoriety. Despite this hindrance that in my mind prevents it from being of even greater value, "Kissed" is a film which I would say still remains worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Song in Dance Scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fecalite
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie! It definitely encouraged my friend to pursue a career in death care. The soundtrack is awesome too, but one of my favorite songs from the movie is missing from it. Near the beginning of the movie when the young Sandra is playing with her only friend, Carol, Sandra discovers that her can has found a family of dead mice. Sandra tells Carol they will have a special ceremony to commemorate the mice and they find a place in the wood to bury them. After interment, Sandra plays a rather 70s style song on her tape recorder and she and Carol dance to it. Does anyone know what the title of the song is and who wrote it? It's not on the soundtrack. Thanks!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting subject matter; very poorly handled (some pun intended)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s k
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As some other reviewers have already pointed out, "Kissed" is not a bad film because it tries to tackle the taboo subject of necrophilia -- it's a bad film because it does a bad job of dealing with the subject matter. It's as if the writer and director wanted to make a "Lifetime" movie about necrophilia. (See how yucky that is? Well...that's pretty much the feeling throughout the movie as well.) As I stated in one of the board threads, what I found most disturbing about this film was not the subject matter of necrophilia, although that clearly IS something very disturbing in itself. What I found most disturbing is the fact that the film maker has attempted to somehow glorify that sick, twisted fetish and equate it with love. It is NOT LOVE. It is mental illness of the highest order. And to even begin to glamorize, beautify, or glorify it, as this film does, is even more offensive than the subject matter itself. IF the film had at least attempted to try to UNDERSTAND necrophilia -- which in and of itself would have been one hell of an undertaking -- that would be different. But it doesn't come close to doing that. What it does is titillate and obfuscate the issue(s), then paint some twisted variation of a Disney "ain't love grand" nonsensical ending over top of it. Kissed might arguably be a worthwhile film to watch if for nothing else than to see what necrophilia is NOT, and to stimulate some sort of thought process into what it might be. Aside from that, the film has little if any redeeming value.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as terrible or as brilliant as the extremes profess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mojochi
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a purposefully simple and obvious film, but good. Could it have been more complex or developed? Sure. Did it need to be? I think not. The goals were achieved. The mood was executed appropriately, and the performances were given well enough that additional development, while perhaps useful, was not necessary to the objective. Do we need to know why the little girl is attracted to dead things? Not really, unless you're doing a psyche profile on her. For dramatic purposes, it is simply enough to note that she has a life long relationship to it. In fact, in this case there is even a romanticism & perhaps myth centering around her obsession, such that overly defining how it came about would defeat its allure. That allure is what the film is embracing, the allure of necrophilia being more than just a sexual fetish, involving perhaps all four of the principal characters, the girl, her boyfriend, her mentor, & even the custodian, all of whom have varied, & uniquely unnatural fascinations with the subject. The story is direct, & it drives straight to the point without delay, & its characters all have a purpose & design, which conclude fittingly, even including the girl's undertaker mentor, who gets a glimpse into her truth at the end & leaves speechless, knowing all too well what is really happening, just as his custodian knows too well the truth of him. Anyway, onto the question everybody needs answered. Is this arousing? Well, in any well adjusted sense, of course the notion of making love to the dead is not supposed to be sexually arousing, but the film is, or at least alluring, if not in a fully sexual way. Truth be told, there is something arousing about this film, even if it's only arousing to the subject of necrophilia in a voyeuristic way. In short, it's not arousing such that it makes you want to go hump a corpse, but it does make you want to watch her do it. As such, the film is a success at pushing the artistic envelop. To understand the level of difficulty in achieving something like this, one need only reflect on how impossible it would be to make an equally enticing story about any other abominable fetish, like fecophilia. Sounds pretty tough doesn't it? A great deal of the success in making this story alluring was in how it was presented & by whom, & I mean specifically the well played performance given by the celestially beautiful Molly Parker, whose every square inch of freckled majesty I worship, so much so that I too would hang myself, sooner than look away from her glorious visage, or turn away from hearing the hushed tones of her sweet & transcendent voice I would feel myself bask in her radiance, even if it were a movie wherein she only sat at a bus stop & read from the phone book. I'll watch anything that woman is in, & in this case, I felt I spent my time wisely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What amazes me is that there are people that love and praise this film...I think I'm going to an alarm system for my house!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This story is about a lonely and twisted lady who has a fascination with dead people--so much so that she gets a job in a mortuary. However, she is not just fascinated but stimulated by the dead and begins to have her way with them. When she meets a seemingly nice guy who cares about her, she cannot give of herself to him...as he's alive. So, in a bizarre twist, he makes himself more attractive to her in a very sick but supposedly romantic finale. The acting is decent and the film is technically well done...but very, very unsettling and grotesque. Years ago, I saw this film and was hesitant to ever review it--after all, I'd hate my friends to know I've seen this! Plus, I tried very, very hard to erase the film from my memory because I regretted seeing such a sick and thoroughly nasty film--with almost nothing to recommend it. After all, the film glorifies and romanticizes necrophilia--yes, necrophilia (that's doing the nasty with dead folks for you less informed readers). If Lynne Stopkewich and Angus Fraser had made a movie glorifying pedophiles or serial rapists would people have praised it?! Probably not...or at least they wouldn't have done so publicly...after all, these are nasty and illegal. So, why, then, praise necrophilia?! It's illegal (in most but not all places) and really, really gross...yet to some, it's romantic or compelling?! Why not, then, make films about urophilics (people who like to tinkle on others for gratification) or copraphilics (people who like to defecate on others for gratification)?! By the way, if you notice I am using euphemisms and talking around things, IMDb won't allow certain key words in its reviews. The fact that people actually LIKED this film disturbs me more than the fact that the film was made in the first place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mediocre film veiled behind droning philosophy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dead_doll00
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally, I didn't so much get worked up over this movie as I found it rather...mediocre. Many times I was bored and I found that Sandra's constant notions of "light, energy, etc." were forced and unoriginal. So she slept with corpses and experienced a euphoric awakening? Sorry, I just couldn't buy that. I understand the movie was trying to convey a message about transcendence and the similarities between life/death and love/hate (and yes, I understood the point of Matt's suicide and the many progressive layers of his obsession/love for her), but for me, that message just didn't come through well at all. In the end, it felt like it was all about her growing sexual attraction to death more so than anything else, culminating with her finally going all the way with her cadavers, droning on philosophically while she diddled away as though to curtain the fact that if she wasn't the kind of character she was, the interpretation of this movie would have been far less kinder. I think, had they made her character less of the "ethereal, mysterious outcast" type they so desperately tried to convey her as being, the subject matter wouldn't have been seen as deep and artsy but rather just a bland movie about necrophilia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Parker is great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ellkew
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This had an odd film to it that reminded me of Harold and Maude in tone. It does not really fit in any category which is always a good thing in my book. That said it didn't work on a complete level. I had problems with the boyfriend and I found it hard to believe the way he responded to her sleeping with dead people from the start. I expected him to be a little more horrified. I also didn't believe his outcome but I suppose it was always going to happen. Molly Parker was simply great and it was such a difficult role to pull off but she does it admirably. I really believed her and this world she ventured into. It manages to make a taboo subject seem quite fascinating which in itself is groundbreaking. I think it does stand true that if the sexes were switched then audiences would indeed have trouble swallowing the story but this way round it is more acceptable. Well that's the double standard thing again. Thought provoking and sensual. I take away from this Parker's performance more than anything, without her I think the film would be consigned to the annals of history.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    interesting subject
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomnkiki
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had to give this movie 9 stars out of ten because, having some background in Abnormal Psychology, this subject was very interesting to me. It is not often the subject of necrophilia is presented in a film that is non-academic or a complete gore fest. The portrayal of the main character's abnormal obsession with dead corpses was presented in a very enlightened and informed manner which was surprising. This deviant behavior was portrayed as being right and normal in the psyche of the necrophiliac and that is exactly how this type of necrophilia is described by those who have this particular type of compulsion/attraction. The sensitive, almost spiritual, love that the main character feels toward these cadavers is portrayed in a very ethereal manner and it allows us, the viewers, to almost understand the attraction. The inability of the main character to have a healthy relationship with a living being is also very common with this type of deviancy. That two people who have something of the same infatuation should be attracted to each other is not uncommon, nor is the willingness to be a participant in such a relationship. These are abnormal personality disorders and as such, cannot be judged by normal behavioral measures. This is a film that successfully taps into the psyche of this type of necrophilia that can manifest itself for no apparent reason. It is difficult to know how such abnormal behavior develops but there has been discussion that it may have something to do with aberrant development of the pre-frontal cortex in the brain, although it is not completely limited to this region. This type of development is difficult to predict or to even map within the realm of science much less cinematography. The director showed an inspired understanding of early manifested behavioral patterns that created a realistic lead-in to increased aberrant behavior. Good show!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    convincingly conveyed mix of true innocence and corruption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    christopher-underwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Obviously not for everyone but I just love this little film. I am sure there are plot holes galore but I am persuaded by the film's inner truth. From those early shots of the young girl's ritualistic behaviour and the chilling/exciting manner in which she strokes herself with the little parcels, one is surely hooked and ready to explore the world of this young lady who wishes to cavort with the departed. There is just enough humour and masses of emotion. Molly Parker and Peter Outerbridge are most convincing in their difficult roles, his probably even more difficult than hers. She has to convince us of the attractiveness of the unthinkable but he has to convince us that he can go along with all this as her girlfriend, and does. It reminded me a bit of Peter Jackson's, Heavenly Creatures (back when he made real films!) and I think it was because of that rarely convincingly conveyed mix of true innocence and corruption. Heady stuff,
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much more than a necrophiliac girl
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rqwxyz
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe the greatest achievement of the film is that it was able to deal with an subject such as necrophilia without falling into tastelessness. It's easy getting horrified at the idea of people being sexually attracted for corpses, but the relationship of mankind with death (That primigenial and fascinating fear) can go that far and, if you think of it, it goes way far beyond . If you are not willing to get into any reflexions about how the dead are treated, you may fell uneasy about the film. The contrast between Sandra and the other people manipulating bodies (the teachers, the embalmer) is rather eloquent. But what I personally liked the best about it is how it figures relationships, elucidating the insane need of one not having the other have its own and private corner, the need of forcing the other to share it, and the woe that comes from not being able to stand it. In this line, necrophilia becomes just an excuse.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is the tackling of taboos a good enough reason to see a film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Howlin Wolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kissed" walks very close to the invisible line marked out by this question. I say this because it wasn't necessarily compositional quality that kept me watching; more instead the apparent 'shock factor' of its topic, because gratuity often has a tendency to overwhelm any nuances that may also be present. When dealing with such an 'underground' subject matter (excuse the pun!), then technical proficiency almost becomes irrelevant. If some of the film's images weren't so loudly sensationalistic, one is left thinking with chagrin that the honest speaking voice could more easily be heard... It's almost unfortunate that there is so much nudity, and that it's such an unusual topic, because the sympathetic quality underlying the script may well be overlooked by a lot of people. If you are the type who is able to put themselves in someone else's position without always agreeing with how they go about things; then the main character's struggle with her feelings may very well move you. I feel that certain shots contained within could well be construed as unnecessarily pandering to controversy, though. If this gets more people to give it a chance, then I guess it might well turn out to be a good thing. For the film-makers it must have been a case of being caught between the devil and the deep blue sea, and each individual person will resolve the decided final approach in their own way... The journey the audience take is an unsettling walk with a person longing to find a state where people don't judge, and it affected me far deeper emotionally when it was more reticent about what it revealed, not vice-versa. By holding back on what was shown and exercising just a little more subtlety, it's my opinion that a far stronger position would then be gained to concentrate entirely on this poor young woman and her inner torment. In fact, the more I think about it, not permitting her to give in to the temptation of the act would also lend more resonance to the moment when we finally learn how the people who love her deal with this issue, too. I think too much 'exposure' too soon unfortunately undermines a great deal of its potential impact at the cost of gaining the work a wider notoriety. Despite this hindrance that in my mind prevents it from being of even greater value, "Kissed" is a film which I would say still remains worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Song in Dance Scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fecalite
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie! It definitely encouraged my friend to pursue a career in death care. The soundtrack is awesome too, but one of my favorite songs from the movie is missing from it. Near the beginning of the movie when the young Sandra is playing with her only friend, Carol, Sandra discovers that her can has found a family of dead mice. Sandra tells Carol they will have a special ceremony to commemorate the mice and they find a place in the wood to bury them. After interment, Sandra plays a rather 70s style song on her tape recorder and she and Carol dance to it. Does anyone know what the title of the song is and who wrote it? It's not on the soundtrack. Thanks!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting subject matter; very poorly handled (some pun intended)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s k
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As some other reviewers have already pointed out, "Kissed" is not a bad film because it tries to tackle the taboo subject of necrophilia -- it's a bad film because it does a bad job of dealing with the subject matter. It's as if the writer and director wanted to make a "Lifetime" movie about necrophilia. (See how yucky that is? Well...that's pretty much the feeling throughout the movie as well.) As I stated in one of the board threads, what I found most disturbing about this film was not the subject matter of necrophilia, although that clearly IS something very disturbing in itself. What I found most disturbing is the fact that the film maker has attempted to somehow glorify that sick, twisted fetish and equate it with love. It is NOT LOVE. It is mental illness of the highest order. And to even begin to glamorize, beautify, or glorify it, as this film does, is even more offensive than the subject matter itself. IF the film had at least attempted to try to UNDERSTAND necrophilia -- which in and of itself would have been one hell of an undertaking -- that would be different. But it doesn't come close to doing that. What it does is titillate and obfuscate the issue(s), then paint some twisted variation of a Disney "ain't love grand" nonsensical ending over top of it. Kissed might arguably be a worthwhile film to watch if for nothing else than to see what necrophilia is NOT, and to stimulate some sort of thought process into what it might be. Aside from that, the film has little if any redeeming value.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as terrible or as brilliant as the extremes profess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mojochi
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a purposefully simple and obvious film, but good. Could it have been more complex or developed? Sure. Did it need to be? I think not. The goals were achieved. The mood was executed appropriately, and the performances were given well enough that additional development, while perhaps useful, was not necessary to the objective. Do we need to know why the little girl is attracted to dead things? Not really, unless you're doing a psyche profile on her. For dramatic purposes, it is simply enough to note that she has a life long relationship to it. In fact, in this case there is even a romanticism & perhaps myth centering around her obsession, such that overly defining how it came about would defeat its allure. That allure is what the film is embracing, the allure of necrophilia being more than just a sexual fetish, involving perhaps all four of the principal characters, the girl, her boyfriend, her mentor, & even the custodian, all of whom have varied, & uniquely unnatural fascinations with the subject. The story is direct, & it drives straight to the point without delay, & its characters all have a purpose & design, which conclude fittingly, even including the girl's undertaker mentor, who gets a glimpse into her truth at the end & leaves speechless, knowing all too well what is really happening, just as his custodian knows too well the truth of him. Anyway, onto the question everybody needs answered. Is this arousing? Well, in any well adjusted sense, of course the notion of making love to the dead is not supposed to be sexually arousing, but the film is, or at least alluring, if not in a fully sexual way. Truth be told, there is something arousing about this film, even if it's only arousing to the subject of necrophilia in a voyeuristic way. In short, it's not arousing such that it makes you want to go hump a corpse, but it does make you want to watch her do it. As such, the film is a success at pushing the artistic envelop. To understand the level of difficulty in achieving something like this, one need only reflect on how impossible it would be to make an equally enticing story about any other abominable fetish, like fecophilia. Sounds pretty tough doesn't it? A great deal of the success in making this story alluring was in how it was presented & by whom, & I mean specifically the well played performance given by the celestially beautiful Molly Parker, whose every square inch of freckled majesty I worship, so much so that I too would hang myself, sooner than look away from her glorious visage, or turn away from hearing the hushed tones of her sweet & transcendent voice I would feel myself bask in her radiance, even if it were a movie wherein she only sat at a bus stop & read from the phone book. I'll watch anything that woman is in, & in this case, I felt I spent my time wisely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What amazes me is that there are people that love and praise this film...I think I'm going to an alarm system for my house!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This story is about a lonely and twisted lady who has a fascination with dead people--so much so that she gets a job in a mortuary. However, she is not just fascinated but stimulated by the dead and begins to have her way with them. When she meets a seemingly nice guy who cares about her, she cannot give of herself to him...as he's alive. So, in a bizarre twist, he makes himself more attractive to her in a very sick but supposedly romantic finale. The acting is decent and the film is technically well done...but very, very unsettling and grotesque. Years ago, I saw this film and was hesitant to ever review it--after all, I'd hate my friends to know I've seen this! Plus, I tried very, very hard to erase the film from my memory because I regretted seeing such a sick and thoroughly nasty film--with almost nothing to recommend it. After all, the film glorifies and romanticizes necrophilia--yes, necrophilia (that's doing the nasty with dead folks for you less informed readers). If Lynne Stopkewich and Angus Fraser had made a movie glorifying pedophiles or serial rapists would people have praised it?! Probably not...or at least they wouldn't have done so publicly...after all, these are nasty and illegal. So, why, then, praise necrophilia?! It's illegal (in most but not all places) and really, really gross...yet to some, it's romantic or compelling?! Why not, then, make films about urophilics (people who like to tinkle on others for gratification) or copraphilics (people who like to defecate on others for gratification)?! By the way, if you notice I am using euphemisms and talking around things, IMDb won't allow certain key words in its reviews. The fact that people actually LIKED this film disturbs me more than the fact that the film was made in the first place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mediocre film veiled behind droning philosophy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dead_doll00
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally, I didn't so much get worked up over this movie as I found it rather...mediocre. Many times I was bored and I found that Sandra's constant notions of "light, energy, etc." were forced and unoriginal. So she slept with corpses and experienced a euphoric awakening? Sorry, I just couldn't buy that. I understand the movie was trying to convey a message about transcendence and the similarities between life/death and love/hate (and yes, I understood the point of Matt's suicide and the many progressive layers of his obsession/love for her), but for me, that message just didn't come through well at all. In the end, it felt like it was all about her growing sexual attraction to death more so than anything else, culminating with her finally going all the way with her cadavers, droning on philosophically while she diddled away as though to curtain the fact that if she wasn't the kind of character she was, the interpretation of this movie would have been far less kinder. I think, had they made her character less of the "ethereal, mysterious outcast" type they so desperately tried to convey her as being, the subject matter wouldn't have been seen as deep and artsy but rather just a bland movie about necrophilia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Parker is great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ellkew
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This had an odd film to it that reminded me of Harold and Maude in tone. It does not really fit in any category which is always a good thing in my book. That said it didn't work on a complete level. I had problems with the boyfriend and I found it hard to believe the way he responded to her sleeping with dead people from the start. I expected him to be a little more horrified. I also didn't believe his outcome but I suppose it was always going to happen. Molly Parker was simply great and it was such a difficult role to pull off but she does it admirably. I really believed her and this world she ventured into. It manages to make a taboo subject seem quite fascinating which in itself is groundbreaking. I think it does stand true that if the sexes were switched then audiences would indeed have trouble swallowing the story but this way round it is more acceptable. Well that's the double standard thing again. Thought provoking and sensual. I take away from this Parker's performance more than anything, without her I think the film would be consigned to the annals of history.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    interesting subject
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomnkiki
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had to give this movie 9 stars out of ten because, having some background in Abnormal Psychology, this subject was very interesting to me. It is not often the subject of necrophilia is presented in a film that is non-academic or a complete gore fest. The portrayal of the main character's abnormal obsession with dead corpses was presented in a very enlightened and informed manner which was surprising. This deviant behavior was portrayed as being right and normal in the psyche of the necrophiliac and that is exactly how this type of necrophilia is described by those who have this particular type of compulsion/attraction. The sensitive, almost spiritual, love that the main character feels toward these cadavers is portrayed in a very ethereal manner and it allows us, the viewers, to almost understand the attraction. The inability of the main character to have a healthy relationship with a living being is also very common with this type of deviancy. That two people who have something of the same infatuation should be attracted to each other is not uncommon, nor is the willingness to be a participant in such a relationship. These are abnormal personality disorders and as such, cannot be judged by normal behavioral measures. This is a film that successfully taps into the psyche of this type of necrophilia that can manifest itself for no apparent reason. It is difficult to know how such abnormal behavior develops but there has been discussion that it may have something to do with aberrant development of the pre-frontal cortex in the brain, although it is not completely limited to this region. This type of development is difficult to predict or to even map within the realm of science much less cinematography. The director showed an inspired understanding of early manifested behavioral patterns that created a realistic lead-in to increased aberrant behavior. Good show!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    convincingly conveyed mix of true innocence and corruption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    christopher-underwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Obviously not for everyone but I just love this little film. I am sure there are plot holes galore but I am persuaded by the film's inner truth. From those early shots of the young girl's ritualistic behaviour and the chilling/exciting manner in which she strokes herself with the little parcels, one is surely hooked and ready to explore the world of this young lady who wishes to cavort with the departed. There is just enough humour and masses of emotion. Molly Parker and Peter Outerbridge are most convincing in their difficult roles, his probably even more difficult than hers. She has to convince us of the attractiveness of the unthinkable but he has to convince us that he can go along with all this as her girlfriend, and does. It reminded me a bit of Peter Jackson's, Heavenly Creatures (back when he made real films!) and I think it was because of that rarely convincingly conveyed mix of true innocence and corruption. Heady stuff,
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much more than a necrophiliac girl
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rqwxyz
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe the greatest achievement of the film is that it was able to deal with an subject such as necrophilia without falling into tastelessness. It's easy getting horrified at the idea of people being sexually attracted for corpses, but the relationship of mankind with death (That primigenial and fascinating fear) can go that far and, if you think of it, it goes way far beyond . If you are not willing to get into any reflexions about how the dead are treated, you may fell uneasy about the film. The contrast between Sandra and the other people manipulating bodies (the teachers, the embalmer) is rather eloquent. But what I personally liked the best about it is how it figures relationships, elucidating the insane need of one not having the other have its own and private corner, the need of forcing the other to share it, and the woe that comes from not being able to stand it. In this line, necrophilia becomes just an excuse.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is the tackling of taboos a good enough reason to see a film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Howlin Wolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kissed" walks very close to the invisible line marked out by this question. I say this because it wasn't necessarily compositional quality that kept me watching; more instead the apparent 'shock factor' of its topic, because gratuity often has a tendency to overwhelm any nuances that may also be present. When dealing with such an 'underground' subject matter (excuse the pun!), then technical proficiency almost becomes irrelevant. If some of the film's images weren't so loudly sensationalistic, one is left thinking with chagrin that the honest speaking voice could more easily be heard... It's almost unfortunate that there is so much nudity, and that it's such an unusual topic, because the sympathetic quality underlying the script may well be overlooked by a lot of people. If you are the type who is able to put themselves in someone else's position without always agreeing with how they go about things; then the main character's struggle with her feelings may very well move you. I feel that certain shots contained within could well be construed as unnecessarily pandering to controversy, though. If this gets more people to give it a chance, then I guess it might well turn out to be a good thing. For the film-makers it must have been a case of being caught between the devil and the deep blue sea, and each individual person will resolve the decided final approach in their own way... The journey the audience take is an unsettling walk with a person longing to find a state where people don't judge, and it affected me far deeper emotionally when it was more reticent about what it revealed, not vice-versa. By holding back on what was shown and exercising just a little more subtlety, it's my opinion that a far stronger position would then be gained to concentrate entirely on this poor young woman and her inner torment. In fact, the more I think about it, not permitting her to give in to the temptation of the act would also lend more resonance to the moment when we finally learn how the people who love her deal with this issue, too. I think too much 'exposure' too soon unfortunately undermines a great deal of its potential impact at the cost of gaining the work a wider notoriety. Despite this hindrance that in my mind prevents it from being of even greater value, "Kissed" is a film which I would say still remains worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Song in Dance Scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fecalite
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie! It definitely encouraged my friend to pursue a career in death care. The soundtrack is awesome too, but one of my favorite songs from the movie is missing from it. Near the beginning of the movie when the young Sandra is playing with her only friend, Carol, Sandra discovers that her can has found a family of dead mice. Sandra tells Carol they will have a special ceremony to commemorate the mice and they find a place in the wood to bury them. After interment, Sandra plays a rather 70s style song on her tape recorder and she and Carol dance to it. Does anyone know what the title of the song is and who wrote it? It's not on the soundtrack. Thanks!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
