<filme>
 <id>
  122
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0115798
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Pentelho
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A lonely and disturbed cable guy raised on television just wants a new friend, but his target, a designer, rejects him, with bad consequences.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Steven Kovak has been kicked out of his apartment by his girlfriend. Steven has a new apartment, and decides to slip the cable guy (Chip) $50 for free cable. Steven then fakes an interest in Chip's line of work. However Chip takes this to heart trying to become Steven's best bud. When Steven no longer wants to be Chips friend the man who can do it all goes on an all out assault to ruin Steven's life. In the backdrop is the delicate sub-plot of the trial of a former kid star for murdering his brother.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   friend
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   cable guy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   television
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   homoerotic
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   stalking
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Ben Stiller
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Lou Holtz Jr.
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jim Carrey
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Matthew Broderick
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Leslie Mann
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey ruins yet another movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scohcon
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's two reasons I watched this movie, or rather suffered through it. One was was because I'm a fan of Matthew Broderick. And two is because it was on TV and I didn't have to pay to see it. And even though I've always been repulsed by anything Jim Carrey has done, I thought maybe I'd be able to bear it. This movie made me realize that Jim Carrey is so pathetically untalented and annoying that he could ruin any movie. And like all of his other movies, he manages to ruin this one as well. He's like a retarded version of Jerry Lewis. Don't get me wrong, I'm a huge fan of Lewis, who was an original, but a bad fake imitation of Lewis with brain damage with a lame accent that can't act... not so much. Truth is, if one could assemble the greatest director, the best actors, the best screen writers, and the best special effects technicians that ever lived to make a movie with an unlimited budget, if you were to add Jim Carrey in the mix, he would spoil it all and insure the film would be capable of inducing vomiting. After all, that's his only "talent".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misunderstood. Carrey's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bradleyluke79
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd like to start off by saying that The Cable Guy is disliked by a lot of people. This would explain it's low rating. But don't be thrown off by that. The Cable Guy is a black comedy. So, some people will be unsettled by the plot of the movie. "Chip" is a disturbed Cable Guy, raised on television, who only wants a friend. Steve is a designer, recently kicked out of his girlfriend's apartment. Moving into his new apartment, his friend Rick tells him to bribe the cable guy, to get illegal cable. But the cable guy, "Chip" sees this is an invitation to be best buds. Steve, trying to be nice fakes an interest in his work, but this just brings "Chip" closer and closer to him. This movie is a misunderstood classic. And in my opinion it's Jim Carrey's best movie. It's a nice change for Carrey's character, having him play the psychotic two faced Cable Guy. With Steve(Matthew Brodrick) in the most awkward of situations by the hilarious Cable Guy(Jim Carrey) this movie should bring you laughs and enjoyment. It does get progressively dark as the film goes on but it's nothing major. The film also has many, many film and T.V. references that you'll enjoy along the way. In my opinion, The Cable Guy is the motion picture version of mar-mite. You will ever love it or hate it. And I love it. A must watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Necessary protest vote
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wouldn't normally have left a review for this but stumbled on the shockingly low mark and was compelled to write something! What a sick joke this movie has such a low rating on IMDb. I have a sneaking suspicion it's down to the pathological Jim Carrey haters rather than based on the movie's merits. I'm giving it a star more than I would have otherwise as a protest vote. I guess if a particular person in a movie annoys you that much then it's going to preclude it from being a good movie for you, *but surely* you can take a step back, and say something like "ah now wait a minute, that's just my personal dislike for an individual and it wouldn't really be fair to transfer that dislike onto any collective effort they happened to be a part of". What about the poor writer, director, other actors and the crew? I know I've made a big assumption there and it's possible people just didn't find it funny. I find that so hard to believe though - I've seen *a hell of a lot* of comedies over the last 40 years, and find the vast majority made from 1990 onwards to be safe, lazy and badly-written, or more recently trying to be zany or alternative and failing miserably. However I found this surprisingly well-written, well-made and brilliantly-acted(comedy acting, not Oliver/Gielgud!) and all-round compelling and bloody hilarious. I think it's a great idea - the central character's minor misdemeanour at the start results in immediate payback in the form of a demented psychopath taking over his life. It gets pretty dark in a couple of places which somehow makes the humour work better. Whatever you think of Jim Carrey, the range of stuff he pulls off on screen is incredible. Like a reanimated old Vaudevillian on PCP. I found him totally convincing as the lonely Walter Mitty/psycho who really just needs a friend and uses what he knows best to make it happen. Broderick is a born fall guy and effortlessly provides the anything-for-a-quiet-life victim, ill-equipped to halt the psycho's hostile takeover of his life. There's also a micro-element of social comment on using people, friendship, the abuse of power, and the influence TV can have on a person's life. Tutt and scoff all you want at that, but can you honestly say there's even that much depth in any other comedies made now? So for anybody who doesn't hate Jim Carrey, please don't listen to all the negative reviews and give this one a chance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It isn't Jim Carrey's best movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew- T-3055
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film which doesn't do justice to Jim Carrey as one of Hollywood's funniest actors. It is another one of his films with many voices and faces being pulled by his character, but this film is different and it just doesn't work. The film follows The Cable Guy who tries to become his latest clients new best friend. He is Steven M. Kovacs (played by Matthew Broderick). But Steven just wants his cable fixed and then to get on with his life. But they become "friends" despite Broderick being a bit awkward and unsure around him. Yet this awkward bond I feel is returned by Carrey's character who is just making annoying over the top jokes which just didn't work in this scenario. This is sad as if it was a mystery or a bit more dramatic like some of his other films then it could've had great potential. I just don't think it works. I feel the best part of the film comes from Jack Black's role as Rick who is Steven's friend, the role is relatively small yet I think it's portrayed well. If the film had extended his role a bit more, with a bit more depth I think that would've improved the film. I would say this is worst film I've seen Jim Carrey in. The premise of the film is good but the acting wasn't and I felt the storyline should have had a bit more depth in places, the film had a lot of potential though.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Must Watch If You Love Jim Carrey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nirbhay Pandey
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We want to like Jim Carrey. A movie that makes us dislike him is a strategic mistake. The opening scenes of "The Cable Guy" are promising; Carrey seems to be playing a variation on his usual hyperkinetic goofball. Then our reaction grows more puzzled: This is supposed to be fun, right? By the end, the movie has declared itself as a black comedy about one very deeply troubled cable guy. The plot centers around a character named Steven (Matthew Broderick), who has just been turned down for marriage by his girlfriend Robin (Leslie Mann). He moves into a bachelor pad and calls for cable service, and Chip Douglas (Carrey) comes pounding on his door (making sure, of course, to arrive very late and while Steven is in the shower). The cable guy is a manic nerd with a lisp and an under slung jaw. He wants to be Steven's friend. He has a lot of trouble pronouncing certain words. "My brother is a speech therapist," Steven says helpfully. The cable guy says, "Tho?" Soon the cable guy has insinuated himself into Steven's life and is offering detailed advice about life (which he reveals he has learned that morning from the summation at the end of a Jerry Springer program). His strategy for getting Robin to come back: Watch "Sleepless in Seattle" with her. Women are suckers for it. Many of these strategies works, and we're reminded of the relationship in the British comedy classic "School for Scoundrels" (which Carrey should remake) in which a cad teaches one-upmanship to a loser. But soon the movie drifts into murkier waters. The cable guy has an unhealthy need to be Steven's friend, and he pursues that goal with behavior designed to scare anyone. He's a stalker. He's obnoxious and peculiar and inappropriate and relentless, and we start disliking him, and that's when the movie jumps the rails. The director, Ben Stiller ("Reality Bites"), throws in a lot of gratuitous but funny asides; there's a running gag about a CourtTV trial involving Hollywood twins whose relationship ends in murder. And in-jokes, as when the cable guy covers his face with fried chicken skin to imitate a scene from "Silence of the Lambs" (the actor Charles Napier, whose face was borrowed by Hannibal Lecter in "Lambs," turns up here as a cop). And there's a fake TV commercial showing Eric Roberts plays a dual role in "Brother, Sweet Brother," the docudrama based on the Hollywood trial. Maybe it would have worked better if the cable guy had become a real friend to Steven, devising love strategies and Machiavellian schemes to win back Robin and thwart her other suitors. As it is, the movie goes in one direction and the cable guy goes in another, and by the end we aren't really looking forward to seeing Jim Carrey reappear on the screen. Note to the producers: There's an old showbiz saying that "satire is what closes on Saturday night." To which could be added another: "Black comedy is not what you pay someone $20 million to-do." ******* BUT STILL MUST WATCH IF YOU LOVE JIM CARREY *******
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible. Really terrible.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesguerin
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am very disappointed that I stayed for the duration of this film. It really is awful, in my opinion. I like stupid humour, when it's done properly like Monty Python or Aeroplane. This was just poor. Jim Carrey plays a psychotic yet supposedly lovable former cable guy. The purpose of his character seems to be more focused on saying random "jokes" than advancing the plot in any way. He starts the film as a stalker and does not develop. Matthew Broderick is also annoyingly bad in places, though not nearly to the same extent. This film failed to make me actually laugh once, although I did manage a smirk a few times. If you like smart dumb comedies, this isn't for you. If you like laughing at anything said in a funny voice, prepare to be entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great fun!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lucas_carvalhaes
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you like Jim Carrey and strong emotions this is definitely for you! I rated 10 because few movies made me laugh so hard, be afraid, be really scared, be lost, feel strange stuff, see awesome scenes in such a short period of time. I don't even know how to describe the feelings this movie gets you... Just watch with friends willing to have fun and you have a great time! Jim Carrey acts so Carrey in this movie even the other actors couldn't resist... so many awesome faces, so much bizarre and yet a great dramatic story. The plot isn't the best and Ben stiller does absolutely nothing during the movie. He just appears as a lesser supporting actor. No, seriously, focus on Carrey's acting and you will have a real roller coaster ride of craziness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misunderstood half-thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cedde6
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Kovacks (Matthew Broderick), a designer who just separated from his girlfriend, has cable installed to his new apartment. Enters the quirky and slightly deranged cable guy (Jim Carey) whom then never exits... A rather simple plot which became in 1996 a very odd and yet pleasurable film indeed. Although following a pretty straight forward structure, the script provides enough background to Jim Carey's character to make of him a lot more than just a run-of-the-mill weirdo while Matthew Broderick aptly counterbalance the excessive title role by a fair performance of the without-a-glitch nice guy of the piece. The constant referencing to TV culture also makes it an entertaining and strangely enough somewhat nostalgic experience. It is quite obvious that a fair amount of improvisation was incorporated to the piece to sometimes great effect (the "Silence of the Lamb" episode anyone?) which I suppose is probably the most effective way to work with someone such as Jim Carey. Curiously however, the main asset of the film also becomes at some point its main shortcoming. This was to Jim Carey what 1994's "The Good Son" was to Macauley Culkin: a departure from their comedic roots to more darker territories, but as opposed to Joseph Ruben's thriller, "The Cable Guy" seems to always hesitate to boldly go as far as its story would allow it to. In Jim Carey's work this is certainly darker than anything he had done up to that point but if this was also supposed to be a thriller then it felt a little bland, the star's antics sometimes overshadowing the actual depth of the story. Still, don't let this put you off for "The Cable Guy", playfully directed by Ben Stiller, is one of these misunderstood films that are really worth watching for its clever take on the media in general and the hidden harm you find it does to people's mind once stripped off the apparent sense of comfort it is supposed to bring. It might have been done a little too light-heartedly maybe but at least it was done at all. And decently done too. This is a more serious film than it looks at first glance and that alone makes it an interesting one. No masterpiece mind you, but then again, it never pretended to be one. Like many films of that ilk, it was generally trashed upon by critics back then, in this case for its lack of downright slapstick-laugh-out-loud moments (Carey's salary the true reason for the furore) although they also criticized "Ace Ventura: when natures call" for being completely empty, the previous year. Oh well, sometimes one can never win...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    it is a matter of comedic taste
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobrobertsst
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In order to rate this movie you must have a good sense of what comedy consists. Most people have a sense of humor that involves the lameness of Napoleon Dynamite and it's completely humorless involvement with society. Ergo if you are a Napoleon Dynamite fan please do not rate any comedy other than your favorite. If I were a sociopath then I should not rate anything involving emotions. You should not rate or judge anything you do not understand. Therefore if you are a Napoleon Dynamite fan it is very obvious you do not have a comedic sense of art. If you do enjoy Woody Allen and Napoleon Dynamite then perhaps you have a split personality. (I am a Woody Allen fan ;-) There is only 1 comedy that has won the Best Picture award (yes it was Woody Allen). This fact illuminates the fact that people do not understand comedy, the reason for this being that comedy does not have a universal appeal. Humor is much more unique and personal than drama.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey is top of his class.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guitarmasta-242-110720
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always been a Carrey fan, so when I stumbled upon this while DVD hunting at a local video store, naturally I bought it. I was not disappointed. Jim Carrey was made for the role of Chip Douglas. His acting in this movie is all but un-paralleled. He really shows us what he is capable of in the acting department. If Jim Carrey can be said to be one of those actors where you either love him or hate him, then the same can be said for this movie. It has a very particular type of often quite dark humor in it, which doesn't appeal to a lot of people, but in which Carrey thrives. If you didn't like this movie, give it another watch. You might change your mind. This movie is a must for any Carrey fan, or any fan of good 90's comedy. Ben Stiller does a fantastic job directing, and the rest of the cast supports Carrey's role brilliantly. 10/10 (Also, I heard that the Chip Douglas role wasn't originally intended for Carrey, but after watching it, can you honestly picture anyone else executing it so damn well??)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey ruins yet another movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scohcon
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's two reasons I watched this movie, or rather suffered through it. One was was because I'm a fan of Matthew Broderick. And two is because it was on TV and I didn't have to pay to see it. And even though I've always been repulsed by anything Jim Carrey has done, I thought maybe I'd be able to bear it. This movie made me realize that Jim Carrey is so pathetically untalented and annoying that he could ruin any movie. And like all of his other movies, he manages to ruin this one as well. He's like a retarded version of Jerry Lewis. Don't get me wrong, I'm a huge fan of Lewis, who was an original, but a bad fake imitation of Lewis with brain damage with a lame accent that can't act... not so much. Truth is, if one could assemble the greatest director, the best actors, the best screen writers, and the best special effects technicians that ever lived to make a movie with an unlimited budget, if you were to add Jim Carrey in the mix, he would spoil it all and insure the film would be capable of inducing vomiting. After all, that's his only "talent".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misunderstood. Carrey's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bradleyluke79
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd like to start off by saying that The Cable Guy is disliked by a lot of people. This would explain it's low rating. But don't be thrown off by that. The Cable Guy is a black comedy. So, some people will be unsettled by the plot of the movie. "Chip" is a disturbed Cable Guy, raised on television, who only wants a friend. Steve is a designer, recently kicked out of his girlfriend's apartment. Moving into his new apartment, his friend Rick tells him to bribe the cable guy, to get illegal cable. But the cable guy, "Chip" sees this is an invitation to be best buds. Steve, trying to be nice fakes an interest in his work, but this just brings "Chip" closer and closer to him. This movie is a misunderstood classic. And in my opinion it's Jim Carrey's best movie. It's a nice change for Carrey's character, having him play the psychotic two faced Cable Guy. With Steve(Matthew Brodrick) in the most awkward of situations by the hilarious Cable Guy(Jim Carrey) this movie should bring you laughs and enjoyment. It does get progressively dark as the film goes on but it's nothing major. The film also has many, many film and T.V. references that you'll enjoy along the way. In my opinion, The Cable Guy is the motion picture version of mar-mite. You will ever love it or hate it. And I love it. A must watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Necessary protest vote
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wouldn't normally have left a review for this but stumbled on the shockingly low mark and was compelled to write something! What a sick joke this movie has such a low rating on IMDb. I have a sneaking suspicion it's down to the pathological Jim Carrey haters rather than based on the movie's merits. I'm giving it a star more than I would have otherwise as a protest vote. I guess if a particular person in a movie annoys you that much then it's going to preclude it from being a good movie for you, *but surely* you can take a step back, and say something like "ah now wait a minute, that's just my personal dislike for an individual and it wouldn't really be fair to transfer that dislike onto any collective effort they happened to be a part of". What about the poor writer, director, other actors and the crew? I know I've made a big assumption there and it's possible people just didn't find it funny. I find that so hard to believe though - I've seen *a hell of a lot* of comedies over the last 40 years, and find the vast majority made from 1990 onwards to be safe, lazy and badly-written, or more recently trying to be zany or alternative and failing miserably. However I found this surprisingly well-written, well-made and brilliantly-acted(comedy acting, not Oliver/Gielgud!) and all-round compelling and bloody hilarious. I think it's a great idea - the central character's minor misdemeanour at the start results in immediate payback in the form of a demented psychopath taking over his life. It gets pretty dark in a couple of places which somehow makes the humour work better. Whatever you think of Jim Carrey, the range of stuff he pulls off on screen is incredible. Like a reanimated old Vaudevillian on PCP. I found him totally convincing as the lonely Walter Mitty/psycho who really just needs a friend and uses what he knows best to make it happen. Broderick is a born fall guy and effortlessly provides the anything-for-a-quiet-life victim, ill-equipped to halt the psycho's hostile takeover of his life. There's also a micro-element of social comment on using people, friendship, the abuse of power, and the influence TV can have on a person's life. Tutt and scoff all you want at that, but can you honestly say there's even that much depth in any other comedies made now? So for anybody who doesn't hate Jim Carrey, please don't listen to all the negative reviews and give this one a chance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It isn't Jim Carrey's best movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew- T-3055
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film which doesn't do justice to Jim Carrey as one of Hollywood's funniest actors. It is another one of his films with many voices and faces being pulled by his character, but this film is different and it just doesn't work. The film follows The Cable Guy who tries to become his latest clients new best friend. He is Steven M. Kovacs (played by Matthew Broderick). But Steven just wants his cable fixed and then to get on with his life. But they become "friends" despite Broderick being a bit awkward and unsure around him. Yet this awkward bond I feel is returned by Carrey's character who is just making annoying over the top jokes which just didn't work in this scenario. This is sad as if it was a mystery or a bit more dramatic like some of his other films then it could've had great potential. I just don't think it works. I feel the best part of the film comes from Jack Black's role as Rick who is Steven's friend, the role is relatively small yet I think it's portrayed well. If the film had extended his role a bit more, with a bit more depth I think that would've improved the film. I would say this is worst film I've seen Jim Carrey in. The premise of the film is good but the acting wasn't and I felt the storyline should have had a bit more depth in places, the film had a lot of potential though.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Must Watch If You Love Jim Carrey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nirbhay Pandey
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We want to like Jim Carrey. A movie that makes us dislike him is a strategic mistake. The opening scenes of "The Cable Guy" are promising; Carrey seems to be playing a variation on his usual hyperkinetic goofball. Then our reaction grows more puzzled: This is supposed to be fun, right? By the end, the movie has declared itself as a black comedy about one very deeply troubled cable guy. The plot centers around a character named Steven (Matthew Broderick), who has just been turned down for marriage by his girlfriend Robin (Leslie Mann). He moves into a bachelor pad and calls for cable service, and Chip Douglas (Carrey) comes pounding on his door (making sure, of course, to arrive very late and while Steven is in the shower). The cable guy is a manic nerd with a lisp and an under slung jaw. He wants to be Steven's friend. He has a lot of trouble pronouncing certain words. "My brother is a speech therapist," Steven says helpfully. The cable guy says, "Tho?" Soon the cable guy has insinuated himself into Steven's life and is offering detailed advice about life (which he reveals he has learned that morning from the summation at the end of a Jerry Springer program). His strategy for getting Robin to come back: Watch "Sleepless in Seattle" with her. Women are suckers for it. Many of these strategies works, and we're reminded of the relationship in the British comedy classic "School for Scoundrels" (which Carrey should remake) in which a cad teaches one-upmanship to a loser. But soon the movie drifts into murkier waters. The cable guy has an unhealthy need to be Steven's friend, and he pursues that goal with behavior designed to scare anyone. He's a stalker. He's obnoxious and peculiar and inappropriate and relentless, and we start disliking him, and that's when the movie jumps the rails. The director, Ben Stiller ("Reality Bites"), throws in a lot of gratuitous but funny asides; there's a running gag about a CourtTV trial involving Hollywood twins whose relationship ends in murder. And in-jokes, as when the cable guy covers his face with fried chicken skin to imitate a scene from "Silence of the Lambs" (the actor Charles Napier, whose face was borrowed by Hannibal Lecter in "Lambs," turns up here as a cop). And there's a fake TV commercial showing Eric Roberts plays a dual role in "Brother, Sweet Brother," the docudrama based on the Hollywood trial. Maybe it would have worked better if the cable guy had become a real friend to Steven, devising love strategies and Machiavellian schemes to win back Robin and thwart her other suitors. As it is, the movie goes in one direction and the cable guy goes in another, and by the end we aren't really looking forward to seeing Jim Carrey reappear on the screen. Note to the producers: There's an old showbiz saying that "satire is what closes on Saturday night." To which could be added another: "Black comedy is not what you pay someone $20 million to-do." ******* BUT STILL MUST WATCH IF YOU LOVE JIM CARREY *******
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible. Really terrible.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesguerin
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am very disappointed that I stayed for the duration of this film. It really is awful, in my opinion. I like stupid humour, when it's done properly like Monty Python or Aeroplane. This was just poor. Jim Carrey plays a psychotic yet supposedly lovable former cable guy. The purpose of his character seems to be more focused on saying random "jokes" than advancing the plot in any way. He starts the film as a stalker and does not develop. Matthew Broderick is also annoyingly bad in places, though not nearly to the same extent. This film failed to make me actually laugh once, although I did manage a smirk a few times. If you like smart dumb comedies, this isn't for you. If you like laughing at anything said in a funny voice, prepare to be entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great fun!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lucas_carvalhaes
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you like Jim Carrey and strong emotions this is definitely for you! I rated 10 because few movies made me laugh so hard, be afraid, be really scared, be lost, feel strange stuff, see awesome scenes in such a short period of time. I don't even know how to describe the feelings this movie gets you... Just watch with friends willing to have fun and you have a great time! Jim Carrey acts so Carrey in this movie even the other actors couldn't resist... so many awesome faces, so much bizarre and yet a great dramatic story. The plot isn't the best and Ben stiller does absolutely nothing during the movie. He just appears as a lesser supporting actor. No, seriously, focus on Carrey's acting and you will have a real roller coaster ride of craziness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misunderstood half-thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cedde6
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Kovacks (Matthew Broderick), a designer who just separated from his girlfriend, has cable installed to his new apartment. Enters the quirky and slightly deranged cable guy (Jim Carey) whom then never exits... A rather simple plot which became in 1996 a very odd and yet pleasurable film indeed. Although following a pretty straight forward structure, the script provides enough background to Jim Carey's character to make of him a lot more than just a run-of-the-mill weirdo while Matthew Broderick aptly counterbalance the excessive title role by a fair performance of the without-a-glitch nice guy of the piece. The constant referencing to TV culture also makes it an entertaining and strangely enough somewhat nostalgic experience. It is quite obvious that a fair amount of improvisation was incorporated to the piece to sometimes great effect (the "Silence of the Lamb" episode anyone?) which I suppose is probably the most effective way to work with someone such as Jim Carey. Curiously however, the main asset of the film also becomes at some point its main shortcoming. This was to Jim Carey what 1994's "The Good Son" was to Macauley Culkin: a departure from their comedic roots to more darker territories, but as opposed to Joseph Ruben's thriller, "The Cable Guy" seems to always hesitate to boldly go as far as its story would allow it to. In Jim Carey's work this is certainly darker than anything he had done up to that point but if this was also supposed to be a thriller then it felt a little bland, the star's antics sometimes overshadowing the actual depth of the story. Still, don't let this put you off for "The Cable Guy", playfully directed by Ben Stiller, is one of these misunderstood films that are really worth watching for its clever take on the media in general and the hidden harm you find it does to people's mind once stripped off the apparent sense of comfort it is supposed to bring. It might have been done a little too light-heartedly maybe but at least it was done at all. And decently done too. This is a more serious film than it looks at first glance and that alone makes it an interesting one. No masterpiece mind you, but then again, it never pretended to be one. Like many films of that ilk, it was generally trashed upon by critics back then, in this case for its lack of downright slapstick-laugh-out-loud moments (Carey's salary the true reason for the furore) although they also criticized "Ace Ventura: when natures call" for being completely empty, the previous year. Oh well, sometimes one can never win...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    it is a matter of comedic taste
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobrobertsst
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In order to rate this movie you must have a good sense of what comedy consists. Most people have a sense of humor that involves the lameness of Napoleon Dynamite and it's completely humorless involvement with society. Ergo if you are a Napoleon Dynamite fan please do not rate any comedy other than your favorite. If I were a sociopath then I should not rate anything involving emotions. You should not rate or judge anything you do not understand. Therefore if you are a Napoleon Dynamite fan it is very obvious you do not have a comedic sense of art. If you do enjoy Woody Allen and Napoleon Dynamite then perhaps you have a split personality. (I am a Woody Allen fan ;-) There is only 1 comedy that has won the Best Picture award (yes it was Woody Allen). This fact illuminates the fact that people do not understand comedy, the reason for this being that comedy does not have a universal appeal. Humor is much more unique and personal than drama.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey is top of his class.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guitarmasta-242-110720
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always been a Carrey fan, so when I stumbled upon this while DVD hunting at a local video store, naturally I bought it. I was not disappointed. Jim Carrey was made for the role of Chip Douglas. His acting in this movie is all but un-paralleled. He really shows us what he is capable of in the acting department. If Jim Carrey can be said to be one of those actors where you either love him or hate him, then the same can be said for this movie. It has a very particular type of often quite dark humor in it, which doesn't appeal to a lot of people, but in which Carrey thrives. If you didn't like this movie, give it another watch. You might change your mind. This movie is a must for any Carrey fan, or any fan of good 90's comedy. Ben Stiller does a fantastic job directing, and the rest of the cast supports Carrey's role brilliantly. 10/10 (Also, I heard that the Chip Douglas role wasn't originally intended for Carrey, but after watching it, can you honestly picture anyone else executing it so damn well??)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey ruins yet another movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scohcon
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's two reasons I watched this movie, or rather suffered through it. One was was because I'm a fan of Matthew Broderick. And two is because it was on TV and I didn't have to pay to see it. And even though I've always been repulsed by anything Jim Carrey has done, I thought maybe I'd be able to bear it. This movie made me realize that Jim Carrey is so pathetically untalented and annoying that he could ruin any movie. And like all of his other movies, he manages to ruin this one as well. He's like a retarded version of Jerry Lewis. Don't get me wrong, I'm a huge fan of Lewis, who was an original, but a bad fake imitation of Lewis with brain damage with a lame accent that can't act... not so much. Truth is, if one could assemble the greatest director, the best actors, the best screen writers, and the best special effects technicians that ever lived to make a movie with an unlimited budget, if you were to add Jim Carrey in the mix, he would spoil it all and insure the film would be capable of inducing vomiting. After all, that's his only "talent".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misunderstood. Carrey's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bradleyluke79
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd like to start off by saying that The Cable Guy is disliked by a lot of people. This would explain it's low rating. But don't be thrown off by that. The Cable Guy is a black comedy. So, some people will be unsettled by the plot of the movie. "Chip" is a disturbed Cable Guy, raised on television, who only wants a friend. Steve is a designer, recently kicked out of his girlfriend's apartment. Moving into his new apartment, his friend Rick tells him to bribe the cable guy, to get illegal cable. But the cable guy, "Chip" sees this is an invitation to be best buds. Steve, trying to be nice fakes an interest in his work, but this just brings "Chip" closer and closer to him. This movie is a misunderstood classic. And in my opinion it's Jim Carrey's best movie. It's a nice change for Carrey's character, having him play the psychotic two faced Cable Guy. With Steve(Matthew Brodrick) in the most awkward of situations by the hilarious Cable Guy(Jim Carrey) this movie should bring you laughs and enjoyment. It does get progressively dark as the film goes on but it's nothing major. The film also has many, many film and T.V. references that you'll enjoy along the way. In my opinion, The Cable Guy is the motion picture version of mar-mite. You will ever love it or hate it. And I love it. A must watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Necessary protest vote
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wouldn't normally have left a review for this but stumbled on the shockingly low mark and was compelled to write something! What a sick joke this movie has such a low rating on IMDb. I have a sneaking suspicion it's down to the pathological Jim Carrey haters rather than based on the movie's merits. I'm giving it a star more than I would have otherwise as a protest vote. I guess if a particular person in a movie annoys you that much then it's going to preclude it from being a good movie for you, *but surely* you can take a step back, and say something like "ah now wait a minute, that's just my personal dislike for an individual and it wouldn't really be fair to transfer that dislike onto any collective effort they happened to be a part of". What about the poor writer, director, other actors and the crew? I know I've made a big assumption there and it's possible people just didn't find it funny. I find that so hard to believe though - I've seen *a hell of a lot* of comedies over the last 40 years, and find the vast majority made from 1990 onwards to be safe, lazy and badly-written, or more recently trying to be zany or alternative and failing miserably. However I found this surprisingly well-written, well-made and brilliantly-acted(comedy acting, not Oliver/Gielgud!) and all-round compelling and bloody hilarious. I think it's a great idea - the central character's minor misdemeanour at the start results in immediate payback in the form of a demented psychopath taking over his life. It gets pretty dark in a couple of places which somehow makes the humour work better. Whatever you think of Jim Carrey, the range of stuff he pulls off on screen is incredible. Like a reanimated old Vaudevillian on PCP. I found him totally convincing as the lonely Walter Mitty/psycho who really just needs a friend and uses what he knows best to make it happen. Broderick is a born fall guy and effortlessly provides the anything-for-a-quiet-life victim, ill-equipped to halt the psycho's hostile takeover of his life. There's also a micro-element of social comment on using people, friendship, the abuse of power, and the influence TV can have on a person's life. Tutt and scoff all you want at that, but can you honestly say there's even that much depth in any other comedies made now? So for anybody who doesn't hate Jim Carrey, please don't listen to all the negative reviews and give this one a chance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It isn't Jim Carrey's best movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew- T-3055
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film which doesn't do justice to Jim Carrey as one of Hollywood's funniest actors. It is another one of his films with many voices and faces being pulled by his character, but this film is different and it just doesn't work. The film follows The Cable Guy who tries to become his latest clients new best friend. He is Steven M. Kovacs (played by Matthew Broderick). But Steven just wants his cable fixed and then to get on with his life. But they become "friends" despite Broderick being a bit awkward and unsure around him. Yet this awkward bond I feel is returned by Carrey's character who is just making annoying over the top jokes which just didn't work in this scenario. This is sad as if it was a mystery or a bit more dramatic like some of his other films then it could've had great potential. I just don't think it works. I feel the best part of the film comes from Jack Black's role as Rick who is Steven's friend, the role is relatively small yet I think it's portrayed well. If the film had extended his role a bit more, with a bit more depth I think that would've improved the film. I would say this is worst film I've seen Jim Carrey in. The premise of the film is good but the acting wasn't and I felt the storyline should have had a bit more depth in places, the film had a lot of potential though.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Must Watch If You Love Jim Carrey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nirbhay Pandey
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We want to like Jim Carrey. A movie that makes us dislike him is a strategic mistake. The opening scenes of "The Cable Guy" are promising; Carrey seems to be playing a variation on his usual hyperkinetic goofball. Then our reaction grows more puzzled: This is supposed to be fun, right? By the end, the movie has declared itself as a black comedy about one very deeply troubled cable guy. The plot centers around a character named Steven (Matthew Broderick), who has just been turned down for marriage by his girlfriend Robin (Leslie Mann). He moves into a bachelor pad and calls for cable service, and Chip Douglas (Carrey) comes pounding on his door (making sure, of course, to arrive very late and while Steven is in the shower). The cable guy is a manic nerd with a lisp and an under slung jaw. He wants to be Steven's friend. He has a lot of trouble pronouncing certain words. "My brother is a speech therapist," Steven says helpfully. The cable guy says, "Tho?" Soon the cable guy has insinuated himself into Steven's life and is offering detailed advice about life (which he reveals he has learned that morning from the summation at the end of a Jerry Springer program). His strategy for getting Robin to come back: Watch "Sleepless in Seattle" with her. Women are suckers for it. Many of these strategies works, and we're reminded of the relationship in the British comedy classic "School for Scoundrels" (which Carrey should remake) in which a cad teaches one-upmanship to a loser. But soon the movie drifts into murkier waters. The cable guy has an unhealthy need to be Steven's friend, and he pursues that goal with behavior designed to scare anyone. He's a stalker. He's obnoxious and peculiar and inappropriate and relentless, and we start disliking him, and that's when the movie jumps the rails. The director, Ben Stiller ("Reality Bites"), throws in a lot of gratuitous but funny asides; there's a running gag about a CourtTV trial involving Hollywood twins whose relationship ends in murder. And in-jokes, as when the cable guy covers his face with fried chicken skin to imitate a scene from "Silence of the Lambs" (the actor Charles Napier, whose face was borrowed by Hannibal Lecter in "Lambs," turns up here as a cop). And there's a fake TV commercial showing Eric Roberts plays a dual role in "Brother, Sweet Brother," the docudrama based on the Hollywood trial. Maybe it would have worked better if the cable guy had become a real friend to Steven, devising love strategies and Machiavellian schemes to win back Robin and thwart her other suitors. As it is, the movie goes in one direction and the cable guy goes in another, and by the end we aren't really looking forward to seeing Jim Carrey reappear on the screen. Note to the producers: There's an old showbiz saying that "satire is what closes on Saturday night." To which could be added another: "Black comedy is not what you pay someone $20 million to-do." ******* BUT STILL MUST WATCH IF YOU LOVE JIM CARREY *******
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible. Really terrible.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesguerin
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am very disappointed that I stayed for the duration of this film. It really is awful, in my opinion. I like stupid humour, when it's done properly like Monty Python or Aeroplane. This was just poor. Jim Carrey plays a psychotic yet supposedly lovable former cable guy. The purpose of his character seems to be more focused on saying random "jokes" than advancing the plot in any way. He starts the film as a stalker and does not develop. Matthew Broderick is also annoyingly bad in places, though not nearly to the same extent. This film failed to make me actually laugh once, although I did manage a smirk a few times. If you like smart dumb comedies, this isn't for you. If you like laughing at anything said in a funny voice, prepare to be entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great fun!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lucas_carvalhaes
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you like Jim Carrey and strong emotions this is definitely for you! I rated 10 because few movies made me laugh so hard, be afraid, be really scared, be lost, feel strange stuff, see awesome scenes in such a short period of time. I don't even know how to describe the feelings this movie gets you... Just watch with friends willing to have fun and you have a great time! Jim Carrey acts so Carrey in this movie even the other actors couldn't resist... so many awesome faces, so much bizarre and yet a great dramatic story. The plot isn't the best and Ben stiller does absolutely nothing during the movie. He just appears as a lesser supporting actor. No, seriously, focus on Carrey's acting and you will have a real roller coaster ride of craziness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misunderstood half-thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cedde6
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Kovacks (Matthew Broderick), a designer who just separated from his girlfriend, has cable installed to his new apartment. Enters the quirky and slightly deranged cable guy (Jim Carey) whom then never exits... A rather simple plot which became in 1996 a very odd and yet pleasurable film indeed. Although following a pretty straight forward structure, the script provides enough background to Jim Carey's character to make of him a lot more than just a run-of-the-mill weirdo while Matthew Broderick aptly counterbalance the excessive title role by a fair performance of the without-a-glitch nice guy of the piece. The constant referencing to TV culture also makes it an entertaining and strangely enough somewhat nostalgic experience. It is quite obvious that a fair amount of improvisation was incorporated to the piece to sometimes great effect (the "Silence of the Lamb" episode anyone?) which I suppose is probably the most effective way to work with someone such as Jim Carey. Curiously however, the main asset of the film also becomes at some point its main shortcoming. This was to Jim Carey what 1994's "The Good Son" was to Macauley Culkin: a departure from their comedic roots to more darker territories, but as opposed to Joseph Ruben's thriller, "The Cable Guy" seems to always hesitate to boldly go as far as its story would allow it to. In Jim Carey's work this is certainly darker than anything he had done up to that point but if this was also supposed to be a thriller then it felt a little bland, the star's antics sometimes overshadowing the actual depth of the story. Still, don't let this put you off for "The Cable Guy", playfully directed by Ben Stiller, is one of these misunderstood films that are really worth watching for its clever take on the media in general and the hidden harm you find it does to people's mind once stripped off the apparent sense of comfort it is supposed to bring. It might have been done a little too light-heartedly maybe but at least it was done at all. And decently done too. This is a more serious film than it looks at first glance and that alone makes it an interesting one. No masterpiece mind you, but then again, it never pretended to be one. Like many films of that ilk, it was generally trashed upon by critics back then, in this case for its lack of downright slapstick-laugh-out-loud moments (Carey's salary the true reason for the furore) although they also criticized "Ace Ventura: when natures call" for being completely empty, the previous year. Oh well, sometimes one can never win...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    it is a matter of comedic taste
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobrobertsst
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In order to rate this movie you must have a good sense of what comedy consists. Most people have a sense of humor that involves the lameness of Napoleon Dynamite and it's completely humorless involvement with society. Ergo if you are a Napoleon Dynamite fan please do not rate any comedy other than your favorite. If I were a sociopath then I should not rate anything involving emotions. You should not rate or judge anything you do not understand. Therefore if you are a Napoleon Dynamite fan it is very obvious you do not have a comedic sense of art. If you do enjoy Woody Allen and Napoleon Dynamite then perhaps you have a split personality. (I am a Woody Allen fan ;-) There is only 1 comedy that has won the Best Picture award (yes it was Woody Allen). This fact illuminates the fact that people do not understand comedy, the reason for this being that comedy does not have a universal appeal. Humor is much more unique and personal than drama.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey is top of his class.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guitarmasta-242-110720
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always been a Carrey fan, so when I stumbled upon this while DVD hunting at a local video store, naturally I bought it. I was not disappointed. Jim Carrey was made for the role of Chip Douglas. His acting in this movie is all but un-paralleled. He really shows us what he is capable of in the acting department. If Jim Carrey can be said to be one of those actors where you either love him or hate him, then the same can be said for this movie. It has a very particular type of often quite dark humor in it, which doesn't appeal to a lot of people, but in which Carrey thrives. If you didn't like this movie, give it another watch. You might change your mind. This movie is a must for any Carrey fan, or any fan of good 90's comedy. Ben Stiller does a fantastic job directing, and the rest of the cast supports Carrey's role brilliantly. 10/10 (Also, I heard that the Chip Douglas role wasn't originally intended for Carrey, but after watching it, can you honestly picture anyone else executing it so damn well??)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey ruins yet another movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scohcon
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's two reasons I watched this movie, or rather suffered through it. One was was because I'm a fan of Matthew Broderick. And two is because it was on TV and I didn't have to pay to see it. And even though I've always been repulsed by anything Jim Carrey has done, I thought maybe I'd be able to bear it. This movie made me realize that Jim Carrey is so pathetically untalented and annoying that he could ruin any movie. And like all of his other movies, he manages to ruin this one as well. He's like a retarded version of Jerry Lewis. Don't get me wrong, I'm a huge fan of Lewis, who was an original, but a bad fake imitation of Lewis with brain damage with a lame accent that can't act... not so much. Truth is, if one could assemble the greatest director, the best actors, the best screen writers, and the best special effects technicians that ever lived to make a movie with an unlimited budget, if you were to add Jim Carrey in the mix, he would spoil it all and insure the film would be capable of inducing vomiting. After all, that's his only "talent".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misunderstood. Carrey's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bradleyluke79
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd like to start off by saying that The Cable Guy is disliked by a lot of people. This would explain it's low rating. But don't be thrown off by that. The Cable Guy is a black comedy. So, some people will be unsettled by the plot of the movie. "Chip" is a disturbed Cable Guy, raised on television, who only wants a friend. Steve is a designer, recently kicked out of his girlfriend's apartment. Moving into his new apartment, his friend Rick tells him to bribe the cable guy, to get illegal cable. But the cable guy, "Chip" sees this is an invitation to be best buds. Steve, trying to be nice fakes an interest in his work, but this just brings "Chip" closer and closer to him. This movie is a misunderstood classic. And in my opinion it's Jim Carrey's best movie. It's a nice change for Carrey's character, having him play the psychotic two faced Cable Guy. With Steve(Matthew Brodrick) in the most awkward of situations by the hilarious Cable Guy(Jim Carrey) this movie should bring you laughs and enjoyment. It does get progressively dark as the film goes on but it's nothing major. The film also has many, many film and T.V. references that you'll enjoy along the way. In my opinion, The Cable Guy is the motion picture version of mar-mite. You will ever love it or hate it. And I love it. A must watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Necessary protest vote
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wouldn't normally have left a review for this but stumbled on the shockingly low mark and was compelled to write something! What a sick joke this movie has such a low rating on IMDb. I have a sneaking suspicion it's down to the pathological Jim Carrey haters rather than based on the movie's merits. I'm giving it a star more than I would have otherwise as a protest vote. I guess if a particular person in a movie annoys you that much then it's going to preclude it from being a good movie for you, *but surely* you can take a step back, and say something like "ah now wait a minute, that's just my personal dislike for an individual and it wouldn't really be fair to transfer that dislike onto any collective effort they happened to be a part of". What about the poor writer, director, other actors and the crew? I know I've made a big assumption there and it's possible people just didn't find it funny. I find that so hard to believe though - I've seen *a hell of a lot* of comedies over the last 40 years, and find the vast majority made from 1990 onwards to be safe, lazy and badly-written, or more recently trying to be zany or alternative and failing miserably. However I found this surprisingly well-written, well-made and brilliantly-acted(comedy acting, not Oliver/Gielgud!) and all-round compelling and bloody hilarious. I think it's a great idea - the central character's minor misdemeanour at the start results in immediate payback in the form of a demented psychopath taking over his life. It gets pretty dark in a couple of places which somehow makes the humour work better. Whatever you think of Jim Carrey, the range of stuff he pulls off on screen is incredible. Like a reanimated old Vaudevillian on PCP. I found him totally convincing as the lonely Walter Mitty/psycho who really just needs a friend and uses what he knows best to make it happen. Broderick is a born fall guy and effortlessly provides the anything-for-a-quiet-life victim, ill-equipped to halt the psycho's hostile takeover of his life. There's also a micro-element of social comment on using people, friendship, the abuse of power, and the influence TV can have on a person's life. Tutt and scoff all you want at that, but can you honestly say there's even that much depth in any other comedies made now? So for anybody who doesn't hate Jim Carrey, please don't listen to all the negative reviews and give this one a chance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It isn't Jim Carrey's best movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew- T-3055
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film which doesn't do justice to Jim Carrey as one of Hollywood's funniest actors. It is another one of his films with many voices and faces being pulled by his character, but this film is different and it just doesn't work. The film follows The Cable Guy who tries to become his latest clients new best friend. He is Steven M. Kovacs (played by Matthew Broderick). But Steven just wants his cable fixed and then to get on with his life. But they become "friends" despite Broderick being a bit awkward and unsure around him. Yet this awkward bond I feel is returned by Carrey's character who is just making annoying over the top jokes which just didn't work in this scenario. This is sad as if it was a mystery or a bit more dramatic like some of his other films then it could've had great potential. I just don't think it works. I feel the best part of the film comes from Jack Black's role as Rick who is Steven's friend, the role is relatively small yet I think it's portrayed well. If the film had extended his role a bit more, with a bit more depth I think that would've improved the film. I would say this is worst film I've seen Jim Carrey in. The premise of the film is good but the acting wasn't and I felt the storyline should have had a bit more depth in places, the film had a lot of potential though.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Must Watch If You Love Jim Carrey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nirbhay Pandey
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We want to like Jim Carrey. A movie that makes us dislike him is a strategic mistake. The opening scenes of "The Cable Guy" are promising; Carrey seems to be playing a variation on his usual hyperkinetic goofball. Then our reaction grows more puzzled: This is supposed to be fun, right? By the end, the movie has declared itself as a black comedy about one very deeply troubled cable guy. The plot centers around a character named Steven (Matthew Broderick), who has just been turned down for marriage by his girlfriend Robin (Leslie Mann). He moves into a bachelor pad and calls for cable service, and Chip Douglas (Carrey) comes pounding on his door (making sure, of course, to arrive very late and while Steven is in the shower). The cable guy is a manic nerd with a lisp and an under slung jaw. He wants to be Steven's friend. He has a lot of trouble pronouncing certain words. "My brother is a speech therapist," Steven says helpfully. The cable guy says, "Tho?" Soon the cable guy has insinuated himself into Steven's life and is offering detailed advice about life (which he reveals he has learned that morning from the summation at the end of a Jerry Springer program). His strategy for getting Robin to come back: Watch "Sleepless in Seattle" with her. Women are suckers for it. Many of these strategies works, and we're reminded of the relationship in the British comedy classic "School for Scoundrels" (which Carrey should remake) in which a cad teaches one-upmanship to a loser. But soon the movie drifts into murkier waters. The cable guy has an unhealthy need to be Steven's friend, and he pursues that goal with behavior designed to scare anyone. He's a stalker. He's obnoxious and peculiar and inappropriate and relentless, and we start disliking him, and that's when the movie jumps the rails. The director, Ben Stiller ("Reality Bites"), throws in a lot of gratuitous but funny asides; there's a running gag about a CourtTV trial involving Hollywood twins whose relationship ends in murder. And in-jokes, as when the cable guy covers his face with fried chicken skin to imitate a scene from "Silence of the Lambs" (the actor Charles Napier, whose face was borrowed by Hannibal Lecter in "Lambs," turns up here as a cop). And there's a fake TV commercial showing Eric Roberts plays a dual role in "Brother, Sweet Brother," the docudrama based on the Hollywood trial. Maybe it would have worked better if the cable guy had become a real friend to Steven, devising love strategies and Machiavellian schemes to win back Robin and thwart her other suitors. As it is, the movie goes in one direction and the cable guy goes in another, and by the end we aren't really looking forward to seeing Jim Carrey reappear on the screen. Note to the producers: There's an old showbiz saying that "satire is what closes on Saturday night." To which could be added another: "Black comedy is not what you pay someone $20 million to-do." ******* BUT STILL MUST WATCH IF YOU LOVE JIM CARREY *******
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible. Really terrible.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesguerin
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am very disappointed that I stayed for the duration of this film. It really is awful, in my opinion. I like stupid humour, when it's done properly like Monty Python or Aeroplane. This was just poor. Jim Carrey plays a psychotic yet supposedly lovable former cable guy. The purpose of his character seems to be more focused on saying random "jokes" than advancing the plot in any way. He starts the film as a stalker and does not develop. Matthew Broderick is also annoyingly bad in places, though not nearly to the same extent. This film failed to make me actually laugh once, although I did manage a smirk a few times. If you like smart dumb comedies, this isn't for you. If you like laughing at anything said in a funny voice, prepare to be entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great fun!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lucas_carvalhaes
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you like Jim Carrey and strong emotions this is definitely for you! I rated 10 because few movies made me laugh so hard, be afraid, be really scared, be lost, feel strange stuff, see awesome scenes in such a short period of time. I don't even know how to describe the feelings this movie gets you... Just watch with friends willing to have fun and you have a great time! Jim Carrey acts so Carrey in this movie even the other actors couldn't resist... so many awesome faces, so much bizarre and yet a great dramatic story. The plot isn't the best and Ben stiller does absolutely nothing during the movie. He just appears as a lesser supporting actor. No, seriously, focus on Carrey's acting and you will have a real roller coaster ride of craziness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misunderstood half-thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cedde6
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Kovacks (Matthew Broderick), a designer who just separated from his girlfriend, has cable installed to his new apartment. Enters the quirky and slightly deranged cable guy (Jim Carey) whom then never exits... A rather simple plot which became in 1996 a very odd and yet pleasurable film indeed. Although following a pretty straight forward structure, the script provides enough background to Jim Carey's character to make of him a lot more than just a run-of-the-mill weirdo while Matthew Broderick aptly counterbalance the excessive title role by a fair performance of the without-a-glitch nice guy of the piece. The constant referencing to TV culture also makes it an entertaining and strangely enough somewhat nostalgic experience. It is quite obvious that a fair amount of improvisation was incorporated to the piece to sometimes great effect (the "Silence of the Lamb" episode anyone?) which I suppose is probably the most effective way to work with someone such as Jim Carey. Curiously however, the main asset of the film also becomes at some point its main shortcoming. This was to Jim Carey what 1994's "The Good Son" was to Macauley Culkin: a departure from their comedic roots to more darker territories, but as opposed to Joseph Ruben's thriller, "The Cable Guy" seems to always hesitate to boldly go as far as its story would allow it to. In Jim Carey's work this is certainly darker than anything he had done up to that point but if this was also supposed to be a thriller then it felt a little bland, the star's antics sometimes overshadowing the actual depth of the story. Still, don't let this put you off for "The Cable Guy", playfully directed by Ben Stiller, is one of these misunderstood films that are really worth watching for its clever take on the media in general and the hidden harm you find it does to people's mind once stripped off the apparent sense of comfort it is supposed to bring. It might have been done a little too light-heartedly maybe but at least it was done at all. And decently done too. This is a more serious film than it looks at first glance and that alone makes it an interesting one. No masterpiece mind you, but then again, it never pretended to be one. Like many films of that ilk, it was generally trashed upon by critics back then, in this case for its lack of downright slapstick-laugh-out-loud moments (Carey's salary the true reason for the furore) although they also criticized "Ace Ventura: when natures call" for being completely empty, the previous year. Oh well, sometimes one can never win...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    it is a matter of comedic taste
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobrobertsst
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In order to rate this movie you must have a good sense of what comedy consists. Most people have a sense of humor that involves the lameness of Napoleon Dynamite and it's completely humorless involvement with society. Ergo if you are a Napoleon Dynamite fan please do not rate any comedy other than your favorite. If I were a sociopath then I should not rate anything involving emotions. You should not rate or judge anything you do not understand. Therefore if you are a Napoleon Dynamite fan it is very obvious you do not have a comedic sense of art. If you do enjoy Woody Allen and Napoleon Dynamite then perhaps you have a split personality. (I am a Woody Allen fan ;-) There is only 1 comedy that has won the Best Picture award (yes it was Woody Allen). This fact illuminates the fact that people do not understand comedy, the reason for this being that comedy does not have a universal appeal. Humor is much more unique and personal than drama.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey is top of his class.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guitarmasta-242-110720
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always been a Carrey fan, so when I stumbled upon this while DVD hunting at a local video store, naturally I bought it. I was not disappointed. Jim Carrey was made for the role of Chip Douglas. His acting in this movie is all but un-paralleled. He really shows us what he is capable of in the acting department. If Jim Carrey can be said to be one of those actors where you either love him or hate him, then the same can be said for this movie. It has a very particular type of often quite dark humor in it, which doesn't appeal to a lot of people, but in which Carrey thrives. If you didn't like this movie, give it another watch. You might change your mind. This movie is a must for any Carrey fan, or any fan of good 90's comedy. Ben Stiller does a fantastic job directing, and the rest of the cast supports Carrey's role brilliantly. 10/10 (Also, I heard that the Chip Douglas role wasn't originally intended for Carrey, but after watching it, can you honestly picture anyone else executing it so damn well??)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey ruins yet another movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scohcon
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's two reasons I watched this movie, or rather suffered through it. One was was because I'm a fan of Matthew Broderick. And two is because it was on TV and I didn't have to pay to see it. And even though I've always been repulsed by anything Jim Carrey has done, I thought maybe I'd be able to bear it. This movie made me realize that Jim Carrey is so pathetically untalented and annoying that he could ruin any movie. And like all of his other movies, he manages to ruin this one as well. He's like a retarded version of Jerry Lewis. Don't get me wrong, I'm a huge fan of Lewis, who was an original, but a bad fake imitation of Lewis with brain damage with a lame accent that can't act... not so much. Truth is, if one could assemble the greatest director, the best actors, the best screen writers, and the best special effects technicians that ever lived to make a movie with an unlimited budget, if you were to add Jim Carrey in the mix, he would spoil it all and insure the film would be capable of inducing vomiting. After all, that's his only "talent".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misunderstood. Carrey's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bradleyluke79
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd like to start off by saying that The Cable Guy is disliked by a lot of people. This would explain it's low rating. But don't be thrown off by that. The Cable Guy is a black comedy. So, some people will be unsettled by the plot of the movie. "Chip" is a disturbed Cable Guy, raised on television, who only wants a friend. Steve is a designer, recently kicked out of his girlfriend's apartment. Moving into his new apartment, his friend Rick tells him to bribe the cable guy, to get illegal cable. But the cable guy, "Chip" sees this is an invitation to be best buds. Steve, trying to be nice fakes an interest in his work, but this just brings "Chip" closer and closer to him. This movie is a misunderstood classic. And in my opinion it's Jim Carrey's best movie. It's a nice change for Carrey's character, having him play the psychotic two faced Cable Guy. With Steve(Matthew Brodrick) in the most awkward of situations by the hilarious Cable Guy(Jim Carrey) this movie should bring you laughs and enjoyment. It does get progressively dark as the film goes on but it's nothing major. The film also has many, many film and T.V. references that you'll enjoy along the way. In my opinion, The Cable Guy is the motion picture version of mar-mite. You will ever love it or hate it. And I love it. A must watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Necessary protest vote
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wouldn't normally have left a review for this but stumbled on the shockingly low mark and was compelled to write something! What a sick joke this movie has such a low rating on IMDb. I have a sneaking suspicion it's down to the pathological Jim Carrey haters rather than based on the movie's merits. I'm giving it a star more than I would have otherwise as a protest vote. I guess if a particular person in a movie annoys you that much then it's going to preclude it from being a good movie for you, *but surely* you can take a step back, and say something like "ah now wait a minute, that's just my personal dislike for an individual and it wouldn't really be fair to transfer that dislike onto any collective effort they happened to be a part of". What about the poor writer, director, other actors and the crew? I know I've made a big assumption there and it's possible people just didn't find it funny. I find that so hard to believe though - I've seen *a hell of a lot* of comedies over the last 40 years, and find the vast majority made from 1990 onwards to be safe, lazy and badly-written, or more recently trying to be zany or alternative and failing miserably. However I found this surprisingly well-written, well-made and brilliantly-acted(comedy acting, not Oliver/Gielgud!) and all-round compelling and bloody hilarious. I think it's a great idea - the central character's minor misdemeanour at the start results in immediate payback in the form of a demented psychopath taking over his life. It gets pretty dark in a couple of places which somehow makes the humour work better. Whatever you think of Jim Carrey, the range of stuff he pulls off on screen is incredible. Like a reanimated old Vaudevillian on PCP. I found him totally convincing as the lonely Walter Mitty/psycho who really just needs a friend and uses what he knows best to make it happen. Broderick is a born fall guy and effortlessly provides the anything-for-a-quiet-life victim, ill-equipped to halt the psycho's hostile takeover of his life. There's also a micro-element of social comment on using people, friendship, the abuse of power, and the influence TV can have on a person's life. Tutt and scoff all you want at that, but can you honestly say there's even that much depth in any other comedies made now? So for anybody who doesn't hate Jim Carrey, please don't listen to all the negative reviews and give this one a chance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It isn't Jim Carrey's best movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew- T-3055
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film which doesn't do justice to Jim Carrey as one of Hollywood's funniest actors. It is another one of his films with many voices and faces being pulled by his character, but this film is different and it just doesn't work. The film follows The Cable Guy who tries to become his latest clients new best friend. He is Steven M. Kovacs (played by Matthew Broderick). But Steven just wants his cable fixed and then to get on with his life. But they become "friends" despite Broderick being a bit awkward and unsure around him. Yet this awkward bond I feel is returned by Carrey's character who is just making annoying over the top jokes which just didn't work in this scenario. This is sad as if it was a mystery or a bit more dramatic like some of his other films then it could've had great potential. I just don't think it works. I feel the best part of the film comes from Jack Black's role as Rick who is Steven's friend, the role is relatively small yet I think it's portrayed well. If the film had extended his role a bit more, with a bit more depth I think that would've improved the film. I would say this is worst film I've seen Jim Carrey in. The premise of the film is good but the acting wasn't and I felt the storyline should have had a bit more depth in places, the film had a lot of potential though.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Must Watch If You Love Jim Carrey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nirbhay Pandey
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We want to like Jim Carrey. A movie that makes us dislike him is a strategic mistake. The opening scenes of "The Cable Guy" are promising; Carrey seems to be playing a variation on his usual hyperkinetic goofball. Then our reaction grows more puzzled: This is supposed to be fun, right? By the end, the movie has declared itself as a black comedy about one very deeply troubled cable guy. The plot centers around a character named Steven (Matthew Broderick), who has just been turned down for marriage by his girlfriend Robin (Leslie Mann). He moves into a bachelor pad and calls for cable service, and Chip Douglas (Carrey) comes pounding on his door (making sure, of course, to arrive very late and while Steven is in the shower). The cable guy is a manic nerd with a lisp and an under slung jaw. He wants to be Steven's friend. He has a lot of trouble pronouncing certain words. "My brother is a speech therapist," Steven says helpfully. The cable guy says, "Tho?" Soon the cable guy has insinuated himself into Steven's life and is offering detailed advice about life (which he reveals he has learned that morning from the summation at the end of a Jerry Springer program). His strategy for getting Robin to come back: Watch "Sleepless in Seattle" with her. Women are suckers for it. Many of these strategies works, and we're reminded of the relationship in the British comedy classic "School for Scoundrels" (which Carrey should remake) in which a cad teaches one-upmanship to a loser. But soon the movie drifts into murkier waters. The cable guy has an unhealthy need to be Steven's friend, and he pursues that goal with behavior designed to scare anyone. He's a stalker. He's obnoxious and peculiar and inappropriate and relentless, and we start disliking him, and that's when the movie jumps the rails. The director, Ben Stiller ("Reality Bites"), throws in a lot of gratuitous but funny asides; there's a running gag about a CourtTV trial involving Hollywood twins whose relationship ends in murder. And in-jokes, as when the cable guy covers his face with fried chicken skin to imitate a scene from "Silence of the Lambs" (the actor Charles Napier, whose face was borrowed by Hannibal Lecter in "Lambs," turns up here as a cop). And there's a fake TV commercial showing Eric Roberts plays a dual role in "Brother, Sweet Brother," the docudrama based on the Hollywood trial. Maybe it would have worked better if the cable guy had become a real friend to Steven, devising love strategies and Machiavellian schemes to win back Robin and thwart her other suitors. As it is, the movie goes in one direction and the cable guy goes in another, and by the end we aren't really looking forward to seeing Jim Carrey reappear on the screen. Note to the producers: There's an old showbiz saying that "satire is what closes on Saturday night." To which could be added another: "Black comedy is not what you pay someone $20 million to-do." ******* BUT STILL MUST WATCH IF YOU LOVE JIM CARREY *******
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible. Really terrible.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesguerin
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am very disappointed that I stayed for the duration of this film. It really is awful, in my opinion. I like stupid humour, when it's done properly like Monty Python or Aeroplane. This was just poor. Jim Carrey plays a psychotic yet supposedly lovable former cable guy. The purpose of his character seems to be more focused on saying random "jokes" than advancing the plot in any way. He starts the film as a stalker and does not develop. Matthew Broderick is also annoyingly bad in places, though not nearly to the same extent. This film failed to make me actually laugh once, although I did manage a smirk a few times. If you like smart dumb comedies, this isn't for you. If you like laughing at anything said in a funny voice, prepare to be entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great fun!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lucas_carvalhaes
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you like Jim Carrey and strong emotions this is definitely for you! I rated 10 because few movies made me laugh so hard, be afraid, be really scared, be lost, feel strange stuff, see awesome scenes in such a short period of time. I don't even know how to describe the feelings this movie gets you... Just watch with friends willing to have fun and you have a great time! Jim Carrey acts so Carrey in this movie even the other actors couldn't resist... so many awesome faces, so much bizarre and yet a great dramatic story. The plot isn't the best and Ben stiller does absolutely nothing during the movie. He just appears as a lesser supporting actor. No, seriously, focus on Carrey's acting and you will have a real roller coaster ride of craziness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misunderstood half-thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cedde6
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Kovacks (Matthew Broderick), a designer who just separated from his girlfriend, has cable installed to his new apartment. Enters the quirky and slightly deranged cable guy (Jim Carey) whom then never exits... A rather simple plot which became in 1996 a very odd and yet pleasurable film indeed. Although following a pretty straight forward structure, the script provides enough background to Jim Carey's character to make of him a lot more than just a run-of-the-mill weirdo while Matthew Broderick aptly counterbalance the excessive title role by a fair performance of the without-a-glitch nice guy of the piece. The constant referencing to TV culture also makes it an entertaining and strangely enough somewhat nostalgic experience. It is quite obvious that a fair amount of improvisation was incorporated to the piece to sometimes great effect (the "Silence of the Lamb" episode anyone?) which I suppose is probably the most effective way to work with someone such as Jim Carey. Curiously however, the main asset of the film also becomes at some point its main shortcoming. This was to Jim Carey what 1994's "The Good Son" was to Macauley Culkin: a departure from their comedic roots to more darker territories, but as opposed to Joseph Ruben's thriller, "The Cable Guy" seems to always hesitate to boldly go as far as its story would allow it to. In Jim Carey's work this is certainly darker than anything he had done up to that point but if this was also supposed to be a thriller then it felt a little bland, the star's antics sometimes overshadowing the actual depth of the story. Still, don't let this put you off for "The Cable Guy", playfully directed by Ben Stiller, is one of these misunderstood films that are really worth watching for its clever take on the media in general and the hidden harm you find it does to people's mind once stripped off the apparent sense of comfort it is supposed to bring. It might have been done a little too light-heartedly maybe but at least it was done at all. And decently done too. This is a more serious film than it looks at first glance and that alone makes it an interesting one. No masterpiece mind you, but then again, it never pretended to be one. Like many films of that ilk, it was generally trashed upon by critics back then, in this case for its lack of downright slapstick-laugh-out-loud moments (Carey's salary the true reason for the furore) although they also criticized "Ace Ventura: when natures call" for being completely empty, the previous year. Oh well, sometimes one can never win...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    it is a matter of comedic taste
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobrobertsst
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In order to rate this movie you must have a good sense of what comedy consists. Most people have a sense of humor that involves the lameness of Napoleon Dynamite and it's completely humorless involvement with society. Ergo if you are a Napoleon Dynamite fan please do not rate any comedy other than your favorite. If I were a sociopath then I should not rate anything involving emotions. You should not rate or judge anything you do not understand. Therefore if you are a Napoleon Dynamite fan it is very obvious you do not have a comedic sense of art. If you do enjoy Woody Allen and Napoleon Dynamite then perhaps you have a split personality. (I am a Woody Allen fan ;-) There is only 1 comedy that has won the Best Picture award (yes it was Woody Allen). This fact illuminates the fact that people do not understand comedy, the reason for this being that comedy does not have a universal appeal. Humor is much more unique and personal than drama.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey is top of his class.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guitarmasta-242-110720
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always been a Carrey fan, so when I stumbled upon this while DVD hunting at a local video store, naturally I bought it. I was not disappointed. Jim Carrey was made for the role of Chip Douglas. His acting in this movie is all but un-paralleled. He really shows us what he is capable of in the acting department. If Jim Carrey can be said to be one of those actors where you either love him or hate him, then the same can be said for this movie. It has a very particular type of often quite dark humor in it, which doesn't appeal to a lot of people, but in which Carrey thrives. If you didn't like this movie, give it another watch. You might change your mind. This movie is a must for any Carrey fan, or any fan of good 90's comedy. Ben Stiller does a fantastic job directing, and the rest of the cast supports Carrey's role brilliantly. 10/10 (Also, I heard that the Chip Douglas role wasn't originally intended for Carrey, but after watching it, can you honestly picture anyone else executing it so damn well??)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey ruins yet another movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scohcon
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's two reasons I watched this movie, or rather suffered through it. One was was because I'm a fan of Matthew Broderick. And two is because it was on TV and I didn't have to pay to see it. And even though I've always been repulsed by anything Jim Carrey has done, I thought maybe I'd be able to bear it. This movie made me realize that Jim Carrey is so pathetically untalented and annoying that he could ruin any movie. And like all of his other movies, he manages to ruin this one as well. He's like a retarded version of Jerry Lewis. Don't get me wrong, I'm a huge fan of Lewis, who was an original, but a bad fake imitation of Lewis with brain damage with a lame accent that can't act... not so much. Truth is, if one could assemble the greatest director, the best actors, the best screen writers, and the best special effects technicians that ever lived to make a movie with an unlimited budget, if you were to add Jim Carrey in the mix, he would spoil it all and insure the film would be capable of inducing vomiting. After all, that's his only "talent".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misunderstood. Carrey's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bradleyluke79
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd like to start off by saying that The Cable Guy is disliked by a lot of people. This would explain it's low rating. But don't be thrown off by that. The Cable Guy is a black comedy. So, some people will be unsettled by the plot of the movie. "Chip" is a disturbed Cable Guy, raised on television, who only wants a friend. Steve is a designer, recently kicked out of his girlfriend's apartment. Moving into his new apartment, his friend Rick tells him to bribe the cable guy, to get illegal cable. But the cable guy, "Chip" sees this is an invitation to be best buds. Steve, trying to be nice fakes an interest in his work, but this just brings "Chip" closer and closer to him. This movie is a misunderstood classic. And in my opinion it's Jim Carrey's best movie. It's a nice change for Carrey's character, having him play the psychotic two faced Cable Guy. With Steve(Matthew Brodrick) in the most awkward of situations by the hilarious Cable Guy(Jim Carrey) this movie should bring you laughs and enjoyment. It does get progressively dark as the film goes on but it's nothing major. The film also has many, many film and T.V. references that you'll enjoy along the way. In my opinion, The Cable Guy is the motion picture version of mar-mite. You will ever love it or hate it. And I love it. A must watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Necessary protest vote
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wouldn't normally have left a review for this but stumbled on the shockingly low mark and was compelled to write something! What a sick joke this movie has such a low rating on IMDb. I have a sneaking suspicion it's down to the pathological Jim Carrey haters rather than based on the movie's merits. I'm giving it a star more than I would have otherwise as a protest vote. I guess if a particular person in a movie annoys you that much then it's going to preclude it from being a good movie for you, *but surely* you can take a step back, and say something like "ah now wait a minute, that's just my personal dislike for an individual and it wouldn't really be fair to transfer that dislike onto any collective effort they happened to be a part of". What about the poor writer, director, other actors and the crew? I know I've made a big assumption there and it's possible people just didn't find it funny. I find that so hard to believe though - I've seen *a hell of a lot* of comedies over the last 40 years, and find the vast majority made from 1990 onwards to be safe, lazy and badly-written, or more recently trying to be zany or alternative and failing miserably. However I found this surprisingly well-written, well-made and brilliantly-acted(comedy acting, not Oliver/Gielgud!) and all-round compelling and bloody hilarious. I think it's a great idea - the central character's minor misdemeanour at the start results in immediate payback in the form of a demented psychopath taking over his life. It gets pretty dark in a couple of places which somehow makes the humour work better. Whatever you think of Jim Carrey, the range of stuff he pulls off on screen is incredible. Like a reanimated old Vaudevillian on PCP. I found him totally convincing as the lonely Walter Mitty/psycho who really just needs a friend and uses what he knows best to make it happen. Broderick is a born fall guy and effortlessly provides the anything-for-a-quiet-life victim, ill-equipped to halt the psycho's hostile takeover of his life. There's also a micro-element of social comment on using people, friendship, the abuse of power, and the influence TV can have on a person's life. Tutt and scoff all you want at that, but can you honestly say there's even that much depth in any other comedies made now? So for anybody who doesn't hate Jim Carrey, please don't listen to all the negative reviews and give this one a chance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It isn't Jim Carrey's best movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew- T-3055
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film which doesn't do justice to Jim Carrey as one of Hollywood's funniest actors. It is another one of his films with many voices and faces being pulled by his character, but this film is different and it just doesn't work. The film follows The Cable Guy who tries to become his latest clients new best friend. He is Steven M. Kovacs (played by Matthew Broderick). But Steven just wants his cable fixed and then to get on with his life. But they become "friends" despite Broderick being a bit awkward and unsure around him. Yet this awkward bond I feel is returned by Carrey's character who is just making annoying over the top jokes which just didn't work in this scenario. This is sad as if it was a mystery or a bit more dramatic like some of his other films then it could've had great potential. I just don't think it works. I feel the best part of the film comes from Jack Black's role as Rick who is Steven's friend, the role is relatively small yet I think it's portrayed well. If the film had extended his role a bit more, with a bit more depth I think that would've improved the film. I would say this is worst film I've seen Jim Carrey in. The premise of the film is good but the acting wasn't and I felt the storyline should have had a bit more depth in places, the film had a lot of potential though.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Must Watch If You Love Jim Carrey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nirbhay Pandey
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We want to like Jim Carrey. A movie that makes us dislike him is a strategic mistake. The opening scenes of "The Cable Guy" are promising; Carrey seems to be playing a variation on his usual hyperkinetic goofball. Then our reaction grows more puzzled: This is supposed to be fun, right? By the end, the movie has declared itself as a black comedy about one very deeply troubled cable guy. The plot centers around a character named Steven (Matthew Broderick), who has just been turned down for marriage by his girlfriend Robin (Leslie Mann). He moves into a bachelor pad and calls for cable service, and Chip Douglas (Carrey) comes pounding on his door (making sure, of course, to arrive very late and while Steven is in the shower). The cable guy is a manic nerd with a lisp and an under slung jaw. He wants to be Steven's friend. He has a lot of trouble pronouncing certain words. "My brother is a speech therapist," Steven says helpfully. The cable guy says, "Tho?" Soon the cable guy has insinuated himself into Steven's life and is offering detailed advice about life (which he reveals he has learned that morning from the summation at the end of a Jerry Springer program). His strategy for getting Robin to come back: Watch "Sleepless in Seattle" with her. Women are suckers for it. Many of these strategies works, and we're reminded of the relationship in the British comedy classic "School for Scoundrels" (which Carrey should remake) in which a cad teaches one-upmanship to a loser. But soon the movie drifts into murkier waters. The cable guy has an unhealthy need to be Steven's friend, and he pursues that goal with behavior designed to scare anyone. He's a stalker. He's obnoxious and peculiar and inappropriate and relentless, and we start disliking him, and that's when the movie jumps the rails. The director, Ben Stiller ("Reality Bites"), throws in a lot of gratuitous but funny asides; there's a running gag about a CourtTV trial involving Hollywood twins whose relationship ends in murder. And in-jokes, as when the cable guy covers his face with fried chicken skin to imitate a scene from "Silence of the Lambs" (the actor Charles Napier, whose face was borrowed by Hannibal Lecter in "Lambs," turns up here as a cop). And there's a fake TV commercial showing Eric Roberts plays a dual role in "Brother, Sweet Brother," the docudrama based on the Hollywood trial. Maybe it would have worked better if the cable guy had become a real friend to Steven, devising love strategies and Machiavellian schemes to win back Robin and thwart her other suitors. As it is, the movie goes in one direction and the cable guy goes in another, and by the end we aren't really looking forward to seeing Jim Carrey reappear on the screen. Note to the producers: There's an old showbiz saying that "satire is what closes on Saturday night." To which could be added another: "Black comedy is not what you pay someone $20 million to-do." ******* BUT STILL MUST WATCH IF YOU LOVE JIM CARREY *******
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible. Really terrible.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesguerin
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am very disappointed that I stayed for the duration of this film. It really is awful, in my opinion. I like stupid humour, when it's done properly like Monty Python or Aeroplane. This was just poor. Jim Carrey plays a psychotic yet supposedly lovable former cable guy. The purpose of his character seems to be more focused on saying random "jokes" than advancing the plot in any way. He starts the film as a stalker and does not develop. Matthew Broderick is also annoyingly bad in places, though not nearly to the same extent. This film failed to make me actually laugh once, although I did manage a smirk a few times. If you like smart dumb comedies, this isn't for you. If you like laughing at anything said in a funny voice, prepare to be entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great fun!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lucas_carvalhaes
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you like Jim Carrey and strong emotions this is definitely for you! I rated 10 because few movies made me laugh so hard, be afraid, be really scared, be lost, feel strange stuff, see awesome scenes in such a short period of time. I don't even know how to describe the feelings this movie gets you... Just watch with friends willing to have fun and you have a great time! Jim Carrey acts so Carrey in this movie even the other actors couldn't resist... so many awesome faces, so much bizarre and yet a great dramatic story. The plot isn't the best and Ben stiller does absolutely nothing during the movie. He just appears as a lesser supporting actor. No, seriously, focus on Carrey's acting and you will have a real roller coaster ride of craziness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misunderstood half-thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cedde6
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Kovacks (Matthew Broderick), a designer who just separated from his girlfriend, has cable installed to his new apartment. Enters the quirky and slightly deranged cable guy (Jim Carey) whom then never exits... A rather simple plot which became in 1996 a very odd and yet pleasurable film indeed. Although following a pretty straight forward structure, the script provides enough background to Jim Carey's character to make of him a lot more than just a run-of-the-mill weirdo while Matthew Broderick aptly counterbalance the excessive title role by a fair performance of the without-a-glitch nice guy of the piece. The constant referencing to TV culture also makes it an entertaining and strangely enough somewhat nostalgic experience. It is quite obvious that a fair amount of improvisation was incorporated to the piece to sometimes great effect (the "Silence of the Lamb" episode anyone?) which I suppose is probably the most effective way to work with someone such as Jim Carey. Curiously however, the main asset of the film also becomes at some point its main shortcoming. This was to Jim Carey what 1994's "The Good Son" was to Macauley Culkin: a departure from their comedic roots to more darker territories, but as opposed to Joseph Ruben's thriller, "The Cable Guy" seems to always hesitate to boldly go as far as its story would allow it to. In Jim Carey's work this is certainly darker than anything he had done up to that point but if this was also supposed to be a thriller then it felt a little bland, the star's antics sometimes overshadowing the actual depth of the story. Still, don't let this put you off for "The Cable Guy", playfully directed by Ben Stiller, is one of these misunderstood films that are really worth watching for its clever take on the media in general and the hidden harm you find it does to people's mind once stripped off the apparent sense of comfort it is supposed to bring. It might have been done a little too light-heartedly maybe but at least it was done at all. And decently done too. This is a more serious film than it looks at first glance and that alone makes it an interesting one. No masterpiece mind you, but then again, it never pretended to be one. Like many films of that ilk, it was generally trashed upon by critics back then, in this case for its lack of downright slapstick-laugh-out-loud moments (Carey's salary the true reason for the furore) although they also criticized "Ace Ventura: when natures call" for being completely empty, the previous year. Oh well, sometimes one can never win...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    it is a matter of comedic taste
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobrobertsst
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In order to rate this movie you must have a good sense of what comedy consists. Most people have a sense of humor that involves the lameness of Napoleon Dynamite and it's completely humorless involvement with society. Ergo if you are a Napoleon Dynamite fan please do not rate any comedy other than your favorite. If I were a sociopath then I should not rate anything involving emotions. You should not rate or judge anything you do not understand. Therefore if you are a Napoleon Dynamite fan it is very obvious you do not have a comedic sense of art. If you do enjoy Woody Allen and Napoleon Dynamite then perhaps you have a split personality. (I am a Woody Allen fan ;-) There is only 1 comedy that has won the Best Picture award (yes it was Woody Allen). This fact illuminates the fact that people do not understand comedy, the reason for this being that comedy does not have a universal appeal. Humor is much more unique and personal than drama.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey is top of his class.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guitarmasta-242-110720
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always been a Carrey fan, so when I stumbled upon this while DVD hunting at a local video store, naturally I bought it. I was not disappointed. Jim Carrey was made for the role of Chip Douglas. His acting in this movie is all but un-paralleled. He really shows us what he is capable of in the acting department. If Jim Carrey can be said to be one of those actors where you either love him or hate him, then the same can be said for this movie. It has a very particular type of often quite dark humor in it, which doesn't appeal to a lot of people, but in which Carrey thrives. If you didn't like this movie, give it another watch. You might change your mind. This movie is a must for any Carrey fan, or any fan of good 90's comedy. Ben Stiller does a fantastic job directing, and the rest of the cast supports Carrey's role brilliantly. 10/10 (Also, I heard that the Chip Douglas role wasn't originally intended for Carrey, but after watching it, can you honestly picture anyone else executing it so damn well??)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey ruins yet another movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scohcon
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's two reasons I watched this movie, or rather suffered through it. One was was because I'm a fan of Matthew Broderick. And two is because it was on TV and I didn't have to pay to see it. And even though I've always been repulsed by anything Jim Carrey has done, I thought maybe I'd be able to bear it. This movie made me realize that Jim Carrey is so pathetically untalented and annoying that he could ruin any movie. And like all of his other movies, he manages to ruin this one as well. He's like a retarded version of Jerry Lewis. Don't get me wrong, I'm a huge fan of Lewis, who was an original, but a bad fake imitation of Lewis with brain damage with a lame accent that can't act... not so much. Truth is, if one could assemble the greatest director, the best actors, the best screen writers, and the best special effects technicians that ever lived to make a movie with an unlimited budget, if you were to add Jim Carrey in the mix, he would spoil it all and insure the film would be capable of inducing vomiting. After all, that's his only "talent".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misunderstood. Carrey's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bradleyluke79
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd like to start off by saying that The Cable Guy is disliked by a lot of people. This would explain it's low rating. But don't be thrown off by that. The Cable Guy is a black comedy. So, some people will be unsettled by the plot of the movie. "Chip" is a disturbed Cable Guy, raised on television, who only wants a friend. Steve is a designer, recently kicked out of his girlfriend's apartment. Moving into his new apartment, his friend Rick tells him to bribe the cable guy, to get illegal cable. But the cable guy, "Chip" sees this is an invitation to be best buds. Steve, trying to be nice fakes an interest in his work, but this just brings "Chip" closer and closer to him. This movie is a misunderstood classic. And in my opinion it's Jim Carrey's best movie. It's a nice change for Carrey's character, having him play the psychotic two faced Cable Guy. With Steve(Matthew Brodrick) in the most awkward of situations by the hilarious Cable Guy(Jim Carrey) this movie should bring you laughs and enjoyment. It does get progressively dark as the film goes on but it's nothing major. The film also has many, many film and T.V. references that you'll enjoy along the way. In my opinion, The Cable Guy is the motion picture version of mar-mite. You will ever love it or hate it. And I love it. A must watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Necessary protest vote
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wouldn't normally have left a review for this but stumbled on the shockingly low mark and was compelled to write something! What a sick joke this movie has such a low rating on IMDb. I have a sneaking suspicion it's down to the pathological Jim Carrey haters rather than based on the movie's merits. I'm giving it a star more than I would have otherwise as a protest vote. I guess if a particular person in a movie annoys you that much then it's going to preclude it from being a good movie for you, *but surely* you can take a step back, and say something like "ah now wait a minute, that's just my personal dislike for an individual and it wouldn't really be fair to transfer that dislike onto any collective effort they happened to be a part of". What about the poor writer, director, other actors and the crew? I know I've made a big assumption there and it's possible people just didn't find it funny. I find that so hard to believe though - I've seen *a hell of a lot* of comedies over the last 40 years, and find the vast majority made from 1990 onwards to be safe, lazy and badly-written, or more recently trying to be zany or alternative and failing miserably. However I found this surprisingly well-written, well-made and brilliantly-acted(comedy acting, not Oliver/Gielgud!) and all-round compelling and bloody hilarious. I think it's a great idea - the central character's minor misdemeanour at the start results in immediate payback in the form of a demented psychopath taking over his life. It gets pretty dark in a couple of places which somehow makes the humour work better. Whatever you think of Jim Carrey, the range of stuff he pulls off on screen is incredible. Like a reanimated old Vaudevillian on PCP. I found him totally convincing as the lonely Walter Mitty/psycho who really just needs a friend and uses what he knows best to make it happen. Broderick is a born fall guy and effortlessly provides the anything-for-a-quiet-life victim, ill-equipped to halt the psycho's hostile takeover of his life. There's also a micro-element of social comment on using people, friendship, the abuse of power, and the influence TV can have on a person's life. Tutt and scoff all you want at that, but can you honestly say there's even that much depth in any other comedies made now? So for anybody who doesn't hate Jim Carrey, please don't listen to all the negative reviews and give this one a chance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It isn't Jim Carrey's best movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew- T-3055
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film which doesn't do justice to Jim Carrey as one of Hollywood's funniest actors. It is another one of his films with many voices and faces being pulled by his character, but this film is different and it just doesn't work. The film follows The Cable Guy who tries to become his latest clients new best friend. He is Steven M. Kovacs (played by Matthew Broderick). But Steven just wants his cable fixed and then to get on with his life. But they become "friends" despite Broderick being a bit awkward and unsure around him. Yet this awkward bond I feel is returned by Carrey's character who is just making annoying over the top jokes which just didn't work in this scenario. This is sad as if it was a mystery or a bit more dramatic like some of his other films then it could've had great potential. I just don't think it works. I feel the best part of the film comes from Jack Black's role as Rick who is Steven's friend, the role is relatively small yet I think it's portrayed well. If the film had extended his role a bit more, with a bit more depth I think that would've improved the film. I would say this is worst film I've seen Jim Carrey in. The premise of the film is good but the acting wasn't and I felt the storyline should have had a bit more depth in places, the film had a lot of potential though.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Must Watch If You Love Jim Carrey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nirbhay Pandey
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We want to like Jim Carrey. A movie that makes us dislike him is a strategic mistake. The opening scenes of "The Cable Guy" are promising; Carrey seems to be playing a variation on his usual hyperkinetic goofball. Then our reaction grows more puzzled: This is supposed to be fun, right? By the end, the movie has declared itself as a black comedy about one very deeply troubled cable guy. The plot centers around a character named Steven (Matthew Broderick), who has just been turned down for marriage by his girlfriend Robin (Leslie Mann). He moves into a bachelor pad and calls for cable service, and Chip Douglas (Carrey) comes pounding on his door (making sure, of course, to arrive very late and while Steven is in the shower). The cable guy is a manic nerd with a lisp and an under slung jaw. He wants to be Steven's friend. He has a lot of trouble pronouncing certain words. "My brother is a speech therapist," Steven says helpfully. The cable guy says, "Tho?" Soon the cable guy has insinuated himself into Steven's life and is offering detailed advice about life (which he reveals he has learned that morning from the summation at the end of a Jerry Springer program). His strategy for getting Robin to come back: Watch "Sleepless in Seattle" with her. Women are suckers for it. Many of these strategies works, and we're reminded of the relationship in the British comedy classic "School for Scoundrels" (which Carrey should remake) in which a cad teaches one-upmanship to a loser. But soon the movie drifts into murkier waters. The cable guy has an unhealthy need to be Steven's friend, and he pursues that goal with behavior designed to scare anyone. He's a stalker. He's obnoxious and peculiar and inappropriate and relentless, and we start disliking him, and that's when the movie jumps the rails. The director, Ben Stiller ("Reality Bites"), throws in a lot of gratuitous but funny asides; there's a running gag about a CourtTV trial involving Hollywood twins whose relationship ends in murder. And in-jokes, as when the cable guy covers his face with fried chicken skin to imitate a scene from "Silence of the Lambs" (the actor Charles Napier, whose face was borrowed by Hannibal Lecter in "Lambs," turns up here as a cop). And there's a fake TV commercial showing Eric Roberts plays a dual role in "Brother, Sweet Brother," the docudrama based on the Hollywood trial. Maybe it would have worked better if the cable guy had become a real friend to Steven, devising love strategies and Machiavellian schemes to win back Robin and thwart her other suitors. As it is, the movie goes in one direction and the cable guy goes in another, and by the end we aren't really looking forward to seeing Jim Carrey reappear on the screen. Note to the producers: There's an old showbiz saying that "satire is what closes on Saturday night." To which could be added another: "Black comedy is not what you pay someone $20 million to-do." ******* BUT STILL MUST WATCH IF YOU LOVE JIM CARREY *******
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible. Really terrible.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesguerin
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am very disappointed that I stayed for the duration of this film. It really is awful, in my opinion. I like stupid humour, when it's done properly like Monty Python or Aeroplane. This was just poor. Jim Carrey plays a psychotic yet supposedly lovable former cable guy. The purpose of his character seems to be more focused on saying random "jokes" than advancing the plot in any way. He starts the film as a stalker and does not develop. Matthew Broderick is also annoyingly bad in places, though not nearly to the same extent. This film failed to make me actually laugh once, although I did manage a smirk a few times. If you like smart dumb comedies, this isn't for you. If you like laughing at anything said in a funny voice, prepare to be entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great fun!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lucas_carvalhaes
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you like Jim Carrey and strong emotions this is definitely for you! I rated 10 because few movies made me laugh so hard, be afraid, be really scared, be lost, feel strange stuff, see awesome scenes in such a short period of time. I don't even know how to describe the feelings this movie gets you... Just watch with friends willing to have fun and you have a great time! Jim Carrey acts so Carrey in this movie even the other actors couldn't resist... so many awesome faces, so much bizarre and yet a great dramatic story. The plot isn't the best and Ben stiller does absolutely nothing during the movie. He just appears as a lesser supporting actor. No, seriously, focus on Carrey's acting and you will have a real roller coaster ride of craziness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misunderstood half-thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cedde6
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Kovacks (Matthew Broderick), a designer who just separated from his girlfriend, has cable installed to his new apartment. Enters the quirky and slightly deranged cable guy (Jim Carey) whom then never exits... A rather simple plot which became in 1996 a very odd and yet pleasurable film indeed. Although following a pretty straight forward structure, the script provides enough background to Jim Carey's character to make of him a lot more than just a run-of-the-mill weirdo while Matthew Broderick aptly counterbalance the excessive title role by a fair performance of the without-a-glitch nice guy of the piece. The constant referencing to TV culture also makes it an entertaining and strangely enough somewhat nostalgic experience. It is quite obvious that a fair amount of improvisation was incorporated to the piece to sometimes great effect (the "Silence of the Lamb" episode anyone?) which I suppose is probably the most effective way to work with someone such as Jim Carey. Curiously however, the main asset of the film also becomes at some point its main shortcoming. This was to Jim Carey what 1994's "The Good Son" was to Macauley Culkin: a departure from their comedic roots to more darker territories, but as opposed to Joseph Ruben's thriller, "The Cable Guy" seems to always hesitate to boldly go as far as its story would allow it to. In Jim Carey's work this is certainly darker than anything he had done up to that point but if this was also supposed to be a thriller then it felt a little bland, the star's antics sometimes overshadowing the actual depth of the story. Still, don't let this put you off for "The Cable Guy", playfully directed by Ben Stiller, is one of these misunderstood films that are really worth watching for its clever take on the media in general and the hidden harm you find it does to people's mind once stripped off the apparent sense of comfort it is supposed to bring. It might have been done a little too light-heartedly maybe but at least it was done at all. And decently done too. This is a more serious film than it looks at first glance and that alone makes it an interesting one. No masterpiece mind you, but then again, it never pretended to be one. Like many films of that ilk, it was generally trashed upon by critics back then, in this case for its lack of downright slapstick-laugh-out-loud moments (Carey's salary the true reason for the furore) although they also criticized "Ace Ventura: when natures call" for being completely empty, the previous year. Oh well, sometimes one can never win...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    it is a matter of comedic taste
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobrobertsst
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In order to rate this movie you must have a good sense of what comedy consists. Most people have a sense of humor that involves the lameness of Napoleon Dynamite and it's completely humorless involvement with society. Ergo if you are a Napoleon Dynamite fan please do not rate any comedy other than your favorite. If I were a sociopath then I should not rate anything involving emotions. You should not rate or judge anything you do not understand. Therefore if you are a Napoleon Dynamite fan it is very obvious you do not have a comedic sense of art. If you do enjoy Woody Allen and Napoleon Dynamite then perhaps you have a split personality. (I am a Woody Allen fan ;-) There is only 1 comedy that has won the Best Picture award (yes it was Woody Allen). This fact illuminates the fact that people do not understand comedy, the reason for this being that comedy does not have a universal appeal. Humor is much more unique and personal than drama.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey is top of his class.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guitarmasta-242-110720
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always been a Carrey fan, so when I stumbled upon this while DVD hunting at a local video store, naturally I bought it. I was not disappointed. Jim Carrey was made for the role of Chip Douglas. His acting in this movie is all but un-paralleled. He really shows us what he is capable of in the acting department. If Jim Carrey can be said to be one of those actors where you either love him or hate him, then the same can be said for this movie. It has a very particular type of often quite dark humor in it, which doesn't appeal to a lot of people, but in which Carrey thrives. If you didn't like this movie, give it another watch. You might change your mind. This movie is a must for any Carrey fan, or any fan of good 90's comedy. Ben Stiller does a fantastic job directing, and the rest of the cast supports Carrey's role brilliantly. 10/10 (Also, I heard that the Chip Douglas role wasn't originally intended for Carrey, but after watching it, can you honestly picture anyone else executing it so damn well??)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey ruins yet another movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scohcon
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's two reasons I watched this movie, or rather suffered through it. One was was because I'm a fan of Matthew Broderick. And two is because it was on TV and I didn't have to pay to see it. And even though I've always been repulsed by anything Jim Carrey has done, I thought maybe I'd be able to bear it. This movie made me realize that Jim Carrey is so pathetically untalented and annoying that he could ruin any movie. And like all of his other movies, he manages to ruin this one as well. He's like a retarded version of Jerry Lewis. Don't get me wrong, I'm a huge fan of Lewis, who was an original, but a bad fake imitation of Lewis with brain damage with a lame accent that can't act... not so much. Truth is, if one could assemble the greatest director, the best actors, the best screen writers, and the best special effects technicians that ever lived to make a movie with an unlimited budget, if you were to add Jim Carrey in the mix, he would spoil it all and insure the film would be capable of inducing vomiting. After all, that's his only "talent".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misunderstood. Carrey's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bradleyluke79
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd like to start off by saying that The Cable Guy is disliked by a lot of people. This would explain it's low rating. But don't be thrown off by that. The Cable Guy is a black comedy. So, some people will be unsettled by the plot of the movie. "Chip" is a disturbed Cable Guy, raised on television, who only wants a friend. Steve is a designer, recently kicked out of his girlfriend's apartment. Moving into his new apartment, his friend Rick tells him to bribe the cable guy, to get illegal cable. But the cable guy, "Chip" sees this is an invitation to be best buds. Steve, trying to be nice fakes an interest in his work, but this just brings "Chip" closer and closer to him. This movie is a misunderstood classic. And in my opinion it's Jim Carrey's best movie. It's a nice change for Carrey's character, having him play the psychotic two faced Cable Guy. With Steve(Matthew Brodrick) in the most awkward of situations by the hilarious Cable Guy(Jim Carrey) this movie should bring you laughs and enjoyment. It does get progressively dark as the film goes on but it's nothing major. The film also has many, many film and T.V. references that you'll enjoy along the way. In my opinion, The Cable Guy is the motion picture version of mar-mite. You will ever love it or hate it. And I love it. A must watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Necessary protest vote
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wouldn't normally have left a review for this but stumbled on the shockingly low mark and was compelled to write something! What a sick joke this movie has such a low rating on IMDb. I have a sneaking suspicion it's down to the pathological Jim Carrey haters rather than based on the movie's merits. I'm giving it a star more than I would have otherwise as a protest vote. I guess if a particular person in a movie annoys you that much then it's going to preclude it from being a good movie for you, *but surely* you can take a step back, and say something like "ah now wait a minute, that's just my personal dislike for an individual and it wouldn't really be fair to transfer that dislike onto any collective effort they happened to be a part of". What about the poor writer, director, other actors and the crew? I know I've made a big assumption there and it's possible people just didn't find it funny. I find that so hard to believe though - I've seen *a hell of a lot* of comedies over the last 40 years, and find the vast majority made from 1990 onwards to be safe, lazy and badly-written, or more recently trying to be zany or alternative and failing miserably. However I found this surprisingly well-written, well-made and brilliantly-acted(comedy acting, not Oliver/Gielgud!) and all-round compelling and bloody hilarious. I think it's a great idea - the central character's minor misdemeanour at the start results in immediate payback in the form of a demented psychopath taking over his life. It gets pretty dark in a couple of places which somehow makes the humour work better. Whatever you think of Jim Carrey, the range of stuff he pulls off on screen is incredible. Like a reanimated old Vaudevillian on PCP. I found him totally convincing as the lonely Walter Mitty/psycho who really just needs a friend and uses what he knows best to make it happen. Broderick is a born fall guy and effortlessly provides the anything-for-a-quiet-life victim, ill-equipped to halt the psycho's hostile takeover of his life. There's also a micro-element of social comment on using people, friendship, the abuse of power, and the influence TV can have on a person's life. Tutt and scoff all you want at that, but can you honestly say there's even that much depth in any other comedies made now? So for anybody who doesn't hate Jim Carrey, please don't listen to all the negative reviews and give this one a chance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It isn't Jim Carrey's best movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew- T-3055
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film which doesn't do justice to Jim Carrey as one of Hollywood's funniest actors. It is another one of his films with many voices and faces being pulled by his character, but this film is different and it just doesn't work. The film follows The Cable Guy who tries to become his latest clients new best friend. He is Steven M. Kovacs (played by Matthew Broderick). But Steven just wants his cable fixed and then to get on with his life. But they become "friends" despite Broderick being a bit awkward and unsure around him. Yet this awkward bond I feel is returned by Carrey's character who is just making annoying over the top jokes which just didn't work in this scenario. This is sad as if it was a mystery or a bit more dramatic like some of his other films then it could've had great potential. I just don't think it works. I feel the best part of the film comes from Jack Black's role as Rick who is Steven's friend, the role is relatively small yet I think it's portrayed well. If the film had extended his role a bit more, with a bit more depth I think that would've improved the film. I would say this is worst film I've seen Jim Carrey in. The premise of the film is good but the acting wasn't and I felt the storyline should have had a bit more depth in places, the film had a lot of potential though.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Must Watch If You Love Jim Carrey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nirbhay Pandey
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We want to like Jim Carrey. A movie that makes us dislike him is a strategic mistake. The opening scenes of "The Cable Guy" are promising; Carrey seems to be playing a variation on his usual hyperkinetic goofball. Then our reaction grows more puzzled: This is supposed to be fun, right? By the end, the movie has declared itself as a black comedy about one very deeply troubled cable guy. The plot centers around a character named Steven (Matthew Broderick), who has just been turned down for marriage by his girlfriend Robin (Leslie Mann). He moves into a bachelor pad and calls for cable service, and Chip Douglas (Carrey) comes pounding on his door (making sure, of course, to arrive very late and while Steven is in the shower). The cable guy is a manic nerd with a lisp and an under slung jaw. He wants to be Steven's friend. He has a lot of trouble pronouncing certain words. "My brother is a speech therapist," Steven says helpfully. The cable guy says, "Tho?" Soon the cable guy has insinuated himself into Steven's life and is offering detailed advice about life (which he reveals he has learned that morning from the summation at the end of a Jerry Springer program). His strategy for getting Robin to come back: Watch "Sleepless in Seattle" with her. Women are suckers for it. Many of these strategies works, and we're reminded of the relationship in the British comedy classic "School for Scoundrels" (which Carrey should remake) in which a cad teaches one-upmanship to a loser. But soon the movie drifts into murkier waters. The cable guy has an unhealthy need to be Steven's friend, and he pursues that goal with behavior designed to scare anyone. He's a stalker. He's obnoxious and peculiar and inappropriate and relentless, and we start disliking him, and that's when the movie jumps the rails. The director, Ben Stiller ("Reality Bites"), throws in a lot of gratuitous but funny asides; there's a running gag about a CourtTV trial involving Hollywood twins whose relationship ends in murder. And in-jokes, as when the cable guy covers his face with fried chicken skin to imitate a scene from "Silence of the Lambs" (the actor Charles Napier, whose face was borrowed by Hannibal Lecter in "Lambs," turns up here as a cop). And there's a fake TV commercial showing Eric Roberts plays a dual role in "Brother, Sweet Brother," the docudrama based on the Hollywood trial. Maybe it would have worked better if the cable guy had become a real friend to Steven, devising love strategies and Machiavellian schemes to win back Robin and thwart her other suitors. As it is, the movie goes in one direction and the cable guy goes in another, and by the end we aren't really looking forward to seeing Jim Carrey reappear on the screen. Note to the producers: There's an old showbiz saying that "satire is what closes on Saturday night." To which could be added another: "Black comedy is not what you pay someone $20 million to-do." ******* BUT STILL MUST WATCH IF YOU LOVE JIM CARREY *******
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible. Really terrible.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesguerin
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am very disappointed that I stayed for the duration of this film. It really is awful, in my opinion. I like stupid humour, when it's done properly like Monty Python or Aeroplane. This was just poor. Jim Carrey plays a psychotic yet supposedly lovable former cable guy. The purpose of his character seems to be more focused on saying random "jokes" than advancing the plot in any way. He starts the film as a stalker and does not develop. Matthew Broderick is also annoyingly bad in places, though not nearly to the same extent. This film failed to make me actually laugh once, although I did manage a smirk a few times. If you like smart dumb comedies, this isn't for you. If you like laughing at anything said in a funny voice, prepare to be entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great fun!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lucas_carvalhaes
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you like Jim Carrey and strong emotions this is definitely for you! I rated 10 because few movies made me laugh so hard, be afraid, be really scared, be lost, feel strange stuff, see awesome scenes in such a short period of time. I don't even know how to describe the feelings this movie gets you... Just watch with friends willing to have fun and you have a great time! Jim Carrey acts so Carrey in this movie even the other actors couldn't resist... so many awesome faces, so much bizarre and yet a great dramatic story. The plot isn't the best and Ben stiller does absolutely nothing during the movie. He just appears as a lesser supporting actor. No, seriously, focus on Carrey's acting and you will have a real roller coaster ride of craziness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misunderstood half-thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cedde6
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Kovacks (Matthew Broderick), a designer who just separated from his girlfriend, has cable installed to his new apartment. Enters the quirky and slightly deranged cable guy (Jim Carey) whom then never exits... A rather simple plot which became in 1996 a very odd and yet pleasurable film indeed. Although following a pretty straight forward structure, the script provides enough background to Jim Carey's character to make of him a lot more than just a run-of-the-mill weirdo while Matthew Broderick aptly counterbalance the excessive title role by a fair performance of the without-a-glitch nice guy of the piece. The constant referencing to TV culture also makes it an entertaining and strangely enough somewhat nostalgic experience. It is quite obvious that a fair amount of improvisation was incorporated to the piece to sometimes great effect (the "Silence of the Lamb" episode anyone?) which I suppose is probably the most effective way to work with someone such as Jim Carey. Curiously however, the main asset of the film also becomes at some point its main shortcoming. This was to Jim Carey what 1994's "The Good Son" was to Macauley Culkin: a departure from their comedic roots to more darker territories, but as opposed to Joseph Ruben's thriller, "The Cable Guy" seems to always hesitate to boldly go as far as its story would allow it to. In Jim Carey's work this is certainly darker than anything he had done up to that point but if this was also supposed to be a thriller then it felt a little bland, the star's antics sometimes overshadowing the actual depth of the story. Still, don't let this put you off for "The Cable Guy", playfully directed by Ben Stiller, is one of these misunderstood films that are really worth watching for its clever take on the media in general and the hidden harm you find it does to people's mind once stripped off the apparent sense of comfort it is supposed to bring. It might have been done a little too light-heartedly maybe but at least it was done at all. And decently done too. This is a more serious film than it looks at first glance and that alone makes it an interesting one. No masterpiece mind you, but then again, it never pretended to be one. Like many films of that ilk, it was generally trashed upon by critics back then, in this case for its lack of downright slapstick-laugh-out-loud moments (Carey's salary the true reason for the furore) although they also criticized "Ace Ventura: when natures call" for being completely empty, the previous year. Oh well, sometimes one can never win...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    it is a matter of comedic taste
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobrobertsst
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In order to rate this movie you must have a good sense of what comedy consists. Most people have a sense of humor that involves the lameness of Napoleon Dynamite and it's completely humorless involvement with society. Ergo if you are a Napoleon Dynamite fan please do not rate any comedy other than your favorite. If I were a sociopath then I should not rate anything involving emotions. You should not rate or judge anything you do not understand. Therefore if you are a Napoleon Dynamite fan it is very obvious you do not have a comedic sense of art. If you do enjoy Woody Allen and Napoleon Dynamite then perhaps you have a split personality. (I am a Woody Allen fan ;-) There is only 1 comedy that has won the Best Picture award (yes it was Woody Allen). This fact illuminates the fact that people do not understand comedy, the reason for this being that comedy does not have a universal appeal. Humor is much more unique and personal than drama.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey is top of his class.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guitarmasta-242-110720
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always been a Carrey fan, so when I stumbled upon this while DVD hunting at a local video store, naturally I bought it. I was not disappointed. Jim Carrey was made for the role of Chip Douglas. His acting in this movie is all but un-paralleled. He really shows us what he is capable of in the acting department. If Jim Carrey can be said to be one of those actors where you either love him or hate him, then the same can be said for this movie. It has a very particular type of often quite dark humor in it, which doesn't appeal to a lot of people, but in which Carrey thrives. If you didn't like this movie, give it another watch. You might change your mind. This movie is a must for any Carrey fan, or any fan of good 90's comedy. Ben Stiller does a fantastic job directing, and the rest of the cast supports Carrey's role brilliantly. 10/10 (Also, I heard that the Chip Douglas role wasn't originally intended for Carrey, but after watching it, can you honestly picture anyone else executing it so damn well??)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey ruins yet another movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scohcon
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's two reasons I watched this movie, or rather suffered through it. One was was because I'm a fan of Matthew Broderick. And two is because it was on TV and I didn't have to pay to see it. And even though I've always been repulsed by anything Jim Carrey has done, I thought maybe I'd be able to bear it. This movie made me realize that Jim Carrey is so pathetically untalented and annoying that he could ruin any movie. And like all of his other movies, he manages to ruin this one as well. He's like a retarded version of Jerry Lewis. Don't get me wrong, I'm a huge fan of Lewis, who was an original, but a bad fake imitation of Lewis with brain damage with a lame accent that can't act... not so much. Truth is, if one could assemble the greatest director, the best actors, the best screen writers, and the best special effects technicians that ever lived to make a movie with an unlimited budget, if you were to add Jim Carrey in the mix, he would spoil it all and insure the film would be capable of inducing vomiting. After all, that's his only "talent".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misunderstood. Carrey's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bradleyluke79
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd like to start off by saying that The Cable Guy is disliked by a lot of people. This would explain it's low rating. But don't be thrown off by that. The Cable Guy is a black comedy. So, some people will be unsettled by the plot of the movie. "Chip" is a disturbed Cable Guy, raised on television, who only wants a friend. Steve is a designer, recently kicked out of his girlfriend's apartment. Moving into his new apartment, his friend Rick tells him to bribe the cable guy, to get illegal cable. But the cable guy, "Chip" sees this is an invitation to be best buds. Steve, trying to be nice fakes an interest in his work, but this just brings "Chip" closer and closer to him. This movie is a misunderstood classic. And in my opinion it's Jim Carrey's best movie. It's a nice change for Carrey's character, having him play the psychotic two faced Cable Guy. With Steve(Matthew Brodrick) in the most awkward of situations by the hilarious Cable Guy(Jim Carrey) this movie should bring you laughs and enjoyment. It does get progressively dark as the film goes on but it's nothing major. The film also has many, many film and T.V. references that you'll enjoy along the way. In my opinion, The Cable Guy is the motion picture version of mar-mite. You will ever love it or hate it. And I love it. A must watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Necessary protest vote
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wouldn't normally have left a review for this but stumbled on the shockingly low mark and was compelled to write something! What a sick joke this movie has such a low rating on IMDb. I have a sneaking suspicion it's down to the pathological Jim Carrey haters rather than based on the movie's merits. I'm giving it a star more than I would have otherwise as a protest vote. I guess if a particular person in a movie annoys you that much then it's going to preclude it from being a good movie for you, *but surely* you can take a step back, and say something like "ah now wait a minute, that's just my personal dislike for an individual and it wouldn't really be fair to transfer that dislike onto any collective effort they happened to be a part of". What about the poor writer, director, other actors and the crew? I know I've made a big assumption there and it's possible people just didn't find it funny. I find that so hard to believe though - I've seen *a hell of a lot* of comedies over the last 40 years, and find the vast majority made from 1990 onwards to be safe, lazy and badly-written, or more recently trying to be zany or alternative and failing miserably. However I found this surprisingly well-written, well-made and brilliantly-acted(comedy acting, not Oliver/Gielgud!) and all-round compelling and bloody hilarious. I think it's a great idea - the central character's minor misdemeanour at the start results in immediate payback in the form of a demented psychopath taking over his life. It gets pretty dark in a couple of places which somehow makes the humour work better. Whatever you think of Jim Carrey, the range of stuff he pulls off on screen is incredible. Like a reanimated old Vaudevillian on PCP. I found him totally convincing as the lonely Walter Mitty/psycho who really just needs a friend and uses what he knows best to make it happen. Broderick is a born fall guy and effortlessly provides the anything-for-a-quiet-life victim, ill-equipped to halt the psycho's hostile takeover of his life. There's also a micro-element of social comment on using people, friendship, the abuse of power, and the influence TV can have on a person's life. Tutt and scoff all you want at that, but can you honestly say there's even that much depth in any other comedies made now? So for anybody who doesn't hate Jim Carrey, please don't listen to all the negative reviews and give this one a chance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It isn't Jim Carrey's best movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew- T-3055
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film which doesn't do justice to Jim Carrey as one of Hollywood's funniest actors. It is another one of his films with many voices and faces being pulled by his character, but this film is different and it just doesn't work. The film follows The Cable Guy who tries to become his latest clients new best friend. He is Steven M. Kovacs (played by Matthew Broderick). But Steven just wants his cable fixed and then to get on with his life. But they become "friends" despite Broderick being a bit awkward and unsure around him. Yet this awkward bond I feel is returned by Carrey's character who is just making annoying over the top jokes which just didn't work in this scenario. This is sad as if it was a mystery or a bit more dramatic like some of his other films then it could've had great potential. I just don't think it works. I feel the best part of the film comes from Jack Black's role as Rick who is Steven's friend, the role is relatively small yet I think it's portrayed well. If the film had extended his role a bit more, with a bit more depth I think that would've improved the film. I would say this is worst film I've seen Jim Carrey in. The premise of the film is good but the acting wasn't and I felt the storyline should have had a bit more depth in places, the film had a lot of potential though.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Must Watch If You Love Jim Carrey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nirbhay Pandey
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We want to like Jim Carrey. A movie that makes us dislike him is a strategic mistake. The opening scenes of "The Cable Guy" are promising; Carrey seems to be playing a variation on his usual hyperkinetic goofball. Then our reaction grows more puzzled: This is supposed to be fun, right? By the end, the movie has declared itself as a black comedy about one very deeply troubled cable guy. The plot centers around a character named Steven (Matthew Broderick), who has just been turned down for marriage by his girlfriend Robin (Leslie Mann). He moves into a bachelor pad and calls for cable service, and Chip Douglas (Carrey) comes pounding on his door (making sure, of course, to arrive very late and while Steven is in the shower). The cable guy is a manic nerd with a lisp and an under slung jaw. He wants to be Steven's friend. He has a lot of trouble pronouncing certain words. "My brother is a speech therapist," Steven says helpfully. The cable guy says, "Tho?" Soon the cable guy has insinuated himself into Steven's life and is offering detailed advice about life (which he reveals he has learned that morning from the summation at the end of a Jerry Springer program). His strategy for getting Robin to come back: Watch "Sleepless in Seattle" with her. Women are suckers for it. Many of these strategies works, and we're reminded of the relationship in the British comedy classic "School for Scoundrels" (which Carrey should remake) in which a cad teaches one-upmanship to a loser. But soon the movie drifts into murkier waters. The cable guy has an unhealthy need to be Steven's friend, and he pursues that goal with behavior designed to scare anyone. He's a stalker. He's obnoxious and peculiar and inappropriate and relentless, and we start disliking him, and that's when the movie jumps the rails. The director, Ben Stiller ("Reality Bites"), throws in a lot of gratuitous but funny asides; there's a running gag about a CourtTV trial involving Hollywood twins whose relationship ends in murder. And in-jokes, as when the cable guy covers his face with fried chicken skin to imitate a scene from "Silence of the Lambs" (the actor Charles Napier, whose face was borrowed by Hannibal Lecter in "Lambs," turns up here as a cop). And there's a fake TV commercial showing Eric Roberts plays a dual role in "Brother, Sweet Brother," the docudrama based on the Hollywood trial. Maybe it would have worked better if the cable guy had become a real friend to Steven, devising love strategies and Machiavellian schemes to win back Robin and thwart her other suitors. As it is, the movie goes in one direction and the cable guy goes in another, and by the end we aren't really looking forward to seeing Jim Carrey reappear on the screen. Note to the producers: There's an old showbiz saying that "satire is what closes on Saturday night." To which could be added another: "Black comedy is not what you pay someone $20 million to-do." ******* BUT STILL MUST WATCH IF YOU LOVE JIM CARREY *******
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible. Really terrible.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesguerin
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am very disappointed that I stayed for the duration of this film. It really is awful, in my opinion. I like stupid humour, when it's done properly like Monty Python or Aeroplane. This was just poor. Jim Carrey plays a psychotic yet supposedly lovable former cable guy. The purpose of his character seems to be more focused on saying random "jokes" than advancing the plot in any way. He starts the film as a stalker and does not develop. Matthew Broderick is also annoyingly bad in places, though not nearly to the same extent. This film failed to make me actually laugh once, although I did manage a smirk a few times. If you like smart dumb comedies, this isn't for you. If you like laughing at anything said in a funny voice, prepare to be entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great fun!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lucas_carvalhaes
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you like Jim Carrey and strong emotions this is definitely for you! I rated 10 because few movies made me laugh so hard, be afraid, be really scared, be lost, feel strange stuff, see awesome scenes in such a short period of time. I don't even know how to describe the feelings this movie gets you... Just watch with friends willing to have fun and you have a great time! Jim Carrey acts so Carrey in this movie even the other actors couldn't resist... so many awesome faces, so much bizarre and yet a great dramatic story. The plot isn't the best and Ben stiller does absolutely nothing during the movie. He just appears as a lesser supporting actor. No, seriously, focus on Carrey's acting and you will have a real roller coaster ride of craziness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misunderstood half-thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cedde6
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Kovacks (Matthew Broderick), a designer who just separated from his girlfriend, has cable installed to his new apartment. Enters the quirky and slightly deranged cable guy (Jim Carey) whom then never exits... A rather simple plot which became in 1996 a very odd and yet pleasurable film indeed. Although following a pretty straight forward structure, the script provides enough background to Jim Carey's character to make of him a lot more than just a run-of-the-mill weirdo while Matthew Broderick aptly counterbalance the excessive title role by a fair performance of the without-a-glitch nice guy of the piece. The constant referencing to TV culture also makes it an entertaining and strangely enough somewhat nostalgic experience. It is quite obvious that a fair amount of improvisation was incorporated to the piece to sometimes great effect (the "Silence of the Lamb" episode anyone?) which I suppose is probably the most effective way to work with someone such as Jim Carey. Curiously however, the main asset of the film also becomes at some point its main shortcoming. This was to Jim Carey what 1994's "The Good Son" was to Macauley Culkin: a departure from their comedic roots to more darker territories, but as opposed to Joseph Ruben's thriller, "The Cable Guy" seems to always hesitate to boldly go as far as its story would allow it to. In Jim Carey's work this is certainly darker than anything he had done up to that point but if this was also supposed to be a thriller then it felt a little bland, the star's antics sometimes overshadowing the actual depth of the story. Still, don't let this put you off for "The Cable Guy", playfully directed by Ben Stiller, is one of these misunderstood films that are really worth watching for its clever take on the media in general and the hidden harm you find it does to people's mind once stripped off the apparent sense of comfort it is supposed to bring. It might have been done a little too light-heartedly maybe but at least it was done at all. And decently done too. This is a more serious film than it looks at first glance and that alone makes it an interesting one. No masterpiece mind you, but then again, it never pretended to be one. Like many films of that ilk, it was generally trashed upon by critics back then, in this case for its lack of downright slapstick-laugh-out-loud moments (Carey's salary the true reason for the furore) although they also criticized "Ace Ventura: when natures call" for being completely empty, the previous year. Oh well, sometimes one can never win...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    it is a matter of comedic taste
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobrobertsst
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In order to rate this movie you must have a good sense of what comedy consists. Most people have a sense of humor that involves the lameness of Napoleon Dynamite and it's completely humorless involvement with society. Ergo if you are a Napoleon Dynamite fan please do not rate any comedy other than your favorite. If I were a sociopath then I should not rate anything involving emotions. You should not rate or judge anything you do not understand. Therefore if you are a Napoleon Dynamite fan it is very obvious you do not have a comedic sense of art. If you do enjoy Woody Allen and Napoleon Dynamite then perhaps you have a split personality. (I am a Woody Allen fan ;-) There is only 1 comedy that has won the Best Picture award (yes it was Woody Allen). This fact illuminates the fact that people do not understand comedy, the reason for this being that comedy does not have a universal appeal. Humor is much more unique and personal than drama.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey is top of his class.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guitarmasta-242-110720
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always been a Carrey fan, so when I stumbled upon this while DVD hunting at a local video store, naturally I bought it. I was not disappointed. Jim Carrey was made for the role of Chip Douglas. His acting in this movie is all but un-paralleled. He really shows us what he is capable of in the acting department. If Jim Carrey can be said to be one of those actors where you either love him or hate him, then the same can be said for this movie. It has a very particular type of often quite dark humor in it, which doesn't appeal to a lot of people, but in which Carrey thrives. If you didn't like this movie, give it another watch. You might change your mind. This movie is a must for any Carrey fan, or any fan of good 90's comedy. Ben Stiller does a fantastic job directing, and the rest of the cast supports Carrey's role brilliantly. 10/10 (Also, I heard that the Chip Douglas role wasn't originally intended for Carrey, but after watching it, can you honestly picture anyone else executing it so damn well??)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey ruins yet another movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scohcon
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's two reasons I watched this movie, or rather suffered through it. One was was because I'm a fan of Matthew Broderick. And two is because it was on TV and I didn't have to pay to see it. And even though I've always been repulsed by anything Jim Carrey has done, I thought maybe I'd be able to bear it. This movie made me realize that Jim Carrey is so pathetically untalented and annoying that he could ruin any movie. And like all of his other movies, he manages to ruin this one as well. He's like a retarded version of Jerry Lewis. Don't get me wrong, I'm a huge fan of Lewis, who was an original, but a bad fake imitation of Lewis with brain damage with a lame accent that can't act... not so much. Truth is, if one could assemble the greatest director, the best actors, the best screen writers, and the best special effects technicians that ever lived to make a movie with an unlimited budget, if you were to add Jim Carrey in the mix, he would spoil it all and insure the film would be capable of inducing vomiting. After all, that's his only "talent".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misunderstood. Carrey's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bradleyluke79
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd like to start off by saying that The Cable Guy is disliked by a lot of people. This would explain it's low rating. But don't be thrown off by that. The Cable Guy is a black comedy. So, some people will be unsettled by the plot of the movie. "Chip" is a disturbed Cable Guy, raised on television, who only wants a friend. Steve is a designer, recently kicked out of his girlfriend's apartment. Moving into his new apartment, his friend Rick tells him to bribe the cable guy, to get illegal cable. But the cable guy, "Chip" sees this is an invitation to be best buds. Steve, trying to be nice fakes an interest in his work, but this just brings "Chip" closer and closer to him. This movie is a misunderstood classic. And in my opinion it's Jim Carrey's best movie. It's a nice change for Carrey's character, having him play the psychotic two faced Cable Guy. With Steve(Matthew Brodrick) in the most awkward of situations by the hilarious Cable Guy(Jim Carrey) this movie should bring you laughs and enjoyment. It does get progressively dark as the film goes on but it's nothing major. The film also has many, many film and T.V. references that you'll enjoy along the way. In my opinion, The Cable Guy is the motion picture version of mar-mite. You will ever love it or hate it. And I love it. A must watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Necessary protest vote
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wouldn't normally have left a review for this but stumbled on the shockingly low mark and was compelled to write something! What a sick joke this movie has such a low rating on IMDb. I have a sneaking suspicion it's down to the pathological Jim Carrey haters rather than based on the movie's merits. I'm giving it a star more than I would have otherwise as a protest vote. I guess if a particular person in a movie annoys you that much then it's going to preclude it from being a good movie for you, *but surely* you can take a step back, and say something like "ah now wait a minute, that's just my personal dislike for an individual and it wouldn't really be fair to transfer that dislike onto any collective effort they happened to be a part of". What about the poor writer, director, other actors and the crew? I know I've made a big assumption there and it's possible people just didn't find it funny. I find that so hard to believe though - I've seen *a hell of a lot* of comedies over the last 40 years, and find the vast majority made from 1990 onwards to be safe, lazy and badly-written, or more recently trying to be zany or alternative and failing miserably. However I found this surprisingly well-written, well-made and brilliantly-acted(comedy acting, not Oliver/Gielgud!) and all-round compelling and bloody hilarious. I think it's a great idea - the central character's minor misdemeanour at the start results in immediate payback in the form of a demented psychopath taking over his life. It gets pretty dark in a couple of places which somehow makes the humour work better. Whatever you think of Jim Carrey, the range of stuff he pulls off on screen is incredible. Like a reanimated old Vaudevillian on PCP. I found him totally convincing as the lonely Walter Mitty/psycho who really just needs a friend and uses what he knows best to make it happen. Broderick is a born fall guy and effortlessly provides the anything-for-a-quiet-life victim, ill-equipped to halt the psycho's hostile takeover of his life. There's also a micro-element of social comment on using people, friendship, the abuse of power, and the influence TV can have on a person's life. Tutt and scoff all you want at that, but can you honestly say there's even that much depth in any other comedies made now? So for anybody who doesn't hate Jim Carrey, please don't listen to all the negative reviews and give this one a chance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It isn't Jim Carrey's best movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew- T-3055
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film which doesn't do justice to Jim Carrey as one of Hollywood's funniest actors. It is another one of his films with many voices and faces being pulled by his character, but this film is different and it just doesn't work. The film follows The Cable Guy who tries to become his latest clients new best friend. He is Steven M. Kovacs (played by Matthew Broderick). But Steven just wants his cable fixed and then to get on with his life. But they become "friends" despite Broderick being a bit awkward and unsure around him. Yet this awkward bond I feel is returned by Carrey's character who is just making annoying over the top jokes which just didn't work in this scenario. This is sad as if it was a mystery or a bit more dramatic like some of his other films then it could've had great potential. I just don't think it works. I feel the best part of the film comes from Jack Black's role as Rick who is Steven's friend, the role is relatively small yet I think it's portrayed well. If the film had extended his role a bit more, with a bit more depth I think that would've improved the film. I would say this is worst film I've seen Jim Carrey in. The premise of the film is good but the acting wasn't and I felt the storyline should have had a bit more depth in places, the film had a lot of potential though.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Must Watch If You Love Jim Carrey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nirbhay Pandey
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We want to like Jim Carrey. A movie that makes us dislike him is a strategic mistake. The opening scenes of "The Cable Guy" are promising; Carrey seems to be playing a variation on his usual hyperkinetic goofball. Then our reaction grows more puzzled: This is supposed to be fun, right? By the end, the movie has declared itself as a black comedy about one very deeply troubled cable guy. The plot centers around a character named Steven (Matthew Broderick), who has just been turned down for marriage by his girlfriend Robin (Leslie Mann). He moves into a bachelor pad and calls for cable service, and Chip Douglas (Carrey) comes pounding on his door (making sure, of course, to arrive very late and while Steven is in the shower). The cable guy is a manic nerd with a lisp and an under slung jaw. He wants to be Steven's friend. He has a lot of trouble pronouncing certain words. "My brother is a speech therapist," Steven says helpfully. The cable guy says, "Tho?" Soon the cable guy has insinuated himself into Steven's life and is offering detailed advice about life (which he reveals he has learned that morning from the summation at the end of a Jerry Springer program). His strategy for getting Robin to come back: Watch "Sleepless in Seattle" with her. Women are suckers for it. Many of these strategies works, and we're reminded of the relationship in the British comedy classic "School for Scoundrels" (which Carrey should remake) in which a cad teaches one-upmanship to a loser. But soon the movie drifts into murkier waters. The cable guy has an unhealthy need to be Steven's friend, and he pursues that goal with behavior designed to scare anyone. He's a stalker. He's obnoxious and peculiar and inappropriate and relentless, and we start disliking him, and that's when the movie jumps the rails. The director, Ben Stiller ("Reality Bites"), throws in a lot of gratuitous but funny asides; there's a running gag about a CourtTV trial involving Hollywood twins whose relationship ends in murder. And in-jokes, as when the cable guy covers his face with fried chicken skin to imitate a scene from "Silence of the Lambs" (the actor Charles Napier, whose face was borrowed by Hannibal Lecter in "Lambs," turns up here as a cop). And there's a fake TV commercial showing Eric Roberts plays a dual role in "Brother, Sweet Brother," the docudrama based on the Hollywood trial. Maybe it would have worked better if the cable guy had become a real friend to Steven, devising love strategies and Machiavellian schemes to win back Robin and thwart her other suitors. As it is, the movie goes in one direction and the cable guy goes in another, and by the end we aren't really looking forward to seeing Jim Carrey reappear on the screen. Note to the producers: There's an old showbiz saying that "satire is what closes on Saturday night." To which could be added another: "Black comedy is not what you pay someone $20 million to-do." ******* BUT STILL MUST WATCH IF YOU LOVE JIM CARREY *******
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible. Really terrible.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesguerin
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am very disappointed that I stayed for the duration of this film. It really is awful, in my opinion. I like stupid humour, when it's done properly like Monty Python or Aeroplane. This was just poor. Jim Carrey plays a psychotic yet supposedly lovable former cable guy. The purpose of his character seems to be more focused on saying random "jokes" than advancing the plot in any way. He starts the film as a stalker and does not develop. Matthew Broderick is also annoyingly bad in places, though not nearly to the same extent. This film failed to make me actually laugh once, although I did manage a smirk a few times. If you like smart dumb comedies, this isn't for you. If you like laughing at anything said in a funny voice, prepare to be entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great fun!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lucas_carvalhaes
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you like Jim Carrey and strong emotions this is definitely for you! I rated 10 because few movies made me laugh so hard, be afraid, be really scared, be lost, feel strange stuff, see awesome scenes in such a short period of time. I don't even know how to describe the feelings this movie gets you... Just watch with friends willing to have fun and you have a great time! Jim Carrey acts so Carrey in this movie even the other actors couldn't resist... so many awesome faces, so much bizarre and yet a great dramatic story. The plot isn't the best and Ben stiller does absolutely nothing during the movie. He just appears as a lesser supporting actor. No, seriously, focus on Carrey's acting and you will have a real roller coaster ride of craziness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Misunderstood half-thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cedde6
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Kovacks (Matthew Broderick), a designer who just separated from his girlfriend, has cable installed to his new apartment. Enters the quirky and slightly deranged cable guy (Jim Carey) whom then never exits... A rather simple plot which became in 1996 a very odd and yet pleasurable film indeed. Although following a pretty straight forward structure, the script provides enough background to Jim Carey's character to make of him a lot more than just a run-of-the-mill weirdo while Matthew Broderick aptly counterbalance the excessive title role by a fair performance of the without-a-glitch nice guy of the piece. The constant referencing to TV culture also makes it an entertaining and strangely enough somewhat nostalgic experience. It is quite obvious that a fair amount of improvisation was incorporated to the piece to sometimes great effect (the "Silence of the Lamb" episode anyone?) which I suppose is probably the most effective way to work with someone such as Jim Carey. Curiously however, the main asset of the film also becomes at some point its main shortcoming. This was to Jim Carey what 1994's "The Good Son" was to Macauley Culkin: a departure from their comedic roots to more darker territories, but as opposed to Joseph Ruben's thriller, "The Cable Guy" seems to always hesitate to boldly go as far as its story would allow it to. In Jim Carey's work this is certainly darker than anything he had done up to that point but if this was also supposed to be a thriller then it felt a little bland, the star's antics sometimes overshadowing the actual depth of the story. Still, don't let this put you off for "The Cable Guy", playfully directed by Ben Stiller, is one of these misunderstood films that are really worth watching for its clever take on the media in general and the hidden harm you find it does to people's mind once stripped off the apparent sense of comfort it is supposed to bring. It might have been done a little too light-heartedly maybe but at least it was done at all. And decently done too. This is a more serious film than it looks at first glance and that alone makes it an interesting one. No masterpiece mind you, but then again, it never pretended to be one. Like many films of that ilk, it was generally trashed upon by critics back then, in this case for its lack of downright slapstick-laugh-out-loud moments (Carey's salary the true reason for the furore) although they also criticized "Ace Ventura: when natures call" for being completely empty, the previous year. Oh well, sometimes one can never win...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    it is a matter of comedic taste
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobrobertsst
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In order to rate this movie you must have a good sense of what comedy consists. Most people have a sense of humor that involves the lameness of Napoleon Dynamite and it's completely humorless involvement with society. Ergo if you are a Napoleon Dynamite fan please do not rate any comedy other than your favorite. If I were a sociopath then I should not rate anything involving emotions. You should not rate or judge anything you do not understand. Therefore if you are a Napoleon Dynamite fan it is very obvious you do not have a comedic sense of art. If you do enjoy Woody Allen and Napoleon Dynamite then perhaps you have a split personality. (I am a Woody Allen fan ;-) There is only 1 comedy that has won the Best Picture award (yes it was Woody Allen). This fact illuminates the fact that people do not understand comedy, the reason for this being that comedy does not have a universal appeal. Humor is much more unique and personal than drama.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey is top of his class.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guitarmasta-242-110720
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always been a Carrey fan, so when I stumbled upon this while DVD hunting at a local video store, naturally I bought it. I was not disappointed. Jim Carrey was made for the role of Chip Douglas. His acting in this movie is all but un-paralleled. He really shows us what he is capable of in the acting department. If Jim Carrey can be said to be one of those actors where you either love him or hate him, then the same can be said for this movie. It has a very particular type of often quite dark humor in it, which doesn't appeal to a lot of people, but in which Carrey thrives. If you didn't like this movie, give it another watch. You might change your mind. This movie is a must for any Carrey fan, or any fan of good 90's comedy. Ben Stiller does a fantastic job directing, and the rest of the cast supports Carrey's role brilliantly. 10/10 (Also, I heard that the Chip Douglas role wasn't originally intended for Carrey, but after watching it, can you honestly picture anyone else executing it so damn well??)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
