<filme>
 <id>
  1224
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0111094
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Pancada
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The story of a baseball scout who discovers a talented but troubled baseball player.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Al Percolo is a major league baseball scout sent to scout in Mexico as a punishment. However, he eventually stumbles across Steve Nebraska, a young American who can pitch AND hit better than anyone else can do either. He signs Steve and returns home in glory. It soon becomes obvious, though, that Steve is immature and possibly unstable, and Al turns to psychiatrist Doctor H. Aaron, whom he picks for her name, for help.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sport
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   baseball
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sports team
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   psychoanalysis
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   baseball movie
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   based on article
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Michael Ritchie
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Roger Angell
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Andrew Bergman
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Albert Brooks
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Brendan Fraser
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Dianne Wiest
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Two films for the price of one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tony Adam (aadamtx@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After seeing THE SCOUT again on TV, I've come to accept that the main problem with the film is that it's actually two completely different films smashed together. On the one hand you've got the comedy surrounding Albert Brooks and his hunt for that one baseball player who will save his scouting career. As one of our great comic screen writers, Brooks delivers some witty lines now and then, particularly in the first part of the film. However, the second film is a half-written drama dealing with the emotional/mental problems of Steve Nebraska, Brendan Frasier's character. There's next to know explanation and/or resolution to his emotional storyline, and although the wonderful Diane Wiest as his psychiatrist is on the team, she barely makes it to the warm-up spot and pretty much fades out without much ado. Screenwriter Brooks keeps tossing tantalizing hints into Frasier's emotional mix - the laundry concerns, for example -- but then does nothing with them. By the last inning, THE SCOUT can't decide whether it's FEAR STRIKES OUT or MAJOR LEAGUE.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Albert Brooks at his best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evannaturally
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is really an underrated gem in its own way. It's important to mention that this movie was released during the infamous baseball strike and unfortunately not many people wanted to go see a movie about baseball because they were so upset with the way things were being handled. It's really too bad because this is a very good movie. The best thing about this movie is the way director/star Albert Brooks blends his own unique style of humor with a deep underlying current of the father/son relationship and how psychological problems can effect and athlete's performance. There are some very big laughs as well as many scenes that are funny in an Albert Brooks sort of way; scenes that make you smile and chuckle rather than belly laugh. The best crafted scenes in the film however come from the way Steve Nebraska (Fraser) looks up to Al (Brooks) as the father figure he never had. Some of these scenes are very emotional and deeply touching as well. The only thing I didn't love about the movie is the ending. It's a little too neat and tidy for my taste, but let's face it Brooks is trying to make a funny and touching movie that makes you happy and uplifted when its over, and for that I say a good well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What a Fun Movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vegasniceguy
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you ever had dreams of being a big-league star, in any sport, then you have to watch this flick. It's classic Albert Brooks. But, it is like watching a Rocky comedy. Tears come to my eyes evewn after the 10th viewing. Fraser is great. You don't need to be a sports fan to like the movie, it is good regardless. As a baseball fan, it was nice seeing Yankee Stadium. I went there in the last year of the original stadium. It was an historical stadium. Though, I hated paying $9 for a beer, but it was nice being able to take the subway to get there. Other baseball flicks that are good are "It Happens Every Spring" and naturally, "Bang the Drum Slowly".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ridiculously bad movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bravesfan35
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is definitely one of the worst sports movies of all-time. The writers made little to no effort in creating a decent plot. Albert Brooks plays a scout for the New York Yankees who thinks he finds the next great pitcher, but the guy can't handle pitching in front of large crowds and ends up puking on the mound. When Brooks travels down to Mexico, he discovers a phenom who is a fan favorite named Steve Nebraska (played by Brendan Fraser). When he tries to convince the Yankees GM that he's found an outstanding pitcher, he's told he isn't bringing anyone up and ends up getting fired. I'm a huge baseball fan, but I found this movie appalling, especially near the end when Nebraska pitches in a World Series game. He throws 81 pitches, all strikes, and no hitter even makes contact. Who ends up with the only run of the game? Nebraska, of course, with a home run. Imagine that. They obviously thought no one would see the flaws in that game. For one thing, being in an American League park, they would be using a DH. The pitcher would not be hitting. Another, how did he end up with only 1 at-bat the whole game if he pitched the whole game? This movie was very predictable and, therefore, very boring. I would not recommend this movie to my worst enemy. I wonder if even Fraser looks back on this movie and wonders why he made the mistake of agreeing to do it. It's not Fraser's fault though. No matter who was picked to star in this movie, it would have been bad simply because of the plot. I found Little Big League to be more realistic than this and that was about a little kid managing a major league team.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Thin comedy has silly plot saved by some amusing moments...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Doyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    BRENDAN FRASER seems to specialize in playing dumb--or at least that's the impression I had after watching him emote as a child-like baseball player who happens to have a great pitching arm in THE SCOUT. He does get laughs with his dumb act, so I suppose that's why he was chosen for this particular role. But most of the laughs come from the fact that ALBERT BROOKS is his co-star, a man who can say a funny line without ever giving a hint that he thinks it's funny. And sometimes, the result is hilarious--particularly in the "knife" scene in which Brooks is trying to hide all his kitchen knives from Fraser who "wants to cut something". None of the humor is particularly subtle, but DIANNE WIEST is a welcome addition as Dr. Aarons, the psychiatrist who determines that Fraser might have his dangerous moments after subjecting him to a series of tests with photos. But the baseball scenes at the finish are too over-the-top, straining credulity to the limits. The Tony Bennett nightclub sequence is also guaranteed to have you squirming in discomfort as Fraser sings an off-key version of "I Left My Heart in San Francisco", much to Bennett's chagrin. Summing up: With a wittier script and a different approach, could have been a very winning comedy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst sports movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mpionus
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The acting wasn't bad but they completely butchered any semblance of reality with regards to baseball. Let's just recap all that was wrong just with the "final game" (Game 1 of the World Series) 1) A player can't make his first appearance in the World Series--he'd have to be on roster before then 2) Since Steve Nebraska was playing in Yankee stadium, the DH rule was in effect. Meaning he couldn't have batted. 3) In order for Nebraska to have used his 81st pitch to strike out Ozzie Smith, that means that the Cardinals put "The Wizard" batting 9th in the order. Yeah, right. 4) Before the game, Costas makes some comment about how "many are predicting a perfect game from Steve Nebraska". Seeing as how there have only been 17 perfect games in history, one would highly doubt a 1st ever start would be a perfect game. 5) 81 strikes in a row...nobody even hit a ball? A World Series caliber team can't ONCE key in to a 110 mile per hour fastball to make even accidental contact once? Most idiotic movie regarding baseball of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good enough for me. . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bilro
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was fun watching Brooks do his bit. Given most movies that I've seen on the TV as of late, to include the offerings on Pay per View, HBO and Starz, this one was a welcome change. I've read some reviews that say the ending was less than acceptable. Well, such is life. A story doesn't have to have a transcendental message to be enjoyed. For those who think that's essential, I suggest they watch the movie up to the final fifteen minutes, turn off the TV and make up their own ending. As for me, I can live with it just the way it was. One clear measure that I have that it was a movie worth watching? Well, my wife actually stayed awake through most of it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Fraser Film For the Dust Bin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do they let Brendan Fraser keep on making movies? He's not funny, he's hideously deformed and his antics get on my nerves like you wouldn't believe. A scout for the Yankees, after finding prospects in the past who "flake out", is sent to Mexico where he finds Steve Nebraska (Fraser), the greatest ball player that ever lived. But after a mandatory psych exam, Nebraska begins to "flake out", too. The general plot is decent, and the idea of a perfect ballplayer is a fun one (though hardly original, especially after I just watched "The Natural"). But Fraser is not a likable character for me, and I was really hoping he would be hit by a bus. The film is thoroughly predictable with no twists or surprises at all, and an ending that still leaves some key issues unexplained (again like "The Natural" it ends rather abruptly). I can't say what they issues are at the risk of writing spoilers, although I don't know how you can spoil a film this simple. In the beginning of the film, the scout brings in Michael Rapaport as his star player (before Rapaport flakes out). Now, if he had brought in Fraser and then later on had Rapaport playing Fraser's part, this film might have been one of the better baseball movies ever made. But whoever did the casting clearly has no idea that Fraser is utterly worthless as an actor. A few cheap laughs in "Bedazzled" and "Encino Man" do not a great comedian make.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some good one-liners in asinine comic set-up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Albert Brooks co-wrote and stars in this sometimes-bright but terribly unsubtle comedy about a talent scout for the New York Yankees who loses his reputation after getting a skittish college Freshman signed to the team (the Yankees apparently scheduled the kid to pitch in a televised game without any training or pre-game publicity whatsoever, so don't they get what they deserve?); Brooks is banished to South Central Mexico to find talent, and yet when he comes up with another promising pitcher, he's fired over the telephone (in one of those excruciating sitcom developments the movie occasionally falls prey to). The new pitcher (Brendan Fraser, still in "Encino Man" mode) is a child in a young man's body, thereby linking the scout and the player on an emotionally-needy basis (not solid ground for laugh-out-loud comedy). Brooks as an actor is very ingratiating--he always has been--but this material, despite some very amusing one-liners, is stale, highly concocted, and immature. Many real-life sports luminaries appear in cameos...perhaps they should have been allowed to strengthen the script. ** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Damn Yankees!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jotix100
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Poor Al Percolo, he is a man that has brought shame to the Yankees by recommending prospects to the team that don't work out. The team's general manager, Ron Wilson, wants to punish him by sending him deep into Mexico to scout new talent. When Al sees Steven Nebraska pitch in a Mexican league ball game, he realizes this is going to be his redemption. Not only is he a great pitcher, but can that man belt home runs out of the ball park! As Al stages a test to show the different major league teams what Steve can do, Steve Nebraska proves to be the man they all have been waiting for. He is signed for an awful lot of money, but he must pass a sanity test in order to join the team. No sweat! Al gets the name of a psychiatrist out of the Yellow Pages, who turns out to be Al's worst nightmare. Dr. Aaron discovers Steve is an abused child that has a lot to deal with. Michael Ritchie directed this funny comedy. Albert Brooks contributed to the screen play he co-wrote with Andrew Bregman and Monica Johnson. Mr. Brooks plays Al Percolo, the scout of the title with his usual style that makes him one of the best actors working in comedies these days. Brendan Fraser is Steve Nebraska, a complex man who loves to play baseball, but has too many unresolved issues to deal with. The amazing Dianne Wiest plays Dr. Aaron, who injects a shot of reality into the movie. There are some funny moments in the film. One of the best involves Tony Bennett, who is performing in a night club where Steve and Al have been invited by the Yankee management. When Tony Bennett introduces young Steve Nebraska as the next Yankee star, the young man takes a bout and decides to lead the house in a rendition of "I Left my Heart in San Francisco". The other great moment occurs when Mr. Bennett shows up to sing the National Anthem at the start of a World Series game and he sees Steve, and he asks him is he is going to have the whole stadium sing. There have been other great baseball pictures. This one doesn't try to be one of them. It's just a light movie done for laughs and the mistake most viewers make is to expect it to be what it never intended to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Two films for the price of one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tony Adam (aadamtx@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After seeing THE SCOUT again on TV, I've come to accept that the main problem with the film is that it's actually two completely different films smashed together. On the one hand you've got the comedy surrounding Albert Brooks and his hunt for that one baseball player who will save his scouting career. As one of our great comic screen writers, Brooks delivers some witty lines now and then, particularly in the first part of the film. However, the second film is a half-written drama dealing with the emotional/mental problems of Steve Nebraska, Brendan Frasier's character. There's next to know explanation and/or resolution to his emotional storyline, and although the wonderful Diane Wiest as his psychiatrist is on the team, she barely makes it to the warm-up spot and pretty much fades out without much ado. Screenwriter Brooks keeps tossing tantalizing hints into Frasier's emotional mix - the laundry concerns, for example -- but then does nothing with them. By the last inning, THE SCOUT can't decide whether it's FEAR STRIKES OUT or MAJOR LEAGUE.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Albert Brooks at his best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evannaturally
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is really an underrated gem in its own way. It's important to mention that this movie was released during the infamous baseball strike and unfortunately not many people wanted to go see a movie about baseball because they were so upset with the way things were being handled. It's really too bad because this is a very good movie. The best thing about this movie is the way director/star Albert Brooks blends his own unique style of humor with a deep underlying current of the father/son relationship and how psychological problems can effect and athlete's performance. There are some very big laughs as well as many scenes that are funny in an Albert Brooks sort of way; scenes that make you smile and chuckle rather than belly laugh. The best crafted scenes in the film however come from the way Steve Nebraska (Fraser) looks up to Al (Brooks) as the father figure he never had. Some of these scenes are very emotional and deeply touching as well. The only thing I didn't love about the movie is the ending. It's a little too neat and tidy for my taste, but let's face it Brooks is trying to make a funny and touching movie that makes you happy and uplifted when its over, and for that I say a good well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What a Fun Movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vegasniceguy
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you ever had dreams of being a big-league star, in any sport, then you have to watch this flick. It's classic Albert Brooks. But, it is like watching a Rocky comedy. Tears come to my eyes evewn after the 10th viewing. Fraser is great. You don't need to be a sports fan to like the movie, it is good regardless. As a baseball fan, it was nice seeing Yankee Stadium. I went there in the last year of the original stadium. It was an historical stadium. Though, I hated paying $9 for a beer, but it was nice being able to take the subway to get there. Other baseball flicks that are good are "It Happens Every Spring" and naturally, "Bang the Drum Slowly".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ridiculously bad movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bravesfan35
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is definitely one of the worst sports movies of all-time. The writers made little to no effort in creating a decent plot. Albert Brooks plays a scout for the New York Yankees who thinks he finds the next great pitcher, but the guy can't handle pitching in front of large crowds and ends up puking on the mound. When Brooks travels down to Mexico, he discovers a phenom who is a fan favorite named Steve Nebraska (played by Brendan Fraser). When he tries to convince the Yankees GM that he's found an outstanding pitcher, he's told he isn't bringing anyone up and ends up getting fired. I'm a huge baseball fan, but I found this movie appalling, especially near the end when Nebraska pitches in a World Series game. He throws 81 pitches, all strikes, and no hitter even makes contact. Who ends up with the only run of the game? Nebraska, of course, with a home run. Imagine that. They obviously thought no one would see the flaws in that game. For one thing, being in an American League park, they would be using a DH. The pitcher would not be hitting. Another, how did he end up with only 1 at-bat the whole game if he pitched the whole game? This movie was very predictable and, therefore, very boring. I would not recommend this movie to my worst enemy. I wonder if even Fraser looks back on this movie and wonders why he made the mistake of agreeing to do it. It's not Fraser's fault though. No matter who was picked to star in this movie, it would have been bad simply because of the plot. I found Little Big League to be more realistic than this and that was about a little kid managing a major league team.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Thin comedy has silly plot saved by some amusing moments...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Doyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    BRENDAN FRASER seems to specialize in playing dumb--or at least that's the impression I had after watching him emote as a child-like baseball player who happens to have a great pitching arm in THE SCOUT. He does get laughs with his dumb act, so I suppose that's why he was chosen for this particular role. But most of the laughs come from the fact that ALBERT BROOKS is his co-star, a man who can say a funny line without ever giving a hint that he thinks it's funny. And sometimes, the result is hilarious--particularly in the "knife" scene in which Brooks is trying to hide all his kitchen knives from Fraser who "wants to cut something". None of the humor is particularly subtle, but DIANNE WIEST is a welcome addition as Dr. Aarons, the psychiatrist who determines that Fraser might have his dangerous moments after subjecting him to a series of tests with photos. But the baseball scenes at the finish are too over-the-top, straining credulity to the limits. The Tony Bennett nightclub sequence is also guaranteed to have you squirming in discomfort as Fraser sings an off-key version of "I Left My Heart in San Francisco", much to Bennett's chagrin. Summing up: With a wittier script and a different approach, could have been a very winning comedy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst sports movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mpionus
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The acting wasn't bad but they completely butchered any semblance of reality with regards to baseball. Let's just recap all that was wrong just with the "final game" (Game 1 of the World Series) 1) A player can't make his first appearance in the World Series--he'd have to be on roster before then 2) Since Steve Nebraska was playing in Yankee stadium, the DH rule was in effect. Meaning he couldn't have batted. 3) In order for Nebraska to have used his 81st pitch to strike out Ozzie Smith, that means that the Cardinals put "The Wizard" batting 9th in the order. Yeah, right. 4) Before the game, Costas makes some comment about how "many are predicting a perfect game from Steve Nebraska". Seeing as how there have only been 17 perfect games in history, one would highly doubt a 1st ever start would be a perfect game. 5) 81 strikes in a row...nobody even hit a ball? A World Series caliber team can't ONCE key in to a 110 mile per hour fastball to make even accidental contact once? Most idiotic movie regarding baseball of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good enough for me. . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bilro
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was fun watching Brooks do his bit. Given most movies that I've seen on the TV as of late, to include the offerings on Pay per View, HBO and Starz, this one was a welcome change. I've read some reviews that say the ending was less than acceptable. Well, such is life. A story doesn't have to have a transcendental message to be enjoyed. For those who think that's essential, I suggest they watch the movie up to the final fifteen minutes, turn off the TV and make up their own ending. As for me, I can live with it just the way it was. One clear measure that I have that it was a movie worth watching? Well, my wife actually stayed awake through most of it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Fraser Film For the Dust Bin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do they let Brendan Fraser keep on making movies? He's not funny, he's hideously deformed and his antics get on my nerves like you wouldn't believe. A scout for the Yankees, after finding prospects in the past who "flake out", is sent to Mexico where he finds Steve Nebraska (Fraser), the greatest ball player that ever lived. But after a mandatory psych exam, Nebraska begins to "flake out", too. The general plot is decent, and the idea of a perfect ballplayer is a fun one (though hardly original, especially after I just watched "The Natural"). But Fraser is not a likable character for me, and I was really hoping he would be hit by a bus. The film is thoroughly predictable with no twists or surprises at all, and an ending that still leaves some key issues unexplained (again like "The Natural" it ends rather abruptly). I can't say what they issues are at the risk of writing spoilers, although I don't know how you can spoil a film this simple. In the beginning of the film, the scout brings in Michael Rapaport as his star player (before Rapaport flakes out). Now, if he had brought in Fraser and then later on had Rapaport playing Fraser's part, this film might have been one of the better baseball movies ever made. But whoever did the casting clearly has no idea that Fraser is utterly worthless as an actor. A few cheap laughs in "Bedazzled" and "Encino Man" do not a great comedian make.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some good one-liners in asinine comic set-up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Albert Brooks co-wrote and stars in this sometimes-bright but terribly unsubtle comedy about a talent scout for the New York Yankees who loses his reputation after getting a skittish college Freshman signed to the team (the Yankees apparently scheduled the kid to pitch in a televised game without any training or pre-game publicity whatsoever, so don't they get what they deserve?); Brooks is banished to South Central Mexico to find talent, and yet when he comes up with another promising pitcher, he's fired over the telephone (in one of those excruciating sitcom developments the movie occasionally falls prey to). The new pitcher (Brendan Fraser, still in "Encino Man" mode) is a child in a young man's body, thereby linking the scout and the player on an emotionally-needy basis (not solid ground for laugh-out-loud comedy). Brooks as an actor is very ingratiating--he always has been--but this material, despite some very amusing one-liners, is stale, highly concocted, and immature. Many real-life sports luminaries appear in cameos...perhaps they should have been allowed to strengthen the script. ** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Damn Yankees!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jotix100
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Poor Al Percolo, he is a man that has brought shame to the Yankees by recommending prospects to the team that don't work out. The team's general manager, Ron Wilson, wants to punish him by sending him deep into Mexico to scout new talent. When Al sees Steven Nebraska pitch in a Mexican league ball game, he realizes this is going to be his redemption. Not only is he a great pitcher, but can that man belt home runs out of the ball park! As Al stages a test to show the different major league teams what Steve can do, Steve Nebraska proves to be the man they all have been waiting for. He is signed for an awful lot of money, but he must pass a sanity test in order to join the team. No sweat! Al gets the name of a psychiatrist out of the Yellow Pages, who turns out to be Al's worst nightmare. Dr. Aaron discovers Steve is an abused child that has a lot to deal with. Michael Ritchie directed this funny comedy. Albert Brooks contributed to the screen play he co-wrote with Andrew Bregman and Monica Johnson. Mr. Brooks plays Al Percolo, the scout of the title with his usual style that makes him one of the best actors working in comedies these days. Brendan Fraser is Steve Nebraska, a complex man who loves to play baseball, but has too many unresolved issues to deal with. The amazing Dianne Wiest plays Dr. Aaron, who injects a shot of reality into the movie. There are some funny moments in the film. One of the best involves Tony Bennett, who is performing in a night club where Steve and Al have been invited by the Yankee management. When Tony Bennett introduces young Steve Nebraska as the next Yankee star, the young man takes a bout and decides to lead the house in a rendition of "I Left my Heart in San Francisco". The other great moment occurs when Mr. Bennett shows up to sing the National Anthem at the start of a World Series game and he sees Steve, and he asks him is he is going to have the whole stadium sing. There have been other great baseball pictures. This one doesn't try to be one of them. It's just a light movie done for laughs and the mistake most viewers make is to expect it to be what it never intended to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Two films for the price of one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tony Adam (aadamtx@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After seeing THE SCOUT again on TV, I've come to accept that the main problem with the film is that it's actually two completely different films smashed together. On the one hand you've got the comedy surrounding Albert Brooks and his hunt for that one baseball player who will save his scouting career. As one of our great comic screen writers, Brooks delivers some witty lines now and then, particularly in the first part of the film. However, the second film is a half-written drama dealing with the emotional/mental problems of Steve Nebraska, Brendan Frasier's character. There's next to know explanation and/or resolution to his emotional storyline, and although the wonderful Diane Wiest as his psychiatrist is on the team, she barely makes it to the warm-up spot and pretty much fades out without much ado. Screenwriter Brooks keeps tossing tantalizing hints into Frasier's emotional mix - the laundry concerns, for example -- but then does nothing with them. By the last inning, THE SCOUT can't decide whether it's FEAR STRIKES OUT or MAJOR LEAGUE.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Albert Brooks at his best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evannaturally
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is really an underrated gem in its own way. It's important to mention that this movie was released during the infamous baseball strike and unfortunately not many people wanted to go see a movie about baseball because they were so upset with the way things were being handled. It's really too bad because this is a very good movie. The best thing about this movie is the way director/star Albert Brooks blends his own unique style of humor with a deep underlying current of the father/son relationship and how psychological problems can effect and athlete's performance. There are some very big laughs as well as many scenes that are funny in an Albert Brooks sort of way; scenes that make you smile and chuckle rather than belly laugh. The best crafted scenes in the film however come from the way Steve Nebraska (Fraser) looks up to Al (Brooks) as the father figure he never had. Some of these scenes are very emotional and deeply touching as well. The only thing I didn't love about the movie is the ending. It's a little too neat and tidy for my taste, but let's face it Brooks is trying to make a funny and touching movie that makes you happy and uplifted when its over, and for that I say a good well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What a Fun Movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vegasniceguy
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you ever had dreams of being a big-league star, in any sport, then you have to watch this flick. It's classic Albert Brooks. But, it is like watching a Rocky comedy. Tears come to my eyes evewn after the 10th viewing. Fraser is great. You don't need to be a sports fan to like the movie, it is good regardless. As a baseball fan, it was nice seeing Yankee Stadium. I went there in the last year of the original stadium. It was an historical stadium. Though, I hated paying $9 for a beer, but it was nice being able to take the subway to get there. Other baseball flicks that are good are "It Happens Every Spring" and naturally, "Bang the Drum Slowly".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ridiculously bad movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bravesfan35
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is definitely one of the worst sports movies of all-time. The writers made little to no effort in creating a decent plot. Albert Brooks plays a scout for the New York Yankees who thinks he finds the next great pitcher, but the guy can't handle pitching in front of large crowds and ends up puking on the mound. When Brooks travels down to Mexico, he discovers a phenom who is a fan favorite named Steve Nebraska (played by Brendan Fraser). When he tries to convince the Yankees GM that he's found an outstanding pitcher, he's told he isn't bringing anyone up and ends up getting fired. I'm a huge baseball fan, but I found this movie appalling, especially near the end when Nebraska pitches in a World Series game. He throws 81 pitches, all strikes, and no hitter even makes contact. Who ends up with the only run of the game? Nebraska, of course, with a home run. Imagine that. They obviously thought no one would see the flaws in that game. For one thing, being in an American League park, they would be using a DH. The pitcher would not be hitting. Another, how did he end up with only 1 at-bat the whole game if he pitched the whole game? This movie was very predictable and, therefore, very boring. I would not recommend this movie to my worst enemy. I wonder if even Fraser looks back on this movie and wonders why he made the mistake of agreeing to do it. It's not Fraser's fault though. No matter who was picked to star in this movie, it would have been bad simply because of the plot. I found Little Big League to be more realistic than this and that was about a little kid managing a major league team.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Thin comedy has silly plot saved by some amusing moments...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Doyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    BRENDAN FRASER seems to specialize in playing dumb--or at least that's the impression I had after watching him emote as a child-like baseball player who happens to have a great pitching arm in THE SCOUT. He does get laughs with his dumb act, so I suppose that's why he was chosen for this particular role. But most of the laughs come from the fact that ALBERT BROOKS is his co-star, a man who can say a funny line without ever giving a hint that he thinks it's funny. And sometimes, the result is hilarious--particularly in the "knife" scene in which Brooks is trying to hide all his kitchen knives from Fraser who "wants to cut something". None of the humor is particularly subtle, but DIANNE WIEST is a welcome addition as Dr. Aarons, the psychiatrist who determines that Fraser might have his dangerous moments after subjecting him to a series of tests with photos. But the baseball scenes at the finish are too over-the-top, straining credulity to the limits. The Tony Bennett nightclub sequence is also guaranteed to have you squirming in discomfort as Fraser sings an off-key version of "I Left My Heart in San Francisco", much to Bennett's chagrin. Summing up: With a wittier script and a different approach, could have been a very winning comedy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst sports movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mpionus
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The acting wasn't bad but they completely butchered any semblance of reality with regards to baseball. Let's just recap all that was wrong just with the "final game" (Game 1 of the World Series) 1) A player can't make his first appearance in the World Series--he'd have to be on roster before then 2) Since Steve Nebraska was playing in Yankee stadium, the DH rule was in effect. Meaning he couldn't have batted. 3) In order for Nebraska to have used his 81st pitch to strike out Ozzie Smith, that means that the Cardinals put "The Wizard" batting 9th in the order. Yeah, right. 4) Before the game, Costas makes some comment about how "many are predicting a perfect game from Steve Nebraska". Seeing as how there have only been 17 perfect games in history, one would highly doubt a 1st ever start would be a perfect game. 5) 81 strikes in a row...nobody even hit a ball? A World Series caliber team can't ONCE key in to a 110 mile per hour fastball to make even accidental contact once? Most idiotic movie regarding baseball of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good enough for me. . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bilro
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was fun watching Brooks do his bit. Given most movies that I've seen on the TV as of late, to include the offerings on Pay per View, HBO and Starz, this one was a welcome change. I've read some reviews that say the ending was less than acceptable. Well, such is life. A story doesn't have to have a transcendental message to be enjoyed. For those who think that's essential, I suggest they watch the movie up to the final fifteen minutes, turn off the TV and make up their own ending. As for me, I can live with it just the way it was. One clear measure that I have that it was a movie worth watching? Well, my wife actually stayed awake through most of it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Fraser Film For the Dust Bin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do they let Brendan Fraser keep on making movies? He's not funny, he's hideously deformed and his antics get on my nerves like you wouldn't believe. A scout for the Yankees, after finding prospects in the past who "flake out", is sent to Mexico where he finds Steve Nebraska (Fraser), the greatest ball player that ever lived. But after a mandatory psych exam, Nebraska begins to "flake out", too. The general plot is decent, and the idea of a perfect ballplayer is a fun one (though hardly original, especially after I just watched "The Natural"). But Fraser is not a likable character for me, and I was really hoping he would be hit by a bus. The film is thoroughly predictable with no twists or surprises at all, and an ending that still leaves some key issues unexplained (again like "The Natural" it ends rather abruptly). I can't say what they issues are at the risk of writing spoilers, although I don't know how you can spoil a film this simple. In the beginning of the film, the scout brings in Michael Rapaport as his star player (before Rapaport flakes out). Now, if he had brought in Fraser and then later on had Rapaport playing Fraser's part, this film might have been one of the better baseball movies ever made. But whoever did the casting clearly has no idea that Fraser is utterly worthless as an actor. A few cheap laughs in "Bedazzled" and "Encino Man" do not a great comedian make.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some good one-liners in asinine comic set-up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Albert Brooks co-wrote and stars in this sometimes-bright but terribly unsubtle comedy about a talent scout for the New York Yankees who loses his reputation after getting a skittish college Freshman signed to the team (the Yankees apparently scheduled the kid to pitch in a televised game without any training or pre-game publicity whatsoever, so don't they get what they deserve?); Brooks is banished to South Central Mexico to find talent, and yet when he comes up with another promising pitcher, he's fired over the telephone (in one of those excruciating sitcom developments the movie occasionally falls prey to). The new pitcher (Brendan Fraser, still in "Encino Man" mode) is a child in a young man's body, thereby linking the scout and the player on an emotionally-needy basis (not solid ground for laugh-out-loud comedy). Brooks as an actor is very ingratiating--he always has been--but this material, despite some very amusing one-liners, is stale, highly concocted, and immature. Many real-life sports luminaries appear in cameos...perhaps they should have been allowed to strengthen the script. ** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Damn Yankees!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jotix100
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Poor Al Percolo, he is a man that has brought shame to the Yankees by recommending prospects to the team that don't work out. The team's general manager, Ron Wilson, wants to punish him by sending him deep into Mexico to scout new talent. When Al sees Steven Nebraska pitch in a Mexican league ball game, he realizes this is going to be his redemption. Not only is he a great pitcher, but can that man belt home runs out of the ball park! As Al stages a test to show the different major league teams what Steve can do, Steve Nebraska proves to be the man they all have been waiting for. He is signed for an awful lot of money, but he must pass a sanity test in order to join the team. No sweat! Al gets the name of a psychiatrist out of the Yellow Pages, who turns out to be Al's worst nightmare. Dr. Aaron discovers Steve is an abused child that has a lot to deal with. Michael Ritchie directed this funny comedy. Albert Brooks contributed to the screen play he co-wrote with Andrew Bregman and Monica Johnson. Mr. Brooks plays Al Percolo, the scout of the title with his usual style that makes him one of the best actors working in comedies these days. Brendan Fraser is Steve Nebraska, a complex man who loves to play baseball, but has too many unresolved issues to deal with. The amazing Dianne Wiest plays Dr. Aaron, who injects a shot of reality into the movie. There are some funny moments in the film. One of the best involves Tony Bennett, who is performing in a night club where Steve and Al have been invited by the Yankee management. When Tony Bennett introduces young Steve Nebraska as the next Yankee star, the young man takes a bout and decides to lead the house in a rendition of "I Left my Heart in San Francisco". The other great moment occurs when Mr. Bennett shows up to sing the National Anthem at the start of a World Series game and he sees Steve, and he asks him is he is going to have the whole stadium sing. There have been other great baseball pictures. This one doesn't try to be one of them. It's just a light movie done for laughs and the mistake most viewers make is to expect it to be what it never intended to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Two films for the price of one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tony Adam (aadamtx@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After seeing THE SCOUT again on TV, I've come to accept that the main problem with the film is that it's actually two completely different films smashed together. On the one hand you've got the comedy surrounding Albert Brooks and his hunt for that one baseball player who will save his scouting career. As one of our great comic screen writers, Brooks delivers some witty lines now and then, particularly in the first part of the film. However, the second film is a half-written drama dealing with the emotional/mental problems of Steve Nebraska, Brendan Frasier's character. There's next to know explanation and/or resolution to his emotional storyline, and although the wonderful Diane Wiest as his psychiatrist is on the team, she barely makes it to the warm-up spot and pretty much fades out without much ado. Screenwriter Brooks keeps tossing tantalizing hints into Frasier's emotional mix - the laundry concerns, for example -- but then does nothing with them. By the last inning, THE SCOUT can't decide whether it's FEAR STRIKES OUT or MAJOR LEAGUE.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Albert Brooks at his best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evannaturally
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is really an underrated gem in its own way. It's important to mention that this movie was released during the infamous baseball strike and unfortunately not many people wanted to go see a movie about baseball because they were so upset with the way things were being handled. It's really too bad because this is a very good movie. The best thing about this movie is the way director/star Albert Brooks blends his own unique style of humor with a deep underlying current of the father/son relationship and how psychological problems can effect and athlete's performance. There are some very big laughs as well as many scenes that are funny in an Albert Brooks sort of way; scenes that make you smile and chuckle rather than belly laugh. The best crafted scenes in the film however come from the way Steve Nebraska (Fraser) looks up to Al (Brooks) as the father figure he never had. Some of these scenes are very emotional and deeply touching as well. The only thing I didn't love about the movie is the ending. It's a little too neat and tidy for my taste, but let's face it Brooks is trying to make a funny and touching movie that makes you happy and uplifted when its over, and for that I say a good well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What a Fun Movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vegasniceguy
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you ever had dreams of being a big-league star, in any sport, then you have to watch this flick. It's classic Albert Brooks. But, it is like watching a Rocky comedy. Tears come to my eyes evewn after the 10th viewing. Fraser is great. You don't need to be a sports fan to like the movie, it is good regardless. As a baseball fan, it was nice seeing Yankee Stadium. I went there in the last year of the original stadium. It was an historical stadium. Though, I hated paying $9 for a beer, but it was nice being able to take the subway to get there. Other baseball flicks that are good are "It Happens Every Spring" and naturally, "Bang the Drum Slowly".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ridiculously bad movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bravesfan35
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is definitely one of the worst sports movies of all-time. The writers made little to no effort in creating a decent plot. Albert Brooks plays a scout for the New York Yankees who thinks he finds the next great pitcher, but the guy can't handle pitching in front of large crowds and ends up puking on the mound. When Brooks travels down to Mexico, he discovers a phenom who is a fan favorite named Steve Nebraska (played by Brendan Fraser). When he tries to convince the Yankees GM that he's found an outstanding pitcher, he's told he isn't bringing anyone up and ends up getting fired. I'm a huge baseball fan, but I found this movie appalling, especially near the end when Nebraska pitches in a World Series game. He throws 81 pitches, all strikes, and no hitter even makes contact. Who ends up with the only run of the game? Nebraska, of course, with a home run. Imagine that. They obviously thought no one would see the flaws in that game. For one thing, being in an American League park, they would be using a DH. The pitcher would not be hitting. Another, how did he end up with only 1 at-bat the whole game if he pitched the whole game? This movie was very predictable and, therefore, very boring. I would not recommend this movie to my worst enemy. I wonder if even Fraser looks back on this movie and wonders why he made the mistake of agreeing to do it. It's not Fraser's fault though. No matter who was picked to star in this movie, it would have been bad simply because of the plot. I found Little Big League to be more realistic than this and that was about a little kid managing a major league team.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Thin comedy has silly plot saved by some amusing moments...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Doyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    BRENDAN FRASER seems to specialize in playing dumb--or at least that's the impression I had after watching him emote as a child-like baseball player who happens to have a great pitching arm in THE SCOUT. He does get laughs with his dumb act, so I suppose that's why he was chosen for this particular role. But most of the laughs come from the fact that ALBERT BROOKS is his co-star, a man who can say a funny line without ever giving a hint that he thinks it's funny. And sometimes, the result is hilarious--particularly in the "knife" scene in which Brooks is trying to hide all his kitchen knives from Fraser who "wants to cut something". None of the humor is particularly subtle, but DIANNE WIEST is a welcome addition as Dr. Aarons, the psychiatrist who determines that Fraser might have his dangerous moments after subjecting him to a series of tests with photos. But the baseball scenes at the finish are too over-the-top, straining credulity to the limits. The Tony Bennett nightclub sequence is also guaranteed to have you squirming in discomfort as Fraser sings an off-key version of "I Left My Heart in San Francisco", much to Bennett's chagrin. Summing up: With a wittier script and a different approach, could have been a very winning comedy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst sports movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mpionus
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The acting wasn't bad but they completely butchered any semblance of reality with regards to baseball. Let's just recap all that was wrong just with the "final game" (Game 1 of the World Series) 1) A player can't make his first appearance in the World Series--he'd have to be on roster before then 2) Since Steve Nebraska was playing in Yankee stadium, the DH rule was in effect. Meaning he couldn't have batted. 3) In order for Nebraska to have used his 81st pitch to strike out Ozzie Smith, that means that the Cardinals put "The Wizard" batting 9th in the order. Yeah, right. 4) Before the game, Costas makes some comment about how "many are predicting a perfect game from Steve Nebraska". Seeing as how there have only been 17 perfect games in history, one would highly doubt a 1st ever start would be a perfect game. 5) 81 strikes in a row...nobody even hit a ball? A World Series caliber team can't ONCE key in to a 110 mile per hour fastball to make even accidental contact once? Most idiotic movie regarding baseball of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good enough for me. . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bilro
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was fun watching Brooks do his bit. Given most movies that I've seen on the TV as of late, to include the offerings on Pay per View, HBO and Starz, this one was a welcome change. I've read some reviews that say the ending was less than acceptable. Well, such is life. A story doesn't have to have a transcendental message to be enjoyed. For those who think that's essential, I suggest they watch the movie up to the final fifteen minutes, turn off the TV and make up their own ending. As for me, I can live with it just the way it was. One clear measure that I have that it was a movie worth watching? Well, my wife actually stayed awake through most of it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Fraser Film For the Dust Bin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do they let Brendan Fraser keep on making movies? He's not funny, he's hideously deformed and his antics get on my nerves like you wouldn't believe. A scout for the Yankees, after finding prospects in the past who "flake out", is sent to Mexico where he finds Steve Nebraska (Fraser), the greatest ball player that ever lived. But after a mandatory psych exam, Nebraska begins to "flake out", too. The general plot is decent, and the idea of a perfect ballplayer is a fun one (though hardly original, especially after I just watched "The Natural"). But Fraser is not a likable character for me, and I was really hoping he would be hit by a bus. The film is thoroughly predictable with no twists or surprises at all, and an ending that still leaves some key issues unexplained (again like "The Natural" it ends rather abruptly). I can't say what they issues are at the risk of writing spoilers, although I don't know how you can spoil a film this simple. In the beginning of the film, the scout brings in Michael Rapaport as his star player (before Rapaport flakes out). Now, if he had brought in Fraser and then later on had Rapaport playing Fraser's part, this film might have been one of the better baseball movies ever made. But whoever did the casting clearly has no idea that Fraser is utterly worthless as an actor. A few cheap laughs in "Bedazzled" and "Encino Man" do not a great comedian make.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some good one-liners in asinine comic set-up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Albert Brooks co-wrote and stars in this sometimes-bright but terribly unsubtle comedy about a talent scout for the New York Yankees who loses his reputation after getting a skittish college Freshman signed to the team (the Yankees apparently scheduled the kid to pitch in a televised game without any training or pre-game publicity whatsoever, so don't they get what they deserve?); Brooks is banished to South Central Mexico to find talent, and yet when he comes up with another promising pitcher, he's fired over the telephone (in one of those excruciating sitcom developments the movie occasionally falls prey to). The new pitcher (Brendan Fraser, still in "Encino Man" mode) is a child in a young man's body, thereby linking the scout and the player on an emotionally-needy basis (not solid ground for laugh-out-loud comedy). Brooks as an actor is very ingratiating--he always has been--but this material, despite some very amusing one-liners, is stale, highly concocted, and immature. Many real-life sports luminaries appear in cameos...perhaps they should have been allowed to strengthen the script. ** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Damn Yankees!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jotix100
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Poor Al Percolo, he is a man that has brought shame to the Yankees by recommending prospects to the team that don't work out. The team's general manager, Ron Wilson, wants to punish him by sending him deep into Mexico to scout new talent. When Al sees Steven Nebraska pitch in a Mexican league ball game, he realizes this is going to be his redemption. Not only is he a great pitcher, but can that man belt home runs out of the ball park! As Al stages a test to show the different major league teams what Steve can do, Steve Nebraska proves to be the man they all have been waiting for. He is signed for an awful lot of money, but he must pass a sanity test in order to join the team. No sweat! Al gets the name of a psychiatrist out of the Yellow Pages, who turns out to be Al's worst nightmare. Dr. Aaron discovers Steve is an abused child that has a lot to deal with. Michael Ritchie directed this funny comedy. Albert Brooks contributed to the screen play he co-wrote with Andrew Bregman and Monica Johnson. Mr. Brooks plays Al Percolo, the scout of the title with his usual style that makes him one of the best actors working in comedies these days. Brendan Fraser is Steve Nebraska, a complex man who loves to play baseball, but has too many unresolved issues to deal with. The amazing Dianne Wiest plays Dr. Aaron, who injects a shot of reality into the movie. There are some funny moments in the film. One of the best involves Tony Bennett, who is performing in a night club where Steve and Al have been invited by the Yankee management. When Tony Bennett introduces young Steve Nebraska as the next Yankee star, the young man takes a bout and decides to lead the house in a rendition of "I Left my Heart in San Francisco". The other great moment occurs when Mr. Bennett shows up to sing the National Anthem at the start of a World Series game and he sees Steve, and he asks him is he is going to have the whole stadium sing. There have been other great baseball pictures. This one doesn't try to be one of them. It's just a light movie done for laughs and the mistake most viewers make is to expect it to be what it never intended to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
