<filme>
 <id>
  1226
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119783
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Sombras da Lei
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A newly elected District attorney finds himself in the middle of a police corruption investigation that may involve his father and his partner.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Sean Casey is the newest member of the district attorneys office and he is close to uncovering a police scandal that might involve his father Liam, who works for the NYPD. Then his father is critically wounded in a stake-out, Sean is chosen to prosecute the case.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   corruption
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   district attorney
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   justice
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   lawyer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   internal affairs
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Sidney Lumet
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Robert Daley
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Sidney Lumet
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Andy Garcia
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Richard Dreyfuss
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Lena Olin
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Thought Provoking, Intelligent & Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Night Falls On Manhattan" is a fascinating movie about police corruption, political rivalries and personal loyalties and the ways in which they affect the workings of the justice system in New York City. The point that this drama makes most powerfully, however, is that in order to achieve anything within the system, compromises, deals and trade-offs have to be made and that inevitably,cherished principles and moral absolutes often have to be abandoned in the process. The experiences of a young and rather naive Assistant D.A. are skilfully used to illustrate some of the ethical dilemmas that have to be confronted as he learns how to survive in his chosen profession. Two New York detectives on a stakeout are given a tip by an informant that a drug dealer that they're interested in, is currently in the building that they're watching. Detective Liam Casey (Ian Holm) promptly rushes into the building to make an arrest and his partner, Detective Joey Allegretto (James Gandolfini) follows a little later after having called for back up. Officers from three precincts respond to the call for assistance but the operation ends disastrously as Casey is shot and critically injured, three other officers are killed and the drug dealer, Jordan Washington (Shiek Mahmud-Bey), embarrassingly manages to escape in an NYPD squad car. Washington, under the supervision of his lawyer, Sam Vigoda (Richard Dreyfuss) turns himself in to the police and New York D.A. Morgenstern (Ron Leibman) swiftly appoints one of his most junior assistants, Sean Casey (Andy Garcia) to prosecute the case. Casey is very inexperienced but Morgenstern calculates that it will play well with the media if the wounded detective's son is involved in the high profile trial. This appointment also neatly avoids Morgenstern having to give the case (and any potential kudos that might be gained) to his senior assistant, Elihu Harrison (Colm Feore) who is a fiercely ambitious man who intends to stand for election against him at the next opportunity. At Washington's trial, Vigoda claims that his client had been paying protection money to the police and when another drug kingpin had offered to pay them more, he refused to get involved in a bidding war. This, he believed, made him a target and as he was convinced that the corrupt police were out to kill him, Washington had simply acted in self-defence during the raid on his apartment. Washington claimed to have been paying money to officers from the same three precincts that were involved in the shootout at his building and also said that one of the corrupt officers was Kurt Kleinhoff. Despite Vigoda's accusations, Sean Casey discredits Wahington so successfully that a guilty verdict and sentencing soon follow. Casey's victory in court wins him valuable publicity and so when D.A Morgenstern suffers a heart attack and has to stand down from his job, Casey wins the election to be his successor. At this point, things seem to be going perfectly but matters soon take on a different complexion after Kurt Kleinhoff's body and a book containing the names of a number of officers from the same three precincts that were involved in the shootout are found. This triggers an Internal Affairs investigation which brings to light some matters that threaten to unravel the case that brought Casey all his success and point the finger of suspicion at people who are close to him. The ways in which this highly principled man responds to the various improprieties that are unearthed seriously tests his integrity and leads him to recognise the value of pragmatism. This movie is full of really strong characters that are brought to life very convincingly by its talented cast. Andy Garcia does a good job of conveying the range of emotions that Sean goes through on his journey from being an impractical idealist to achieving the kind of maturity that enables him to navigate his way through some difficult situations. Ron Leibman is terrific as the wonderfully hyperactive Morgenstern who's very adept at manipulating events to suit his own purposes and Richard Dreyfuss also impresses as a defence attorney with a personal agenda. Ian Holm and James Gandolfini are also very good in their supporting roles. "Night Falls On Manhattan" is a criminally under-appreciated film that's not only thought-provoking, intelligent and realistic but also thoroughly entertaining to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Nobody's Perfect."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I, who know nothing, am sitting there watching these events unfold after having missed the first couple of minutes, including the credits. It begins with a horrific shoot out involving a black drug dealer and an absolute horde of confused NYPD cops milling around and shouting at each other. A couple of cops are dead, another wounded. The drug dealer disguises himself as a cop, coolly enters one of the squad cars and drives away. Later he surrenders himself under the legal guidance of Richard Dreyfuss. As soon as Dreyfuss and the black dealer show up, the cops go ape, bust the windows of the car, and beat the crap out of the dealer as they drag him away like a lynch mob gone wild. Newbie District Attorney, Andy Garcia, wins the case against the dealer, who is sentenced to life without parole. Garcia's father was the old cop wounded in the shoot out, and it's partly because of Garcia's status as victim that he wins the case and the office. He's an idealist, always a bad sign. And when he begins to look into the context in which the shoot out occurred -- the dealer trying to save himself from crooked cops out to kill him -- the trail is long and winding and eventually the cool arms of the law begin to enfold his own father. By this time, I'm thinking, "By Gad, this is Sidney Lumet territory!" Not just because of the subject -- police corruption and torn allegiances on the streets of New York -- but because of the detached style in which this dramatic material is handled. It was, of course, directed by Sidney Lumet, who has an indisputable feel for this sort of stuff. (Makes one wonder about his childhood.) I think, at times, he let's Garcia's quest for perfection get a little out of hand though. Garcia is best at projecting stifled intensity, what with his fevered eyes and unblinking stare, but Lumet may have him shouting when he should be glaring. But that doesn't happen often. Garcia is a likable and thoroughly competent actor and the role suits him. Well, as long as I'm carping, let me add that the name of Garcia's cop shouldn't have been Sean Casey. It should have been Juan Cansino. And men don't embrace or kiss cheeks in Irish families either. Both Ian Holm and James Gandolfini do quite well in their roles. The latter is an affable cop who cheerfully admits to perjury but, when faced with serious charges, blows himself away after sensibly getting skunked. Ian Holm is really surprising in his range. I mean, the guy is a Limey and still entirely believable as an aging New York cop. Some of the touches he brings to the role are so subtle as to go almost unnoticed. (Eg., when he learns by phone of the suicide of Gandolfini, who was his partner, his elbow slips off his knee an inch or so.) He was even convincing as a treacherous robot in "Alien." I don't know if this production is up there with "Serpico", "Prince of the City", or "Q & A". The script for that last flick is probably the weakest. But, in any case, trying to rank order movies is a hopeless task, each film being made up of its own unique dimensions -- casting, photography, score, performances, locations, and so forth. Still, Lumet's series on cops in New York is so much better than the typical kind of Manichean garbage on today's screens -- one impeccable hero against an army of venomous villains, not one of whom even has a stamp collection, just money, power, broads, and evil intent. In Lumet's work, the protagonist finds himself in all kinds of unanticipated morally gray areas. It challenges you. It asks, "What would YOU do under these circumstances?" I can understand why it might generate unease in some viewers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Andy Garcia miscast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfrost
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Andy Garcia is a great actor, but casting a Cuban American as an Irish American (Sean Casey), is too much of a stretch. Ian Holm, a Brit, plays his father (Liam Casey), and no one would visualize the two as father and son. It is no coincidence that he was cast previously as a person of Mediterranean or Latin American heritage. Otherwise a fine film about New York police, divided loyalties, the illegal drug business, the corruption drug money makes possible, and the ethical consequences that involve everyone knowing of the crimes committed. "Night Falls on Manhattan" contains a good plot from the novel by Robert Daley and has a strong supporting cast with James Gandolfini, Richard Dreyfuss, Lena Olin, Dominic Chianese, Shiek Mahmud-Bey, and Paul Guilfoyle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intelligent and well acted .........
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Night Falls on Manhattan" seems like a rather generic title for a film that explores the gray area of political and law enforcement corruption. The acting is good, with special mention going to Andy Garcia, Richard Dreyfuss, and Ron Leibman. As for Lena Olin, her character is so unimportant to the overall storyline, that it probably could have been eliminated entirely. After a bang bang beginning, the rest of the movie quietly explores who's on the take, and the back room deals necessary to bring corrupt cops to justice. This process is a real eye opener for Andy Garcia, who plays an idealistic district attorney. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not So Much a Fall as a Stumble
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    arieliondotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A "film noir" filmed in color, this story about a DA who shoots from being a student to the DA trips over itself from the start with spurts of action mixed with schmaltzy melodrama that comes across ultimately as an overly long TV movie. The only saving graces are the talents of Gandolfini & Dreyfus but sadly they are on screen far too seldom. The exciting start is like a colorful cover of a boring book (remember those?). Leave it on the shelf. It's a confused mess which (according to IMDb) had an alternate ending which is apparent not knowing what to make of itself. Nightfall & darkness is a mercy sometimes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (butchfilms@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I liked this film, this is not a great movie but it's a good one, and the most important thing was that it didn't bore me for a moment. The performances are good, the plot is interesting and clever. What I didn't like about it was that the shots of the film looked like a movie made for TV. The plot is about how Sean Casey ,an assistant district attorney working for just six months, improves very fast in his way up at his job but he is going to discover many dirty things about policemen and politics and is at this point where he will have to make difficult decisions that will put in text his principles. If you like intelligent police or court movies, this one is for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you want clean hands, become a priest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fascinating story of politics and justice in New York, or anywhere else for that matter. Most don't realize that on 3% of murder cases ever see a jury; most are plea bargained. But, there are those, like the one depicted here, that are essential, not for justice, but for the political ambitions of the DA and Mayor. Sidney Lumet (Find Me Guilty, Dog Day Afternoon) likes working with ethical questions, and he did a good job here in presenting a world that is not black and white, but gray. I generally do not like Andy Garcia (Ocean's Eleven, The Godfather Part III) or Ron Leibman (Zorro, the Gay Blade), but that may be because of their politics off the screen. It affects my judgment. I have to say that they both gave interesting performances that made this film worth watch. But, there were a lot of good stars in this film: Sir Ian Holm (Chariots of First) as Garcia's father, James Gandolfini (Tony Soprano) as a corrupt cop and Holm's partner, Richard Dreyfuss (Mr. Holland's Opus, The Goodbye Girl, Jaws) as a liberal lawyer, Colm Feore (Bon Cop, Bad Cop, The Red Violin, Chicago) as an ADA that wants the top job, and Lena Olin (Enemies: A Love Story, Chocolat, "Alias") as the love interest. Very good acting throughout and a compelling story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Must see for any law student:
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maureenwheat
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The plot was predictable; what was VERY good is the realistic sour compromises that atty's make. that alone warrants this movie as MUST SEE for students. I went to St.Johns University (undergraduate legal education), as did Sean Casey (AndyGarcia) No punches were pulled there, and that was reflected in the protagonist effort to make ethical decisions. There was one line that summarizes so much: "...if you want clean hands, become a priest. The degree to which police, criminal attys, DA's and all parties with knowledge about a criminal action get ugly is very true. This hopefully will take the hot air out of many law students, puffed up with him or herself. Well done and accurate, even if predictable. The DEVIL is in the movie detail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a hot steaming turd of a movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    devaryap
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sure, Ebert and other failed-novelist intellectuals will cream over this movie ---"Roger, a big thumbs up, its a tough insightful look into the criminal justice system." All it gives you an insight into is the right-wing hysteria of that noted auteur of the courtroom, Sidney Lumet. Once again, he sets up a bogus straw man into order to wax rhapsodic over the forces of law and order. This time, its a monstrous drug dealer (black, of course) who is on trial for killing three police officers. His flamboyant, crazed-radical criminal defense lawyer(is there really any other kind in the world of Hollywood?) whines that the baddie had no choice but to gun down the cops since they were involved in the drug rackets with him and they were aiming to blow him away first. Of course, this is an absolutely ludicrous argument, but Lumet urges us to take it seriously so that when the conviction comes down, we can rejoice, Himmler-style, in the grandeur of the thin blue line. Old Lumet sets up the old straw man and knocks him down. What a hack. Probably the most offensive moment in the film comes when our fearless young protagonist, assistant DA Sean Casey (Andy Garcia) meets with the crazed-radical criminal defense attorney Vigoda (Richard Dreyfuss). While they are both in a steam room with wet towels draped over their shoulders (a Roman motif or a bit of unacknowledged homo erotica?), Vigoda confesses that he too has a deep affection for LAW AND ORDER and he solemnly intones, "Sometimes I think that we have to give up on an entire generation and lock them up and throw away the key." Well, you don't need to read to carefully between the lines for the answer to "A generation of whom?" Why those bad minorities of course who Vigoda and Casey agree, sotte voce, must be dealt with harshly, given that their naughty drug dealing and assorted criminality upset National Security State, which of course putters along fine in the face of corporate scandals. The day that Sidney Lumet whines about the corporate scandals that have engulfed our society is the day that I begin to take him seriously. Sidney Lumet, in The Verdict, Q and A, Prince of the City, and now Night Falls on Manhattan, along with other "tough and gritty" movies, has demonstrated that he a vulgar buffoon is incapable of or unwilling to learn about the American legal system. He fawns upon power, and unspools magic theories about the careful deliberations that attends its use. Our packed prisons are eloquent testimony to the just how much deliberation the powerful exercise when it comes to the lives of the weak. It the meantime, he endlessly denigrates the criminal defense bar and by extrapolation, those hapless suckers too poor and unconnected to avoid criminal prosecution. No doubt, he is considered part of "liberal Hollywood," and would self-identify himself so. If he is indeed a liberal, the governing assumptions that he buys into show just how little discourse there is in our society, particularly on the criminal justice system.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sydney Lumet looks into honesty and corruption again.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mnfried
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The theme of corruption is examined in almost every Sydney Lumet film. He is fascinated by power and the use and misuse of it. The cast of this character-driven film is played to perfection by Andy Garcia, James Gandolfini, Lena Olin, Shiek Mahmud-Bey, Ian Holm, Ron Leibman, Richard Dreyfuss, Sam Vigoda and Paul Guilfoyle. They are all in the same gut-wrenching movie about the prosecutors who do not operate in a black-and-white world, rather in one of shades of gray. There are two especially touching relationships. One is between a father and son, the other is the love story between Andy Garcia and Lena Olin that survives this very tense and complex situation in a film about an important subject. I recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Thought Provoking, Intelligent & Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Night Falls On Manhattan" is a fascinating movie about police corruption, political rivalries and personal loyalties and the ways in which they affect the workings of the justice system in New York City. The point that this drama makes most powerfully, however, is that in order to achieve anything within the system, compromises, deals and trade-offs have to be made and that inevitably,cherished principles and moral absolutes often have to be abandoned in the process. The experiences of a young and rather naive Assistant D.A. are skilfully used to illustrate some of the ethical dilemmas that have to be confronted as he learns how to survive in his chosen profession. Two New York detectives on a stakeout are given a tip by an informant that a drug dealer that they're interested in, is currently in the building that they're watching. Detective Liam Casey (Ian Holm) promptly rushes into the building to make an arrest and his partner, Detective Joey Allegretto (James Gandolfini) follows a little later after having called for back up. Officers from three precincts respond to the call for assistance but the operation ends disastrously as Casey is shot and critically injured, three other officers are killed and the drug dealer, Jordan Washington (Shiek Mahmud-Bey), embarrassingly manages to escape in an NYPD squad car. Washington, under the supervision of his lawyer, Sam Vigoda (Richard Dreyfuss) turns himself in to the police and New York D.A. Morgenstern (Ron Leibman) swiftly appoints one of his most junior assistants, Sean Casey (Andy Garcia) to prosecute the case. Casey is very inexperienced but Morgenstern calculates that it will play well with the media if the wounded detective's son is involved in the high profile trial. This appointment also neatly avoids Morgenstern having to give the case (and any potential kudos that might be gained) to his senior assistant, Elihu Harrison (Colm Feore) who is a fiercely ambitious man who intends to stand for election against him at the next opportunity. At Washington's trial, Vigoda claims that his client had been paying protection money to the police and when another drug kingpin had offered to pay them more, he refused to get involved in a bidding war. This, he believed, made him a target and as he was convinced that the corrupt police were out to kill him, Washington had simply acted in self-defence during the raid on his apartment. Washington claimed to have been paying money to officers from the same three precincts that were involved in the shootout at his building and also said that one of the corrupt officers was Kurt Kleinhoff. Despite Vigoda's accusations, Sean Casey discredits Wahington so successfully that a guilty verdict and sentencing soon follow. Casey's victory in court wins him valuable publicity and so when D.A Morgenstern suffers a heart attack and has to stand down from his job, Casey wins the election to be his successor. At this point, things seem to be going perfectly but matters soon take on a different complexion after Kurt Kleinhoff's body and a book containing the names of a number of officers from the same three precincts that were involved in the shootout are found. This triggers an Internal Affairs investigation which brings to light some matters that threaten to unravel the case that brought Casey all his success and point the finger of suspicion at people who are close to him. The ways in which this highly principled man responds to the various improprieties that are unearthed seriously tests his integrity and leads him to recognise the value of pragmatism. This movie is full of really strong characters that are brought to life very convincingly by its talented cast. Andy Garcia does a good job of conveying the range of emotions that Sean goes through on his journey from being an impractical idealist to achieving the kind of maturity that enables him to navigate his way through some difficult situations. Ron Leibman is terrific as the wonderfully hyperactive Morgenstern who's very adept at manipulating events to suit his own purposes and Richard Dreyfuss also impresses as a defence attorney with a personal agenda. Ian Holm and James Gandolfini are also very good in their supporting roles. "Night Falls On Manhattan" is a criminally under-appreciated film that's not only thought-provoking, intelligent and realistic but also thoroughly entertaining to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Nobody's Perfect."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I, who know nothing, am sitting there watching these events unfold after having missed the first couple of minutes, including the credits. It begins with a horrific shoot out involving a black drug dealer and an absolute horde of confused NYPD cops milling around and shouting at each other. A couple of cops are dead, another wounded. The drug dealer disguises himself as a cop, coolly enters one of the squad cars and drives away. Later he surrenders himself under the legal guidance of Richard Dreyfuss. As soon as Dreyfuss and the black dealer show up, the cops go ape, bust the windows of the car, and beat the crap out of the dealer as they drag him away like a lynch mob gone wild. Newbie District Attorney, Andy Garcia, wins the case against the dealer, who is sentenced to life without parole. Garcia's father was the old cop wounded in the shoot out, and it's partly because of Garcia's status as victim that he wins the case and the office. He's an idealist, always a bad sign. And when he begins to look into the context in which the shoot out occurred -- the dealer trying to save himself from crooked cops out to kill him -- the trail is long and winding and eventually the cool arms of the law begin to enfold his own father. By this time, I'm thinking, "By Gad, this is Sidney Lumet territory!" Not just because of the subject -- police corruption and torn allegiances on the streets of New York -- but because of the detached style in which this dramatic material is handled. It was, of course, directed by Sidney Lumet, who has an indisputable feel for this sort of stuff. (Makes one wonder about his childhood.) I think, at times, he let's Garcia's quest for perfection get a little out of hand though. Garcia is best at projecting stifled intensity, what with his fevered eyes and unblinking stare, but Lumet may have him shouting when he should be glaring. But that doesn't happen often. Garcia is a likable and thoroughly competent actor and the role suits him. Well, as long as I'm carping, let me add that the name of Garcia's cop shouldn't have been Sean Casey. It should have been Juan Cansino. And men don't embrace or kiss cheeks in Irish families either. Both Ian Holm and James Gandolfini do quite well in their roles. The latter is an affable cop who cheerfully admits to perjury but, when faced with serious charges, blows himself away after sensibly getting skunked. Ian Holm is really surprising in his range. I mean, the guy is a Limey and still entirely believable as an aging New York cop. Some of the touches he brings to the role are so subtle as to go almost unnoticed. (Eg., when he learns by phone of the suicide of Gandolfini, who was his partner, his elbow slips off his knee an inch or so.) He was even convincing as a treacherous robot in "Alien." I don't know if this production is up there with "Serpico", "Prince of the City", or "Q & A". The script for that last flick is probably the weakest. But, in any case, trying to rank order movies is a hopeless task, each film being made up of its own unique dimensions -- casting, photography, score, performances, locations, and so forth. Still, Lumet's series on cops in New York is so much better than the typical kind of Manichean garbage on today's screens -- one impeccable hero against an army of venomous villains, not one of whom even has a stamp collection, just money, power, broads, and evil intent. In Lumet's work, the protagonist finds himself in all kinds of unanticipated morally gray areas. It challenges you. It asks, "What would YOU do under these circumstances?" I can understand why it might generate unease in some viewers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Andy Garcia miscast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfrost
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Andy Garcia is a great actor, but casting a Cuban American as an Irish American (Sean Casey), is too much of a stretch. Ian Holm, a Brit, plays his father (Liam Casey), and no one would visualize the two as father and son. It is no coincidence that he was cast previously as a person of Mediterranean or Latin American heritage. Otherwise a fine film about New York police, divided loyalties, the illegal drug business, the corruption drug money makes possible, and the ethical consequences that involve everyone knowing of the crimes committed. "Night Falls on Manhattan" contains a good plot from the novel by Robert Daley and has a strong supporting cast with James Gandolfini, Richard Dreyfuss, Lena Olin, Dominic Chianese, Shiek Mahmud-Bey, and Paul Guilfoyle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intelligent and well acted .........
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Night Falls on Manhattan" seems like a rather generic title for a film that explores the gray area of political and law enforcement corruption. The acting is good, with special mention going to Andy Garcia, Richard Dreyfuss, and Ron Leibman. As for Lena Olin, her character is so unimportant to the overall storyline, that it probably could have been eliminated entirely. After a bang bang beginning, the rest of the movie quietly explores who's on the take, and the back room deals necessary to bring corrupt cops to justice. This process is a real eye opener for Andy Garcia, who plays an idealistic district attorney. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not So Much a Fall as a Stumble
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    arieliondotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A "film noir" filmed in color, this story about a DA who shoots from being a student to the DA trips over itself from the start with spurts of action mixed with schmaltzy melodrama that comes across ultimately as an overly long TV movie. The only saving graces are the talents of Gandolfini & Dreyfus but sadly they are on screen far too seldom. The exciting start is like a colorful cover of a boring book (remember those?). Leave it on the shelf. It's a confused mess which (according to IMDb) had an alternate ending which is apparent not knowing what to make of itself. Nightfall & darkness is a mercy sometimes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (butchfilms@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I liked this film, this is not a great movie but it's a good one, and the most important thing was that it didn't bore me for a moment. The performances are good, the plot is interesting and clever. What I didn't like about it was that the shots of the film looked like a movie made for TV. The plot is about how Sean Casey ,an assistant district attorney working for just six months, improves very fast in his way up at his job but he is going to discover many dirty things about policemen and politics and is at this point where he will have to make difficult decisions that will put in text his principles. If you like intelligent police or court movies, this one is for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you want clean hands, become a priest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fascinating story of politics and justice in New York, or anywhere else for that matter. Most don't realize that on 3% of murder cases ever see a jury; most are plea bargained. But, there are those, like the one depicted here, that are essential, not for justice, but for the political ambitions of the DA and Mayor. Sidney Lumet (Find Me Guilty, Dog Day Afternoon) likes working with ethical questions, and he did a good job here in presenting a world that is not black and white, but gray. I generally do not like Andy Garcia (Ocean's Eleven, The Godfather Part III) or Ron Leibman (Zorro, the Gay Blade), but that may be because of their politics off the screen. It affects my judgment. I have to say that they both gave interesting performances that made this film worth watch. But, there were a lot of good stars in this film: Sir Ian Holm (Chariots of First) as Garcia's father, James Gandolfini (Tony Soprano) as a corrupt cop and Holm's partner, Richard Dreyfuss (Mr. Holland's Opus, The Goodbye Girl, Jaws) as a liberal lawyer, Colm Feore (Bon Cop, Bad Cop, The Red Violin, Chicago) as an ADA that wants the top job, and Lena Olin (Enemies: A Love Story, Chocolat, "Alias") as the love interest. Very good acting throughout and a compelling story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Must see for any law student:
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maureenwheat
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The plot was predictable; what was VERY good is the realistic sour compromises that atty's make. that alone warrants this movie as MUST SEE for students. I went to St.Johns University (undergraduate legal education), as did Sean Casey (AndyGarcia) No punches were pulled there, and that was reflected in the protagonist effort to make ethical decisions. There was one line that summarizes so much: "...if you want clean hands, become a priest. The degree to which police, criminal attys, DA's and all parties with knowledge about a criminal action get ugly is very true. This hopefully will take the hot air out of many law students, puffed up with him or herself. Well done and accurate, even if predictable. The DEVIL is in the movie detail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a hot steaming turd of a movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    devaryap
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sure, Ebert and other failed-novelist intellectuals will cream over this movie ---"Roger, a big thumbs up, its a tough insightful look into the criminal justice system." All it gives you an insight into is the right-wing hysteria of that noted auteur of the courtroom, Sidney Lumet. Once again, he sets up a bogus straw man into order to wax rhapsodic over the forces of law and order. This time, its a monstrous drug dealer (black, of course) who is on trial for killing three police officers. His flamboyant, crazed-radical criminal defense lawyer(is there really any other kind in the world of Hollywood?) whines that the baddie had no choice but to gun down the cops since they were involved in the drug rackets with him and they were aiming to blow him away first. Of course, this is an absolutely ludicrous argument, but Lumet urges us to take it seriously so that when the conviction comes down, we can rejoice, Himmler-style, in the grandeur of the thin blue line. Old Lumet sets up the old straw man and knocks him down. What a hack. Probably the most offensive moment in the film comes when our fearless young protagonist, assistant DA Sean Casey (Andy Garcia) meets with the crazed-radical criminal defense attorney Vigoda (Richard Dreyfuss). While they are both in a steam room with wet towels draped over their shoulders (a Roman motif or a bit of unacknowledged homo erotica?), Vigoda confesses that he too has a deep affection for LAW AND ORDER and he solemnly intones, "Sometimes I think that we have to give up on an entire generation and lock them up and throw away the key." Well, you don't need to read to carefully between the lines for the answer to "A generation of whom?" Why those bad minorities of course who Vigoda and Casey agree, sotte voce, must be dealt with harshly, given that their naughty drug dealing and assorted criminality upset National Security State, which of course putters along fine in the face of corporate scandals. The day that Sidney Lumet whines about the corporate scandals that have engulfed our society is the day that I begin to take him seriously. Sidney Lumet, in The Verdict, Q and A, Prince of the City, and now Night Falls on Manhattan, along with other "tough and gritty" movies, has demonstrated that he a vulgar buffoon is incapable of or unwilling to learn about the American legal system. He fawns upon power, and unspools magic theories about the careful deliberations that attends its use. Our packed prisons are eloquent testimony to the just how much deliberation the powerful exercise when it comes to the lives of the weak. It the meantime, he endlessly denigrates the criminal defense bar and by extrapolation, those hapless suckers too poor and unconnected to avoid criminal prosecution. No doubt, he is considered part of "liberal Hollywood," and would self-identify himself so. If he is indeed a liberal, the governing assumptions that he buys into show just how little discourse there is in our society, particularly on the criminal justice system.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sydney Lumet looks into honesty and corruption again.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mnfried
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The theme of corruption is examined in almost every Sydney Lumet film. He is fascinated by power and the use and misuse of it. The cast of this character-driven film is played to perfection by Andy Garcia, James Gandolfini, Lena Olin, Shiek Mahmud-Bey, Ian Holm, Ron Leibman, Richard Dreyfuss, Sam Vigoda and Paul Guilfoyle. They are all in the same gut-wrenching movie about the prosecutors who do not operate in a black-and-white world, rather in one of shades of gray. There are two especially touching relationships. One is between a father and son, the other is the love story between Andy Garcia and Lena Olin that survives this very tense and complex situation in a film about an important subject. I recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Thought Provoking, Intelligent & Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Night Falls On Manhattan" is a fascinating movie about police corruption, political rivalries and personal loyalties and the ways in which they affect the workings of the justice system in New York City. The point that this drama makes most powerfully, however, is that in order to achieve anything within the system, compromises, deals and trade-offs have to be made and that inevitably,cherished principles and moral absolutes often have to be abandoned in the process. The experiences of a young and rather naive Assistant D.A. are skilfully used to illustrate some of the ethical dilemmas that have to be confronted as he learns how to survive in his chosen profession. Two New York detectives on a stakeout are given a tip by an informant that a drug dealer that they're interested in, is currently in the building that they're watching. Detective Liam Casey (Ian Holm) promptly rushes into the building to make an arrest and his partner, Detective Joey Allegretto (James Gandolfini) follows a little later after having called for back up. Officers from three precincts respond to the call for assistance but the operation ends disastrously as Casey is shot and critically injured, three other officers are killed and the drug dealer, Jordan Washington (Shiek Mahmud-Bey), embarrassingly manages to escape in an NYPD squad car. Washington, under the supervision of his lawyer, Sam Vigoda (Richard Dreyfuss) turns himself in to the police and New York D.A. Morgenstern (Ron Leibman) swiftly appoints one of his most junior assistants, Sean Casey (Andy Garcia) to prosecute the case. Casey is very inexperienced but Morgenstern calculates that it will play well with the media if the wounded detective's son is involved in the high profile trial. This appointment also neatly avoids Morgenstern having to give the case (and any potential kudos that might be gained) to his senior assistant, Elihu Harrison (Colm Feore) who is a fiercely ambitious man who intends to stand for election against him at the next opportunity. At Washington's trial, Vigoda claims that his client had been paying protection money to the police and when another drug kingpin had offered to pay them more, he refused to get involved in a bidding war. This, he believed, made him a target and as he was convinced that the corrupt police were out to kill him, Washington had simply acted in self-defence during the raid on his apartment. Washington claimed to have been paying money to officers from the same three precincts that were involved in the shootout at his building and also said that one of the corrupt officers was Kurt Kleinhoff. Despite Vigoda's accusations, Sean Casey discredits Wahington so successfully that a guilty verdict and sentencing soon follow. Casey's victory in court wins him valuable publicity and so when D.A Morgenstern suffers a heart attack and has to stand down from his job, Casey wins the election to be his successor. At this point, things seem to be going perfectly but matters soon take on a different complexion after Kurt Kleinhoff's body and a book containing the names of a number of officers from the same three precincts that were involved in the shootout are found. This triggers an Internal Affairs investigation which brings to light some matters that threaten to unravel the case that brought Casey all his success and point the finger of suspicion at people who are close to him. The ways in which this highly principled man responds to the various improprieties that are unearthed seriously tests his integrity and leads him to recognise the value of pragmatism. This movie is full of really strong characters that are brought to life very convincingly by its talented cast. Andy Garcia does a good job of conveying the range of emotions that Sean goes through on his journey from being an impractical idealist to achieving the kind of maturity that enables him to navigate his way through some difficult situations. Ron Leibman is terrific as the wonderfully hyperactive Morgenstern who's very adept at manipulating events to suit his own purposes and Richard Dreyfuss also impresses as a defence attorney with a personal agenda. Ian Holm and James Gandolfini are also very good in their supporting roles. "Night Falls On Manhattan" is a criminally under-appreciated film that's not only thought-provoking, intelligent and realistic but also thoroughly entertaining to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Nobody's Perfect."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I, who know nothing, am sitting there watching these events unfold after having missed the first couple of minutes, including the credits. It begins with a horrific shoot out involving a black drug dealer and an absolute horde of confused NYPD cops milling around and shouting at each other. A couple of cops are dead, another wounded. The drug dealer disguises himself as a cop, coolly enters one of the squad cars and drives away. Later he surrenders himself under the legal guidance of Richard Dreyfuss. As soon as Dreyfuss and the black dealer show up, the cops go ape, bust the windows of the car, and beat the crap out of the dealer as they drag him away like a lynch mob gone wild. Newbie District Attorney, Andy Garcia, wins the case against the dealer, who is sentenced to life without parole. Garcia's father was the old cop wounded in the shoot out, and it's partly because of Garcia's status as victim that he wins the case and the office. He's an idealist, always a bad sign. And when he begins to look into the context in which the shoot out occurred -- the dealer trying to save himself from crooked cops out to kill him -- the trail is long and winding and eventually the cool arms of the law begin to enfold his own father. By this time, I'm thinking, "By Gad, this is Sidney Lumet territory!" Not just because of the subject -- police corruption and torn allegiances on the streets of New York -- but because of the detached style in which this dramatic material is handled. It was, of course, directed by Sidney Lumet, who has an indisputable feel for this sort of stuff. (Makes one wonder about his childhood.) I think, at times, he let's Garcia's quest for perfection get a little out of hand though. Garcia is best at projecting stifled intensity, what with his fevered eyes and unblinking stare, but Lumet may have him shouting when he should be glaring. But that doesn't happen often. Garcia is a likable and thoroughly competent actor and the role suits him. Well, as long as I'm carping, let me add that the name of Garcia's cop shouldn't have been Sean Casey. It should have been Juan Cansino. And men don't embrace or kiss cheeks in Irish families either. Both Ian Holm and James Gandolfini do quite well in their roles. The latter is an affable cop who cheerfully admits to perjury but, when faced with serious charges, blows himself away after sensibly getting skunked. Ian Holm is really surprising in his range. I mean, the guy is a Limey and still entirely believable as an aging New York cop. Some of the touches he brings to the role are so subtle as to go almost unnoticed. (Eg., when he learns by phone of the suicide of Gandolfini, who was his partner, his elbow slips off his knee an inch or so.) He was even convincing as a treacherous robot in "Alien." I don't know if this production is up there with "Serpico", "Prince of the City", or "Q & A". The script for that last flick is probably the weakest. But, in any case, trying to rank order movies is a hopeless task, each film being made up of its own unique dimensions -- casting, photography, score, performances, locations, and so forth. Still, Lumet's series on cops in New York is so much better than the typical kind of Manichean garbage on today's screens -- one impeccable hero against an army of venomous villains, not one of whom even has a stamp collection, just money, power, broads, and evil intent. In Lumet's work, the protagonist finds himself in all kinds of unanticipated morally gray areas. It challenges you. It asks, "What would YOU do under these circumstances?" I can understand why it might generate unease in some viewers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Andy Garcia miscast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfrost
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Andy Garcia is a great actor, but casting a Cuban American as an Irish American (Sean Casey), is too much of a stretch. Ian Holm, a Brit, plays his father (Liam Casey), and no one would visualize the two as father and son. It is no coincidence that he was cast previously as a person of Mediterranean or Latin American heritage. Otherwise a fine film about New York police, divided loyalties, the illegal drug business, the corruption drug money makes possible, and the ethical consequences that involve everyone knowing of the crimes committed. "Night Falls on Manhattan" contains a good plot from the novel by Robert Daley and has a strong supporting cast with James Gandolfini, Richard Dreyfuss, Lena Olin, Dominic Chianese, Shiek Mahmud-Bey, and Paul Guilfoyle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intelligent and well acted .........
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Night Falls on Manhattan" seems like a rather generic title for a film that explores the gray area of political and law enforcement corruption. The acting is good, with special mention going to Andy Garcia, Richard Dreyfuss, and Ron Leibman. As for Lena Olin, her character is so unimportant to the overall storyline, that it probably could have been eliminated entirely. After a bang bang beginning, the rest of the movie quietly explores who's on the take, and the back room deals necessary to bring corrupt cops to justice. This process is a real eye opener for Andy Garcia, who plays an idealistic district attorney. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not So Much a Fall as a Stumble
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    arieliondotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A "film noir" filmed in color, this story about a DA who shoots from being a student to the DA trips over itself from the start with spurts of action mixed with schmaltzy melodrama that comes across ultimately as an overly long TV movie. The only saving graces are the talents of Gandolfini & Dreyfus but sadly they are on screen far too seldom. The exciting start is like a colorful cover of a boring book (remember those?). Leave it on the shelf. It's a confused mess which (according to IMDb) had an alternate ending which is apparent not knowing what to make of itself. Nightfall & darkness is a mercy sometimes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (butchfilms@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I liked this film, this is not a great movie but it's a good one, and the most important thing was that it didn't bore me for a moment. The performances are good, the plot is interesting and clever. What I didn't like about it was that the shots of the film looked like a movie made for TV. The plot is about how Sean Casey ,an assistant district attorney working for just six months, improves very fast in his way up at his job but he is going to discover many dirty things about policemen and politics and is at this point where he will have to make difficult decisions that will put in text his principles. If you like intelligent police or court movies, this one is for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you want clean hands, become a priest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fascinating story of politics and justice in New York, or anywhere else for that matter. Most don't realize that on 3% of murder cases ever see a jury; most are plea bargained. But, there are those, like the one depicted here, that are essential, not for justice, but for the political ambitions of the DA and Mayor. Sidney Lumet (Find Me Guilty, Dog Day Afternoon) likes working with ethical questions, and he did a good job here in presenting a world that is not black and white, but gray. I generally do not like Andy Garcia (Ocean's Eleven, The Godfather Part III) or Ron Leibman (Zorro, the Gay Blade), but that may be because of their politics off the screen. It affects my judgment. I have to say that they both gave interesting performances that made this film worth watch. But, there were a lot of good stars in this film: Sir Ian Holm (Chariots of First) as Garcia's father, James Gandolfini (Tony Soprano) as a corrupt cop and Holm's partner, Richard Dreyfuss (Mr. Holland's Opus, The Goodbye Girl, Jaws) as a liberal lawyer, Colm Feore (Bon Cop, Bad Cop, The Red Violin, Chicago) as an ADA that wants the top job, and Lena Olin (Enemies: A Love Story, Chocolat, "Alias") as the love interest. Very good acting throughout and a compelling story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Must see for any law student:
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maureenwheat
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The plot was predictable; what was VERY good is the realistic sour compromises that atty's make. that alone warrants this movie as MUST SEE for students. I went to St.Johns University (undergraduate legal education), as did Sean Casey (AndyGarcia) No punches were pulled there, and that was reflected in the protagonist effort to make ethical decisions. There was one line that summarizes so much: "...if you want clean hands, become a priest. The degree to which police, criminal attys, DA's and all parties with knowledge about a criminal action get ugly is very true. This hopefully will take the hot air out of many law students, puffed up with him or herself. Well done and accurate, even if predictable. The DEVIL is in the movie detail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a hot steaming turd of a movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    devaryap
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sure, Ebert and other failed-novelist intellectuals will cream over this movie ---"Roger, a big thumbs up, its a tough insightful look into the criminal justice system." All it gives you an insight into is the right-wing hysteria of that noted auteur of the courtroom, Sidney Lumet. Once again, he sets up a bogus straw man into order to wax rhapsodic over the forces of law and order. This time, its a monstrous drug dealer (black, of course) who is on trial for killing three police officers. His flamboyant, crazed-radical criminal defense lawyer(is there really any other kind in the world of Hollywood?) whines that the baddie had no choice but to gun down the cops since they were involved in the drug rackets with him and they were aiming to blow him away first. Of course, this is an absolutely ludicrous argument, but Lumet urges us to take it seriously so that when the conviction comes down, we can rejoice, Himmler-style, in the grandeur of the thin blue line. Old Lumet sets up the old straw man and knocks him down. What a hack. Probably the most offensive moment in the film comes when our fearless young protagonist, assistant DA Sean Casey (Andy Garcia) meets with the crazed-radical criminal defense attorney Vigoda (Richard Dreyfuss). While they are both in a steam room with wet towels draped over their shoulders (a Roman motif or a bit of unacknowledged homo erotica?), Vigoda confesses that he too has a deep affection for LAW AND ORDER and he solemnly intones, "Sometimes I think that we have to give up on an entire generation and lock them up and throw away the key." Well, you don't need to read to carefully between the lines for the answer to "A generation of whom?" Why those bad minorities of course who Vigoda and Casey agree, sotte voce, must be dealt with harshly, given that their naughty drug dealing and assorted criminality upset National Security State, which of course putters along fine in the face of corporate scandals. The day that Sidney Lumet whines about the corporate scandals that have engulfed our society is the day that I begin to take him seriously. Sidney Lumet, in The Verdict, Q and A, Prince of the City, and now Night Falls on Manhattan, along with other "tough and gritty" movies, has demonstrated that he a vulgar buffoon is incapable of or unwilling to learn about the American legal system. He fawns upon power, and unspools magic theories about the careful deliberations that attends its use. Our packed prisons are eloquent testimony to the just how much deliberation the powerful exercise when it comes to the lives of the weak. It the meantime, he endlessly denigrates the criminal defense bar and by extrapolation, those hapless suckers too poor and unconnected to avoid criminal prosecution. No doubt, he is considered part of "liberal Hollywood," and would self-identify himself so. If he is indeed a liberal, the governing assumptions that he buys into show just how little discourse there is in our society, particularly on the criminal justice system.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sydney Lumet looks into honesty and corruption again.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mnfried
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The theme of corruption is examined in almost every Sydney Lumet film. He is fascinated by power and the use and misuse of it. The cast of this character-driven film is played to perfection by Andy Garcia, James Gandolfini, Lena Olin, Shiek Mahmud-Bey, Ian Holm, Ron Leibman, Richard Dreyfuss, Sam Vigoda and Paul Guilfoyle. They are all in the same gut-wrenching movie about the prosecutors who do not operate in a black-and-white world, rather in one of shades of gray. There are two especially touching relationships. One is between a father and son, the other is the love story between Andy Garcia and Lena Olin that survives this very tense and complex situation in a film about an important subject. I recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
