<filme>
 <id>
  1230
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110907
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Pr&ecirc;t-&agrave;-Porter
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  4.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A fashion show in Paris draws the usual bunch of people; designers, reporters, models, magazine editors, photographers. Lots of unconnected stories which all revolve around this show, and ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A fashion show in Paris draws the usual bunch of people; designers, reporters, models, magazine editors, photographers. Lots of unconnected stories which all revolve around this show, and an all-star cast.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   fashion show
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   fashion
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   france
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   journalism
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   female stockinged legs
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Robert Altman
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Robert Altman
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Barbara Shulgasser
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Sophia Loren
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Julia Roberts
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Marcello Mastroianni
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wanted to Like It. Didn't.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    curtis martin
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've been on an Altman kick lately. He was a very interesting filmmaker whose output is split pretty evenly between wonderful successes and crashing-bore failures that are at least interesting in a train wreck kind of way. Very few of his films fall in the middle ground between these two. Unfortunately, "Pret a Porter" (Ready to Wear) is one of those very few. This film has the same inter-cut multi-story structure as the classic "Nashville" and the underrated "A Wedding," but none of the anarchic madness or depth of those earlier films. But it's also not a spectacular "what the hell were they thinking" failure like "Quintet," "Popeye," or "OC & Stiggs." "Pret" falls squarely in the middle ground. And the result is a film that is almost too boring to watch. There's just nothing special here--the story isn't special, the style in which the story is told isn't special, the cinematography is straight and bland, the sense of reality and improvisation is missing, and the signature Altman overlapping dialog is nowhere to be heard. It's like Altman wrote the script and then handed it over to Chris Columbus to direct. Like I said before, I wanted to like it. But there's nothing there that's any better or worse than bland average blah-ness. Middle of the middle ground. And for Robert Altman--the middle ground equals total failure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    AVOID this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dgf999
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As another review wrote: "Altman was clearly saying with this film how ridiculous the fashion industry is." Unfortunately, you have to endure 2 hours of completely boring, unfunny "French farce" to get to the part of the film that makes this point. (That would be the last 5 minutes of the film) I could not stay awake through this totally predictable bore-fest. Julia Roberts gives a robotic performance here, and a list of incredibly talented actors and actresses are just wasted on a dull, uninspired script. The movie seems so contrived because of the bad direction, either that, or it was supposed to be a satire of "farce films". Either way, I thought this movie sucked.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A highbrow film about dog poop?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I am Diogenes the Dog. I nuzzle the kind, bark at the greedy and bite scoundrels!"  Diogenes Like most of Robert Altman's films, "Pret-a-Porter" involves a large cast of characters gathering together to put on a performance, in this case a prestigious fashion show in Paris. The film was marketed as a satire, but it really isn't. This is fashion industry as scatology, a "world of sh*t" in which everything is grotesque and warped. As with Diane Arbus' famous photographs on "freaks", Altman deliberately blurs the boundaries between the "ideal" and the "abnormal", the "beautifully formed" and the "deformed", the "feces" and the "sanitary", the "inside" and the "outside". All the characters here are thus "freaks" in some way, all part of the same freakish human circus. There are dwarf attendants and magazine editors, transvestites, cross-dressers, lesbians, gays, the obese, the pregnant, adulterers, illegitimate babies, mortuary attendants, and a multitude of abrasive caricatures. Mixed in with these are the "ideal" bodies of the celebrities, the exposed unnatural/natural bodies of the models, identical twins who exchange their sexual partners, film-star parodies, television personalities and original film-stars reliving previous roles. Altman then contrasts modern sex icons (Basinger, Roberts etc), with ageing, disintegrating sex icons of the past (Sophia Loren, Lauren Bacall etc), and goes out of his way to tarnish "surface beauty" by imbuing the film's sex bombs with abrasive personalities. The much derided abrasiveness of the film is therefore intentional. Altman isn't just dealing with caricatures, he's dealing with the grotesque. Of course grotesque art is, by definition, "the least ideal form", always a war of "attraction and repulsion". As such, the reoccurring motifs here are dogs, animals and dog feces. More than juvenile poop jokes, Altman's recalling the scatological traditions of Diogenes, the dog philosopher. Diogenes was associated with public outbursts and obscenity. His ragged, unashamedly dirty existence radiated disrespect and contempt for all who gazed upon him. But while he was an animal, putrid and filthy, he was nevertheless "more civilised" than his "cultured" audience. In a similar fashion, everyone in this film is held under the contemptible gaze of Diogenes, whose mischievous dog feces show scorn for an intrusive and aggressive kind of, not so much modern culture (typified by television, celebrity, photography, fame and fashion  the usual boring targets of satire), but the hypocrisy of all culture. In the film, both television and photography are implicitly connected by characters accidentally stepping in dog feces. These accidents occur in both private and public places, playfully linking the home, studio and streets with a media culture which both intrudes on privacy (exposing shameful human behaviours, foibles and frailties) and disguises these behaviours by glitzing and glamming them up. So Altman is less concerned about the fashion industry, than about what garments and technology alternatively hide and expose, the prevalence of his symbolic doggy poop serving to bring the "high" down "low". Everything is grotesque whether you're on or off the catwalk. The film ends with a nude catwalk scene, one of Altman's most brilliant sequences. Here, models walk fully nude whilst the words "You're so beautiful the way you are" hum on the soundtrack. The sequence derides the commodification of "beauty", serves as an admittance that humanity is as grotesque as its ornaments/apparels, works as a dig at the fashion industry's obsession with "authenticity" (the true "inner subject/self", the "stripped down ego or essence"), and of course points toward the end result of all fashion-as-fetish-wear: total, naked sex. More than this, though, the sequence suggests that there is beauty in freakishness and freakishness in beauty, which is why a strange aura of both life and death radiates from this sequence. The catwalk models are like clones, cold stick figures, one of which is pregnant. The pregnant model speaks of a mystery about birth and something new, but she is also the least sexual of the models. Conversely, the others are like zombies, dead, crawling out of a tomb, yet are beautifully sexualised. This blurring, this confusion (ugliness in beauty, beauty in ugliness) is the very point of Grotesque art. Unlike the satirist, the grotesque artist does not analyse and instruct in terms of right and wrong or true and false (satire=logical, grotesque=irrational), nor does he attempt to distinguish between these. On the contrary, he is concerned about demonstrating their inseparability. Satire generally aims at three reactions from the audience - laughter, anger or disgust - but it aims to produce these separately. The grotesque, however, produces a reaction of confusion. With satire, there is an alternation or distinction between laughter and the gross evil which arouses anger. With the grotesque, however, laughter, hatred and anger seem to meld. Beyond this there are references to "Funny Face" and "Blow Up" (guess why), and Altman re-enacts a scene from De Sica's "Yesterday, Today and Tomorrow" with the same actors (Loren and Mastroianni). It's like the two lovers from De Sica's film (itself a film in which Loren and Mastroianni played multiple characters) stepped out of it and resumed their tale 40 years later in older bodies. Surprisingly, the same lead actors from Fellini's "La Dolce Vita" also appear, adding a dark tinge to Fellini's tale of those seeking "the good life". Tactics like this create a further effect. The characters lose weight, becoming flat, depth-less images. Consider when the real Elsa Klensch is interviewed by Kim Basinger who plays an Elsa Klensch character or when "real celebrities" like Cher and Harry Bellefonte briefly appear but yet still come across as empty, screen representations of themselves. The film paints a world obsessed with the "image", but stresses that there are few "authentic" images. The supermodels of the 90s were clones, destratified personae, simulations of imagined and imagined bodies, part of man's ritualised games of narcissism. By the films end, even a naked repudiation of this narcissism becomes a form of narcissism. 7.5/10  Two viewings required.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not half as bad as people say.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nikita Myullyari
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to hear such malignant commentaries from those who have watched this film. Granted, it is not done in Altman's usual style, and may seem vague or shallow to some, but I believe that this is a misconception. The characters... some are rather undeveloped, but I have a hunch that this is on purpose. 2 hours is not enough to form a picture of a person, and so I think Altman made them so undeveloped because these are, when all is said and done, regular people. A large amount of correspondents, a few model designers, a bit of these, a few of those... the only character which seemed foolishly vague in my opinion was the Communist Italian. Apart from that, I only saw people that I would see on the street, or on some show, or some that I wouldn't see at all, that merely write stories which others publish and get credited for. The theme of fashion design seems to be quite irrelevant here, or rather, it serves as the backdrop for an array of the aforementioned characters. Who cares about a fashion show when such drama is going on? Who cares who designed what dress when a mischievous Irishman is so irreverently teasing famous personages in such a hilarious manner? Who cares what outfit was voted best when two complete strangers are trying to sort out the mess their arrival was? All in all, I believe that this movie fits comfortably among Altman's successes. The story is gripping, logical, and possesses a vivid array of characters reminiscent of Guy Ritchie's films (yes, not exactly chronically correct: Guy Ritchie came later, but I just wanted to make the image.), and funny. An enjoyment from beginning to end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Versace, Dior, Armani, Altman(?)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A winning streak can't last forever. After making a critical comeback with "Vincent & Theo" and "The Player," and then making one of his best films in "Short Cuts," Robert Altman gave us this rather limp lampoon of the fashion industry. "Pret a Porter" is not one of my favorite Altman films, but it's not a disaster. It's one of his big ensemble comedies that probably largely came together in the editing room, but it doesn't cohere the way "Nashville" or "Short Cuts" does. I get the mental image of Robert Altman throwing darts at a dart board and seeing what sticks, and with this film not much does. This is Altman's attempt at a French sex farce, and he gives his film an international flavor by casting big-time stars like Sophia Loren, Marcello Mastroianni and Anouk Aimee, but he acts like simply casting them is enough and forgets to give them any material to work with. Perhaps the biggest problem with "Pret a Porter" is that Altman satirizes something that itself is already largely a satire: the world of high fashion. Fashion is a big industry, no doubt, but it makes a rather meager subject for satire, and Altman doesn't seem to have much of a point to make about the industry anyway. It's fun for a while to just watch goofy people walking around saying and doing goofy things, but without a stronger script to anchor the action, the fun in people watching wears thin after a while. The large cast features a ton of famous faces, some of them actors Altman had worked with before (Tim Robbins, Sally Kellerman, Lili Taylor, Richard E. Grant) and many new to Altman's world (Julia Roberts, Tracy Ullmann, Stephen Rea, Linda Hunt, Danny Aiello, Teri Garr). But really, the only one who made much impression on me was Kim Basinger, who gets the Geraldine Chaplin role from "Nashville," playing a fish-out-of-water reporter who seems to be everywhere at once and sidelines unsuspecting subjects with impromptu interviews. It's a riot to watch Basinger's reporter stumble her way through interviews about a subject she knows nothing about, all the while doing so with a twangy Texan accent, and Basinger damn near steals the show. Grade: C+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arty, overblown and awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aemmering
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll give this one two points because, some parts of it are really visually interesting (as one would certainly expect in a film about fashion). Altman, whose work I've always mistrusted, shows his true colors here. His take on the superficiality of the fashion world is as superficial as fashion itself! I guess our auteur thinks shots of feet stepping in poo will subtly express a righteous disdain for the fashion world. Mr.Altman, taking cheap shots at obvious (and incredibly easy) targets is not clever. Your lack of subtlety (and understanding) of your subject amazes. Your trademark intertwining of several plot lines does not work here. Know this--its a simple topic, really, and deserves a simple approach. Even your self righteous disgust at the superficiality of the fashion world is misplaced. This marks you as an intellectual snob (I just always knew your were). Fashion is silly, but it's also fun, and it's more important to us than we care to admit. You show no empathy for any of your many characters,you just set them up like bowling pins and proceed to knock them down as noisily and messily as possible. Some of your most unpleasant traits persist here--this is clearly a director's statement, your gig, and the actors, famous as they are, are just chess pieces to be moved about according to whim--is this sort of power amusing to you? The story line is so poorly thought out, that it just doesn't exist. You are clearly annoyed with the idea of celebrity, but guess what--you're one too--don't we get any fun out of status--are we that proud? Why the hostility towards fashion people? I suppose they're not thinking the sorts of important thoughts that you deem necessary to justify one's existence. This is a great masturbatory mess of a movie, a so called social critique/fantasy that tells us nothing and goes nowhere. Even the last scene, the now-infamous nude modeling romp, doesn't cut the boredom or blot out the odious stench of pretension. I'm with the English--subtlety is the key to effective humor, including satire (I assume this piece was intended be a satire--of something!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Now classic Altman train wreck
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JasparLamarCrabb
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every great director has their follies. Robert Altman just happened to make his with an enormous cast, a lot of great music, a lot of hideous clothes and the city of Paris. The primary plot concerns Jean-Pierre Cassel turning up dead with Marcello Mastroianni as chief suspect. Cassel's wife (Sophia Loren) could care less, while his mistress (Anouk Aimee) is devastated. They're surrounded by a literal cast of thousands, some (like Jean Rocherfort and Rupert Everett) have SOMETHING to do with the plot while others play every type of fashionista imaginable...there's Tracey Ullman, Linda Hunt and Sally Kellerman as various versions of Diana Vreeland, Lauren Bacall as a fashion broker trying to sell Lyle Lovett's boots, Stephen Rea as a decidedly callous uber-photographer and a very funny Richard E. Grant and Forrest Whittaker as very bitchy rival designers/ex-lovers. A number of plots are completely disposable ---Julia Roberts and Tim Robbins as reporters trapped in the same hotel room and Danny Aiello as a chain-store buyer with a deep dark secret among them. And Altman definitely should have derailed Kim Basinger's attempt to play an overly intrusive fashion reporter (echoes of Geraldine Chaplin in NASHVILLE?) Not horrendous by any means, it's all very watchable, but also very forgettable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    zzzzz One of the most boring films ever! zzzzz
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scottmwade-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film should be prescribed by doctors as a cure for insomniacs! It really doesn't go anywhere and is a total drag. It's hard to believe so many great actors were willing to participate in this waste of two hours. Tim Robbins made Shawshank Redeption in 1994 (One of the greatest films of all time) and then follows it up with this piece of junk??? Don't really know what he was thinking. Julia Roberts, Sophia Loren and a lot of other big name talents are in the film as well. Like I said earlier, if you are having trouble sleeping rent this DVD and it'll put you right to sleep! zzzzzzzzzzzzzzz...... I gave it two starts instead of one only for the naked models at the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What? (Ready to Wear)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    do-bye
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard to say anything about this movie. The guy played by Stephen Rea was a silly taking pictures of all of the woman who wanted him. He needs to go somewhere. They got him back. "Ready to Wear" was an interesting satire. It shows how crazy and ridiculous it is in the industry. The women were beautiful. Kim Basinger, Sophia Loren,Julia Roberts, Tracy Ullman were all characterized in different ways. Each had their own personalities. Ms. Roberts and Tim Robbins in the bed all day was funny. They just loved steaming up the room. That was something to see right there. There have been few films like "Ready to Wear" that shed so much light on one industry. The ending was crazy. The models coming out nude(naked) was some serious mess. No way would I put that on the runway. That is the down part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Rare Miss From the Master
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DeanNYC (thedeanofnyc@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you think of a Robert Altman film, what *should* come to mind are elements like bitingly sharp satire, clever takes on human interaction and a brilliant portrayal of the subject matter; in other words, a mirror is held up to the topic examined and reflected back to the audience with maybe a tweak, a twist or a knowing wink. That's not the case with "Pr&ecirc;t-&agrave;-Porter" or "Ready To Wear," as it was released in its US theatrical run. The problem with this film is a complete lack of focus and understanding about what happens during Market week in the fashion industry, what is important about it, and for this film, most crucially, what's interesting about it! The result shows that this time, the Auteur didn't do his homework. The plot of the film is multi-layered, like all of Altman's work, so there's a lot going on, but each layer is more preposterous than the previous. Perhaps had only one of the threads been so off track, it could have still worked. However, with every element being a farcical storyline, it is simply too much to stomach. Even with the all-star cast gathered on location in the City of Light, dealing with theft, love, murder, manipulation, a bald tattoo, a lot of champagne and a clich&eacute; about the sidewalks of that European capital, and... oh yeah! the world of fashion... you can confidently skip this chapter of the Altman story and know you didn't miss anything.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wanted to Like It. Didn't.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    curtis martin
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've been on an Altman kick lately. He was a very interesting filmmaker whose output is split pretty evenly between wonderful successes and crashing-bore failures that are at least interesting in a train wreck kind of way. Very few of his films fall in the middle ground between these two. Unfortunately, "Pret a Porter" (Ready to Wear) is one of those very few. This film has the same inter-cut multi-story structure as the classic "Nashville" and the underrated "A Wedding," but none of the anarchic madness or depth of those earlier films. But it's also not a spectacular "what the hell were they thinking" failure like "Quintet," "Popeye," or "OC & Stiggs." "Pret" falls squarely in the middle ground. And the result is a film that is almost too boring to watch. There's just nothing special here--the story isn't special, the style in which the story is told isn't special, the cinematography is straight and bland, the sense of reality and improvisation is missing, and the signature Altman overlapping dialog is nowhere to be heard. It's like Altman wrote the script and then handed it over to Chris Columbus to direct. Like I said before, I wanted to like it. But there's nothing there that's any better or worse than bland average blah-ness. Middle of the middle ground. And for Robert Altman--the middle ground equals total failure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    AVOID this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dgf999
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As another review wrote: "Altman was clearly saying with this film how ridiculous the fashion industry is." Unfortunately, you have to endure 2 hours of completely boring, unfunny "French farce" to get to the part of the film that makes this point. (That would be the last 5 minutes of the film) I could not stay awake through this totally predictable bore-fest. Julia Roberts gives a robotic performance here, and a list of incredibly talented actors and actresses are just wasted on a dull, uninspired script. The movie seems so contrived because of the bad direction, either that, or it was supposed to be a satire of "farce films". Either way, I thought this movie sucked.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A highbrow film about dog poop?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I am Diogenes the Dog. I nuzzle the kind, bark at the greedy and bite scoundrels!"  Diogenes Like most of Robert Altman's films, "Pret-a-Porter" involves a large cast of characters gathering together to put on a performance, in this case a prestigious fashion show in Paris. The film was marketed as a satire, but it really isn't. This is fashion industry as scatology, a "world of sh*t" in which everything is grotesque and warped. As with Diane Arbus' famous photographs on "freaks", Altman deliberately blurs the boundaries between the "ideal" and the "abnormal", the "beautifully formed" and the "deformed", the "feces" and the "sanitary", the "inside" and the "outside". All the characters here are thus "freaks" in some way, all part of the same freakish human circus. There are dwarf attendants and magazine editors, transvestites, cross-dressers, lesbians, gays, the obese, the pregnant, adulterers, illegitimate babies, mortuary attendants, and a multitude of abrasive caricatures. Mixed in with these are the "ideal" bodies of the celebrities, the exposed unnatural/natural bodies of the models, identical twins who exchange their sexual partners, film-star parodies, television personalities and original film-stars reliving previous roles. Altman then contrasts modern sex icons (Basinger, Roberts etc), with ageing, disintegrating sex icons of the past (Sophia Loren, Lauren Bacall etc), and goes out of his way to tarnish "surface beauty" by imbuing the film's sex bombs with abrasive personalities. The much derided abrasiveness of the film is therefore intentional. Altman isn't just dealing with caricatures, he's dealing with the grotesque. Of course grotesque art is, by definition, "the least ideal form", always a war of "attraction and repulsion". As such, the reoccurring motifs here are dogs, animals and dog feces. More than juvenile poop jokes, Altman's recalling the scatological traditions of Diogenes, the dog philosopher. Diogenes was associated with public outbursts and obscenity. His ragged, unashamedly dirty existence radiated disrespect and contempt for all who gazed upon him. But while he was an animal, putrid and filthy, he was nevertheless "more civilised" than his "cultured" audience. In a similar fashion, everyone in this film is held under the contemptible gaze of Diogenes, whose mischievous dog feces show scorn for an intrusive and aggressive kind of, not so much modern culture (typified by television, celebrity, photography, fame and fashion  the usual boring targets of satire), but the hypocrisy of all culture. In the film, both television and photography are implicitly connected by characters accidentally stepping in dog feces. These accidents occur in both private and public places, playfully linking the home, studio and streets with a media culture which both intrudes on privacy (exposing shameful human behaviours, foibles and frailties) and disguises these behaviours by glitzing and glamming them up. So Altman is less concerned about the fashion industry, than about what garments and technology alternatively hide and expose, the prevalence of his symbolic doggy poop serving to bring the "high" down "low". Everything is grotesque whether you're on or off the catwalk. The film ends with a nude catwalk scene, one of Altman's most brilliant sequences. Here, models walk fully nude whilst the words "You're so beautiful the way you are" hum on the soundtrack. The sequence derides the commodification of "beauty", serves as an admittance that humanity is as grotesque as its ornaments/apparels, works as a dig at the fashion industry's obsession with "authenticity" (the true "inner subject/self", the "stripped down ego or essence"), and of course points toward the end result of all fashion-as-fetish-wear: total, naked sex. More than this, though, the sequence suggests that there is beauty in freakishness and freakishness in beauty, which is why a strange aura of both life and death radiates from this sequence. The catwalk models are like clones, cold stick figures, one of which is pregnant. The pregnant model speaks of a mystery about birth and something new, but she is also the least sexual of the models. Conversely, the others are like zombies, dead, crawling out of a tomb, yet are beautifully sexualised. This blurring, this confusion (ugliness in beauty, beauty in ugliness) is the very point of Grotesque art. Unlike the satirist, the grotesque artist does not analyse and instruct in terms of right and wrong or true and false (satire=logical, grotesque=irrational), nor does he attempt to distinguish between these. On the contrary, he is concerned about demonstrating their inseparability. Satire generally aims at three reactions from the audience - laughter, anger or disgust - but it aims to produce these separately. The grotesque, however, produces a reaction of confusion. With satire, there is an alternation or distinction between laughter and the gross evil which arouses anger. With the grotesque, however, laughter, hatred and anger seem to meld. Beyond this there are references to "Funny Face" and "Blow Up" (guess why), and Altman re-enacts a scene from De Sica's "Yesterday, Today and Tomorrow" with the same actors (Loren and Mastroianni). It's like the two lovers from De Sica's film (itself a film in which Loren and Mastroianni played multiple characters) stepped out of it and resumed their tale 40 years later in older bodies. Surprisingly, the same lead actors from Fellini's "La Dolce Vita" also appear, adding a dark tinge to Fellini's tale of those seeking "the good life". Tactics like this create a further effect. The characters lose weight, becoming flat, depth-less images. Consider when the real Elsa Klensch is interviewed by Kim Basinger who plays an Elsa Klensch character or when "real celebrities" like Cher and Harry Bellefonte briefly appear but yet still come across as empty, screen representations of themselves. The film paints a world obsessed with the "image", but stresses that there are few "authentic" images. The supermodels of the 90s were clones, destratified personae, simulations of imagined and imagined bodies, part of man's ritualised games of narcissism. By the films end, even a naked repudiation of this narcissism becomes a form of narcissism. 7.5/10  Two viewings required.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not half as bad as people say.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nikita Myullyari
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to hear such malignant commentaries from those who have watched this film. Granted, it is not done in Altman's usual style, and may seem vague or shallow to some, but I believe that this is a misconception. The characters... some are rather undeveloped, but I have a hunch that this is on purpose. 2 hours is not enough to form a picture of a person, and so I think Altman made them so undeveloped because these are, when all is said and done, regular people. A large amount of correspondents, a few model designers, a bit of these, a few of those... the only character which seemed foolishly vague in my opinion was the Communist Italian. Apart from that, I only saw people that I would see on the street, or on some show, or some that I wouldn't see at all, that merely write stories which others publish and get credited for. The theme of fashion design seems to be quite irrelevant here, or rather, it serves as the backdrop for an array of the aforementioned characters. Who cares about a fashion show when such drama is going on? Who cares who designed what dress when a mischievous Irishman is so irreverently teasing famous personages in such a hilarious manner? Who cares what outfit was voted best when two complete strangers are trying to sort out the mess their arrival was? All in all, I believe that this movie fits comfortably among Altman's successes. The story is gripping, logical, and possesses a vivid array of characters reminiscent of Guy Ritchie's films (yes, not exactly chronically correct: Guy Ritchie came later, but I just wanted to make the image.), and funny. An enjoyment from beginning to end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Versace, Dior, Armani, Altman(?)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A winning streak can't last forever. After making a critical comeback with "Vincent & Theo" and "The Player," and then making one of his best films in "Short Cuts," Robert Altman gave us this rather limp lampoon of the fashion industry. "Pret a Porter" is not one of my favorite Altman films, but it's not a disaster. It's one of his big ensemble comedies that probably largely came together in the editing room, but it doesn't cohere the way "Nashville" or "Short Cuts" does. I get the mental image of Robert Altman throwing darts at a dart board and seeing what sticks, and with this film not much does. This is Altman's attempt at a French sex farce, and he gives his film an international flavor by casting big-time stars like Sophia Loren, Marcello Mastroianni and Anouk Aimee, but he acts like simply casting them is enough and forgets to give them any material to work with. Perhaps the biggest problem with "Pret a Porter" is that Altman satirizes something that itself is already largely a satire: the world of high fashion. Fashion is a big industry, no doubt, but it makes a rather meager subject for satire, and Altman doesn't seem to have much of a point to make about the industry anyway. It's fun for a while to just watch goofy people walking around saying and doing goofy things, but without a stronger script to anchor the action, the fun in people watching wears thin after a while. The large cast features a ton of famous faces, some of them actors Altman had worked with before (Tim Robbins, Sally Kellerman, Lili Taylor, Richard E. Grant) and many new to Altman's world (Julia Roberts, Tracy Ullmann, Stephen Rea, Linda Hunt, Danny Aiello, Teri Garr). But really, the only one who made much impression on me was Kim Basinger, who gets the Geraldine Chaplin role from "Nashville," playing a fish-out-of-water reporter who seems to be everywhere at once and sidelines unsuspecting subjects with impromptu interviews. It's a riot to watch Basinger's reporter stumble her way through interviews about a subject she knows nothing about, all the while doing so with a twangy Texan accent, and Basinger damn near steals the show. Grade: C+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arty, overblown and awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aemmering
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll give this one two points because, some parts of it are really visually interesting (as one would certainly expect in a film about fashion). Altman, whose work I've always mistrusted, shows his true colors here. His take on the superficiality of the fashion world is as superficial as fashion itself! I guess our auteur thinks shots of feet stepping in poo will subtly express a righteous disdain for the fashion world. Mr.Altman, taking cheap shots at obvious (and incredibly easy) targets is not clever. Your lack of subtlety (and understanding) of your subject amazes. Your trademark intertwining of several plot lines does not work here. Know this--its a simple topic, really, and deserves a simple approach. Even your self righteous disgust at the superficiality of the fashion world is misplaced. This marks you as an intellectual snob (I just always knew your were). Fashion is silly, but it's also fun, and it's more important to us than we care to admit. You show no empathy for any of your many characters,you just set them up like bowling pins and proceed to knock them down as noisily and messily as possible. Some of your most unpleasant traits persist here--this is clearly a director's statement, your gig, and the actors, famous as they are, are just chess pieces to be moved about according to whim--is this sort of power amusing to you? The story line is so poorly thought out, that it just doesn't exist. You are clearly annoyed with the idea of celebrity, but guess what--you're one too--don't we get any fun out of status--are we that proud? Why the hostility towards fashion people? I suppose they're not thinking the sorts of important thoughts that you deem necessary to justify one's existence. This is a great masturbatory mess of a movie, a so called social critique/fantasy that tells us nothing and goes nowhere. Even the last scene, the now-infamous nude modeling romp, doesn't cut the boredom or blot out the odious stench of pretension. I'm with the English--subtlety is the key to effective humor, including satire (I assume this piece was intended be a satire--of something!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Now classic Altman train wreck
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JasparLamarCrabb
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every great director has their follies. Robert Altman just happened to make his with an enormous cast, a lot of great music, a lot of hideous clothes and the city of Paris. The primary plot concerns Jean-Pierre Cassel turning up dead with Marcello Mastroianni as chief suspect. Cassel's wife (Sophia Loren) could care less, while his mistress (Anouk Aimee) is devastated. They're surrounded by a literal cast of thousands, some (like Jean Rocherfort and Rupert Everett) have SOMETHING to do with the plot while others play every type of fashionista imaginable...there's Tracey Ullman, Linda Hunt and Sally Kellerman as various versions of Diana Vreeland, Lauren Bacall as a fashion broker trying to sell Lyle Lovett's boots, Stephen Rea as a decidedly callous uber-photographer and a very funny Richard E. Grant and Forrest Whittaker as very bitchy rival designers/ex-lovers. A number of plots are completely disposable ---Julia Roberts and Tim Robbins as reporters trapped in the same hotel room and Danny Aiello as a chain-store buyer with a deep dark secret among them. And Altman definitely should have derailed Kim Basinger's attempt to play an overly intrusive fashion reporter (echoes of Geraldine Chaplin in NASHVILLE?) Not horrendous by any means, it's all very watchable, but also very forgettable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    zzzzz One of the most boring films ever! zzzzz
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scottmwade-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film should be prescribed by doctors as a cure for insomniacs! It really doesn't go anywhere and is a total drag. It's hard to believe so many great actors were willing to participate in this waste of two hours. Tim Robbins made Shawshank Redeption in 1994 (One of the greatest films of all time) and then follows it up with this piece of junk??? Don't really know what he was thinking. Julia Roberts, Sophia Loren and a lot of other big name talents are in the film as well. Like I said earlier, if you are having trouble sleeping rent this DVD and it'll put you right to sleep! zzzzzzzzzzzzzzz...... I gave it two starts instead of one only for the naked models at the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What? (Ready to Wear)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    do-bye
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard to say anything about this movie. The guy played by Stephen Rea was a silly taking pictures of all of the woman who wanted him. He needs to go somewhere. They got him back. "Ready to Wear" was an interesting satire. It shows how crazy and ridiculous it is in the industry. The women were beautiful. Kim Basinger, Sophia Loren,Julia Roberts, Tracy Ullman were all characterized in different ways. Each had their own personalities. Ms. Roberts and Tim Robbins in the bed all day was funny. They just loved steaming up the room. That was something to see right there. There have been few films like "Ready to Wear" that shed so much light on one industry. The ending was crazy. The models coming out nude(naked) was some serious mess. No way would I put that on the runway. That is the down part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Rare Miss From the Master
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DeanNYC (thedeanofnyc@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you think of a Robert Altman film, what *should* come to mind are elements like bitingly sharp satire, clever takes on human interaction and a brilliant portrayal of the subject matter; in other words, a mirror is held up to the topic examined and reflected back to the audience with maybe a tweak, a twist or a knowing wink. That's not the case with "Pr&ecirc;t-&agrave;-Porter" or "Ready To Wear," as it was released in its US theatrical run. The problem with this film is a complete lack of focus and understanding about what happens during Market week in the fashion industry, what is important about it, and for this film, most crucially, what's interesting about it! The result shows that this time, the Auteur didn't do his homework. The plot of the film is multi-layered, like all of Altman's work, so there's a lot going on, but each layer is more preposterous than the previous. Perhaps had only one of the threads been so off track, it could have still worked. However, with every element being a farcical storyline, it is simply too much to stomach. Even with the all-star cast gathered on location in the City of Light, dealing with theft, love, murder, manipulation, a bald tattoo, a lot of champagne and a clich&eacute; about the sidewalks of that European capital, and... oh yeah! the world of fashion... you can confidently skip this chapter of the Altman story and know you didn't miss anything.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wanted to Like It. Didn't.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    curtis martin
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've been on an Altman kick lately. He was a very interesting filmmaker whose output is split pretty evenly between wonderful successes and crashing-bore failures that are at least interesting in a train wreck kind of way. Very few of his films fall in the middle ground between these two. Unfortunately, "Pret a Porter" (Ready to Wear) is one of those very few. This film has the same inter-cut multi-story structure as the classic "Nashville" and the underrated "A Wedding," but none of the anarchic madness or depth of those earlier films. But it's also not a spectacular "what the hell were they thinking" failure like "Quintet," "Popeye," or "OC & Stiggs." "Pret" falls squarely in the middle ground. And the result is a film that is almost too boring to watch. There's just nothing special here--the story isn't special, the style in which the story is told isn't special, the cinematography is straight and bland, the sense of reality and improvisation is missing, and the signature Altman overlapping dialog is nowhere to be heard. It's like Altman wrote the script and then handed it over to Chris Columbus to direct. Like I said before, I wanted to like it. But there's nothing there that's any better or worse than bland average blah-ness. Middle of the middle ground. And for Robert Altman--the middle ground equals total failure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    AVOID this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dgf999
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As another review wrote: "Altman was clearly saying with this film how ridiculous the fashion industry is." Unfortunately, you have to endure 2 hours of completely boring, unfunny "French farce" to get to the part of the film that makes this point. (That would be the last 5 minutes of the film) I could not stay awake through this totally predictable bore-fest. Julia Roberts gives a robotic performance here, and a list of incredibly talented actors and actresses are just wasted on a dull, uninspired script. The movie seems so contrived because of the bad direction, either that, or it was supposed to be a satire of "farce films". Either way, I thought this movie sucked.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A highbrow film about dog poop?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I am Diogenes the Dog. I nuzzle the kind, bark at the greedy and bite scoundrels!"  Diogenes Like most of Robert Altman's films, "Pret-a-Porter" involves a large cast of characters gathering together to put on a performance, in this case a prestigious fashion show in Paris. The film was marketed as a satire, but it really isn't. This is fashion industry as scatology, a "world of sh*t" in which everything is grotesque and warped. As with Diane Arbus' famous photographs on "freaks", Altman deliberately blurs the boundaries between the "ideal" and the "abnormal", the "beautifully formed" and the "deformed", the "feces" and the "sanitary", the "inside" and the "outside". All the characters here are thus "freaks" in some way, all part of the same freakish human circus. There are dwarf attendants and magazine editors, transvestites, cross-dressers, lesbians, gays, the obese, the pregnant, adulterers, illegitimate babies, mortuary attendants, and a multitude of abrasive caricatures. Mixed in with these are the "ideal" bodies of the celebrities, the exposed unnatural/natural bodies of the models, identical twins who exchange their sexual partners, film-star parodies, television personalities and original film-stars reliving previous roles. Altman then contrasts modern sex icons (Basinger, Roberts etc), with ageing, disintegrating sex icons of the past (Sophia Loren, Lauren Bacall etc), and goes out of his way to tarnish "surface beauty" by imbuing the film's sex bombs with abrasive personalities. The much derided abrasiveness of the film is therefore intentional. Altman isn't just dealing with caricatures, he's dealing with the grotesque. Of course grotesque art is, by definition, "the least ideal form", always a war of "attraction and repulsion". As such, the reoccurring motifs here are dogs, animals and dog feces. More than juvenile poop jokes, Altman's recalling the scatological traditions of Diogenes, the dog philosopher. Diogenes was associated with public outbursts and obscenity. His ragged, unashamedly dirty existence radiated disrespect and contempt for all who gazed upon him. But while he was an animal, putrid and filthy, he was nevertheless "more civilised" than his "cultured" audience. In a similar fashion, everyone in this film is held under the contemptible gaze of Diogenes, whose mischievous dog feces show scorn for an intrusive and aggressive kind of, not so much modern culture (typified by television, celebrity, photography, fame and fashion  the usual boring targets of satire), but the hypocrisy of all culture. In the film, both television and photography are implicitly connected by characters accidentally stepping in dog feces. These accidents occur in both private and public places, playfully linking the home, studio and streets with a media culture which both intrudes on privacy (exposing shameful human behaviours, foibles and frailties) and disguises these behaviours by glitzing and glamming them up. So Altman is less concerned about the fashion industry, than about what garments and technology alternatively hide and expose, the prevalence of his symbolic doggy poop serving to bring the "high" down "low". Everything is grotesque whether you're on or off the catwalk. The film ends with a nude catwalk scene, one of Altman's most brilliant sequences. Here, models walk fully nude whilst the words "You're so beautiful the way you are" hum on the soundtrack. The sequence derides the commodification of "beauty", serves as an admittance that humanity is as grotesque as its ornaments/apparels, works as a dig at the fashion industry's obsession with "authenticity" (the true "inner subject/self", the "stripped down ego or essence"), and of course points toward the end result of all fashion-as-fetish-wear: total, naked sex. More than this, though, the sequence suggests that there is beauty in freakishness and freakishness in beauty, which is why a strange aura of both life and death radiates from this sequence. The catwalk models are like clones, cold stick figures, one of which is pregnant. The pregnant model speaks of a mystery about birth and something new, but she is also the least sexual of the models. Conversely, the others are like zombies, dead, crawling out of a tomb, yet are beautifully sexualised. This blurring, this confusion (ugliness in beauty, beauty in ugliness) is the very point of Grotesque art. Unlike the satirist, the grotesque artist does not analyse and instruct in terms of right and wrong or true and false (satire=logical, grotesque=irrational), nor does he attempt to distinguish between these. On the contrary, he is concerned about demonstrating their inseparability. Satire generally aims at three reactions from the audience - laughter, anger or disgust - but it aims to produce these separately. The grotesque, however, produces a reaction of confusion. With satire, there is an alternation or distinction between laughter and the gross evil which arouses anger. With the grotesque, however, laughter, hatred and anger seem to meld. Beyond this there are references to "Funny Face" and "Blow Up" (guess why), and Altman re-enacts a scene from De Sica's "Yesterday, Today and Tomorrow" with the same actors (Loren and Mastroianni). It's like the two lovers from De Sica's film (itself a film in which Loren and Mastroianni played multiple characters) stepped out of it and resumed their tale 40 years later in older bodies. Surprisingly, the same lead actors from Fellini's "La Dolce Vita" also appear, adding a dark tinge to Fellini's tale of those seeking "the good life". Tactics like this create a further effect. The characters lose weight, becoming flat, depth-less images. Consider when the real Elsa Klensch is interviewed by Kim Basinger who plays an Elsa Klensch character or when "real celebrities" like Cher and Harry Bellefonte briefly appear but yet still come across as empty, screen representations of themselves. The film paints a world obsessed with the "image", but stresses that there are few "authentic" images. The supermodels of the 90s were clones, destratified personae, simulations of imagined and imagined bodies, part of man's ritualised games of narcissism. By the films end, even a naked repudiation of this narcissism becomes a form of narcissism. 7.5/10  Two viewings required.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not half as bad as people say.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nikita Myullyari
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to hear such malignant commentaries from those who have watched this film. Granted, it is not done in Altman's usual style, and may seem vague or shallow to some, but I believe that this is a misconception. The characters... some are rather undeveloped, but I have a hunch that this is on purpose. 2 hours is not enough to form a picture of a person, and so I think Altman made them so undeveloped because these are, when all is said and done, regular people. A large amount of correspondents, a few model designers, a bit of these, a few of those... the only character which seemed foolishly vague in my opinion was the Communist Italian. Apart from that, I only saw people that I would see on the street, or on some show, or some that I wouldn't see at all, that merely write stories which others publish and get credited for. The theme of fashion design seems to be quite irrelevant here, or rather, it serves as the backdrop for an array of the aforementioned characters. Who cares about a fashion show when such drama is going on? Who cares who designed what dress when a mischievous Irishman is so irreverently teasing famous personages in such a hilarious manner? Who cares what outfit was voted best when two complete strangers are trying to sort out the mess their arrival was? All in all, I believe that this movie fits comfortably among Altman's successes. The story is gripping, logical, and possesses a vivid array of characters reminiscent of Guy Ritchie's films (yes, not exactly chronically correct: Guy Ritchie came later, but I just wanted to make the image.), and funny. An enjoyment from beginning to end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Versace, Dior, Armani, Altman(?)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A winning streak can't last forever. After making a critical comeback with "Vincent & Theo" and "The Player," and then making one of his best films in "Short Cuts," Robert Altman gave us this rather limp lampoon of the fashion industry. "Pret a Porter" is not one of my favorite Altman films, but it's not a disaster. It's one of his big ensemble comedies that probably largely came together in the editing room, but it doesn't cohere the way "Nashville" or "Short Cuts" does. I get the mental image of Robert Altman throwing darts at a dart board and seeing what sticks, and with this film not much does. This is Altman's attempt at a French sex farce, and he gives his film an international flavor by casting big-time stars like Sophia Loren, Marcello Mastroianni and Anouk Aimee, but he acts like simply casting them is enough and forgets to give them any material to work with. Perhaps the biggest problem with "Pret a Porter" is that Altman satirizes something that itself is already largely a satire: the world of high fashion. Fashion is a big industry, no doubt, but it makes a rather meager subject for satire, and Altman doesn't seem to have much of a point to make about the industry anyway. It's fun for a while to just watch goofy people walking around saying and doing goofy things, but without a stronger script to anchor the action, the fun in people watching wears thin after a while. The large cast features a ton of famous faces, some of them actors Altman had worked with before (Tim Robbins, Sally Kellerman, Lili Taylor, Richard E. Grant) and many new to Altman's world (Julia Roberts, Tracy Ullmann, Stephen Rea, Linda Hunt, Danny Aiello, Teri Garr). But really, the only one who made much impression on me was Kim Basinger, who gets the Geraldine Chaplin role from "Nashville," playing a fish-out-of-water reporter who seems to be everywhere at once and sidelines unsuspecting subjects with impromptu interviews. It's a riot to watch Basinger's reporter stumble her way through interviews about a subject she knows nothing about, all the while doing so with a twangy Texan accent, and Basinger damn near steals the show. Grade: C+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arty, overblown and awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aemmering
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll give this one two points because, some parts of it are really visually interesting (as one would certainly expect in a film about fashion). Altman, whose work I've always mistrusted, shows his true colors here. His take on the superficiality of the fashion world is as superficial as fashion itself! I guess our auteur thinks shots of feet stepping in poo will subtly express a righteous disdain for the fashion world. Mr.Altman, taking cheap shots at obvious (and incredibly easy) targets is not clever. Your lack of subtlety (and understanding) of your subject amazes. Your trademark intertwining of several plot lines does not work here. Know this--its a simple topic, really, and deserves a simple approach. Even your self righteous disgust at the superficiality of the fashion world is misplaced. This marks you as an intellectual snob (I just always knew your were). Fashion is silly, but it's also fun, and it's more important to us than we care to admit. You show no empathy for any of your many characters,you just set them up like bowling pins and proceed to knock them down as noisily and messily as possible. Some of your most unpleasant traits persist here--this is clearly a director's statement, your gig, and the actors, famous as they are, are just chess pieces to be moved about according to whim--is this sort of power amusing to you? The story line is so poorly thought out, that it just doesn't exist. You are clearly annoyed with the idea of celebrity, but guess what--you're one too--don't we get any fun out of status--are we that proud? Why the hostility towards fashion people? I suppose they're not thinking the sorts of important thoughts that you deem necessary to justify one's existence. This is a great masturbatory mess of a movie, a so called social critique/fantasy that tells us nothing and goes nowhere. Even the last scene, the now-infamous nude modeling romp, doesn't cut the boredom or blot out the odious stench of pretension. I'm with the English--subtlety is the key to effective humor, including satire (I assume this piece was intended be a satire--of something!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Now classic Altman train wreck
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JasparLamarCrabb
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every great director has their follies. Robert Altman just happened to make his with an enormous cast, a lot of great music, a lot of hideous clothes and the city of Paris. The primary plot concerns Jean-Pierre Cassel turning up dead with Marcello Mastroianni as chief suspect. Cassel's wife (Sophia Loren) could care less, while his mistress (Anouk Aimee) is devastated. They're surrounded by a literal cast of thousands, some (like Jean Rocherfort and Rupert Everett) have SOMETHING to do with the plot while others play every type of fashionista imaginable...there's Tracey Ullman, Linda Hunt and Sally Kellerman as various versions of Diana Vreeland, Lauren Bacall as a fashion broker trying to sell Lyle Lovett's boots, Stephen Rea as a decidedly callous uber-photographer and a very funny Richard E. Grant and Forrest Whittaker as very bitchy rival designers/ex-lovers. A number of plots are completely disposable ---Julia Roberts and Tim Robbins as reporters trapped in the same hotel room and Danny Aiello as a chain-store buyer with a deep dark secret among them. And Altman definitely should have derailed Kim Basinger's attempt to play an overly intrusive fashion reporter (echoes of Geraldine Chaplin in NASHVILLE?) Not horrendous by any means, it's all very watchable, but also very forgettable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    zzzzz One of the most boring films ever! zzzzz
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scottmwade-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film should be prescribed by doctors as a cure for insomniacs! It really doesn't go anywhere and is a total drag. It's hard to believe so many great actors were willing to participate in this waste of two hours. Tim Robbins made Shawshank Redeption in 1994 (One of the greatest films of all time) and then follows it up with this piece of junk??? Don't really know what he was thinking. Julia Roberts, Sophia Loren and a lot of other big name talents are in the film as well. Like I said earlier, if you are having trouble sleeping rent this DVD and it'll put you right to sleep! zzzzzzzzzzzzzzz...... I gave it two starts instead of one only for the naked models at the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What? (Ready to Wear)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    do-bye
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard to say anything about this movie. The guy played by Stephen Rea was a silly taking pictures of all of the woman who wanted him. He needs to go somewhere. They got him back. "Ready to Wear" was an interesting satire. It shows how crazy and ridiculous it is in the industry. The women were beautiful. Kim Basinger, Sophia Loren,Julia Roberts, Tracy Ullman were all characterized in different ways. Each had their own personalities. Ms. Roberts and Tim Robbins in the bed all day was funny. They just loved steaming up the room. That was something to see right there. There have been few films like "Ready to Wear" that shed so much light on one industry. The ending was crazy. The models coming out nude(naked) was some serious mess. No way would I put that on the runway. That is the down part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Rare Miss From the Master
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DeanNYC (thedeanofnyc@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you think of a Robert Altman film, what *should* come to mind are elements like bitingly sharp satire, clever takes on human interaction and a brilliant portrayal of the subject matter; in other words, a mirror is held up to the topic examined and reflected back to the audience with maybe a tweak, a twist or a knowing wink. That's not the case with "Pr&ecirc;t-&agrave;-Porter" or "Ready To Wear," as it was released in its US theatrical run. The problem with this film is a complete lack of focus and understanding about what happens during Market week in the fashion industry, what is important about it, and for this film, most crucially, what's interesting about it! The result shows that this time, the Auteur didn't do his homework. The plot of the film is multi-layered, like all of Altman's work, so there's a lot going on, but each layer is more preposterous than the previous. Perhaps had only one of the threads been so off track, it could have still worked. However, with every element being a farcical storyline, it is simply too much to stomach. Even with the all-star cast gathered on location in the City of Light, dealing with theft, love, murder, manipulation, a bald tattoo, a lot of champagne and a clich&eacute; about the sidewalks of that European capital, and... oh yeah! the world of fashion... you can confidently skip this chapter of the Altman story and know you didn't miss anything.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wanted to Like It. Didn't.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    curtis martin
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've been on an Altman kick lately. He was a very interesting filmmaker whose output is split pretty evenly between wonderful successes and crashing-bore failures that are at least interesting in a train wreck kind of way. Very few of his films fall in the middle ground between these two. Unfortunately, "Pret a Porter" (Ready to Wear) is one of those very few. This film has the same inter-cut multi-story structure as the classic "Nashville" and the underrated "A Wedding," but none of the anarchic madness or depth of those earlier films. But it's also not a spectacular "what the hell were they thinking" failure like "Quintet," "Popeye," or "OC & Stiggs." "Pret" falls squarely in the middle ground. And the result is a film that is almost too boring to watch. There's just nothing special here--the story isn't special, the style in which the story is told isn't special, the cinematography is straight and bland, the sense of reality and improvisation is missing, and the signature Altman overlapping dialog is nowhere to be heard. It's like Altman wrote the script and then handed it over to Chris Columbus to direct. Like I said before, I wanted to like it. But there's nothing there that's any better or worse than bland average blah-ness. Middle of the middle ground. And for Robert Altman--the middle ground equals total failure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    AVOID this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dgf999
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As another review wrote: "Altman was clearly saying with this film how ridiculous the fashion industry is." Unfortunately, you have to endure 2 hours of completely boring, unfunny "French farce" to get to the part of the film that makes this point. (That would be the last 5 minutes of the film) I could not stay awake through this totally predictable bore-fest. Julia Roberts gives a robotic performance here, and a list of incredibly talented actors and actresses are just wasted on a dull, uninspired script. The movie seems so contrived because of the bad direction, either that, or it was supposed to be a satire of "farce films". Either way, I thought this movie sucked.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A highbrow film about dog poop?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I am Diogenes the Dog. I nuzzle the kind, bark at the greedy and bite scoundrels!"  Diogenes Like most of Robert Altman's films, "Pret-a-Porter" involves a large cast of characters gathering together to put on a performance, in this case a prestigious fashion show in Paris. The film was marketed as a satire, but it really isn't. This is fashion industry as scatology, a "world of sh*t" in which everything is grotesque and warped. As with Diane Arbus' famous photographs on "freaks", Altman deliberately blurs the boundaries between the "ideal" and the "abnormal", the "beautifully formed" and the "deformed", the "feces" and the "sanitary", the "inside" and the "outside". All the characters here are thus "freaks" in some way, all part of the same freakish human circus. There are dwarf attendants and magazine editors, transvestites, cross-dressers, lesbians, gays, the obese, the pregnant, adulterers, illegitimate babies, mortuary attendants, and a multitude of abrasive caricatures. Mixed in with these are the "ideal" bodies of the celebrities, the exposed unnatural/natural bodies of the models, identical twins who exchange their sexual partners, film-star parodies, television personalities and original film-stars reliving previous roles. Altman then contrasts modern sex icons (Basinger, Roberts etc), with ageing, disintegrating sex icons of the past (Sophia Loren, Lauren Bacall etc), and goes out of his way to tarnish "surface beauty" by imbuing the film's sex bombs with abrasive personalities. The much derided abrasiveness of the film is therefore intentional. Altman isn't just dealing with caricatures, he's dealing with the grotesque. Of course grotesque art is, by definition, "the least ideal form", always a war of "attraction and repulsion". As such, the reoccurring motifs here are dogs, animals and dog feces. More than juvenile poop jokes, Altman's recalling the scatological traditions of Diogenes, the dog philosopher. Diogenes was associated with public outbursts and obscenity. His ragged, unashamedly dirty existence radiated disrespect and contempt for all who gazed upon him. But while he was an animal, putrid and filthy, he was nevertheless "more civilised" than his "cultured" audience. In a similar fashion, everyone in this film is held under the contemptible gaze of Diogenes, whose mischievous dog feces show scorn for an intrusive and aggressive kind of, not so much modern culture (typified by television, celebrity, photography, fame and fashion  the usual boring targets of satire), but the hypocrisy of all culture. In the film, both television and photography are implicitly connected by characters accidentally stepping in dog feces. These accidents occur in both private and public places, playfully linking the home, studio and streets with a media culture which both intrudes on privacy (exposing shameful human behaviours, foibles and frailties) and disguises these behaviours by glitzing and glamming them up. So Altman is less concerned about the fashion industry, than about what garments and technology alternatively hide and expose, the prevalence of his symbolic doggy poop serving to bring the "high" down "low". Everything is grotesque whether you're on or off the catwalk. The film ends with a nude catwalk scene, one of Altman's most brilliant sequences. Here, models walk fully nude whilst the words "You're so beautiful the way you are" hum on the soundtrack. The sequence derides the commodification of "beauty", serves as an admittance that humanity is as grotesque as its ornaments/apparels, works as a dig at the fashion industry's obsession with "authenticity" (the true "inner subject/self", the "stripped down ego or essence"), and of course points toward the end result of all fashion-as-fetish-wear: total, naked sex. More than this, though, the sequence suggests that there is beauty in freakishness and freakishness in beauty, which is why a strange aura of both life and death radiates from this sequence. The catwalk models are like clones, cold stick figures, one of which is pregnant. The pregnant model speaks of a mystery about birth and something new, but she is also the least sexual of the models. Conversely, the others are like zombies, dead, crawling out of a tomb, yet are beautifully sexualised. This blurring, this confusion (ugliness in beauty, beauty in ugliness) is the very point of Grotesque art. Unlike the satirist, the grotesque artist does not analyse and instruct in terms of right and wrong or true and false (satire=logical, grotesque=irrational), nor does he attempt to distinguish between these. On the contrary, he is concerned about demonstrating their inseparability. Satire generally aims at three reactions from the audience - laughter, anger or disgust - but it aims to produce these separately. The grotesque, however, produces a reaction of confusion. With satire, there is an alternation or distinction between laughter and the gross evil which arouses anger. With the grotesque, however, laughter, hatred and anger seem to meld. Beyond this there are references to "Funny Face" and "Blow Up" (guess why), and Altman re-enacts a scene from De Sica's "Yesterday, Today and Tomorrow" with the same actors (Loren and Mastroianni). It's like the two lovers from De Sica's film (itself a film in which Loren and Mastroianni played multiple characters) stepped out of it and resumed their tale 40 years later in older bodies. Surprisingly, the same lead actors from Fellini's "La Dolce Vita" also appear, adding a dark tinge to Fellini's tale of those seeking "the good life". Tactics like this create a further effect. The characters lose weight, becoming flat, depth-less images. Consider when the real Elsa Klensch is interviewed by Kim Basinger who plays an Elsa Klensch character or when "real celebrities" like Cher and Harry Bellefonte briefly appear but yet still come across as empty, screen representations of themselves. The film paints a world obsessed with the "image", but stresses that there are few "authentic" images. The supermodels of the 90s were clones, destratified personae, simulations of imagined and imagined bodies, part of man's ritualised games of narcissism. By the films end, even a naked repudiation of this narcissism becomes a form of narcissism. 7.5/10  Two viewings required.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not half as bad as people say.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nikita Myullyari
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to hear such malignant commentaries from those who have watched this film. Granted, it is not done in Altman's usual style, and may seem vague or shallow to some, but I believe that this is a misconception. The characters... some are rather undeveloped, but I have a hunch that this is on purpose. 2 hours is not enough to form a picture of a person, and so I think Altman made them so undeveloped because these are, when all is said and done, regular people. A large amount of correspondents, a few model designers, a bit of these, a few of those... the only character which seemed foolishly vague in my opinion was the Communist Italian. Apart from that, I only saw people that I would see on the street, or on some show, or some that I wouldn't see at all, that merely write stories which others publish and get credited for. The theme of fashion design seems to be quite irrelevant here, or rather, it serves as the backdrop for an array of the aforementioned characters. Who cares about a fashion show when such drama is going on? Who cares who designed what dress when a mischievous Irishman is so irreverently teasing famous personages in such a hilarious manner? Who cares what outfit was voted best when two complete strangers are trying to sort out the mess their arrival was? All in all, I believe that this movie fits comfortably among Altman's successes. The story is gripping, logical, and possesses a vivid array of characters reminiscent of Guy Ritchie's films (yes, not exactly chronically correct: Guy Ritchie came later, but I just wanted to make the image.), and funny. An enjoyment from beginning to end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Versace, Dior, Armani, Altman(?)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A winning streak can't last forever. After making a critical comeback with "Vincent & Theo" and "The Player," and then making one of his best films in "Short Cuts," Robert Altman gave us this rather limp lampoon of the fashion industry. "Pret a Porter" is not one of my favorite Altman films, but it's not a disaster. It's one of his big ensemble comedies that probably largely came together in the editing room, but it doesn't cohere the way "Nashville" or "Short Cuts" does. I get the mental image of Robert Altman throwing darts at a dart board and seeing what sticks, and with this film not much does. This is Altman's attempt at a French sex farce, and he gives his film an international flavor by casting big-time stars like Sophia Loren, Marcello Mastroianni and Anouk Aimee, but he acts like simply casting them is enough and forgets to give them any material to work with. Perhaps the biggest problem with "Pret a Porter" is that Altman satirizes something that itself is already largely a satire: the world of high fashion. Fashion is a big industry, no doubt, but it makes a rather meager subject for satire, and Altman doesn't seem to have much of a point to make about the industry anyway. It's fun for a while to just watch goofy people walking around saying and doing goofy things, but without a stronger script to anchor the action, the fun in people watching wears thin after a while. The large cast features a ton of famous faces, some of them actors Altman had worked with before (Tim Robbins, Sally Kellerman, Lili Taylor, Richard E. Grant) and many new to Altman's world (Julia Roberts, Tracy Ullmann, Stephen Rea, Linda Hunt, Danny Aiello, Teri Garr). But really, the only one who made much impression on me was Kim Basinger, who gets the Geraldine Chaplin role from "Nashville," playing a fish-out-of-water reporter who seems to be everywhere at once and sidelines unsuspecting subjects with impromptu interviews. It's a riot to watch Basinger's reporter stumble her way through interviews about a subject she knows nothing about, all the while doing so with a twangy Texan accent, and Basinger damn near steals the show. Grade: C+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arty, overblown and awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aemmering
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll give this one two points because, some parts of it are really visually interesting (as one would certainly expect in a film about fashion). Altman, whose work I've always mistrusted, shows his true colors here. His take on the superficiality of the fashion world is as superficial as fashion itself! I guess our auteur thinks shots of feet stepping in poo will subtly express a righteous disdain for the fashion world. Mr.Altman, taking cheap shots at obvious (and incredibly easy) targets is not clever. Your lack of subtlety (and understanding) of your subject amazes. Your trademark intertwining of several plot lines does not work here. Know this--its a simple topic, really, and deserves a simple approach. Even your self righteous disgust at the superficiality of the fashion world is misplaced. This marks you as an intellectual snob (I just always knew your were). Fashion is silly, but it's also fun, and it's more important to us than we care to admit. You show no empathy for any of your many characters,you just set them up like bowling pins and proceed to knock them down as noisily and messily as possible. Some of your most unpleasant traits persist here--this is clearly a director's statement, your gig, and the actors, famous as they are, are just chess pieces to be moved about according to whim--is this sort of power amusing to you? The story line is so poorly thought out, that it just doesn't exist. You are clearly annoyed with the idea of celebrity, but guess what--you're one too--don't we get any fun out of status--are we that proud? Why the hostility towards fashion people? I suppose they're not thinking the sorts of important thoughts that you deem necessary to justify one's existence. This is a great masturbatory mess of a movie, a so called social critique/fantasy that tells us nothing and goes nowhere. Even the last scene, the now-infamous nude modeling romp, doesn't cut the boredom or blot out the odious stench of pretension. I'm with the English--subtlety is the key to effective humor, including satire (I assume this piece was intended be a satire--of something!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Now classic Altman train wreck
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JasparLamarCrabb
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every great director has their follies. Robert Altman just happened to make his with an enormous cast, a lot of great music, a lot of hideous clothes and the city of Paris. The primary plot concerns Jean-Pierre Cassel turning up dead with Marcello Mastroianni as chief suspect. Cassel's wife (Sophia Loren) could care less, while his mistress (Anouk Aimee) is devastated. They're surrounded by a literal cast of thousands, some (like Jean Rocherfort and Rupert Everett) have SOMETHING to do with the plot while others play every type of fashionista imaginable...there's Tracey Ullman, Linda Hunt and Sally Kellerman as various versions of Diana Vreeland, Lauren Bacall as a fashion broker trying to sell Lyle Lovett's boots, Stephen Rea as a decidedly callous uber-photographer and a very funny Richard E. Grant and Forrest Whittaker as very bitchy rival designers/ex-lovers. A number of plots are completely disposable ---Julia Roberts and Tim Robbins as reporters trapped in the same hotel room and Danny Aiello as a chain-store buyer with a deep dark secret among them. And Altman definitely should have derailed Kim Basinger's attempt to play an overly intrusive fashion reporter (echoes of Geraldine Chaplin in NASHVILLE?) Not horrendous by any means, it's all very watchable, but also very forgettable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    zzzzz One of the most boring films ever! zzzzz
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scottmwade-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film should be prescribed by doctors as a cure for insomniacs! It really doesn't go anywhere and is a total drag. It's hard to believe so many great actors were willing to participate in this waste of two hours. Tim Robbins made Shawshank Redeption in 1994 (One of the greatest films of all time) and then follows it up with this piece of junk??? Don't really know what he was thinking. Julia Roberts, Sophia Loren and a lot of other big name talents are in the film as well. Like I said earlier, if you are having trouble sleeping rent this DVD and it'll put you right to sleep! zzzzzzzzzzzzzzz...... I gave it two starts instead of one only for the naked models at the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What? (Ready to Wear)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    do-bye
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard to say anything about this movie. The guy played by Stephen Rea was a silly taking pictures of all of the woman who wanted him. He needs to go somewhere. They got him back. "Ready to Wear" was an interesting satire. It shows how crazy and ridiculous it is in the industry. The women were beautiful. Kim Basinger, Sophia Loren,Julia Roberts, Tracy Ullman were all characterized in different ways. Each had their own personalities. Ms. Roberts and Tim Robbins in the bed all day was funny. They just loved steaming up the room. That was something to see right there. There have been few films like "Ready to Wear" that shed so much light on one industry. The ending was crazy. The models coming out nude(naked) was some serious mess. No way would I put that on the runway. That is the down part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Rare Miss From the Master
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DeanNYC (thedeanofnyc@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you think of a Robert Altman film, what *should* come to mind are elements like bitingly sharp satire, clever takes on human interaction and a brilliant portrayal of the subject matter; in other words, a mirror is held up to the topic examined and reflected back to the audience with maybe a tweak, a twist or a knowing wink. That's not the case with "Pr&ecirc;t-&agrave;-Porter" or "Ready To Wear," as it was released in its US theatrical run. The problem with this film is a complete lack of focus and understanding about what happens during Market week in the fashion industry, what is important about it, and for this film, most crucially, what's interesting about it! The result shows that this time, the Auteur didn't do his homework. The plot of the film is multi-layered, like all of Altman's work, so there's a lot going on, but each layer is more preposterous than the previous. Perhaps had only one of the threads been so off track, it could have still worked. However, with every element being a farcical storyline, it is simply too much to stomach. Even with the all-star cast gathered on location in the City of Light, dealing with theft, love, murder, manipulation, a bald tattoo, a lot of champagne and a clich&eacute; about the sidewalks of that European capital, and... oh yeah! the world of fashion... you can confidently skip this chapter of the Altman story and know you didn't miss anything.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wanted to Like It. Didn't.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    curtis martin
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've been on an Altman kick lately. He was a very interesting filmmaker whose output is split pretty evenly between wonderful successes and crashing-bore failures that are at least interesting in a train wreck kind of way. Very few of his films fall in the middle ground between these two. Unfortunately, "Pret a Porter" (Ready to Wear) is one of those very few. This film has the same inter-cut multi-story structure as the classic "Nashville" and the underrated "A Wedding," but none of the anarchic madness or depth of those earlier films. But it's also not a spectacular "what the hell were they thinking" failure like "Quintet," "Popeye," or "OC & Stiggs." "Pret" falls squarely in the middle ground. And the result is a film that is almost too boring to watch. There's just nothing special here--the story isn't special, the style in which the story is told isn't special, the cinematography is straight and bland, the sense of reality and improvisation is missing, and the signature Altman overlapping dialog is nowhere to be heard. It's like Altman wrote the script and then handed it over to Chris Columbus to direct. Like I said before, I wanted to like it. But there's nothing there that's any better or worse than bland average blah-ness. Middle of the middle ground. And for Robert Altman--the middle ground equals total failure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    AVOID this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dgf999
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As another review wrote: "Altman was clearly saying with this film how ridiculous the fashion industry is." Unfortunately, you have to endure 2 hours of completely boring, unfunny "French farce" to get to the part of the film that makes this point. (That would be the last 5 minutes of the film) I could not stay awake through this totally predictable bore-fest. Julia Roberts gives a robotic performance here, and a list of incredibly talented actors and actresses are just wasted on a dull, uninspired script. The movie seems so contrived because of the bad direction, either that, or it was supposed to be a satire of "farce films". Either way, I thought this movie sucked.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A highbrow film about dog poop?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I am Diogenes the Dog. I nuzzle the kind, bark at the greedy and bite scoundrels!"  Diogenes Like most of Robert Altman's films, "Pret-a-Porter" involves a large cast of characters gathering together to put on a performance, in this case a prestigious fashion show in Paris. The film was marketed as a satire, but it really isn't. This is fashion industry as scatology, a "world of sh*t" in which everything is grotesque and warped. As with Diane Arbus' famous photographs on "freaks", Altman deliberately blurs the boundaries between the "ideal" and the "abnormal", the "beautifully formed" and the "deformed", the "feces" and the "sanitary", the "inside" and the "outside". All the characters here are thus "freaks" in some way, all part of the same freakish human circus. There are dwarf attendants and magazine editors, transvestites, cross-dressers, lesbians, gays, the obese, the pregnant, adulterers, illegitimate babies, mortuary attendants, and a multitude of abrasive caricatures. Mixed in with these are the "ideal" bodies of the celebrities, the exposed unnatural/natural bodies of the models, identical twins who exchange their sexual partners, film-star parodies, television personalities and original film-stars reliving previous roles. Altman then contrasts modern sex icons (Basinger, Roberts etc), with ageing, disintegrating sex icons of the past (Sophia Loren, Lauren Bacall etc), and goes out of his way to tarnish "surface beauty" by imbuing the film's sex bombs with abrasive personalities. The much derided abrasiveness of the film is therefore intentional. Altman isn't just dealing with caricatures, he's dealing with the grotesque. Of course grotesque art is, by definition, "the least ideal form", always a war of "attraction and repulsion". As such, the reoccurring motifs here are dogs, animals and dog feces. More than juvenile poop jokes, Altman's recalling the scatological traditions of Diogenes, the dog philosopher. Diogenes was associated with public outbursts and obscenity. His ragged, unashamedly dirty existence radiated disrespect and contempt for all who gazed upon him. But while he was an animal, putrid and filthy, he was nevertheless "more civilised" than his "cultured" audience. In a similar fashion, everyone in this film is held under the contemptible gaze of Diogenes, whose mischievous dog feces show scorn for an intrusive and aggressive kind of, not so much modern culture (typified by television, celebrity, photography, fame and fashion  the usual boring targets of satire), but the hypocrisy of all culture. In the film, both television and photography are implicitly connected by characters accidentally stepping in dog feces. These accidents occur in both private and public places, playfully linking the home, studio and streets with a media culture which both intrudes on privacy (exposing shameful human behaviours, foibles and frailties) and disguises these behaviours by glitzing and glamming them up. So Altman is less concerned about the fashion industry, than about what garments and technology alternatively hide and expose, the prevalence of his symbolic doggy poop serving to bring the "high" down "low". Everything is grotesque whether you're on or off the catwalk. The film ends with a nude catwalk scene, one of Altman's most brilliant sequences. Here, models walk fully nude whilst the words "You're so beautiful the way you are" hum on the soundtrack. The sequence derides the commodification of "beauty", serves as an admittance that humanity is as grotesque as its ornaments/apparels, works as a dig at the fashion industry's obsession with "authenticity" (the true "inner subject/self", the "stripped down ego or essence"), and of course points toward the end result of all fashion-as-fetish-wear: total, naked sex. More than this, though, the sequence suggests that there is beauty in freakishness and freakishness in beauty, which is why a strange aura of both life and death radiates from this sequence. The catwalk models are like clones, cold stick figures, one of which is pregnant. The pregnant model speaks of a mystery about birth and something new, but she is also the least sexual of the models. Conversely, the others are like zombies, dead, crawling out of a tomb, yet are beautifully sexualised. This blurring, this confusion (ugliness in beauty, beauty in ugliness) is the very point of Grotesque art. Unlike the satirist, the grotesque artist does not analyse and instruct in terms of right and wrong or true and false (satire=logical, grotesque=irrational), nor does he attempt to distinguish between these. On the contrary, he is concerned about demonstrating their inseparability. Satire generally aims at three reactions from the audience - laughter, anger or disgust - but it aims to produce these separately. The grotesque, however, produces a reaction of confusion. With satire, there is an alternation or distinction between laughter and the gross evil which arouses anger. With the grotesque, however, laughter, hatred and anger seem to meld. Beyond this there are references to "Funny Face" and "Blow Up" (guess why), and Altman re-enacts a scene from De Sica's "Yesterday, Today and Tomorrow" with the same actors (Loren and Mastroianni). It's like the two lovers from De Sica's film (itself a film in which Loren and Mastroianni played multiple characters) stepped out of it and resumed their tale 40 years later in older bodies. Surprisingly, the same lead actors from Fellini's "La Dolce Vita" also appear, adding a dark tinge to Fellini's tale of those seeking "the good life". Tactics like this create a further effect. The characters lose weight, becoming flat, depth-less images. Consider when the real Elsa Klensch is interviewed by Kim Basinger who plays an Elsa Klensch character or when "real celebrities" like Cher and Harry Bellefonte briefly appear but yet still come across as empty, screen representations of themselves. The film paints a world obsessed with the "image", but stresses that there are few "authentic" images. The supermodels of the 90s were clones, destratified personae, simulations of imagined and imagined bodies, part of man's ritualised games of narcissism. By the films end, even a naked repudiation of this narcissism becomes a form of narcissism. 7.5/10  Two viewings required.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not half as bad as people say.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nikita Myullyari
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to hear such malignant commentaries from those who have watched this film. Granted, it is not done in Altman's usual style, and may seem vague or shallow to some, but I believe that this is a misconception. The characters... some are rather undeveloped, but I have a hunch that this is on purpose. 2 hours is not enough to form a picture of a person, and so I think Altman made them so undeveloped because these are, when all is said and done, regular people. A large amount of correspondents, a few model designers, a bit of these, a few of those... the only character which seemed foolishly vague in my opinion was the Communist Italian. Apart from that, I only saw people that I would see on the street, or on some show, or some that I wouldn't see at all, that merely write stories which others publish and get credited for. The theme of fashion design seems to be quite irrelevant here, or rather, it serves as the backdrop for an array of the aforementioned characters. Who cares about a fashion show when such drama is going on? Who cares who designed what dress when a mischievous Irishman is so irreverently teasing famous personages in such a hilarious manner? Who cares what outfit was voted best when two complete strangers are trying to sort out the mess their arrival was? All in all, I believe that this movie fits comfortably among Altman's successes. The story is gripping, logical, and possesses a vivid array of characters reminiscent of Guy Ritchie's films (yes, not exactly chronically correct: Guy Ritchie came later, but I just wanted to make the image.), and funny. An enjoyment from beginning to end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Versace, Dior, Armani, Altman(?)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A winning streak can't last forever. After making a critical comeback with "Vincent & Theo" and "The Player," and then making one of his best films in "Short Cuts," Robert Altman gave us this rather limp lampoon of the fashion industry. "Pret a Porter" is not one of my favorite Altman films, but it's not a disaster. It's one of his big ensemble comedies that probably largely came together in the editing room, but it doesn't cohere the way "Nashville" or "Short Cuts" does. I get the mental image of Robert Altman throwing darts at a dart board and seeing what sticks, and with this film not much does. This is Altman's attempt at a French sex farce, and he gives his film an international flavor by casting big-time stars like Sophia Loren, Marcello Mastroianni and Anouk Aimee, but he acts like simply casting them is enough and forgets to give them any material to work with. Perhaps the biggest problem with "Pret a Porter" is that Altman satirizes something that itself is already largely a satire: the world of high fashion. Fashion is a big industry, no doubt, but it makes a rather meager subject for satire, and Altman doesn't seem to have much of a point to make about the industry anyway. It's fun for a while to just watch goofy people walking around saying and doing goofy things, but without a stronger script to anchor the action, the fun in people watching wears thin after a while. The large cast features a ton of famous faces, some of them actors Altman had worked with before (Tim Robbins, Sally Kellerman, Lili Taylor, Richard E. Grant) and many new to Altman's world (Julia Roberts, Tracy Ullmann, Stephen Rea, Linda Hunt, Danny Aiello, Teri Garr). But really, the only one who made much impression on me was Kim Basinger, who gets the Geraldine Chaplin role from "Nashville," playing a fish-out-of-water reporter who seems to be everywhere at once and sidelines unsuspecting subjects with impromptu interviews. It's a riot to watch Basinger's reporter stumble her way through interviews about a subject she knows nothing about, all the while doing so with a twangy Texan accent, and Basinger damn near steals the show. Grade: C+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arty, overblown and awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aemmering
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll give this one two points because, some parts of it are really visually interesting (as one would certainly expect in a film about fashion). Altman, whose work I've always mistrusted, shows his true colors here. His take on the superficiality of the fashion world is as superficial as fashion itself! I guess our auteur thinks shots of feet stepping in poo will subtly express a righteous disdain for the fashion world. Mr.Altman, taking cheap shots at obvious (and incredibly easy) targets is not clever. Your lack of subtlety (and understanding) of your subject amazes. Your trademark intertwining of several plot lines does not work here. Know this--its a simple topic, really, and deserves a simple approach. Even your self righteous disgust at the superficiality of the fashion world is misplaced. This marks you as an intellectual snob (I just always knew your were). Fashion is silly, but it's also fun, and it's more important to us than we care to admit. You show no empathy for any of your many characters,you just set them up like bowling pins and proceed to knock them down as noisily and messily as possible. Some of your most unpleasant traits persist here--this is clearly a director's statement, your gig, and the actors, famous as they are, are just chess pieces to be moved about according to whim--is this sort of power amusing to you? The story line is so poorly thought out, that it just doesn't exist. You are clearly annoyed with the idea of celebrity, but guess what--you're one too--don't we get any fun out of status--are we that proud? Why the hostility towards fashion people? I suppose they're not thinking the sorts of important thoughts that you deem necessary to justify one's existence. This is a great masturbatory mess of a movie, a so called social critique/fantasy that tells us nothing and goes nowhere. Even the last scene, the now-infamous nude modeling romp, doesn't cut the boredom or blot out the odious stench of pretension. I'm with the English--subtlety is the key to effective humor, including satire (I assume this piece was intended be a satire--of something!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Now classic Altman train wreck
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JasparLamarCrabb
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every great director has their follies. Robert Altman just happened to make his with an enormous cast, a lot of great music, a lot of hideous clothes and the city of Paris. The primary plot concerns Jean-Pierre Cassel turning up dead with Marcello Mastroianni as chief suspect. Cassel's wife (Sophia Loren) could care less, while his mistress (Anouk Aimee) is devastated. They're surrounded by a literal cast of thousands, some (like Jean Rocherfort and Rupert Everett) have SOMETHING to do with the plot while others play every type of fashionista imaginable...there's Tracey Ullman, Linda Hunt and Sally Kellerman as various versions of Diana Vreeland, Lauren Bacall as a fashion broker trying to sell Lyle Lovett's boots, Stephen Rea as a decidedly callous uber-photographer and a very funny Richard E. Grant and Forrest Whittaker as very bitchy rival designers/ex-lovers. A number of plots are completely disposable ---Julia Roberts and Tim Robbins as reporters trapped in the same hotel room and Danny Aiello as a chain-store buyer with a deep dark secret among them. And Altman definitely should have derailed Kim Basinger's attempt to play an overly intrusive fashion reporter (echoes of Geraldine Chaplin in NASHVILLE?) Not horrendous by any means, it's all very watchable, but also very forgettable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    zzzzz One of the most boring films ever! zzzzz
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scottmwade-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film should be prescribed by doctors as a cure for insomniacs! It really doesn't go anywhere and is a total drag. It's hard to believe so many great actors were willing to participate in this waste of two hours. Tim Robbins made Shawshank Redeption in 1994 (One of the greatest films of all time) and then follows it up with this piece of junk??? Don't really know what he was thinking. Julia Roberts, Sophia Loren and a lot of other big name talents are in the film as well. Like I said earlier, if you are having trouble sleeping rent this DVD and it'll put you right to sleep! zzzzzzzzzzzzzzz...... I gave it two starts instead of one only for the naked models at the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What? (Ready to Wear)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    do-bye
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard to say anything about this movie. The guy played by Stephen Rea was a silly taking pictures of all of the woman who wanted him. He needs to go somewhere. They got him back. "Ready to Wear" was an interesting satire. It shows how crazy and ridiculous it is in the industry. The women were beautiful. Kim Basinger, Sophia Loren,Julia Roberts, Tracy Ullman were all characterized in different ways. Each had their own personalities. Ms. Roberts and Tim Robbins in the bed all day was funny. They just loved steaming up the room. That was something to see right there. There have been few films like "Ready to Wear" that shed so much light on one industry. The ending was crazy. The models coming out nude(naked) was some serious mess. No way would I put that on the runway. That is the down part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Rare Miss From the Master
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DeanNYC (thedeanofnyc@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you think of a Robert Altman film, what *should* come to mind are elements like bitingly sharp satire, clever takes on human interaction and a brilliant portrayal of the subject matter; in other words, a mirror is held up to the topic examined and reflected back to the audience with maybe a tweak, a twist or a knowing wink. That's not the case with "Pr&ecirc;t-&agrave;-Porter" or "Ready To Wear," as it was released in its US theatrical run. The problem with this film is a complete lack of focus and understanding about what happens during Market week in the fashion industry, what is important about it, and for this film, most crucially, what's interesting about it! The result shows that this time, the Auteur didn't do his homework. The plot of the film is multi-layered, like all of Altman's work, so there's a lot going on, but each layer is more preposterous than the previous. Perhaps had only one of the threads been so off track, it could have still worked. However, with every element being a farcical storyline, it is simply too much to stomach. Even with the all-star cast gathered on location in the City of Light, dealing with theft, love, murder, manipulation, a bald tattoo, a lot of champagne and a clich&eacute; about the sidewalks of that European capital, and... oh yeah! the world of fashion... you can confidently skip this chapter of the Altman story and know you didn't miss anything.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
