<filme>
 <id>
  1231
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0100114
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1990
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Marcado Para a Morte
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Chicago DEA agent John Hatcher has just returned from Colombia, where his partner was killed in the line of duty by a drug dealer who has since been taken down. As a result of his partner's... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Chicago DEA agent John Hatcher has just returned from Colombia, where his partner was killed in the line of duty by a drug dealer who has since been taken down. As a result of his partner's death, John has decided to retire, but his retirement may not be permanent. On the next day, after reuniting with his sister Melissa and Melissa's daughter Tracy, John gets into a shootout against a Jamaican drug kingpin known as Screwface, taking down some of Screwface's men. John brings himself out of retirement when Screwface retaliates by attempting to kill Melissa and Tracy. After the shooting, John is reunited with two old friends - a local high school football coach named Max, and a Jamaican Chicago cop named Charles. John and Max set out to hunt Screwface down, only to discover that Screwface has gone back to Jamaica. John and Max take Charles with them to Jamaica for an all out war against Screwface and his drug empire.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   drugs
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   jamaica
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   jamaican
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   shootout
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   drug dealer
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Dwight H. Little
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Michael Grais
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Mark Victor
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Steven Seagal
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Joanna Pacula
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Basil Wallace
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unimpressive movie from the golden years of Seagal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    GOOD THINGS : I like two songs from this movie , both by Jimmy Cliff : "No justice" and "John Crow" . Cliff even makes appearance in the movie . I was good to see Joanna Pacula in small role of Leslie  expert of foreign cultures . She gives the best performance in the movie. The girl who plays the part of Screwface's ex-girlfriend is hot. It was also good to see Danny Trejo in a small episode. "MFD" has a little more budget than typical Seagal movie , so we get to see a little bit of Mexico and Jamaica. It was also interesting to use Jamaicans as the villains . Maybe the writers were inspired by the "Predator 2" ? "Marked for death " is certainly more watchable and better than all those straight to DVD crap movies Seagal is now making  BAD THINGS : but it doesn't mean it's a good movie . The characters in this movie are one-dimensional . The story is flat and lacks a heart . The acting is rather poor (with the exception of Pacula ) , especially from the actor who plays the main villain . All the fights and action sequences are rather unimpressive and not too exciting. Despite some decent budget "MFD" feels like a made for TV movie . The twist at the end could be impressive , but the movie hints it to us too early and not in subtle way . The romance between Seagal's character and Leslie seems forced , undeveloped and rather unnecessary. There are some attempts at making the characters more human and the dialogue tries very hard to be funny and cool , but both those efforts are fruitless. VERDICT : Nothing really worth watching . Still , it's one of Seagal better movies . His fans should be pleased . I give it 3/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Marked for death is a waste of time , stupid as anuthing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julesdil
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marked for death , is corny , i don't care i hate this film it is a story about Jamaican drug fdealers ,, oouuggg horrible the accent and dialouge goes into a childish form , kids will love this garbage but as an action film it is a cartoon , the violence is tame and horrible because the film has no realistic fights the revenge action scenes ares simple , ohhhhh , shoot em up , no death that is good. Steven is a bad actor and in this mutters a stupid plot and just puts you off , i mean the actors and characters are in some kind of wannabe good film but is only for you cheesy corny film lovers . Avoid anyone who is good.Overrated 15 certificate for moderate violence and language.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Seagal action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When DEA agent John Hatcher's partner is killed he decides it is time to retire as no matter how much they do and how many villains they arrest there is always somebody else waiting to take there place. When he returns to his home in Chicago he finds the Jamaican Posses are selling drugs. At first he doesn't want to get involved but eventually he has no choice and deals with one of the gang. This puts both him and his family firmly in the sights of Screwface, the gang's leader. After an attack on his home leaves his niece critically injured he sets about hunting Screwface down; a mission that will take him from Chicago to Jamaica and back again and everywhere he goes he fill have to take on Screwface's many men and the black magic they claim to wield. If you enjoyed other early Seagal films you are sure to like this as it is packed with bone crunching action; he frequently has to fight several thugs at once. As well as the expected martial arts action there is plenty of gunplay, a car chase and even a sword fight! The story isn't too deep but there is an unforgettable twist that first time viewers are sure to enjoy. Seagal isn't the best actor in the world but he knows how to do action so if that is what you want you won't be disappointed. Some of the Jamaican patois is a little hard to understand but that doesn't spoil anything as most of what they say can be guessed anyway it is nearly always a threat of some sort!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who and Where was there a "John Crow"?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael A. Martinez (aylmer666@juno.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one gets my vote for "best" Steven Seagal action picture. Sure UNDER SIEGE is slicker and more expensive, ABOVE THE LAW has a more serious and compelling story, and OUT FOR JUSTICE has Seagal at his self-righteously most over the top, but none of those are half as fun as this little gem. Admittedly the plot to this film is on the simplistic side and it takes itself quite seriously for the most part. Seagal here is an originally unwilling crusader against drug gangs and violence but of course kills more people and causes more mayhem and property damage than any cartel ever did. Already at this point was he starting to exhibit some of his quirky mannerisms (obvious stunt doubles and enigmatic heroes who disappear to let their lackies do the "boring" stuff) which turned into B-action tropes over the years. He also starts to find his own identity as a bonafide 80's era action star with snappy post-mortem one-liners and creative almost artfully balletic corpse-kills. A lot of the fun comes from the ethnocentrism at hand in the form of the ridiculousness assigned to the antagonistic Jamaican cartel. Their heavily accented dialog and Basil Wallace's performance as their leader makes it feel as though Seagal is up against a gang of cartoon characters. The movie casts aside any shred of realism and treats us to seeing Seagal cathartically and unemotionally taking down multiple adversaries at once without even breaking a sweat. This was the only film I think Seagal did for 20th Century Fox so perhaps that's why it breaks a mold a little bit and allows the villains to land a few punches on our mighty hero (not that it makes any difference). One cannot talk about this movie without mentioning Basil Wallace's delirious portrayal of perhaps the most emotionally unbalanced villain of any action movie, and that includes anything Vernon Wells has ever done. He enthusiastically incantates voodoo and mysticism with wild-eyed abandon in an effort to intimidate his posse, but it largely comes across as quite comical. He's the polar opposite of the wooden and inexpressive Seagal, who just sort of drifts around and looks annoyed when there's no more baddies to murder. Pathetically the film tries to go the PC route and with the casting of Jamaican Tom Wright as a vindictive Island cop and American black character actor Keith David as Seagal's buddy vigilante. Amazingly, David's character is the close-minded one and no chance is spared to teach him how Jamaica as a tough but unfortunate breeding ground for vermin, though mostly populated by mostly good people. I don't know if it was out of PC-ness or in keeping with the tone of the villainy in the film, but the soundtrack contains a lot of great reggae tracks, largely by the one and only Jimmy Cliff who even appears in the film as himself singing about the upcoming death of the film's villain (!). The film ends on a high note with a nonstop action spectacular and immediately rolls into one of the most unforgettable reggae songs of all time. I really don't know who John Crow was or what he had to do with anything (perhaps they changed Hatcher's name at some point during production?) but at least we got a great song out of it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie dates back to when Steven segal was making entertaining movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marcus Geebs
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marked For Death" is a lot of fun. most of Steven segals movies are made by warner bros but this one is made by 20th century fox. The plot is John Hatcher (Seagal) is a jaded DEA agent. After witnessing the death of his partner, he resigns from the force and vows to return to family life in a quiet neighborhood of Chicago. However, he arrives to find his hometown teeming with Jamaican drug dealers, headed by the psychotic voodoo cultist Screwface (Basil Wallace, Blood Diamond). Though he does his best to ignore the impending danger, Hatcher finds both himself and his family in the dealers' sights after interfering in an assassination attempt, prompting him to team up with an old military comrade (Keith David, "The Thing") and take the fight to the criminals. this film is not perfect. the points of incompetence are limited and don't permeate the entire picture.It's a shame that this movie isn't recalled as readily as some of our hero's other work, since it supplies the adrenaline just as well. Btw Steven segal gets beat up a little in this movie unlike some of his other films we don't see him get hit once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid Seagal vehicle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In one of his early vehicles with the three-word descriptive titles, Steven Seagal this time is fighting the war on drugs. Or, to be more accurate, he's out to annihilate the Jamaican drug pushers who've infiltrated his Chicago community. He didn't feel like doing so at first; he'd burned out while on the job as a DEA agent and realized that in order to win he'd become no better than his adversaries. It's only inevitable that he'll once again get motivated to righteous fury when his own family is victimized. The bad guys in these movies never ever learn that simple lesson - mess with the hero's loved ones and they're just as marked for death as the good guy. Here, Seagal showed that in the earlier years of his career how he really gave more of an effort and could be quite engaging. He's given a truly kick ass sidekick in the form of eternally cool Keith David, as the old buddy / football coach disgusted by what he sees around him. Also lending assistance are Jamaican cop Tom Wright and a professor played by Joanna Pacula. "Marked for Death" does its job in a number of areas; as directed by Dwight H. Little ("Halloween 4: The Return of Michael Myers", "Rapid Fire"), it hits the ground running, and delivers exactly what we as fans of Seagal movies expect: rampant brutality, with broken limbs aplenty, bullets in foreheads, bodies crashing through windows, impalement, eyes gouged out, etc. The topicality of the script does take a back seat to all of the violent action - there's always one great scene around the corner. There's even a little bit of nudity to spice things up. A major appeal of the movie is the soundtrack, which features some tunes by Jimmy Cliff, who also appears on screen performing with his band. The supporting cast is full of familiar faces - Kevin Dunn, Tony DiBenedetto, Peter Jason, Danny Trejo, Gary Carlos Cervantes, and Earl Boen, with Danielle Harris, whom Little had directed in "Halloween 4", in a bit as Seagal's niece. Basil Wallace, an actor who should have broken bigger after this, has enough intensity and charisma to make for an effective villain. All in all, "Marked for Death" is good fun and builds to a really good finale as well as an amusing twist and resulting final one-liner. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First Steven Seagal movie I seen...Well didn't make me a fan of his
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the first Steven Seagal movie I seen. So I wasn't familiar with his films but from what I know, he usually plays a arrogant and cocky character that goes after the bad guys without hardly ever getting hurt or breaking a sweat. So in another words it sounded like some absurd and ridiculous action movie with bunch of kung-fu thrown in and to some degree that is exactly what this movie is. In this Steven Seagal's character is a retired DEA after on a the line of duty things don't go according to plan. And now he is going after Jamaican drug dealers with dreadlocks and is in some sort of cult with a couple of friends after they mess with his loved ones. Yeah the plot is very very narrow and the villains are comical and not in a good way either. After just few minutes in the movie just seemed to drag, constantly putting excuse to put some action sequences in which this has a lot of. Steven Seagal beats people up while saying catch phrases, some works some just don't. Just about everything about this movie is generic and predictable and almost nothing is all that engaging. The fight sequences with Seagal using judo or aikido was sort of cool though and watchable thus I give this movie a 4.5 even if the acting is atrocious thus I am being generous. I will just say this movie didn't make me a fan of his. 4.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vintage Fun!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Marked for Death' is Vintage Fun. Power-Packed, Fast-Paced, Action-Packed & Loud, it has it all. Also, its damn cool to watch bad-ass Steven Seagal getting it right completely. 'Marked for Death' stars Seagal as John Hatcher, a former DEA troubleshooter. Upon moving back to his home town, Hatcher finds it taken over by a gang of vicious Jamaican drug dealers, led by the twisted Screwface. 'Marked for Death' is Power-Packed, Fast-Paced & Loud Cinema at its best. The film never loses pace & always keeps you engrossed. Michael Grais & Mark Victor's Screenplay is Great Fun. Dwight H. Little's Direction is decent. Cinematography & Editing are fair, while the Action-Sequences/Fights are awesome. Performance-Wise: Seagal gets it right completely. His fights are a pleasure to watch & does his part with great energy & style. Basil Wallace as the twisted Screface is frightening. Keith David is perfect. On the whole, 'Marked for Death' is Vintage Fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well, I liked 2 things, and one of them was Seagal's car !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all know that it is B grade B movie. The "afternoon" or "rainy night" kind of time filler. So I won't get harsh, though with the presence of Steven Seagal it's impossible not to ! After Seagal's first movie (Above the Law  1988), some critic said about the new rising star "He's a fine mix of John Wayne, Bruce Lee and Clint Eastwood". How deceived that miserable critic was ! In fact Seagal is nothing but another Charles Bronson yet with marital arts experience. Observe well Seagal's so-called acting to discover easily that he must have watched Bronson's Death Wish movies for countless times ! The conflict this round is some tough cop fighting some voodoo drug dealers. The friction of the two's worlds was done absurdly. That cop's violence is too much; he walks like a deadly epidemic that leaves no wounded guys, only corpses. The attack at the gang's headquarters reminded me of (Commando), 5 years earlier. However the real reason of bothering was Seagal himself. It's not about the eternal truth that he doesn't smile, or doesn't know the way to. It's about another thing. They gave him a little dialog, which is a good idea, till you know that it was filled with many one-liners. OK, how they got the nerve ?! That guy is the worst of the worst at delivering any one-liner ! Watch him saying "They were both wrong" or "I hope they weren't triplets"; if Tom from Tom and Jerry said these lines, he would be less awful and more cool than Mr. Steven-The Whispering Zombie-Seagal ! The action is average, but it works. In movies of that kind don't ask much, just watch the fights. In general I liked 2 things, one of them is Seagal's black car; it was a stunner for every guy back in the 1990s start. And the second is of course the surprise of the evil guy as alive; that trick of having a twin brother was excellent (that fake decapitated head was so real it's freaky too !). Other than that...Seagal's grins could have killed me ! P.S : I read that Seagal didn't want to make this movie, hating it openly from day one till now, so how come he produced it ?!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fleetingly entertaining but forgettable action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    DEA Agent John Hatcher (Steven Seagal) is busy kickin' ass in Colombia when he decides to make his return to the U.S. after some spiritual enlightenment from his priest. He returns to find his city overrun by Jamaican 'posses', and when at a bar, he and his old friend Max (Keith David) find themselves caught amidst a gang war shootout. Hatcher, naturally, kicks the s**t out of some of them and finds that he and his family have been 'marked for death' by gang boss Screwface (Basil Wallace). His sisters house is attacked and when his niece is shot, Hatcher and Max team up with Jamaican police man Charles (Tom Wright) to find Screwface and end his reign of terror. Clearly neither Screwface nor his ever-dispensable gang of cronies have ever seen a Steven Seagal film, or they would have left him the f**k alone. Guns, swords and even voodoo cannot stop the pony-tailed action hero. This is actually considered to be the 'finest' of Seagal's vast action backlog, which is quite tragic given that this film is pretty s**t. I will say this for it, however - it's relentlessly entertaining. Yet this derives from the unintentionally hilarious dialogue, woeful acting, some appallingly gruesome action scenes, and plot devices that simply defy logic. Possibly the funniest moment in the film has Hatcher, who has, by the way, just committed murder (he's retired from the police) and has to be the police's main suspect, taking part in a high speed chase through the city that sees one car drive along the pavement causing massive damage, only to later fly through the window of a department store. Hatcher walks in shooting and stabbing his way through the bad guys only to calmly stroll out afterwards. Surely the police would have noticed something during the carnage? Yes, yes, I'm missing the point, this is a dumb action film - this is hardly trying to be The Wire. Marked for Death does have the sense to show off Seagal's martial arts skills. While many of his other films have him mainly either carrying a gun or simply throwing people onto tables, this has him breaking many, many bones with his bare hands. It's shockingly gory for an 90's action film, which naturally makes the whole film more likable. Basil Wallace is plenty of fun as the interestingly named Screwface, all wide-eyed and using an over-accentuated Jamaican accent. The voodoo element is certainly different, and the practises shown in the film are apparently well-researched and accurate. Definitely one for the action junkies, but for me, it's a laughable nostalgia trip into an overly macho time, and ultimately a rather forgettable one. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unimpressive movie from the golden years of Seagal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    GOOD THINGS : I like two songs from this movie , both by Jimmy Cliff : "No justice" and "John Crow" . Cliff even makes appearance in the movie . I was good to see Joanna Pacula in small role of Leslie  expert of foreign cultures . She gives the best performance in the movie. The girl who plays the part of Screwface's ex-girlfriend is hot. It was also good to see Danny Trejo in a small episode. "MFD" has a little more budget than typical Seagal movie , so we get to see a little bit of Mexico and Jamaica. It was also interesting to use Jamaicans as the villains . Maybe the writers were inspired by the "Predator 2" ? "Marked for death " is certainly more watchable and better than all those straight to DVD crap movies Seagal is now making  BAD THINGS : but it doesn't mean it's a good movie . The characters in this movie are one-dimensional . The story is flat and lacks a heart . The acting is rather poor (with the exception of Pacula ) , especially from the actor who plays the main villain . All the fights and action sequences are rather unimpressive and not too exciting. Despite some decent budget "MFD" feels like a made for TV movie . The twist at the end could be impressive , but the movie hints it to us too early and not in subtle way . The romance between Seagal's character and Leslie seems forced , undeveloped and rather unnecessary. There are some attempts at making the characters more human and the dialogue tries very hard to be funny and cool , but both those efforts are fruitless. VERDICT : Nothing really worth watching . Still , it's one of Seagal better movies . His fans should be pleased . I give it 3/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Marked for death is a waste of time , stupid as anuthing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julesdil
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marked for death , is corny , i don't care i hate this film it is a story about Jamaican drug fdealers ,, oouuggg horrible the accent and dialouge goes into a childish form , kids will love this garbage but as an action film it is a cartoon , the violence is tame and horrible because the film has no realistic fights the revenge action scenes ares simple , ohhhhh , shoot em up , no death that is good. Steven is a bad actor and in this mutters a stupid plot and just puts you off , i mean the actors and characters are in some kind of wannabe good film but is only for you cheesy corny film lovers . Avoid anyone who is good.Overrated 15 certificate for moderate violence and language.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Seagal action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When DEA agent John Hatcher's partner is killed he decides it is time to retire as no matter how much they do and how many villains they arrest there is always somebody else waiting to take there place. When he returns to his home in Chicago he finds the Jamaican Posses are selling drugs. At first he doesn't want to get involved but eventually he has no choice and deals with one of the gang. This puts both him and his family firmly in the sights of Screwface, the gang's leader. After an attack on his home leaves his niece critically injured he sets about hunting Screwface down; a mission that will take him from Chicago to Jamaica and back again and everywhere he goes he fill have to take on Screwface's many men and the black magic they claim to wield. If you enjoyed other early Seagal films you are sure to like this as it is packed with bone crunching action; he frequently has to fight several thugs at once. As well as the expected martial arts action there is plenty of gunplay, a car chase and even a sword fight! The story isn't too deep but there is an unforgettable twist that first time viewers are sure to enjoy. Seagal isn't the best actor in the world but he knows how to do action so if that is what you want you won't be disappointed. Some of the Jamaican patois is a little hard to understand but that doesn't spoil anything as most of what they say can be guessed anyway it is nearly always a threat of some sort!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who and Where was there a "John Crow"?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael A. Martinez (aylmer666@juno.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one gets my vote for "best" Steven Seagal action picture. Sure UNDER SIEGE is slicker and more expensive, ABOVE THE LAW has a more serious and compelling story, and OUT FOR JUSTICE has Seagal at his self-righteously most over the top, but none of those are half as fun as this little gem. Admittedly the plot to this film is on the simplistic side and it takes itself quite seriously for the most part. Seagal here is an originally unwilling crusader against drug gangs and violence but of course kills more people and causes more mayhem and property damage than any cartel ever did. Already at this point was he starting to exhibit some of his quirky mannerisms (obvious stunt doubles and enigmatic heroes who disappear to let their lackies do the "boring" stuff) which turned into B-action tropes over the years. He also starts to find his own identity as a bonafide 80's era action star with snappy post-mortem one-liners and creative almost artfully balletic corpse-kills. A lot of the fun comes from the ethnocentrism at hand in the form of the ridiculousness assigned to the antagonistic Jamaican cartel. Their heavily accented dialog and Basil Wallace's performance as their leader makes it feel as though Seagal is up against a gang of cartoon characters. The movie casts aside any shred of realism and treats us to seeing Seagal cathartically and unemotionally taking down multiple adversaries at once without even breaking a sweat. This was the only film I think Seagal did for 20th Century Fox so perhaps that's why it breaks a mold a little bit and allows the villains to land a few punches on our mighty hero (not that it makes any difference). One cannot talk about this movie without mentioning Basil Wallace's delirious portrayal of perhaps the most emotionally unbalanced villain of any action movie, and that includes anything Vernon Wells has ever done. He enthusiastically incantates voodoo and mysticism with wild-eyed abandon in an effort to intimidate his posse, but it largely comes across as quite comical. He's the polar opposite of the wooden and inexpressive Seagal, who just sort of drifts around and looks annoyed when there's no more baddies to murder. Pathetically the film tries to go the PC route and with the casting of Jamaican Tom Wright as a vindictive Island cop and American black character actor Keith David as Seagal's buddy vigilante. Amazingly, David's character is the close-minded one and no chance is spared to teach him how Jamaica as a tough but unfortunate breeding ground for vermin, though mostly populated by mostly good people. I don't know if it was out of PC-ness or in keeping with the tone of the villainy in the film, but the soundtrack contains a lot of great reggae tracks, largely by the one and only Jimmy Cliff who even appears in the film as himself singing about the upcoming death of the film's villain (!). The film ends on a high note with a nonstop action spectacular and immediately rolls into one of the most unforgettable reggae songs of all time. I really don't know who John Crow was or what he had to do with anything (perhaps they changed Hatcher's name at some point during production?) but at least we got a great song out of it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie dates back to when Steven segal was making entertaining movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marcus Geebs
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marked For Death" is a lot of fun. most of Steven segals movies are made by warner bros but this one is made by 20th century fox. The plot is John Hatcher (Seagal) is a jaded DEA agent. After witnessing the death of his partner, he resigns from the force and vows to return to family life in a quiet neighborhood of Chicago. However, he arrives to find his hometown teeming with Jamaican drug dealers, headed by the psychotic voodoo cultist Screwface (Basil Wallace, Blood Diamond). Though he does his best to ignore the impending danger, Hatcher finds both himself and his family in the dealers' sights after interfering in an assassination attempt, prompting him to team up with an old military comrade (Keith David, "The Thing") and take the fight to the criminals. this film is not perfect. the points of incompetence are limited and don't permeate the entire picture.It's a shame that this movie isn't recalled as readily as some of our hero's other work, since it supplies the adrenaline just as well. Btw Steven segal gets beat up a little in this movie unlike some of his other films we don't see him get hit once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid Seagal vehicle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In one of his early vehicles with the three-word descriptive titles, Steven Seagal this time is fighting the war on drugs. Or, to be more accurate, he's out to annihilate the Jamaican drug pushers who've infiltrated his Chicago community. He didn't feel like doing so at first; he'd burned out while on the job as a DEA agent and realized that in order to win he'd become no better than his adversaries. It's only inevitable that he'll once again get motivated to righteous fury when his own family is victimized. The bad guys in these movies never ever learn that simple lesson - mess with the hero's loved ones and they're just as marked for death as the good guy. Here, Seagal showed that in the earlier years of his career how he really gave more of an effort and could be quite engaging. He's given a truly kick ass sidekick in the form of eternally cool Keith David, as the old buddy / football coach disgusted by what he sees around him. Also lending assistance are Jamaican cop Tom Wright and a professor played by Joanna Pacula. "Marked for Death" does its job in a number of areas; as directed by Dwight H. Little ("Halloween 4: The Return of Michael Myers", "Rapid Fire"), it hits the ground running, and delivers exactly what we as fans of Seagal movies expect: rampant brutality, with broken limbs aplenty, bullets in foreheads, bodies crashing through windows, impalement, eyes gouged out, etc. The topicality of the script does take a back seat to all of the violent action - there's always one great scene around the corner. There's even a little bit of nudity to spice things up. A major appeal of the movie is the soundtrack, which features some tunes by Jimmy Cliff, who also appears on screen performing with his band. The supporting cast is full of familiar faces - Kevin Dunn, Tony DiBenedetto, Peter Jason, Danny Trejo, Gary Carlos Cervantes, and Earl Boen, with Danielle Harris, whom Little had directed in "Halloween 4", in a bit as Seagal's niece. Basil Wallace, an actor who should have broken bigger after this, has enough intensity and charisma to make for an effective villain. All in all, "Marked for Death" is good fun and builds to a really good finale as well as an amusing twist and resulting final one-liner. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First Steven Seagal movie I seen...Well didn't make me a fan of his
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the first Steven Seagal movie I seen. So I wasn't familiar with his films but from what I know, he usually plays a arrogant and cocky character that goes after the bad guys without hardly ever getting hurt or breaking a sweat. So in another words it sounded like some absurd and ridiculous action movie with bunch of kung-fu thrown in and to some degree that is exactly what this movie is. In this Steven Seagal's character is a retired DEA after on a the line of duty things don't go according to plan. And now he is going after Jamaican drug dealers with dreadlocks and is in some sort of cult with a couple of friends after they mess with his loved ones. Yeah the plot is very very narrow and the villains are comical and not in a good way either. After just few minutes in the movie just seemed to drag, constantly putting excuse to put some action sequences in which this has a lot of. Steven Seagal beats people up while saying catch phrases, some works some just don't. Just about everything about this movie is generic and predictable and almost nothing is all that engaging. The fight sequences with Seagal using judo or aikido was sort of cool though and watchable thus I give this movie a 4.5 even if the acting is atrocious thus I am being generous. I will just say this movie didn't make me a fan of his. 4.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vintage Fun!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Marked for Death' is Vintage Fun. Power-Packed, Fast-Paced, Action-Packed & Loud, it has it all. Also, its damn cool to watch bad-ass Steven Seagal getting it right completely. 'Marked for Death' stars Seagal as John Hatcher, a former DEA troubleshooter. Upon moving back to his home town, Hatcher finds it taken over by a gang of vicious Jamaican drug dealers, led by the twisted Screwface. 'Marked for Death' is Power-Packed, Fast-Paced & Loud Cinema at its best. The film never loses pace & always keeps you engrossed. Michael Grais & Mark Victor's Screenplay is Great Fun. Dwight H. Little's Direction is decent. Cinematography & Editing are fair, while the Action-Sequences/Fights are awesome. Performance-Wise: Seagal gets it right completely. His fights are a pleasure to watch & does his part with great energy & style. Basil Wallace as the twisted Screface is frightening. Keith David is perfect. On the whole, 'Marked for Death' is Vintage Fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well, I liked 2 things, and one of them was Seagal's car !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all know that it is B grade B movie. The "afternoon" or "rainy night" kind of time filler. So I won't get harsh, though with the presence of Steven Seagal it's impossible not to ! After Seagal's first movie (Above the Law  1988), some critic said about the new rising star "He's a fine mix of John Wayne, Bruce Lee and Clint Eastwood". How deceived that miserable critic was ! In fact Seagal is nothing but another Charles Bronson yet with marital arts experience. Observe well Seagal's so-called acting to discover easily that he must have watched Bronson's Death Wish movies for countless times ! The conflict this round is some tough cop fighting some voodoo drug dealers. The friction of the two's worlds was done absurdly. That cop's violence is too much; he walks like a deadly epidemic that leaves no wounded guys, only corpses. The attack at the gang's headquarters reminded me of (Commando), 5 years earlier. However the real reason of bothering was Seagal himself. It's not about the eternal truth that he doesn't smile, or doesn't know the way to. It's about another thing. They gave him a little dialog, which is a good idea, till you know that it was filled with many one-liners. OK, how they got the nerve ?! That guy is the worst of the worst at delivering any one-liner ! Watch him saying "They were both wrong" or "I hope they weren't triplets"; if Tom from Tom and Jerry said these lines, he would be less awful and more cool than Mr. Steven-The Whispering Zombie-Seagal ! The action is average, but it works. In movies of that kind don't ask much, just watch the fights. In general I liked 2 things, one of them is Seagal's black car; it was a stunner for every guy back in the 1990s start. And the second is of course the surprise of the evil guy as alive; that trick of having a twin brother was excellent (that fake decapitated head was so real it's freaky too !). Other than that...Seagal's grins could have killed me ! P.S : I read that Seagal didn't want to make this movie, hating it openly from day one till now, so how come he produced it ?!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fleetingly entertaining but forgettable action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    DEA Agent John Hatcher (Steven Seagal) is busy kickin' ass in Colombia when he decides to make his return to the U.S. after some spiritual enlightenment from his priest. He returns to find his city overrun by Jamaican 'posses', and when at a bar, he and his old friend Max (Keith David) find themselves caught amidst a gang war shootout. Hatcher, naturally, kicks the s**t out of some of them and finds that he and his family have been 'marked for death' by gang boss Screwface (Basil Wallace). His sisters house is attacked and when his niece is shot, Hatcher and Max team up with Jamaican police man Charles (Tom Wright) to find Screwface and end his reign of terror. Clearly neither Screwface nor his ever-dispensable gang of cronies have ever seen a Steven Seagal film, or they would have left him the f**k alone. Guns, swords and even voodoo cannot stop the pony-tailed action hero. This is actually considered to be the 'finest' of Seagal's vast action backlog, which is quite tragic given that this film is pretty s**t. I will say this for it, however - it's relentlessly entertaining. Yet this derives from the unintentionally hilarious dialogue, woeful acting, some appallingly gruesome action scenes, and plot devices that simply defy logic. Possibly the funniest moment in the film has Hatcher, who has, by the way, just committed murder (he's retired from the police) and has to be the police's main suspect, taking part in a high speed chase through the city that sees one car drive along the pavement causing massive damage, only to later fly through the window of a department store. Hatcher walks in shooting and stabbing his way through the bad guys only to calmly stroll out afterwards. Surely the police would have noticed something during the carnage? Yes, yes, I'm missing the point, this is a dumb action film - this is hardly trying to be The Wire. Marked for Death does have the sense to show off Seagal's martial arts skills. While many of his other films have him mainly either carrying a gun or simply throwing people onto tables, this has him breaking many, many bones with his bare hands. It's shockingly gory for an 90's action film, which naturally makes the whole film more likable. Basil Wallace is plenty of fun as the interestingly named Screwface, all wide-eyed and using an over-accentuated Jamaican accent. The voodoo element is certainly different, and the practises shown in the film are apparently well-researched and accurate. Definitely one for the action junkies, but for me, it's a laughable nostalgia trip into an overly macho time, and ultimately a rather forgettable one. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unimpressive movie from the golden years of Seagal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    GOOD THINGS : I like two songs from this movie , both by Jimmy Cliff : "No justice" and "John Crow" . Cliff even makes appearance in the movie . I was good to see Joanna Pacula in small role of Leslie  expert of foreign cultures . She gives the best performance in the movie. The girl who plays the part of Screwface's ex-girlfriend is hot. It was also good to see Danny Trejo in a small episode. "MFD" has a little more budget than typical Seagal movie , so we get to see a little bit of Mexico and Jamaica. It was also interesting to use Jamaicans as the villains . Maybe the writers were inspired by the "Predator 2" ? "Marked for death " is certainly more watchable and better than all those straight to DVD crap movies Seagal is now making  BAD THINGS : but it doesn't mean it's a good movie . The characters in this movie are one-dimensional . The story is flat and lacks a heart . The acting is rather poor (with the exception of Pacula ) , especially from the actor who plays the main villain . All the fights and action sequences are rather unimpressive and not too exciting. Despite some decent budget "MFD" feels like a made for TV movie . The twist at the end could be impressive , but the movie hints it to us too early and not in subtle way . The romance between Seagal's character and Leslie seems forced , undeveloped and rather unnecessary. There are some attempts at making the characters more human and the dialogue tries very hard to be funny and cool , but both those efforts are fruitless. VERDICT : Nothing really worth watching . Still , it's one of Seagal better movies . His fans should be pleased . I give it 3/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Marked for death is a waste of time , stupid as anuthing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julesdil
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marked for death , is corny , i don't care i hate this film it is a story about Jamaican drug fdealers ,, oouuggg horrible the accent and dialouge goes into a childish form , kids will love this garbage but as an action film it is a cartoon , the violence is tame and horrible because the film has no realistic fights the revenge action scenes ares simple , ohhhhh , shoot em up , no death that is good. Steven is a bad actor and in this mutters a stupid plot and just puts you off , i mean the actors and characters are in some kind of wannabe good film but is only for you cheesy corny film lovers . Avoid anyone who is good.Overrated 15 certificate for moderate violence and language.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Seagal action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When DEA agent John Hatcher's partner is killed he decides it is time to retire as no matter how much they do and how many villains they arrest there is always somebody else waiting to take there place. When he returns to his home in Chicago he finds the Jamaican Posses are selling drugs. At first he doesn't want to get involved but eventually he has no choice and deals with one of the gang. This puts both him and his family firmly in the sights of Screwface, the gang's leader. After an attack on his home leaves his niece critically injured he sets about hunting Screwface down; a mission that will take him from Chicago to Jamaica and back again and everywhere he goes he fill have to take on Screwface's many men and the black magic they claim to wield. If you enjoyed other early Seagal films you are sure to like this as it is packed with bone crunching action; he frequently has to fight several thugs at once. As well as the expected martial arts action there is plenty of gunplay, a car chase and even a sword fight! The story isn't too deep but there is an unforgettable twist that first time viewers are sure to enjoy. Seagal isn't the best actor in the world but he knows how to do action so if that is what you want you won't be disappointed. Some of the Jamaican patois is a little hard to understand but that doesn't spoil anything as most of what they say can be guessed anyway it is nearly always a threat of some sort!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who and Where was there a "John Crow"?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael A. Martinez (aylmer666@juno.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one gets my vote for "best" Steven Seagal action picture. Sure UNDER SIEGE is slicker and more expensive, ABOVE THE LAW has a more serious and compelling story, and OUT FOR JUSTICE has Seagal at his self-righteously most over the top, but none of those are half as fun as this little gem. Admittedly the plot to this film is on the simplistic side and it takes itself quite seriously for the most part. Seagal here is an originally unwilling crusader against drug gangs and violence but of course kills more people and causes more mayhem and property damage than any cartel ever did. Already at this point was he starting to exhibit some of his quirky mannerisms (obvious stunt doubles and enigmatic heroes who disappear to let their lackies do the "boring" stuff) which turned into B-action tropes over the years. He also starts to find his own identity as a bonafide 80's era action star with snappy post-mortem one-liners and creative almost artfully balletic corpse-kills. A lot of the fun comes from the ethnocentrism at hand in the form of the ridiculousness assigned to the antagonistic Jamaican cartel. Their heavily accented dialog and Basil Wallace's performance as their leader makes it feel as though Seagal is up against a gang of cartoon characters. The movie casts aside any shred of realism and treats us to seeing Seagal cathartically and unemotionally taking down multiple adversaries at once without even breaking a sweat. This was the only film I think Seagal did for 20th Century Fox so perhaps that's why it breaks a mold a little bit and allows the villains to land a few punches on our mighty hero (not that it makes any difference). One cannot talk about this movie without mentioning Basil Wallace's delirious portrayal of perhaps the most emotionally unbalanced villain of any action movie, and that includes anything Vernon Wells has ever done. He enthusiastically incantates voodoo and mysticism with wild-eyed abandon in an effort to intimidate his posse, but it largely comes across as quite comical. He's the polar opposite of the wooden and inexpressive Seagal, who just sort of drifts around and looks annoyed when there's no more baddies to murder. Pathetically the film tries to go the PC route and with the casting of Jamaican Tom Wright as a vindictive Island cop and American black character actor Keith David as Seagal's buddy vigilante. Amazingly, David's character is the close-minded one and no chance is spared to teach him how Jamaica as a tough but unfortunate breeding ground for vermin, though mostly populated by mostly good people. I don't know if it was out of PC-ness or in keeping with the tone of the villainy in the film, but the soundtrack contains a lot of great reggae tracks, largely by the one and only Jimmy Cliff who even appears in the film as himself singing about the upcoming death of the film's villain (!). The film ends on a high note with a nonstop action spectacular and immediately rolls into one of the most unforgettable reggae songs of all time. I really don't know who John Crow was or what he had to do with anything (perhaps they changed Hatcher's name at some point during production?) but at least we got a great song out of it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie dates back to when Steven segal was making entertaining movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marcus Geebs
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marked For Death" is a lot of fun. most of Steven segals movies are made by warner bros but this one is made by 20th century fox. The plot is John Hatcher (Seagal) is a jaded DEA agent. After witnessing the death of his partner, he resigns from the force and vows to return to family life in a quiet neighborhood of Chicago. However, he arrives to find his hometown teeming with Jamaican drug dealers, headed by the psychotic voodoo cultist Screwface (Basil Wallace, Blood Diamond). Though he does his best to ignore the impending danger, Hatcher finds both himself and his family in the dealers' sights after interfering in an assassination attempt, prompting him to team up with an old military comrade (Keith David, "The Thing") and take the fight to the criminals. this film is not perfect. the points of incompetence are limited and don't permeate the entire picture.It's a shame that this movie isn't recalled as readily as some of our hero's other work, since it supplies the adrenaline just as well. Btw Steven segal gets beat up a little in this movie unlike some of his other films we don't see him get hit once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid Seagal vehicle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In one of his early vehicles with the three-word descriptive titles, Steven Seagal this time is fighting the war on drugs. Or, to be more accurate, he's out to annihilate the Jamaican drug pushers who've infiltrated his Chicago community. He didn't feel like doing so at first; he'd burned out while on the job as a DEA agent and realized that in order to win he'd become no better than his adversaries. It's only inevitable that he'll once again get motivated to righteous fury when his own family is victimized. The bad guys in these movies never ever learn that simple lesson - mess with the hero's loved ones and they're just as marked for death as the good guy. Here, Seagal showed that in the earlier years of his career how he really gave more of an effort and could be quite engaging. He's given a truly kick ass sidekick in the form of eternally cool Keith David, as the old buddy / football coach disgusted by what he sees around him. Also lending assistance are Jamaican cop Tom Wright and a professor played by Joanna Pacula. "Marked for Death" does its job in a number of areas; as directed by Dwight H. Little ("Halloween 4: The Return of Michael Myers", "Rapid Fire"), it hits the ground running, and delivers exactly what we as fans of Seagal movies expect: rampant brutality, with broken limbs aplenty, bullets in foreheads, bodies crashing through windows, impalement, eyes gouged out, etc. The topicality of the script does take a back seat to all of the violent action - there's always one great scene around the corner. There's even a little bit of nudity to spice things up. A major appeal of the movie is the soundtrack, which features some tunes by Jimmy Cliff, who also appears on screen performing with his band. The supporting cast is full of familiar faces - Kevin Dunn, Tony DiBenedetto, Peter Jason, Danny Trejo, Gary Carlos Cervantes, and Earl Boen, with Danielle Harris, whom Little had directed in "Halloween 4", in a bit as Seagal's niece. Basil Wallace, an actor who should have broken bigger after this, has enough intensity and charisma to make for an effective villain. All in all, "Marked for Death" is good fun and builds to a really good finale as well as an amusing twist and resulting final one-liner. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First Steven Seagal movie I seen...Well didn't make me a fan of his
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the first Steven Seagal movie I seen. So I wasn't familiar with his films but from what I know, he usually plays a arrogant and cocky character that goes after the bad guys without hardly ever getting hurt or breaking a sweat. So in another words it sounded like some absurd and ridiculous action movie with bunch of kung-fu thrown in and to some degree that is exactly what this movie is. In this Steven Seagal's character is a retired DEA after on a the line of duty things don't go according to plan. And now he is going after Jamaican drug dealers with dreadlocks and is in some sort of cult with a couple of friends after they mess with his loved ones. Yeah the plot is very very narrow and the villains are comical and not in a good way either. After just few minutes in the movie just seemed to drag, constantly putting excuse to put some action sequences in which this has a lot of. Steven Seagal beats people up while saying catch phrases, some works some just don't. Just about everything about this movie is generic and predictable and almost nothing is all that engaging. The fight sequences with Seagal using judo or aikido was sort of cool though and watchable thus I give this movie a 4.5 even if the acting is atrocious thus I am being generous. I will just say this movie didn't make me a fan of his. 4.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vintage Fun!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Marked for Death' is Vintage Fun. Power-Packed, Fast-Paced, Action-Packed & Loud, it has it all. Also, its damn cool to watch bad-ass Steven Seagal getting it right completely. 'Marked for Death' stars Seagal as John Hatcher, a former DEA troubleshooter. Upon moving back to his home town, Hatcher finds it taken over by a gang of vicious Jamaican drug dealers, led by the twisted Screwface. 'Marked for Death' is Power-Packed, Fast-Paced & Loud Cinema at its best. The film never loses pace & always keeps you engrossed. Michael Grais & Mark Victor's Screenplay is Great Fun. Dwight H. Little's Direction is decent. Cinematography & Editing are fair, while the Action-Sequences/Fights are awesome. Performance-Wise: Seagal gets it right completely. His fights are a pleasure to watch & does his part with great energy & style. Basil Wallace as the twisted Screface is frightening. Keith David is perfect. On the whole, 'Marked for Death' is Vintage Fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well, I liked 2 things, and one of them was Seagal's car !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all know that it is B grade B movie. The "afternoon" or "rainy night" kind of time filler. So I won't get harsh, though with the presence of Steven Seagal it's impossible not to ! After Seagal's first movie (Above the Law  1988), some critic said about the new rising star "He's a fine mix of John Wayne, Bruce Lee and Clint Eastwood". How deceived that miserable critic was ! In fact Seagal is nothing but another Charles Bronson yet with marital arts experience. Observe well Seagal's so-called acting to discover easily that he must have watched Bronson's Death Wish movies for countless times ! The conflict this round is some tough cop fighting some voodoo drug dealers. The friction of the two's worlds was done absurdly. That cop's violence is too much; he walks like a deadly epidemic that leaves no wounded guys, only corpses. The attack at the gang's headquarters reminded me of (Commando), 5 years earlier. However the real reason of bothering was Seagal himself. It's not about the eternal truth that he doesn't smile, or doesn't know the way to. It's about another thing. They gave him a little dialog, which is a good idea, till you know that it was filled with many one-liners. OK, how they got the nerve ?! That guy is the worst of the worst at delivering any one-liner ! Watch him saying "They were both wrong" or "I hope they weren't triplets"; if Tom from Tom and Jerry said these lines, he would be less awful and more cool than Mr. Steven-The Whispering Zombie-Seagal ! The action is average, but it works. In movies of that kind don't ask much, just watch the fights. In general I liked 2 things, one of them is Seagal's black car; it was a stunner for every guy back in the 1990s start. And the second is of course the surprise of the evil guy as alive; that trick of having a twin brother was excellent (that fake decapitated head was so real it's freaky too !). Other than that...Seagal's grins could have killed me ! P.S : I read that Seagal didn't want to make this movie, hating it openly from day one till now, so how come he produced it ?!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fleetingly entertaining but forgettable action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    DEA Agent John Hatcher (Steven Seagal) is busy kickin' ass in Colombia when he decides to make his return to the U.S. after some spiritual enlightenment from his priest. He returns to find his city overrun by Jamaican 'posses', and when at a bar, he and his old friend Max (Keith David) find themselves caught amidst a gang war shootout. Hatcher, naturally, kicks the s**t out of some of them and finds that he and his family have been 'marked for death' by gang boss Screwface (Basil Wallace). His sisters house is attacked and when his niece is shot, Hatcher and Max team up with Jamaican police man Charles (Tom Wright) to find Screwface and end his reign of terror. Clearly neither Screwface nor his ever-dispensable gang of cronies have ever seen a Steven Seagal film, or they would have left him the f**k alone. Guns, swords and even voodoo cannot stop the pony-tailed action hero. This is actually considered to be the 'finest' of Seagal's vast action backlog, which is quite tragic given that this film is pretty s**t. I will say this for it, however - it's relentlessly entertaining. Yet this derives from the unintentionally hilarious dialogue, woeful acting, some appallingly gruesome action scenes, and plot devices that simply defy logic. Possibly the funniest moment in the film has Hatcher, who has, by the way, just committed murder (he's retired from the police) and has to be the police's main suspect, taking part in a high speed chase through the city that sees one car drive along the pavement causing massive damage, only to later fly through the window of a department store. Hatcher walks in shooting and stabbing his way through the bad guys only to calmly stroll out afterwards. Surely the police would have noticed something during the carnage? Yes, yes, I'm missing the point, this is a dumb action film - this is hardly trying to be The Wire. Marked for Death does have the sense to show off Seagal's martial arts skills. While many of his other films have him mainly either carrying a gun or simply throwing people onto tables, this has him breaking many, many bones with his bare hands. It's shockingly gory for an 90's action film, which naturally makes the whole film more likable. Basil Wallace is plenty of fun as the interestingly named Screwface, all wide-eyed and using an over-accentuated Jamaican accent. The voodoo element is certainly different, and the practises shown in the film are apparently well-researched and accurate. Definitely one for the action junkies, but for me, it's a laughable nostalgia trip into an overly macho time, and ultimately a rather forgettable one. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unimpressive movie from the golden years of Seagal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    GOOD THINGS : I like two songs from this movie , both by Jimmy Cliff : "No justice" and "John Crow" . Cliff even makes appearance in the movie . I was good to see Joanna Pacula in small role of Leslie  expert of foreign cultures . She gives the best performance in the movie. The girl who plays the part of Screwface's ex-girlfriend is hot. It was also good to see Danny Trejo in a small episode. "MFD" has a little more budget than typical Seagal movie , so we get to see a little bit of Mexico and Jamaica. It was also interesting to use Jamaicans as the villains . Maybe the writers were inspired by the "Predator 2" ? "Marked for death " is certainly more watchable and better than all those straight to DVD crap movies Seagal is now making  BAD THINGS : but it doesn't mean it's a good movie . The characters in this movie are one-dimensional . The story is flat and lacks a heart . The acting is rather poor (with the exception of Pacula ) , especially from the actor who plays the main villain . All the fights and action sequences are rather unimpressive and not too exciting. Despite some decent budget "MFD" feels like a made for TV movie . The twist at the end could be impressive , but the movie hints it to us too early and not in subtle way . The romance between Seagal's character and Leslie seems forced , undeveloped and rather unnecessary. There are some attempts at making the characters more human and the dialogue tries very hard to be funny and cool , but both those efforts are fruitless. VERDICT : Nothing really worth watching . Still , it's one of Seagal better movies . His fans should be pleased . I give it 3/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Marked for death is a waste of time , stupid as anuthing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julesdil
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marked for death , is corny , i don't care i hate this film it is a story about Jamaican drug fdealers ,, oouuggg horrible the accent and dialouge goes into a childish form , kids will love this garbage but as an action film it is a cartoon , the violence is tame and horrible because the film has no realistic fights the revenge action scenes ares simple , ohhhhh , shoot em up , no death that is good. Steven is a bad actor and in this mutters a stupid plot and just puts you off , i mean the actors and characters are in some kind of wannabe good film but is only for you cheesy corny film lovers . Avoid anyone who is good.Overrated 15 certificate for moderate violence and language.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Seagal action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When DEA agent John Hatcher's partner is killed he decides it is time to retire as no matter how much they do and how many villains they arrest there is always somebody else waiting to take there place. When he returns to his home in Chicago he finds the Jamaican Posses are selling drugs. At first he doesn't want to get involved but eventually he has no choice and deals with one of the gang. This puts both him and his family firmly in the sights of Screwface, the gang's leader. After an attack on his home leaves his niece critically injured he sets about hunting Screwface down; a mission that will take him from Chicago to Jamaica and back again and everywhere he goes he fill have to take on Screwface's many men and the black magic they claim to wield. If you enjoyed other early Seagal films you are sure to like this as it is packed with bone crunching action; he frequently has to fight several thugs at once. As well as the expected martial arts action there is plenty of gunplay, a car chase and even a sword fight! The story isn't too deep but there is an unforgettable twist that first time viewers are sure to enjoy. Seagal isn't the best actor in the world but he knows how to do action so if that is what you want you won't be disappointed. Some of the Jamaican patois is a little hard to understand but that doesn't spoil anything as most of what they say can be guessed anyway it is nearly always a threat of some sort!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who and Where was there a "John Crow"?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael A. Martinez (aylmer666@juno.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one gets my vote for "best" Steven Seagal action picture. Sure UNDER SIEGE is slicker and more expensive, ABOVE THE LAW has a more serious and compelling story, and OUT FOR JUSTICE has Seagal at his self-righteously most over the top, but none of those are half as fun as this little gem. Admittedly the plot to this film is on the simplistic side and it takes itself quite seriously for the most part. Seagal here is an originally unwilling crusader against drug gangs and violence but of course kills more people and causes more mayhem and property damage than any cartel ever did. Already at this point was he starting to exhibit some of his quirky mannerisms (obvious stunt doubles and enigmatic heroes who disappear to let their lackies do the "boring" stuff) which turned into B-action tropes over the years. He also starts to find his own identity as a bonafide 80's era action star with snappy post-mortem one-liners and creative almost artfully balletic corpse-kills. A lot of the fun comes from the ethnocentrism at hand in the form of the ridiculousness assigned to the antagonistic Jamaican cartel. Their heavily accented dialog and Basil Wallace's performance as their leader makes it feel as though Seagal is up against a gang of cartoon characters. The movie casts aside any shred of realism and treats us to seeing Seagal cathartically and unemotionally taking down multiple adversaries at once without even breaking a sweat. This was the only film I think Seagal did for 20th Century Fox so perhaps that's why it breaks a mold a little bit and allows the villains to land a few punches on our mighty hero (not that it makes any difference). One cannot talk about this movie without mentioning Basil Wallace's delirious portrayal of perhaps the most emotionally unbalanced villain of any action movie, and that includes anything Vernon Wells has ever done. He enthusiastically incantates voodoo and mysticism with wild-eyed abandon in an effort to intimidate his posse, but it largely comes across as quite comical. He's the polar opposite of the wooden and inexpressive Seagal, who just sort of drifts around and looks annoyed when there's no more baddies to murder. Pathetically the film tries to go the PC route and with the casting of Jamaican Tom Wright as a vindictive Island cop and American black character actor Keith David as Seagal's buddy vigilante. Amazingly, David's character is the close-minded one and no chance is spared to teach him how Jamaica as a tough but unfortunate breeding ground for vermin, though mostly populated by mostly good people. I don't know if it was out of PC-ness or in keeping with the tone of the villainy in the film, but the soundtrack contains a lot of great reggae tracks, largely by the one and only Jimmy Cliff who even appears in the film as himself singing about the upcoming death of the film's villain (!). The film ends on a high note with a nonstop action spectacular and immediately rolls into one of the most unforgettable reggae songs of all time. I really don't know who John Crow was or what he had to do with anything (perhaps they changed Hatcher's name at some point during production?) but at least we got a great song out of it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie dates back to when Steven segal was making entertaining movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marcus Geebs
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marked For Death" is a lot of fun. most of Steven segals movies are made by warner bros but this one is made by 20th century fox. The plot is John Hatcher (Seagal) is a jaded DEA agent. After witnessing the death of his partner, he resigns from the force and vows to return to family life in a quiet neighborhood of Chicago. However, he arrives to find his hometown teeming with Jamaican drug dealers, headed by the psychotic voodoo cultist Screwface (Basil Wallace, Blood Diamond). Though he does his best to ignore the impending danger, Hatcher finds both himself and his family in the dealers' sights after interfering in an assassination attempt, prompting him to team up with an old military comrade (Keith David, "The Thing") and take the fight to the criminals. this film is not perfect. the points of incompetence are limited and don't permeate the entire picture.It's a shame that this movie isn't recalled as readily as some of our hero's other work, since it supplies the adrenaline just as well. Btw Steven segal gets beat up a little in this movie unlike some of his other films we don't see him get hit once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid Seagal vehicle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In one of his early vehicles with the three-word descriptive titles, Steven Seagal this time is fighting the war on drugs. Or, to be more accurate, he's out to annihilate the Jamaican drug pushers who've infiltrated his Chicago community. He didn't feel like doing so at first; he'd burned out while on the job as a DEA agent and realized that in order to win he'd become no better than his adversaries. It's only inevitable that he'll once again get motivated to righteous fury when his own family is victimized. The bad guys in these movies never ever learn that simple lesson - mess with the hero's loved ones and they're just as marked for death as the good guy. Here, Seagal showed that in the earlier years of his career how he really gave more of an effort and could be quite engaging. He's given a truly kick ass sidekick in the form of eternally cool Keith David, as the old buddy / football coach disgusted by what he sees around him. Also lending assistance are Jamaican cop Tom Wright and a professor played by Joanna Pacula. "Marked for Death" does its job in a number of areas; as directed by Dwight H. Little ("Halloween 4: The Return of Michael Myers", "Rapid Fire"), it hits the ground running, and delivers exactly what we as fans of Seagal movies expect: rampant brutality, with broken limbs aplenty, bullets in foreheads, bodies crashing through windows, impalement, eyes gouged out, etc. The topicality of the script does take a back seat to all of the violent action - there's always one great scene around the corner. There's even a little bit of nudity to spice things up. A major appeal of the movie is the soundtrack, which features some tunes by Jimmy Cliff, who also appears on screen performing with his band. The supporting cast is full of familiar faces - Kevin Dunn, Tony DiBenedetto, Peter Jason, Danny Trejo, Gary Carlos Cervantes, and Earl Boen, with Danielle Harris, whom Little had directed in "Halloween 4", in a bit as Seagal's niece. Basil Wallace, an actor who should have broken bigger after this, has enough intensity and charisma to make for an effective villain. All in all, "Marked for Death" is good fun and builds to a really good finale as well as an amusing twist and resulting final one-liner. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First Steven Seagal movie I seen...Well didn't make me a fan of his
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the first Steven Seagal movie I seen. So I wasn't familiar with his films but from what I know, he usually plays a arrogant and cocky character that goes after the bad guys without hardly ever getting hurt or breaking a sweat. So in another words it sounded like some absurd and ridiculous action movie with bunch of kung-fu thrown in and to some degree that is exactly what this movie is. In this Steven Seagal's character is a retired DEA after on a the line of duty things don't go according to plan. And now he is going after Jamaican drug dealers with dreadlocks and is in some sort of cult with a couple of friends after they mess with his loved ones. Yeah the plot is very very narrow and the villains are comical and not in a good way either. After just few minutes in the movie just seemed to drag, constantly putting excuse to put some action sequences in which this has a lot of. Steven Seagal beats people up while saying catch phrases, some works some just don't. Just about everything about this movie is generic and predictable and almost nothing is all that engaging. The fight sequences with Seagal using judo or aikido was sort of cool though and watchable thus I give this movie a 4.5 even if the acting is atrocious thus I am being generous. I will just say this movie didn't make me a fan of his. 4.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vintage Fun!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Marked for Death' is Vintage Fun. Power-Packed, Fast-Paced, Action-Packed & Loud, it has it all. Also, its damn cool to watch bad-ass Steven Seagal getting it right completely. 'Marked for Death' stars Seagal as John Hatcher, a former DEA troubleshooter. Upon moving back to his home town, Hatcher finds it taken over by a gang of vicious Jamaican drug dealers, led by the twisted Screwface. 'Marked for Death' is Power-Packed, Fast-Paced & Loud Cinema at its best. The film never loses pace & always keeps you engrossed. Michael Grais & Mark Victor's Screenplay is Great Fun. Dwight H. Little's Direction is decent. Cinematography & Editing are fair, while the Action-Sequences/Fights are awesome. Performance-Wise: Seagal gets it right completely. His fights are a pleasure to watch & does his part with great energy & style. Basil Wallace as the twisted Screface is frightening. Keith David is perfect. On the whole, 'Marked for Death' is Vintage Fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well, I liked 2 things, and one of them was Seagal's car !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all know that it is B grade B movie. The "afternoon" or "rainy night" kind of time filler. So I won't get harsh, though with the presence of Steven Seagal it's impossible not to ! After Seagal's first movie (Above the Law  1988), some critic said about the new rising star "He's a fine mix of John Wayne, Bruce Lee and Clint Eastwood". How deceived that miserable critic was ! In fact Seagal is nothing but another Charles Bronson yet with marital arts experience. Observe well Seagal's so-called acting to discover easily that he must have watched Bronson's Death Wish movies for countless times ! The conflict this round is some tough cop fighting some voodoo drug dealers. The friction of the two's worlds was done absurdly. That cop's violence is too much; he walks like a deadly epidemic that leaves no wounded guys, only corpses. The attack at the gang's headquarters reminded me of (Commando), 5 years earlier. However the real reason of bothering was Seagal himself. It's not about the eternal truth that he doesn't smile, or doesn't know the way to. It's about another thing. They gave him a little dialog, which is a good idea, till you know that it was filled with many one-liners. OK, how they got the nerve ?! That guy is the worst of the worst at delivering any one-liner ! Watch him saying "They were both wrong" or "I hope they weren't triplets"; if Tom from Tom and Jerry said these lines, he would be less awful and more cool than Mr. Steven-The Whispering Zombie-Seagal ! The action is average, but it works. In movies of that kind don't ask much, just watch the fights. In general I liked 2 things, one of them is Seagal's black car; it was a stunner for every guy back in the 1990s start. And the second is of course the surprise of the evil guy as alive; that trick of having a twin brother was excellent (that fake decapitated head was so real it's freaky too !). Other than that...Seagal's grins could have killed me ! P.S : I read that Seagal didn't want to make this movie, hating it openly from day one till now, so how come he produced it ?!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fleetingly entertaining but forgettable action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    DEA Agent John Hatcher (Steven Seagal) is busy kickin' ass in Colombia when he decides to make his return to the U.S. after some spiritual enlightenment from his priest. He returns to find his city overrun by Jamaican 'posses', and when at a bar, he and his old friend Max (Keith David) find themselves caught amidst a gang war shootout. Hatcher, naturally, kicks the s**t out of some of them and finds that he and his family have been 'marked for death' by gang boss Screwface (Basil Wallace). His sisters house is attacked and when his niece is shot, Hatcher and Max team up with Jamaican police man Charles (Tom Wright) to find Screwface and end his reign of terror. Clearly neither Screwface nor his ever-dispensable gang of cronies have ever seen a Steven Seagal film, or they would have left him the f**k alone. Guns, swords and even voodoo cannot stop the pony-tailed action hero. This is actually considered to be the 'finest' of Seagal's vast action backlog, which is quite tragic given that this film is pretty s**t. I will say this for it, however - it's relentlessly entertaining. Yet this derives from the unintentionally hilarious dialogue, woeful acting, some appallingly gruesome action scenes, and plot devices that simply defy logic. Possibly the funniest moment in the film has Hatcher, who has, by the way, just committed murder (he's retired from the police) and has to be the police's main suspect, taking part in a high speed chase through the city that sees one car drive along the pavement causing massive damage, only to later fly through the window of a department store. Hatcher walks in shooting and stabbing his way through the bad guys only to calmly stroll out afterwards. Surely the police would have noticed something during the carnage? Yes, yes, I'm missing the point, this is a dumb action film - this is hardly trying to be The Wire. Marked for Death does have the sense to show off Seagal's martial arts skills. While many of his other films have him mainly either carrying a gun or simply throwing people onto tables, this has him breaking many, many bones with his bare hands. It's shockingly gory for an 90's action film, which naturally makes the whole film more likable. Basil Wallace is plenty of fun as the interestingly named Screwface, all wide-eyed and using an over-accentuated Jamaican accent. The voodoo element is certainly different, and the practises shown in the film are apparently well-researched and accurate. Definitely one for the action junkies, but for me, it's a laughable nostalgia trip into an overly macho time, and ultimately a rather forgettable one. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unimpressive movie from the golden years of Seagal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    GOOD THINGS : I like two songs from this movie , both by Jimmy Cliff : "No justice" and "John Crow" . Cliff even makes appearance in the movie . I was good to see Joanna Pacula in small role of Leslie  expert of foreign cultures . She gives the best performance in the movie. The girl who plays the part of Screwface's ex-girlfriend is hot. It was also good to see Danny Trejo in a small episode. "MFD" has a little more budget than typical Seagal movie , so we get to see a little bit of Mexico and Jamaica. It was also interesting to use Jamaicans as the villains . Maybe the writers were inspired by the "Predator 2" ? "Marked for death " is certainly more watchable and better than all those straight to DVD crap movies Seagal is now making  BAD THINGS : but it doesn't mean it's a good movie . The characters in this movie are one-dimensional . The story is flat and lacks a heart . The acting is rather poor (with the exception of Pacula ) , especially from the actor who plays the main villain . All the fights and action sequences are rather unimpressive and not too exciting. Despite some decent budget "MFD" feels like a made for TV movie . The twist at the end could be impressive , but the movie hints it to us too early and not in subtle way . The romance between Seagal's character and Leslie seems forced , undeveloped and rather unnecessary. There are some attempts at making the characters more human and the dialogue tries very hard to be funny and cool , but both those efforts are fruitless. VERDICT : Nothing really worth watching . Still , it's one of Seagal better movies . His fans should be pleased . I give it 3/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Marked for death is a waste of time , stupid as anuthing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julesdil
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marked for death , is corny , i don't care i hate this film it is a story about Jamaican drug fdealers ,, oouuggg horrible the accent and dialouge goes into a childish form , kids will love this garbage but as an action film it is a cartoon , the violence is tame and horrible because the film has no realistic fights the revenge action scenes ares simple , ohhhhh , shoot em up , no death that is good. Steven is a bad actor and in this mutters a stupid plot and just puts you off , i mean the actors and characters are in some kind of wannabe good film but is only for you cheesy corny film lovers . Avoid anyone who is good.Overrated 15 certificate for moderate violence and language.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Seagal action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When DEA agent John Hatcher's partner is killed he decides it is time to retire as no matter how much they do and how many villains they arrest there is always somebody else waiting to take there place. When he returns to his home in Chicago he finds the Jamaican Posses are selling drugs. At first he doesn't want to get involved but eventually he has no choice and deals with one of the gang. This puts both him and his family firmly in the sights of Screwface, the gang's leader. After an attack on his home leaves his niece critically injured he sets about hunting Screwface down; a mission that will take him from Chicago to Jamaica and back again and everywhere he goes he fill have to take on Screwface's many men and the black magic they claim to wield. If you enjoyed other early Seagal films you are sure to like this as it is packed with bone crunching action; he frequently has to fight several thugs at once. As well as the expected martial arts action there is plenty of gunplay, a car chase and even a sword fight! The story isn't too deep but there is an unforgettable twist that first time viewers are sure to enjoy. Seagal isn't the best actor in the world but he knows how to do action so if that is what you want you won't be disappointed. Some of the Jamaican patois is a little hard to understand but that doesn't spoil anything as most of what they say can be guessed anyway it is nearly always a threat of some sort!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who and Where was there a "John Crow"?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael A. Martinez (aylmer666@juno.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one gets my vote for "best" Steven Seagal action picture. Sure UNDER SIEGE is slicker and more expensive, ABOVE THE LAW has a more serious and compelling story, and OUT FOR JUSTICE has Seagal at his self-righteously most over the top, but none of those are half as fun as this little gem. Admittedly the plot to this film is on the simplistic side and it takes itself quite seriously for the most part. Seagal here is an originally unwilling crusader against drug gangs and violence but of course kills more people and causes more mayhem and property damage than any cartel ever did. Already at this point was he starting to exhibit some of his quirky mannerisms (obvious stunt doubles and enigmatic heroes who disappear to let their lackies do the "boring" stuff) which turned into B-action tropes over the years. He also starts to find his own identity as a bonafide 80's era action star with snappy post-mortem one-liners and creative almost artfully balletic corpse-kills. A lot of the fun comes from the ethnocentrism at hand in the form of the ridiculousness assigned to the antagonistic Jamaican cartel. Their heavily accented dialog and Basil Wallace's performance as their leader makes it feel as though Seagal is up against a gang of cartoon characters. The movie casts aside any shred of realism and treats us to seeing Seagal cathartically and unemotionally taking down multiple adversaries at once without even breaking a sweat. This was the only film I think Seagal did for 20th Century Fox so perhaps that's why it breaks a mold a little bit and allows the villains to land a few punches on our mighty hero (not that it makes any difference). One cannot talk about this movie without mentioning Basil Wallace's delirious portrayal of perhaps the most emotionally unbalanced villain of any action movie, and that includes anything Vernon Wells has ever done. He enthusiastically incantates voodoo and mysticism with wild-eyed abandon in an effort to intimidate his posse, but it largely comes across as quite comical. He's the polar opposite of the wooden and inexpressive Seagal, who just sort of drifts around and looks annoyed when there's no more baddies to murder. Pathetically the film tries to go the PC route and with the casting of Jamaican Tom Wright as a vindictive Island cop and American black character actor Keith David as Seagal's buddy vigilante. Amazingly, David's character is the close-minded one and no chance is spared to teach him how Jamaica as a tough but unfortunate breeding ground for vermin, though mostly populated by mostly good people. I don't know if it was out of PC-ness or in keeping with the tone of the villainy in the film, but the soundtrack contains a lot of great reggae tracks, largely by the one and only Jimmy Cliff who even appears in the film as himself singing about the upcoming death of the film's villain (!). The film ends on a high note with a nonstop action spectacular and immediately rolls into one of the most unforgettable reggae songs of all time. I really don't know who John Crow was or what he had to do with anything (perhaps they changed Hatcher's name at some point during production?) but at least we got a great song out of it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie dates back to when Steven segal was making entertaining movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marcus Geebs
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marked For Death" is a lot of fun. most of Steven segals movies are made by warner bros but this one is made by 20th century fox. The plot is John Hatcher (Seagal) is a jaded DEA agent. After witnessing the death of his partner, he resigns from the force and vows to return to family life in a quiet neighborhood of Chicago. However, he arrives to find his hometown teeming with Jamaican drug dealers, headed by the psychotic voodoo cultist Screwface (Basil Wallace, Blood Diamond). Though he does his best to ignore the impending danger, Hatcher finds both himself and his family in the dealers' sights after interfering in an assassination attempt, prompting him to team up with an old military comrade (Keith David, "The Thing") and take the fight to the criminals. this film is not perfect. the points of incompetence are limited and don't permeate the entire picture.It's a shame that this movie isn't recalled as readily as some of our hero's other work, since it supplies the adrenaline just as well. Btw Steven segal gets beat up a little in this movie unlike some of his other films we don't see him get hit once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid Seagal vehicle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In one of his early vehicles with the three-word descriptive titles, Steven Seagal this time is fighting the war on drugs. Or, to be more accurate, he's out to annihilate the Jamaican drug pushers who've infiltrated his Chicago community. He didn't feel like doing so at first; he'd burned out while on the job as a DEA agent and realized that in order to win he'd become no better than his adversaries. It's only inevitable that he'll once again get motivated to righteous fury when his own family is victimized. The bad guys in these movies never ever learn that simple lesson - mess with the hero's loved ones and they're just as marked for death as the good guy. Here, Seagal showed that in the earlier years of his career how he really gave more of an effort and could be quite engaging. He's given a truly kick ass sidekick in the form of eternally cool Keith David, as the old buddy / football coach disgusted by what he sees around him. Also lending assistance are Jamaican cop Tom Wright and a professor played by Joanna Pacula. "Marked for Death" does its job in a number of areas; as directed by Dwight H. Little ("Halloween 4: The Return of Michael Myers", "Rapid Fire"), it hits the ground running, and delivers exactly what we as fans of Seagal movies expect: rampant brutality, with broken limbs aplenty, bullets in foreheads, bodies crashing through windows, impalement, eyes gouged out, etc. The topicality of the script does take a back seat to all of the violent action - there's always one great scene around the corner. There's even a little bit of nudity to spice things up. A major appeal of the movie is the soundtrack, which features some tunes by Jimmy Cliff, who also appears on screen performing with his band. The supporting cast is full of familiar faces - Kevin Dunn, Tony DiBenedetto, Peter Jason, Danny Trejo, Gary Carlos Cervantes, and Earl Boen, with Danielle Harris, whom Little had directed in "Halloween 4", in a bit as Seagal's niece. Basil Wallace, an actor who should have broken bigger after this, has enough intensity and charisma to make for an effective villain. All in all, "Marked for Death" is good fun and builds to a really good finale as well as an amusing twist and resulting final one-liner. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First Steven Seagal movie I seen...Well didn't make me a fan of his
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the first Steven Seagal movie I seen. So I wasn't familiar with his films but from what I know, he usually plays a arrogant and cocky character that goes after the bad guys without hardly ever getting hurt or breaking a sweat. So in another words it sounded like some absurd and ridiculous action movie with bunch of kung-fu thrown in and to some degree that is exactly what this movie is. In this Steven Seagal's character is a retired DEA after on a the line of duty things don't go according to plan. And now he is going after Jamaican drug dealers with dreadlocks and is in some sort of cult with a couple of friends after they mess with his loved ones. Yeah the plot is very very narrow and the villains are comical and not in a good way either. After just few minutes in the movie just seemed to drag, constantly putting excuse to put some action sequences in which this has a lot of. Steven Seagal beats people up while saying catch phrases, some works some just don't. Just about everything about this movie is generic and predictable and almost nothing is all that engaging. The fight sequences with Seagal using judo or aikido was sort of cool though and watchable thus I give this movie a 4.5 even if the acting is atrocious thus I am being generous. I will just say this movie didn't make me a fan of his. 4.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vintage Fun!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Marked for Death' is Vintage Fun. Power-Packed, Fast-Paced, Action-Packed & Loud, it has it all. Also, its damn cool to watch bad-ass Steven Seagal getting it right completely. 'Marked for Death' stars Seagal as John Hatcher, a former DEA troubleshooter. Upon moving back to his home town, Hatcher finds it taken over by a gang of vicious Jamaican drug dealers, led by the twisted Screwface. 'Marked for Death' is Power-Packed, Fast-Paced & Loud Cinema at its best. The film never loses pace & always keeps you engrossed. Michael Grais & Mark Victor's Screenplay is Great Fun. Dwight H. Little's Direction is decent. Cinematography & Editing are fair, while the Action-Sequences/Fights are awesome. Performance-Wise: Seagal gets it right completely. His fights are a pleasure to watch & does his part with great energy & style. Basil Wallace as the twisted Screface is frightening. Keith David is perfect. On the whole, 'Marked for Death' is Vintage Fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well, I liked 2 things, and one of them was Seagal's car !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all know that it is B grade B movie. The "afternoon" or "rainy night" kind of time filler. So I won't get harsh, though with the presence of Steven Seagal it's impossible not to ! After Seagal's first movie (Above the Law  1988), some critic said about the new rising star "He's a fine mix of John Wayne, Bruce Lee and Clint Eastwood". How deceived that miserable critic was ! In fact Seagal is nothing but another Charles Bronson yet with marital arts experience. Observe well Seagal's so-called acting to discover easily that he must have watched Bronson's Death Wish movies for countless times ! The conflict this round is some tough cop fighting some voodoo drug dealers. The friction of the two's worlds was done absurdly. That cop's violence is too much; he walks like a deadly epidemic that leaves no wounded guys, only corpses. The attack at the gang's headquarters reminded me of (Commando), 5 years earlier. However the real reason of bothering was Seagal himself. It's not about the eternal truth that he doesn't smile, or doesn't know the way to. It's about another thing. They gave him a little dialog, which is a good idea, till you know that it was filled with many one-liners. OK, how they got the nerve ?! That guy is the worst of the worst at delivering any one-liner ! Watch him saying "They were both wrong" or "I hope they weren't triplets"; if Tom from Tom and Jerry said these lines, he would be less awful and more cool than Mr. Steven-The Whispering Zombie-Seagal ! The action is average, but it works. In movies of that kind don't ask much, just watch the fights. In general I liked 2 things, one of them is Seagal's black car; it was a stunner for every guy back in the 1990s start. And the second is of course the surprise of the evil guy as alive; that trick of having a twin brother was excellent (that fake decapitated head was so real it's freaky too !). Other than that...Seagal's grins could have killed me ! P.S : I read that Seagal didn't want to make this movie, hating it openly from day one till now, so how come he produced it ?!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fleetingly entertaining but forgettable action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    DEA Agent John Hatcher (Steven Seagal) is busy kickin' ass in Colombia when he decides to make his return to the U.S. after some spiritual enlightenment from his priest. He returns to find his city overrun by Jamaican 'posses', and when at a bar, he and his old friend Max (Keith David) find themselves caught amidst a gang war shootout. Hatcher, naturally, kicks the s**t out of some of them and finds that he and his family have been 'marked for death' by gang boss Screwface (Basil Wallace). His sisters house is attacked and when his niece is shot, Hatcher and Max team up with Jamaican police man Charles (Tom Wright) to find Screwface and end his reign of terror. Clearly neither Screwface nor his ever-dispensable gang of cronies have ever seen a Steven Seagal film, or they would have left him the f**k alone. Guns, swords and even voodoo cannot stop the pony-tailed action hero. This is actually considered to be the 'finest' of Seagal's vast action backlog, which is quite tragic given that this film is pretty s**t. I will say this for it, however - it's relentlessly entertaining. Yet this derives from the unintentionally hilarious dialogue, woeful acting, some appallingly gruesome action scenes, and plot devices that simply defy logic. Possibly the funniest moment in the film has Hatcher, who has, by the way, just committed murder (he's retired from the police) and has to be the police's main suspect, taking part in a high speed chase through the city that sees one car drive along the pavement causing massive damage, only to later fly through the window of a department store. Hatcher walks in shooting and stabbing his way through the bad guys only to calmly stroll out afterwards. Surely the police would have noticed something during the carnage? Yes, yes, I'm missing the point, this is a dumb action film - this is hardly trying to be The Wire. Marked for Death does have the sense to show off Seagal's martial arts skills. While many of his other films have him mainly either carrying a gun or simply throwing people onto tables, this has him breaking many, many bones with his bare hands. It's shockingly gory for an 90's action film, which naturally makes the whole film more likable. Basil Wallace is plenty of fun as the interestingly named Screwface, all wide-eyed and using an over-accentuated Jamaican accent. The voodoo element is certainly different, and the practises shown in the film are apparently well-researched and accurate. Definitely one for the action junkies, but for me, it's a laughable nostalgia trip into an overly macho time, and ultimately a rather forgettable one. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unimpressive movie from the golden years of Seagal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    GOOD THINGS : I like two songs from this movie , both by Jimmy Cliff : "No justice" and "John Crow" . Cliff even makes appearance in the movie . I was good to see Joanna Pacula in small role of Leslie  expert of foreign cultures . She gives the best performance in the movie. The girl who plays the part of Screwface's ex-girlfriend is hot. It was also good to see Danny Trejo in a small episode. "MFD" has a little more budget than typical Seagal movie , so we get to see a little bit of Mexico and Jamaica. It was also interesting to use Jamaicans as the villains . Maybe the writers were inspired by the "Predator 2" ? "Marked for death " is certainly more watchable and better than all those straight to DVD crap movies Seagal is now making  BAD THINGS : but it doesn't mean it's a good movie . The characters in this movie are one-dimensional . The story is flat and lacks a heart . The acting is rather poor (with the exception of Pacula ) , especially from the actor who plays the main villain . All the fights and action sequences are rather unimpressive and not too exciting. Despite some decent budget "MFD" feels like a made for TV movie . The twist at the end could be impressive , but the movie hints it to us too early and not in subtle way . The romance between Seagal's character and Leslie seems forced , undeveloped and rather unnecessary. There are some attempts at making the characters more human and the dialogue tries very hard to be funny and cool , but both those efforts are fruitless. VERDICT : Nothing really worth watching . Still , it's one of Seagal better movies . His fans should be pleased . I give it 3/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Marked for death is a waste of time , stupid as anuthing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julesdil
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marked for death , is corny , i don't care i hate this film it is a story about Jamaican drug fdealers ,, oouuggg horrible the accent and dialouge goes into a childish form , kids will love this garbage but as an action film it is a cartoon , the violence is tame and horrible because the film has no realistic fights the revenge action scenes ares simple , ohhhhh , shoot em up , no death that is good. Steven is a bad actor and in this mutters a stupid plot and just puts you off , i mean the actors and characters are in some kind of wannabe good film but is only for you cheesy corny film lovers . Avoid anyone who is good.Overrated 15 certificate for moderate violence and language.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Seagal action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When DEA agent John Hatcher's partner is killed he decides it is time to retire as no matter how much they do and how many villains they arrest there is always somebody else waiting to take there place. When he returns to his home in Chicago he finds the Jamaican Posses are selling drugs. At first he doesn't want to get involved but eventually he has no choice and deals with one of the gang. This puts both him and his family firmly in the sights of Screwface, the gang's leader. After an attack on his home leaves his niece critically injured he sets about hunting Screwface down; a mission that will take him from Chicago to Jamaica and back again and everywhere he goes he fill have to take on Screwface's many men and the black magic they claim to wield. If you enjoyed other early Seagal films you are sure to like this as it is packed with bone crunching action; he frequently has to fight several thugs at once. As well as the expected martial arts action there is plenty of gunplay, a car chase and even a sword fight! The story isn't too deep but there is an unforgettable twist that first time viewers are sure to enjoy. Seagal isn't the best actor in the world but he knows how to do action so if that is what you want you won't be disappointed. Some of the Jamaican patois is a little hard to understand but that doesn't spoil anything as most of what they say can be guessed anyway it is nearly always a threat of some sort!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who and Where was there a "John Crow"?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael A. Martinez (aylmer666@juno.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one gets my vote for "best" Steven Seagal action picture. Sure UNDER SIEGE is slicker and more expensive, ABOVE THE LAW has a more serious and compelling story, and OUT FOR JUSTICE has Seagal at his self-righteously most over the top, but none of those are half as fun as this little gem. Admittedly the plot to this film is on the simplistic side and it takes itself quite seriously for the most part. Seagal here is an originally unwilling crusader against drug gangs and violence but of course kills more people and causes more mayhem and property damage than any cartel ever did. Already at this point was he starting to exhibit some of his quirky mannerisms (obvious stunt doubles and enigmatic heroes who disappear to let their lackies do the "boring" stuff) which turned into B-action tropes over the years. He also starts to find his own identity as a bonafide 80's era action star with snappy post-mortem one-liners and creative almost artfully balletic corpse-kills. A lot of the fun comes from the ethnocentrism at hand in the form of the ridiculousness assigned to the antagonistic Jamaican cartel. Their heavily accented dialog and Basil Wallace's performance as their leader makes it feel as though Seagal is up against a gang of cartoon characters. The movie casts aside any shred of realism and treats us to seeing Seagal cathartically and unemotionally taking down multiple adversaries at once without even breaking a sweat. This was the only film I think Seagal did for 20th Century Fox so perhaps that's why it breaks a mold a little bit and allows the villains to land a few punches on our mighty hero (not that it makes any difference). One cannot talk about this movie without mentioning Basil Wallace's delirious portrayal of perhaps the most emotionally unbalanced villain of any action movie, and that includes anything Vernon Wells has ever done. He enthusiastically incantates voodoo and mysticism with wild-eyed abandon in an effort to intimidate his posse, but it largely comes across as quite comical. He's the polar opposite of the wooden and inexpressive Seagal, who just sort of drifts around and looks annoyed when there's no more baddies to murder. Pathetically the film tries to go the PC route and with the casting of Jamaican Tom Wright as a vindictive Island cop and American black character actor Keith David as Seagal's buddy vigilante. Amazingly, David's character is the close-minded one and no chance is spared to teach him how Jamaica as a tough but unfortunate breeding ground for vermin, though mostly populated by mostly good people. I don't know if it was out of PC-ness or in keeping with the tone of the villainy in the film, but the soundtrack contains a lot of great reggae tracks, largely by the one and only Jimmy Cliff who even appears in the film as himself singing about the upcoming death of the film's villain (!). The film ends on a high note with a nonstop action spectacular and immediately rolls into one of the most unforgettable reggae songs of all time. I really don't know who John Crow was or what he had to do with anything (perhaps they changed Hatcher's name at some point during production?) but at least we got a great song out of it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie dates back to when Steven segal was making entertaining movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marcus Geebs
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marked For Death" is a lot of fun. most of Steven segals movies are made by warner bros but this one is made by 20th century fox. The plot is John Hatcher (Seagal) is a jaded DEA agent. After witnessing the death of his partner, he resigns from the force and vows to return to family life in a quiet neighborhood of Chicago. However, he arrives to find his hometown teeming with Jamaican drug dealers, headed by the psychotic voodoo cultist Screwface (Basil Wallace, Blood Diamond). Though he does his best to ignore the impending danger, Hatcher finds both himself and his family in the dealers' sights after interfering in an assassination attempt, prompting him to team up with an old military comrade (Keith David, "The Thing") and take the fight to the criminals. this film is not perfect. the points of incompetence are limited and don't permeate the entire picture.It's a shame that this movie isn't recalled as readily as some of our hero's other work, since it supplies the adrenaline just as well. Btw Steven segal gets beat up a little in this movie unlike some of his other films we don't see him get hit once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid Seagal vehicle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In one of his early vehicles with the three-word descriptive titles, Steven Seagal this time is fighting the war on drugs. Or, to be more accurate, he's out to annihilate the Jamaican drug pushers who've infiltrated his Chicago community. He didn't feel like doing so at first; he'd burned out while on the job as a DEA agent and realized that in order to win he'd become no better than his adversaries. It's only inevitable that he'll once again get motivated to righteous fury when his own family is victimized. The bad guys in these movies never ever learn that simple lesson - mess with the hero's loved ones and they're just as marked for death as the good guy. Here, Seagal showed that in the earlier years of his career how he really gave more of an effort and could be quite engaging. He's given a truly kick ass sidekick in the form of eternally cool Keith David, as the old buddy / football coach disgusted by what he sees around him. Also lending assistance are Jamaican cop Tom Wright and a professor played by Joanna Pacula. "Marked for Death" does its job in a number of areas; as directed by Dwight H. Little ("Halloween 4: The Return of Michael Myers", "Rapid Fire"), it hits the ground running, and delivers exactly what we as fans of Seagal movies expect: rampant brutality, with broken limbs aplenty, bullets in foreheads, bodies crashing through windows, impalement, eyes gouged out, etc. The topicality of the script does take a back seat to all of the violent action - there's always one great scene around the corner. There's even a little bit of nudity to spice things up. A major appeal of the movie is the soundtrack, which features some tunes by Jimmy Cliff, who also appears on screen performing with his band. The supporting cast is full of familiar faces - Kevin Dunn, Tony DiBenedetto, Peter Jason, Danny Trejo, Gary Carlos Cervantes, and Earl Boen, with Danielle Harris, whom Little had directed in "Halloween 4", in a bit as Seagal's niece. Basil Wallace, an actor who should have broken bigger after this, has enough intensity and charisma to make for an effective villain. All in all, "Marked for Death" is good fun and builds to a really good finale as well as an amusing twist and resulting final one-liner. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First Steven Seagal movie I seen...Well didn't make me a fan of his
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the first Steven Seagal movie I seen. So I wasn't familiar with his films but from what I know, he usually plays a arrogant and cocky character that goes after the bad guys without hardly ever getting hurt or breaking a sweat. So in another words it sounded like some absurd and ridiculous action movie with bunch of kung-fu thrown in and to some degree that is exactly what this movie is. In this Steven Seagal's character is a retired DEA after on a the line of duty things don't go according to plan. And now he is going after Jamaican drug dealers with dreadlocks and is in some sort of cult with a couple of friends after they mess with his loved ones. Yeah the plot is very very narrow and the villains are comical and not in a good way either. After just few minutes in the movie just seemed to drag, constantly putting excuse to put some action sequences in which this has a lot of. Steven Seagal beats people up while saying catch phrases, some works some just don't. Just about everything about this movie is generic and predictable and almost nothing is all that engaging. The fight sequences with Seagal using judo or aikido was sort of cool though and watchable thus I give this movie a 4.5 even if the acting is atrocious thus I am being generous. I will just say this movie didn't make me a fan of his. 4.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vintage Fun!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Marked for Death' is Vintage Fun. Power-Packed, Fast-Paced, Action-Packed & Loud, it has it all. Also, its damn cool to watch bad-ass Steven Seagal getting it right completely. 'Marked for Death' stars Seagal as John Hatcher, a former DEA troubleshooter. Upon moving back to his home town, Hatcher finds it taken over by a gang of vicious Jamaican drug dealers, led by the twisted Screwface. 'Marked for Death' is Power-Packed, Fast-Paced & Loud Cinema at its best. The film never loses pace & always keeps you engrossed. Michael Grais & Mark Victor's Screenplay is Great Fun. Dwight H. Little's Direction is decent. Cinematography & Editing are fair, while the Action-Sequences/Fights are awesome. Performance-Wise: Seagal gets it right completely. His fights are a pleasure to watch & does his part with great energy & style. Basil Wallace as the twisted Screface is frightening. Keith David is perfect. On the whole, 'Marked for Death' is Vintage Fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well, I liked 2 things, and one of them was Seagal's car !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all know that it is B grade B movie. The "afternoon" or "rainy night" kind of time filler. So I won't get harsh, though with the presence of Steven Seagal it's impossible not to ! After Seagal's first movie (Above the Law  1988), some critic said about the new rising star "He's a fine mix of John Wayne, Bruce Lee and Clint Eastwood". How deceived that miserable critic was ! In fact Seagal is nothing but another Charles Bronson yet with marital arts experience. Observe well Seagal's so-called acting to discover easily that he must have watched Bronson's Death Wish movies for countless times ! The conflict this round is some tough cop fighting some voodoo drug dealers. The friction of the two's worlds was done absurdly. That cop's violence is too much; he walks like a deadly epidemic that leaves no wounded guys, only corpses. The attack at the gang's headquarters reminded me of (Commando), 5 years earlier. However the real reason of bothering was Seagal himself. It's not about the eternal truth that he doesn't smile, or doesn't know the way to. It's about another thing. They gave him a little dialog, which is a good idea, till you know that it was filled with many one-liners. OK, how they got the nerve ?! That guy is the worst of the worst at delivering any one-liner ! Watch him saying "They were both wrong" or "I hope they weren't triplets"; if Tom from Tom and Jerry said these lines, he would be less awful and more cool than Mr. Steven-The Whispering Zombie-Seagal ! The action is average, but it works. In movies of that kind don't ask much, just watch the fights. In general I liked 2 things, one of them is Seagal's black car; it was a stunner for every guy back in the 1990s start. And the second is of course the surprise of the evil guy as alive; that trick of having a twin brother was excellent (that fake decapitated head was so real it's freaky too !). Other than that...Seagal's grins could have killed me ! P.S : I read that Seagal didn't want to make this movie, hating it openly from day one till now, so how come he produced it ?!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fleetingly entertaining but forgettable action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    DEA Agent John Hatcher (Steven Seagal) is busy kickin' ass in Colombia when he decides to make his return to the U.S. after some spiritual enlightenment from his priest. He returns to find his city overrun by Jamaican 'posses', and when at a bar, he and his old friend Max (Keith David) find themselves caught amidst a gang war shootout. Hatcher, naturally, kicks the s**t out of some of them and finds that he and his family have been 'marked for death' by gang boss Screwface (Basil Wallace). His sisters house is attacked and when his niece is shot, Hatcher and Max team up with Jamaican police man Charles (Tom Wright) to find Screwface and end his reign of terror. Clearly neither Screwface nor his ever-dispensable gang of cronies have ever seen a Steven Seagal film, or they would have left him the f**k alone. Guns, swords and even voodoo cannot stop the pony-tailed action hero. This is actually considered to be the 'finest' of Seagal's vast action backlog, which is quite tragic given that this film is pretty s**t. I will say this for it, however - it's relentlessly entertaining. Yet this derives from the unintentionally hilarious dialogue, woeful acting, some appallingly gruesome action scenes, and plot devices that simply defy logic. Possibly the funniest moment in the film has Hatcher, who has, by the way, just committed murder (he's retired from the police) and has to be the police's main suspect, taking part in a high speed chase through the city that sees one car drive along the pavement causing massive damage, only to later fly through the window of a department store. Hatcher walks in shooting and stabbing his way through the bad guys only to calmly stroll out afterwards. Surely the police would have noticed something during the carnage? Yes, yes, I'm missing the point, this is a dumb action film - this is hardly trying to be The Wire. Marked for Death does have the sense to show off Seagal's martial arts skills. While many of his other films have him mainly either carrying a gun or simply throwing people onto tables, this has him breaking many, many bones with his bare hands. It's shockingly gory for an 90's action film, which naturally makes the whole film more likable. Basil Wallace is plenty of fun as the interestingly named Screwface, all wide-eyed and using an over-accentuated Jamaican accent. The voodoo element is certainly different, and the practises shown in the film are apparently well-researched and accurate. Definitely one for the action junkies, but for me, it's a laughable nostalgia trip into an overly macho time, and ultimately a rather forgettable one. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unimpressive movie from the golden years of Seagal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    GOOD THINGS : I like two songs from this movie , both by Jimmy Cliff : "No justice" and "John Crow" . Cliff even makes appearance in the movie . I was good to see Joanna Pacula in small role of Leslie  expert of foreign cultures . She gives the best performance in the movie. The girl who plays the part of Screwface's ex-girlfriend is hot. It was also good to see Danny Trejo in a small episode. "MFD" has a little more budget than typical Seagal movie , so we get to see a little bit of Mexico and Jamaica. It was also interesting to use Jamaicans as the villains . Maybe the writers were inspired by the "Predator 2" ? "Marked for death " is certainly more watchable and better than all those straight to DVD crap movies Seagal is now making  BAD THINGS : but it doesn't mean it's a good movie . The characters in this movie are one-dimensional . The story is flat and lacks a heart . The acting is rather poor (with the exception of Pacula ) , especially from the actor who plays the main villain . All the fights and action sequences are rather unimpressive and not too exciting. Despite some decent budget "MFD" feels like a made for TV movie . The twist at the end could be impressive , but the movie hints it to us too early and not in subtle way . The romance between Seagal's character and Leslie seems forced , undeveloped and rather unnecessary. There are some attempts at making the characters more human and the dialogue tries very hard to be funny and cool , but both those efforts are fruitless. VERDICT : Nothing really worth watching . Still , it's one of Seagal better movies . His fans should be pleased . I give it 3/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Marked for death is a waste of time , stupid as anuthing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julesdil
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marked for death , is corny , i don't care i hate this film it is a story about Jamaican drug fdealers ,, oouuggg horrible the accent and dialouge goes into a childish form , kids will love this garbage but as an action film it is a cartoon , the violence is tame and horrible because the film has no realistic fights the revenge action scenes ares simple , ohhhhh , shoot em up , no death that is good. Steven is a bad actor and in this mutters a stupid plot and just puts you off , i mean the actors and characters are in some kind of wannabe good film but is only for you cheesy corny film lovers . Avoid anyone who is good.Overrated 15 certificate for moderate violence and language.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Seagal action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When DEA agent John Hatcher's partner is killed he decides it is time to retire as no matter how much they do and how many villains they arrest there is always somebody else waiting to take there place. When he returns to his home in Chicago he finds the Jamaican Posses are selling drugs. At first he doesn't want to get involved but eventually he has no choice and deals with one of the gang. This puts both him and his family firmly in the sights of Screwface, the gang's leader. After an attack on his home leaves his niece critically injured he sets about hunting Screwface down; a mission that will take him from Chicago to Jamaica and back again and everywhere he goes he fill have to take on Screwface's many men and the black magic they claim to wield. If you enjoyed other early Seagal films you are sure to like this as it is packed with bone crunching action; he frequently has to fight several thugs at once. As well as the expected martial arts action there is plenty of gunplay, a car chase and even a sword fight! The story isn't too deep but there is an unforgettable twist that first time viewers are sure to enjoy. Seagal isn't the best actor in the world but he knows how to do action so if that is what you want you won't be disappointed. Some of the Jamaican patois is a little hard to understand but that doesn't spoil anything as most of what they say can be guessed anyway it is nearly always a threat of some sort!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who and Where was there a "John Crow"?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael A. Martinez (aylmer666@juno.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one gets my vote for "best" Steven Seagal action picture. Sure UNDER SIEGE is slicker and more expensive, ABOVE THE LAW has a more serious and compelling story, and OUT FOR JUSTICE has Seagal at his self-righteously most over the top, but none of those are half as fun as this little gem. Admittedly the plot to this film is on the simplistic side and it takes itself quite seriously for the most part. Seagal here is an originally unwilling crusader against drug gangs and violence but of course kills more people and causes more mayhem and property damage than any cartel ever did. Already at this point was he starting to exhibit some of his quirky mannerisms (obvious stunt doubles and enigmatic heroes who disappear to let their lackies do the "boring" stuff) which turned into B-action tropes over the years. He also starts to find his own identity as a bonafide 80's era action star with snappy post-mortem one-liners and creative almost artfully balletic corpse-kills. A lot of the fun comes from the ethnocentrism at hand in the form of the ridiculousness assigned to the antagonistic Jamaican cartel. Their heavily accented dialog and Basil Wallace's performance as their leader makes it feel as though Seagal is up against a gang of cartoon characters. The movie casts aside any shred of realism and treats us to seeing Seagal cathartically and unemotionally taking down multiple adversaries at once without even breaking a sweat. This was the only film I think Seagal did for 20th Century Fox so perhaps that's why it breaks a mold a little bit and allows the villains to land a few punches on our mighty hero (not that it makes any difference). One cannot talk about this movie without mentioning Basil Wallace's delirious portrayal of perhaps the most emotionally unbalanced villain of any action movie, and that includes anything Vernon Wells has ever done. He enthusiastically incantates voodoo and mysticism with wild-eyed abandon in an effort to intimidate his posse, but it largely comes across as quite comical. He's the polar opposite of the wooden and inexpressive Seagal, who just sort of drifts around and looks annoyed when there's no more baddies to murder. Pathetically the film tries to go the PC route and with the casting of Jamaican Tom Wright as a vindictive Island cop and American black character actor Keith David as Seagal's buddy vigilante. Amazingly, David's character is the close-minded one and no chance is spared to teach him how Jamaica as a tough but unfortunate breeding ground for vermin, though mostly populated by mostly good people. I don't know if it was out of PC-ness or in keeping with the tone of the villainy in the film, but the soundtrack contains a lot of great reggae tracks, largely by the one and only Jimmy Cliff who even appears in the film as himself singing about the upcoming death of the film's villain (!). The film ends on a high note with a nonstop action spectacular and immediately rolls into one of the most unforgettable reggae songs of all time. I really don't know who John Crow was or what he had to do with anything (perhaps they changed Hatcher's name at some point during production?) but at least we got a great song out of it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie dates back to when Steven segal was making entertaining movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marcus Geebs
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marked For Death" is a lot of fun. most of Steven segals movies are made by warner bros but this one is made by 20th century fox. The plot is John Hatcher (Seagal) is a jaded DEA agent. After witnessing the death of his partner, he resigns from the force and vows to return to family life in a quiet neighborhood of Chicago. However, he arrives to find his hometown teeming with Jamaican drug dealers, headed by the psychotic voodoo cultist Screwface (Basil Wallace, Blood Diamond). Though he does his best to ignore the impending danger, Hatcher finds both himself and his family in the dealers' sights after interfering in an assassination attempt, prompting him to team up with an old military comrade (Keith David, "The Thing") and take the fight to the criminals. this film is not perfect. the points of incompetence are limited and don't permeate the entire picture.It's a shame that this movie isn't recalled as readily as some of our hero's other work, since it supplies the adrenaline just as well. Btw Steven segal gets beat up a little in this movie unlike some of his other films we don't see him get hit once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid Seagal vehicle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In one of his early vehicles with the three-word descriptive titles, Steven Seagal this time is fighting the war on drugs. Or, to be more accurate, he's out to annihilate the Jamaican drug pushers who've infiltrated his Chicago community. He didn't feel like doing so at first; he'd burned out while on the job as a DEA agent and realized that in order to win he'd become no better than his adversaries. It's only inevitable that he'll once again get motivated to righteous fury when his own family is victimized. The bad guys in these movies never ever learn that simple lesson - mess with the hero's loved ones and they're just as marked for death as the good guy. Here, Seagal showed that in the earlier years of his career how he really gave more of an effort and could be quite engaging. He's given a truly kick ass sidekick in the form of eternally cool Keith David, as the old buddy / football coach disgusted by what he sees around him. Also lending assistance are Jamaican cop Tom Wright and a professor played by Joanna Pacula. "Marked for Death" does its job in a number of areas; as directed by Dwight H. Little ("Halloween 4: The Return of Michael Myers", "Rapid Fire"), it hits the ground running, and delivers exactly what we as fans of Seagal movies expect: rampant brutality, with broken limbs aplenty, bullets in foreheads, bodies crashing through windows, impalement, eyes gouged out, etc. The topicality of the script does take a back seat to all of the violent action - there's always one great scene around the corner. There's even a little bit of nudity to spice things up. A major appeal of the movie is the soundtrack, which features some tunes by Jimmy Cliff, who also appears on screen performing with his band. The supporting cast is full of familiar faces - Kevin Dunn, Tony DiBenedetto, Peter Jason, Danny Trejo, Gary Carlos Cervantes, and Earl Boen, with Danielle Harris, whom Little had directed in "Halloween 4", in a bit as Seagal's niece. Basil Wallace, an actor who should have broken bigger after this, has enough intensity and charisma to make for an effective villain. All in all, "Marked for Death" is good fun and builds to a really good finale as well as an amusing twist and resulting final one-liner. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First Steven Seagal movie I seen...Well didn't make me a fan of his
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the first Steven Seagal movie I seen. So I wasn't familiar with his films but from what I know, he usually plays a arrogant and cocky character that goes after the bad guys without hardly ever getting hurt or breaking a sweat. So in another words it sounded like some absurd and ridiculous action movie with bunch of kung-fu thrown in and to some degree that is exactly what this movie is. In this Steven Seagal's character is a retired DEA after on a the line of duty things don't go according to plan. And now he is going after Jamaican drug dealers with dreadlocks and is in some sort of cult with a couple of friends after they mess with his loved ones. Yeah the plot is very very narrow and the villains are comical and not in a good way either. After just few minutes in the movie just seemed to drag, constantly putting excuse to put some action sequences in which this has a lot of. Steven Seagal beats people up while saying catch phrases, some works some just don't. Just about everything about this movie is generic and predictable and almost nothing is all that engaging. The fight sequences with Seagal using judo or aikido was sort of cool though and watchable thus I give this movie a 4.5 even if the acting is atrocious thus I am being generous. I will just say this movie didn't make me a fan of his. 4.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vintage Fun!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Marked for Death' is Vintage Fun. Power-Packed, Fast-Paced, Action-Packed & Loud, it has it all. Also, its damn cool to watch bad-ass Steven Seagal getting it right completely. 'Marked for Death' stars Seagal as John Hatcher, a former DEA troubleshooter. Upon moving back to his home town, Hatcher finds it taken over by a gang of vicious Jamaican drug dealers, led by the twisted Screwface. 'Marked for Death' is Power-Packed, Fast-Paced & Loud Cinema at its best. The film never loses pace & always keeps you engrossed. Michael Grais & Mark Victor's Screenplay is Great Fun. Dwight H. Little's Direction is decent. Cinematography & Editing are fair, while the Action-Sequences/Fights are awesome. Performance-Wise: Seagal gets it right completely. His fights are a pleasure to watch & does his part with great energy & style. Basil Wallace as the twisted Screface is frightening. Keith David is perfect. On the whole, 'Marked for Death' is Vintage Fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well, I liked 2 things, and one of them was Seagal's car !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all know that it is B grade B movie. The "afternoon" or "rainy night" kind of time filler. So I won't get harsh, though with the presence of Steven Seagal it's impossible not to ! After Seagal's first movie (Above the Law  1988), some critic said about the new rising star "He's a fine mix of John Wayne, Bruce Lee and Clint Eastwood". How deceived that miserable critic was ! In fact Seagal is nothing but another Charles Bronson yet with marital arts experience. Observe well Seagal's so-called acting to discover easily that he must have watched Bronson's Death Wish movies for countless times ! The conflict this round is some tough cop fighting some voodoo drug dealers. The friction of the two's worlds was done absurdly. That cop's violence is too much; he walks like a deadly epidemic that leaves no wounded guys, only corpses. The attack at the gang's headquarters reminded me of (Commando), 5 years earlier. However the real reason of bothering was Seagal himself. It's not about the eternal truth that he doesn't smile, or doesn't know the way to. It's about another thing. They gave him a little dialog, which is a good idea, till you know that it was filled with many one-liners. OK, how they got the nerve ?! That guy is the worst of the worst at delivering any one-liner ! Watch him saying "They were both wrong" or "I hope they weren't triplets"; if Tom from Tom and Jerry said these lines, he would be less awful and more cool than Mr. Steven-The Whispering Zombie-Seagal ! The action is average, but it works. In movies of that kind don't ask much, just watch the fights. In general I liked 2 things, one of them is Seagal's black car; it was a stunner for every guy back in the 1990s start. And the second is of course the surprise of the evil guy as alive; that trick of having a twin brother was excellent (that fake decapitated head was so real it's freaky too !). Other than that...Seagal's grins could have killed me ! P.S : I read that Seagal didn't want to make this movie, hating it openly from day one till now, so how come he produced it ?!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fleetingly entertaining but forgettable action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    DEA Agent John Hatcher (Steven Seagal) is busy kickin' ass in Colombia when he decides to make his return to the U.S. after some spiritual enlightenment from his priest. He returns to find his city overrun by Jamaican 'posses', and when at a bar, he and his old friend Max (Keith David) find themselves caught amidst a gang war shootout. Hatcher, naturally, kicks the s**t out of some of them and finds that he and his family have been 'marked for death' by gang boss Screwface (Basil Wallace). His sisters house is attacked and when his niece is shot, Hatcher and Max team up with Jamaican police man Charles (Tom Wright) to find Screwface and end his reign of terror. Clearly neither Screwface nor his ever-dispensable gang of cronies have ever seen a Steven Seagal film, or they would have left him the f**k alone. Guns, swords and even voodoo cannot stop the pony-tailed action hero. This is actually considered to be the 'finest' of Seagal's vast action backlog, which is quite tragic given that this film is pretty s**t. I will say this for it, however - it's relentlessly entertaining. Yet this derives from the unintentionally hilarious dialogue, woeful acting, some appallingly gruesome action scenes, and plot devices that simply defy logic. Possibly the funniest moment in the film has Hatcher, who has, by the way, just committed murder (he's retired from the police) and has to be the police's main suspect, taking part in a high speed chase through the city that sees one car drive along the pavement causing massive damage, only to later fly through the window of a department store. Hatcher walks in shooting and stabbing his way through the bad guys only to calmly stroll out afterwards. Surely the police would have noticed something during the carnage? Yes, yes, I'm missing the point, this is a dumb action film - this is hardly trying to be The Wire. Marked for Death does have the sense to show off Seagal's martial arts skills. While many of his other films have him mainly either carrying a gun or simply throwing people onto tables, this has him breaking many, many bones with his bare hands. It's shockingly gory for an 90's action film, which naturally makes the whole film more likable. Basil Wallace is plenty of fun as the interestingly named Screwface, all wide-eyed and using an over-accentuated Jamaican accent. The voodoo element is certainly different, and the practises shown in the film are apparently well-researched and accurate. Definitely one for the action junkies, but for me, it's a laughable nostalgia trip into an overly macho time, and ultimately a rather forgettable one. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unimpressive movie from the golden years of Seagal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    GOOD THINGS : I like two songs from this movie , both by Jimmy Cliff : "No justice" and "John Crow" . Cliff even makes appearance in the movie . I was good to see Joanna Pacula in small role of Leslie  expert of foreign cultures . She gives the best performance in the movie. The girl who plays the part of Screwface's ex-girlfriend is hot. It was also good to see Danny Trejo in a small episode. "MFD" has a little more budget than typical Seagal movie , so we get to see a little bit of Mexico and Jamaica. It was also interesting to use Jamaicans as the villains . Maybe the writers were inspired by the "Predator 2" ? "Marked for death " is certainly more watchable and better than all those straight to DVD crap movies Seagal is now making  BAD THINGS : but it doesn't mean it's a good movie . The characters in this movie are one-dimensional . The story is flat and lacks a heart . The acting is rather poor (with the exception of Pacula ) , especially from the actor who plays the main villain . All the fights and action sequences are rather unimpressive and not too exciting. Despite some decent budget "MFD" feels like a made for TV movie . The twist at the end could be impressive , but the movie hints it to us too early and not in subtle way . The romance between Seagal's character and Leslie seems forced , undeveloped and rather unnecessary. There are some attempts at making the characters more human and the dialogue tries very hard to be funny and cool , but both those efforts are fruitless. VERDICT : Nothing really worth watching . Still , it's one of Seagal better movies . His fans should be pleased . I give it 3/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Marked for death is a waste of time , stupid as anuthing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julesdil
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marked for death , is corny , i don't care i hate this film it is a story about Jamaican drug fdealers ,, oouuggg horrible the accent and dialouge goes into a childish form , kids will love this garbage but as an action film it is a cartoon , the violence is tame and horrible because the film has no realistic fights the revenge action scenes ares simple , ohhhhh , shoot em up , no death that is good. Steven is a bad actor and in this mutters a stupid plot and just puts you off , i mean the actors and characters are in some kind of wannabe good film but is only for you cheesy corny film lovers . Avoid anyone who is good.Overrated 15 certificate for moderate violence and language.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Seagal action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When DEA agent John Hatcher's partner is killed he decides it is time to retire as no matter how much they do and how many villains they arrest there is always somebody else waiting to take there place. When he returns to his home in Chicago he finds the Jamaican Posses are selling drugs. At first he doesn't want to get involved but eventually he has no choice and deals with one of the gang. This puts both him and his family firmly in the sights of Screwface, the gang's leader. After an attack on his home leaves his niece critically injured he sets about hunting Screwface down; a mission that will take him from Chicago to Jamaica and back again and everywhere he goes he fill have to take on Screwface's many men and the black magic they claim to wield. If you enjoyed other early Seagal films you are sure to like this as it is packed with bone crunching action; he frequently has to fight several thugs at once. As well as the expected martial arts action there is plenty of gunplay, a car chase and even a sword fight! The story isn't too deep but there is an unforgettable twist that first time viewers are sure to enjoy. Seagal isn't the best actor in the world but he knows how to do action so if that is what you want you won't be disappointed. Some of the Jamaican patois is a little hard to understand but that doesn't spoil anything as most of what they say can be guessed anyway it is nearly always a threat of some sort!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who and Where was there a "John Crow"?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael A. Martinez (aylmer666@juno.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one gets my vote for "best" Steven Seagal action picture. Sure UNDER SIEGE is slicker and more expensive, ABOVE THE LAW has a more serious and compelling story, and OUT FOR JUSTICE has Seagal at his self-righteously most over the top, but none of those are half as fun as this little gem. Admittedly the plot to this film is on the simplistic side and it takes itself quite seriously for the most part. Seagal here is an originally unwilling crusader against drug gangs and violence but of course kills more people and causes more mayhem and property damage than any cartel ever did. Already at this point was he starting to exhibit some of his quirky mannerisms (obvious stunt doubles and enigmatic heroes who disappear to let their lackies do the "boring" stuff) which turned into B-action tropes over the years. He also starts to find his own identity as a bonafide 80's era action star with snappy post-mortem one-liners and creative almost artfully balletic corpse-kills. A lot of the fun comes from the ethnocentrism at hand in the form of the ridiculousness assigned to the antagonistic Jamaican cartel. Their heavily accented dialog and Basil Wallace's performance as their leader makes it feel as though Seagal is up against a gang of cartoon characters. The movie casts aside any shred of realism and treats us to seeing Seagal cathartically and unemotionally taking down multiple adversaries at once without even breaking a sweat. This was the only film I think Seagal did for 20th Century Fox so perhaps that's why it breaks a mold a little bit and allows the villains to land a few punches on our mighty hero (not that it makes any difference). One cannot talk about this movie without mentioning Basil Wallace's delirious portrayal of perhaps the most emotionally unbalanced villain of any action movie, and that includes anything Vernon Wells has ever done. He enthusiastically incantates voodoo and mysticism with wild-eyed abandon in an effort to intimidate his posse, but it largely comes across as quite comical. He's the polar opposite of the wooden and inexpressive Seagal, who just sort of drifts around and looks annoyed when there's no more baddies to murder. Pathetically the film tries to go the PC route and with the casting of Jamaican Tom Wright as a vindictive Island cop and American black character actor Keith David as Seagal's buddy vigilante. Amazingly, David's character is the close-minded one and no chance is spared to teach him how Jamaica as a tough but unfortunate breeding ground for vermin, though mostly populated by mostly good people. I don't know if it was out of PC-ness or in keeping with the tone of the villainy in the film, but the soundtrack contains a lot of great reggae tracks, largely by the one and only Jimmy Cliff who even appears in the film as himself singing about the upcoming death of the film's villain (!). The film ends on a high note with a nonstop action spectacular and immediately rolls into one of the most unforgettable reggae songs of all time. I really don't know who John Crow was or what he had to do with anything (perhaps they changed Hatcher's name at some point during production?) but at least we got a great song out of it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie dates back to when Steven segal was making entertaining movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marcus Geebs
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marked For Death" is a lot of fun. most of Steven segals movies are made by warner bros but this one is made by 20th century fox. The plot is John Hatcher (Seagal) is a jaded DEA agent. After witnessing the death of his partner, he resigns from the force and vows to return to family life in a quiet neighborhood of Chicago. However, he arrives to find his hometown teeming with Jamaican drug dealers, headed by the psychotic voodoo cultist Screwface (Basil Wallace, Blood Diamond). Though he does his best to ignore the impending danger, Hatcher finds both himself and his family in the dealers' sights after interfering in an assassination attempt, prompting him to team up with an old military comrade (Keith David, "The Thing") and take the fight to the criminals. this film is not perfect. the points of incompetence are limited and don't permeate the entire picture.It's a shame that this movie isn't recalled as readily as some of our hero's other work, since it supplies the adrenaline just as well. Btw Steven segal gets beat up a little in this movie unlike some of his other films we don't see him get hit once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid Seagal vehicle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In one of his early vehicles with the three-word descriptive titles, Steven Seagal this time is fighting the war on drugs. Or, to be more accurate, he's out to annihilate the Jamaican drug pushers who've infiltrated his Chicago community. He didn't feel like doing so at first; he'd burned out while on the job as a DEA agent and realized that in order to win he'd become no better than his adversaries. It's only inevitable that he'll once again get motivated to righteous fury when his own family is victimized. The bad guys in these movies never ever learn that simple lesson - mess with the hero's loved ones and they're just as marked for death as the good guy. Here, Seagal showed that in the earlier years of his career how he really gave more of an effort and could be quite engaging. He's given a truly kick ass sidekick in the form of eternally cool Keith David, as the old buddy / football coach disgusted by what he sees around him. Also lending assistance are Jamaican cop Tom Wright and a professor played by Joanna Pacula. "Marked for Death" does its job in a number of areas; as directed by Dwight H. Little ("Halloween 4: The Return of Michael Myers", "Rapid Fire"), it hits the ground running, and delivers exactly what we as fans of Seagal movies expect: rampant brutality, with broken limbs aplenty, bullets in foreheads, bodies crashing through windows, impalement, eyes gouged out, etc. The topicality of the script does take a back seat to all of the violent action - there's always one great scene around the corner. There's even a little bit of nudity to spice things up. A major appeal of the movie is the soundtrack, which features some tunes by Jimmy Cliff, who also appears on screen performing with his band. The supporting cast is full of familiar faces - Kevin Dunn, Tony DiBenedetto, Peter Jason, Danny Trejo, Gary Carlos Cervantes, and Earl Boen, with Danielle Harris, whom Little had directed in "Halloween 4", in a bit as Seagal's niece. Basil Wallace, an actor who should have broken bigger after this, has enough intensity and charisma to make for an effective villain. All in all, "Marked for Death" is good fun and builds to a really good finale as well as an amusing twist and resulting final one-liner. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First Steven Seagal movie I seen...Well didn't make me a fan of his
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the first Steven Seagal movie I seen. So I wasn't familiar with his films but from what I know, he usually plays a arrogant and cocky character that goes after the bad guys without hardly ever getting hurt or breaking a sweat. So in another words it sounded like some absurd and ridiculous action movie with bunch of kung-fu thrown in and to some degree that is exactly what this movie is. In this Steven Seagal's character is a retired DEA after on a the line of duty things don't go according to plan. And now he is going after Jamaican drug dealers with dreadlocks and is in some sort of cult with a couple of friends after they mess with his loved ones. Yeah the plot is very very narrow and the villains are comical and not in a good way either. After just few minutes in the movie just seemed to drag, constantly putting excuse to put some action sequences in which this has a lot of. Steven Seagal beats people up while saying catch phrases, some works some just don't. Just about everything about this movie is generic and predictable and almost nothing is all that engaging. The fight sequences with Seagal using judo or aikido was sort of cool though and watchable thus I give this movie a 4.5 even if the acting is atrocious thus I am being generous. I will just say this movie didn't make me a fan of his. 4.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vintage Fun!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Marked for Death' is Vintage Fun. Power-Packed, Fast-Paced, Action-Packed & Loud, it has it all. Also, its damn cool to watch bad-ass Steven Seagal getting it right completely. 'Marked for Death' stars Seagal as John Hatcher, a former DEA troubleshooter. Upon moving back to his home town, Hatcher finds it taken over by a gang of vicious Jamaican drug dealers, led by the twisted Screwface. 'Marked for Death' is Power-Packed, Fast-Paced & Loud Cinema at its best. The film never loses pace & always keeps you engrossed. Michael Grais & Mark Victor's Screenplay is Great Fun. Dwight H. Little's Direction is decent. Cinematography & Editing are fair, while the Action-Sequences/Fights are awesome. Performance-Wise: Seagal gets it right completely. His fights are a pleasure to watch & does his part with great energy & style. Basil Wallace as the twisted Screface is frightening. Keith David is perfect. On the whole, 'Marked for Death' is Vintage Fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well, I liked 2 things, and one of them was Seagal's car !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all know that it is B grade B movie. The "afternoon" or "rainy night" kind of time filler. So I won't get harsh, though with the presence of Steven Seagal it's impossible not to ! After Seagal's first movie (Above the Law  1988), some critic said about the new rising star "He's a fine mix of John Wayne, Bruce Lee and Clint Eastwood". How deceived that miserable critic was ! In fact Seagal is nothing but another Charles Bronson yet with marital arts experience. Observe well Seagal's so-called acting to discover easily that he must have watched Bronson's Death Wish movies for countless times ! The conflict this round is some tough cop fighting some voodoo drug dealers. The friction of the two's worlds was done absurdly. That cop's violence is too much; he walks like a deadly epidemic that leaves no wounded guys, only corpses. The attack at the gang's headquarters reminded me of (Commando), 5 years earlier. However the real reason of bothering was Seagal himself. It's not about the eternal truth that he doesn't smile, or doesn't know the way to. It's about another thing. They gave him a little dialog, which is a good idea, till you know that it was filled with many one-liners. OK, how they got the nerve ?! That guy is the worst of the worst at delivering any one-liner ! Watch him saying "They were both wrong" or "I hope they weren't triplets"; if Tom from Tom and Jerry said these lines, he would be less awful and more cool than Mr. Steven-The Whispering Zombie-Seagal ! The action is average, but it works. In movies of that kind don't ask much, just watch the fights. In general I liked 2 things, one of them is Seagal's black car; it was a stunner for every guy back in the 1990s start. And the second is of course the surprise of the evil guy as alive; that trick of having a twin brother was excellent (that fake decapitated head was so real it's freaky too !). Other than that...Seagal's grins could have killed me ! P.S : I read that Seagal didn't want to make this movie, hating it openly from day one till now, so how come he produced it ?!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fleetingly entertaining but forgettable action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    DEA Agent John Hatcher (Steven Seagal) is busy kickin' ass in Colombia when he decides to make his return to the U.S. after some spiritual enlightenment from his priest. He returns to find his city overrun by Jamaican 'posses', and when at a bar, he and his old friend Max (Keith David) find themselves caught amidst a gang war shootout. Hatcher, naturally, kicks the s**t out of some of them and finds that he and his family have been 'marked for death' by gang boss Screwface (Basil Wallace). His sisters house is attacked and when his niece is shot, Hatcher and Max team up with Jamaican police man Charles (Tom Wright) to find Screwface and end his reign of terror. Clearly neither Screwface nor his ever-dispensable gang of cronies have ever seen a Steven Seagal film, or they would have left him the f**k alone. Guns, swords and even voodoo cannot stop the pony-tailed action hero. This is actually considered to be the 'finest' of Seagal's vast action backlog, which is quite tragic given that this film is pretty s**t. I will say this for it, however - it's relentlessly entertaining. Yet this derives from the unintentionally hilarious dialogue, woeful acting, some appallingly gruesome action scenes, and plot devices that simply defy logic. Possibly the funniest moment in the film has Hatcher, who has, by the way, just committed murder (he's retired from the police) and has to be the police's main suspect, taking part in a high speed chase through the city that sees one car drive along the pavement causing massive damage, only to later fly through the window of a department store. Hatcher walks in shooting and stabbing his way through the bad guys only to calmly stroll out afterwards. Surely the police would have noticed something during the carnage? Yes, yes, I'm missing the point, this is a dumb action film - this is hardly trying to be The Wire. Marked for Death does have the sense to show off Seagal's martial arts skills. While many of his other films have him mainly either carrying a gun or simply throwing people onto tables, this has him breaking many, many bones with his bare hands. It's shockingly gory for an 90's action film, which naturally makes the whole film more likable. Basil Wallace is plenty of fun as the interestingly named Screwface, all wide-eyed and using an over-accentuated Jamaican accent. The voodoo element is certainly different, and the practises shown in the film are apparently well-researched and accurate. Definitely one for the action junkies, but for me, it's a laughable nostalgia trip into an overly macho time, and ultimately a rather forgettable one. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unimpressive movie from the golden years of Seagal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    GOOD THINGS : I like two songs from this movie , both by Jimmy Cliff : "No justice" and "John Crow" . Cliff even makes appearance in the movie . I was good to see Joanna Pacula in small role of Leslie  expert of foreign cultures . She gives the best performance in the movie. The girl who plays the part of Screwface's ex-girlfriend is hot. It was also good to see Danny Trejo in a small episode. "MFD" has a little more budget than typical Seagal movie , so we get to see a little bit of Mexico and Jamaica. It was also interesting to use Jamaicans as the villains . Maybe the writers were inspired by the "Predator 2" ? "Marked for death " is certainly more watchable and better than all those straight to DVD crap movies Seagal is now making  BAD THINGS : but it doesn't mean it's a good movie . The characters in this movie are one-dimensional . The story is flat and lacks a heart . The acting is rather poor (with the exception of Pacula ) , especially from the actor who plays the main villain . All the fights and action sequences are rather unimpressive and not too exciting. Despite some decent budget "MFD" feels like a made for TV movie . The twist at the end could be impressive , but the movie hints it to us too early and not in subtle way . The romance between Seagal's character and Leslie seems forced , undeveloped and rather unnecessary. There are some attempts at making the characters more human and the dialogue tries very hard to be funny and cool , but both those efforts are fruitless. VERDICT : Nothing really worth watching . Still , it's one of Seagal better movies . His fans should be pleased . I give it 3/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Marked for death is a waste of time , stupid as anuthing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julesdil
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marked for death , is corny , i don't care i hate this film it is a story about Jamaican drug fdealers ,, oouuggg horrible the accent and dialouge goes into a childish form , kids will love this garbage but as an action film it is a cartoon , the violence is tame and horrible because the film has no realistic fights the revenge action scenes ares simple , ohhhhh , shoot em up , no death that is good. Steven is a bad actor and in this mutters a stupid plot and just puts you off , i mean the actors and characters are in some kind of wannabe good film but is only for you cheesy corny film lovers . Avoid anyone who is good.Overrated 15 certificate for moderate violence and language.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Seagal action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When DEA agent John Hatcher's partner is killed he decides it is time to retire as no matter how much they do and how many villains they arrest there is always somebody else waiting to take there place. When he returns to his home in Chicago he finds the Jamaican Posses are selling drugs. At first he doesn't want to get involved but eventually he has no choice and deals with one of the gang. This puts both him and his family firmly in the sights of Screwface, the gang's leader. After an attack on his home leaves his niece critically injured he sets about hunting Screwface down; a mission that will take him from Chicago to Jamaica and back again and everywhere he goes he fill have to take on Screwface's many men and the black magic they claim to wield. If you enjoyed other early Seagal films you are sure to like this as it is packed with bone crunching action; he frequently has to fight several thugs at once. As well as the expected martial arts action there is plenty of gunplay, a car chase and even a sword fight! The story isn't too deep but there is an unforgettable twist that first time viewers are sure to enjoy. Seagal isn't the best actor in the world but he knows how to do action so if that is what you want you won't be disappointed. Some of the Jamaican patois is a little hard to understand but that doesn't spoil anything as most of what they say can be guessed anyway it is nearly always a threat of some sort!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who and Where was there a "John Crow"?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael A. Martinez (aylmer666@juno.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one gets my vote for "best" Steven Seagal action picture. Sure UNDER SIEGE is slicker and more expensive, ABOVE THE LAW has a more serious and compelling story, and OUT FOR JUSTICE has Seagal at his self-righteously most over the top, but none of those are half as fun as this little gem. Admittedly the plot to this film is on the simplistic side and it takes itself quite seriously for the most part. Seagal here is an originally unwilling crusader against drug gangs and violence but of course kills more people and causes more mayhem and property damage than any cartel ever did. Already at this point was he starting to exhibit some of his quirky mannerisms (obvious stunt doubles and enigmatic heroes who disappear to let their lackies do the "boring" stuff) which turned into B-action tropes over the years. He also starts to find his own identity as a bonafide 80's era action star with snappy post-mortem one-liners and creative almost artfully balletic corpse-kills. A lot of the fun comes from the ethnocentrism at hand in the form of the ridiculousness assigned to the antagonistic Jamaican cartel. Their heavily accented dialog and Basil Wallace's performance as their leader makes it feel as though Seagal is up against a gang of cartoon characters. The movie casts aside any shred of realism and treats us to seeing Seagal cathartically and unemotionally taking down multiple adversaries at once without even breaking a sweat. This was the only film I think Seagal did for 20th Century Fox so perhaps that's why it breaks a mold a little bit and allows the villains to land a few punches on our mighty hero (not that it makes any difference). One cannot talk about this movie without mentioning Basil Wallace's delirious portrayal of perhaps the most emotionally unbalanced villain of any action movie, and that includes anything Vernon Wells has ever done. He enthusiastically incantates voodoo and mysticism with wild-eyed abandon in an effort to intimidate his posse, but it largely comes across as quite comical. He's the polar opposite of the wooden and inexpressive Seagal, who just sort of drifts around and looks annoyed when there's no more baddies to murder. Pathetically the film tries to go the PC route and with the casting of Jamaican Tom Wright as a vindictive Island cop and American black character actor Keith David as Seagal's buddy vigilante. Amazingly, David's character is the close-minded one and no chance is spared to teach him how Jamaica as a tough but unfortunate breeding ground for vermin, though mostly populated by mostly good people. I don't know if it was out of PC-ness or in keeping with the tone of the villainy in the film, but the soundtrack contains a lot of great reggae tracks, largely by the one and only Jimmy Cliff who even appears in the film as himself singing about the upcoming death of the film's villain (!). The film ends on a high note with a nonstop action spectacular and immediately rolls into one of the most unforgettable reggae songs of all time. I really don't know who John Crow was or what he had to do with anything (perhaps they changed Hatcher's name at some point during production?) but at least we got a great song out of it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie dates back to when Steven segal was making entertaining movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marcus Geebs
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marked For Death" is a lot of fun. most of Steven segals movies are made by warner bros but this one is made by 20th century fox. The plot is John Hatcher (Seagal) is a jaded DEA agent. After witnessing the death of his partner, he resigns from the force and vows to return to family life in a quiet neighborhood of Chicago. However, he arrives to find his hometown teeming with Jamaican drug dealers, headed by the psychotic voodoo cultist Screwface (Basil Wallace, Blood Diamond). Though he does his best to ignore the impending danger, Hatcher finds both himself and his family in the dealers' sights after interfering in an assassination attempt, prompting him to team up with an old military comrade (Keith David, "The Thing") and take the fight to the criminals. this film is not perfect. the points of incompetence are limited and don't permeate the entire picture.It's a shame that this movie isn't recalled as readily as some of our hero's other work, since it supplies the adrenaline just as well. Btw Steven segal gets beat up a little in this movie unlike some of his other films we don't see him get hit once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid Seagal vehicle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In one of his early vehicles with the three-word descriptive titles, Steven Seagal this time is fighting the war on drugs. Or, to be more accurate, he's out to annihilate the Jamaican drug pushers who've infiltrated his Chicago community. He didn't feel like doing so at first; he'd burned out while on the job as a DEA agent and realized that in order to win he'd become no better than his adversaries. It's only inevitable that he'll once again get motivated to righteous fury when his own family is victimized. The bad guys in these movies never ever learn that simple lesson - mess with the hero's loved ones and they're just as marked for death as the good guy. Here, Seagal showed that in the earlier years of his career how he really gave more of an effort and could be quite engaging. He's given a truly kick ass sidekick in the form of eternally cool Keith David, as the old buddy / football coach disgusted by what he sees around him. Also lending assistance are Jamaican cop Tom Wright and a professor played by Joanna Pacula. "Marked for Death" does its job in a number of areas; as directed by Dwight H. Little ("Halloween 4: The Return of Michael Myers", "Rapid Fire"), it hits the ground running, and delivers exactly what we as fans of Seagal movies expect: rampant brutality, with broken limbs aplenty, bullets in foreheads, bodies crashing through windows, impalement, eyes gouged out, etc. The topicality of the script does take a back seat to all of the violent action - there's always one great scene around the corner. There's even a little bit of nudity to spice things up. A major appeal of the movie is the soundtrack, which features some tunes by Jimmy Cliff, who also appears on screen performing with his band. The supporting cast is full of familiar faces - Kevin Dunn, Tony DiBenedetto, Peter Jason, Danny Trejo, Gary Carlos Cervantes, and Earl Boen, with Danielle Harris, whom Little had directed in "Halloween 4", in a bit as Seagal's niece. Basil Wallace, an actor who should have broken bigger after this, has enough intensity and charisma to make for an effective villain. All in all, "Marked for Death" is good fun and builds to a really good finale as well as an amusing twist and resulting final one-liner. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First Steven Seagal movie I seen...Well didn't make me a fan of his
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the first Steven Seagal movie I seen. So I wasn't familiar with his films but from what I know, he usually plays a arrogant and cocky character that goes after the bad guys without hardly ever getting hurt or breaking a sweat. So in another words it sounded like some absurd and ridiculous action movie with bunch of kung-fu thrown in and to some degree that is exactly what this movie is. In this Steven Seagal's character is a retired DEA after on a the line of duty things don't go according to plan. And now he is going after Jamaican drug dealers with dreadlocks and is in some sort of cult with a couple of friends after they mess with his loved ones. Yeah the plot is very very narrow and the villains are comical and not in a good way either. After just few minutes in the movie just seemed to drag, constantly putting excuse to put some action sequences in which this has a lot of. Steven Seagal beats people up while saying catch phrases, some works some just don't. Just about everything about this movie is generic and predictable and almost nothing is all that engaging. The fight sequences with Seagal using judo or aikido was sort of cool though and watchable thus I give this movie a 4.5 even if the acting is atrocious thus I am being generous. I will just say this movie didn't make me a fan of his. 4.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vintage Fun!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Marked for Death' is Vintage Fun. Power-Packed, Fast-Paced, Action-Packed & Loud, it has it all. Also, its damn cool to watch bad-ass Steven Seagal getting it right completely. 'Marked for Death' stars Seagal as John Hatcher, a former DEA troubleshooter. Upon moving back to his home town, Hatcher finds it taken over by a gang of vicious Jamaican drug dealers, led by the twisted Screwface. 'Marked for Death' is Power-Packed, Fast-Paced & Loud Cinema at its best. The film never loses pace & always keeps you engrossed. Michael Grais & Mark Victor's Screenplay is Great Fun. Dwight H. Little's Direction is decent. Cinematography & Editing are fair, while the Action-Sequences/Fights are awesome. Performance-Wise: Seagal gets it right completely. His fights are a pleasure to watch & does his part with great energy & style. Basil Wallace as the twisted Screface is frightening. Keith David is perfect. On the whole, 'Marked for Death' is Vintage Fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well, I liked 2 things, and one of them was Seagal's car !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all know that it is B grade B movie. The "afternoon" or "rainy night" kind of time filler. So I won't get harsh, though with the presence of Steven Seagal it's impossible not to ! After Seagal's first movie (Above the Law  1988), some critic said about the new rising star "He's a fine mix of John Wayne, Bruce Lee and Clint Eastwood". How deceived that miserable critic was ! In fact Seagal is nothing but another Charles Bronson yet with marital arts experience. Observe well Seagal's so-called acting to discover easily that he must have watched Bronson's Death Wish movies for countless times ! The conflict this round is some tough cop fighting some voodoo drug dealers. The friction of the two's worlds was done absurdly. That cop's violence is too much; he walks like a deadly epidemic that leaves no wounded guys, only corpses. The attack at the gang's headquarters reminded me of (Commando), 5 years earlier. However the real reason of bothering was Seagal himself. It's not about the eternal truth that he doesn't smile, or doesn't know the way to. It's about another thing. They gave him a little dialog, which is a good idea, till you know that it was filled with many one-liners. OK, how they got the nerve ?! That guy is the worst of the worst at delivering any one-liner ! Watch him saying "They were both wrong" or "I hope they weren't triplets"; if Tom from Tom and Jerry said these lines, he would be less awful and more cool than Mr. Steven-The Whispering Zombie-Seagal ! The action is average, but it works. In movies of that kind don't ask much, just watch the fights. In general I liked 2 things, one of them is Seagal's black car; it was a stunner for every guy back in the 1990s start. And the second is of course the surprise of the evil guy as alive; that trick of having a twin brother was excellent (that fake decapitated head was so real it's freaky too !). Other than that...Seagal's grins could have killed me ! P.S : I read that Seagal didn't want to make this movie, hating it openly from day one till now, so how come he produced it ?!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fleetingly entertaining but forgettable action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    DEA Agent John Hatcher (Steven Seagal) is busy kickin' ass in Colombia when he decides to make his return to the U.S. after some spiritual enlightenment from his priest. He returns to find his city overrun by Jamaican 'posses', and when at a bar, he and his old friend Max (Keith David) find themselves caught amidst a gang war shootout. Hatcher, naturally, kicks the s**t out of some of them and finds that he and his family have been 'marked for death' by gang boss Screwface (Basil Wallace). His sisters house is attacked and when his niece is shot, Hatcher and Max team up with Jamaican police man Charles (Tom Wright) to find Screwface and end his reign of terror. Clearly neither Screwface nor his ever-dispensable gang of cronies have ever seen a Steven Seagal film, or they would have left him the f**k alone. Guns, swords and even voodoo cannot stop the pony-tailed action hero. This is actually considered to be the 'finest' of Seagal's vast action backlog, which is quite tragic given that this film is pretty s**t. I will say this for it, however - it's relentlessly entertaining. Yet this derives from the unintentionally hilarious dialogue, woeful acting, some appallingly gruesome action scenes, and plot devices that simply defy logic. Possibly the funniest moment in the film has Hatcher, who has, by the way, just committed murder (he's retired from the police) and has to be the police's main suspect, taking part in a high speed chase through the city that sees one car drive along the pavement causing massive damage, only to later fly through the window of a department store. Hatcher walks in shooting and stabbing his way through the bad guys only to calmly stroll out afterwards. Surely the police would have noticed something during the carnage? Yes, yes, I'm missing the point, this is a dumb action film - this is hardly trying to be The Wire. Marked for Death does have the sense to show off Seagal's martial arts skills. While many of his other films have him mainly either carrying a gun or simply throwing people onto tables, this has him breaking many, many bones with his bare hands. It's shockingly gory for an 90's action film, which naturally makes the whole film more likable. Basil Wallace is plenty of fun as the interestingly named Screwface, all wide-eyed and using an over-accentuated Jamaican accent. The voodoo element is certainly different, and the practises shown in the film are apparently well-researched and accurate. Definitely one for the action junkies, but for me, it's a laughable nostalgia trip into an overly macho time, and ultimately a rather forgettable one. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
