<filme>
 <id>
  1232
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0102370
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1991
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Na Cama Com Madonna
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Documentary following singer Madonna on her controversial Blond Ambition tour in 1990.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  From the rain of Japan, through threats of arrest for 'public indecency' in Canada, and a birthday tribute to her father in Detroit, this documentary follows Madonna on her 1990 'Blond Ambition' concert tour. Filmed in black and white, with the concert pieces in glittering MTV color, it is an intimate look at the work of the music performer, from a prayer circle with the dancers before each performance to bed games with the dance troupe afterwards.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Documentary
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Music
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   dancer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   ambition
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   singer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sex
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   backstage
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Alek Keshishian
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Boy Toy
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Madonna
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Donna DeLory
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Niki Harris
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a strictly narcissistic self portrait
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The ersatz Madonna 'documentary' offers proof of the Material Girl's genius for self-promotion, pretending to be a candid behind-the-scenes portrait of her Blond Ambition tour when it's really just selling a lot of self-conscious backstage posturing, sandwiched between the expected MTV concert footage. Some fashionably grainy black-and-white photography gives the film a spurious air of raw slice-of-life candor, but the whole thing is one long public relations whitewash, no less calculated than her elaborate stage show and often just about as substantial. At times it seems the only purpose of the film is to reinforce the singer's image as some sort of blue-collar angel/whore, with strong maternal instincts toward her dancing troupe. Nothing else about her is revealed, except for a purely mercenary streak of exhibitionism, hardly front-page news. But there's a peculiar irony in watching Madonna (of all people) try to act natural with a camera lens constantly in her face; the effort to simply be herself can almost be called the best 'performance' of her career.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Madonna takes herself very seriously
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dierregi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie for the first time in 2009, almost twenty years after its release and this proves I am not a big Madonna fan. In fact, I never particularly liked or disliked her. I thought she was "cool" in "Desperately seeking Susan", but that was the "Into the Groove" time, when she had just started her rise. The "Blonde Ambition" tour was probably the top of Madonna's career, and this would-be documentary shows her at her most unbearable. Somebody mentioned that it shines a light on her "human" side (as if she was some sort of alien), but in truth she comes across as a controlling, pretentious bitch who goes out of her way to humiliate and annoy people. Hardly the best human side one can show. Even the visit to her mother's grave is disgustingly theatrical. Instead of making you feel sorry for the child of five who lost her mum it makes you feel sorry for the spoiled brat she became. Of course we all know that Madonna built her career on sex and the Catholic religion and by now I doubt anybody would be shocked by her swinging crucifix or her masturbation. However, tasteful it was not... and still isn't. The part filmed on stage is disappointing because some of songs performed are just not good, no matter how much sex is thrown in to spice them. The "documentary" part is embarrassing to watch. It was interesting for me to see that Madonna had a crush on Antonio Banderas, but at the time he was married with a pretty Spanish lady (who looked a lot better both of Madonna and Melanie Griffith). Warren Beatty makes the only decent comment about the whole filming, but he is also brushed off and humiliated, not to mention the poor Costner. I am not a Costner fan either, but his comment sounded rather sarcastic to me ("Neat" applied to the overbearing and vulgar show sounds like a sarcastic way to say "It sucked"), but looks like Madonna did not get the joke. She definitely takes herself very seriously when she describes herself as an "artist" who will not change anything in her show, even if she risks to get arrested for "indecent exposure" or any such like - very unlikely - charge. Finally, when she talks to her father she is so arrogant and dismissive that I felt sorry for the poor guy. She even uses the word "chatartic" with the intent of confuse her father; but looks like she herself had no clue as to what that word means. Madonna was an icon of the 80's and early 90's and possibly a decent singer, but for sure she was never a great actress and definitely not somebody with any sense of humor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    too narcissistic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jdmxrain
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From the very first second that this documentary starts Madonna is full of her own ego. She is very self-centered from the get-go. Watching this documentary I understand why none of her relationships in life last very long. And I mean more than just romantic relationships, she's had a lot of broken friendships. Anyway after 7 minutes of watching it, I decided to skip around to the Warren Beatty parts, I was really curious about him. After his scenes, I skipped towards the end. Yea I skipped around a lot in this documentary because I didn't think it was worth watching the entire hour and 59 minutes. Sure I like some of her music, but her act of using her sexuality is nothing new. Also spoiled divas are nothing new in this world. In the end she's an entertainer and nothing more. I'm not impressed with her quests for spirituality either. I skipped a lot with this documentary, I was really interested in her relationship with Warren Beatty. She's very disrespectful, she calls him up and he's supposed to meet her but there's some misunderstanding and instead of working it out like a woman, she decides to hang up on him. To Madonna people are just expendable, its all just a game to her. I don't think people should take themselves seriously but its like she mistreats people and I don't like that. I get why none of her relationships last and why her marriage probably didn't last. Warren Beatty also tries to talk to Madonna and bring her to reality, he's not mean either, he actually seems like a very nice man, he speaks in a normal voice and tries to reason with her. I can see why it took a long time for Warren Beatty to commit to a woman because with a circus trainwreck like Madonna, even the nicest guy in the world would run. Warren grew up and married Annette Bening and Madonna didn't grow up at all. Not even with kids in her life. She's going to be one of those lonely old people in the end with no one by her side when she really hits her senior years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Less of each than we are led to believe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a simple concert video, this one is above average. But the title is very misleading. First let's deal with the 'truth' aspect. Madonna's friends pop in on her - Warren Beatty, Sandra Bernhart - but you get little in the way of glimpses into her relationships with others. You see Madonna playing Mother Hen to her backup performers, but you get the sense that she isn't very close to any of them. Thus, even though this is supposed to be an expose of Madonna's true private life, there is so little of this on screen that the audience is denied a genuine insider's view. And when Madonna deals with the business aspects of her tour, the boardroom door closes on the camera and the audience. This aspect of the life of a performer so well known for her product-image management might potentially be the most fascinating part of the tour, but the audience is kept outside. And compared to some of what Madonna has done on the screen, this is so far below her usual standards of shock as to hardly qualify as 'daring'. It is worth a watch, but beware of a stretching of the 'truth' when it comes to packaging.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Portrait of an Artist as a young woman.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (victor7754@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Madonna is captivating in Truth or Dare, a self produced documentary showcasing the Blond Pop Star on stage and back stage. There are no cigarettes and their is little drinking, if any going on in the film. Truth or Dare is more about a formed family that produces one hell of a spectacle and at the center is Madonna who holds everyone together using a soft tongue, humor, vulgarity, sex and prayer. Madonna is a phenomenon who soaks up the paparazzi like a magnet; she loves the camera and attention. It is fun to watch Madonna shrewdly humiliate famous men like Kevin Costner and Warren Beatty. It's fun to see her get playful with her dancers and show her breasts off to her friends not letting them get too close. Madonna holds prayer meetings before her concerts with her dancers and back up singers as she chomps gum. It is more like a pep prayer getting everyone into a strong light of commitment and perseverance. The film cuts between stage acts with some of Madonna's top songs then to back stage of other avenues of Madonna's life like visiting the grave of her Mother. Madonna has a helpful brother who shows up in many scenes and his presence is laid back and intelligent. Madonna works hard and achieves much in return for her abilities. She is a living legend who speaks about our rights of artistic expression. We see a kind Madonna who mothers her extended family of dancers and friends and we see a strong Madonna who laughs in the face of humility and gets away with it. Truth or Dare is more rewarding now because we have seen the direction this woman has taken. She has set the example on how to succeed in the Music World and have a good time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like You've Never Seen Her Before.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    so_original
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Truth or Dare" is a documentary that follows the escapades of pop queen Madonna and her backup dancers during her infamous 1990 Blonde Ambition World Tour. Some of her performances from this tour are included, and are filmed in color, while the moments she is not performing are filmed in black and white. Madonna is famous for constantly reinventing her image, and this Madonna is quite different from the Madonna of today. This was before the two kids and the African baby adoption, the second marriage to Guy Ritchie, and Kabbalah. This is the Madonna of 1990 : bold, controversial, sexual, artistic, and constantly pushing boundaries and limits. Her Blonde Ambition tour was a spectacle, full of elaborate choreography, costume and set changes, religious themes, and sexuality. Whether you love or hate her, one look at this movie does not question why she is one of the most successful female artists ever. She is no doubt a visionary, very driven, charismatic, and an energetic performer. Everyone knows Madonna the performer. But, Truth or Dare gives you a peek at Madonna the person. Some people have painted a picture of her as a cold-hearted bitch. There is no doubt that Madonna can dish out some diva attitude when she wants to. She sees herself as the boss, and anyone who tries to step on her toes better watch out. Plus the BA tour was very demanding, with back to back dates and non-stop sets. I'm sure you'd be quite stressed or frustrated in that situation as well. But her critics don't really take the time to point out her good qualities. She has a great sense of humor & can be very caring towards others, like her family and her back up dancers, whom she regards as her family. She sings "Happy Birthday" on stage to her father, waits for hours for her brother to show up backstage, and promotes unity between her dancers. This all seems like very genuine behavior to me. In one scene, a few of her family and friends note how impatient and demanding she can be. But she does seem to gain the people around her's love and respect. Yes, Madonna is very smart and a master at manipulating the media. So she did have control over this project and what was seen and what wasn't. But I give her credit for being brave enough to show the good & bad of her, and being unafraid to face criticism for it. In my opinion, nothing in the film was too appalling. The infamous "laugh" when she discovers her makeup artist was drugged and raped was a nervous reaction, and she did immediately apologize after wards. Madonna has often taken flack for her image, and it could just be the fact that some people don't know how to handle a strong-minded, ambitious woman. I recommend this film to people who like Madonna, cause if you don't you probably won't appreciate it or like it. There's great concert footage included as well, which fans will especially enjoy. It's also a great snap shot of the past Madonna. Whether you agree with her actions or not, she's always compelling and interesting to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Neat"? Anyone who says my show is neat has to go.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always been fascinated with Madonna. I feel that she has been unfairly maligned over the years, as are many who stretch the envelope with new ideas and thinking. I have to admit I tuned into this documentary just to see Pedro Almodovar. I hadn't realized that Madonna had a thing for Antonio Bandaras and she got to meet him at a party thrown in her honor by Almodovar. Unbelievable, that she lost out to Melanie Griffith. Seeing Madonna backstage shines a whole new light on her and makes her out to be someone who really cares about putting on a good show and, more importantly, shows her as someone who loves every - black, white, gay, straight - it doesn't matter. Everyone except Kevin Costner, who had the audacity to call her show "neat."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    On Tour With An Icon
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    avjr27
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the Blond Ambition tour was never officially released, The documentary of Truth or Dare was the only way fans could have a piece of the tour on DVD. Madonna's documentary covers all her personal and private issues. while dealing with boyfriend issues with Warren Beatty to traveling all over the world with dancers she temporarily claimed as her own, To speeches at the Vatican in Rome to having legal issues in Toronto, this is real Madonna at her campiest best. this is the documentary of all documentary's. Madonna proves to be a true business woman and Icon.this is a must for anyone who loves Madonna or anyone that enjoys good music and a great show! Anthony V Jr
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strike a Pose
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mpact75
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Madonna at her best while during the prime of her music career. Although the film was released in 1991, Truth or Dare actually takes place during the summer of 1990, as Madonna went around the globe on her Blonde Ambition tour. This documentary / music film is a piece of history of not only of Madonna back in the day but what the styles and sounds of the year where like. Boy does it bring back memories! From spandex biker shorts, to that famous cone bra, and not to forget the hairstyles... its really great to watch and think back of what life was like when "Vogue" was her biggest hit to date. She is so revealing, funny, demanding, and warm at heart. It shows the no nonsense business side of her and the sad reflective side of her as she thinks about her mother who died when she was so very young. The film is packed with celebrities, including Warren Beatty, whom she dated while filming his blockbuster film, Dick Tracy. It shows the lives of her dancers, backup singers, and the crew behind the stage as they all mingle around her and do their best for camera time. LOL But in the end, there is no brighter star than Madonna. To this day she is still pushing buttons, creating great music, and daring us all to watch. And just like this film, I think its safe to say she accomplished what she set out to do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a natural star is born???
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    giuliamaddox
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i loved this movie and was amazed by how natural madonna finally seemed in front of a camera. this is so interesting to me, primarily because of how terrible she is in every other film other then 'desperatly seeking susan,' which was just another version of her. in her other ventures into features the biggest problem with her acting is how forced, stiff, and unnatural she is in her every waking motion. it's like the camera goes on and every bad high school actor out there is suddenly channeling thru madge. yet how is it then that she is so comfortable in front of this camera? it's one of two things, as near as i can figure, either she's just a crap actress, having nothing to do with her stress in front of the camera, or, she overloads when attempting to create a manufactured person with a manufactured person. damn, i just lost my train of thought right when i was writing that second one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a strictly narcissistic self portrait
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The ersatz Madonna 'documentary' offers proof of the Material Girl's genius for self-promotion, pretending to be a candid behind-the-scenes portrait of her Blond Ambition tour when it's really just selling a lot of self-conscious backstage posturing, sandwiched between the expected MTV concert footage. Some fashionably grainy black-and-white photography gives the film a spurious air of raw slice-of-life candor, but the whole thing is one long public relations whitewash, no less calculated than her elaborate stage show and often just about as substantial. At times it seems the only purpose of the film is to reinforce the singer's image as some sort of blue-collar angel/whore, with strong maternal instincts toward her dancing troupe. Nothing else about her is revealed, except for a purely mercenary streak of exhibitionism, hardly front-page news. But there's a peculiar irony in watching Madonna (of all people) try to act natural with a camera lens constantly in her face; the effort to simply be herself can almost be called the best 'performance' of her career.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Madonna takes herself very seriously
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dierregi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie for the first time in 2009, almost twenty years after its release and this proves I am not a big Madonna fan. In fact, I never particularly liked or disliked her. I thought she was "cool" in "Desperately seeking Susan", but that was the "Into the Groove" time, when she had just started her rise. The "Blonde Ambition" tour was probably the top of Madonna's career, and this would-be documentary shows her at her most unbearable. Somebody mentioned that it shines a light on her "human" side (as if she was some sort of alien), but in truth she comes across as a controlling, pretentious bitch who goes out of her way to humiliate and annoy people. Hardly the best human side one can show. Even the visit to her mother's grave is disgustingly theatrical. Instead of making you feel sorry for the child of five who lost her mum it makes you feel sorry for the spoiled brat she became. Of course we all know that Madonna built her career on sex and the Catholic religion and by now I doubt anybody would be shocked by her swinging crucifix or her masturbation. However, tasteful it was not... and still isn't. The part filmed on stage is disappointing because some of songs performed are just not good, no matter how much sex is thrown in to spice them. The "documentary" part is embarrassing to watch. It was interesting for me to see that Madonna had a crush on Antonio Banderas, but at the time he was married with a pretty Spanish lady (who looked a lot better both of Madonna and Melanie Griffith). Warren Beatty makes the only decent comment about the whole filming, but he is also brushed off and humiliated, not to mention the poor Costner. I am not a Costner fan either, but his comment sounded rather sarcastic to me ("Neat" applied to the overbearing and vulgar show sounds like a sarcastic way to say "It sucked"), but looks like Madonna did not get the joke. She definitely takes herself very seriously when she describes herself as an "artist" who will not change anything in her show, even if she risks to get arrested for "indecent exposure" or any such like - very unlikely - charge. Finally, when she talks to her father she is so arrogant and dismissive that I felt sorry for the poor guy. She even uses the word "chatartic" with the intent of confuse her father; but looks like she herself had no clue as to what that word means. Madonna was an icon of the 80's and early 90's and possibly a decent singer, but for sure she was never a great actress and definitely not somebody with any sense of humor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    too narcissistic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jdmxrain
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From the very first second that this documentary starts Madonna is full of her own ego. She is very self-centered from the get-go. Watching this documentary I understand why none of her relationships in life last very long. And I mean more than just romantic relationships, she's had a lot of broken friendships. Anyway after 7 minutes of watching it, I decided to skip around to the Warren Beatty parts, I was really curious about him. After his scenes, I skipped towards the end. Yea I skipped around a lot in this documentary because I didn't think it was worth watching the entire hour and 59 minutes. Sure I like some of her music, but her act of using her sexuality is nothing new. Also spoiled divas are nothing new in this world. In the end she's an entertainer and nothing more. I'm not impressed with her quests for spirituality either. I skipped a lot with this documentary, I was really interested in her relationship with Warren Beatty. She's very disrespectful, she calls him up and he's supposed to meet her but there's some misunderstanding and instead of working it out like a woman, she decides to hang up on him. To Madonna people are just expendable, its all just a game to her. I don't think people should take themselves seriously but its like she mistreats people and I don't like that. I get why none of her relationships last and why her marriage probably didn't last. Warren Beatty also tries to talk to Madonna and bring her to reality, he's not mean either, he actually seems like a very nice man, he speaks in a normal voice and tries to reason with her. I can see why it took a long time for Warren Beatty to commit to a woman because with a circus trainwreck like Madonna, even the nicest guy in the world would run. Warren grew up and married Annette Bening and Madonna didn't grow up at all. Not even with kids in her life. She's going to be one of those lonely old people in the end with no one by her side when she really hits her senior years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Less of each than we are led to believe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a simple concert video, this one is above average. But the title is very misleading. First let's deal with the 'truth' aspect. Madonna's friends pop in on her - Warren Beatty, Sandra Bernhart - but you get little in the way of glimpses into her relationships with others. You see Madonna playing Mother Hen to her backup performers, but you get the sense that she isn't very close to any of them. Thus, even though this is supposed to be an expose of Madonna's true private life, there is so little of this on screen that the audience is denied a genuine insider's view. And when Madonna deals with the business aspects of her tour, the boardroom door closes on the camera and the audience. This aspect of the life of a performer so well known for her product-image management might potentially be the most fascinating part of the tour, but the audience is kept outside. And compared to some of what Madonna has done on the screen, this is so far below her usual standards of shock as to hardly qualify as 'daring'. It is worth a watch, but beware of a stretching of the 'truth' when it comes to packaging.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Portrait of an Artist as a young woman.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (victor7754@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Madonna is captivating in Truth or Dare, a self produced documentary showcasing the Blond Pop Star on stage and back stage. There are no cigarettes and their is little drinking, if any going on in the film. Truth or Dare is more about a formed family that produces one hell of a spectacle and at the center is Madonna who holds everyone together using a soft tongue, humor, vulgarity, sex and prayer. Madonna is a phenomenon who soaks up the paparazzi like a magnet; she loves the camera and attention. It is fun to watch Madonna shrewdly humiliate famous men like Kevin Costner and Warren Beatty. It's fun to see her get playful with her dancers and show her breasts off to her friends not letting them get too close. Madonna holds prayer meetings before her concerts with her dancers and back up singers as she chomps gum. It is more like a pep prayer getting everyone into a strong light of commitment and perseverance. The film cuts between stage acts with some of Madonna's top songs then to back stage of other avenues of Madonna's life like visiting the grave of her Mother. Madonna has a helpful brother who shows up in many scenes and his presence is laid back and intelligent. Madonna works hard and achieves much in return for her abilities. She is a living legend who speaks about our rights of artistic expression. We see a kind Madonna who mothers her extended family of dancers and friends and we see a strong Madonna who laughs in the face of humility and gets away with it. Truth or Dare is more rewarding now because we have seen the direction this woman has taken. She has set the example on how to succeed in the Music World and have a good time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like You've Never Seen Her Before.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    so_original
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Truth or Dare" is a documentary that follows the escapades of pop queen Madonna and her backup dancers during her infamous 1990 Blonde Ambition World Tour. Some of her performances from this tour are included, and are filmed in color, while the moments she is not performing are filmed in black and white. Madonna is famous for constantly reinventing her image, and this Madonna is quite different from the Madonna of today. This was before the two kids and the African baby adoption, the second marriage to Guy Ritchie, and Kabbalah. This is the Madonna of 1990 : bold, controversial, sexual, artistic, and constantly pushing boundaries and limits. Her Blonde Ambition tour was a spectacle, full of elaborate choreography, costume and set changes, religious themes, and sexuality. Whether you love or hate her, one look at this movie does not question why she is one of the most successful female artists ever. She is no doubt a visionary, very driven, charismatic, and an energetic performer. Everyone knows Madonna the performer. But, Truth or Dare gives you a peek at Madonna the person. Some people have painted a picture of her as a cold-hearted bitch. There is no doubt that Madonna can dish out some diva attitude when she wants to. She sees herself as the boss, and anyone who tries to step on her toes better watch out. Plus the BA tour was very demanding, with back to back dates and non-stop sets. I'm sure you'd be quite stressed or frustrated in that situation as well. But her critics don't really take the time to point out her good qualities. She has a great sense of humor & can be very caring towards others, like her family and her back up dancers, whom she regards as her family. She sings "Happy Birthday" on stage to her father, waits for hours for her brother to show up backstage, and promotes unity between her dancers. This all seems like very genuine behavior to me. In one scene, a few of her family and friends note how impatient and demanding she can be. But she does seem to gain the people around her's love and respect. Yes, Madonna is very smart and a master at manipulating the media. So she did have control over this project and what was seen and what wasn't. But I give her credit for being brave enough to show the good & bad of her, and being unafraid to face criticism for it. In my opinion, nothing in the film was too appalling. The infamous "laugh" when she discovers her makeup artist was drugged and raped was a nervous reaction, and she did immediately apologize after wards. Madonna has often taken flack for her image, and it could just be the fact that some people don't know how to handle a strong-minded, ambitious woman. I recommend this film to people who like Madonna, cause if you don't you probably won't appreciate it or like it. There's great concert footage included as well, which fans will especially enjoy. It's also a great snap shot of the past Madonna. Whether you agree with her actions or not, she's always compelling and interesting to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Neat"? Anyone who says my show is neat has to go.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always been fascinated with Madonna. I feel that she has been unfairly maligned over the years, as are many who stretch the envelope with new ideas and thinking. I have to admit I tuned into this documentary just to see Pedro Almodovar. I hadn't realized that Madonna had a thing for Antonio Bandaras and she got to meet him at a party thrown in her honor by Almodovar. Unbelievable, that she lost out to Melanie Griffith. Seeing Madonna backstage shines a whole new light on her and makes her out to be someone who really cares about putting on a good show and, more importantly, shows her as someone who loves every - black, white, gay, straight - it doesn't matter. Everyone except Kevin Costner, who had the audacity to call her show "neat."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    On Tour With An Icon
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    avjr27
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the Blond Ambition tour was never officially released, The documentary of Truth or Dare was the only way fans could have a piece of the tour on DVD. Madonna's documentary covers all her personal and private issues. while dealing with boyfriend issues with Warren Beatty to traveling all over the world with dancers she temporarily claimed as her own, To speeches at the Vatican in Rome to having legal issues in Toronto, this is real Madonna at her campiest best. this is the documentary of all documentary's. Madonna proves to be a true business woman and Icon.this is a must for anyone who loves Madonna or anyone that enjoys good music and a great show! Anthony V Jr
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strike a Pose
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mpact75
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Madonna at her best while during the prime of her music career. Although the film was released in 1991, Truth or Dare actually takes place during the summer of 1990, as Madonna went around the globe on her Blonde Ambition tour. This documentary / music film is a piece of history of not only of Madonna back in the day but what the styles and sounds of the year where like. Boy does it bring back memories! From spandex biker shorts, to that famous cone bra, and not to forget the hairstyles... its really great to watch and think back of what life was like when "Vogue" was her biggest hit to date. She is so revealing, funny, demanding, and warm at heart. It shows the no nonsense business side of her and the sad reflective side of her as she thinks about her mother who died when she was so very young. The film is packed with celebrities, including Warren Beatty, whom she dated while filming his blockbuster film, Dick Tracy. It shows the lives of her dancers, backup singers, and the crew behind the stage as they all mingle around her and do their best for camera time. LOL But in the end, there is no brighter star than Madonna. To this day she is still pushing buttons, creating great music, and daring us all to watch. And just like this film, I think its safe to say she accomplished what she set out to do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a natural star is born???
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    giuliamaddox
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i loved this movie and was amazed by how natural madonna finally seemed in front of a camera. this is so interesting to me, primarily because of how terrible she is in every other film other then 'desperatly seeking susan,' which was just another version of her. in her other ventures into features the biggest problem with her acting is how forced, stiff, and unnatural she is in her every waking motion. it's like the camera goes on and every bad high school actor out there is suddenly channeling thru madge. yet how is it then that she is so comfortable in front of this camera? it's one of two things, as near as i can figure, either she's just a crap actress, having nothing to do with her stress in front of the camera, or, she overloads when attempting to create a manufactured person with a manufactured person. damn, i just lost my train of thought right when i was writing that second one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a strictly narcissistic self portrait
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The ersatz Madonna 'documentary' offers proof of the Material Girl's genius for self-promotion, pretending to be a candid behind-the-scenes portrait of her Blond Ambition tour when it's really just selling a lot of self-conscious backstage posturing, sandwiched between the expected MTV concert footage. Some fashionably grainy black-and-white photography gives the film a spurious air of raw slice-of-life candor, but the whole thing is one long public relations whitewash, no less calculated than her elaborate stage show and often just about as substantial. At times it seems the only purpose of the film is to reinforce the singer's image as some sort of blue-collar angel/whore, with strong maternal instincts toward her dancing troupe. Nothing else about her is revealed, except for a purely mercenary streak of exhibitionism, hardly front-page news. But there's a peculiar irony in watching Madonna (of all people) try to act natural with a camera lens constantly in her face; the effort to simply be herself can almost be called the best 'performance' of her career.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Madonna takes herself very seriously
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dierregi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie for the first time in 2009, almost twenty years after its release and this proves I am not a big Madonna fan. In fact, I never particularly liked or disliked her. I thought she was "cool" in "Desperately seeking Susan", but that was the "Into the Groove" time, when she had just started her rise. The "Blonde Ambition" tour was probably the top of Madonna's career, and this would-be documentary shows her at her most unbearable. Somebody mentioned that it shines a light on her "human" side (as if she was some sort of alien), but in truth she comes across as a controlling, pretentious bitch who goes out of her way to humiliate and annoy people. Hardly the best human side one can show. Even the visit to her mother's grave is disgustingly theatrical. Instead of making you feel sorry for the child of five who lost her mum it makes you feel sorry for the spoiled brat she became. Of course we all know that Madonna built her career on sex and the Catholic religion and by now I doubt anybody would be shocked by her swinging crucifix or her masturbation. However, tasteful it was not... and still isn't. The part filmed on stage is disappointing because some of songs performed are just not good, no matter how much sex is thrown in to spice them. The "documentary" part is embarrassing to watch. It was interesting for me to see that Madonna had a crush on Antonio Banderas, but at the time he was married with a pretty Spanish lady (who looked a lot better both of Madonna and Melanie Griffith). Warren Beatty makes the only decent comment about the whole filming, but he is also brushed off and humiliated, not to mention the poor Costner. I am not a Costner fan either, but his comment sounded rather sarcastic to me ("Neat" applied to the overbearing and vulgar show sounds like a sarcastic way to say "It sucked"), but looks like Madonna did not get the joke. She definitely takes herself very seriously when she describes herself as an "artist" who will not change anything in her show, even if she risks to get arrested for "indecent exposure" or any such like - very unlikely - charge. Finally, when she talks to her father she is so arrogant and dismissive that I felt sorry for the poor guy. She even uses the word "chatartic" with the intent of confuse her father; but looks like she herself had no clue as to what that word means. Madonna was an icon of the 80's and early 90's and possibly a decent singer, but for sure she was never a great actress and definitely not somebody with any sense of humor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    too narcissistic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jdmxrain
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From the very first second that this documentary starts Madonna is full of her own ego. She is very self-centered from the get-go. Watching this documentary I understand why none of her relationships in life last very long. And I mean more than just romantic relationships, she's had a lot of broken friendships. Anyway after 7 minutes of watching it, I decided to skip around to the Warren Beatty parts, I was really curious about him. After his scenes, I skipped towards the end. Yea I skipped around a lot in this documentary because I didn't think it was worth watching the entire hour and 59 minutes. Sure I like some of her music, but her act of using her sexuality is nothing new. Also spoiled divas are nothing new in this world. In the end she's an entertainer and nothing more. I'm not impressed with her quests for spirituality either. I skipped a lot with this documentary, I was really interested in her relationship with Warren Beatty. She's very disrespectful, she calls him up and he's supposed to meet her but there's some misunderstanding and instead of working it out like a woman, she decides to hang up on him. To Madonna people are just expendable, its all just a game to her. I don't think people should take themselves seriously but its like she mistreats people and I don't like that. I get why none of her relationships last and why her marriage probably didn't last. Warren Beatty also tries to talk to Madonna and bring her to reality, he's not mean either, he actually seems like a very nice man, he speaks in a normal voice and tries to reason with her. I can see why it took a long time for Warren Beatty to commit to a woman because with a circus trainwreck like Madonna, even the nicest guy in the world would run. Warren grew up and married Annette Bening and Madonna didn't grow up at all. Not even with kids in her life. She's going to be one of those lonely old people in the end with no one by her side when she really hits her senior years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Less of each than we are led to believe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a simple concert video, this one is above average. But the title is very misleading. First let's deal with the 'truth' aspect. Madonna's friends pop in on her - Warren Beatty, Sandra Bernhart - but you get little in the way of glimpses into her relationships with others. You see Madonna playing Mother Hen to her backup performers, but you get the sense that she isn't very close to any of them. Thus, even though this is supposed to be an expose of Madonna's true private life, there is so little of this on screen that the audience is denied a genuine insider's view. And when Madonna deals with the business aspects of her tour, the boardroom door closes on the camera and the audience. This aspect of the life of a performer so well known for her product-image management might potentially be the most fascinating part of the tour, but the audience is kept outside. And compared to some of what Madonna has done on the screen, this is so far below her usual standards of shock as to hardly qualify as 'daring'. It is worth a watch, but beware of a stretching of the 'truth' when it comes to packaging.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Portrait of an Artist as a young woman.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (victor7754@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Madonna is captivating in Truth or Dare, a self produced documentary showcasing the Blond Pop Star on stage and back stage. There are no cigarettes and their is little drinking, if any going on in the film. Truth or Dare is more about a formed family that produces one hell of a spectacle and at the center is Madonna who holds everyone together using a soft tongue, humor, vulgarity, sex and prayer. Madonna is a phenomenon who soaks up the paparazzi like a magnet; she loves the camera and attention. It is fun to watch Madonna shrewdly humiliate famous men like Kevin Costner and Warren Beatty. It's fun to see her get playful with her dancers and show her breasts off to her friends not letting them get too close. Madonna holds prayer meetings before her concerts with her dancers and back up singers as she chomps gum. It is more like a pep prayer getting everyone into a strong light of commitment and perseverance. The film cuts between stage acts with some of Madonna's top songs then to back stage of other avenues of Madonna's life like visiting the grave of her Mother. Madonna has a helpful brother who shows up in many scenes and his presence is laid back and intelligent. Madonna works hard and achieves much in return for her abilities. She is a living legend who speaks about our rights of artistic expression. We see a kind Madonna who mothers her extended family of dancers and friends and we see a strong Madonna who laughs in the face of humility and gets away with it. Truth or Dare is more rewarding now because we have seen the direction this woman has taken. She has set the example on how to succeed in the Music World and have a good time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like You've Never Seen Her Before.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    so_original
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Truth or Dare" is a documentary that follows the escapades of pop queen Madonna and her backup dancers during her infamous 1990 Blonde Ambition World Tour. Some of her performances from this tour are included, and are filmed in color, while the moments she is not performing are filmed in black and white. Madonna is famous for constantly reinventing her image, and this Madonna is quite different from the Madonna of today. This was before the two kids and the African baby adoption, the second marriage to Guy Ritchie, and Kabbalah. This is the Madonna of 1990 : bold, controversial, sexual, artistic, and constantly pushing boundaries and limits. Her Blonde Ambition tour was a spectacle, full of elaborate choreography, costume and set changes, religious themes, and sexuality. Whether you love or hate her, one look at this movie does not question why she is one of the most successful female artists ever. She is no doubt a visionary, very driven, charismatic, and an energetic performer. Everyone knows Madonna the performer. But, Truth or Dare gives you a peek at Madonna the person. Some people have painted a picture of her as a cold-hearted bitch. There is no doubt that Madonna can dish out some diva attitude when she wants to. She sees herself as the boss, and anyone who tries to step on her toes better watch out. Plus the BA tour was very demanding, with back to back dates and non-stop sets. I'm sure you'd be quite stressed or frustrated in that situation as well. But her critics don't really take the time to point out her good qualities. She has a great sense of humor & can be very caring towards others, like her family and her back up dancers, whom she regards as her family. She sings "Happy Birthday" on stage to her father, waits for hours for her brother to show up backstage, and promotes unity between her dancers. This all seems like very genuine behavior to me. In one scene, a few of her family and friends note how impatient and demanding she can be. But she does seem to gain the people around her's love and respect. Yes, Madonna is very smart and a master at manipulating the media. So she did have control over this project and what was seen and what wasn't. But I give her credit for being brave enough to show the good & bad of her, and being unafraid to face criticism for it. In my opinion, nothing in the film was too appalling. The infamous "laugh" when she discovers her makeup artist was drugged and raped was a nervous reaction, and she did immediately apologize after wards. Madonna has often taken flack for her image, and it could just be the fact that some people don't know how to handle a strong-minded, ambitious woman. I recommend this film to people who like Madonna, cause if you don't you probably won't appreciate it or like it. There's great concert footage included as well, which fans will especially enjoy. It's also a great snap shot of the past Madonna. Whether you agree with her actions or not, she's always compelling and interesting to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Neat"? Anyone who says my show is neat has to go.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always been fascinated with Madonna. I feel that she has been unfairly maligned over the years, as are many who stretch the envelope with new ideas and thinking. I have to admit I tuned into this documentary just to see Pedro Almodovar. I hadn't realized that Madonna had a thing for Antonio Bandaras and she got to meet him at a party thrown in her honor by Almodovar. Unbelievable, that she lost out to Melanie Griffith. Seeing Madonna backstage shines a whole new light on her and makes her out to be someone who really cares about putting on a good show and, more importantly, shows her as someone who loves every - black, white, gay, straight - it doesn't matter. Everyone except Kevin Costner, who had the audacity to call her show "neat."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    On Tour With An Icon
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    avjr27
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the Blond Ambition tour was never officially released, The documentary of Truth or Dare was the only way fans could have a piece of the tour on DVD. Madonna's documentary covers all her personal and private issues. while dealing with boyfriend issues with Warren Beatty to traveling all over the world with dancers she temporarily claimed as her own, To speeches at the Vatican in Rome to having legal issues in Toronto, this is real Madonna at her campiest best. this is the documentary of all documentary's. Madonna proves to be a true business woman and Icon.this is a must for anyone who loves Madonna or anyone that enjoys good music and a great show! Anthony V Jr
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strike a Pose
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mpact75
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Madonna at her best while during the prime of her music career. Although the film was released in 1991, Truth or Dare actually takes place during the summer of 1990, as Madonna went around the globe on her Blonde Ambition tour. This documentary / music film is a piece of history of not only of Madonna back in the day but what the styles and sounds of the year where like. Boy does it bring back memories! From spandex biker shorts, to that famous cone bra, and not to forget the hairstyles... its really great to watch and think back of what life was like when "Vogue" was her biggest hit to date. She is so revealing, funny, demanding, and warm at heart. It shows the no nonsense business side of her and the sad reflective side of her as she thinks about her mother who died when she was so very young. The film is packed with celebrities, including Warren Beatty, whom she dated while filming his blockbuster film, Dick Tracy. It shows the lives of her dancers, backup singers, and the crew behind the stage as they all mingle around her and do their best for camera time. LOL But in the end, there is no brighter star than Madonna. To this day she is still pushing buttons, creating great music, and daring us all to watch. And just like this film, I think its safe to say she accomplished what she set out to do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a natural star is born???
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    giuliamaddox
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i loved this movie and was amazed by how natural madonna finally seemed in front of a camera. this is so interesting to me, primarily because of how terrible she is in every other film other then 'desperatly seeking susan,' which was just another version of her. in her other ventures into features the biggest problem with her acting is how forced, stiff, and unnatural she is in her every waking motion. it's like the camera goes on and every bad high school actor out there is suddenly channeling thru madge. yet how is it then that she is so comfortable in front of this camera? it's one of two things, as near as i can figure, either she's just a crap actress, having nothing to do with her stress in front of the camera, or, she overloads when attempting to create a manufactured person with a manufactured person. damn, i just lost my train of thought right when i was writing that second one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a strictly narcissistic self portrait
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The ersatz Madonna 'documentary' offers proof of the Material Girl's genius for self-promotion, pretending to be a candid behind-the-scenes portrait of her Blond Ambition tour when it's really just selling a lot of self-conscious backstage posturing, sandwiched between the expected MTV concert footage. Some fashionably grainy black-and-white photography gives the film a spurious air of raw slice-of-life candor, but the whole thing is one long public relations whitewash, no less calculated than her elaborate stage show and often just about as substantial. At times it seems the only purpose of the film is to reinforce the singer's image as some sort of blue-collar angel/whore, with strong maternal instincts toward her dancing troupe. Nothing else about her is revealed, except for a purely mercenary streak of exhibitionism, hardly front-page news. But there's a peculiar irony in watching Madonna (of all people) try to act natural with a camera lens constantly in her face; the effort to simply be herself can almost be called the best 'performance' of her career.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Madonna takes herself very seriously
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dierregi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie for the first time in 2009, almost twenty years after its release and this proves I am not a big Madonna fan. In fact, I never particularly liked or disliked her. I thought she was "cool" in "Desperately seeking Susan", but that was the "Into the Groove" time, when she had just started her rise. The "Blonde Ambition" tour was probably the top of Madonna's career, and this would-be documentary shows her at her most unbearable. Somebody mentioned that it shines a light on her "human" side (as if she was some sort of alien), but in truth she comes across as a controlling, pretentious bitch who goes out of her way to humiliate and annoy people. Hardly the best human side one can show. Even the visit to her mother's grave is disgustingly theatrical. Instead of making you feel sorry for the child of five who lost her mum it makes you feel sorry for the spoiled brat she became. Of course we all know that Madonna built her career on sex and the Catholic religion and by now I doubt anybody would be shocked by her swinging crucifix or her masturbation. However, tasteful it was not... and still isn't. The part filmed on stage is disappointing because some of songs performed are just not good, no matter how much sex is thrown in to spice them. The "documentary" part is embarrassing to watch. It was interesting for me to see that Madonna had a crush on Antonio Banderas, but at the time he was married with a pretty Spanish lady (who looked a lot better both of Madonna and Melanie Griffith). Warren Beatty makes the only decent comment about the whole filming, but he is also brushed off and humiliated, not to mention the poor Costner. I am not a Costner fan either, but his comment sounded rather sarcastic to me ("Neat" applied to the overbearing and vulgar show sounds like a sarcastic way to say "It sucked"), but looks like Madonna did not get the joke. She definitely takes herself very seriously when she describes herself as an "artist" who will not change anything in her show, even if she risks to get arrested for "indecent exposure" or any such like - very unlikely - charge. Finally, when she talks to her father she is so arrogant and dismissive that I felt sorry for the poor guy. She even uses the word "chatartic" with the intent of confuse her father; but looks like she herself had no clue as to what that word means. Madonna was an icon of the 80's and early 90's and possibly a decent singer, but for sure she was never a great actress and definitely not somebody with any sense of humor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    too narcissistic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jdmxrain
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From the very first second that this documentary starts Madonna is full of her own ego. She is very self-centered from the get-go. Watching this documentary I understand why none of her relationships in life last very long. And I mean more than just romantic relationships, she's had a lot of broken friendships. Anyway after 7 minutes of watching it, I decided to skip around to the Warren Beatty parts, I was really curious about him. After his scenes, I skipped towards the end. Yea I skipped around a lot in this documentary because I didn't think it was worth watching the entire hour and 59 minutes. Sure I like some of her music, but her act of using her sexuality is nothing new. Also spoiled divas are nothing new in this world. In the end she's an entertainer and nothing more. I'm not impressed with her quests for spirituality either. I skipped a lot with this documentary, I was really interested in her relationship with Warren Beatty. She's very disrespectful, she calls him up and he's supposed to meet her but there's some misunderstanding and instead of working it out like a woman, she decides to hang up on him. To Madonna people are just expendable, its all just a game to her. I don't think people should take themselves seriously but its like she mistreats people and I don't like that. I get why none of her relationships last and why her marriage probably didn't last. Warren Beatty also tries to talk to Madonna and bring her to reality, he's not mean either, he actually seems like a very nice man, he speaks in a normal voice and tries to reason with her. I can see why it took a long time for Warren Beatty to commit to a woman because with a circus trainwreck like Madonna, even the nicest guy in the world would run. Warren grew up and married Annette Bening and Madonna didn't grow up at all. Not even with kids in her life. She's going to be one of those lonely old people in the end with no one by her side when she really hits her senior years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Less of each than we are led to believe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a simple concert video, this one is above average. But the title is very misleading. First let's deal with the 'truth' aspect. Madonna's friends pop in on her - Warren Beatty, Sandra Bernhart - but you get little in the way of glimpses into her relationships with others. You see Madonna playing Mother Hen to her backup performers, but you get the sense that she isn't very close to any of them. Thus, even though this is supposed to be an expose of Madonna's true private life, there is so little of this on screen that the audience is denied a genuine insider's view. And when Madonna deals with the business aspects of her tour, the boardroom door closes on the camera and the audience. This aspect of the life of a performer so well known for her product-image management might potentially be the most fascinating part of the tour, but the audience is kept outside. And compared to some of what Madonna has done on the screen, this is so far below her usual standards of shock as to hardly qualify as 'daring'. It is worth a watch, but beware of a stretching of the 'truth' when it comes to packaging.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Portrait of an Artist as a young woman.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (victor7754@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Madonna is captivating in Truth or Dare, a self produced documentary showcasing the Blond Pop Star on stage and back stage. There are no cigarettes and their is little drinking, if any going on in the film. Truth or Dare is more about a formed family that produces one hell of a spectacle and at the center is Madonna who holds everyone together using a soft tongue, humor, vulgarity, sex and prayer. Madonna is a phenomenon who soaks up the paparazzi like a magnet; she loves the camera and attention. It is fun to watch Madonna shrewdly humiliate famous men like Kevin Costner and Warren Beatty. It's fun to see her get playful with her dancers and show her breasts off to her friends not letting them get too close. Madonna holds prayer meetings before her concerts with her dancers and back up singers as she chomps gum. It is more like a pep prayer getting everyone into a strong light of commitment and perseverance. The film cuts between stage acts with some of Madonna's top songs then to back stage of other avenues of Madonna's life like visiting the grave of her Mother. Madonna has a helpful brother who shows up in many scenes and his presence is laid back and intelligent. Madonna works hard and achieves much in return for her abilities. She is a living legend who speaks about our rights of artistic expression. We see a kind Madonna who mothers her extended family of dancers and friends and we see a strong Madonna who laughs in the face of humility and gets away with it. Truth or Dare is more rewarding now because we have seen the direction this woman has taken. She has set the example on how to succeed in the Music World and have a good time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like You've Never Seen Her Before.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    so_original
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Truth or Dare" is a documentary that follows the escapades of pop queen Madonna and her backup dancers during her infamous 1990 Blonde Ambition World Tour. Some of her performances from this tour are included, and are filmed in color, while the moments she is not performing are filmed in black and white. Madonna is famous for constantly reinventing her image, and this Madonna is quite different from the Madonna of today. This was before the two kids and the African baby adoption, the second marriage to Guy Ritchie, and Kabbalah. This is the Madonna of 1990 : bold, controversial, sexual, artistic, and constantly pushing boundaries and limits. Her Blonde Ambition tour was a spectacle, full of elaborate choreography, costume and set changes, religious themes, and sexuality. Whether you love or hate her, one look at this movie does not question why she is one of the most successful female artists ever. She is no doubt a visionary, very driven, charismatic, and an energetic performer. Everyone knows Madonna the performer. But, Truth or Dare gives you a peek at Madonna the person. Some people have painted a picture of her as a cold-hearted bitch. There is no doubt that Madonna can dish out some diva attitude when she wants to. She sees herself as the boss, and anyone who tries to step on her toes better watch out. Plus the BA tour was very demanding, with back to back dates and non-stop sets. I'm sure you'd be quite stressed or frustrated in that situation as well. But her critics don't really take the time to point out her good qualities. She has a great sense of humor & can be very caring towards others, like her family and her back up dancers, whom she regards as her family. She sings "Happy Birthday" on stage to her father, waits for hours for her brother to show up backstage, and promotes unity between her dancers. This all seems like very genuine behavior to me. In one scene, a few of her family and friends note how impatient and demanding she can be. But she does seem to gain the people around her's love and respect. Yes, Madonna is very smart and a master at manipulating the media. So she did have control over this project and what was seen and what wasn't. But I give her credit for being brave enough to show the good & bad of her, and being unafraid to face criticism for it. In my opinion, nothing in the film was too appalling. The infamous "laugh" when she discovers her makeup artist was drugged and raped was a nervous reaction, and she did immediately apologize after wards. Madonna has often taken flack for her image, and it could just be the fact that some people don't know how to handle a strong-minded, ambitious woman. I recommend this film to people who like Madonna, cause if you don't you probably won't appreciate it or like it. There's great concert footage included as well, which fans will especially enjoy. It's also a great snap shot of the past Madonna. Whether you agree with her actions or not, she's always compelling and interesting to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Neat"? Anyone who says my show is neat has to go.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always been fascinated with Madonna. I feel that she has been unfairly maligned over the years, as are many who stretch the envelope with new ideas and thinking. I have to admit I tuned into this documentary just to see Pedro Almodovar. I hadn't realized that Madonna had a thing for Antonio Bandaras and she got to meet him at a party thrown in her honor by Almodovar. Unbelievable, that she lost out to Melanie Griffith. Seeing Madonna backstage shines a whole new light on her and makes her out to be someone who really cares about putting on a good show and, more importantly, shows her as someone who loves every - black, white, gay, straight - it doesn't matter. Everyone except Kevin Costner, who had the audacity to call her show "neat."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    On Tour With An Icon
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    avjr27
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the Blond Ambition tour was never officially released, The documentary of Truth or Dare was the only way fans could have a piece of the tour on DVD. Madonna's documentary covers all her personal and private issues. while dealing with boyfriend issues with Warren Beatty to traveling all over the world with dancers she temporarily claimed as her own, To speeches at the Vatican in Rome to having legal issues in Toronto, this is real Madonna at her campiest best. this is the documentary of all documentary's. Madonna proves to be a true business woman and Icon.this is a must for anyone who loves Madonna or anyone that enjoys good music and a great show! Anthony V Jr
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strike a Pose
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mpact75
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Madonna at her best while during the prime of her music career. Although the film was released in 1991, Truth or Dare actually takes place during the summer of 1990, as Madonna went around the globe on her Blonde Ambition tour. This documentary / music film is a piece of history of not only of Madonna back in the day but what the styles and sounds of the year where like. Boy does it bring back memories! From spandex biker shorts, to that famous cone bra, and not to forget the hairstyles... its really great to watch and think back of what life was like when "Vogue" was her biggest hit to date. She is so revealing, funny, demanding, and warm at heart. It shows the no nonsense business side of her and the sad reflective side of her as she thinks about her mother who died when she was so very young. The film is packed with celebrities, including Warren Beatty, whom she dated while filming his blockbuster film, Dick Tracy. It shows the lives of her dancers, backup singers, and the crew behind the stage as they all mingle around her and do their best for camera time. LOL But in the end, there is no brighter star than Madonna. To this day she is still pushing buttons, creating great music, and daring us all to watch. And just like this film, I think its safe to say she accomplished what she set out to do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a natural star is born???
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    giuliamaddox
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i loved this movie and was amazed by how natural madonna finally seemed in front of a camera. this is so interesting to me, primarily because of how terrible she is in every other film other then 'desperatly seeking susan,' which was just another version of her. in her other ventures into features the biggest problem with her acting is how forced, stiff, and unnatural she is in her every waking motion. it's like the camera goes on and every bad high school actor out there is suddenly channeling thru madge. yet how is it then that she is so comfortable in front of this camera? it's one of two things, as near as i can figure, either she's just a crap actress, having nothing to do with her stress in front of the camera, or, she overloads when attempting to create a manufactured person with a manufactured person. damn, i just lost my train of thought right when i was writing that second one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a strictly narcissistic self portrait
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The ersatz Madonna 'documentary' offers proof of the Material Girl's genius for self-promotion, pretending to be a candid behind-the-scenes portrait of her Blond Ambition tour when it's really just selling a lot of self-conscious backstage posturing, sandwiched between the expected MTV concert footage. Some fashionably grainy black-and-white photography gives the film a spurious air of raw slice-of-life candor, but the whole thing is one long public relations whitewash, no less calculated than her elaborate stage show and often just about as substantial. At times it seems the only purpose of the film is to reinforce the singer's image as some sort of blue-collar angel/whore, with strong maternal instincts toward her dancing troupe. Nothing else about her is revealed, except for a purely mercenary streak of exhibitionism, hardly front-page news. But there's a peculiar irony in watching Madonna (of all people) try to act natural with a camera lens constantly in her face; the effort to simply be herself can almost be called the best 'performance' of her career.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Madonna takes herself very seriously
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dierregi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie for the first time in 2009, almost twenty years after its release and this proves I am not a big Madonna fan. In fact, I never particularly liked or disliked her. I thought she was "cool" in "Desperately seeking Susan", but that was the "Into the Groove" time, when she had just started her rise. The "Blonde Ambition" tour was probably the top of Madonna's career, and this would-be documentary shows her at her most unbearable. Somebody mentioned that it shines a light on her "human" side (as if she was some sort of alien), but in truth she comes across as a controlling, pretentious bitch who goes out of her way to humiliate and annoy people. Hardly the best human side one can show. Even the visit to her mother's grave is disgustingly theatrical. Instead of making you feel sorry for the child of five who lost her mum it makes you feel sorry for the spoiled brat she became. Of course we all know that Madonna built her career on sex and the Catholic religion and by now I doubt anybody would be shocked by her swinging crucifix or her masturbation. However, tasteful it was not... and still isn't. The part filmed on stage is disappointing because some of songs performed are just not good, no matter how much sex is thrown in to spice them. The "documentary" part is embarrassing to watch. It was interesting for me to see that Madonna had a crush on Antonio Banderas, but at the time he was married with a pretty Spanish lady (who looked a lot better both of Madonna and Melanie Griffith). Warren Beatty makes the only decent comment about the whole filming, but he is also brushed off and humiliated, not to mention the poor Costner. I am not a Costner fan either, but his comment sounded rather sarcastic to me ("Neat" applied to the overbearing and vulgar show sounds like a sarcastic way to say "It sucked"), but looks like Madonna did not get the joke. She definitely takes herself very seriously when she describes herself as an "artist" who will not change anything in her show, even if she risks to get arrested for "indecent exposure" or any such like - very unlikely - charge. Finally, when she talks to her father she is so arrogant and dismissive that I felt sorry for the poor guy. She even uses the word "chatartic" with the intent of confuse her father; but looks like she herself had no clue as to what that word means. Madonna was an icon of the 80's and early 90's and possibly a decent singer, but for sure she was never a great actress and definitely not somebody with any sense of humor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    too narcissistic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jdmxrain
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From the very first second that this documentary starts Madonna is full of her own ego. She is very self-centered from the get-go. Watching this documentary I understand why none of her relationships in life last very long. And I mean more than just romantic relationships, she's had a lot of broken friendships. Anyway after 7 minutes of watching it, I decided to skip around to the Warren Beatty parts, I was really curious about him. After his scenes, I skipped towards the end. Yea I skipped around a lot in this documentary because I didn't think it was worth watching the entire hour and 59 minutes. Sure I like some of her music, but her act of using her sexuality is nothing new. Also spoiled divas are nothing new in this world. In the end she's an entertainer and nothing more. I'm not impressed with her quests for spirituality either. I skipped a lot with this documentary, I was really interested in her relationship with Warren Beatty. She's very disrespectful, she calls him up and he's supposed to meet her but there's some misunderstanding and instead of working it out like a woman, she decides to hang up on him. To Madonna people are just expendable, its all just a game to her. I don't think people should take themselves seriously but its like she mistreats people and I don't like that. I get why none of her relationships last and why her marriage probably didn't last. Warren Beatty also tries to talk to Madonna and bring her to reality, he's not mean either, he actually seems like a very nice man, he speaks in a normal voice and tries to reason with her. I can see why it took a long time for Warren Beatty to commit to a woman because with a circus trainwreck like Madonna, even the nicest guy in the world would run. Warren grew up and married Annette Bening and Madonna didn't grow up at all. Not even with kids in her life. She's going to be one of those lonely old people in the end with no one by her side when she really hits her senior years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Less of each than we are led to believe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a simple concert video, this one is above average. But the title is very misleading. First let's deal with the 'truth' aspect. Madonna's friends pop in on her - Warren Beatty, Sandra Bernhart - but you get little in the way of glimpses into her relationships with others. You see Madonna playing Mother Hen to her backup performers, but you get the sense that she isn't very close to any of them. Thus, even though this is supposed to be an expose of Madonna's true private life, there is so little of this on screen that the audience is denied a genuine insider's view. And when Madonna deals with the business aspects of her tour, the boardroom door closes on the camera and the audience. This aspect of the life of a performer so well known for her product-image management might potentially be the most fascinating part of the tour, but the audience is kept outside. And compared to some of what Madonna has done on the screen, this is so far below her usual standards of shock as to hardly qualify as 'daring'. It is worth a watch, but beware of a stretching of the 'truth' when it comes to packaging.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Portrait of an Artist as a young woman.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (victor7754@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Madonna is captivating in Truth or Dare, a self produced documentary showcasing the Blond Pop Star on stage and back stage. There are no cigarettes and their is little drinking, if any going on in the film. Truth or Dare is more about a formed family that produces one hell of a spectacle and at the center is Madonna who holds everyone together using a soft tongue, humor, vulgarity, sex and prayer. Madonna is a phenomenon who soaks up the paparazzi like a magnet; she loves the camera and attention. It is fun to watch Madonna shrewdly humiliate famous men like Kevin Costner and Warren Beatty. It's fun to see her get playful with her dancers and show her breasts off to her friends not letting them get too close. Madonna holds prayer meetings before her concerts with her dancers and back up singers as she chomps gum. It is more like a pep prayer getting everyone into a strong light of commitment and perseverance. The film cuts between stage acts with some of Madonna's top songs then to back stage of other avenues of Madonna's life like visiting the grave of her Mother. Madonna has a helpful brother who shows up in many scenes and his presence is laid back and intelligent. Madonna works hard and achieves much in return for her abilities. She is a living legend who speaks about our rights of artistic expression. We see a kind Madonna who mothers her extended family of dancers and friends and we see a strong Madonna who laughs in the face of humility and gets away with it. Truth or Dare is more rewarding now because we have seen the direction this woman has taken. She has set the example on how to succeed in the Music World and have a good time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like You've Never Seen Her Before.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    so_original
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Truth or Dare" is a documentary that follows the escapades of pop queen Madonna and her backup dancers during her infamous 1990 Blonde Ambition World Tour. Some of her performances from this tour are included, and are filmed in color, while the moments she is not performing are filmed in black and white. Madonna is famous for constantly reinventing her image, and this Madonna is quite different from the Madonna of today. This was before the two kids and the African baby adoption, the second marriage to Guy Ritchie, and Kabbalah. This is the Madonna of 1990 : bold, controversial, sexual, artistic, and constantly pushing boundaries and limits. Her Blonde Ambition tour was a spectacle, full of elaborate choreography, costume and set changes, religious themes, and sexuality. Whether you love or hate her, one look at this movie does not question why she is one of the most successful female artists ever. She is no doubt a visionary, very driven, charismatic, and an energetic performer. Everyone knows Madonna the performer. But, Truth or Dare gives you a peek at Madonna the person. Some people have painted a picture of her as a cold-hearted bitch. There is no doubt that Madonna can dish out some diva attitude when she wants to. She sees herself as the boss, and anyone who tries to step on her toes better watch out. Plus the BA tour was very demanding, with back to back dates and non-stop sets. I'm sure you'd be quite stressed or frustrated in that situation as well. But her critics don't really take the time to point out her good qualities. She has a great sense of humor & can be very caring towards others, like her family and her back up dancers, whom she regards as her family. She sings "Happy Birthday" on stage to her father, waits for hours for her brother to show up backstage, and promotes unity between her dancers. This all seems like very genuine behavior to me. In one scene, a few of her family and friends note how impatient and demanding she can be. But she does seem to gain the people around her's love and respect. Yes, Madonna is very smart and a master at manipulating the media. So she did have control over this project and what was seen and what wasn't. But I give her credit for being brave enough to show the good & bad of her, and being unafraid to face criticism for it. In my opinion, nothing in the film was too appalling. The infamous "laugh" when she discovers her makeup artist was drugged and raped was a nervous reaction, and she did immediately apologize after wards. Madonna has often taken flack for her image, and it could just be the fact that some people don't know how to handle a strong-minded, ambitious woman. I recommend this film to people who like Madonna, cause if you don't you probably won't appreciate it or like it. There's great concert footage included as well, which fans will especially enjoy. It's also a great snap shot of the past Madonna. Whether you agree with her actions or not, she's always compelling and interesting to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Neat"? Anyone who says my show is neat has to go.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always been fascinated with Madonna. I feel that she has been unfairly maligned over the years, as are many who stretch the envelope with new ideas and thinking. I have to admit I tuned into this documentary just to see Pedro Almodovar. I hadn't realized that Madonna had a thing for Antonio Bandaras and she got to meet him at a party thrown in her honor by Almodovar. Unbelievable, that she lost out to Melanie Griffith. Seeing Madonna backstage shines a whole new light on her and makes her out to be someone who really cares about putting on a good show and, more importantly, shows her as someone who loves every - black, white, gay, straight - it doesn't matter. Everyone except Kevin Costner, who had the audacity to call her show "neat."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    On Tour With An Icon
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    avjr27
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the Blond Ambition tour was never officially released, The documentary of Truth or Dare was the only way fans could have a piece of the tour on DVD. Madonna's documentary covers all her personal and private issues. while dealing with boyfriend issues with Warren Beatty to traveling all over the world with dancers she temporarily claimed as her own, To speeches at the Vatican in Rome to having legal issues in Toronto, this is real Madonna at her campiest best. this is the documentary of all documentary's. Madonna proves to be a true business woman and Icon.this is a must for anyone who loves Madonna or anyone that enjoys good music and a great show! Anthony V Jr
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strike a Pose
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mpact75
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Madonna at her best while during the prime of her music career. Although the film was released in 1991, Truth or Dare actually takes place during the summer of 1990, as Madonna went around the globe on her Blonde Ambition tour. This documentary / music film is a piece of history of not only of Madonna back in the day but what the styles and sounds of the year where like. Boy does it bring back memories! From spandex biker shorts, to that famous cone bra, and not to forget the hairstyles... its really great to watch and think back of what life was like when "Vogue" was her biggest hit to date. She is so revealing, funny, demanding, and warm at heart. It shows the no nonsense business side of her and the sad reflective side of her as she thinks about her mother who died when she was so very young. The film is packed with celebrities, including Warren Beatty, whom she dated while filming his blockbuster film, Dick Tracy. It shows the lives of her dancers, backup singers, and the crew behind the stage as they all mingle around her and do their best for camera time. LOL But in the end, there is no brighter star than Madonna. To this day she is still pushing buttons, creating great music, and daring us all to watch. And just like this film, I think its safe to say she accomplished what she set out to do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a natural star is born???
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    giuliamaddox
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i loved this movie and was amazed by how natural madonna finally seemed in front of a camera. this is so interesting to me, primarily because of how terrible she is in every other film other then 'desperatly seeking susan,' which was just another version of her. in her other ventures into features the biggest problem with her acting is how forced, stiff, and unnatural she is in her every waking motion. it's like the camera goes on and every bad high school actor out there is suddenly channeling thru madge. yet how is it then that she is so comfortable in front of this camera? it's one of two things, as near as i can figure, either she's just a crap actress, having nothing to do with her stress in front of the camera, or, she overloads when attempting to create a manufactured person with a manufactured person. damn, i just lost my train of thought right when i was writing that second one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a strictly narcissistic self portrait
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The ersatz Madonna 'documentary' offers proof of the Material Girl's genius for self-promotion, pretending to be a candid behind-the-scenes portrait of her Blond Ambition tour when it's really just selling a lot of self-conscious backstage posturing, sandwiched between the expected MTV concert footage. Some fashionably grainy black-and-white photography gives the film a spurious air of raw slice-of-life candor, but the whole thing is one long public relations whitewash, no less calculated than her elaborate stage show and often just about as substantial. At times it seems the only purpose of the film is to reinforce the singer's image as some sort of blue-collar angel/whore, with strong maternal instincts toward her dancing troupe. Nothing else about her is revealed, except for a purely mercenary streak of exhibitionism, hardly front-page news. But there's a peculiar irony in watching Madonna (of all people) try to act natural with a camera lens constantly in her face; the effort to simply be herself can almost be called the best 'performance' of her career.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Madonna takes herself very seriously
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dierregi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie for the first time in 2009, almost twenty years after its release and this proves I am not a big Madonna fan. In fact, I never particularly liked or disliked her. I thought she was "cool" in "Desperately seeking Susan", but that was the "Into the Groove" time, when she had just started her rise. The "Blonde Ambition" tour was probably the top of Madonna's career, and this would-be documentary shows her at her most unbearable. Somebody mentioned that it shines a light on her "human" side (as if she was some sort of alien), but in truth she comes across as a controlling, pretentious bitch who goes out of her way to humiliate and annoy people. Hardly the best human side one can show. Even the visit to her mother's grave is disgustingly theatrical. Instead of making you feel sorry for the child of five who lost her mum it makes you feel sorry for the spoiled brat she became. Of course we all know that Madonna built her career on sex and the Catholic religion and by now I doubt anybody would be shocked by her swinging crucifix or her masturbation. However, tasteful it was not... and still isn't. The part filmed on stage is disappointing because some of songs performed are just not good, no matter how much sex is thrown in to spice them. The "documentary" part is embarrassing to watch. It was interesting for me to see that Madonna had a crush on Antonio Banderas, but at the time he was married with a pretty Spanish lady (who looked a lot better both of Madonna and Melanie Griffith). Warren Beatty makes the only decent comment about the whole filming, but he is also brushed off and humiliated, not to mention the poor Costner. I am not a Costner fan either, but his comment sounded rather sarcastic to me ("Neat" applied to the overbearing and vulgar show sounds like a sarcastic way to say "It sucked"), but looks like Madonna did not get the joke. She definitely takes herself very seriously when she describes herself as an "artist" who will not change anything in her show, even if she risks to get arrested for "indecent exposure" or any such like - very unlikely - charge. Finally, when she talks to her father she is so arrogant and dismissive that I felt sorry for the poor guy. She even uses the word "chatartic" with the intent of confuse her father; but looks like she herself had no clue as to what that word means. Madonna was an icon of the 80's and early 90's and possibly a decent singer, but for sure she was never a great actress and definitely not somebody with any sense of humor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    too narcissistic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jdmxrain
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From the very first second that this documentary starts Madonna is full of her own ego. She is very self-centered from the get-go. Watching this documentary I understand why none of her relationships in life last very long. And I mean more than just romantic relationships, she's had a lot of broken friendships. Anyway after 7 minutes of watching it, I decided to skip around to the Warren Beatty parts, I was really curious about him. After his scenes, I skipped towards the end. Yea I skipped around a lot in this documentary because I didn't think it was worth watching the entire hour and 59 minutes. Sure I like some of her music, but her act of using her sexuality is nothing new. Also spoiled divas are nothing new in this world. In the end she's an entertainer and nothing more. I'm not impressed with her quests for spirituality either. I skipped a lot with this documentary, I was really interested in her relationship with Warren Beatty. She's very disrespectful, she calls him up and he's supposed to meet her but there's some misunderstanding and instead of working it out like a woman, she decides to hang up on him. To Madonna people are just expendable, its all just a game to her. I don't think people should take themselves seriously but its like she mistreats people and I don't like that. I get why none of her relationships last and why her marriage probably didn't last. Warren Beatty also tries to talk to Madonna and bring her to reality, he's not mean either, he actually seems like a very nice man, he speaks in a normal voice and tries to reason with her. I can see why it took a long time for Warren Beatty to commit to a woman because with a circus trainwreck like Madonna, even the nicest guy in the world would run. Warren grew up and married Annette Bening and Madonna didn't grow up at all. Not even with kids in her life. She's going to be one of those lonely old people in the end with no one by her side when she really hits her senior years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Less of each than we are led to believe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a simple concert video, this one is above average. But the title is very misleading. First let's deal with the 'truth' aspect. Madonna's friends pop in on her - Warren Beatty, Sandra Bernhart - but you get little in the way of glimpses into her relationships with others. You see Madonna playing Mother Hen to her backup performers, but you get the sense that she isn't very close to any of them. Thus, even though this is supposed to be an expose of Madonna's true private life, there is so little of this on screen that the audience is denied a genuine insider's view. And when Madonna deals with the business aspects of her tour, the boardroom door closes on the camera and the audience. This aspect of the life of a performer so well known for her product-image management might potentially be the most fascinating part of the tour, but the audience is kept outside. And compared to some of what Madonna has done on the screen, this is so far below her usual standards of shock as to hardly qualify as 'daring'. It is worth a watch, but beware of a stretching of the 'truth' when it comes to packaging.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Portrait of an Artist as a young woman.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (victor7754@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Madonna is captivating in Truth or Dare, a self produced documentary showcasing the Blond Pop Star on stage and back stage. There are no cigarettes and their is little drinking, if any going on in the film. Truth or Dare is more about a formed family that produces one hell of a spectacle and at the center is Madonna who holds everyone together using a soft tongue, humor, vulgarity, sex and prayer. Madonna is a phenomenon who soaks up the paparazzi like a magnet; she loves the camera and attention. It is fun to watch Madonna shrewdly humiliate famous men like Kevin Costner and Warren Beatty. It's fun to see her get playful with her dancers and show her breasts off to her friends not letting them get too close. Madonna holds prayer meetings before her concerts with her dancers and back up singers as she chomps gum. It is more like a pep prayer getting everyone into a strong light of commitment and perseverance. The film cuts between stage acts with some of Madonna's top songs then to back stage of other avenues of Madonna's life like visiting the grave of her Mother. Madonna has a helpful brother who shows up in many scenes and his presence is laid back and intelligent. Madonna works hard and achieves much in return for her abilities. She is a living legend who speaks about our rights of artistic expression. We see a kind Madonna who mothers her extended family of dancers and friends and we see a strong Madonna who laughs in the face of humility and gets away with it. Truth or Dare is more rewarding now because we have seen the direction this woman has taken. She has set the example on how to succeed in the Music World and have a good time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like You've Never Seen Her Before.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    so_original
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Truth or Dare" is a documentary that follows the escapades of pop queen Madonna and her backup dancers during her infamous 1990 Blonde Ambition World Tour. Some of her performances from this tour are included, and are filmed in color, while the moments she is not performing are filmed in black and white. Madonna is famous for constantly reinventing her image, and this Madonna is quite different from the Madonna of today. This was before the two kids and the African baby adoption, the second marriage to Guy Ritchie, and Kabbalah. This is the Madonna of 1990 : bold, controversial, sexual, artistic, and constantly pushing boundaries and limits. Her Blonde Ambition tour was a spectacle, full of elaborate choreography, costume and set changes, religious themes, and sexuality. Whether you love or hate her, one look at this movie does not question why she is one of the most successful female artists ever. She is no doubt a visionary, very driven, charismatic, and an energetic performer. Everyone knows Madonna the performer. But, Truth or Dare gives you a peek at Madonna the person. Some people have painted a picture of her as a cold-hearted bitch. There is no doubt that Madonna can dish out some diva attitude when she wants to. She sees herself as the boss, and anyone who tries to step on her toes better watch out. Plus the BA tour was very demanding, with back to back dates and non-stop sets. I'm sure you'd be quite stressed or frustrated in that situation as well. But her critics don't really take the time to point out her good qualities. She has a great sense of humor & can be very caring towards others, like her family and her back up dancers, whom she regards as her family. She sings "Happy Birthday" on stage to her father, waits for hours for her brother to show up backstage, and promotes unity between her dancers. This all seems like very genuine behavior to me. In one scene, a few of her family and friends note how impatient and demanding she can be. But she does seem to gain the people around her's love and respect. Yes, Madonna is very smart and a master at manipulating the media. So she did have control over this project and what was seen and what wasn't. But I give her credit for being brave enough to show the good & bad of her, and being unafraid to face criticism for it. In my opinion, nothing in the film was too appalling. The infamous "laugh" when she discovers her makeup artist was drugged and raped was a nervous reaction, and she did immediately apologize after wards. Madonna has often taken flack for her image, and it could just be the fact that some people don't know how to handle a strong-minded, ambitious woman. I recommend this film to people who like Madonna, cause if you don't you probably won't appreciate it or like it. There's great concert footage included as well, which fans will especially enjoy. It's also a great snap shot of the past Madonna. Whether you agree with her actions or not, she's always compelling and interesting to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Neat"? Anyone who says my show is neat has to go.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have always been fascinated with Madonna. I feel that she has been unfairly maligned over the years, as are many who stretch the envelope with new ideas and thinking. I have to admit I tuned into this documentary just to see Pedro Almodovar. I hadn't realized that Madonna had a thing for Antonio Bandaras and she got to meet him at a party thrown in her honor by Almodovar. Unbelievable, that she lost out to Melanie Griffith. Seeing Madonna backstage shines a whole new light on her and makes her out to be someone who really cares about putting on a good show and, more importantly, shows her as someone who loves every - black, white, gay, straight - it doesn't matter. Everyone except Kevin Costner, who had the audacity to call her show "neat."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    On Tour With An Icon
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    avjr27
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the Blond Ambition tour was never officially released, The documentary of Truth or Dare was the only way fans could have a piece of the tour on DVD. Madonna's documentary covers all her personal and private issues. while dealing with boyfriend issues with Warren Beatty to traveling all over the world with dancers she temporarily claimed as her own, To speeches at the Vatican in Rome to having legal issues in Toronto, this is real Madonna at her campiest best. this is the documentary of all documentary's. Madonna proves to be a true business woman and Icon.this is a must for anyone who loves Madonna or anyone that enjoys good music and a great show! Anthony V Jr
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strike a Pose
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mpact75
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Madonna at her best while during the prime of her music career. Although the film was released in 1991, Truth or Dare actually takes place during the summer of 1990, as Madonna went around the globe on her Blonde Ambition tour. This documentary / music film is a piece of history of not only of Madonna back in the day but what the styles and sounds of the year where like. Boy does it bring back memories! From spandex biker shorts, to that famous cone bra, and not to forget the hairstyles... its really great to watch and think back of what life was like when "Vogue" was her biggest hit to date. She is so revealing, funny, demanding, and warm at heart. It shows the no nonsense business side of her and the sad reflective side of her as she thinks about her mother who died when she was so very young. The film is packed with celebrities, including Warren Beatty, whom she dated while filming his blockbuster film, Dick Tracy. It shows the lives of her dancers, backup singers, and the crew behind the stage as they all mingle around her and do their best for camera time. LOL But in the end, there is no brighter star than Madonna. To this day she is still pushing buttons, creating great music, and daring us all to watch. And just like this film, I think its safe to say she accomplished what she set out to do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a natural star is born???
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    giuliamaddox
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i loved this movie and was amazed by how natural madonna finally seemed in front of a camera. this is so interesting to me, primarily because of how terrible she is in every other film other then 'desperatly seeking susan,' which was just another version of her. in her other ventures into features the biggest problem with her acting is how forced, stiff, and unnatural she is in her every waking motion. it's like the camera goes on and every bad high school actor out there is suddenly channeling thru madge. yet how is it then that she is so comfortable in front of this camera? it's one of two things, as near as i can figure, either she's just a crap actress, having nothing to do with her stress in front of the camera, or, she overloads when attempting to create a manufactured person with a manufactured person. damn, i just lost my train of thought right when i was writing that second one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
