<filme>
 <id>
  1235
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109266
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Bang
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A young woman in L.A. is having a bad day: she's evicted, an audition ends with a producer furious she won't trade sex for the part, and a policeman nabs her for something she didn't do, ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A young woman in L.A. is having a bad day: she's evicted, an audition ends with a producer furious she won't trade sex for the part, and a policeman nabs her for something she didn't do, demanding fellatio to release her. She snaps, grabs his gun, takes his uniform, and leaves him cuffed to a tree where he's soon having a defenseless chat with a homeless man. She takes off on the cop's motorcycle and, for an afternoon, experiences a cop's life. She talks a young man out of suicide and then is plunged into violence after a friendly encounter with two "vatos." She is torn between self-protection and others' expectations. Is there any resolution for her torrent of feelings?
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   motorcycle
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   homeless
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   street life
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   police officer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   streetwise
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Ash Baron-Cohen
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Ash Baron-Cohen
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Darling Narita
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Peter Greene
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Michael Newland
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pointless drivel that will only to appeal to fans of self-indulgent artsy flicks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    broken_and_beautiful
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not sure why this movie seems to have gotten such rave reviews. While watching "Bang" one night on TV, I found myself bored by the nonsensical, random plot which was occurring on screen. The entire movie seems to be nothing more than an exercise in meaningless, artsy-fartsy self-indulgence on the part of the filmmaker. The fact that the director/writer goes by a one name moniker only reinforces this sense of pretentiousness. Those interested in indie flicks would be better off looking for something better written and dare I say, more entertaining than this complete waste of time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a must watch film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael livesey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't agree with the other review i really enjoyed the film .Its a hard hitting drama that keeps you watching, a little twisted in places but i think it was intended to shock a very art-house sort of film .I watched it on an independent film channel in the UK late one night so maybe the alcohol helped watch out for the little sub plot running through the film strange anyway enjoy the film its a must see,the film starts slowly but soon gets going a bent policeman plays a nasty trick on the leading lady and is soon caught out resulting in the tables being turned on him. She then steals the policeman's motorbike and pretends to be a policeman then the story begins
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, empowering and inspiring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    couch_potato_with_cheese
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A down-and-out actress from L.A. gets evicted and arrested, then gets revenge on all those who wronged her. This film takes an improbable series of events and creates a bizarre yet plausible storyline. It reminds me of John Schlesigner's "Billy Liar" - except that the protagonist in Bang! actually gets to play out her fantasies. One of my all time favorites. It's a movie about crooked cops, individual rights, L.A., latinos, asians, unfortunate circumstance, women's rights, etc. There's much to say but I don't want to give it away and I can't submit a review unless it's at least ten lines long so stop reading this already and go watch Bang!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting experiment.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gridoon
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/10/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bleak look at the life of the less-privileged in contemporary Los Angeles. Darling Narita is utterly believable as the unemployed, homeless actress who gets to be a "cop" for a day, and the dialogue, situations and general flow of the film have a definite ring of authenticity (you will never say to yourself "no, this couldn't happen"). The director's documentary-like technique draws you into the film; on the other hand, it doesn't give you too many insights into the characters. Ultimately, the film comes to a dead end - like its heroine, it has nowhere to go. (**1/2)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Waste of time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eko123
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2000
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The only memorable things about "Bang" is that it features a female Asian protagonist in a non-stereotypical role and its use of cinema verite techniques. That said, the movie meanders about without any sort of coherent plot or message. At times, I felt as if the filmmaker was making the story up as he was filming it. Essentially "Bang" is all flash and no substance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Original, ridiculous, quasi-authentic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dennis Littrell
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2000
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Note: Over 500 of my movie reviews are now available in my book "Cut to the Chaise Lounge or I Can't Believe I Swallowed the Remote!" Get it at Amazon.) This is an interesting movie with some superior shtick. It's outrageous of course, but there's a semi-plausibility to it throughout, once you accept the initial premise. Here it is: Asian kind of girl (Darling Narita) gets kicked out of her L.A. digs by a landlord thinking only of his mortgage payments. He just locks her out and tells her he is selling her stuff. But she has some hope: she has an audition with a Hollywood producer. His "office" is his home in the Hollywood hills. Before she goes in she befriends a schizophrenic street person. He hustles her for a dollar. Inside the house "producer" proves to be particularly slimy and we can see he is just scamming her for sex, and when she doesn't come across he verbally abuses her and throws her out. The schizo dude meets her and trashes the street a little just to pent and splits as a motorcycle cop drives up. She runs because it looks like she did the trashing and he chases her into the lush hills where he handcuffs her and gives her a choice: On your knees and do the deed, or you'll spend a night in jail. After assuming the position she manages to grab his gun and handcuffs him to a tree. She has had a bad morning. She freaks and makes him strip and takes his uni, dons it, and his motorcycle and goes on to play cop around town. She cruises some ghetto scenes and gets way into her act: she encounters pushers, dealers, killers, hookers, pimps, gangland lords and she gets engaged. Everybody thinks she's a cop, but she seems to forget herself sometimes. She hands out some money to some street people, runs out of gas and smokes some weed with a Latino hommie. By the way, the scene in the car with Juan and Jesus is just really excellent as it captures the barrio style. Then it gets a little rough. The cute cholo gets blasted in a drive by as his bro is filling her gas tank. She takes off after the perps and ends up shooting a dude. She spots this Asian hooker and tries to tell her she is doing wrong but gets kicked around by her and her pimp for her trouble. Strange how the film has turned a little. She walked more than a mile in the cop's shoes and suddenly we have identification with the enemy in a sense. The movie is now a kind of slapstick symbolic jaunt showing how being a cop in the modern urban scene corrupts absolutely. (I wonder how much of this was intended by Director and writer Ash.) She goes to the ocean to shake off what has happened to her. And then of course she returns to have her way with the lecherous producer and the wayward cop and further befriends the schizo dude. Ah, gee it's kind of sweet in a la la land sort of way. Best joke on the square: CIA = Cocaine Import Agency.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth watching..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (miadrake@earthlink.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2000
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ash definitely has talent.. a clever script.. you must watch to the end to fully appreciate his talent..of course there were limitations being a low budget movie.. i didn't particularly like the filming style, the hand held camera going back and forth to the different characters.. but the story, a struggling actress, kicked out of her apartment and thrown into a 'real' acting part by bad circumstances, is very interesting and thought provoking and scary. The lead actress is particularly good. like i said before.. don't give up.. see it all the way through.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An excellent indy film. Darling Narita is way cool.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (deverman@earthlink.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/1999
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film. Darling Narita's performance convinced me that what I was seeing was possible, however improbable. She carries the film, but there are several other fine performances here. An added bonus: Lucy Liu, currently appearing in TV's Ally McBeal, in a small but important role as a strung out hooker. Note: I rented this film from BlockBuster under the title "Bang" with a release date of 1997.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite good independent movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Landauer Marc (landauer.marc@teleweb.at)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/1999
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, you can&acute;t say really it&acute;s a B-Movie, more a good solid independent flick. Mainly the scenes are from the streets of L.A, the good and the bad parts. The main actor is this Asian-heritaged woman, who got the clothes from a police-officer and following that she cruised around with his bike, diving so to speak into L.A&acute;s street life, with its gang-shooting, relationships, homelessness etc. A bit sad but also it got humour in it. Quite recommended!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Something like an urban fairy-tale, complete with the ogres.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Taylor
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/1999
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ever seen a movie with an unbelievable opening plot device, yet the grim urban reality that it is set in allows you to buy it, in some strange way? Well, I think that describes 'Bang' pretty well. The idea of an actress assuming the role of a cop for a day is outlandish (and that stolen uniform fits pretty nicely). But it works if you let it. Don't expect reality in the plot, but you'll find it in the details of this one. A movie that makes you think about the assumption of identity, about who has power in society, and how that shifts depending on the circumstances.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pointless drivel that will only to appeal to fans of self-indulgent artsy flicks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    broken_and_beautiful
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not sure why this movie seems to have gotten such rave reviews. While watching "Bang" one night on TV, I found myself bored by the nonsensical, random plot which was occurring on screen. The entire movie seems to be nothing more than an exercise in meaningless, artsy-fartsy self-indulgence on the part of the filmmaker. The fact that the director/writer goes by a one name moniker only reinforces this sense of pretentiousness. Those interested in indie flicks would be better off looking for something better written and dare I say, more entertaining than this complete waste of time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a must watch film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael livesey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't agree with the other review i really enjoyed the film .Its a hard hitting drama that keeps you watching, a little twisted in places but i think it was intended to shock a very art-house sort of film .I watched it on an independent film channel in the UK late one night so maybe the alcohol helped watch out for the little sub plot running through the film strange anyway enjoy the film its a must see,the film starts slowly but soon gets going a bent policeman plays a nasty trick on the leading lady and is soon caught out resulting in the tables being turned on him. She then steals the policeman's motorbike and pretends to be a policeman then the story begins
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, empowering and inspiring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    couch_potato_with_cheese
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A down-and-out actress from L.A. gets evicted and arrested, then gets revenge on all those who wronged her. This film takes an improbable series of events and creates a bizarre yet plausible storyline. It reminds me of John Schlesigner's "Billy Liar" - except that the protagonist in Bang! actually gets to play out her fantasies. One of my all time favorites. It's a movie about crooked cops, individual rights, L.A., latinos, asians, unfortunate circumstance, women's rights, etc. There's much to say but I don't want to give it away and I can't submit a review unless it's at least ten lines long so stop reading this already and go watch Bang!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting experiment.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gridoon
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/10/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bleak look at the life of the less-privileged in contemporary Los Angeles. Darling Narita is utterly believable as the unemployed, homeless actress who gets to be a "cop" for a day, and the dialogue, situations and general flow of the film have a definite ring of authenticity (you will never say to yourself "no, this couldn't happen"). The director's documentary-like technique draws you into the film; on the other hand, it doesn't give you too many insights into the characters. Ultimately, the film comes to a dead end - like its heroine, it has nowhere to go. (**1/2)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Waste of time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eko123
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2000
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The only memorable things about "Bang" is that it features a female Asian protagonist in a non-stereotypical role and its use of cinema verite techniques. That said, the movie meanders about without any sort of coherent plot or message. At times, I felt as if the filmmaker was making the story up as he was filming it. Essentially "Bang" is all flash and no substance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Original, ridiculous, quasi-authentic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dennis Littrell
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2000
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Note: Over 500 of my movie reviews are now available in my book "Cut to the Chaise Lounge or I Can't Believe I Swallowed the Remote!" Get it at Amazon.) This is an interesting movie with some superior shtick. It's outrageous of course, but there's a semi-plausibility to it throughout, once you accept the initial premise. Here it is: Asian kind of girl (Darling Narita) gets kicked out of her L.A. digs by a landlord thinking only of his mortgage payments. He just locks her out and tells her he is selling her stuff. But she has some hope: she has an audition with a Hollywood producer. His "office" is his home in the Hollywood hills. Before she goes in she befriends a schizophrenic street person. He hustles her for a dollar. Inside the house "producer" proves to be particularly slimy and we can see he is just scamming her for sex, and when she doesn't come across he verbally abuses her and throws her out. The schizo dude meets her and trashes the street a little just to pent and splits as a motorcycle cop drives up. She runs because it looks like she did the trashing and he chases her into the lush hills where he handcuffs her and gives her a choice: On your knees and do the deed, or you'll spend a night in jail. After assuming the position she manages to grab his gun and handcuffs him to a tree. She has had a bad morning. She freaks and makes him strip and takes his uni, dons it, and his motorcycle and goes on to play cop around town. She cruises some ghetto scenes and gets way into her act: she encounters pushers, dealers, killers, hookers, pimps, gangland lords and she gets engaged. Everybody thinks she's a cop, but she seems to forget herself sometimes. She hands out some money to some street people, runs out of gas and smokes some weed with a Latino hommie. By the way, the scene in the car with Juan and Jesus is just really excellent as it captures the barrio style. Then it gets a little rough. The cute cholo gets blasted in a drive by as his bro is filling her gas tank. She takes off after the perps and ends up shooting a dude. She spots this Asian hooker and tries to tell her she is doing wrong but gets kicked around by her and her pimp for her trouble. Strange how the film has turned a little. She walked more than a mile in the cop's shoes and suddenly we have identification with the enemy in a sense. The movie is now a kind of slapstick symbolic jaunt showing how being a cop in the modern urban scene corrupts absolutely. (I wonder how much of this was intended by Director and writer Ash.) She goes to the ocean to shake off what has happened to her. And then of course she returns to have her way with the lecherous producer and the wayward cop and further befriends the schizo dude. Ah, gee it's kind of sweet in a la la land sort of way. Best joke on the square: CIA = Cocaine Import Agency.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth watching..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (miadrake@earthlink.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2000
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ash definitely has talent.. a clever script.. you must watch to the end to fully appreciate his talent..of course there were limitations being a low budget movie.. i didn't particularly like the filming style, the hand held camera going back and forth to the different characters.. but the story, a struggling actress, kicked out of her apartment and thrown into a 'real' acting part by bad circumstances, is very interesting and thought provoking and scary. The lead actress is particularly good. like i said before.. don't give up.. see it all the way through.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An excellent indy film. Darling Narita is way cool.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (deverman@earthlink.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/1999
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film. Darling Narita's performance convinced me that what I was seeing was possible, however improbable. She carries the film, but there are several other fine performances here. An added bonus: Lucy Liu, currently appearing in TV's Ally McBeal, in a small but important role as a strung out hooker. Note: I rented this film from BlockBuster under the title "Bang" with a release date of 1997.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite good independent movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Landauer Marc (landauer.marc@teleweb.at)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/1999
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, you can&acute;t say really it&acute;s a B-Movie, more a good solid independent flick. Mainly the scenes are from the streets of L.A, the good and the bad parts. The main actor is this Asian-heritaged woman, who got the clothes from a police-officer and following that she cruised around with his bike, diving so to speak into L.A&acute;s street life, with its gang-shooting, relationships, homelessness etc. A bit sad but also it got humour in it. Quite recommended!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Something like an urban fairy-tale, complete with the ogres.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Taylor
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/1999
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ever seen a movie with an unbelievable opening plot device, yet the grim urban reality that it is set in allows you to buy it, in some strange way? Well, I think that describes 'Bang' pretty well. The idea of an actress assuming the role of a cop for a day is outlandish (and that stolen uniform fits pretty nicely). But it works if you let it. Don't expect reality in the plot, but you'll find it in the details of this one. A movie that makes you think about the assumption of identity, about who has power in society, and how that shifts depending on the circumstances.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
