<filme>
 <id>
  1239
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112760
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Ilha da Garganta Cortada
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A female pirate and her companion race against their rivals to find a hidden island that contains a fabulous treasure.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Morgan Adams and her slave, William Shaw, are on a quest to recover the three portions of a treasure map. Unfortunately, the final portion is held by her murderous uncle, Dawg. Her crew is skeptical of her leadership abilities, so she must complete her quest before they mutiny against her. This is made yet more difficult by the efforts of the British crown to end her piratical raids.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   treasure
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   slave
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   pirate
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   pirate ship
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hook for hand
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Renny Harlin
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Michael Frost Beckner
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   James Gorman
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Geena Davis
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Matthew Modine
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Frank Langella
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ahoy Geena Davis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After the death of her father, swashbuckling Geena Davis (as Morgan Adams) inherits his pirate ship. More importantly, she acquires one-third of a treasure map. The map's location reveals the answer to the question, "Why did men in the 17th century wear thick, long-haired wigs." Of course, it's because they had treasure maps tattooed to their scalps. Probably, you did not know that. Baldness was also a problem back then, as the scalp map was written in Latin to discourage common spectators. Not well-versed in Latin, Ms. Davis must buy a slave to help translate the treasure map... Recently sentenced to slavery after stealing a woman's jewels, handsome blond-haired Matthew Modine (as William Shaw) is called into service. Not only does he read and speak Latin, he's also good at doctoring and kissing. A jack-of-all-trades slave, Mr. Modine quickly comes into possession of another third of the treasure map. The last third is kept by dastardly Frank Langella (as Douglas "Dawg" Brown). Davis and Modine must put the three pieces together, but Mr. Langella isn't cooperating. In fact, he would rather kill Davis and Modine, then keep all of the treasure for himself... "King Charles" (the monkey), Chris Masterson (as Bowen), Rex Linn (as Blair) and Stan Shaw (as Glasspoole) are supportive. Davis doesn't seem like a bad choice for the lead, even when you consider she was Mr. Harlin's wife. But her performance is far too indirect. Modine is appropriately less masculine. Even with its faults, this should have been a better picture for director Renny Harlin and his crew. Sure, it's crammed and cramped, but there is enough action to bring people into the theaters. While too blaring and bombastic, it might have been a hit in more pirate-friendly waters. ***** Cutthroat Island (12/22/95) Renny Harlin ~ Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, Frank Langella, Chris Masterson
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than other more popular pirate movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    basilisksamuk (sam.salt@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a mystery that will probably never be solved. Why did this film flop so badly whilst the Pirates of the Caribbean did so well? I don't even know anyone who has been able to stay awake right until the end of POTC part 3, a film so long that people have used up their entire annual leave watching it and still not got to the end. People who claim to have seen part 4 are clearly lying. Anyhow, Cutthroat Island delivers everything that you want to see in a swashbuckler and it does it in a sensible amount of time without filler and without a gazillion CGI shots. Geena Davis is very winning as the lead, the cinematography is excellent and the score is outstanding. Bears comparison with anything from the Golden Age of swashbuckling. Now this would have been a good basis for a franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    captain davis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i never that this movie had flopped in the theaters,, i was reading someone's comments and i was like wow it shouldn't have,, ig guess the times back then wasn't really ready for a swashbuckling female captain,, geena davis did do a decent job,, matthew modine was alright,, probably cud have used someone a little better to compliment geena. the premise wasn't bad,, makes you wander if pirates of the Caribbean took some of this and made it their own,, o well food for thought ,, overall this isn't a bad movie,, it has it's decent moment,, but it's not a great movie either, it's like right in the middle of the road so that's why i rated it a 5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Motorskallen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember this as one of my childhoods greatest action/adventure movies. Being a great fan of any good pirate story, I just had to re-watch it as an adult. What I found was a movie almost as good as I remember it. As an adult, I would of course smirk a bit at plot holes and some of the cheesy choreography (by which I mean such things as a bunch of Carolinians standing still in the middle of a battle, almost 'waiting' for the coming bomb to go of, or the 'good guys' appearing out of nowhere right behind the said Carolinians). But never mind that! Let's focus on the good things instead. It starts in the middle of a scene in which we are introduced to two of the main characters, the protagonist and the antagonist. The incident makes us understand that the protagonist (the pirate captain) is a well known pirate with a reputation, and the antagonist (a highly reputable politician) has got a taste for pirate flesh (on several levels, I might add). We quickly get into the story, and along the story goes on, we are introduced to more and more details about the persons and what has happened "before the movie". A plus is that it's not like thrown in your face at the end. Another mark on the good side is all the playing around with details typical for the pirate genre (by which I mean both books and movies, of course). But it never really gets clich&eacute;! Sometimes the movie is on the edge to get so, but never quite takes that final step over. We got a treasure island (Cutthroat Island), a bunch of hilarious/funny/goofy/kick ass pirates fighting each other and the 1600s government, some clever lines, a few bottles of rum and the Caribbean landscape. What else can you ask for in a pirate movie? The stunts, effects, acting and editing are never less than so-so, sometimes really good. Bare in mind that it was made almost twenty years ago, and the conditions as we have today wasn't really the same (which makes it easier for me to watch ... I know films from today that are far worse made). On the hole: if you would like to watch a good ol' pirate movie, with all the necessary ingredients, this is the one for you. I you are not a fan of pirate movies, but would like to change your mind, this is definitely the one for you!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Congratulations, madam. There's another town you've destroyed."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In its day, "Cutthroat Island" was the most entertaining pirate adventure that I was ever aware of. Coming from the director of "Cliffhanger," you just know that this film is going to have enough explosions to make Michael Bay jealous. Sure enough, the film is loaded with explosive action and hard-hitting sword fights. A lot of the action dominates the film's final act, which is pretty much an all-out extravaganza of wild swashbuckling, booming muskets, and ear-shattering cannon fire. The rest of the film is fairly light and adventurous; maybe not perfectly-paced, but not too boring either. It also tries its best to be hard-edged, but it never really feels like anything more than a mere PG-13 flick. In this day and age, the "Pirates of the Caribbean" series totally supplants this film in all areas. The story for "CI" is pretty straightforward, and dare I say standard fare. Pirates get a hold of a map, find some treasure, then duke it out. That's pretty much it. The film tries its best to make the plot roll up and down in a standard thrill-ride formula, stretching the thin story out to fill the runtime. Even though it entertains, it's not terribly deep or anything. The best that can be said is that the characters are likable (including the villain). The film looks nice, with some decent and stylish photography and editing. Acting is not too bad; I enjoyed Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, and Frank Langella in their roles. Writing is not terribly sophisticated, but it gets the job done. This production has sets, props, and costumes that look the part and fit in with the film's settings. Music is appropriately adventurous. Maybe not the best film in this genre, but it certainly entertains. It's worth a rental. 4/5 (Entertainment: Good | Story: Average | Film: Pretty Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hey, Real Stunts!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bermingham
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just as good as Pirates of the Caribbean and wonderful example of a movie that relied on practical FX and stunts. Before CGI locked its claws on Hollywood and turned film into highdef cartoons. Sure, most can complain about the hollowness of the script and some bad acting. COUGH: Matthew Modine. But, over all, if you like pirates, lost gold, remote islands real wooden ships, gigantic (and I mean GIGANTIC) explosions then this movie for you. In fact during a scene where people fall down a seaside cliff into an oncoming wave my 5 year old gasped out loud. Proof that despite our technical achievements in movie making, a solid stunt can still marvel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I was born poor, I had no choice but to become a thief and a liar.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cutthroat Island is directed by Renny Harlin and written by Robert King and Marc Norman. It stars Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, Frank Langella, Maury Chaykin, Patrick Malahide, Stan Shaw and Rex Linn. Music is scored by John Debney and cinematography by Peter Levy. A film of many flaws, with a reputation akin to it being the devil of big budget failures, it is, however, a wonderful piece of piratical entertainment if you are prepared to see past the monetary excess. Famously cited as the film that bankrupted Caroloco Pictures, the truth is that Carolco was going under anyway, the studio had filed for bankruptcy before Cutthroat Island had even been released, the box office performance was irrelevant, it wouldn't have made a bit of difference. And while no amount of hard sell marketing could have gotten the film to make back the $98 million spent making it, it received no support from distributor MGM who were in the process of being sold, so finances for marketing were not available. Harlin's movie has all the pirate movie ingredients crammed in to the plot, though it is a standard plot that sees Davis as female pirate Morgan Adams who leads her charges on a quest to find the ultimate treasure hoard. Problem is that the map is in three parts, each part held by separate people, one of which is Morgan's vicious Uncle Dawg (Langella). The hunt and race is on, and Harlin doesn't pause for breath, he's a kid in a sweet shop armed with wads of cash, but the money, as gargantuan as it is, is there on the screen; well except for the hiring of better actors that is. Two magnificent ships were built for the production and they are magnificent, the costumes, the sets, pyrotechnics, exotic locations (Malta and Thailand standing in for 1668 Jamaica), stunning sound editing and visual thrills, all high on value and all cloaked by a tremendously robust score from Debney. Action junkies are well served here, with wild horse drawn carriage chases, sword fights aplenty, ships in side by side explosive battle, mucho perilous situations, bodies falling from heights or thrown in the sea, and we even get a comic relief simian! Who, as it turns out, is one of the best actors on show. It's hard to believe that a pirate action film such as this would not be better appreciated had it been released in the last ten years, and I say that not just because of the success of the Pirates of the Caribbean franchise, but more so that the blunderbuss popcorn movie has greater support these days. There's a good portion of the movie loving faithful who just want to be entertained, where rapid thrills are a requisite, not well drawn characterisations and thespian class. Judged on those terms then Cutthroat Island is a winner for sure. Main problems are the clunky script and the three pronged miscast errors in the lead roles. Davis (erm, wife of Harlin) is full of guts, really attacking the material with gusto, but she never convinces, it always feels like a caricature and she's uncomfortable delivering key lines. She would prove herself a fine action actress a year later with The Long Kiss Goodnight (also with Harlin directing), but she's woefully out of place here. With Davis demanding more and more screen time for her character, the role of Shaw began to thin out, which was too much to bear for Michael Douglas who bowed out late in the day. In came Matthew Modine, zero chemistry with Davis, a bland acting style and as far removed from the period setting as you could get. Langella just isn't menacing as the main villain of the piece, a very good actor in the right role, but not here and some of his attempts at nastiness feel like panto season has started early. Problems for sure, but wade through some of the misconceptions and poisonous press and you will find a film desperately aiming to please you, with much on offer for the pirate movie fan to savour. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sorry, Ms D....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cutthroat Island is, as you might expect, a pirate movie. It is bright, colourful, action packed, with some excellent set pieces, some decent villains, good production values, some rather ubiquitous music (the stuff never stops, I mean never), and some miscasting in the main two parts. Matthew Modine is a decent actor, but he is fairly light on charisma. His part demands someone who can play a likable rogue while commanding the screen - Jeff Daniels might have worked in a part which would have suited the young Harrison Ford (it is very Han Solo-ish). The fact that the rather unimposing Modine was cast may be explained by the casting of the main character. The chief protagonist, the lady pirate, is played by Geena Davis. I don't much care for Geena Davis most of the time - she does nothing for me - although she was excellent in The Long Kiss Goodnight. Here, however, she does not suit the part, although she tries hard. Director Renny Harlin obviously thought she was right for the part, though - mind you, he would have had plenty of opportunity to audition her, what with being married to her at the time. This may explain why the male support was cast with an actor who does not overshadow her. With different leads, especially with some chemistry between them, this would have been a terrific film. As it is, it's OK.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best "modern Pirates" with both humor and action.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    allan-p3-896-87316
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Geena Davis is truly believable in this film. She makes me feel that this is almost a 'documentary'- even though I know, many things are "makebelive". Artistic freedom its called ;-) But I WANT to believe ! And the humor - even in the action scenes makes me believe. I does seem plausible :) Maybe you have to like her to like the film, I don't know. But after seeing her in the movie 'Long kiss goodnight', I don't understand that these films don't get a 10' from people. Maybe its because shes a female "hero" ? Shes occupying the "male scenario", and this never makes people "feel at home". But that its the charm of it. None of the people I recommended the film to, were disappointed. In my eyes its a GOOD film for anybody above 10 years. Both with laughter and suspense. An old pirate version of "Raiders of the Lost Ark". I still feel the same of the film even after seeing it more than 10 times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bomb at Sea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Justin Brill
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is truly deserving of all the scorn heaped upon it. Geena Davis reads her lines like she's playing a tobacco store Indian instead of a wacky 17th century lady-pirate, which is already a goofy thing to make a movie about. Matthew Modine? What is he doing in here? I almost feel terrible for the army of set and ship builders that must have worked on this picture for having done such a fantastic job making such a splendid looking cesspool. I mean that - the production values are really excellent, and all for naught. I'm not sure Renny Harlin isn't a complete moron, in fact, I'm fairly certain he is a drooling idiot. The movie has no heart. It races from bombastic set-piece to more bombastic set-piece, without developing the characters in plausible way, shape, or form. In one of the first scenes of the film, Geena Davis scalps her father. What??? Okay, so she scalps her father. Does this have any emotional impact on her? Not a chance. Her uncle kills her brother and spends the entire film trying to kill her. Does this affect her character's psyche in the slightest? Nope. Instead, she goes and bangs Matthew Modine. What a stupid movie. People who like this movie should be forced to have "I like Cutthroat Island" tattooed on their foreheads so they can be ridiculed more quickly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ahoy Geena Davis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After the death of her father, swashbuckling Geena Davis (as Morgan Adams) inherits his pirate ship. More importantly, she acquires one-third of a treasure map. The map's location reveals the answer to the question, "Why did men in the 17th century wear thick, long-haired wigs." Of course, it's because they had treasure maps tattooed to their scalps. Probably, you did not know that. Baldness was also a problem back then, as the scalp map was written in Latin to discourage common spectators. Not well-versed in Latin, Ms. Davis must buy a slave to help translate the treasure map... Recently sentenced to slavery after stealing a woman's jewels, handsome blond-haired Matthew Modine (as William Shaw) is called into service. Not only does he read and speak Latin, he's also good at doctoring and kissing. A jack-of-all-trades slave, Mr. Modine quickly comes into possession of another third of the treasure map. The last third is kept by dastardly Frank Langella (as Douglas "Dawg" Brown). Davis and Modine must put the three pieces together, but Mr. Langella isn't cooperating. In fact, he would rather kill Davis and Modine, then keep all of the treasure for himself... "King Charles" (the monkey), Chris Masterson (as Bowen), Rex Linn (as Blair) and Stan Shaw (as Glasspoole) are supportive. Davis doesn't seem like a bad choice for the lead, even when you consider she was Mr. Harlin's wife. But her performance is far too indirect. Modine is appropriately less masculine. Even with its faults, this should have been a better picture for director Renny Harlin and his crew. Sure, it's crammed and cramped, but there is enough action to bring people into the theaters. While too blaring and bombastic, it might have been a hit in more pirate-friendly waters. ***** Cutthroat Island (12/22/95) Renny Harlin ~ Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, Frank Langella, Chris Masterson
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than other more popular pirate movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    basilisksamuk (sam.salt@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a mystery that will probably never be solved. Why did this film flop so badly whilst the Pirates of the Caribbean did so well? I don't even know anyone who has been able to stay awake right until the end of POTC part 3, a film so long that people have used up their entire annual leave watching it and still not got to the end. People who claim to have seen part 4 are clearly lying. Anyhow, Cutthroat Island delivers everything that you want to see in a swashbuckler and it does it in a sensible amount of time without filler and without a gazillion CGI shots. Geena Davis is very winning as the lead, the cinematography is excellent and the score is outstanding. Bears comparison with anything from the Golden Age of swashbuckling. Now this would have been a good basis for a franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    captain davis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i never that this movie had flopped in the theaters,, i was reading someone's comments and i was like wow it shouldn't have,, ig guess the times back then wasn't really ready for a swashbuckling female captain,, geena davis did do a decent job,, matthew modine was alright,, probably cud have used someone a little better to compliment geena. the premise wasn't bad,, makes you wander if pirates of the Caribbean took some of this and made it their own,, o well food for thought ,, overall this isn't a bad movie,, it has it's decent moment,, but it's not a great movie either, it's like right in the middle of the road so that's why i rated it a 5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Motorskallen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember this as one of my childhoods greatest action/adventure movies. Being a great fan of any good pirate story, I just had to re-watch it as an adult. What I found was a movie almost as good as I remember it. As an adult, I would of course smirk a bit at plot holes and some of the cheesy choreography (by which I mean such things as a bunch of Carolinians standing still in the middle of a battle, almost 'waiting' for the coming bomb to go of, or the 'good guys' appearing out of nowhere right behind the said Carolinians). But never mind that! Let's focus on the good things instead. It starts in the middle of a scene in which we are introduced to two of the main characters, the protagonist and the antagonist. The incident makes us understand that the protagonist (the pirate captain) is a well known pirate with a reputation, and the antagonist (a highly reputable politician) has got a taste for pirate flesh (on several levels, I might add). We quickly get into the story, and along the story goes on, we are introduced to more and more details about the persons and what has happened "before the movie". A plus is that it's not like thrown in your face at the end. Another mark on the good side is all the playing around with details typical for the pirate genre (by which I mean both books and movies, of course). But it never really gets clich&eacute;! Sometimes the movie is on the edge to get so, but never quite takes that final step over. We got a treasure island (Cutthroat Island), a bunch of hilarious/funny/goofy/kick ass pirates fighting each other and the 1600s government, some clever lines, a few bottles of rum and the Caribbean landscape. What else can you ask for in a pirate movie? The stunts, effects, acting and editing are never less than so-so, sometimes really good. Bare in mind that it was made almost twenty years ago, and the conditions as we have today wasn't really the same (which makes it easier for me to watch ... I know films from today that are far worse made). On the hole: if you would like to watch a good ol' pirate movie, with all the necessary ingredients, this is the one for you. I you are not a fan of pirate movies, but would like to change your mind, this is definitely the one for you!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Congratulations, madam. There's another town you've destroyed."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In its day, "Cutthroat Island" was the most entertaining pirate adventure that I was ever aware of. Coming from the director of "Cliffhanger," you just know that this film is going to have enough explosions to make Michael Bay jealous. Sure enough, the film is loaded with explosive action and hard-hitting sword fights. A lot of the action dominates the film's final act, which is pretty much an all-out extravaganza of wild swashbuckling, booming muskets, and ear-shattering cannon fire. The rest of the film is fairly light and adventurous; maybe not perfectly-paced, but not too boring either. It also tries its best to be hard-edged, but it never really feels like anything more than a mere PG-13 flick. In this day and age, the "Pirates of the Caribbean" series totally supplants this film in all areas. The story for "CI" is pretty straightforward, and dare I say standard fare. Pirates get a hold of a map, find some treasure, then duke it out. That's pretty much it. The film tries its best to make the plot roll up and down in a standard thrill-ride formula, stretching the thin story out to fill the runtime. Even though it entertains, it's not terribly deep or anything. The best that can be said is that the characters are likable (including the villain). The film looks nice, with some decent and stylish photography and editing. Acting is not too bad; I enjoyed Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, and Frank Langella in their roles. Writing is not terribly sophisticated, but it gets the job done. This production has sets, props, and costumes that look the part and fit in with the film's settings. Music is appropriately adventurous. Maybe not the best film in this genre, but it certainly entertains. It's worth a rental. 4/5 (Entertainment: Good | Story: Average | Film: Pretty Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hey, Real Stunts!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bermingham
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just as good as Pirates of the Caribbean and wonderful example of a movie that relied on practical FX and stunts. Before CGI locked its claws on Hollywood and turned film into highdef cartoons. Sure, most can complain about the hollowness of the script and some bad acting. COUGH: Matthew Modine. But, over all, if you like pirates, lost gold, remote islands real wooden ships, gigantic (and I mean GIGANTIC) explosions then this movie for you. In fact during a scene where people fall down a seaside cliff into an oncoming wave my 5 year old gasped out loud. Proof that despite our technical achievements in movie making, a solid stunt can still marvel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I was born poor, I had no choice but to become a thief and a liar.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cutthroat Island is directed by Renny Harlin and written by Robert King and Marc Norman. It stars Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, Frank Langella, Maury Chaykin, Patrick Malahide, Stan Shaw and Rex Linn. Music is scored by John Debney and cinematography by Peter Levy. A film of many flaws, with a reputation akin to it being the devil of big budget failures, it is, however, a wonderful piece of piratical entertainment if you are prepared to see past the monetary excess. Famously cited as the film that bankrupted Caroloco Pictures, the truth is that Carolco was going under anyway, the studio had filed for bankruptcy before Cutthroat Island had even been released, the box office performance was irrelevant, it wouldn't have made a bit of difference. And while no amount of hard sell marketing could have gotten the film to make back the $98 million spent making it, it received no support from distributor MGM who were in the process of being sold, so finances for marketing were not available. Harlin's movie has all the pirate movie ingredients crammed in to the plot, though it is a standard plot that sees Davis as female pirate Morgan Adams who leads her charges on a quest to find the ultimate treasure hoard. Problem is that the map is in three parts, each part held by separate people, one of which is Morgan's vicious Uncle Dawg (Langella). The hunt and race is on, and Harlin doesn't pause for breath, he's a kid in a sweet shop armed with wads of cash, but the money, as gargantuan as it is, is there on the screen; well except for the hiring of better actors that is. Two magnificent ships were built for the production and they are magnificent, the costumes, the sets, pyrotechnics, exotic locations (Malta and Thailand standing in for 1668 Jamaica), stunning sound editing and visual thrills, all high on value and all cloaked by a tremendously robust score from Debney. Action junkies are well served here, with wild horse drawn carriage chases, sword fights aplenty, ships in side by side explosive battle, mucho perilous situations, bodies falling from heights or thrown in the sea, and we even get a comic relief simian! Who, as it turns out, is one of the best actors on show. It's hard to believe that a pirate action film such as this would not be better appreciated had it been released in the last ten years, and I say that not just because of the success of the Pirates of the Caribbean franchise, but more so that the blunderbuss popcorn movie has greater support these days. There's a good portion of the movie loving faithful who just want to be entertained, where rapid thrills are a requisite, not well drawn characterisations and thespian class. Judged on those terms then Cutthroat Island is a winner for sure. Main problems are the clunky script and the three pronged miscast errors in the lead roles. Davis (erm, wife of Harlin) is full of guts, really attacking the material with gusto, but she never convinces, it always feels like a caricature and she's uncomfortable delivering key lines. She would prove herself a fine action actress a year later with The Long Kiss Goodnight (also with Harlin directing), but she's woefully out of place here. With Davis demanding more and more screen time for her character, the role of Shaw began to thin out, which was too much to bear for Michael Douglas who bowed out late in the day. In came Matthew Modine, zero chemistry with Davis, a bland acting style and as far removed from the period setting as you could get. Langella just isn't menacing as the main villain of the piece, a very good actor in the right role, but not here and some of his attempts at nastiness feel like panto season has started early. Problems for sure, but wade through some of the misconceptions and poisonous press and you will find a film desperately aiming to please you, with much on offer for the pirate movie fan to savour. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sorry, Ms D....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cutthroat Island is, as you might expect, a pirate movie. It is bright, colourful, action packed, with some excellent set pieces, some decent villains, good production values, some rather ubiquitous music (the stuff never stops, I mean never), and some miscasting in the main two parts. Matthew Modine is a decent actor, but he is fairly light on charisma. His part demands someone who can play a likable rogue while commanding the screen - Jeff Daniels might have worked in a part which would have suited the young Harrison Ford (it is very Han Solo-ish). The fact that the rather unimposing Modine was cast may be explained by the casting of the main character. The chief protagonist, the lady pirate, is played by Geena Davis. I don't much care for Geena Davis most of the time - she does nothing for me - although she was excellent in The Long Kiss Goodnight. Here, however, she does not suit the part, although she tries hard. Director Renny Harlin obviously thought she was right for the part, though - mind you, he would have had plenty of opportunity to audition her, what with being married to her at the time. This may explain why the male support was cast with an actor who does not overshadow her. With different leads, especially with some chemistry between them, this would have been a terrific film. As it is, it's OK.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best "modern Pirates" with both humor and action.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    allan-p3-896-87316
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Geena Davis is truly believable in this film. She makes me feel that this is almost a 'documentary'- even though I know, many things are "makebelive". Artistic freedom its called ;-) But I WANT to believe ! And the humor - even in the action scenes makes me believe. I does seem plausible :) Maybe you have to like her to like the film, I don't know. But after seeing her in the movie 'Long kiss goodnight', I don't understand that these films don't get a 10' from people. Maybe its because shes a female "hero" ? Shes occupying the "male scenario", and this never makes people "feel at home". But that its the charm of it. None of the people I recommended the film to, were disappointed. In my eyes its a GOOD film for anybody above 10 years. Both with laughter and suspense. An old pirate version of "Raiders of the Lost Ark". I still feel the same of the film even after seeing it more than 10 times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bomb at Sea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Justin Brill
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is truly deserving of all the scorn heaped upon it. Geena Davis reads her lines like she's playing a tobacco store Indian instead of a wacky 17th century lady-pirate, which is already a goofy thing to make a movie about. Matthew Modine? What is he doing in here? I almost feel terrible for the army of set and ship builders that must have worked on this picture for having done such a fantastic job making such a splendid looking cesspool. I mean that - the production values are really excellent, and all for naught. I'm not sure Renny Harlin isn't a complete moron, in fact, I'm fairly certain he is a drooling idiot. The movie has no heart. It races from bombastic set-piece to more bombastic set-piece, without developing the characters in plausible way, shape, or form. In one of the first scenes of the film, Geena Davis scalps her father. What??? Okay, so she scalps her father. Does this have any emotional impact on her? Not a chance. Her uncle kills her brother and spends the entire film trying to kill her. Does this affect her character's psyche in the slightest? Nope. Instead, she goes and bangs Matthew Modine. What a stupid movie. People who like this movie should be forced to have "I like Cutthroat Island" tattooed on their foreheads so they can be ridiculed more quickly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ahoy Geena Davis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After the death of her father, swashbuckling Geena Davis (as Morgan Adams) inherits his pirate ship. More importantly, she acquires one-third of a treasure map. The map's location reveals the answer to the question, "Why did men in the 17th century wear thick, long-haired wigs." Of course, it's because they had treasure maps tattooed to their scalps. Probably, you did not know that. Baldness was also a problem back then, as the scalp map was written in Latin to discourage common spectators. Not well-versed in Latin, Ms. Davis must buy a slave to help translate the treasure map... Recently sentenced to slavery after stealing a woman's jewels, handsome blond-haired Matthew Modine (as William Shaw) is called into service. Not only does he read and speak Latin, he's also good at doctoring and kissing. A jack-of-all-trades slave, Mr. Modine quickly comes into possession of another third of the treasure map. The last third is kept by dastardly Frank Langella (as Douglas "Dawg" Brown). Davis and Modine must put the three pieces together, but Mr. Langella isn't cooperating. In fact, he would rather kill Davis and Modine, then keep all of the treasure for himself... "King Charles" (the monkey), Chris Masterson (as Bowen), Rex Linn (as Blair) and Stan Shaw (as Glasspoole) are supportive. Davis doesn't seem like a bad choice for the lead, even when you consider she was Mr. Harlin's wife. But her performance is far too indirect. Modine is appropriately less masculine. Even with its faults, this should have been a better picture for director Renny Harlin and his crew. Sure, it's crammed and cramped, but there is enough action to bring people into the theaters. While too blaring and bombastic, it might have been a hit in more pirate-friendly waters. ***** Cutthroat Island (12/22/95) Renny Harlin ~ Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, Frank Langella, Chris Masterson
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than other more popular pirate movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    basilisksamuk (sam.salt@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a mystery that will probably never be solved. Why did this film flop so badly whilst the Pirates of the Caribbean did so well? I don't even know anyone who has been able to stay awake right until the end of POTC part 3, a film so long that people have used up their entire annual leave watching it and still not got to the end. People who claim to have seen part 4 are clearly lying. Anyhow, Cutthroat Island delivers everything that you want to see in a swashbuckler and it does it in a sensible amount of time without filler and without a gazillion CGI shots. Geena Davis is very winning as the lead, the cinematography is excellent and the score is outstanding. Bears comparison with anything from the Golden Age of swashbuckling. Now this would have been a good basis for a franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    captain davis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i never that this movie had flopped in the theaters,, i was reading someone's comments and i was like wow it shouldn't have,, ig guess the times back then wasn't really ready for a swashbuckling female captain,, geena davis did do a decent job,, matthew modine was alright,, probably cud have used someone a little better to compliment geena. the premise wasn't bad,, makes you wander if pirates of the Caribbean took some of this and made it their own,, o well food for thought ,, overall this isn't a bad movie,, it has it's decent moment,, but it's not a great movie either, it's like right in the middle of the road so that's why i rated it a 5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Motorskallen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember this as one of my childhoods greatest action/adventure movies. Being a great fan of any good pirate story, I just had to re-watch it as an adult. What I found was a movie almost as good as I remember it. As an adult, I would of course smirk a bit at plot holes and some of the cheesy choreography (by which I mean such things as a bunch of Carolinians standing still in the middle of a battle, almost 'waiting' for the coming bomb to go of, or the 'good guys' appearing out of nowhere right behind the said Carolinians). But never mind that! Let's focus on the good things instead. It starts in the middle of a scene in which we are introduced to two of the main characters, the protagonist and the antagonist. The incident makes us understand that the protagonist (the pirate captain) is a well known pirate with a reputation, and the antagonist (a highly reputable politician) has got a taste for pirate flesh (on several levels, I might add). We quickly get into the story, and along the story goes on, we are introduced to more and more details about the persons and what has happened "before the movie". A plus is that it's not like thrown in your face at the end. Another mark on the good side is all the playing around with details typical for the pirate genre (by which I mean both books and movies, of course). But it never really gets clich&eacute;! Sometimes the movie is on the edge to get so, but never quite takes that final step over. We got a treasure island (Cutthroat Island), a bunch of hilarious/funny/goofy/kick ass pirates fighting each other and the 1600s government, some clever lines, a few bottles of rum and the Caribbean landscape. What else can you ask for in a pirate movie? The stunts, effects, acting and editing are never less than so-so, sometimes really good. Bare in mind that it was made almost twenty years ago, and the conditions as we have today wasn't really the same (which makes it easier for me to watch ... I know films from today that are far worse made). On the hole: if you would like to watch a good ol' pirate movie, with all the necessary ingredients, this is the one for you. I you are not a fan of pirate movies, but would like to change your mind, this is definitely the one for you!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Congratulations, madam. There's another town you've destroyed."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In its day, "Cutthroat Island" was the most entertaining pirate adventure that I was ever aware of. Coming from the director of "Cliffhanger," you just know that this film is going to have enough explosions to make Michael Bay jealous. Sure enough, the film is loaded with explosive action and hard-hitting sword fights. A lot of the action dominates the film's final act, which is pretty much an all-out extravaganza of wild swashbuckling, booming muskets, and ear-shattering cannon fire. The rest of the film is fairly light and adventurous; maybe not perfectly-paced, but not too boring either. It also tries its best to be hard-edged, but it never really feels like anything more than a mere PG-13 flick. In this day and age, the "Pirates of the Caribbean" series totally supplants this film in all areas. The story for "CI" is pretty straightforward, and dare I say standard fare. Pirates get a hold of a map, find some treasure, then duke it out. That's pretty much it. The film tries its best to make the plot roll up and down in a standard thrill-ride formula, stretching the thin story out to fill the runtime. Even though it entertains, it's not terribly deep or anything. The best that can be said is that the characters are likable (including the villain). The film looks nice, with some decent and stylish photography and editing. Acting is not too bad; I enjoyed Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, and Frank Langella in their roles. Writing is not terribly sophisticated, but it gets the job done. This production has sets, props, and costumes that look the part and fit in with the film's settings. Music is appropriately adventurous. Maybe not the best film in this genre, but it certainly entertains. It's worth a rental. 4/5 (Entertainment: Good | Story: Average | Film: Pretty Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hey, Real Stunts!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bermingham
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just as good as Pirates of the Caribbean and wonderful example of a movie that relied on practical FX and stunts. Before CGI locked its claws on Hollywood and turned film into highdef cartoons. Sure, most can complain about the hollowness of the script and some bad acting. COUGH: Matthew Modine. But, over all, if you like pirates, lost gold, remote islands real wooden ships, gigantic (and I mean GIGANTIC) explosions then this movie for you. In fact during a scene where people fall down a seaside cliff into an oncoming wave my 5 year old gasped out loud. Proof that despite our technical achievements in movie making, a solid stunt can still marvel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I was born poor, I had no choice but to become a thief and a liar.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cutthroat Island is directed by Renny Harlin and written by Robert King and Marc Norman. It stars Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, Frank Langella, Maury Chaykin, Patrick Malahide, Stan Shaw and Rex Linn. Music is scored by John Debney and cinematography by Peter Levy. A film of many flaws, with a reputation akin to it being the devil of big budget failures, it is, however, a wonderful piece of piratical entertainment if you are prepared to see past the monetary excess. Famously cited as the film that bankrupted Caroloco Pictures, the truth is that Carolco was going under anyway, the studio had filed for bankruptcy before Cutthroat Island had even been released, the box office performance was irrelevant, it wouldn't have made a bit of difference. And while no amount of hard sell marketing could have gotten the film to make back the $98 million spent making it, it received no support from distributor MGM who were in the process of being sold, so finances for marketing were not available. Harlin's movie has all the pirate movie ingredients crammed in to the plot, though it is a standard plot that sees Davis as female pirate Morgan Adams who leads her charges on a quest to find the ultimate treasure hoard. Problem is that the map is in three parts, each part held by separate people, one of which is Morgan's vicious Uncle Dawg (Langella). The hunt and race is on, and Harlin doesn't pause for breath, he's a kid in a sweet shop armed with wads of cash, but the money, as gargantuan as it is, is there on the screen; well except for the hiring of better actors that is. Two magnificent ships were built for the production and they are magnificent, the costumes, the sets, pyrotechnics, exotic locations (Malta and Thailand standing in for 1668 Jamaica), stunning sound editing and visual thrills, all high on value and all cloaked by a tremendously robust score from Debney. Action junkies are well served here, with wild horse drawn carriage chases, sword fights aplenty, ships in side by side explosive battle, mucho perilous situations, bodies falling from heights or thrown in the sea, and we even get a comic relief simian! Who, as it turns out, is one of the best actors on show. It's hard to believe that a pirate action film such as this would not be better appreciated had it been released in the last ten years, and I say that not just because of the success of the Pirates of the Caribbean franchise, but more so that the blunderbuss popcorn movie has greater support these days. There's a good portion of the movie loving faithful who just want to be entertained, where rapid thrills are a requisite, not well drawn characterisations and thespian class. Judged on those terms then Cutthroat Island is a winner for sure. Main problems are the clunky script and the three pronged miscast errors in the lead roles. Davis (erm, wife of Harlin) is full of guts, really attacking the material with gusto, but she never convinces, it always feels like a caricature and she's uncomfortable delivering key lines. She would prove herself a fine action actress a year later with The Long Kiss Goodnight (also with Harlin directing), but she's woefully out of place here. With Davis demanding more and more screen time for her character, the role of Shaw began to thin out, which was too much to bear for Michael Douglas who bowed out late in the day. In came Matthew Modine, zero chemistry with Davis, a bland acting style and as far removed from the period setting as you could get. Langella just isn't menacing as the main villain of the piece, a very good actor in the right role, but not here and some of his attempts at nastiness feel like panto season has started early. Problems for sure, but wade through some of the misconceptions and poisonous press and you will find a film desperately aiming to please you, with much on offer for the pirate movie fan to savour. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sorry, Ms D....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cutthroat Island is, as you might expect, a pirate movie. It is bright, colourful, action packed, with some excellent set pieces, some decent villains, good production values, some rather ubiquitous music (the stuff never stops, I mean never), and some miscasting in the main two parts. Matthew Modine is a decent actor, but he is fairly light on charisma. His part demands someone who can play a likable rogue while commanding the screen - Jeff Daniels might have worked in a part which would have suited the young Harrison Ford (it is very Han Solo-ish). The fact that the rather unimposing Modine was cast may be explained by the casting of the main character. The chief protagonist, the lady pirate, is played by Geena Davis. I don't much care for Geena Davis most of the time - she does nothing for me - although she was excellent in The Long Kiss Goodnight. Here, however, she does not suit the part, although she tries hard. Director Renny Harlin obviously thought she was right for the part, though - mind you, he would have had plenty of opportunity to audition her, what with being married to her at the time. This may explain why the male support was cast with an actor who does not overshadow her. With different leads, especially with some chemistry between them, this would have been a terrific film. As it is, it's OK.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best "modern Pirates" with both humor and action.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    allan-p3-896-87316
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Geena Davis is truly believable in this film. She makes me feel that this is almost a 'documentary'- even though I know, many things are "makebelive". Artistic freedom its called ;-) But I WANT to believe ! And the humor - even in the action scenes makes me believe. I does seem plausible :) Maybe you have to like her to like the film, I don't know. But after seeing her in the movie 'Long kiss goodnight', I don't understand that these films don't get a 10' from people. Maybe its because shes a female "hero" ? Shes occupying the "male scenario", and this never makes people "feel at home". But that its the charm of it. None of the people I recommended the film to, were disappointed. In my eyes its a GOOD film for anybody above 10 years. Both with laughter and suspense. An old pirate version of "Raiders of the Lost Ark". I still feel the same of the film even after seeing it more than 10 times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bomb at Sea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Justin Brill
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is truly deserving of all the scorn heaped upon it. Geena Davis reads her lines like she's playing a tobacco store Indian instead of a wacky 17th century lady-pirate, which is already a goofy thing to make a movie about. Matthew Modine? What is he doing in here? I almost feel terrible for the army of set and ship builders that must have worked on this picture for having done such a fantastic job making such a splendid looking cesspool. I mean that - the production values are really excellent, and all for naught. I'm not sure Renny Harlin isn't a complete moron, in fact, I'm fairly certain he is a drooling idiot. The movie has no heart. It races from bombastic set-piece to more bombastic set-piece, without developing the characters in plausible way, shape, or form. In one of the first scenes of the film, Geena Davis scalps her father. What??? Okay, so she scalps her father. Does this have any emotional impact on her? Not a chance. Her uncle kills her brother and spends the entire film trying to kill her. Does this affect her character's psyche in the slightest? Nope. Instead, she goes and bangs Matthew Modine. What a stupid movie. People who like this movie should be forced to have "I like Cutthroat Island" tattooed on their foreheads so they can be ridiculed more quickly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ahoy Geena Davis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After the death of her father, swashbuckling Geena Davis (as Morgan Adams) inherits his pirate ship. More importantly, she acquires one-third of a treasure map. The map's location reveals the answer to the question, "Why did men in the 17th century wear thick, long-haired wigs." Of course, it's because they had treasure maps tattooed to their scalps. Probably, you did not know that. Baldness was also a problem back then, as the scalp map was written in Latin to discourage common spectators. Not well-versed in Latin, Ms. Davis must buy a slave to help translate the treasure map... Recently sentenced to slavery after stealing a woman's jewels, handsome blond-haired Matthew Modine (as William Shaw) is called into service. Not only does he read and speak Latin, he's also good at doctoring and kissing. A jack-of-all-trades slave, Mr. Modine quickly comes into possession of another third of the treasure map. The last third is kept by dastardly Frank Langella (as Douglas "Dawg" Brown). Davis and Modine must put the three pieces together, but Mr. Langella isn't cooperating. In fact, he would rather kill Davis and Modine, then keep all of the treasure for himself... "King Charles" (the monkey), Chris Masterson (as Bowen), Rex Linn (as Blair) and Stan Shaw (as Glasspoole) are supportive. Davis doesn't seem like a bad choice for the lead, even when you consider she was Mr. Harlin's wife. But her performance is far too indirect. Modine is appropriately less masculine. Even with its faults, this should have been a better picture for director Renny Harlin and his crew. Sure, it's crammed and cramped, but there is enough action to bring people into the theaters. While too blaring and bombastic, it might have been a hit in more pirate-friendly waters. ***** Cutthroat Island (12/22/95) Renny Harlin ~ Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, Frank Langella, Chris Masterson
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than other more popular pirate movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    basilisksamuk (sam.salt@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a mystery that will probably never be solved. Why did this film flop so badly whilst the Pirates of the Caribbean did so well? I don't even know anyone who has been able to stay awake right until the end of POTC part 3, a film so long that people have used up their entire annual leave watching it and still not got to the end. People who claim to have seen part 4 are clearly lying. Anyhow, Cutthroat Island delivers everything that you want to see in a swashbuckler and it does it in a sensible amount of time without filler and without a gazillion CGI shots. Geena Davis is very winning as the lead, the cinematography is excellent and the score is outstanding. Bears comparison with anything from the Golden Age of swashbuckling. Now this would have been a good basis for a franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    captain davis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i never that this movie had flopped in the theaters,, i was reading someone's comments and i was like wow it shouldn't have,, ig guess the times back then wasn't really ready for a swashbuckling female captain,, geena davis did do a decent job,, matthew modine was alright,, probably cud have used someone a little better to compliment geena. the premise wasn't bad,, makes you wander if pirates of the Caribbean took some of this and made it their own,, o well food for thought ,, overall this isn't a bad movie,, it has it's decent moment,, but it's not a great movie either, it's like right in the middle of the road so that's why i rated it a 5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Motorskallen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember this as one of my childhoods greatest action/adventure movies. Being a great fan of any good pirate story, I just had to re-watch it as an adult. What I found was a movie almost as good as I remember it. As an adult, I would of course smirk a bit at plot holes and some of the cheesy choreography (by which I mean such things as a bunch of Carolinians standing still in the middle of a battle, almost 'waiting' for the coming bomb to go of, or the 'good guys' appearing out of nowhere right behind the said Carolinians). But never mind that! Let's focus on the good things instead. It starts in the middle of a scene in which we are introduced to two of the main characters, the protagonist and the antagonist. The incident makes us understand that the protagonist (the pirate captain) is a well known pirate with a reputation, and the antagonist (a highly reputable politician) has got a taste for pirate flesh (on several levels, I might add). We quickly get into the story, and along the story goes on, we are introduced to more and more details about the persons and what has happened "before the movie". A plus is that it's not like thrown in your face at the end. Another mark on the good side is all the playing around with details typical for the pirate genre (by which I mean both books and movies, of course). But it never really gets clich&eacute;! Sometimes the movie is on the edge to get so, but never quite takes that final step over. We got a treasure island (Cutthroat Island), a bunch of hilarious/funny/goofy/kick ass pirates fighting each other and the 1600s government, some clever lines, a few bottles of rum and the Caribbean landscape. What else can you ask for in a pirate movie? The stunts, effects, acting and editing are never less than so-so, sometimes really good. Bare in mind that it was made almost twenty years ago, and the conditions as we have today wasn't really the same (which makes it easier for me to watch ... I know films from today that are far worse made). On the hole: if you would like to watch a good ol' pirate movie, with all the necessary ingredients, this is the one for you. I you are not a fan of pirate movies, but would like to change your mind, this is definitely the one for you!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Congratulations, madam. There's another town you've destroyed."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In its day, "Cutthroat Island" was the most entertaining pirate adventure that I was ever aware of. Coming from the director of "Cliffhanger," you just know that this film is going to have enough explosions to make Michael Bay jealous. Sure enough, the film is loaded with explosive action and hard-hitting sword fights. A lot of the action dominates the film's final act, which is pretty much an all-out extravaganza of wild swashbuckling, booming muskets, and ear-shattering cannon fire. The rest of the film is fairly light and adventurous; maybe not perfectly-paced, but not too boring either. It also tries its best to be hard-edged, but it never really feels like anything more than a mere PG-13 flick. In this day and age, the "Pirates of the Caribbean" series totally supplants this film in all areas. The story for "CI" is pretty straightforward, and dare I say standard fare. Pirates get a hold of a map, find some treasure, then duke it out. That's pretty much it. The film tries its best to make the plot roll up and down in a standard thrill-ride formula, stretching the thin story out to fill the runtime. Even though it entertains, it's not terribly deep or anything. The best that can be said is that the characters are likable (including the villain). The film looks nice, with some decent and stylish photography and editing. Acting is not too bad; I enjoyed Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, and Frank Langella in their roles. Writing is not terribly sophisticated, but it gets the job done. This production has sets, props, and costumes that look the part and fit in with the film's settings. Music is appropriately adventurous. Maybe not the best film in this genre, but it certainly entertains. It's worth a rental. 4/5 (Entertainment: Good | Story: Average | Film: Pretty Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hey, Real Stunts!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bermingham
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just as good as Pirates of the Caribbean and wonderful example of a movie that relied on practical FX and stunts. Before CGI locked its claws on Hollywood and turned film into highdef cartoons. Sure, most can complain about the hollowness of the script and some bad acting. COUGH: Matthew Modine. But, over all, if you like pirates, lost gold, remote islands real wooden ships, gigantic (and I mean GIGANTIC) explosions then this movie for you. In fact during a scene where people fall down a seaside cliff into an oncoming wave my 5 year old gasped out loud. Proof that despite our technical achievements in movie making, a solid stunt can still marvel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I was born poor, I had no choice but to become a thief and a liar.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cutthroat Island is directed by Renny Harlin and written by Robert King and Marc Norman. It stars Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, Frank Langella, Maury Chaykin, Patrick Malahide, Stan Shaw and Rex Linn. Music is scored by John Debney and cinematography by Peter Levy. A film of many flaws, with a reputation akin to it being the devil of big budget failures, it is, however, a wonderful piece of piratical entertainment if you are prepared to see past the monetary excess. Famously cited as the film that bankrupted Caroloco Pictures, the truth is that Carolco was going under anyway, the studio had filed for bankruptcy before Cutthroat Island had even been released, the box office performance was irrelevant, it wouldn't have made a bit of difference. And while no amount of hard sell marketing could have gotten the film to make back the $98 million spent making it, it received no support from distributor MGM who were in the process of being sold, so finances for marketing were not available. Harlin's movie has all the pirate movie ingredients crammed in to the plot, though it is a standard plot that sees Davis as female pirate Morgan Adams who leads her charges on a quest to find the ultimate treasure hoard. Problem is that the map is in three parts, each part held by separate people, one of which is Morgan's vicious Uncle Dawg (Langella). The hunt and race is on, and Harlin doesn't pause for breath, he's a kid in a sweet shop armed with wads of cash, but the money, as gargantuan as it is, is there on the screen; well except for the hiring of better actors that is. Two magnificent ships were built for the production and they are magnificent, the costumes, the sets, pyrotechnics, exotic locations (Malta and Thailand standing in for 1668 Jamaica), stunning sound editing and visual thrills, all high on value and all cloaked by a tremendously robust score from Debney. Action junkies are well served here, with wild horse drawn carriage chases, sword fights aplenty, ships in side by side explosive battle, mucho perilous situations, bodies falling from heights or thrown in the sea, and we even get a comic relief simian! Who, as it turns out, is one of the best actors on show. It's hard to believe that a pirate action film such as this would not be better appreciated had it been released in the last ten years, and I say that not just because of the success of the Pirates of the Caribbean franchise, but more so that the blunderbuss popcorn movie has greater support these days. There's a good portion of the movie loving faithful who just want to be entertained, where rapid thrills are a requisite, not well drawn characterisations and thespian class. Judged on those terms then Cutthroat Island is a winner for sure. Main problems are the clunky script and the three pronged miscast errors in the lead roles. Davis (erm, wife of Harlin) is full of guts, really attacking the material with gusto, but she never convinces, it always feels like a caricature and she's uncomfortable delivering key lines. She would prove herself a fine action actress a year later with The Long Kiss Goodnight (also with Harlin directing), but she's woefully out of place here. With Davis demanding more and more screen time for her character, the role of Shaw began to thin out, which was too much to bear for Michael Douglas who bowed out late in the day. In came Matthew Modine, zero chemistry with Davis, a bland acting style and as far removed from the period setting as you could get. Langella just isn't menacing as the main villain of the piece, a very good actor in the right role, but not here and some of his attempts at nastiness feel like panto season has started early. Problems for sure, but wade through some of the misconceptions and poisonous press and you will find a film desperately aiming to please you, with much on offer for the pirate movie fan to savour. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sorry, Ms D....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cutthroat Island is, as you might expect, a pirate movie. It is bright, colourful, action packed, with some excellent set pieces, some decent villains, good production values, some rather ubiquitous music (the stuff never stops, I mean never), and some miscasting in the main two parts. Matthew Modine is a decent actor, but he is fairly light on charisma. His part demands someone who can play a likable rogue while commanding the screen - Jeff Daniels might have worked in a part which would have suited the young Harrison Ford (it is very Han Solo-ish). The fact that the rather unimposing Modine was cast may be explained by the casting of the main character. The chief protagonist, the lady pirate, is played by Geena Davis. I don't much care for Geena Davis most of the time - she does nothing for me - although she was excellent in The Long Kiss Goodnight. Here, however, she does not suit the part, although she tries hard. Director Renny Harlin obviously thought she was right for the part, though - mind you, he would have had plenty of opportunity to audition her, what with being married to her at the time. This may explain why the male support was cast with an actor who does not overshadow her. With different leads, especially with some chemistry between them, this would have been a terrific film. As it is, it's OK.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best "modern Pirates" with both humor and action.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    allan-p3-896-87316
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Geena Davis is truly believable in this film. She makes me feel that this is almost a 'documentary'- even though I know, many things are "makebelive". Artistic freedom its called ;-) But I WANT to believe ! And the humor - even in the action scenes makes me believe. I does seem plausible :) Maybe you have to like her to like the film, I don't know. But after seeing her in the movie 'Long kiss goodnight', I don't understand that these films don't get a 10' from people. Maybe its because shes a female "hero" ? Shes occupying the "male scenario", and this never makes people "feel at home". But that its the charm of it. None of the people I recommended the film to, were disappointed. In my eyes its a GOOD film for anybody above 10 years. Both with laughter and suspense. An old pirate version of "Raiders of the Lost Ark". I still feel the same of the film even after seeing it more than 10 times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bomb at Sea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Justin Brill
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is truly deserving of all the scorn heaped upon it. Geena Davis reads her lines like she's playing a tobacco store Indian instead of a wacky 17th century lady-pirate, which is already a goofy thing to make a movie about. Matthew Modine? What is he doing in here? I almost feel terrible for the army of set and ship builders that must have worked on this picture for having done such a fantastic job making such a splendid looking cesspool. I mean that - the production values are really excellent, and all for naught. I'm not sure Renny Harlin isn't a complete moron, in fact, I'm fairly certain he is a drooling idiot. The movie has no heart. It races from bombastic set-piece to more bombastic set-piece, without developing the characters in plausible way, shape, or form. In one of the first scenes of the film, Geena Davis scalps her father. What??? Okay, so she scalps her father. Does this have any emotional impact on her? Not a chance. Her uncle kills her brother and spends the entire film trying to kill her. Does this affect her character's psyche in the slightest? Nope. Instead, she goes and bangs Matthew Modine. What a stupid movie. People who like this movie should be forced to have "I like Cutthroat Island" tattooed on their foreheads so they can be ridiculed more quickly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ahoy Geena Davis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After the death of her father, swashbuckling Geena Davis (as Morgan Adams) inherits his pirate ship. More importantly, she acquires one-third of a treasure map. The map's location reveals the answer to the question, "Why did men in the 17th century wear thick, long-haired wigs." Of course, it's because they had treasure maps tattooed to their scalps. Probably, you did not know that. Baldness was also a problem back then, as the scalp map was written in Latin to discourage common spectators. Not well-versed in Latin, Ms. Davis must buy a slave to help translate the treasure map... Recently sentenced to slavery after stealing a woman's jewels, handsome blond-haired Matthew Modine (as William Shaw) is called into service. Not only does he read and speak Latin, he's also good at doctoring and kissing. A jack-of-all-trades slave, Mr. Modine quickly comes into possession of another third of the treasure map. The last third is kept by dastardly Frank Langella (as Douglas "Dawg" Brown). Davis and Modine must put the three pieces together, but Mr. Langella isn't cooperating. In fact, he would rather kill Davis and Modine, then keep all of the treasure for himself... "King Charles" (the monkey), Chris Masterson (as Bowen), Rex Linn (as Blair) and Stan Shaw (as Glasspoole) are supportive. Davis doesn't seem like a bad choice for the lead, even when you consider she was Mr. Harlin's wife. But her performance is far too indirect. Modine is appropriately less masculine. Even with its faults, this should have been a better picture for director Renny Harlin and his crew. Sure, it's crammed and cramped, but there is enough action to bring people into the theaters. While too blaring and bombastic, it might have been a hit in more pirate-friendly waters. ***** Cutthroat Island (12/22/95) Renny Harlin ~ Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, Frank Langella, Chris Masterson
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than other more popular pirate movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    basilisksamuk (sam.salt@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a mystery that will probably never be solved. Why did this film flop so badly whilst the Pirates of the Caribbean did so well? I don't even know anyone who has been able to stay awake right until the end of POTC part 3, a film so long that people have used up their entire annual leave watching it and still not got to the end. People who claim to have seen part 4 are clearly lying. Anyhow, Cutthroat Island delivers everything that you want to see in a swashbuckler and it does it in a sensible amount of time without filler and without a gazillion CGI shots. Geena Davis is very winning as the lead, the cinematography is excellent and the score is outstanding. Bears comparison with anything from the Golden Age of swashbuckling. Now this would have been a good basis for a franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    captain davis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i never that this movie had flopped in the theaters,, i was reading someone's comments and i was like wow it shouldn't have,, ig guess the times back then wasn't really ready for a swashbuckling female captain,, geena davis did do a decent job,, matthew modine was alright,, probably cud have used someone a little better to compliment geena. the premise wasn't bad,, makes you wander if pirates of the Caribbean took some of this and made it their own,, o well food for thought ,, overall this isn't a bad movie,, it has it's decent moment,, but it's not a great movie either, it's like right in the middle of the road so that's why i rated it a 5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Motorskallen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember this as one of my childhoods greatest action/adventure movies. Being a great fan of any good pirate story, I just had to re-watch it as an adult. What I found was a movie almost as good as I remember it. As an adult, I would of course smirk a bit at plot holes and some of the cheesy choreography (by which I mean such things as a bunch of Carolinians standing still in the middle of a battle, almost 'waiting' for the coming bomb to go of, or the 'good guys' appearing out of nowhere right behind the said Carolinians). But never mind that! Let's focus on the good things instead. It starts in the middle of a scene in which we are introduced to two of the main characters, the protagonist and the antagonist. The incident makes us understand that the protagonist (the pirate captain) is a well known pirate with a reputation, and the antagonist (a highly reputable politician) has got a taste for pirate flesh (on several levels, I might add). We quickly get into the story, and along the story goes on, we are introduced to more and more details about the persons and what has happened "before the movie". A plus is that it's not like thrown in your face at the end. Another mark on the good side is all the playing around with details typical for the pirate genre (by which I mean both books and movies, of course). But it never really gets clich&eacute;! Sometimes the movie is on the edge to get so, but never quite takes that final step over. We got a treasure island (Cutthroat Island), a bunch of hilarious/funny/goofy/kick ass pirates fighting each other and the 1600s government, some clever lines, a few bottles of rum and the Caribbean landscape. What else can you ask for in a pirate movie? The stunts, effects, acting and editing are never less than so-so, sometimes really good. Bare in mind that it was made almost twenty years ago, and the conditions as we have today wasn't really the same (which makes it easier for me to watch ... I know films from today that are far worse made). On the hole: if you would like to watch a good ol' pirate movie, with all the necessary ingredients, this is the one for you. I you are not a fan of pirate movies, but would like to change your mind, this is definitely the one for you!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Congratulations, madam. There's another town you've destroyed."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In its day, "Cutthroat Island" was the most entertaining pirate adventure that I was ever aware of. Coming from the director of "Cliffhanger," you just know that this film is going to have enough explosions to make Michael Bay jealous. Sure enough, the film is loaded with explosive action and hard-hitting sword fights. A lot of the action dominates the film's final act, which is pretty much an all-out extravaganza of wild swashbuckling, booming muskets, and ear-shattering cannon fire. The rest of the film is fairly light and adventurous; maybe not perfectly-paced, but not too boring either. It also tries its best to be hard-edged, but it never really feels like anything more than a mere PG-13 flick. In this day and age, the "Pirates of the Caribbean" series totally supplants this film in all areas. The story for "CI" is pretty straightforward, and dare I say standard fare. Pirates get a hold of a map, find some treasure, then duke it out. That's pretty much it. The film tries its best to make the plot roll up and down in a standard thrill-ride formula, stretching the thin story out to fill the runtime. Even though it entertains, it's not terribly deep or anything. The best that can be said is that the characters are likable (including the villain). The film looks nice, with some decent and stylish photography and editing. Acting is not too bad; I enjoyed Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, and Frank Langella in their roles. Writing is not terribly sophisticated, but it gets the job done. This production has sets, props, and costumes that look the part and fit in with the film's settings. Music is appropriately adventurous. Maybe not the best film in this genre, but it certainly entertains. It's worth a rental. 4/5 (Entertainment: Good | Story: Average | Film: Pretty Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hey, Real Stunts!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bermingham
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just as good as Pirates of the Caribbean and wonderful example of a movie that relied on practical FX and stunts. Before CGI locked its claws on Hollywood and turned film into highdef cartoons. Sure, most can complain about the hollowness of the script and some bad acting. COUGH: Matthew Modine. But, over all, if you like pirates, lost gold, remote islands real wooden ships, gigantic (and I mean GIGANTIC) explosions then this movie for you. In fact during a scene where people fall down a seaside cliff into an oncoming wave my 5 year old gasped out loud. Proof that despite our technical achievements in movie making, a solid stunt can still marvel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I was born poor, I had no choice but to become a thief and a liar.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cutthroat Island is directed by Renny Harlin and written by Robert King and Marc Norman. It stars Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, Frank Langella, Maury Chaykin, Patrick Malahide, Stan Shaw and Rex Linn. Music is scored by John Debney and cinematography by Peter Levy. A film of many flaws, with a reputation akin to it being the devil of big budget failures, it is, however, a wonderful piece of piratical entertainment if you are prepared to see past the monetary excess. Famously cited as the film that bankrupted Caroloco Pictures, the truth is that Carolco was going under anyway, the studio had filed for bankruptcy before Cutthroat Island had even been released, the box office performance was irrelevant, it wouldn't have made a bit of difference. And while no amount of hard sell marketing could have gotten the film to make back the $98 million spent making it, it received no support from distributor MGM who were in the process of being sold, so finances for marketing were not available. Harlin's movie has all the pirate movie ingredients crammed in to the plot, though it is a standard plot that sees Davis as female pirate Morgan Adams who leads her charges on a quest to find the ultimate treasure hoard. Problem is that the map is in three parts, each part held by separate people, one of which is Morgan's vicious Uncle Dawg (Langella). The hunt and race is on, and Harlin doesn't pause for breath, he's a kid in a sweet shop armed with wads of cash, but the money, as gargantuan as it is, is there on the screen; well except for the hiring of better actors that is. Two magnificent ships were built for the production and they are magnificent, the costumes, the sets, pyrotechnics, exotic locations (Malta and Thailand standing in for 1668 Jamaica), stunning sound editing and visual thrills, all high on value and all cloaked by a tremendously robust score from Debney. Action junkies are well served here, with wild horse drawn carriage chases, sword fights aplenty, ships in side by side explosive battle, mucho perilous situations, bodies falling from heights or thrown in the sea, and we even get a comic relief simian! Who, as it turns out, is one of the best actors on show. It's hard to believe that a pirate action film such as this would not be better appreciated had it been released in the last ten years, and I say that not just because of the success of the Pirates of the Caribbean franchise, but more so that the blunderbuss popcorn movie has greater support these days. There's a good portion of the movie loving faithful who just want to be entertained, where rapid thrills are a requisite, not well drawn characterisations and thespian class. Judged on those terms then Cutthroat Island is a winner for sure. Main problems are the clunky script and the three pronged miscast errors in the lead roles. Davis (erm, wife of Harlin) is full of guts, really attacking the material with gusto, but she never convinces, it always feels like a caricature and she's uncomfortable delivering key lines. She would prove herself a fine action actress a year later with The Long Kiss Goodnight (also with Harlin directing), but she's woefully out of place here. With Davis demanding more and more screen time for her character, the role of Shaw began to thin out, which was too much to bear for Michael Douglas who bowed out late in the day. In came Matthew Modine, zero chemistry with Davis, a bland acting style and as far removed from the period setting as you could get. Langella just isn't menacing as the main villain of the piece, a very good actor in the right role, but not here and some of his attempts at nastiness feel like panto season has started early. Problems for sure, but wade through some of the misconceptions and poisonous press and you will find a film desperately aiming to please you, with much on offer for the pirate movie fan to savour. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sorry, Ms D....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cutthroat Island is, as you might expect, a pirate movie. It is bright, colourful, action packed, with some excellent set pieces, some decent villains, good production values, some rather ubiquitous music (the stuff never stops, I mean never), and some miscasting in the main two parts. Matthew Modine is a decent actor, but he is fairly light on charisma. His part demands someone who can play a likable rogue while commanding the screen - Jeff Daniels might have worked in a part which would have suited the young Harrison Ford (it is very Han Solo-ish). The fact that the rather unimposing Modine was cast may be explained by the casting of the main character. The chief protagonist, the lady pirate, is played by Geena Davis. I don't much care for Geena Davis most of the time - she does nothing for me - although she was excellent in The Long Kiss Goodnight. Here, however, she does not suit the part, although she tries hard. Director Renny Harlin obviously thought she was right for the part, though - mind you, he would have had plenty of opportunity to audition her, what with being married to her at the time. This may explain why the male support was cast with an actor who does not overshadow her. With different leads, especially with some chemistry between them, this would have been a terrific film. As it is, it's OK.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best "modern Pirates" with both humor and action.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    allan-p3-896-87316
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Geena Davis is truly believable in this film. She makes me feel that this is almost a 'documentary'- even though I know, many things are "makebelive". Artistic freedom its called ;-) But I WANT to believe ! And the humor - even in the action scenes makes me believe. I does seem plausible :) Maybe you have to like her to like the film, I don't know. But after seeing her in the movie 'Long kiss goodnight', I don't understand that these films don't get a 10' from people. Maybe its because shes a female "hero" ? Shes occupying the "male scenario", and this never makes people "feel at home". But that its the charm of it. None of the people I recommended the film to, were disappointed. In my eyes its a GOOD film for anybody above 10 years. Both with laughter and suspense. An old pirate version of "Raiders of the Lost Ark". I still feel the same of the film even after seeing it more than 10 times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bomb at Sea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Justin Brill
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is truly deserving of all the scorn heaped upon it. Geena Davis reads her lines like she's playing a tobacco store Indian instead of a wacky 17th century lady-pirate, which is already a goofy thing to make a movie about. Matthew Modine? What is he doing in here? I almost feel terrible for the army of set and ship builders that must have worked on this picture for having done such a fantastic job making such a splendid looking cesspool. I mean that - the production values are really excellent, and all for naught. I'm not sure Renny Harlin isn't a complete moron, in fact, I'm fairly certain he is a drooling idiot. The movie has no heart. It races from bombastic set-piece to more bombastic set-piece, without developing the characters in plausible way, shape, or form. In one of the first scenes of the film, Geena Davis scalps her father. What??? Okay, so she scalps her father. Does this have any emotional impact on her? Not a chance. Her uncle kills her brother and spends the entire film trying to kill her. Does this affect her character's psyche in the slightest? Nope. Instead, she goes and bangs Matthew Modine. What a stupid movie. People who like this movie should be forced to have "I like Cutthroat Island" tattooed on their foreheads so they can be ridiculed more quickly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ahoy Geena Davis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After the death of her father, swashbuckling Geena Davis (as Morgan Adams) inherits his pirate ship. More importantly, she acquires one-third of a treasure map. The map's location reveals the answer to the question, "Why did men in the 17th century wear thick, long-haired wigs." Of course, it's because they had treasure maps tattooed to their scalps. Probably, you did not know that. Baldness was also a problem back then, as the scalp map was written in Latin to discourage common spectators. Not well-versed in Latin, Ms. Davis must buy a slave to help translate the treasure map... Recently sentenced to slavery after stealing a woman's jewels, handsome blond-haired Matthew Modine (as William Shaw) is called into service. Not only does he read and speak Latin, he's also good at doctoring and kissing. A jack-of-all-trades slave, Mr. Modine quickly comes into possession of another third of the treasure map. The last third is kept by dastardly Frank Langella (as Douglas "Dawg" Brown). Davis and Modine must put the three pieces together, but Mr. Langella isn't cooperating. In fact, he would rather kill Davis and Modine, then keep all of the treasure for himself... "King Charles" (the monkey), Chris Masterson (as Bowen), Rex Linn (as Blair) and Stan Shaw (as Glasspoole) are supportive. Davis doesn't seem like a bad choice for the lead, even when you consider she was Mr. Harlin's wife. But her performance is far too indirect. Modine is appropriately less masculine. Even with its faults, this should have been a better picture for director Renny Harlin and his crew. Sure, it's crammed and cramped, but there is enough action to bring people into the theaters. While too blaring and bombastic, it might have been a hit in more pirate-friendly waters. ***** Cutthroat Island (12/22/95) Renny Harlin ~ Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, Frank Langella, Chris Masterson
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than other more popular pirate movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    basilisksamuk (sam.salt@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a mystery that will probably never be solved. Why did this film flop so badly whilst the Pirates of the Caribbean did so well? I don't even know anyone who has been able to stay awake right until the end of POTC part 3, a film so long that people have used up their entire annual leave watching it and still not got to the end. People who claim to have seen part 4 are clearly lying. Anyhow, Cutthroat Island delivers everything that you want to see in a swashbuckler and it does it in a sensible amount of time without filler and without a gazillion CGI shots. Geena Davis is very winning as the lead, the cinematography is excellent and the score is outstanding. Bears comparison with anything from the Golden Age of swashbuckling. Now this would have been a good basis for a franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    captain davis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i never that this movie had flopped in the theaters,, i was reading someone's comments and i was like wow it shouldn't have,, ig guess the times back then wasn't really ready for a swashbuckling female captain,, geena davis did do a decent job,, matthew modine was alright,, probably cud have used someone a little better to compliment geena. the premise wasn't bad,, makes you wander if pirates of the Caribbean took some of this and made it their own,, o well food for thought ,, overall this isn't a bad movie,, it has it's decent moment,, but it's not a great movie either, it's like right in the middle of the road so that's why i rated it a 5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Motorskallen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember this as one of my childhoods greatest action/adventure movies. Being a great fan of any good pirate story, I just had to re-watch it as an adult. What I found was a movie almost as good as I remember it. As an adult, I would of course smirk a bit at plot holes and some of the cheesy choreography (by which I mean such things as a bunch of Carolinians standing still in the middle of a battle, almost 'waiting' for the coming bomb to go of, or the 'good guys' appearing out of nowhere right behind the said Carolinians). But never mind that! Let's focus on the good things instead. It starts in the middle of a scene in which we are introduced to two of the main characters, the protagonist and the antagonist. The incident makes us understand that the protagonist (the pirate captain) is a well known pirate with a reputation, and the antagonist (a highly reputable politician) has got a taste for pirate flesh (on several levels, I might add). We quickly get into the story, and along the story goes on, we are introduced to more and more details about the persons and what has happened "before the movie". A plus is that it's not like thrown in your face at the end. Another mark on the good side is all the playing around with details typical for the pirate genre (by which I mean both books and movies, of course). But it never really gets clich&eacute;! Sometimes the movie is on the edge to get so, but never quite takes that final step over. We got a treasure island (Cutthroat Island), a bunch of hilarious/funny/goofy/kick ass pirates fighting each other and the 1600s government, some clever lines, a few bottles of rum and the Caribbean landscape. What else can you ask for in a pirate movie? The stunts, effects, acting and editing are never less than so-so, sometimes really good. Bare in mind that it was made almost twenty years ago, and the conditions as we have today wasn't really the same (which makes it easier for me to watch ... I know films from today that are far worse made). On the hole: if you would like to watch a good ol' pirate movie, with all the necessary ingredients, this is the one for you. I you are not a fan of pirate movies, but would like to change your mind, this is definitely the one for you!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Congratulations, madam. There's another town you've destroyed."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In its day, "Cutthroat Island" was the most entertaining pirate adventure that I was ever aware of. Coming from the director of "Cliffhanger," you just know that this film is going to have enough explosions to make Michael Bay jealous. Sure enough, the film is loaded with explosive action and hard-hitting sword fights. A lot of the action dominates the film's final act, which is pretty much an all-out extravaganza of wild swashbuckling, booming muskets, and ear-shattering cannon fire. The rest of the film is fairly light and adventurous; maybe not perfectly-paced, but not too boring either. It also tries its best to be hard-edged, but it never really feels like anything more than a mere PG-13 flick. In this day and age, the "Pirates of the Caribbean" series totally supplants this film in all areas. The story for "CI" is pretty straightforward, and dare I say standard fare. Pirates get a hold of a map, find some treasure, then duke it out. That's pretty much it. The film tries its best to make the plot roll up and down in a standard thrill-ride formula, stretching the thin story out to fill the runtime. Even though it entertains, it's not terribly deep or anything. The best that can be said is that the characters are likable (including the villain). The film looks nice, with some decent and stylish photography and editing. Acting is not too bad; I enjoyed Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, and Frank Langella in their roles. Writing is not terribly sophisticated, but it gets the job done. This production has sets, props, and costumes that look the part and fit in with the film's settings. Music is appropriately adventurous. Maybe not the best film in this genre, but it certainly entertains. It's worth a rental. 4/5 (Entertainment: Good | Story: Average | Film: Pretty Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hey, Real Stunts!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bermingham
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just as good as Pirates of the Caribbean and wonderful example of a movie that relied on practical FX and stunts. Before CGI locked its claws on Hollywood and turned film into highdef cartoons. Sure, most can complain about the hollowness of the script and some bad acting. COUGH: Matthew Modine. But, over all, if you like pirates, lost gold, remote islands real wooden ships, gigantic (and I mean GIGANTIC) explosions then this movie for you. In fact during a scene where people fall down a seaside cliff into an oncoming wave my 5 year old gasped out loud. Proof that despite our technical achievements in movie making, a solid stunt can still marvel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I was born poor, I had no choice but to become a thief and a liar.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cutthroat Island is directed by Renny Harlin and written by Robert King and Marc Norman. It stars Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, Frank Langella, Maury Chaykin, Patrick Malahide, Stan Shaw and Rex Linn. Music is scored by John Debney and cinematography by Peter Levy. A film of many flaws, with a reputation akin to it being the devil of big budget failures, it is, however, a wonderful piece of piratical entertainment if you are prepared to see past the monetary excess. Famously cited as the film that bankrupted Caroloco Pictures, the truth is that Carolco was going under anyway, the studio had filed for bankruptcy before Cutthroat Island had even been released, the box office performance was irrelevant, it wouldn't have made a bit of difference. And while no amount of hard sell marketing could have gotten the film to make back the $98 million spent making it, it received no support from distributor MGM who were in the process of being sold, so finances for marketing were not available. Harlin's movie has all the pirate movie ingredients crammed in to the plot, though it is a standard plot that sees Davis as female pirate Morgan Adams who leads her charges on a quest to find the ultimate treasure hoard. Problem is that the map is in three parts, each part held by separate people, one of which is Morgan's vicious Uncle Dawg (Langella). The hunt and race is on, and Harlin doesn't pause for breath, he's a kid in a sweet shop armed with wads of cash, but the money, as gargantuan as it is, is there on the screen; well except for the hiring of better actors that is. Two magnificent ships were built for the production and they are magnificent, the costumes, the sets, pyrotechnics, exotic locations (Malta and Thailand standing in for 1668 Jamaica), stunning sound editing and visual thrills, all high on value and all cloaked by a tremendously robust score from Debney. Action junkies are well served here, with wild horse drawn carriage chases, sword fights aplenty, ships in side by side explosive battle, mucho perilous situations, bodies falling from heights or thrown in the sea, and we even get a comic relief simian! Who, as it turns out, is one of the best actors on show. It's hard to believe that a pirate action film such as this would not be better appreciated had it been released in the last ten years, and I say that not just because of the success of the Pirates of the Caribbean franchise, but more so that the blunderbuss popcorn movie has greater support these days. There's a good portion of the movie loving faithful who just want to be entertained, where rapid thrills are a requisite, not well drawn characterisations and thespian class. Judged on those terms then Cutthroat Island is a winner for sure. Main problems are the clunky script and the three pronged miscast errors in the lead roles. Davis (erm, wife of Harlin) is full of guts, really attacking the material with gusto, but she never convinces, it always feels like a caricature and she's uncomfortable delivering key lines. She would prove herself a fine action actress a year later with The Long Kiss Goodnight (also with Harlin directing), but she's woefully out of place here. With Davis demanding more and more screen time for her character, the role of Shaw began to thin out, which was too much to bear for Michael Douglas who bowed out late in the day. In came Matthew Modine, zero chemistry with Davis, a bland acting style and as far removed from the period setting as you could get. Langella just isn't menacing as the main villain of the piece, a very good actor in the right role, but not here and some of his attempts at nastiness feel like panto season has started early. Problems for sure, but wade through some of the misconceptions and poisonous press and you will find a film desperately aiming to please you, with much on offer for the pirate movie fan to savour. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sorry, Ms D....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cutthroat Island is, as you might expect, a pirate movie. It is bright, colourful, action packed, with some excellent set pieces, some decent villains, good production values, some rather ubiquitous music (the stuff never stops, I mean never), and some miscasting in the main two parts. Matthew Modine is a decent actor, but he is fairly light on charisma. His part demands someone who can play a likable rogue while commanding the screen - Jeff Daniels might have worked in a part which would have suited the young Harrison Ford (it is very Han Solo-ish). The fact that the rather unimposing Modine was cast may be explained by the casting of the main character. The chief protagonist, the lady pirate, is played by Geena Davis. I don't much care for Geena Davis most of the time - she does nothing for me - although she was excellent in The Long Kiss Goodnight. Here, however, she does not suit the part, although she tries hard. Director Renny Harlin obviously thought she was right for the part, though - mind you, he would have had plenty of opportunity to audition her, what with being married to her at the time. This may explain why the male support was cast with an actor who does not overshadow her. With different leads, especially with some chemistry between them, this would have been a terrific film. As it is, it's OK.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best "modern Pirates" with both humor and action.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    allan-p3-896-87316
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Geena Davis is truly believable in this film. She makes me feel that this is almost a 'documentary'- even though I know, many things are "makebelive". Artistic freedom its called ;-) But I WANT to believe ! And the humor - even in the action scenes makes me believe. I does seem plausible :) Maybe you have to like her to like the film, I don't know. But after seeing her in the movie 'Long kiss goodnight', I don't understand that these films don't get a 10' from people. Maybe its because shes a female "hero" ? Shes occupying the "male scenario", and this never makes people "feel at home". But that its the charm of it. None of the people I recommended the film to, were disappointed. In my eyes its a GOOD film for anybody above 10 years. Both with laughter and suspense. An old pirate version of "Raiders of the Lost Ark". I still feel the same of the film even after seeing it more than 10 times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bomb at Sea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Justin Brill
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is truly deserving of all the scorn heaped upon it. Geena Davis reads her lines like she's playing a tobacco store Indian instead of a wacky 17th century lady-pirate, which is already a goofy thing to make a movie about. Matthew Modine? What is he doing in here? I almost feel terrible for the army of set and ship builders that must have worked on this picture for having done such a fantastic job making such a splendid looking cesspool. I mean that - the production values are really excellent, and all for naught. I'm not sure Renny Harlin isn't a complete moron, in fact, I'm fairly certain he is a drooling idiot. The movie has no heart. It races from bombastic set-piece to more bombastic set-piece, without developing the characters in plausible way, shape, or form. In one of the first scenes of the film, Geena Davis scalps her father. What??? Okay, so she scalps her father. Does this have any emotional impact on her? Not a chance. Her uncle kills her brother and spends the entire film trying to kill her. Does this affect her character's psyche in the slightest? Nope. Instead, she goes and bangs Matthew Modine. What a stupid movie. People who like this movie should be forced to have "I like Cutthroat Island" tattooed on their foreheads so they can be ridiculed more quickly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ahoy Geena Davis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After the death of her father, swashbuckling Geena Davis (as Morgan Adams) inherits his pirate ship. More importantly, she acquires one-third of a treasure map. The map's location reveals the answer to the question, "Why did men in the 17th century wear thick, long-haired wigs." Of course, it's because they had treasure maps tattooed to their scalps. Probably, you did not know that. Baldness was also a problem back then, as the scalp map was written in Latin to discourage common spectators. Not well-versed in Latin, Ms. Davis must buy a slave to help translate the treasure map... Recently sentenced to slavery after stealing a woman's jewels, handsome blond-haired Matthew Modine (as William Shaw) is called into service. Not only does he read and speak Latin, he's also good at doctoring and kissing. A jack-of-all-trades slave, Mr. Modine quickly comes into possession of another third of the treasure map. The last third is kept by dastardly Frank Langella (as Douglas "Dawg" Brown). Davis and Modine must put the three pieces together, but Mr. Langella isn't cooperating. In fact, he would rather kill Davis and Modine, then keep all of the treasure for himself... "King Charles" (the monkey), Chris Masterson (as Bowen), Rex Linn (as Blair) and Stan Shaw (as Glasspoole) are supportive. Davis doesn't seem like a bad choice for the lead, even when you consider she was Mr. Harlin's wife. But her performance is far too indirect. Modine is appropriately less masculine. Even with its faults, this should have been a better picture for director Renny Harlin and his crew. Sure, it's crammed and cramped, but there is enough action to bring people into the theaters. While too blaring and bombastic, it might have been a hit in more pirate-friendly waters. ***** Cutthroat Island (12/22/95) Renny Harlin ~ Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, Frank Langella, Chris Masterson
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than other more popular pirate movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    basilisksamuk (sam.salt@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a mystery that will probably never be solved. Why did this film flop so badly whilst the Pirates of the Caribbean did so well? I don't even know anyone who has been able to stay awake right until the end of POTC part 3, a film so long that people have used up their entire annual leave watching it and still not got to the end. People who claim to have seen part 4 are clearly lying. Anyhow, Cutthroat Island delivers everything that you want to see in a swashbuckler and it does it in a sensible amount of time without filler and without a gazillion CGI shots. Geena Davis is very winning as the lead, the cinematography is excellent and the score is outstanding. Bears comparison with anything from the Golden Age of swashbuckling. Now this would have been a good basis for a franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    captain davis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i never that this movie had flopped in the theaters,, i was reading someone's comments and i was like wow it shouldn't have,, ig guess the times back then wasn't really ready for a swashbuckling female captain,, geena davis did do a decent job,, matthew modine was alright,, probably cud have used someone a little better to compliment geena. the premise wasn't bad,, makes you wander if pirates of the Caribbean took some of this and made it their own,, o well food for thought ,, overall this isn't a bad movie,, it has it's decent moment,, but it's not a great movie either, it's like right in the middle of the road so that's why i rated it a 5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Motorskallen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember this as one of my childhoods greatest action/adventure movies. Being a great fan of any good pirate story, I just had to re-watch it as an adult. What I found was a movie almost as good as I remember it. As an adult, I would of course smirk a bit at plot holes and some of the cheesy choreography (by which I mean such things as a bunch of Carolinians standing still in the middle of a battle, almost 'waiting' for the coming bomb to go of, or the 'good guys' appearing out of nowhere right behind the said Carolinians). But never mind that! Let's focus on the good things instead. It starts in the middle of a scene in which we are introduced to two of the main characters, the protagonist and the antagonist. The incident makes us understand that the protagonist (the pirate captain) is a well known pirate with a reputation, and the antagonist (a highly reputable politician) has got a taste for pirate flesh (on several levels, I might add). We quickly get into the story, and along the story goes on, we are introduced to more and more details about the persons and what has happened "before the movie". A plus is that it's not like thrown in your face at the end. Another mark on the good side is all the playing around with details typical for the pirate genre (by which I mean both books and movies, of course). But it never really gets clich&eacute;! Sometimes the movie is on the edge to get so, but never quite takes that final step over. We got a treasure island (Cutthroat Island), a bunch of hilarious/funny/goofy/kick ass pirates fighting each other and the 1600s government, some clever lines, a few bottles of rum and the Caribbean landscape. What else can you ask for in a pirate movie? The stunts, effects, acting and editing are never less than so-so, sometimes really good. Bare in mind that it was made almost twenty years ago, and the conditions as we have today wasn't really the same (which makes it easier for me to watch ... I know films from today that are far worse made). On the hole: if you would like to watch a good ol' pirate movie, with all the necessary ingredients, this is the one for you. I you are not a fan of pirate movies, but would like to change your mind, this is definitely the one for you!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Congratulations, madam. There's another town you've destroyed."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In its day, "Cutthroat Island" was the most entertaining pirate adventure that I was ever aware of. Coming from the director of "Cliffhanger," you just know that this film is going to have enough explosions to make Michael Bay jealous. Sure enough, the film is loaded with explosive action and hard-hitting sword fights. A lot of the action dominates the film's final act, which is pretty much an all-out extravaganza of wild swashbuckling, booming muskets, and ear-shattering cannon fire. The rest of the film is fairly light and adventurous; maybe not perfectly-paced, but not too boring either. It also tries its best to be hard-edged, but it never really feels like anything more than a mere PG-13 flick. In this day and age, the "Pirates of the Caribbean" series totally supplants this film in all areas. The story for "CI" is pretty straightforward, and dare I say standard fare. Pirates get a hold of a map, find some treasure, then duke it out. That's pretty much it. The film tries its best to make the plot roll up and down in a standard thrill-ride formula, stretching the thin story out to fill the runtime. Even though it entertains, it's not terribly deep or anything. The best that can be said is that the characters are likable (including the villain). The film looks nice, with some decent and stylish photography and editing. Acting is not too bad; I enjoyed Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, and Frank Langella in their roles. Writing is not terribly sophisticated, but it gets the job done. This production has sets, props, and costumes that look the part and fit in with the film's settings. Music is appropriately adventurous. Maybe not the best film in this genre, but it certainly entertains. It's worth a rental. 4/5 (Entertainment: Good | Story: Average | Film: Pretty Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hey, Real Stunts!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bermingham
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just as good as Pirates of the Caribbean and wonderful example of a movie that relied on practical FX and stunts. Before CGI locked its claws on Hollywood and turned film into highdef cartoons. Sure, most can complain about the hollowness of the script and some bad acting. COUGH: Matthew Modine. But, over all, if you like pirates, lost gold, remote islands real wooden ships, gigantic (and I mean GIGANTIC) explosions then this movie for you. In fact during a scene where people fall down a seaside cliff into an oncoming wave my 5 year old gasped out loud. Proof that despite our technical achievements in movie making, a solid stunt can still marvel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I was born poor, I had no choice but to become a thief and a liar.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cutthroat Island is directed by Renny Harlin and written by Robert King and Marc Norman. It stars Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, Frank Langella, Maury Chaykin, Patrick Malahide, Stan Shaw and Rex Linn. Music is scored by John Debney and cinematography by Peter Levy. A film of many flaws, with a reputation akin to it being the devil of big budget failures, it is, however, a wonderful piece of piratical entertainment if you are prepared to see past the monetary excess. Famously cited as the film that bankrupted Caroloco Pictures, the truth is that Carolco was going under anyway, the studio had filed for bankruptcy before Cutthroat Island had even been released, the box office performance was irrelevant, it wouldn't have made a bit of difference. And while no amount of hard sell marketing could have gotten the film to make back the $98 million spent making it, it received no support from distributor MGM who were in the process of being sold, so finances for marketing were not available. Harlin's movie has all the pirate movie ingredients crammed in to the plot, though it is a standard plot that sees Davis as female pirate Morgan Adams who leads her charges on a quest to find the ultimate treasure hoard. Problem is that the map is in three parts, each part held by separate people, one of which is Morgan's vicious Uncle Dawg (Langella). The hunt and race is on, and Harlin doesn't pause for breath, he's a kid in a sweet shop armed with wads of cash, but the money, as gargantuan as it is, is there on the screen; well except for the hiring of better actors that is. Two magnificent ships were built for the production and they are magnificent, the costumes, the sets, pyrotechnics, exotic locations (Malta and Thailand standing in for 1668 Jamaica), stunning sound editing and visual thrills, all high on value and all cloaked by a tremendously robust score from Debney. Action junkies are well served here, with wild horse drawn carriage chases, sword fights aplenty, ships in side by side explosive battle, mucho perilous situations, bodies falling from heights or thrown in the sea, and we even get a comic relief simian! Who, as it turns out, is one of the best actors on show. It's hard to believe that a pirate action film such as this would not be better appreciated had it been released in the last ten years, and I say that not just because of the success of the Pirates of the Caribbean franchise, but more so that the blunderbuss popcorn movie has greater support these days. There's a good portion of the movie loving faithful who just want to be entertained, where rapid thrills are a requisite, not well drawn characterisations and thespian class. Judged on those terms then Cutthroat Island is a winner for sure. Main problems are the clunky script and the three pronged miscast errors in the lead roles. Davis (erm, wife of Harlin) is full of guts, really attacking the material with gusto, but she never convinces, it always feels like a caricature and she's uncomfortable delivering key lines. She would prove herself a fine action actress a year later with The Long Kiss Goodnight (also with Harlin directing), but she's woefully out of place here. With Davis demanding more and more screen time for her character, the role of Shaw began to thin out, which was too much to bear for Michael Douglas who bowed out late in the day. In came Matthew Modine, zero chemistry with Davis, a bland acting style and as far removed from the period setting as you could get. Langella just isn't menacing as the main villain of the piece, a very good actor in the right role, but not here and some of his attempts at nastiness feel like panto season has started early. Problems for sure, but wade through some of the misconceptions and poisonous press and you will find a film desperately aiming to please you, with much on offer for the pirate movie fan to savour. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sorry, Ms D....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cutthroat Island is, as you might expect, a pirate movie. It is bright, colourful, action packed, with some excellent set pieces, some decent villains, good production values, some rather ubiquitous music (the stuff never stops, I mean never), and some miscasting in the main two parts. Matthew Modine is a decent actor, but he is fairly light on charisma. His part demands someone who can play a likable rogue while commanding the screen - Jeff Daniels might have worked in a part which would have suited the young Harrison Ford (it is very Han Solo-ish). The fact that the rather unimposing Modine was cast may be explained by the casting of the main character. The chief protagonist, the lady pirate, is played by Geena Davis. I don't much care for Geena Davis most of the time - she does nothing for me - although she was excellent in The Long Kiss Goodnight. Here, however, she does not suit the part, although she tries hard. Director Renny Harlin obviously thought she was right for the part, though - mind you, he would have had plenty of opportunity to audition her, what with being married to her at the time. This may explain why the male support was cast with an actor who does not overshadow her. With different leads, especially with some chemistry between them, this would have been a terrific film. As it is, it's OK.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best "modern Pirates" with both humor and action.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    allan-p3-896-87316
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Geena Davis is truly believable in this film. She makes me feel that this is almost a 'documentary'- even though I know, many things are "makebelive". Artistic freedom its called ;-) But I WANT to believe ! And the humor - even in the action scenes makes me believe. I does seem plausible :) Maybe you have to like her to like the film, I don't know. But after seeing her in the movie 'Long kiss goodnight', I don't understand that these films don't get a 10' from people. Maybe its because shes a female "hero" ? Shes occupying the "male scenario", and this never makes people "feel at home". But that its the charm of it. None of the people I recommended the film to, were disappointed. In my eyes its a GOOD film for anybody above 10 years. Both with laughter and suspense. An old pirate version of "Raiders of the Lost Ark". I still feel the same of the film even after seeing it more than 10 times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bomb at Sea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Justin Brill
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is truly deserving of all the scorn heaped upon it. Geena Davis reads her lines like she's playing a tobacco store Indian instead of a wacky 17th century lady-pirate, which is already a goofy thing to make a movie about. Matthew Modine? What is he doing in here? I almost feel terrible for the army of set and ship builders that must have worked on this picture for having done such a fantastic job making such a splendid looking cesspool. I mean that - the production values are really excellent, and all for naught. I'm not sure Renny Harlin isn't a complete moron, in fact, I'm fairly certain he is a drooling idiot. The movie has no heart. It races from bombastic set-piece to more bombastic set-piece, without developing the characters in plausible way, shape, or form. In one of the first scenes of the film, Geena Davis scalps her father. What??? Okay, so she scalps her father. Does this have any emotional impact on her? Not a chance. Her uncle kills her brother and spends the entire film trying to kill her. Does this affect her character's psyche in the slightest? Nope. Instead, she goes and bangs Matthew Modine. What a stupid movie. People who like this movie should be forced to have "I like Cutthroat Island" tattooed on their foreheads so they can be ridiculed more quickly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ahoy Geena Davis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After the death of her father, swashbuckling Geena Davis (as Morgan Adams) inherits his pirate ship. More importantly, she acquires one-third of a treasure map. The map's location reveals the answer to the question, "Why did men in the 17th century wear thick, long-haired wigs." Of course, it's because they had treasure maps tattooed to their scalps. Probably, you did not know that. Baldness was also a problem back then, as the scalp map was written in Latin to discourage common spectators. Not well-versed in Latin, Ms. Davis must buy a slave to help translate the treasure map... Recently sentenced to slavery after stealing a woman's jewels, handsome blond-haired Matthew Modine (as William Shaw) is called into service. Not only does he read and speak Latin, he's also good at doctoring and kissing. A jack-of-all-trades slave, Mr. Modine quickly comes into possession of another third of the treasure map. The last third is kept by dastardly Frank Langella (as Douglas "Dawg" Brown). Davis and Modine must put the three pieces together, but Mr. Langella isn't cooperating. In fact, he would rather kill Davis and Modine, then keep all of the treasure for himself... "King Charles" (the monkey), Chris Masterson (as Bowen), Rex Linn (as Blair) and Stan Shaw (as Glasspoole) are supportive. Davis doesn't seem like a bad choice for the lead, even when you consider she was Mr. Harlin's wife. But her performance is far too indirect. Modine is appropriately less masculine. Even with its faults, this should have been a better picture for director Renny Harlin and his crew. Sure, it's crammed and cramped, but there is enough action to bring people into the theaters. While too blaring and bombastic, it might have been a hit in more pirate-friendly waters. ***** Cutthroat Island (12/22/95) Renny Harlin ~ Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, Frank Langella, Chris Masterson
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than other more popular pirate movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    basilisksamuk (sam.salt@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a mystery that will probably never be solved. Why did this film flop so badly whilst the Pirates of the Caribbean did so well? I don't even know anyone who has been able to stay awake right until the end of POTC part 3, a film so long that people have used up their entire annual leave watching it and still not got to the end. People who claim to have seen part 4 are clearly lying. Anyhow, Cutthroat Island delivers everything that you want to see in a swashbuckler and it does it in a sensible amount of time without filler and without a gazillion CGI shots. Geena Davis is very winning as the lead, the cinematography is excellent and the score is outstanding. Bears comparison with anything from the Golden Age of swashbuckling. Now this would have been a good basis for a franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    captain davis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i never that this movie had flopped in the theaters,, i was reading someone's comments and i was like wow it shouldn't have,, ig guess the times back then wasn't really ready for a swashbuckling female captain,, geena davis did do a decent job,, matthew modine was alright,, probably cud have used someone a little better to compliment geena. the premise wasn't bad,, makes you wander if pirates of the Caribbean took some of this and made it their own,, o well food for thought ,, overall this isn't a bad movie,, it has it's decent moment,, but it's not a great movie either, it's like right in the middle of the road so that's why i rated it a 5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Motorskallen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember this as one of my childhoods greatest action/adventure movies. Being a great fan of any good pirate story, I just had to re-watch it as an adult. What I found was a movie almost as good as I remember it. As an adult, I would of course smirk a bit at plot holes and some of the cheesy choreography (by which I mean such things as a bunch of Carolinians standing still in the middle of a battle, almost 'waiting' for the coming bomb to go of, or the 'good guys' appearing out of nowhere right behind the said Carolinians). But never mind that! Let's focus on the good things instead. It starts in the middle of a scene in which we are introduced to two of the main characters, the protagonist and the antagonist. The incident makes us understand that the protagonist (the pirate captain) is a well known pirate with a reputation, and the antagonist (a highly reputable politician) has got a taste for pirate flesh (on several levels, I might add). We quickly get into the story, and along the story goes on, we are introduced to more and more details about the persons and what has happened "before the movie". A plus is that it's not like thrown in your face at the end. Another mark on the good side is all the playing around with details typical for the pirate genre (by which I mean both books and movies, of course). But it never really gets clich&eacute;! Sometimes the movie is on the edge to get so, but never quite takes that final step over. We got a treasure island (Cutthroat Island), a bunch of hilarious/funny/goofy/kick ass pirates fighting each other and the 1600s government, some clever lines, a few bottles of rum and the Caribbean landscape. What else can you ask for in a pirate movie? The stunts, effects, acting and editing are never less than so-so, sometimes really good. Bare in mind that it was made almost twenty years ago, and the conditions as we have today wasn't really the same (which makes it easier for me to watch ... I know films from today that are far worse made). On the hole: if you would like to watch a good ol' pirate movie, with all the necessary ingredients, this is the one for you. I you are not a fan of pirate movies, but would like to change your mind, this is definitely the one for you!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Congratulations, madam. There's another town you've destroyed."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In its day, "Cutthroat Island" was the most entertaining pirate adventure that I was ever aware of. Coming from the director of "Cliffhanger," you just know that this film is going to have enough explosions to make Michael Bay jealous. Sure enough, the film is loaded with explosive action and hard-hitting sword fights. A lot of the action dominates the film's final act, which is pretty much an all-out extravaganza of wild swashbuckling, booming muskets, and ear-shattering cannon fire. The rest of the film is fairly light and adventurous; maybe not perfectly-paced, but not too boring either. It also tries its best to be hard-edged, but it never really feels like anything more than a mere PG-13 flick. In this day and age, the "Pirates of the Caribbean" series totally supplants this film in all areas. The story for "CI" is pretty straightforward, and dare I say standard fare. Pirates get a hold of a map, find some treasure, then duke it out. That's pretty much it. The film tries its best to make the plot roll up and down in a standard thrill-ride formula, stretching the thin story out to fill the runtime. Even though it entertains, it's not terribly deep or anything. The best that can be said is that the characters are likable (including the villain). The film looks nice, with some decent and stylish photography and editing. Acting is not too bad; I enjoyed Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, and Frank Langella in their roles. Writing is not terribly sophisticated, but it gets the job done. This production has sets, props, and costumes that look the part and fit in with the film's settings. Music is appropriately adventurous. Maybe not the best film in this genre, but it certainly entertains. It's worth a rental. 4/5 (Entertainment: Good | Story: Average | Film: Pretty Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hey, Real Stunts!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bermingham
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just as good as Pirates of the Caribbean and wonderful example of a movie that relied on practical FX and stunts. Before CGI locked its claws on Hollywood and turned film into highdef cartoons. Sure, most can complain about the hollowness of the script and some bad acting. COUGH: Matthew Modine. But, over all, if you like pirates, lost gold, remote islands real wooden ships, gigantic (and I mean GIGANTIC) explosions then this movie for you. In fact during a scene where people fall down a seaside cliff into an oncoming wave my 5 year old gasped out loud. Proof that despite our technical achievements in movie making, a solid stunt can still marvel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I was born poor, I had no choice but to become a thief and a liar.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cutthroat Island is directed by Renny Harlin and written by Robert King and Marc Norman. It stars Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, Frank Langella, Maury Chaykin, Patrick Malahide, Stan Shaw and Rex Linn. Music is scored by John Debney and cinematography by Peter Levy. A film of many flaws, with a reputation akin to it being the devil of big budget failures, it is, however, a wonderful piece of piratical entertainment if you are prepared to see past the monetary excess. Famously cited as the film that bankrupted Caroloco Pictures, the truth is that Carolco was going under anyway, the studio had filed for bankruptcy before Cutthroat Island had even been released, the box office performance was irrelevant, it wouldn't have made a bit of difference. And while no amount of hard sell marketing could have gotten the film to make back the $98 million spent making it, it received no support from distributor MGM who were in the process of being sold, so finances for marketing were not available. Harlin's movie has all the pirate movie ingredients crammed in to the plot, though it is a standard plot that sees Davis as female pirate Morgan Adams who leads her charges on a quest to find the ultimate treasure hoard. Problem is that the map is in three parts, each part held by separate people, one of which is Morgan's vicious Uncle Dawg (Langella). The hunt and race is on, and Harlin doesn't pause for breath, he's a kid in a sweet shop armed with wads of cash, but the money, as gargantuan as it is, is there on the screen; well except for the hiring of better actors that is. Two magnificent ships were built for the production and they are magnificent, the costumes, the sets, pyrotechnics, exotic locations (Malta and Thailand standing in for 1668 Jamaica), stunning sound editing and visual thrills, all high on value and all cloaked by a tremendously robust score from Debney. Action junkies are well served here, with wild horse drawn carriage chases, sword fights aplenty, ships in side by side explosive battle, mucho perilous situations, bodies falling from heights or thrown in the sea, and we even get a comic relief simian! Who, as it turns out, is one of the best actors on show. It's hard to believe that a pirate action film such as this would not be better appreciated had it been released in the last ten years, and I say that not just because of the success of the Pirates of the Caribbean franchise, but more so that the blunderbuss popcorn movie has greater support these days. There's a good portion of the movie loving faithful who just want to be entertained, where rapid thrills are a requisite, not well drawn characterisations and thespian class. Judged on those terms then Cutthroat Island is a winner for sure. Main problems are the clunky script and the three pronged miscast errors in the lead roles. Davis (erm, wife of Harlin) is full of guts, really attacking the material with gusto, but she never convinces, it always feels like a caricature and she's uncomfortable delivering key lines. She would prove herself a fine action actress a year later with The Long Kiss Goodnight (also with Harlin directing), but she's woefully out of place here. With Davis demanding more and more screen time for her character, the role of Shaw began to thin out, which was too much to bear for Michael Douglas who bowed out late in the day. In came Matthew Modine, zero chemistry with Davis, a bland acting style and as far removed from the period setting as you could get. Langella just isn't menacing as the main villain of the piece, a very good actor in the right role, but not here and some of his attempts at nastiness feel like panto season has started early. Problems for sure, but wade through some of the misconceptions and poisonous press and you will find a film desperately aiming to please you, with much on offer for the pirate movie fan to savour. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sorry, Ms D....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cutthroat Island is, as you might expect, a pirate movie. It is bright, colourful, action packed, with some excellent set pieces, some decent villains, good production values, some rather ubiquitous music (the stuff never stops, I mean never), and some miscasting in the main two parts. Matthew Modine is a decent actor, but he is fairly light on charisma. His part demands someone who can play a likable rogue while commanding the screen - Jeff Daniels might have worked in a part which would have suited the young Harrison Ford (it is very Han Solo-ish). The fact that the rather unimposing Modine was cast may be explained by the casting of the main character. The chief protagonist, the lady pirate, is played by Geena Davis. I don't much care for Geena Davis most of the time - she does nothing for me - although she was excellent in The Long Kiss Goodnight. Here, however, she does not suit the part, although she tries hard. Director Renny Harlin obviously thought she was right for the part, though - mind you, he would have had plenty of opportunity to audition her, what with being married to her at the time. This may explain why the male support was cast with an actor who does not overshadow her. With different leads, especially with some chemistry between them, this would have been a terrific film. As it is, it's OK.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best "modern Pirates" with both humor and action.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    allan-p3-896-87316
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Geena Davis is truly believable in this film. She makes me feel that this is almost a 'documentary'- even though I know, many things are "makebelive". Artistic freedom its called ;-) But I WANT to believe ! And the humor - even in the action scenes makes me believe. I does seem plausible :) Maybe you have to like her to like the film, I don't know. But after seeing her in the movie 'Long kiss goodnight', I don't understand that these films don't get a 10' from people. Maybe its because shes a female "hero" ? Shes occupying the "male scenario", and this never makes people "feel at home". But that its the charm of it. None of the people I recommended the film to, were disappointed. In my eyes its a GOOD film for anybody above 10 years. Both with laughter and suspense. An old pirate version of "Raiders of the Lost Ark". I still feel the same of the film even after seeing it more than 10 times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bomb at Sea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Justin Brill
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is truly deserving of all the scorn heaped upon it. Geena Davis reads her lines like she's playing a tobacco store Indian instead of a wacky 17th century lady-pirate, which is already a goofy thing to make a movie about. Matthew Modine? What is he doing in here? I almost feel terrible for the army of set and ship builders that must have worked on this picture for having done such a fantastic job making such a splendid looking cesspool. I mean that - the production values are really excellent, and all for naught. I'm not sure Renny Harlin isn't a complete moron, in fact, I'm fairly certain he is a drooling idiot. The movie has no heart. It races from bombastic set-piece to more bombastic set-piece, without developing the characters in plausible way, shape, or form. In one of the first scenes of the film, Geena Davis scalps her father. What??? Okay, so she scalps her father. Does this have any emotional impact on her? Not a chance. Her uncle kills her brother and spends the entire film trying to kill her. Does this affect her character's psyche in the slightest? Nope. Instead, she goes and bangs Matthew Modine. What a stupid movie. People who like this movie should be forced to have "I like Cutthroat Island" tattooed on their foreheads so they can be ridiculed more quickly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ahoy Geena Davis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After the death of her father, swashbuckling Geena Davis (as Morgan Adams) inherits his pirate ship. More importantly, she acquires one-third of a treasure map. The map's location reveals the answer to the question, "Why did men in the 17th century wear thick, long-haired wigs." Of course, it's because they had treasure maps tattooed to their scalps. Probably, you did not know that. Baldness was also a problem back then, as the scalp map was written in Latin to discourage common spectators. Not well-versed in Latin, Ms. Davis must buy a slave to help translate the treasure map... Recently sentenced to slavery after stealing a woman's jewels, handsome blond-haired Matthew Modine (as William Shaw) is called into service. Not only does he read and speak Latin, he's also good at doctoring and kissing. A jack-of-all-trades slave, Mr. Modine quickly comes into possession of another third of the treasure map. The last third is kept by dastardly Frank Langella (as Douglas "Dawg" Brown). Davis and Modine must put the three pieces together, but Mr. Langella isn't cooperating. In fact, he would rather kill Davis and Modine, then keep all of the treasure for himself... "King Charles" (the monkey), Chris Masterson (as Bowen), Rex Linn (as Blair) and Stan Shaw (as Glasspoole) are supportive. Davis doesn't seem like a bad choice for the lead, even when you consider she was Mr. Harlin's wife. But her performance is far too indirect. Modine is appropriately less masculine. Even with its faults, this should have been a better picture for director Renny Harlin and his crew. Sure, it's crammed and cramped, but there is enough action to bring people into the theaters. While too blaring and bombastic, it might have been a hit in more pirate-friendly waters. ***** Cutthroat Island (12/22/95) Renny Harlin ~ Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, Frank Langella, Chris Masterson
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than other more popular pirate movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    basilisksamuk (sam.salt@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a mystery that will probably never be solved. Why did this film flop so badly whilst the Pirates of the Caribbean did so well? I don't even know anyone who has been able to stay awake right until the end of POTC part 3, a film so long that people have used up their entire annual leave watching it and still not got to the end. People who claim to have seen part 4 are clearly lying. Anyhow, Cutthroat Island delivers everything that you want to see in a swashbuckler and it does it in a sensible amount of time without filler and without a gazillion CGI shots. Geena Davis is very winning as the lead, the cinematography is excellent and the score is outstanding. Bears comparison with anything from the Golden Age of swashbuckling. Now this would have been a good basis for a franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    captain davis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i never that this movie had flopped in the theaters,, i was reading someone's comments and i was like wow it shouldn't have,, ig guess the times back then wasn't really ready for a swashbuckling female captain,, geena davis did do a decent job,, matthew modine was alright,, probably cud have used someone a little better to compliment geena. the premise wasn't bad,, makes you wander if pirates of the Caribbean took some of this and made it their own,, o well food for thought ,, overall this isn't a bad movie,, it has it's decent moment,, but it's not a great movie either, it's like right in the middle of the road so that's why i rated it a 5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Motorskallen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember this as one of my childhoods greatest action/adventure movies. Being a great fan of any good pirate story, I just had to re-watch it as an adult. What I found was a movie almost as good as I remember it. As an adult, I would of course smirk a bit at plot holes and some of the cheesy choreography (by which I mean such things as a bunch of Carolinians standing still in the middle of a battle, almost 'waiting' for the coming bomb to go of, or the 'good guys' appearing out of nowhere right behind the said Carolinians). But never mind that! Let's focus on the good things instead. It starts in the middle of a scene in which we are introduced to two of the main characters, the protagonist and the antagonist. The incident makes us understand that the protagonist (the pirate captain) is a well known pirate with a reputation, and the antagonist (a highly reputable politician) has got a taste for pirate flesh (on several levels, I might add). We quickly get into the story, and along the story goes on, we are introduced to more and more details about the persons and what has happened "before the movie". A plus is that it's not like thrown in your face at the end. Another mark on the good side is all the playing around with details typical for the pirate genre (by which I mean both books and movies, of course). But it never really gets clich&eacute;! Sometimes the movie is on the edge to get so, but never quite takes that final step over. We got a treasure island (Cutthroat Island), a bunch of hilarious/funny/goofy/kick ass pirates fighting each other and the 1600s government, some clever lines, a few bottles of rum and the Caribbean landscape. What else can you ask for in a pirate movie? The stunts, effects, acting and editing are never less than so-so, sometimes really good. Bare in mind that it was made almost twenty years ago, and the conditions as we have today wasn't really the same (which makes it easier for me to watch ... I know films from today that are far worse made). On the hole: if you would like to watch a good ol' pirate movie, with all the necessary ingredients, this is the one for you. I you are not a fan of pirate movies, but would like to change your mind, this is definitely the one for you!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Congratulations, madam. There's another town you've destroyed."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In its day, "Cutthroat Island" was the most entertaining pirate adventure that I was ever aware of. Coming from the director of "Cliffhanger," you just know that this film is going to have enough explosions to make Michael Bay jealous. Sure enough, the film is loaded with explosive action and hard-hitting sword fights. A lot of the action dominates the film's final act, which is pretty much an all-out extravaganza of wild swashbuckling, booming muskets, and ear-shattering cannon fire. The rest of the film is fairly light and adventurous; maybe not perfectly-paced, but not too boring either. It also tries its best to be hard-edged, but it never really feels like anything more than a mere PG-13 flick. In this day and age, the "Pirates of the Caribbean" series totally supplants this film in all areas. The story for "CI" is pretty straightforward, and dare I say standard fare. Pirates get a hold of a map, find some treasure, then duke it out. That's pretty much it. The film tries its best to make the plot roll up and down in a standard thrill-ride formula, stretching the thin story out to fill the runtime. Even though it entertains, it's not terribly deep or anything. The best that can be said is that the characters are likable (including the villain). The film looks nice, with some decent and stylish photography and editing. Acting is not too bad; I enjoyed Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, and Frank Langella in their roles. Writing is not terribly sophisticated, but it gets the job done. This production has sets, props, and costumes that look the part and fit in with the film's settings. Music is appropriately adventurous. Maybe not the best film in this genre, but it certainly entertains. It's worth a rental. 4/5 (Entertainment: Good | Story: Average | Film: Pretty Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hey, Real Stunts!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bermingham
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just as good as Pirates of the Caribbean and wonderful example of a movie that relied on practical FX and stunts. Before CGI locked its claws on Hollywood and turned film into highdef cartoons. Sure, most can complain about the hollowness of the script and some bad acting. COUGH: Matthew Modine. But, over all, if you like pirates, lost gold, remote islands real wooden ships, gigantic (and I mean GIGANTIC) explosions then this movie for you. In fact during a scene where people fall down a seaside cliff into an oncoming wave my 5 year old gasped out loud. Proof that despite our technical achievements in movie making, a solid stunt can still marvel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I was born poor, I had no choice but to become a thief and a liar.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cutthroat Island is directed by Renny Harlin and written by Robert King and Marc Norman. It stars Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, Frank Langella, Maury Chaykin, Patrick Malahide, Stan Shaw and Rex Linn. Music is scored by John Debney and cinematography by Peter Levy. A film of many flaws, with a reputation akin to it being the devil of big budget failures, it is, however, a wonderful piece of piratical entertainment if you are prepared to see past the monetary excess. Famously cited as the film that bankrupted Caroloco Pictures, the truth is that Carolco was going under anyway, the studio had filed for bankruptcy before Cutthroat Island had even been released, the box office performance was irrelevant, it wouldn't have made a bit of difference. And while no amount of hard sell marketing could have gotten the film to make back the $98 million spent making it, it received no support from distributor MGM who were in the process of being sold, so finances for marketing were not available. Harlin's movie has all the pirate movie ingredients crammed in to the plot, though it is a standard plot that sees Davis as female pirate Morgan Adams who leads her charges on a quest to find the ultimate treasure hoard. Problem is that the map is in three parts, each part held by separate people, one of which is Morgan's vicious Uncle Dawg (Langella). The hunt and race is on, and Harlin doesn't pause for breath, he's a kid in a sweet shop armed with wads of cash, but the money, as gargantuan as it is, is there on the screen; well except for the hiring of better actors that is. Two magnificent ships were built for the production and they are magnificent, the costumes, the sets, pyrotechnics, exotic locations (Malta and Thailand standing in for 1668 Jamaica), stunning sound editing and visual thrills, all high on value and all cloaked by a tremendously robust score from Debney. Action junkies are well served here, with wild horse drawn carriage chases, sword fights aplenty, ships in side by side explosive battle, mucho perilous situations, bodies falling from heights or thrown in the sea, and we even get a comic relief simian! Who, as it turns out, is one of the best actors on show. It's hard to believe that a pirate action film such as this would not be better appreciated had it been released in the last ten years, and I say that not just because of the success of the Pirates of the Caribbean franchise, but more so that the blunderbuss popcorn movie has greater support these days. There's a good portion of the movie loving faithful who just want to be entertained, where rapid thrills are a requisite, not well drawn characterisations and thespian class. Judged on those terms then Cutthroat Island is a winner for sure. Main problems are the clunky script and the three pronged miscast errors in the lead roles. Davis (erm, wife of Harlin) is full of guts, really attacking the material with gusto, but she never convinces, it always feels like a caricature and she's uncomfortable delivering key lines. She would prove herself a fine action actress a year later with The Long Kiss Goodnight (also with Harlin directing), but she's woefully out of place here. With Davis demanding more and more screen time for her character, the role of Shaw began to thin out, which was too much to bear for Michael Douglas who bowed out late in the day. In came Matthew Modine, zero chemistry with Davis, a bland acting style and as far removed from the period setting as you could get. Langella just isn't menacing as the main villain of the piece, a very good actor in the right role, but not here and some of his attempts at nastiness feel like panto season has started early. Problems for sure, but wade through some of the misconceptions and poisonous press and you will find a film desperately aiming to please you, with much on offer for the pirate movie fan to savour. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sorry, Ms D....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cutthroat Island is, as you might expect, a pirate movie. It is bright, colourful, action packed, with some excellent set pieces, some decent villains, good production values, some rather ubiquitous music (the stuff never stops, I mean never), and some miscasting in the main two parts. Matthew Modine is a decent actor, but he is fairly light on charisma. His part demands someone who can play a likable rogue while commanding the screen - Jeff Daniels might have worked in a part which would have suited the young Harrison Ford (it is very Han Solo-ish). The fact that the rather unimposing Modine was cast may be explained by the casting of the main character. The chief protagonist, the lady pirate, is played by Geena Davis. I don't much care for Geena Davis most of the time - she does nothing for me - although she was excellent in The Long Kiss Goodnight. Here, however, she does not suit the part, although she tries hard. Director Renny Harlin obviously thought she was right for the part, though - mind you, he would have had plenty of opportunity to audition her, what with being married to her at the time. This may explain why the male support was cast with an actor who does not overshadow her. With different leads, especially with some chemistry between them, this would have been a terrific film. As it is, it's OK.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best "modern Pirates" with both humor and action.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    allan-p3-896-87316
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Geena Davis is truly believable in this film. She makes me feel that this is almost a 'documentary'- even though I know, many things are "makebelive". Artistic freedom its called ;-) But I WANT to believe ! And the humor - even in the action scenes makes me believe. I does seem plausible :) Maybe you have to like her to like the film, I don't know. But after seeing her in the movie 'Long kiss goodnight', I don't understand that these films don't get a 10' from people. Maybe its because shes a female "hero" ? Shes occupying the "male scenario", and this never makes people "feel at home". But that its the charm of it. None of the people I recommended the film to, were disappointed. In my eyes its a GOOD film for anybody above 10 years. Both with laughter and suspense. An old pirate version of "Raiders of the Lost Ark". I still feel the same of the film even after seeing it more than 10 times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bomb at Sea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Justin Brill
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is truly deserving of all the scorn heaped upon it. Geena Davis reads her lines like she's playing a tobacco store Indian instead of a wacky 17th century lady-pirate, which is already a goofy thing to make a movie about. Matthew Modine? What is he doing in here? I almost feel terrible for the army of set and ship builders that must have worked on this picture for having done such a fantastic job making such a splendid looking cesspool. I mean that - the production values are really excellent, and all for naught. I'm not sure Renny Harlin isn't a complete moron, in fact, I'm fairly certain he is a drooling idiot. The movie has no heart. It races from bombastic set-piece to more bombastic set-piece, without developing the characters in plausible way, shape, or form. In one of the first scenes of the film, Geena Davis scalps her father. What??? Okay, so she scalps her father. Does this have any emotional impact on her? Not a chance. Her uncle kills her brother and spends the entire film trying to kill her. Does this affect her character's psyche in the slightest? Nope. Instead, she goes and bangs Matthew Modine. What a stupid movie. People who like this movie should be forced to have "I like Cutthroat Island" tattooed on their foreheads so they can be ridiculed more quickly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ahoy Geena Davis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After the death of her father, swashbuckling Geena Davis (as Morgan Adams) inherits his pirate ship. More importantly, she acquires one-third of a treasure map. The map's location reveals the answer to the question, "Why did men in the 17th century wear thick, long-haired wigs." Of course, it's because they had treasure maps tattooed to their scalps. Probably, you did not know that. Baldness was also a problem back then, as the scalp map was written in Latin to discourage common spectators. Not well-versed in Latin, Ms. Davis must buy a slave to help translate the treasure map... Recently sentenced to slavery after stealing a woman's jewels, handsome blond-haired Matthew Modine (as William Shaw) is called into service. Not only does he read and speak Latin, he's also good at doctoring and kissing. A jack-of-all-trades slave, Mr. Modine quickly comes into possession of another third of the treasure map. The last third is kept by dastardly Frank Langella (as Douglas "Dawg" Brown). Davis and Modine must put the three pieces together, but Mr. Langella isn't cooperating. In fact, he would rather kill Davis and Modine, then keep all of the treasure for himself... "King Charles" (the monkey), Chris Masterson (as Bowen), Rex Linn (as Blair) and Stan Shaw (as Glasspoole) are supportive. Davis doesn't seem like a bad choice for the lead, even when you consider she was Mr. Harlin's wife. But her performance is far too indirect. Modine is appropriately less masculine. Even with its faults, this should have been a better picture for director Renny Harlin and his crew. Sure, it's crammed and cramped, but there is enough action to bring people into the theaters. While too blaring and bombastic, it might have been a hit in more pirate-friendly waters. ***** Cutthroat Island (12/22/95) Renny Harlin ~ Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, Frank Langella, Chris Masterson
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than other more popular pirate movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    basilisksamuk (sam.salt@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a mystery that will probably never be solved. Why did this film flop so badly whilst the Pirates of the Caribbean did so well? I don't even know anyone who has been able to stay awake right until the end of POTC part 3, a film so long that people have used up their entire annual leave watching it and still not got to the end. People who claim to have seen part 4 are clearly lying. Anyhow, Cutthroat Island delivers everything that you want to see in a swashbuckler and it does it in a sensible amount of time without filler and without a gazillion CGI shots. Geena Davis is very winning as the lead, the cinematography is excellent and the score is outstanding. Bears comparison with anything from the Golden Age of swashbuckling. Now this would have been a good basis for a franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    captain davis
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i never that this movie had flopped in the theaters,, i was reading someone's comments and i was like wow it shouldn't have,, ig guess the times back then wasn't really ready for a swashbuckling female captain,, geena davis did do a decent job,, matthew modine was alright,, probably cud have used someone a little better to compliment geena. the premise wasn't bad,, makes you wander if pirates of the Caribbean took some of this and made it their own,, o well food for thought ,, overall this isn't a bad movie,, it has it's decent moment,, but it's not a great movie either, it's like right in the middle of the road so that's why i rated it a 5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Motorskallen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember this as one of my childhoods greatest action/adventure movies. Being a great fan of any good pirate story, I just had to re-watch it as an adult. What I found was a movie almost as good as I remember it. As an adult, I would of course smirk a bit at plot holes and some of the cheesy choreography (by which I mean such things as a bunch of Carolinians standing still in the middle of a battle, almost 'waiting' for the coming bomb to go of, or the 'good guys' appearing out of nowhere right behind the said Carolinians). But never mind that! Let's focus on the good things instead. It starts in the middle of a scene in which we are introduced to two of the main characters, the protagonist and the antagonist. The incident makes us understand that the protagonist (the pirate captain) is a well known pirate with a reputation, and the antagonist (a highly reputable politician) has got a taste for pirate flesh (on several levels, I might add). We quickly get into the story, and along the story goes on, we are introduced to more and more details about the persons and what has happened "before the movie". A plus is that it's not like thrown in your face at the end. Another mark on the good side is all the playing around with details typical for the pirate genre (by which I mean both books and movies, of course). But it never really gets clich&eacute;! Sometimes the movie is on the edge to get so, but never quite takes that final step over. We got a treasure island (Cutthroat Island), a bunch of hilarious/funny/goofy/kick ass pirates fighting each other and the 1600s government, some clever lines, a few bottles of rum and the Caribbean landscape. What else can you ask for in a pirate movie? The stunts, effects, acting and editing are never less than so-so, sometimes really good. Bare in mind that it was made almost twenty years ago, and the conditions as we have today wasn't really the same (which makes it easier for me to watch ... I know films from today that are far worse made). On the hole: if you would like to watch a good ol' pirate movie, with all the necessary ingredients, this is the one for you. I you are not a fan of pirate movies, but would like to change your mind, this is definitely the one for you!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Congratulations, madam. There's another town you've destroyed."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In its day, "Cutthroat Island" was the most entertaining pirate adventure that I was ever aware of. Coming from the director of "Cliffhanger," you just know that this film is going to have enough explosions to make Michael Bay jealous. Sure enough, the film is loaded with explosive action and hard-hitting sword fights. A lot of the action dominates the film's final act, which is pretty much an all-out extravaganza of wild swashbuckling, booming muskets, and ear-shattering cannon fire. The rest of the film is fairly light and adventurous; maybe not perfectly-paced, but not too boring either. It also tries its best to be hard-edged, but it never really feels like anything more than a mere PG-13 flick. In this day and age, the "Pirates of the Caribbean" series totally supplants this film in all areas. The story for "CI" is pretty straightforward, and dare I say standard fare. Pirates get a hold of a map, find some treasure, then duke it out. That's pretty much it. The film tries its best to make the plot roll up and down in a standard thrill-ride formula, stretching the thin story out to fill the runtime. Even though it entertains, it's not terribly deep or anything. The best that can be said is that the characters are likable (including the villain). The film looks nice, with some decent and stylish photography and editing. Acting is not too bad; I enjoyed Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, and Frank Langella in their roles. Writing is not terribly sophisticated, but it gets the job done. This production has sets, props, and costumes that look the part and fit in with the film's settings. Music is appropriately adventurous. Maybe not the best film in this genre, but it certainly entertains. It's worth a rental. 4/5 (Entertainment: Good | Story: Average | Film: Pretty Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hey, Real Stunts!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bermingham
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just as good as Pirates of the Caribbean and wonderful example of a movie that relied on practical FX and stunts. Before CGI locked its claws on Hollywood and turned film into highdef cartoons. Sure, most can complain about the hollowness of the script and some bad acting. COUGH: Matthew Modine. But, over all, if you like pirates, lost gold, remote islands real wooden ships, gigantic (and I mean GIGANTIC) explosions then this movie for you. In fact during a scene where people fall down a seaside cliff into an oncoming wave my 5 year old gasped out loud. Proof that despite our technical achievements in movie making, a solid stunt can still marvel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I was born poor, I had no choice but to become a thief and a liar.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cutthroat Island is directed by Renny Harlin and written by Robert King and Marc Norman. It stars Geena Davis, Matthew Modine, Frank Langella, Maury Chaykin, Patrick Malahide, Stan Shaw and Rex Linn. Music is scored by John Debney and cinematography by Peter Levy. A film of many flaws, with a reputation akin to it being the devil of big budget failures, it is, however, a wonderful piece of piratical entertainment if you are prepared to see past the monetary excess. Famously cited as the film that bankrupted Caroloco Pictures, the truth is that Carolco was going under anyway, the studio had filed for bankruptcy before Cutthroat Island had even been released, the box office performance was irrelevant, it wouldn't have made a bit of difference. And while no amount of hard sell marketing could have gotten the film to make back the $98 million spent making it, it received no support from distributor MGM who were in the process of being sold, so finances for marketing were not available. Harlin's movie has all the pirate movie ingredients crammed in to the plot, though it is a standard plot that sees Davis as female pirate Morgan Adams who leads her charges on a quest to find the ultimate treasure hoard. Problem is that the map is in three parts, each part held by separate people, one of which is Morgan's vicious Uncle Dawg (Langella). The hunt and race is on, and Harlin doesn't pause for breath, he's a kid in a sweet shop armed with wads of cash, but the money, as gargantuan as it is, is there on the screen; well except for the hiring of better actors that is. Two magnificent ships were built for the production and they are magnificent, the costumes, the sets, pyrotechnics, exotic locations (Malta and Thailand standing in for 1668 Jamaica), stunning sound editing and visual thrills, all high on value and all cloaked by a tremendously robust score from Debney. Action junkies are well served here, with wild horse drawn carriage chases, sword fights aplenty, ships in side by side explosive battle, mucho perilous situations, bodies falling from heights or thrown in the sea, and we even get a comic relief simian! Who, as it turns out, is one of the best actors on show. It's hard to believe that a pirate action film such as this would not be better appreciated had it been released in the last ten years, and I say that not just because of the success of the Pirates of the Caribbean franchise, but more so that the blunderbuss popcorn movie has greater support these days. There's a good portion of the movie loving faithful who just want to be entertained, where rapid thrills are a requisite, not well drawn characterisations and thespian class. Judged on those terms then Cutthroat Island is a winner for sure. Main problems are the clunky script and the three pronged miscast errors in the lead roles. Davis (erm, wife of Harlin) is full of guts, really attacking the material with gusto, but she never convinces, it always feels like a caricature and she's uncomfortable delivering key lines. She would prove herself a fine action actress a year later with The Long Kiss Goodnight (also with Harlin directing), but she's woefully out of place here. With Davis demanding more and more screen time for her character, the role of Shaw began to thin out, which was too much to bear for Michael Douglas who bowed out late in the day. In came Matthew Modine, zero chemistry with Davis, a bland acting style and as far removed from the period setting as you could get. Langella just isn't menacing as the main villain of the piece, a very good actor in the right role, but not here and some of his attempts at nastiness feel like panto season has started early. Problems for sure, but wade through some of the misconceptions and poisonous press and you will find a film desperately aiming to please you, with much on offer for the pirate movie fan to savour. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sorry, Ms D....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cutthroat Island is, as you might expect, a pirate movie. It is bright, colourful, action packed, with some excellent set pieces, some decent villains, good production values, some rather ubiquitous music (the stuff never stops, I mean never), and some miscasting in the main two parts. Matthew Modine is a decent actor, but he is fairly light on charisma. His part demands someone who can play a likable rogue while commanding the screen - Jeff Daniels might have worked in a part which would have suited the young Harrison Ford (it is very Han Solo-ish). The fact that the rather unimposing Modine was cast may be explained by the casting of the main character. The chief protagonist, the lady pirate, is played by Geena Davis. I don't much care for Geena Davis most of the time - she does nothing for me - although she was excellent in The Long Kiss Goodnight. Here, however, she does not suit the part, although she tries hard. Director Renny Harlin obviously thought she was right for the part, though - mind you, he would have had plenty of opportunity to audition her, what with being married to her at the time. This may explain why the male support was cast with an actor who does not overshadow her. With different leads, especially with some chemistry between them, this would have been a terrific film. As it is, it's OK.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best "modern Pirates" with both humor and action.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    allan-p3-896-87316
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Geena Davis is truly believable in this film. She makes me feel that this is almost a 'documentary'- even though I know, many things are "makebelive". Artistic freedom its called ;-) But I WANT to believe ! And the humor - even in the action scenes makes me believe. I does seem plausible :) Maybe you have to like her to like the film, I don't know. But after seeing her in the movie 'Long kiss goodnight', I don't understand that these films don't get a 10' from people. Maybe its because shes a female "hero" ? Shes occupying the "male scenario", and this never makes people "feel at home". But that its the charm of it. None of the people I recommended the film to, were disappointed. In my eyes its a GOOD film for anybody above 10 years. Both with laughter and suspense. An old pirate version of "Raiders of the Lost Ark". I still feel the same of the film even after seeing it more than 10 times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bomb at Sea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Justin Brill
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is truly deserving of all the scorn heaped upon it. Geena Davis reads her lines like she's playing a tobacco store Indian instead of a wacky 17th century lady-pirate, which is already a goofy thing to make a movie about. Matthew Modine? What is he doing in here? I almost feel terrible for the army of set and ship builders that must have worked on this picture for having done such a fantastic job making such a splendid looking cesspool. I mean that - the production values are really excellent, and all for naught. I'm not sure Renny Harlin isn't a complete moron, in fact, I'm fairly certain he is a drooling idiot. The movie has no heart. It races from bombastic set-piece to more bombastic set-piece, without developing the characters in plausible way, shape, or form. In one of the first scenes of the film, Geena Davis scalps her father. What??? Okay, so she scalps her father. Does this have any emotional impact on her? Not a chance. Her uncle kills her brother and spends the entire film trying to kill her. Does this affect her character's psyche in the slightest? Nope. Instead, she goes and bangs Matthew Modine. What a stupid movie. People who like this movie should be forced to have "I like Cutthroat Island" tattooed on their foreheads so they can be ridiculed more quickly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
