<filme>
 <id>
  124
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116905
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Lone Star - A Estrela Solit&aacute;ria
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  When the skeleton of his murdered predecessor is found, Sheriff Sam Deeds unearths many other long-buried secrets in his Texas border town.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  John Sayles' murder-mystery explores interpersonal and interracial tensions in Rio County, Texas. Sam Deeds is the local sheriff who is called to investigate a 40-year-old skeleton found in the desert....As Sam delves deeper into the town's dark secrets, he begins to learn more about his father, the legendary former sheriff Buddy Deeds, who replaced the corrupt Charlie Wade. While Sam puzzles out the long-past events surrounding the mystery corpse, he also longs to rekindle a romance with his old high-school flame. Sayles' complex characters are brought together as the tightly woven plot finally draws to its dramatic close.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Mystery
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   sheriff
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   texas
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   skeleton
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   desert
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   border
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   John Sayles
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   John Sayles
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Chris Cooper
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Elizabeth Pe&ntilde;a
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Stephen Mendillo
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forget the Alamo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paul2001sw-1 (paul2001sw@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this Texas detective story, a sheriff finds himself investigating the past of his own father, a man who was also his predecessor as sheriff, and a local hero everywhere except in his own household. The characters may be slow-moving and tight-lipped out of habit, but the ambiguity of their feelings is plain, and a strength of this drama, as is the way the plot weaves in many aspects of life in a border town. Perhaps some aspects of the way that town life is portrayed are a little too stylised, a little anachronistic, the reality of Mexican-American relations shown through the lens of the traditional western: but but film stays consistently within the world it has created. In terms of overall mood, there are elements that resemble the later 'No Country For Old Men', but without that movie's fall-back psychopath-driven plot, it offers a more interesting and ultimately humane vision of south Texas life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very noir...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anything I found this one a little too complex; there were several threads that seemed totally unrelated to the main thrust of the story. It's also, I felt, a little too long; the filmmakers are asking quite a lot for an audience to concentrate for two hours and fifteen minutes. It is slow paced, but I didn't particularly mind that; I'm used to the noir style and it is usually quite a slow burner. Some great performances with Chris Cooper coping well with the leading role and Kris Kristofferson playing the villain of the peace with gusto. Also we have Elizabeth Pe&ntilde;a, who did an excellent job as the female lead and a small part for Matthew McConaughey as Buddy Deeds. Although it does have its problems I still found it an excellent watch; definitely one to look out for for all you noir fans out there. SteelMonster's verdict: RECOMMENDED My score: 7.5/10. You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A hidden gem.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never thought I would see Matthew McConaughey playing Chris Cooper's farther! But yes, don't worry. It has to do with the simple fact that this movie keeps switching back and forth between present time and the past. With the use of flashback it slowly starts to become more apparent what happened 40-years before a skeleton got dug up, somewhere in the Texas desert. Lots of different story lines and characters end up getting intertwined but luckily the movie never becomes a messy or confusing one. It's actually a nice thing the movie has so many different characters in it, with each their own thing happening. It makes the movie, that otherwise probably would had been kind of slow, one that has always something happening in it and never becomes dull or a drag. You could actually say that the movie thrives on its characters. Everything that is happening and going on in this movie is due to them. They makes things interesting, as basically all of them need to come on terms with themselves and their past. This really ain't no ordinary murder mystery but more of a character-piece instead! And the movie of course has a great cast for that. The movie is well cast, especially when considering that most of the actors who appear in this movie weren't being big stars yet at the time. This for instance goes for Chris Cooper and Matthew McConaughey. All of the actors did a great job in this movie and were given plenty of opportunity to shine in this one. The movie at first truly feels like a Coen-brothers movie and it maintains this sort of feeling and style pretty much throughout the entire movie but it's being a bit more drama than comedy orientated. I actually do believe that if the Coen-brothers directed this movie it would had been a far better known was, as well as a better one I feel. The movie could had used some humor and entertainment in at times, since the right type of story and characters were definitely there for it. But oh well, the movie was going for a different approach and it still is for most part being successful with it as well. It simply great, little and simple movie to watch and there is also no good reason why you shouldn't! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inept plot, however well-meaning the story may be...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know I'm in the vast minority here, but I wasn't too impressed with this film. I think the problem was that too many of the subplots seemed incongruous, and frankly, uninteresting. I would have preferred it if the movie stuck to Chris Cooper's character. I was also expecting more Michael "Mchonohay", maybe if the film had been 1 half set in the present with the Sheriff and then the other half set in the past. Instead we get a bunch of stories about different people of the town that is meant to represent some sort of portrait of America, but they don't interlock the way 'Crash', 'Babel', 'Nashville', or other films do. It's a film trying to be ensemble when it doesn't need to. It probably would have worked better as a TV show, as too many of the loose threads lack that satisfying cohesiveness that a film should offer. The relationship between Sam and Pilar is also quite strange, and by the end, rather off-putting. In addition, the revelation about their past seems completely out of left field and of no relation to the central aspect of the story... or maybe it does in a weird sort of way. Either way, I feel that Sayles script is a little too 1990s PC for my tastes. Much of the moralizing between the characters (save for one brilliant scene outside a Mexican gas station) feels like something out of Schoolhouse Rock. Additionally, I thought the 'who-dunnit' murder plot was rather straightforward. Seeing Kristofferson's evil was entertaining, but I would have expected a bigger reveal or a more interesting resolution to his story. Maybe I was just let down by all the hype. I gave it a 6/10. I definitely would have felt as if I wasted my time if I'd paid money to see it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's not like there's a line between the good people and the bad people. It is not like you're one or the other.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lone Star is written and directed by John Sayles. It stars Chris Cooper, Joe Morton, Stephen J. Lang, Stephen Mendillo, Elizabeth Pe&ntilde;a and Kris Kristofferson. Music is scored by Mason Daring and cinematography by Stuart Dryburgh. The small Texas town of Rio County is rocked when a human skeleton is found in the sand and a Rio County Sheriff's badge found near by. The evidence points to it being the body of one time Sheriff Charlie Wade, a vile man who bullied the town for gratification and who one day just disappeared. Current Sheriff Sam Deeds begins investigating, knowing full well that there's a good chance the murderer could have be his own father, Buddy, who was known to have stood up to Wade with some hostile conviction. A hugely enjoyable pulpy mystery that's given a cunning make over by the talented Sayles. The who done it question at the film's core is merely one ingredient in this particular stew, this deals in themes such as violence, racism and family strife, the impact of lawmen on one small town, spread out across two generations. All the characters are interesting and well delineated, the dialogue as part of a non-linear narrative is precise and telling, while Sayles proves to be a stylistic craftsman by presenting two scenes 40 years apart within the same shot. A morality tale of some substance, with cast performances to match, it's a film sure to reward more with each viewing. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Stretch Of Road Runs Between Nowhere And Not Much Else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Deeds is the son of a late but much beloved Texas county sheriff who has inherited his father's job. But when a body is dug up from forty years ago and Sam investigates he discovers his father's illustrious past contains some dark and painful secrets ... This Texican murder mystery is one of Sayles' many beautifully constructed and densely populated character dramas (see also City Of Hope and Sunshine State) where, as with so much of his work, every single person is interesting, thoughtful and fully-rounded. This film is also a beautiful example of how to elegantly switch a narrative back and forward through two different eras, both visually through lovely little panning shots which dip in and out of time, and plot-wise as gradually the gauze covering the complex relationships is slowly lifted to reveal what has made the characters who they are. This is immensely satisfying as the pieces fit together, delicately played by a sensational ensemble cast who understand exactly what the story is trying to achieve. Cooper and Pe&ntilde;a are both superb as the middle-aged leads, both working county jobs, both struggling to find any meaning to their lives, both unable to move on from a fateful past together. The older actors steal the show with irascible wit, and pragmatism and regret written in equal measure on their faces - Canada in particular is outstanding - and Morton is terrific as ever in one of many parts for Sayles as the no-nonsense army man forced to embrace the tenderness he has long considered a weakness. Perhaps the casting masterstroke though is country legend Kristofferson as the thoroughly evil ghost from the past, whose violent brand of personal justice is horrifyingly plausible. Full of poignant moments, clever misdirection, evocative locations, heartfelt performances and funny lines (when Sam is headed to Mexico and tells a colleague he's going to "the other side", the response is "Republicans ?"), with a fine story and a great ending, this is high quality drama all the way. Shot in the beautiful south-western Texas border cities of Del Rio, Eagle Pass and Laredo.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris and Kris....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tim Kidner (tim@kidnerpix.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Cooper and Kris Kristofferson respectively, play two Mexican border sheriffs in John Sayle's excellent movie, but one is dead and the other is very much alive. This is a brooding, simmering and multi-layered drama of the highest order. The pacing is quite superb, unfolding like a great novel and keeps one quietly riveted for all of its two & a quarter hours. The characters are all so well rounded, their persona's so completely but subtly explored that one lives in and breathes every scene. Watching again on BBC2, after several year's gap, it still smacks of being totally relevant and up to date. Wrapped up within its celluloid binding is a tale of every family nuance, racial bigotry and human thought and emotion that a Chekov might. The soundtrack, too, is wonderfully eclectic and fitting. The plot is involved, but easy to follow, and never patronising in its assumptions. Other reviewers have explored it further than I'm going to and I'm simply reinforcing their voices and opinions and say that Lone Star is a must-see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just fantastic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elexigente48
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my top 20 movies of all time. After 3 viewings this feature just keeps getting better. This movie has a most unusual depth and diversity of characters and cultures that spans many generations (at times back into 19th century history), the only film I can think of that comes close is "Gone with the Wind." The crime scene investigation is only the outermost layer of the onion. It is a metaphor for one man's quest for Truth in a deeply flawed human world that strongly prefers myths. The movie is an exploration of the inexorable individual, generational, cultural, and racial baggage that haunts our mortal existence. It is about the human connections that transcend imagined and ever-changing boundaries. The school PTA meeting scene is not an irrelevant tangent. It is an encapsulation of this central underlying theme. When the white man dances with the Hispanic woman in a Mexican restaurant in Texas to an Ivory Joe Hunter rhythm and blues song sung in Spanish by Freddy Fender you should get the picture! This film is a rich tapestry that can fairly be called "Shakesperian." In classic form, the multiple layers of mythologies are slowly revealed to be solace from the boundless tragedy of human truths. This is a must see film about the threads of humanity that link (and separate) us all across many generations. Strongly recommended. Don't miss it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You are not alone, "Lone Star"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    setiaselalu-setiawan8
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a complex movie, for sure. And i like it because of that. I watch this movie twice. At my first watch, i thought the movie is an okay, i rated it 6/10. But, it made me think, how could a movie this good is an okay for me? So, I decided to watch it again last night. And, ..... wow!!! The acting, the cinematography, the screenplay(the best part from this movie, i guess), and score match together like it made by heaven. It has more than one messages, but don't worry . John Sayles(Director) invited us in a believable way. In my opinion, the twist is one of the best. Bravo!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too many characters, too much dialog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wlee08
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At the risk of sounding like the music critic in the movie Amadeus, who referred to Mozart's music as having "too many notes", I'm inclined to judge this movie as having too much of everything: US-Mexican relations, racism, in depth family histories, US military policies, mixed-race relationships, lost love, Freudian father relationships,...it just goes on and on and on. The dialog is also excessive, with a lot of it sounding like characters from the show "Law and Order". Although there were a few really good/powerful scenes, I felt many scenes were hard to follow along with - making the movie itself very convoluted. (Its been 15 years since its release and nobody has written an IMDb synopsis. Think about it.) I think a lot of the dialog went over my head for several reasons. For one, the sound quality seemed poor (but this could be my TV), the accents made it difficult too. And I might have just stopped caring about every single sentence. It seemed like every character in the movie was named "Buddy", which didn't help either. Anyways, I'm willing to accept partial responsibility for not watching this with 115% concentration. Maybe I'll watch it again someday.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forget the Alamo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paul2001sw-1 (paul2001sw@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this Texas detective story, a sheriff finds himself investigating the past of his own father, a man who was also his predecessor as sheriff, and a local hero everywhere except in his own household. The characters may be slow-moving and tight-lipped out of habit, but the ambiguity of their feelings is plain, and a strength of this drama, as is the way the plot weaves in many aspects of life in a border town. Perhaps some aspects of the way that town life is portrayed are a little too stylised, a little anachronistic, the reality of Mexican-American relations shown through the lens of the traditional western: but but film stays consistently within the world it has created. In terms of overall mood, there are elements that resemble the later 'No Country For Old Men', but without that movie's fall-back psychopath-driven plot, it offers a more interesting and ultimately humane vision of south Texas life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very noir...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anything I found this one a little too complex; there were several threads that seemed totally unrelated to the main thrust of the story. It's also, I felt, a little too long; the filmmakers are asking quite a lot for an audience to concentrate for two hours and fifteen minutes. It is slow paced, but I didn't particularly mind that; I'm used to the noir style and it is usually quite a slow burner. Some great performances with Chris Cooper coping well with the leading role and Kris Kristofferson playing the villain of the peace with gusto. Also we have Elizabeth Pe&ntilde;a, who did an excellent job as the female lead and a small part for Matthew McConaughey as Buddy Deeds. Although it does have its problems I still found it an excellent watch; definitely one to look out for for all you noir fans out there. SteelMonster's verdict: RECOMMENDED My score: 7.5/10. You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A hidden gem.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never thought I would see Matthew McConaughey playing Chris Cooper's farther! But yes, don't worry. It has to do with the simple fact that this movie keeps switching back and forth between present time and the past. With the use of flashback it slowly starts to become more apparent what happened 40-years before a skeleton got dug up, somewhere in the Texas desert. Lots of different story lines and characters end up getting intertwined but luckily the movie never becomes a messy or confusing one. It's actually a nice thing the movie has so many different characters in it, with each their own thing happening. It makes the movie, that otherwise probably would had been kind of slow, one that has always something happening in it and never becomes dull or a drag. You could actually say that the movie thrives on its characters. Everything that is happening and going on in this movie is due to them. They makes things interesting, as basically all of them need to come on terms with themselves and their past. This really ain't no ordinary murder mystery but more of a character-piece instead! And the movie of course has a great cast for that. The movie is well cast, especially when considering that most of the actors who appear in this movie weren't being big stars yet at the time. This for instance goes for Chris Cooper and Matthew McConaughey. All of the actors did a great job in this movie and were given plenty of opportunity to shine in this one. The movie at first truly feels like a Coen-brothers movie and it maintains this sort of feeling and style pretty much throughout the entire movie but it's being a bit more drama than comedy orientated. I actually do believe that if the Coen-brothers directed this movie it would had been a far better known was, as well as a better one I feel. The movie could had used some humor and entertainment in at times, since the right type of story and characters were definitely there for it. But oh well, the movie was going for a different approach and it still is for most part being successful with it as well. It simply great, little and simple movie to watch and there is also no good reason why you shouldn't! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inept plot, however well-meaning the story may be...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know I'm in the vast minority here, but I wasn't too impressed with this film. I think the problem was that too many of the subplots seemed incongruous, and frankly, uninteresting. I would have preferred it if the movie stuck to Chris Cooper's character. I was also expecting more Michael "Mchonohay", maybe if the film had been 1 half set in the present with the Sheriff and then the other half set in the past. Instead we get a bunch of stories about different people of the town that is meant to represent some sort of portrait of America, but they don't interlock the way 'Crash', 'Babel', 'Nashville', or other films do. It's a film trying to be ensemble when it doesn't need to. It probably would have worked better as a TV show, as too many of the loose threads lack that satisfying cohesiveness that a film should offer. The relationship between Sam and Pilar is also quite strange, and by the end, rather off-putting. In addition, the revelation about their past seems completely out of left field and of no relation to the central aspect of the story... or maybe it does in a weird sort of way. Either way, I feel that Sayles script is a little too 1990s PC for my tastes. Much of the moralizing between the characters (save for one brilliant scene outside a Mexican gas station) feels like something out of Schoolhouse Rock. Additionally, I thought the 'who-dunnit' murder plot was rather straightforward. Seeing Kristofferson's evil was entertaining, but I would have expected a bigger reveal or a more interesting resolution to his story. Maybe I was just let down by all the hype. I gave it a 6/10. I definitely would have felt as if I wasted my time if I'd paid money to see it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's not like there's a line between the good people and the bad people. It is not like you're one or the other.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lone Star is written and directed by John Sayles. It stars Chris Cooper, Joe Morton, Stephen J. Lang, Stephen Mendillo, Elizabeth Pe&ntilde;a and Kris Kristofferson. Music is scored by Mason Daring and cinematography by Stuart Dryburgh. The small Texas town of Rio County is rocked when a human skeleton is found in the sand and a Rio County Sheriff's badge found near by. The evidence points to it being the body of one time Sheriff Charlie Wade, a vile man who bullied the town for gratification and who one day just disappeared. Current Sheriff Sam Deeds begins investigating, knowing full well that there's a good chance the murderer could have be his own father, Buddy, who was known to have stood up to Wade with some hostile conviction. A hugely enjoyable pulpy mystery that's given a cunning make over by the talented Sayles. The who done it question at the film's core is merely one ingredient in this particular stew, this deals in themes such as violence, racism and family strife, the impact of lawmen on one small town, spread out across two generations. All the characters are interesting and well delineated, the dialogue as part of a non-linear narrative is precise and telling, while Sayles proves to be a stylistic craftsman by presenting two scenes 40 years apart within the same shot. A morality tale of some substance, with cast performances to match, it's a film sure to reward more with each viewing. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Stretch Of Road Runs Between Nowhere And Not Much Else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Deeds is the son of a late but much beloved Texas county sheriff who has inherited his father's job. But when a body is dug up from forty years ago and Sam investigates he discovers his father's illustrious past contains some dark and painful secrets ... This Texican murder mystery is one of Sayles' many beautifully constructed and densely populated character dramas (see also City Of Hope and Sunshine State) where, as with so much of his work, every single person is interesting, thoughtful and fully-rounded. This film is also a beautiful example of how to elegantly switch a narrative back and forward through two different eras, both visually through lovely little panning shots which dip in and out of time, and plot-wise as gradually the gauze covering the complex relationships is slowly lifted to reveal what has made the characters who they are. This is immensely satisfying as the pieces fit together, delicately played by a sensational ensemble cast who understand exactly what the story is trying to achieve. Cooper and Pe&ntilde;a are both superb as the middle-aged leads, both working county jobs, both struggling to find any meaning to their lives, both unable to move on from a fateful past together. The older actors steal the show with irascible wit, and pragmatism and regret written in equal measure on their faces - Canada in particular is outstanding - and Morton is terrific as ever in one of many parts for Sayles as the no-nonsense army man forced to embrace the tenderness he has long considered a weakness. Perhaps the casting masterstroke though is country legend Kristofferson as the thoroughly evil ghost from the past, whose violent brand of personal justice is horrifyingly plausible. Full of poignant moments, clever misdirection, evocative locations, heartfelt performances and funny lines (when Sam is headed to Mexico and tells a colleague he's going to "the other side", the response is "Republicans ?"), with a fine story and a great ending, this is high quality drama all the way. Shot in the beautiful south-western Texas border cities of Del Rio, Eagle Pass and Laredo.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris and Kris....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tim Kidner (tim@kidnerpix.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Cooper and Kris Kristofferson respectively, play two Mexican border sheriffs in John Sayle's excellent movie, but one is dead and the other is very much alive. This is a brooding, simmering and multi-layered drama of the highest order. The pacing is quite superb, unfolding like a great novel and keeps one quietly riveted for all of its two & a quarter hours. The characters are all so well rounded, their persona's so completely but subtly explored that one lives in and breathes every scene. Watching again on BBC2, after several year's gap, it still smacks of being totally relevant and up to date. Wrapped up within its celluloid binding is a tale of every family nuance, racial bigotry and human thought and emotion that a Chekov might. The soundtrack, too, is wonderfully eclectic and fitting. The plot is involved, but easy to follow, and never patronising in its assumptions. Other reviewers have explored it further than I'm going to and I'm simply reinforcing their voices and opinions and say that Lone Star is a must-see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just fantastic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elexigente48
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my top 20 movies of all time. After 3 viewings this feature just keeps getting better. This movie has a most unusual depth and diversity of characters and cultures that spans many generations (at times back into 19th century history), the only film I can think of that comes close is "Gone with the Wind." The crime scene investigation is only the outermost layer of the onion. It is a metaphor for one man's quest for Truth in a deeply flawed human world that strongly prefers myths. The movie is an exploration of the inexorable individual, generational, cultural, and racial baggage that haunts our mortal existence. It is about the human connections that transcend imagined and ever-changing boundaries. The school PTA meeting scene is not an irrelevant tangent. It is an encapsulation of this central underlying theme. When the white man dances with the Hispanic woman in a Mexican restaurant in Texas to an Ivory Joe Hunter rhythm and blues song sung in Spanish by Freddy Fender you should get the picture! This film is a rich tapestry that can fairly be called "Shakesperian." In classic form, the multiple layers of mythologies are slowly revealed to be solace from the boundless tragedy of human truths. This is a must see film about the threads of humanity that link (and separate) us all across many generations. Strongly recommended. Don't miss it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You are not alone, "Lone Star"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    setiaselalu-setiawan8
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a complex movie, for sure. And i like it because of that. I watch this movie twice. At my first watch, i thought the movie is an okay, i rated it 6/10. But, it made me think, how could a movie this good is an okay for me? So, I decided to watch it again last night. And, ..... wow!!! The acting, the cinematography, the screenplay(the best part from this movie, i guess), and score match together like it made by heaven. It has more than one messages, but don't worry . John Sayles(Director) invited us in a believable way. In my opinion, the twist is one of the best. Bravo!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too many characters, too much dialog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wlee08
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At the risk of sounding like the music critic in the movie Amadeus, who referred to Mozart's music as having "too many notes", I'm inclined to judge this movie as having too much of everything: US-Mexican relations, racism, in depth family histories, US military policies, mixed-race relationships, lost love, Freudian father relationships,...it just goes on and on and on. The dialog is also excessive, with a lot of it sounding like characters from the show "Law and Order". Although there were a few really good/powerful scenes, I felt many scenes were hard to follow along with - making the movie itself very convoluted. (Its been 15 years since its release and nobody has written an IMDb synopsis. Think about it.) I think a lot of the dialog went over my head for several reasons. For one, the sound quality seemed poor (but this could be my TV), the accents made it difficult too. And I might have just stopped caring about every single sentence. It seemed like every character in the movie was named "Buddy", which didn't help either. Anyways, I'm willing to accept partial responsibility for not watching this with 115% concentration. Maybe I'll watch it again someday.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forget the Alamo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paul2001sw-1 (paul2001sw@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this Texas detective story, a sheriff finds himself investigating the past of his own father, a man who was also his predecessor as sheriff, and a local hero everywhere except in his own household. The characters may be slow-moving and tight-lipped out of habit, but the ambiguity of their feelings is plain, and a strength of this drama, as is the way the plot weaves in many aspects of life in a border town. Perhaps some aspects of the way that town life is portrayed are a little too stylised, a little anachronistic, the reality of Mexican-American relations shown through the lens of the traditional western: but but film stays consistently within the world it has created. In terms of overall mood, there are elements that resemble the later 'No Country For Old Men', but without that movie's fall-back psychopath-driven plot, it offers a more interesting and ultimately humane vision of south Texas life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very noir...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anything I found this one a little too complex; there were several threads that seemed totally unrelated to the main thrust of the story. It's also, I felt, a little too long; the filmmakers are asking quite a lot for an audience to concentrate for two hours and fifteen minutes. It is slow paced, but I didn't particularly mind that; I'm used to the noir style and it is usually quite a slow burner. Some great performances with Chris Cooper coping well with the leading role and Kris Kristofferson playing the villain of the peace with gusto. Also we have Elizabeth Pe&ntilde;a, who did an excellent job as the female lead and a small part for Matthew McConaughey as Buddy Deeds. Although it does have its problems I still found it an excellent watch; definitely one to look out for for all you noir fans out there. SteelMonster's verdict: RECOMMENDED My score: 7.5/10. You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A hidden gem.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never thought I would see Matthew McConaughey playing Chris Cooper's farther! But yes, don't worry. It has to do with the simple fact that this movie keeps switching back and forth between present time and the past. With the use of flashback it slowly starts to become more apparent what happened 40-years before a skeleton got dug up, somewhere in the Texas desert. Lots of different story lines and characters end up getting intertwined but luckily the movie never becomes a messy or confusing one. It's actually a nice thing the movie has so many different characters in it, with each their own thing happening. It makes the movie, that otherwise probably would had been kind of slow, one that has always something happening in it and never becomes dull or a drag. You could actually say that the movie thrives on its characters. Everything that is happening and going on in this movie is due to them. They makes things interesting, as basically all of them need to come on terms with themselves and their past. This really ain't no ordinary murder mystery but more of a character-piece instead! And the movie of course has a great cast for that. The movie is well cast, especially when considering that most of the actors who appear in this movie weren't being big stars yet at the time. This for instance goes for Chris Cooper and Matthew McConaughey. All of the actors did a great job in this movie and were given plenty of opportunity to shine in this one. The movie at first truly feels like a Coen-brothers movie and it maintains this sort of feeling and style pretty much throughout the entire movie but it's being a bit more drama than comedy orientated. I actually do believe that if the Coen-brothers directed this movie it would had been a far better known was, as well as a better one I feel. The movie could had used some humor and entertainment in at times, since the right type of story and characters were definitely there for it. But oh well, the movie was going for a different approach and it still is for most part being successful with it as well. It simply great, little and simple movie to watch and there is also no good reason why you shouldn't! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inept plot, however well-meaning the story may be...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know I'm in the vast minority here, but I wasn't too impressed with this film. I think the problem was that too many of the subplots seemed incongruous, and frankly, uninteresting. I would have preferred it if the movie stuck to Chris Cooper's character. I was also expecting more Michael "Mchonohay", maybe if the film had been 1 half set in the present with the Sheriff and then the other half set in the past. Instead we get a bunch of stories about different people of the town that is meant to represent some sort of portrait of America, but they don't interlock the way 'Crash', 'Babel', 'Nashville', or other films do. It's a film trying to be ensemble when it doesn't need to. It probably would have worked better as a TV show, as too many of the loose threads lack that satisfying cohesiveness that a film should offer. The relationship between Sam and Pilar is also quite strange, and by the end, rather off-putting. In addition, the revelation about their past seems completely out of left field and of no relation to the central aspect of the story... or maybe it does in a weird sort of way. Either way, I feel that Sayles script is a little too 1990s PC for my tastes. Much of the moralizing between the characters (save for one brilliant scene outside a Mexican gas station) feels like something out of Schoolhouse Rock. Additionally, I thought the 'who-dunnit' murder plot was rather straightforward. Seeing Kristofferson's evil was entertaining, but I would have expected a bigger reveal or a more interesting resolution to his story. Maybe I was just let down by all the hype. I gave it a 6/10. I definitely would have felt as if I wasted my time if I'd paid money to see it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's not like there's a line between the good people and the bad people. It is not like you're one or the other.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lone Star is written and directed by John Sayles. It stars Chris Cooper, Joe Morton, Stephen J. Lang, Stephen Mendillo, Elizabeth Pe&ntilde;a and Kris Kristofferson. Music is scored by Mason Daring and cinematography by Stuart Dryburgh. The small Texas town of Rio County is rocked when a human skeleton is found in the sand and a Rio County Sheriff's badge found near by. The evidence points to it being the body of one time Sheriff Charlie Wade, a vile man who bullied the town for gratification and who one day just disappeared. Current Sheriff Sam Deeds begins investigating, knowing full well that there's a good chance the murderer could have be his own father, Buddy, who was known to have stood up to Wade with some hostile conviction. A hugely enjoyable pulpy mystery that's given a cunning make over by the talented Sayles. The who done it question at the film's core is merely one ingredient in this particular stew, this deals in themes such as violence, racism and family strife, the impact of lawmen on one small town, spread out across two generations. All the characters are interesting and well delineated, the dialogue as part of a non-linear narrative is precise and telling, while Sayles proves to be a stylistic craftsman by presenting two scenes 40 years apart within the same shot. A morality tale of some substance, with cast performances to match, it's a film sure to reward more with each viewing. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Stretch Of Road Runs Between Nowhere And Not Much Else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Deeds is the son of a late but much beloved Texas county sheriff who has inherited his father's job. But when a body is dug up from forty years ago and Sam investigates he discovers his father's illustrious past contains some dark and painful secrets ... This Texican murder mystery is one of Sayles' many beautifully constructed and densely populated character dramas (see also City Of Hope and Sunshine State) where, as with so much of his work, every single person is interesting, thoughtful and fully-rounded. This film is also a beautiful example of how to elegantly switch a narrative back and forward through two different eras, both visually through lovely little panning shots which dip in and out of time, and plot-wise as gradually the gauze covering the complex relationships is slowly lifted to reveal what has made the characters who they are. This is immensely satisfying as the pieces fit together, delicately played by a sensational ensemble cast who understand exactly what the story is trying to achieve. Cooper and Pe&ntilde;a are both superb as the middle-aged leads, both working county jobs, both struggling to find any meaning to their lives, both unable to move on from a fateful past together. The older actors steal the show with irascible wit, and pragmatism and regret written in equal measure on their faces - Canada in particular is outstanding - and Morton is terrific as ever in one of many parts for Sayles as the no-nonsense army man forced to embrace the tenderness he has long considered a weakness. Perhaps the casting masterstroke though is country legend Kristofferson as the thoroughly evil ghost from the past, whose violent brand of personal justice is horrifyingly plausible. Full of poignant moments, clever misdirection, evocative locations, heartfelt performances and funny lines (when Sam is headed to Mexico and tells a colleague he's going to "the other side", the response is "Republicans ?"), with a fine story and a great ending, this is high quality drama all the way. Shot in the beautiful south-western Texas border cities of Del Rio, Eagle Pass and Laredo.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris and Kris....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tim Kidner (tim@kidnerpix.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Cooper and Kris Kristofferson respectively, play two Mexican border sheriffs in John Sayle's excellent movie, but one is dead and the other is very much alive. This is a brooding, simmering and multi-layered drama of the highest order. The pacing is quite superb, unfolding like a great novel and keeps one quietly riveted for all of its two & a quarter hours. The characters are all so well rounded, their persona's so completely but subtly explored that one lives in and breathes every scene. Watching again on BBC2, after several year's gap, it still smacks of being totally relevant and up to date. Wrapped up within its celluloid binding is a tale of every family nuance, racial bigotry and human thought and emotion that a Chekov might. The soundtrack, too, is wonderfully eclectic and fitting. The plot is involved, but easy to follow, and never patronising in its assumptions. Other reviewers have explored it further than I'm going to and I'm simply reinforcing their voices and opinions and say that Lone Star is a must-see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just fantastic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elexigente48
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my top 20 movies of all time. After 3 viewings this feature just keeps getting better. This movie has a most unusual depth and diversity of characters and cultures that spans many generations (at times back into 19th century history), the only film I can think of that comes close is "Gone with the Wind." The crime scene investigation is only the outermost layer of the onion. It is a metaphor for one man's quest for Truth in a deeply flawed human world that strongly prefers myths. The movie is an exploration of the inexorable individual, generational, cultural, and racial baggage that haunts our mortal existence. It is about the human connections that transcend imagined and ever-changing boundaries. The school PTA meeting scene is not an irrelevant tangent. It is an encapsulation of this central underlying theme. When the white man dances with the Hispanic woman in a Mexican restaurant in Texas to an Ivory Joe Hunter rhythm and blues song sung in Spanish by Freddy Fender you should get the picture! This film is a rich tapestry that can fairly be called "Shakesperian." In classic form, the multiple layers of mythologies are slowly revealed to be solace from the boundless tragedy of human truths. This is a must see film about the threads of humanity that link (and separate) us all across many generations. Strongly recommended. Don't miss it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You are not alone, "Lone Star"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    setiaselalu-setiawan8
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a complex movie, for sure. And i like it because of that. I watch this movie twice. At my first watch, i thought the movie is an okay, i rated it 6/10. But, it made me think, how could a movie this good is an okay for me? So, I decided to watch it again last night. And, ..... wow!!! The acting, the cinematography, the screenplay(the best part from this movie, i guess), and score match together like it made by heaven. It has more than one messages, but don't worry . John Sayles(Director) invited us in a believable way. In my opinion, the twist is one of the best. Bravo!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too many characters, too much dialog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wlee08
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At the risk of sounding like the music critic in the movie Amadeus, who referred to Mozart's music as having "too many notes", I'm inclined to judge this movie as having too much of everything: US-Mexican relations, racism, in depth family histories, US military policies, mixed-race relationships, lost love, Freudian father relationships,...it just goes on and on and on. The dialog is also excessive, with a lot of it sounding like characters from the show "Law and Order". Although there were a few really good/powerful scenes, I felt many scenes were hard to follow along with - making the movie itself very convoluted. (Its been 15 years since its release and nobody has written an IMDb synopsis. Think about it.) I think a lot of the dialog went over my head for several reasons. For one, the sound quality seemed poor (but this could be my TV), the accents made it difficult too. And I might have just stopped caring about every single sentence. It seemed like every character in the movie was named "Buddy", which didn't help either. Anyways, I'm willing to accept partial responsibility for not watching this with 115% concentration. Maybe I'll watch it again someday.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forget the Alamo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paul2001sw-1 (paul2001sw@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this Texas detective story, a sheriff finds himself investigating the past of his own father, a man who was also his predecessor as sheriff, and a local hero everywhere except in his own household. The characters may be slow-moving and tight-lipped out of habit, but the ambiguity of their feelings is plain, and a strength of this drama, as is the way the plot weaves in many aspects of life in a border town. Perhaps some aspects of the way that town life is portrayed are a little too stylised, a little anachronistic, the reality of Mexican-American relations shown through the lens of the traditional western: but but film stays consistently within the world it has created. In terms of overall mood, there are elements that resemble the later 'No Country For Old Men', but without that movie's fall-back psychopath-driven plot, it offers a more interesting and ultimately humane vision of south Texas life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very noir...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anything I found this one a little too complex; there were several threads that seemed totally unrelated to the main thrust of the story. It's also, I felt, a little too long; the filmmakers are asking quite a lot for an audience to concentrate for two hours and fifteen minutes. It is slow paced, but I didn't particularly mind that; I'm used to the noir style and it is usually quite a slow burner. Some great performances with Chris Cooper coping well with the leading role and Kris Kristofferson playing the villain of the peace with gusto. Also we have Elizabeth Pe&ntilde;a, who did an excellent job as the female lead and a small part for Matthew McConaughey as Buddy Deeds. Although it does have its problems I still found it an excellent watch; definitely one to look out for for all you noir fans out there. SteelMonster's verdict: RECOMMENDED My score: 7.5/10. You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A hidden gem.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never thought I would see Matthew McConaughey playing Chris Cooper's farther! But yes, don't worry. It has to do with the simple fact that this movie keeps switching back and forth between present time and the past. With the use of flashback it slowly starts to become more apparent what happened 40-years before a skeleton got dug up, somewhere in the Texas desert. Lots of different story lines and characters end up getting intertwined but luckily the movie never becomes a messy or confusing one. It's actually a nice thing the movie has so many different characters in it, with each their own thing happening. It makes the movie, that otherwise probably would had been kind of slow, one that has always something happening in it and never becomes dull or a drag. You could actually say that the movie thrives on its characters. Everything that is happening and going on in this movie is due to them. They makes things interesting, as basically all of them need to come on terms with themselves and their past. This really ain't no ordinary murder mystery but more of a character-piece instead! And the movie of course has a great cast for that. The movie is well cast, especially when considering that most of the actors who appear in this movie weren't being big stars yet at the time. This for instance goes for Chris Cooper and Matthew McConaughey. All of the actors did a great job in this movie and were given plenty of opportunity to shine in this one. The movie at first truly feels like a Coen-brothers movie and it maintains this sort of feeling and style pretty much throughout the entire movie but it's being a bit more drama than comedy orientated. I actually do believe that if the Coen-brothers directed this movie it would had been a far better known was, as well as a better one I feel. The movie could had used some humor and entertainment in at times, since the right type of story and characters were definitely there for it. But oh well, the movie was going for a different approach and it still is for most part being successful with it as well. It simply great, little and simple movie to watch and there is also no good reason why you shouldn't! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inept plot, however well-meaning the story may be...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know I'm in the vast minority here, but I wasn't too impressed with this film. I think the problem was that too many of the subplots seemed incongruous, and frankly, uninteresting. I would have preferred it if the movie stuck to Chris Cooper's character. I was also expecting more Michael "Mchonohay", maybe if the film had been 1 half set in the present with the Sheriff and then the other half set in the past. Instead we get a bunch of stories about different people of the town that is meant to represent some sort of portrait of America, but they don't interlock the way 'Crash', 'Babel', 'Nashville', or other films do. It's a film trying to be ensemble when it doesn't need to. It probably would have worked better as a TV show, as too many of the loose threads lack that satisfying cohesiveness that a film should offer. The relationship between Sam and Pilar is also quite strange, and by the end, rather off-putting. In addition, the revelation about their past seems completely out of left field and of no relation to the central aspect of the story... or maybe it does in a weird sort of way. Either way, I feel that Sayles script is a little too 1990s PC for my tastes. Much of the moralizing between the characters (save for one brilliant scene outside a Mexican gas station) feels like something out of Schoolhouse Rock. Additionally, I thought the 'who-dunnit' murder plot was rather straightforward. Seeing Kristofferson's evil was entertaining, but I would have expected a bigger reveal or a more interesting resolution to his story. Maybe I was just let down by all the hype. I gave it a 6/10. I definitely would have felt as if I wasted my time if I'd paid money to see it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's not like there's a line between the good people and the bad people. It is not like you're one or the other.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lone Star is written and directed by John Sayles. It stars Chris Cooper, Joe Morton, Stephen J. Lang, Stephen Mendillo, Elizabeth Pe&ntilde;a and Kris Kristofferson. Music is scored by Mason Daring and cinematography by Stuart Dryburgh. The small Texas town of Rio County is rocked when a human skeleton is found in the sand and a Rio County Sheriff's badge found near by. The evidence points to it being the body of one time Sheriff Charlie Wade, a vile man who bullied the town for gratification and who one day just disappeared. Current Sheriff Sam Deeds begins investigating, knowing full well that there's a good chance the murderer could have be his own father, Buddy, who was known to have stood up to Wade with some hostile conviction. A hugely enjoyable pulpy mystery that's given a cunning make over by the talented Sayles. The who done it question at the film's core is merely one ingredient in this particular stew, this deals in themes such as violence, racism and family strife, the impact of lawmen on one small town, spread out across two generations. All the characters are interesting and well delineated, the dialogue as part of a non-linear narrative is precise and telling, while Sayles proves to be a stylistic craftsman by presenting two scenes 40 years apart within the same shot. A morality tale of some substance, with cast performances to match, it's a film sure to reward more with each viewing. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Stretch Of Road Runs Between Nowhere And Not Much Else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Deeds is the son of a late but much beloved Texas county sheriff who has inherited his father's job. But when a body is dug up from forty years ago and Sam investigates he discovers his father's illustrious past contains some dark and painful secrets ... This Texican murder mystery is one of Sayles' many beautifully constructed and densely populated character dramas (see also City Of Hope and Sunshine State) where, as with so much of his work, every single person is interesting, thoughtful and fully-rounded. This film is also a beautiful example of how to elegantly switch a narrative back and forward through two different eras, both visually through lovely little panning shots which dip in and out of time, and plot-wise as gradually the gauze covering the complex relationships is slowly lifted to reveal what has made the characters who they are. This is immensely satisfying as the pieces fit together, delicately played by a sensational ensemble cast who understand exactly what the story is trying to achieve. Cooper and Pe&ntilde;a are both superb as the middle-aged leads, both working county jobs, both struggling to find any meaning to their lives, both unable to move on from a fateful past together. The older actors steal the show with irascible wit, and pragmatism and regret written in equal measure on their faces - Canada in particular is outstanding - and Morton is terrific as ever in one of many parts for Sayles as the no-nonsense army man forced to embrace the tenderness he has long considered a weakness. Perhaps the casting masterstroke though is country legend Kristofferson as the thoroughly evil ghost from the past, whose violent brand of personal justice is horrifyingly plausible. Full of poignant moments, clever misdirection, evocative locations, heartfelt performances and funny lines (when Sam is headed to Mexico and tells a colleague he's going to "the other side", the response is "Republicans ?"), with a fine story and a great ending, this is high quality drama all the way. Shot in the beautiful south-western Texas border cities of Del Rio, Eagle Pass and Laredo.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris and Kris....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tim Kidner (tim@kidnerpix.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Cooper and Kris Kristofferson respectively, play two Mexican border sheriffs in John Sayle's excellent movie, but one is dead and the other is very much alive. This is a brooding, simmering and multi-layered drama of the highest order. The pacing is quite superb, unfolding like a great novel and keeps one quietly riveted for all of its two & a quarter hours. The characters are all so well rounded, their persona's so completely but subtly explored that one lives in and breathes every scene. Watching again on BBC2, after several year's gap, it still smacks of being totally relevant and up to date. Wrapped up within its celluloid binding is a tale of every family nuance, racial bigotry and human thought and emotion that a Chekov might. The soundtrack, too, is wonderfully eclectic and fitting. The plot is involved, but easy to follow, and never patronising in its assumptions. Other reviewers have explored it further than I'm going to and I'm simply reinforcing their voices and opinions and say that Lone Star is a must-see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just fantastic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elexigente48
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my top 20 movies of all time. After 3 viewings this feature just keeps getting better. This movie has a most unusual depth and diversity of characters and cultures that spans many generations (at times back into 19th century history), the only film I can think of that comes close is "Gone with the Wind." The crime scene investigation is only the outermost layer of the onion. It is a metaphor for one man's quest for Truth in a deeply flawed human world that strongly prefers myths. The movie is an exploration of the inexorable individual, generational, cultural, and racial baggage that haunts our mortal existence. It is about the human connections that transcend imagined and ever-changing boundaries. The school PTA meeting scene is not an irrelevant tangent. It is an encapsulation of this central underlying theme. When the white man dances with the Hispanic woman in a Mexican restaurant in Texas to an Ivory Joe Hunter rhythm and blues song sung in Spanish by Freddy Fender you should get the picture! This film is a rich tapestry that can fairly be called "Shakesperian." In classic form, the multiple layers of mythologies are slowly revealed to be solace from the boundless tragedy of human truths. This is a must see film about the threads of humanity that link (and separate) us all across many generations. Strongly recommended. Don't miss it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You are not alone, "Lone Star"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    setiaselalu-setiawan8
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a complex movie, for sure. And i like it because of that. I watch this movie twice. At my first watch, i thought the movie is an okay, i rated it 6/10. But, it made me think, how could a movie this good is an okay for me? So, I decided to watch it again last night. And, ..... wow!!! The acting, the cinematography, the screenplay(the best part from this movie, i guess), and score match together like it made by heaven. It has more than one messages, but don't worry . John Sayles(Director) invited us in a believable way. In my opinion, the twist is one of the best. Bravo!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too many characters, too much dialog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wlee08
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At the risk of sounding like the music critic in the movie Amadeus, who referred to Mozart's music as having "too many notes", I'm inclined to judge this movie as having too much of everything: US-Mexican relations, racism, in depth family histories, US military policies, mixed-race relationships, lost love, Freudian father relationships,...it just goes on and on and on. The dialog is also excessive, with a lot of it sounding like characters from the show "Law and Order". Although there were a few really good/powerful scenes, I felt many scenes were hard to follow along with - making the movie itself very convoluted. (Its been 15 years since its release and nobody has written an IMDb synopsis. Think about it.) I think a lot of the dialog went over my head for several reasons. For one, the sound quality seemed poor (but this could be my TV), the accents made it difficult too. And I might have just stopped caring about every single sentence. It seemed like every character in the movie was named "Buddy", which didn't help either. Anyways, I'm willing to accept partial responsibility for not watching this with 115% concentration. Maybe I'll watch it again someday.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forget the Alamo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paul2001sw-1 (paul2001sw@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this Texas detective story, a sheriff finds himself investigating the past of his own father, a man who was also his predecessor as sheriff, and a local hero everywhere except in his own household. The characters may be slow-moving and tight-lipped out of habit, but the ambiguity of their feelings is plain, and a strength of this drama, as is the way the plot weaves in many aspects of life in a border town. Perhaps some aspects of the way that town life is portrayed are a little too stylised, a little anachronistic, the reality of Mexican-American relations shown through the lens of the traditional western: but but film stays consistently within the world it has created. In terms of overall mood, there are elements that resemble the later 'No Country For Old Men', but without that movie's fall-back psychopath-driven plot, it offers a more interesting and ultimately humane vision of south Texas life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very noir...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anything I found this one a little too complex; there were several threads that seemed totally unrelated to the main thrust of the story. It's also, I felt, a little too long; the filmmakers are asking quite a lot for an audience to concentrate for two hours and fifteen minutes. It is slow paced, but I didn't particularly mind that; I'm used to the noir style and it is usually quite a slow burner. Some great performances with Chris Cooper coping well with the leading role and Kris Kristofferson playing the villain of the peace with gusto. Also we have Elizabeth Pe&ntilde;a, who did an excellent job as the female lead and a small part for Matthew McConaughey as Buddy Deeds. Although it does have its problems I still found it an excellent watch; definitely one to look out for for all you noir fans out there. SteelMonster's verdict: RECOMMENDED My score: 7.5/10. You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A hidden gem.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never thought I would see Matthew McConaughey playing Chris Cooper's farther! But yes, don't worry. It has to do with the simple fact that this movie keeps switching back and forth between present time and the past. With the use of flashback it slowly starts to become more apparent what happened 40-years before a skeleton got dug up, somewhere in the Texas desert. Lots of different story lines and characters end up getting intertwined but luckily the movie never becomes a messy or confusing one. It's actually a nice thing the movie has so many different characters in it, with each their own thing happening. It makes the movie, that otherwise probably would had been kind of slow, one that has always something happening in it and never becomes dull or a drag. You could actually say that the movie thrives on its characters. Everything that is happening and going on in this movie is due to them. They makes things interesting, as basically all of them need to come on terms with themselves and their past. This really ain't no ordinary murder mystery but more of a character-piece instead! And the movie of course has a great cast for that. The movie is well cast, especially when considering that most of the actors who appear in this movie weren't being big stars yet at the time. This for instance goes for Chris Cooper and Matthew McConaughey. All of the actors did a great job in this movie and were given plenty of opportunity to shine in this one. The movie at first truly feels like a Coen-brothers movie and it maintains this sort of feeling and style pretty much throughout the entire movie but it's being a bit more drama than comedy orientated. I actually do believe that if the Coen-brothers directed this movie it would had been a far better known was, as well as a better one I feel. The movie could had used some humor and entertainment in at times, since the right type of story and characters were definitely there for it. But oh well, the movie was going for a different approach and it still is for most part being successful with it as well. It simply great, little and simple movie to watch and there is also no good reason why you shouldn't! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inept plot, however well-meaning the story may be...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know I'm in the vast minority here, but I wasn't too impressed with this film. I think the problem was that too many of the subplots seemed incongruous, and frankly, uninteresting. I would have preferred it if the movie stuck to Chris Cooper's character. I was also expecting more Michael "Mchonohay", maybe if the film had been 1 half set in the present with the Sheriff and then the other half set in the past. Instead we get a bunch of stories about different people of the town that is meant to represent some sort of portrait of America, but they don't interlock the way 'Crash', 'Babel', 'Nashville', or other films do. It's a film trying to be ensemble when it doesn't need to. It probably would have worked better as a TV show, as too many of the loose threads lack that satisfying cohesiveness that a film should offer. The relationship between Sam and Pilar is also quite strange, and by the end, rather off-putting. In addition, the revelation about their past seems completely out of left field and of no relation to the central aspect of the story... or maybe it does in a weird sort of way. Either way, I feel that Sayles script is a little too 1990s PC for my tastes. Much of the moralizing between the characters (save for one brilliant scene outside a Mexican gas station) feels like something out of Schoolhouse Rock. Additionally, I thought the 'who-dunnit' murder plot was rather straightforward. Seeing Kristofferson's evil was entertaining, but I would have expected a bigger reveal or a more interesting resolution to his story. Maybe I was just let down by all the hype. I gave it a 6/10. I definitely would have felt as if I wasted my time if I'd paid money to see it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's not like there's a line between the good people and the bad people. It is not like you're one or the other.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lone Star is written and directed by John Sayles. It stars Chris Cooper, Joe Morton, Stephen J. Lang, Stephen Mendillo, Elizabeth Pe&ntilde;a and Kris Kristofferson. Music is scored by Mason Daring and cinematography by Stuart Dryburgh. The small Texas town of Rio County is rocked when a human skeleton is found in the sand and a Rio County Sheriff's badge found near by. The evidence points to it being the body of one time Sheriff Charlie Wade, a vile man who bullied the town for gratification and who one day just disappeared. Current Sheriff Sam Deeds begins investigating, knowing full well that there's a good chance the murderer could have be his own father, Buddy, who was known to have stood up to Wade with some hostile conviction. A hugely enjoyable pulpy mystery that's given a cunning make over by the talented Sayles. The who done it question at the film's core is merely one ingredient in this particular stew, this deals in themes such as violence, racism and family strife, the impact of lawmen on one small town, spread out across two generations. All the characters are interesting and well delineated, the dialogue as part of a non-linear narrative is precise and telling, while Sayles proves to be a stylistic craftsman by presenting two scenes 40 years apart within the same shot. A morality tale of some substance, with cast performances to match, it's a film sure to reward more with each viewing. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Stretch Of Road Runs Between Nowhere And Not Much Else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Deeds is the son of a late but much beloved Texas county sheriff who has inherited his father's job. But when a body is dug up from forty years ago and Sam investigates he discovers his father's illustrious past contains some dark and painful secrets ... This Texican murder mystery is one of Sayles' many beautifully constructed and densely populated character dramas (see also City Of Hope and Sunshine State) where, as with so much of his work, every single person is interesting, thoughtful and fully-rounded. This film is also a beautiful example of how to elegantly switch a narrative back and forward through two different eras, both visually through lovely little panning shots which dip in and out of time, and plot-wise as gradually the gauze covering the complex relationships is slowly lifted to reveal what has made the characters who they are. This is immensely satisfying as the pieces fit together, delicately played by a sensational ensemble cast who understand exactly what the story is trying to achieve. Cooper and Pe&ntilde;a are both superb as the middle-aged leads, both working county jobs, both struggling to find any meaning to their lives, both unable to move on from a fateful past together. The older actors steal the show with irascible wit, and pragmatism and regret written in equal measure on their faces - Canada in particular is outstanding - and Morton is terrific as ever in one of many parts for Sayles as the no-nonsense army man forced to embrace the tenderness he has long considered a weakness. Perhaps the casting masterstroke though is country legend Kristofferson as the thoroughly evil ghost from the past, whose violent brand of personal justice is horrifyingly plausible. Full of poignant moments, clever misdirection, evocative locations, heartfelt performances and funny lines (when Sam is headed to Mexico and tells a colleague he's going to "the other side", the response is "Republicans ?"), with a fine story and a great ending, this is high quality drama all the way. Shot in the beautiful south-western Texas border cities of Del Rio, Eagle Pass and Laredo.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris and Kris....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tim Kidner (tim@kidnerpix.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Cooper and Kris Kristofferson respectively, play two Mexican border sheriffs in John Sayle's excellent movie, but one is dead and the other is very much alive. This is a brooding, simmering and multi-layered drama of the highest order. The pacing is quite superb, unfolding like a great novel and keeps one quietly riveted for all of its two & a quarter hours. The characters are all so well rounded, their persona's so completely but subtly explored that one lives in and breathes every scene. Watching again on BBC2, after several year's gap, it still smacks of being totally relevant and up to date. Wrapped up within its celluloid binding is a tale of every family nuance, racial bigotry and human thought and emotion that a Chekov might. The soundtrack, too, is wonderfully eclectic and fitting. The plot is involved, but easy to follow, and never patronising in its assumptions. Other reviewers have explored it further than I'm going to and I'm simply reinforcing their voices and opinions and say that Lone Star is a must-see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just fantastic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elexigente48
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my top 20 movies of all time. After 3 viewings this feature just keeps getting better. This movie has a most unusual depth and diversity of characters and cultures that spans many generations (at times back into 19th century history), the only film I can think of that comes close is "Gone with the Wind." The crime scene investigation is only the outermost layer of the onion. It is a metaphor for one man's quest for Truth in a deeply flawed human world that strongly prefers myths. The movie is an exploration of the inexorable individual, generational, cultural, and racial baggage that haunts our mortal existence. It is about the human connections that transcend imagined and ever-changing boundaries. The school PTA meeting scene is not an irrelevant tangent. It is an encapsulation of this central underlying theme. When the white man dances with the Hispanic woman in a Mexican restaurant in Texas to an Ivory Joe Hunter rhythm and blues song sung in Spanish by Freddy Fender you should get the picture! This film is a rich tapestry that can fairly be called "Shakesperian." In classic form, the multiple layers of mythologies are slowly revealed to be solace from the boundless tragedy of human truths. This is a must see film about the threads of humanity that link (and separate) us all across many generations. Strongly recommended. Don't miss it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You are not alone, "Lone Star"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    setiaselalu-setiawan8
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a complex movie, for sure. And i like it because of that. I watch this movie twice. At my first watch, i thought the movie is an okay, i rated it 6/10. But, it made me think, how could a movie this good is an okay for me? So, I decided to watch it again last night. And, ..... wow!!! The acting, the cinematography, the screenplay(the best part from this movie, i guess), and score match together like it made by heaven. It has more than one messages, but don't worry . John Sayles(Director) invited us in a believable way. In my opinion, the twist is one of the best. Bravo!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too many characters, too much dialog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wlee08
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At the risk of sounding like the music critic in the movie Amadeus, who referred to Mozart's music as having "too many notes", I'm inclined to judge this movie as having too much of everything: US-Mexican relations, racism, in depth family histories, US military policies, mixed-race relationships, lost love, Freudian father relationships,...it just goes on and on and on. The dialog is also excessive, with a lot of it sounding like characters from the show "Law and Order". Although there were a few really good/powerful scenes, I felt many scenes were hard to follow along with - making the movie itself very convoluted. (Its been 15 years since its release and nobody has written an IMDb synopsis. Think about it.) I think a lot of the dialog went over my head for several reasons. For one, the sound quality seemed poor (but this could be my TV), the accents made it difficult too. And I might have just stopped caring about every single sentence. It seemed like every character in the movie was named "Buddy", which didn't help either. Anyways, I'm willing to accept partial responsibility for not watching this with 115% concentration. Maybe I'll watch it again someday.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forget the Alamo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paul2001sw-1 (paul2001sw@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this Texas detective story, a sheriff finds himself investigating the past of his own father, a man who was also his predecessor as sheriff, and a local hero everywhere except in his own household. The characters may be slow-moving and tight-lipped out of habit, but the ambiguity of their feelings is plain, and a strength of this drama, as is the way the plot weaves in many aspects of life in a border town. Perhaps some aspects of the way that town life is portrayed are a little too stylised, a little anachronistic, the reality of Mexican-American relations shown through the lens of the traditional western: but but film stays consistently within the world it has created. In terms of overall mood, there are elements that resemble the later 'No Country For Old Men', but without that movie's fall-back psychopath-driven plot, it offers a more interesting and ultimately humane vision of south Texas life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very noir...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anything I found this one a little too complex; there were several threads that seemed totally unrelated to the main thrust of the story. It's also, I felt, a little too long; the filmmakers are asking quite a lot for an audience to concentrate for two hours and fifteen minutes. It is slow paced, but I didn't particularly mind that; I'm used to the noir style and it is usually quite a slow burner. Some great performances with Chris Cooper coping well with the leading role and Kris Kristofferson playing the villain of the peace with gusto. Also we have Elizabeth Pe&ntilde;a, who did an excellent job as the female lead and a small part for Matthew McConaughey as Buddy Deeds. Although it does have its problems I still found it an excellent watch; definitely one to look out for for all you noir fans out there. SteelMonster's verdict: RECOMMENDED My score: 7.5/10. You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A hidden gem.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never thought I would see Matthew McConaughey playing Chris Cooper's farther! But yes, don't worry. It has to do with the simple fact that this movie keeps switching back and forth between present time and the past. With the use of flashback it slowly starts to become more apparent what happened 40-years before a skeleton got dug up, somewhere in the Texas desert. Lots of different story lines and characters end up getting intertwined but luckily the movie never becomes a messy or confusing one. It's actually a nice thing the movie has so many different characters in it, with each their own thing happening. It makes the movie, that otherwise probably would had been kind of slow, one that has always something happening in it and never becomes dull or a drag. You could actually say that the movie thrives on its characters. Everything that is happening and going on in this movie is due to them. They makes things interesting, as basically all of them need to come on terms with themselves and their past. This really ain't no ordinary murder mystery but more of a character-piece instead! And the movie of course has a great cast for that. The movie is well cast, especially when considering that most of the actors who appear in this movie weren't being big stars yet at the time. This for instance goes for Chris Cooper and Matthew McConaughey. All of the actors did a great job in this movie and were given plenty of opportunity to shine in this one. The movie at first truly feels like a Coen-brothers movie and it maintains this sort of feeling and style pretty much throughout the entire movie but it's being a bit more drama than comedy orientated. I actually do believe that if the Coen-brothers directed this movie it would had been a far better known was, as well as a better one I feel. The movie could had used some humor and entertainment in at times, since the right type of story and characters were definitely there for it. But oh well, the movie was going for a different approach and it still is for most part being successful with it as well. It simply great, little and simple movie to watch and there is also no good reason why you shouldn't! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inept plot, however well-meaning the story may be...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know I'm in the vast minority here, but I wasn't too impressed with this film. I think the problem was that too many of the subplots seemed incongruous, and frankly, uninteresting. I would have preferred it if the movie stuck to Chris Cooper's character. I was also expecting more Michael "Mchonohay", maybe if the film had been 1 half set in the present with the Sheriff and then the other half set in the past. Instead we get a bunch of stories about different people of the town that is meant to represent some sort of portrait of America, but they don't interlock the way 'Crash', 'Babel', 'Nashville', or other films do. It's a film trying to be ensemble when it doesn't need to. It probably would have worked better as a TV show, as too many of the loose threads lack that satisfying cohesiveness that a film should offer. The relationship between Sam and Pilar is also quite strange, and by the end, rather off-putting. In addition, the revelation about their past seems completely out of left field and of no relation to the central aspect of the story... or maybe it does in a weird sort of way. Either way, I feel that Sayles script is a little too 1990s PC for my tastes. Much of the moralizing between the characters (save for one brilliant scene outside a Mexican gas station) feels like something out of Schoolhouse Rock. Additionally, I thought the 'who-dunnit' murder plot was rather straightforward. Seeing Kristofferson's evil was entertaining, but I would have expected a bigger reveal or a more interesting resolution to his story. Maybe I was just let down by all the hype. I gave it a 6/10. I definitely would have felt as if I wasted my time if I'd paid money to see it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's not like there's a line between the good people and the bad people. It is not like you're one or the other.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lone Star is written and directed by John Sayles. It stars Chris Cooper, Joe Morton, Stephen J. Lang, Stephen Mendillo, Elizabeth Pe&ntilde;a and Kris Kristofferson. Music is scored by Mason Daring and cinematography by Stuart Dryburgh. The small Texas town of Rio County is rocked when a human skeleton is found in the sand and a Rio County Sheriff's badge found near by. The evidence points to it being the body of one time Sheriff Charlie Wade, a vile man who bullied the town for gratification and who one day just disappeared. Current Sheriff Sam Deeds begins investigating, knowing full well that there's a good chance the murderer could have be his own father, Buddy, who was known to have stood up to Wade with some hostile conviction. A hugely enjoyable pulpy mystery that's given a cunning make over by the talented Sayles. The who done it question at the film's core is merely one ingredient in this particular stew, this deals in themes such as violence, racism and family strife, the impact of lawmen on one small town, spread out across two generations. All the characters are interesting and well delineated, the dialogue as part of a non-linear narrative is precise and telling, while Sayles proves to be a stylistic craftsman by presenting two scenes 40 years apart within the same shot. A morality tale of some substance, with cast performances to match, it's a film sure to reward more with each viewing. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Stretch Of Road Runs Between Nowhere And Not Much Else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Deeds is the son of a late but much beloved Texas county sheriff who has inherited his father's job. But when a body is dug up from forty years ago and Sam investigates he discovers his father's illustrious past contains some dark and painful secrets ... This Texican murder mystery is one of Sayles' many beautifully constructed and densely populated character dramas (see also City Of Hope and Sunshine State) where, as with so much of his work, every single person is interesting, thoughtful and fully-rounded. This film is also a beautiful example of how to elegantly switch a narrative back and forward through two different eras, both visually through lovely little panning shots which dip in and out of time, and plot-wise as gradually the gauze covering the complex relationships is slowly lifted to reveal what has made the characters who they are. This is immensely satisfying as the pieces fit together, delicately played by a sensational ensemble cast who understand exactly what the story is trying to achieve. Cooper and Pe&ntilde;a are both superb as the middle-aged leads, both working county jobs, both struggling to find any meaning to their lives, both unable to move on from a fateful past together. The older actors steal the show with irascible wit, and pragmatism and regret written in equal measure on their faces - Canada in particular is outstanding - and Morton is terrific as ever in one of many parts for Sayles as the no-nonsense army man forced to embrace the tenderness he has long considered a weakness. Perhaps the casting masterstroke though is country legend Kristofferson as the thoroughly evil ghost from the past, whose violent brand of personal justice is horrifyingly plausible. Full of poignant moments, clever misdirection, evocative locations, heartfelt performances and funny lines (when Sam is headed to Mexico and tells a colleague he's going to "the other side", the response is "Republicans ?"), with a fine story and a great ending, this is high quality drama all the way. Shot in the beautiful south-western Texas border cities of Del Rio, Eagle Pass and Laredo.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris and Kris....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tim Kidner (tim@kidnerpix.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Cooper and Kris Kristofferson respectively, play two Mexican border sheriffs in John Sayle's excellent movie, but one is dead and the other is very much alive. This is a brooding, simmering and multi-layered drama of the highest order. The pacing is quite superb, unfolding like a great novel and keeps one quietly riveted for all of its two & a quarter hours. The characters are all so well rounded, their persona's so completely but subtly explored that one lives in and breathes every scene. Watching again on BBC2, after several year's gap, it still smacks of being totally relevant and up to date. Wrapped up within its celluloid binding is a tale of every family nuance, racial bigotry and human thought and emotion that a Chekov might. The soundtrack, too, is wonderfully eclectic and fitting. The plot is involved, but easy to follow, and never patronising in its assumptions. Other reviewers have explored it further than I'm going to and I'm simply reinforcing their voices and opinions and say that Lone Star is a must-see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just fantastic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elexigente48
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my top 20 movies of all time. After 3 viewings this feature just keeps getting better. This movie has a most unusual depth and diversity of characters and cultures that spans many generations (at times back into 19th century history), the only film I can think of that comes close is "Gone with the Wind." The crime scene investigation is only the outermost layer of the onion. It is a metaphor for one man's quest for Truth in a deeply flawed human world that strongly prefers myths. The movie is an exploration of the inexorable individual, generational, cultural, and racial baggage that haunts our mortal existence. It is about the human connections that transcend imagined and ever-changing boundaries. The school PTA meeting scene is not an irrelevant tangent. It is an encapsulation of this central underlying theme. When the white man dances with the Hispanic woman in a Mexican restaurant in Texas to an Ivory Joe Hunter rhythm and blues song sung in Spanish by Freddy Fender you should get the picture! This film is a rich tapestry that can fairly be called "Shakesperian." In classic form, the multiple layers of mythologies are slowly revealed to be solace from the boundless tragedy of human truths. This is a must see film about the threads of humanity that link (and separate) us all across many generations. Strongly recommended. Don't miss it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You are not alone, "Lone Star"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    setiaselalu-setiawan8
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a complex movie, for sure. And i like it because of that. I watch this movie twice. At my first watch, i thought the movie is an okay, i rated it 6/10. But, it made me think, how could a movie this good is an okay for me? So, I decided to watch it again last night. And, ..... wow!!! The acting, the cinematography, the screenplay(the best part from this movie, i guess), and score match together like it made by heaven. It has more than one messages, but don't worry . John Sayles(Director) invited us in a believable way. In my opinion, the twist is one of the best. Bravo!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too many characters, too much dialog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wlee08
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At the risk of sounding like the music critic in the movie Amadeus, who referred to Mozart's music as having "too many notes", I'm inclined to judge this movie as having too much of everything: US-Mexican relations, racism, in depth family histories, US military policies, mixed-race relationships, lost love, Freudian father relationships,...it just goes on and on and on. The dialog is also excessive, with a lot of it sounding like characters from the show "Law and Order". Although there were a few really good/powerful scenes, I felt many scenes were hard to follow along with - making the movie itself very convoluted. (Its been 15 years since its release and nobody has written an IMDb synopsis. Think about it.) I think a lot of the dialog went over my head for several reasons. For one, the sound quality seemed poor (but this could be my TV), the accents made it difficult too. And I might have just stopped caring about every single sentence. It seemed like every character in the movie was named "Buddy", which didn't help either. Anyways, I'm willing to accept partial responsibility for not watching this with 115% concentration. Maybe I'll watch it again someday.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forget the Alamo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paul2001sw-1 (paul2001sw@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this Texas detective story, a sheriff finds himself investigating the past of his own father, a man who was also his predecessor as sheriff, and a local hero everywhere except in his own household. The characters may be slow-moving and tight-lipped out of habit, but the ambiguity of their feelings is plain, and a strength of this drama, as is the way the plot weaves in many aspects of life in a border town. Perhaps some aspects of the way that town life is portrayed are a little too stylised, a little anachronistic, the reality of Mexican-American relations shown through the lens of the traditional western: but but film stays consistently within the world it has created. In terms of overall mood, there are elements that resemble the later 'No Country For Old Men', but without that movie's fall-back psychopath-driven plot, it offers a more interesting and ultimately humane vision of south Texas life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very noir...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anything I found this one a little too complex; there were several threads that seemed totally unrelated to the main thrust of the story. It's also, I felt, a little too long; the filmmakers are asking quite a lot for an audience to concentrate for two hours and fifteen minutes. It is slow paced, but I didn't particularly mind that; I'm used to the noir style and it is usually quite a slow burner. Some great performances with Chris Cooper coping well with the leading role and Kris Kristofferson playing the villain of the peace with gusto. Also we have Elizabeth Pe&ntilde;a, who did an excellent job as the female lead and a small part for Matthew McConaughey as Buddy Deeds. Although it does have its problems I still found it an excellent watch; definitely one to look out for for all you noir fans out there. SteelMonster's verdict: RECOMMENDED My score: 7.5/10. You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A hidden gem.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never thought I would see Matthew McConaughey playing Chris Cooper's farther! But yes, don't worry. It has to do with the simple fact that this movie keeps switching back and forth between present time and the past. With the use of flashback it slowly starts to become more apparent what happened 40-years before a skeleton got dug up, somewhere in the Texas desert. Lots of different story lines and characters end up getting intertwined but luckily the movie never becomes a messy or confusing one. It's actually a nice thing the movie has so many different characters in it, with each their own thing happening. It makes the movie, that otherwise probably would had been kind of slow, one that has always something happening in it and never becomes dull or a drag. You could actually say that the movie thrives on its characters. Everything that is happening and going on in this movie is due to them. They makes things interesting, as basically all of them need to come on terms with themselves and their past. This really ain't no ordinary murder mystery but more of a character-piece instead! And the movie of course has a great cast for that. The movie is well cast, especially when considering that most of the actors who appear in this movie weren't being big stars yet at the time. This for instance goes for Chris Cooper and Matthew McConaughey. All of the actors did a great job in this movie and were given plenty of opportunity to shine in this one. The movie at first truly feels like a Coen-brothers movie and it maintains this sort of feeling and style pretty much throughout the entire movie but it's being a bit more drama than comedy orientated. I actually do believe that if the Coen-brothers directed this movie it would had been a far better known was, as well as a better one I feel. The movie could had used some humor and entertainment in at times, since the right type of story and characters were definitely there for it. But oh well, the movie was going for a different approach and it still is for most part being successful with it as well. It simply great, little and simple movie to watch and there is also no good reason why you shouldn't! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inept plot, however well-meaning the story may be...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know I'm in the vast minority here, but I wasn't too impressed with this film. I think the problem was that too many of the subplots seemed incongruous, and frankly, uninteresting. I would have preferred it if the movie stuck to Chris Cooper's character. I was also expecting more Michael "Mchonohay", maybe if the film had been 1 half set in the present with the Sheriff and then the other half set in the past. Instead we get a bunch of stories about different people of the town that is meant to represent some sort of portrait of America, but they don't interlock the way 'Crash', 'Babel', 'Nashville', or other films do. It's a film trying to be ensemble when it doesn't need to. It probably would have worked better as a TV show, as too many of the loose threads lack that satisfying cohesiveness that a film should offer. The relationship between Sam and Pilar is also quite strange, and by the end, rather off-putting. In addition, the revelation about their past seems completely out of left field and of no relation to the central aspect of the story... or maybe it does in a weird sort of way. Either way, I feel that Sayles script is a little too 1990s PC for my tastes. Much of the moralizing between the characters (save for one brilliant scene outside a Mexican gas station) feels like something out of Schoolhouse Rock. Additionally, I thought the 'who-dunnit' murder plot was rather straightforward. Seeing Kristofferson's evil was entertaining, but I would have expected a bigger reveal or a more interesting resolution to his story. Maybe I was just let down by all the hype. I gave it a 6/10. I definitely would have felt as if I wasted my time if I'd paid money to see it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's not like there's a line between the good people and the bad people. It is not like you're one or the other.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lone Star is written and directed by John Sayles. It stars Chris Cooper, Joe Morton, Stephen J. Lang, Stephen Mendillo, Elizabeth Pe&ntilde;a and Kris Kristofferson. Music is scored by Mason Daring and cinematography by Stuart Dryburgh. The small Texas town of Rio County is rocked when a human skeleton is found in the sand and a Rio County Sheriff's badge found near by. The evidence points to it being the body of one time Sheriff Charlie Wade, a vile man who bullied the town for gratification and who one day just disappeared. Current Sheriff Sam Deeds begins investigating, knowing full well that there's a good chance the murderer could have be his own father, Buddy, who was known to have stood up to Wade with some hostile conviction. A hugely enjoyable pulpy mystery that's given a cunning make over by the talented Sayles. The who done it question at the film's core is merely one ingredient in this particular stew, this deals in themes such as violence, racism and family strife, the impact of lawmen on one small town, spread out across two generations. All the characters are interesting and well delineated, the dialogue as part of a non-linear narrative is precise and telling, while Sayles proves to be a stylistic craftsman by presenting two scenes 40 years apart within the same shot. A morality tale of some substance, with cast performances to match, it's a film sure to reward more with each viewing. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Stretch Of Road Runs Between Nowhere And Not Much Else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Deeds is the son of a late but much beloved Texas county sheriff who has inherited his father's job. But when a body is dug up from forty years ago and Sam investigates he discovers his father's illustrious past contains some dark and painful secrets ... This Texican murder mystery is one of Sayles' many beautifully constructed and densely populated character dramas (see also City Of Hope and Sunshine State) where, as with so much of his work, every single person is interesting, thoughtful and fully-rounded. This film is also a beautiful example of how to elegantly switch a narrative back and forward through two different eras, both visually through lovely little panning shots which dip in and out of time, and plot-wise as gradually the gauze covering the complex relationships is slowly lifted to reveal what has made the characters who they are. This is immensely satisfying as the pieces fit together, delicately played by a sensational ensemble cast who understand exactly what the story is trying to achieve. Cooper and Pe&ntilde;a are both superb as the middle-aged leads, both working county jobs, both struggling to find any meaning to their lives, both unable to move on from a fateful past together. The older actors steal the show with irascible wit, and pragmatism and regret written in equal measure on their faces - Canada in particular is outstanding - and Morton is terrific as ever in one of many parts for Sayles as the no-nonsense army man forced to embrace the tenderness he has long considered a weakness. Perhaps the casting masterstroke though is country legend Kristofferson as the thoroughly evil ghost from the past, whose violent brand of personal justice is horrifyingly plausible. Full of poignant moments, clever misdirection, evocative locations, heartfelt performances and funny lines (when Sam is headed to Mexico and tells a colleague he's going to "the other side", the response is "Republicans ?"), with a fine story and a great ending, this is high quality drama all the way. Shot in the beautiful south-western Texas border cities of Del Rio, Eagle Pass and Laredo.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris and Kris....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tim Kidner (tim@kidnerpix.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Cooper and Kris Kristofferson respectively, play two Mexican border sheriffs in John Sayle's excellent movie, but one is dead and the other is very much alive. This is a brooding, simmering and multi-layered drama of the highest order. The pacing is quite superb, unfolding like a great novel and keeps one quietly riveted for all of its two & a quarter hours. The characters are all so well rounded, their persona's so completely but subtly explored that one lives in and breathes every scene. Watching again on BBC2, after several year's gap, it still smacks of being totally relevant and up to date. Wrapped up within its celluloid binding is a tale of every family nuance, racial bigotry and human thought and emotion that a Chekov might. The soundtrack, too, is wonderfully eclectic and fitting. The plot is involved, but easy to follow, and never patronising in its assumptions. Other reviewers have explored it further than I'm going to and I'm simply reinforcing their voices and opinions and say that Lone Star is a must-see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just fantastic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elexigente48
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my top 20 movies of all time. After 3 viewings this feature just keeps getting better. This movie has a most unusual depth and diversity of characters and cultures that spans many generations (at times back into 19th century history), the only film I can think of that comes close is "Gone with the Wind." The crime scene investigation is only the outermost layer of the onion. It is a metaphor for one man's quest for Truth in a deeply flawed human world that strongly prefers myths. The movie is an exploration of the inexorable individual, generational, cultural, and racial baggage that haunts our mortal existence. It is about the human connections that transcend imagined and ever-changing boundaries. The school PTA meeting scene is not an irrelevant tangent. It is an encapsulation of this central underlying theme. When the white man dances with the Hispanic woman in a Mexican restaurant in Texas to an Ivory Joe Hunter rhythm and blues song sung in Spanish by Freddy Fender you should get the picture! This film is a rich tapestry that can fairly be called "Shakesperian." In classic form, the multiple layers of mythologies are slowly revealed to be solace from the boundless tragedy of human truths. This is a must see film about the threads of humanity that link (and separate) us all across many generations. Strongly recommended. Don't miss it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You are not alone, "Lone Star"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    setiaselalu-setiawan8
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a complex movie, for sure. And i like it because of that. I watch this movie twice. At my first watch, i thought the movie is an okay, i rated it 6/10. But, it made me think, how could a movie this good is an okay for me? So, I decided to watch it again last night. And, ..... wow!!! The acting, the cinematography, the screenplay(the best part from this movie, i guess), and score match together like it made by heaven. It has more than one messages, but don't worry . John Sayles(Director) invited us in a believable way. In my opinion, the twist is one of the best. Bravo!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too many characters, too much dialog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wlee08
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At the risk of sounding like the music critic in the movie Amadeus, who referred to Mozart's music as having "too many notes", I'm inclined to judge this movie as having too much of everything: US-Mexican relations, racism, in depth family histories, US military policies, mixed-race relationships, lost love, Freudian father relationships,...it just goes on and on and on. The dialog is also excessive, with a lot of it sounding like characters from the show "Law and Order". Although there were a few really good/powerful scenes, I felt many scenes were hard to follow along with - making the movie itself very convoluted. (Its been 15 years since its release and nobody has written an IMDb synopsis. Think about it.) I think a lot of the dialog went over my head for several reasons. For one, the sound quality seemed poor (but this could be my TV), the accents made it difficult too. And I might have just stopped caring about every single sentence. It seemed like every character in the movie was named "Buddy", which didn't help either. Anyways, I'm willing to accept partial responsibility for not watching this with 115% concentration. Maybe I'll watch it again someday.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forget the Alamo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paul2001sw-1 (paul2001sw@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this Texas detective story, a sheriff finds himself investigating the past of his own father, a man who was also his predecessor as sheriff, and a local hero everywhere except in his own household. The characters may be slow-moving and tight-lipped out of habit, but the ambiguity of their feelings is plain, and a strength of this drama, as is the way the plot weaves in many aspects of life in a border town. Perhaps some aspects of the way that town life is portrayed are a little too stylised, a little anachronistic, the reality of Mexican-American relations shown through the lens of the traditional western: but but film stays consistently within the world it has created. In terms of overall mood, there are elements that resemble the later 'No Country For Old Men', but without that movie's fall-back psychopath-driven plot, it offers a more interesting and ultimately humane vision of south Texas life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very noir...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anything I found this one a little too complex; there were several threads that seemed totally unrelated to the main thrust of the story. It's also, I felt, a little too long; the filmmakers are asking quite a lot for an audience to concentrate for two hours and fifteen minutes. It is slow paced, but I didn't particularly mind that; I'm used to the noir style and it is usually quite a slow burner. Some great performances with Chris Cooper coping well with the leading role and Kris Kristofferson playing the villain of the peace with gusto. Also we have Elizabeth Pe&ntilde;a, who did an excellent job as the female lead and a small part for Matthew McConaughey as Buddy Deeds. Although it does have its problems I still found it an excellent watch; definitely one to look out for for all you noir fans out there. SteelMonster's verdict: RECOMMENDED My score: 7.5/10. You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A hidden gem.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never thought I would see Matthew McConaughey playing Chris Cooper's farther! But yes, don't worry. It has to do with the simple fact that this movie keeps switching back and forth between present time and the past. With the use of flashback it slowly starts to become more apparent what happened 40-years before a skeleton got dug up, somewhere in the Texas desert. Lots of different story lines and characters end up getting intertwined but luckily the movie never becomes a messy or confusing one. It's actually a nice thing the movie has so many different characters in it, with each their own thing happening. It makes the movie, that otherwise probably would had been kind of slow, one that has always something happening in it and never becomes dull or a drag. You could actually say that the movie thrives on its characters. Everything that is happening and going on in this movie is due to them. They makes things interesting, as basically all of them need to come on terms with themselves and their past. This really ain't no ordinary murder mystery but more of a character-piece instead! And the movie of course has a great cast for that. The movie is well cast, especially when considering that most of the actors who appear in this movie weren't being big stars yet at the time. This for instance goes for Chris Cooper and Matthew McConaughey. All of the actors did a great job in this movie and were given plenty of opportunity to shine in this one. The movie at first truly feels like a Coen-brothers movie and it maintains this sort of feeling and style pretty much throughout the entire movie but it's being a bit more drama than comedy orientated. I actually do believe that if the Coen-brothers directed this movie it would had been a far better known was, as well as a better one I feel. The movie could had used some humor and entertainment in at times, since the right type of story and characters were definitely there for it. But oh well, the movie was going for a different approach and it still is for most part being successful with it as well. It simply great, little and simple movie to watch and there is also no good reason why you shouldn't! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inept plot, however well-meaning the story may be...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know I'm in the vast minority here, but I wasn't too impressed with this film. I think the problem was that too many of the subplots seemed incongruous, and frankly, uninteresting. I would have preferred it if the movie stuck to Chris Cooper's character. I was also expecting more Michael "Mchonohay", maybe if the film had been 1 half set in the present with the Sheriff and then the other half set in the past. Instead we get a bunch of stories about different people of the town that is meant to represent some sort of portrait of America, but they don't interlock the way 'Crash', 'Babel', 'Nashville', or other films do. It's a film trying to be ensemble when it doesn't need to. It probably would have worked better as a TV show, as too many of the loose threads lack that satisfying cohesiveness that a film should offer. The relationship between Sam and Pilar is also quite strange, and by the end, rather off-putting. In addition, the revelation about their past seems completely out of left field and of no relation to the central aspect of the story... or maybe it does in a weird sort of way. Either way, I feel that Sayles script is a little too 1990s PC for my tastes. Much of the moralizing between the characters (save for one brilliant scene outside a Mexican gas station) feels like something out of Schoolhouse Rock. Additionally, I thought the 'who-dunnit' murder plot was rather straightforward. Seeing Kristofferson's evil was entertaining, but I would have expected a bigger reveal or a more interesting resolution to his story. Maybe I was just let down by all the hype. I gave it a 6/10. I definitely would have felt as if I wasted my time if I'd paid money to see it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's not like there's a line between the good people and the bad people. It is not like you're one or the other.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lone Star is written and directed by John Sayles. It stars Chris Cooper, Joe Morton, Stephen J. Lang, Stephen Mendillo, Elizabeth Pe&ntilde;a and Kris Kristofferson. Music is scored by Mason Daring and cinematography by Stuart Dryburgh. The small Texas town of Rio County is rocked when a human skeleton is found in the sand and a Rio County Sheriff's badge found near by. The evidence points to it being the body of one time Sheriff Charlie Wade, a vile man who bullied the town for gratification and who one day just disappeared. Current Sheriff Sam Deeds begins investigating, knowing full well that there's a good chance the murderer could have be his own father, Buddy, who was known to have stood up to Wade with some hostile conviction. A hugely enjoyable pulpy mystery that's given a cunning make over by the talented Sayles. The who done it question at the film's core is merely one ingredient in this particular stew, this deals in themes such as violence, racism and family strife, the impact of lawmen on one small town, spread out across two generations. All the characters are interesting and well delineated, the dialogue as part of a non-linear narrative is precise and telling, while Sayles proves to be a stylistic craftsman by presenting two scenes 40 years apart within the same shot. A morality tale of some substance, with cast performances to match, it's a film sure to reward more with each viewing. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Stretch Of Road Runs Between Nowhere And Not Much Else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Deeds is the son of a late but much beloved Texas county sheriff who has inherited his father's job. But when a body is dug up from forty years ago and Sam investigates he discovers his father's illustrious past contains some dark and painful secrets ... This Texican murder mystery is one of Sayles' many beautifully constructed and densely populated character dramas (see also City Of Hope and Sunshine State) where, as with so much of his work, every single person is interesting, thoughtful and fully-rounded. This film is also a beautiful example of how to elegantly switch a narrative back and forward through two different eras, both visually through lovely little panning shots which dip in and out of time, and plot-wise as gradually the gauze covering the complex relationships is slowly lifted to reveal what has made the characters who they are. This is immensely satisfying as the pieces fit together, delicately played by a sensational ensemble cast who understand exactly what the story is trying to achieve. Cooper and Pe&ntilde;a are both superb as the middle-aged leads, both working county jobs, both struggling to find any meaning to their lives, both unable to move on from a fateful past together. The older actors steal the show with irascible wit, and pragmatism and regret written in equal measure on their faces - Canada in particular is outstanding - and Morton is terrific as ever in one of many parts for Sayles as the no-nonsense army man forced to embrace the tenderness he has long considered a weakness. Perhaps the casting masterstroke though is country legend Kristofferson as the thoroughly evil ghost from the past, whose violent brand of personal justice is horrifyingly plausible. Full of poignant moments, clever misdirection, evocative locations, heartfelt performances and funny lines (when Sam is headed to Mexico and tells a colleague he's going to "the other side", the response is "Republicans ?"), with a fine story and a great ending, this is high quality drama all the way. Shot in the beautiful south-western Texas border cities of Del Rio, Eagle Pass and Laredo.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris and Kris....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tim Kidner (tim@kidnerpix.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Cooper and Kris Kristofferson respectively, play two Mexican border sheriffs in John Sayle's excellent movie, but one is dead and the other is very much alive. This is a brooding, simmering and multi-layered drama of the highest order. The pacing is quite superb, unfolding like a great novel and keeps one quietly riveted for all of its two & a quarter hours. The characters are all so well rounded, their persona's so completely but subtly explored that one lives in and breathes every scene. Watching again on BBC2, after several year's gap, it still smacks of being totally relevant and up to date. Wrapped up within its celluloid binding is a tale of every family nuance, racial bigotry and human thought and emotion that a Chekov might. The soundtrack, too, is wonderfully eclectic and fitting. The plot is involved, but easy to follow, and never patronising in its assumptions. Other reviewers have explored it further than I'm going to and I'm simply reinforcing their voices and opinions and say that Lone Star is a must-see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just fantastic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elexigente48
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my top 20 movies of all time. After 3 viewings this feature just keeps getting better. This movie has a most unusual depth and diversity of characters and cultures that spans many generations (at times back into 19th century history), the only film I can think of that comes close is "Gone with the Wind." The crime scene investigation is only the outermost layer of the onion. It is a metaphor for one man's quest for Truth in a deeply flawed human world that strongly prefers myths. The movie is an exploration of the inexorable individual, generational, cultural, and racial baggage that haunts our mortal existence. It is about the human connections that transcend imagined and ever-changing boundaries. The school PTA meeting scene is not an irrelevant tangent. It is an encapsulation of this central underlying theme. When the white man dances with the Hispanic woman in a Mexican restaurant in Texas to an Ivory Joe Hunter rhythm and blues song sung in Spanish by Freddy Fender you should get the picture! This film is a rich tapestry that can fairly be called "Shakesperian." In classic form, the multiple layers of mythologies are slowly revealed to be solace from the boundless tragedy of human truths. This is a must see film about the threads of humanity that link (and separate) us all across many generations. Strongly recommended. Don't miss it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You are not alone, "Lone Star"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    setiaselalu-setiawan8
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a complex movie, for sure. And i like it because of that. I watch this movie twice. At my first watch, i thought the movie is an okay, i rated it 6/10. But, it made me think, how could a movie this good is an okay for me? So, I decided to watch it again last night. And, ..... wow!!! The acting, the cinematography, the screenplay(the best part from this movie, i guess), and score match together like it made by heaven. It has more than one messages, but don't worry . John Sayles(Director) invited us in a believable way. In my opinion, the twist is one of the best. Bravo!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too many characters, too much dialog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wlee08
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At the risk of sounding like the music critic in the movie Amadeus, who referred to Mozart's music as having "too many notes", I'm inclined to judge this movie as having too much of everything: US-Mexican relations, racism, in depth family histories, US military policies, mixed-race relationships, lost love, Freudian father relationships,...it just goes on and on and on. The dialog is also excessive, with a lot of it sounding like characters from the show "Law and Order". Although there were a few really good/powerful scenes, I felt many scenes were hard to follow along with - making the movie itself very convoluted. (Its been 15 years since its release and nobody has written an IMDb synopsis. Think about it.) I think a lot of the dialog went over my head for several reasons. For one, the sound quality seemed poor (but this could be my TV), the accents made it difficult too. And I might have just stopped caring about every single sentence. It seemed like every character in the movie was named "Buddy", which didn't help either. Anyways, I'm willing to accept partial responsibility for not watching this with 115% concentration. Maybe I'll watch it again someday.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forget the Alamo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paul2001sw-1 (paul2001sw@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this Texas detective story, a sheriff finds himself investigating the past of his own father, a man who was also his predecessor as sheriff, and a local hero everywhere except in his own household. The characters may be slow-moving and tight-lipped out of habit, but the ambiguity of their feelings is plain, and a strength of this drama, as is the way the plot weaves in many aspects of life in a border town. Perhaps some aspects of the way that town life is portrayed are a little too stylised, a little anachronistic, the reality of Mexican-American relations shown through the lens of the traditional western: but but film stays consistently within the world it has created. In terms of overall mood, there are elements that resemble the later 'No Country For Old Men', but without that movie's fall-back psychopath-driven plot, it offers a more interesting and ultimately humane vision of south Texas life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very noir...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anything I found this one a little too complex; there were several threads that seemed totally unrelated to the main thrust of the story. It's also, I felt, a little too long; the filmmakers are asking quite a lot for an audience to concentrate for two hours and fifteen minutes. It is slow paced, but I didn't particularly mind that; I'm used to the noir style and it is usually quite a slow burner. Some great performances with Chris Cooper coping well with the leading role and Kris Kristofferson playing the villain of the peace with gusto. Also we have Elizabeth Pe&ntilde;a, who did an excellent job as the female lead and a small part for Matthew McConaughey as Buddy Deeds. Although it does have its problems I still found it an excellent watch; definitely one to look out for for all you noir fans out there. SteelMonster's verdict: RECOMMENDED My score: 7.5/10. You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A hidden gem.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never thought I would see Matthew McConaughey playing Chris Cooper's farther! But yes, don't worry. It has to do with the simple fact that this movie keeps switching back and forth between present time and the past. With the use of flashback it slowly starts to become more apparent what happened 40-years before a skeleton got dug up, somewhere in the Texas desert. Lots of different story lines and characters end up getting intertwined but luckily the movie never becomes a messy or confusing one. It's actually a nice thing the movie has so many different characters in it, with each their own thing happening. It makes the movie, that otherwise probably would had been kind of slow, one that has always something happening in it and never becomes dull or a drag. You could actually say that the movie thrives on its characters. Everything that is happening and going on in this movie is due to them. They makes things interesting, as basically all of them need to come on terms with themselves and their past. This really ain't no ordinary murder mystery but more of a character-piece instead! And the movie of course has a great cast for that. The movie is well cast, especially when considering that most of the actors who appear in this movie weren't being big stars yet at the time. This for instance goes for Chris Cooper and Matthew McConaughey. All of the actors did a great job in this movie and were given plenty of opportunity to shine in this one. The movie at first truly feels like a Coen-brothers movie and it maintains this sort of feeling and style pretty much throughout the entire movie but it's being a bit more drama than comedy orientated. I actually do believe that if the Coen-brothers directed this movie it would had been a far better known was, as well as a better one I feel. The movie could had used some humor and entertainment in at times, since the right type of story and characters were definitely there for it. But oh well, the movie was going for a different approach and it still is for most part being successful with it as well. It simply great, little and simple movie to watch and there is also no good reason why you shouldn't! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inept plot, however well-meaning the story may be...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know I'm in the vast minority here, but I wasn't too impressed with this film. I think the problem was that too many of the subplots seemed incongruous, and frankly, uninteresting. I would have preferred it if the movie stuck to Chris Cooper's character. I was also expecting more Michael "Mchonohay", maybe if the film had been 1 half set in the present with the Sheriff and then the other half set in the past. Instead we get a bunch of stories about different people of the town that is meant to represent some sort of portrait of America, but they don't interlock the way 'Crash', 'Babel', 'Nashville', or other films do. It's a film trying to be ensemble when it doesn't need to. It probably would have worked better as a TV show, as too many of the loose threads lack that satisfying cohesiveness that a film should offer. The relationship between Sam and Pilar is also quite strange, and by the end, rather off-putting. In addition, the revelation about their past seems completely out of left field and of no relation to the central aspect of the story... or maybe it does in a weird sort of way. Either way, I feel that Sayles script is a little too 1990s PC for my tastes. Much of the moralizing between the characters (save for one brilliant scene outside a Mexican gas station) feels like something out of Schoolhouse Rock. Additionally, I thought the 'who-dunnit' murder plot was rather straightforward. Seeing Kristofferson's evil was entertaining, but I would have expected a bigger reveal or a more interesting resolution to his story. Maybe I was just let down by all the hype. I gave it a 6/10. I definitely would have felt as if I wasted my time if I'd paid money to see it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's not like there's a line between the good people and the bad people. It is not like you're one or the other.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lone Star is written and directed by John Sayles. It stars Chris Cooper, Joe Morton, Stephen J. Lang, Stephen Mendillo, Elizabeth Pe&ntilde;a and Kris Kristofferson. Music is scored by Mason Daring and cinematography by Stuart Dryburgh. The small Texas town of Rio County is rocked when a human skeleton is found in the sand and a Rio County Sheriff's badge found near by. The evidence points to it being the body of one time Sheriff Charlie Wade, a vile man who bullied the town for gratification and who one day just disappeared. Current Sheriff Sam Deeds begins investigating, knowing full well that there's a good chance the murderer could have be his own father, Buddy, who was known to have stood up to Wade with some hostile conviction. A hugely enjoyable pulpy mystery that's given a cunning make over by the talented Sayles. The who done it question at the film's core is merely one ingredient in this particular stew, this deals in themes such as violence, racism and family strife, the impact of lawmen on one small town, spread out across two generations. All the characters are interesting and well delineated, the dialogue as part of a non-linear narrative is precise and telling, while Sayles proves to be a stylistic craftsman by presenting two scenes 40 years apart within the same shot. A morality tale of some substance, with cast performances to match, it's a film sure to reward more with each viewing. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Stretch Of Road Runs Between Nowhere And Not Much Else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Deeds is the son of a late but much beloved Texas county sheriff who has inherited his father's job. But when a body is dug up from forty years ago and Sam investigates he discovers his father's illustrious past contains some dark and painful secrets ... This Texican murder mystery is one of Sayles' many beautifully constructed and densely populated character dramas (see also City Of Hope and Sunshine State) where, as with so much of his work, every single person is interesting, thoughtful and fully-rounded. This film is also a beautiful example of how to elegantly switch a narrative back and forward through two different eras, both visually through lovely little panning shots which dip in and out of time, and plot-wise as gradually the gauze covering the complex relationships is slowly lifted to reveal what has made the characters who they are. This is immensely satisfying as the pieces fit together, delicately played by a sensational ensemble cast who understand exactly what the story is trying to achieve. Cooper and Pe&ntilde;a are both superb as the middle-aged leads, both working county jobs, both struggling to find any meaning to their lives, both unable to move on from a fateful past together. The older actors steal the show with irascible wit, and pragmatism and regret written in equal measure on their faces - Canada in particular is outstanding - and Morton is terrific as ever in one of many parts for Sayles as the no-nonsense army man forced to embrace the tenderness he has long considered a weakness. Perhaps the casting masterstroke though is country legend Kristofferson as the thoroughly evil ghost from the past, whose violent brand of personal justice is horrifyingly plausible. Full of poignant moments, clever misdirection, evocative locations, heartfelt performances and funny lines (when Sam is headed to Mexico and tells a colleague he's going to "the other side", the response is "Republicans ?"), with a fine story and a great ending, this is high quality drama all the way. Shot in the beautiful south-western Texas border cities of Del Rio, Eagle Pass and Laredo.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris and Kris....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tim Kidner (tim@kidnerpix.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Cooper and Kris Kristofferson respectively, play two Mexican border sheriffs in John Sayle's excellent movie, but one is dead and the other is very much alive. This is a brooding, simmering and multi-layered drama of the highest order. The pacing is quite superb, unfolding like a great novel and keeps one quietly riveted for all of its two & a quarter hours. The characters are all so well rounded, their persona's so completely but subtly explored that one lives in and breathes every scene. Watching again on BBC2, after several year's gap, it still smacks of being totally relevant and up to date. Wrapped up within its celluloid binding is a tale of every family nuance, racial bigotry and human thought and emotion that a Chekov might. The soundtrack, too, is wonderfully eclectic and fitting. The plot is involved, but easy to follow, and never patronising in its assumptions. Other reviewers have explored it further than I'm going to and I'm simply reinforcing their voices and opinions and say that Lone Star is a must-see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just fantastic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elexigente48
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my top 20 movies of all time. After 3 viewings this feature just keeps getting better. This movie has a most unusual depth and diversity of characters and cultures that spans many generations (at times back into 19th century history), the only film I can think of that comes close is "Gone with the Wind." The crime scene investigation is only the outermost layer of the onion. It is a metaphor for one man's quest for Truth in a deeply flawed human world that strongly prefers myths. The movie is an exploration of the inexorable individual, generational, cultural, and racial baggage that haunts our mortal existence. It is about the human connections that transcend imagined and ever-changing boundaries. The school PTA meeting scene is not an irrelevant tangent. It is an encapsulation of this central underlying theme. When the white man dances with the Hispanic woman in a Mexican restaurant in Texas to an Ivory Joe Hunter rhythm and blues song sung in Spanish by Freddy Fender you should get the picture! This film is a rich tapestry that can fairly be called "Shakesperian." In classic form, the multiple layers of mythologies are slowly revealed to be solace from the boundless tragedy of human truths. This is a must see film about the threads of humanity that link (and separate) us all across many generations. Strongly recommended. Don't miss it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You are not alone, "Lone Star"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    setiaselalu-setiawan8
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a complex movie, for sure. And i like it because of that. I watch this movie twice. At my first watch, i thought the movie is an okay, i rated it 6/10. But, it made me think, how could a movie this good is an okay for me? So, I decided to watch it again last night. And, ..... wow!!! The acting, the cinematography, the screenplay(the best part from this movie, i guess), and score match together like it made by heaven. It has more than one messages, but don't worry . John Sayles(Director) invited us in a believable way. In my opinion, the twist is one of the best. Bravo!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too many characters, too much dialog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wlee08
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At the risk of sounding like the music critic in the movie Amadeus, who referred to Mozart's music as having "too many notes", I'm inclined to judge this movie as having too much of everything: US-Mexican relations, racism, in depth family histories, US military policies, mixed-race relationships, lost love, Freudian father relationships,...it just goes on and on and on. The dialog is also excessive, with a lot of it sounding like characters from the show "Law and Order". Although there were a few really good/powerful scenes, I felt many scenes were hard to follow along with - making the movie itself very convoluted. (Its been 15 years since its release and nobody has written an IMDb synopsis. Think about it.) I think a lot of the dialog went over my head for several reasons. For one, the sound quality seemed poor (but this could be my TV), the accents made it difficult too. And I might have just stopped caring about every single sentence. It seemed like every character in the movie was named "Buddy", which didn't help either. Anyways, I'm willing to accept partial responsibility for not watching this with 115% concentration. Maybe I'll watch it again someday.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forget the Alamo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paul2001sw-1 (paul2001sw@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this Texas detective story, a sheriff finds himself investigating the past of his own father, a man who was also his predecessor as sheriff, and a local hero everywhere except in his own household. The characters may be slow-moving and tight-lipped out of habit, but the ambiguity of their feelings is plain, and a strength of this drama, as is the way the plot weaves in many aspects of life in a border town. Perhaps some aspects of the way that town life is portrayed are a little too stylised, a little anachronistic, the reality of Mexican-American relations shown through the lens of the traditional western: but but film stays consistently within the world it has created. In terms of overall mood, there are elements that resemble the later 'No Country For Old Men', but without that movie's fall-back psychopath-driven plot, it offers a more interesting and ultimately humane vision of south Texas life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very noir...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anything I found this one a little too complex; there were several threads that seemed totally unrelated to the main thrust of the story. It's also, I felt, a little too long; the filmmakers are asking quite a lot for an audience to concentrate for two hours and fifteen minutes. It is slow paced, but I didn't particularly mind that; I'm used to the noir style and it is usually quite a slow burner. Some great performances with Chris Cooper coping well with the leading role and Kris Kristofferson playing the villain of the peace with gusto. Also we have Elizabeth Pe&ntilde;a, who did an excellent job as the female lead and a small part for Matthew McConaughey as Buddy Deeds. Although it does have its problems I still found it an excellent watch; definitely one to look out for for all you noir fans out there. SteelMonster's verdict: RECOMMENDED My score: 7.5/10. You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A hidden gem.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never thought I would see Matthew McConaughey playing Chris Cooper's farther! But yes, don't worry. It has to do with the simple fact that this movie keeps switching back and forth between present time and the past. With the use of flashback it slowly starts to become more apparent what happened 40-years before a skeleton got dug up, somewhere in the Texas desert. Lots of different story lines and characters end up getting intertwined but luckily the movie never becomes a messy or confusing one. It's actually a nice thing the movie has so many different characters in it, with each their own thing happening. It makes the movie, that otherwise probably would had been kind of slow, one that has always something happening in it and never becomes dull or a drag. You could actually say that the movie thrives on its characters. Everything that is happening and going on in this movie is due to them. They makes things interesting, as basically all of them need to come on terms with themselves and their past. This really ain't no ordinary murder mystery but more of a character-piece instead! And the movie of course has a great cast for that. The movie is well cast, especially when considering that most of the actors who appear in this movie weren't being big stars yet at the time. This for instance goes for Chris Cooper and Matthew McConaughey. All of the actors did a great job in this movie and were given plenty of opportunity to shine in this one. The movie at first truly feels like a Coen-brothers movie and it maintains this sort of feeling and style pretty much throughout the entire movie but it's being a bit more drama than comedy orientated. I actually do believe that if the Coen-brothers directed this movie it would had been a far better known was, as well as a better one I feel. The movie could had used some humor and entertainment in at times, since the right type of story and characters were definitely there for it. But oh well, the movie was going for a different approach and it still is for most part being successful with it as well. It simply great, little and simple movie to watch and there is also no good reason why you shouldn't! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inept plot, however well-meaning the story may be...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know I'm in the vast minority here, but I wasn't too impressed with this film. I think the problem was that too many of the subplots seemed incongruous, and frankly, uninteresting. I would have preferred it if the movie stuck to Chris Cooper's character. I was also expecting more Michael "Mchonohay", maybe if the film had been 1 half set in the present with the Sheriff and then the other half set in the past. Instead we get a bunch of stories about different people of the town that is meant to represent some sort of portrait of America, but they don't interlock the way 'Crash', 'Babel', 'Nashville', or other films do. It's a film trying to be ensemble when it doesn't need to. It probably would have worked better as a TV show, as too many of the loose threads lack that satisfying cohesiveness that a film should offer. The relationship between Sam and Pilar is also quite strange, and by the end, rather off-putting. In addition, the revelation about their past seems completely out of left field and of no relation to the central aspect of the story... or maybe it does in a weird sort of way. Either way, I feel that Sayles script is a little too 1990s PC for my tastes. Much of the moralizing between the characters (save for one brilliant scene outside a Mexican gas station) feels like something out of Schoolhouse Rock. Additionally, I thought the 'who-dunnit' murder plot was rather straightforward. Seeing Kristofferson's evil was entertaining, but I would have expected a bigger reveal or a more interesting resolution to his story. Maybe I was just let down by all the hype. I gave it a 6/10. I definitely would have felt as if I wasted my time if I'd paid money to see it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's not like there's a line between the good people and the bad people. It is not like you're one or the other.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lone Star is written and directed by John Sayles. It stars Chris Cooper, Joe Morton, Stephen J. Lang, Stephen Mendillo, Elizabeth Pe&ntilde;a and Kris Kristofferson. Music is scored by Mason Daring and cinematography by Stuart Dryburgh. The small Texas town of Rio County is rocked when a human skeleton is found in the sand and a Rio County Sheriff's badge found near by. The evidence points to it being the body of one time Sheriff Charlie Wade, a vile man who bullied the town for gratification and who one day just disappeared. Current Sheriff Sam Deeds begins investigating, knowing full well that there's a good chance the murderer could have be his own father, Buddy, who was known to have stood up to Wade with some hostile conviction. A hugely enjoyable pulpy mystery that's given a cunning make over by the talented Sayles. The who done it question at the film's core is merely one ingredient in this particular stew, this deals in themes such as violence, racism and family strife, the impact of lawmen on one small town, spread out across two generations. All the characters are interesting and well delineated, the dialogue as part of a non-linear narrative is precise and telling, while Sayles proves to be a stylistic craftsman by presenting two scenes 40 years apart within the same shot. A morality tale of some substance, with cast performances to match, it's a film sure to reward more with each viewing. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Stretch Of Road Runs Between Nowhere And Not Much Else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Deeds is the son of a late but much beloved Texas county sheriff who has inherited his father's job. But when a body is dug up from forty years ago and Sam investigates he discovers his father's illustrious past contains some dark and painful secrets ... This Texican murder mystery is one of Sayles' many beautifully constructed and densely populated character dramas (see also City Of Hope and Sunshine State) where, as with so much of his work, every single person is interesting, thoughtful and fully-rounded. This film is also a beautiful example of how to elegantly switch a narrative back and forward through two different eras, both visually through lovely little panning shots which dip in and out of time, and plot-wise as gradually the gauze covering the complex relationships is slowly lifted to reveal what has made the characters who they are. This is immensely satisfying as the pieces fit together, delicately played by a sensational ensemble cast who understand exactly what the story is trying to achieve. Cooper and Pe&ntilde;a are both superb as the middle-aged leads, both working county jobs, both struggling to find any meaning to their lives, both unable to move on from a fateful past together. The older actors steal the show with irascible wit, and pragmatism and regret written in equal measure on their faces - Canada in particular is outstanding - and Morton is terrific as ever in one of many parts for Sayles as the no-nonsense army man forced to embrace the tenderness he has long considered a weakness. Perhaps the casting masterstroke though is country legend Kristofferson as the thoroughly evil ghost from the past, whose violent brand of personal justice is horrifyingly plausible. Full of poignant moments, clever misdirection, evocative locations, heartfelt performances and funny lines (when Sam is headed to Mexico and tells a colleague he's going to "the other side", the response is "Republicans ?"), with a fine story and a great ending, this is high quality drama all the way. Shot in the beautiful south-western Texas border cities of Del Rio, Eagle Pass and Laredo.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris and Kris....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tim Kidner (tim@kidnerpix.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Cooper and Kris Kristofferson respectively, play two Mexican border sheriffs in John Sayle's excellent movie, but one is dead and the other is very much alive. This is a brooding, simmering and multi-layered drama of the highest order. The pacing is quite superb, unfolding like a great novel and keeps one quietly riveted for all of its two & a quarter hours. The characters are all so well rounded, their persona's so completely but subtly explored that one lives in and breathes every scene. Watching again on BBC2, after several year's gap, it still smacks of being totally relevant and up to date. Wrapped up within its celluloid binding is a tale of every family nuance, racial bigotry and human thought and emotion that a Chekov might. The soundtrack, too, is wonderfully eclectic and fitting. The plot is involved, but easy to follow, and never patronising in its assumptions. Other reviewers have explored it further than I'm going to and I'm simply reinforcing their voices and opinions and say that Lone Star is a must-see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just fantastic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elexigente48
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my top 20 movies of all time. After 3 viewings this feature just keeps getting better. This movie has a most unusual depth and diversity of characters and cultures that spans many generations (at times back into 19th century history), the only film I can think of that comes close is "Gone with the Wind." The crime scene investigation is only the outermost layer of the onion. It is a metaphor for one man's quest for Truth in a deeply flawed human world that strongly prefers myths. The movie is an exploration of the inexorable individual, generational, cultural, and racial baggage that haunts our mortal existence. It is about the human connections that transcend imagined and ever-changing boundaries. The school PTA meeting scene is not an irrelevant tangent. It is an encapsulation of this central underlying theme. When the white man dances with the Hispanic woman in a Mexican restaurant in Texas to an Ivory Joe Hunter rhythm and blues song sung in Spanish by Freddy Fender you should get the picture! This film is a rich tapestry that can fairly be called "Shakesperian." In classic form, the multiple layers of mythologies are slowly revealed to be solace from the boundless tragedy of human truths. This is a must see film about the threads of humanity that link (and separate) us all across many generations. Strongly recommended. Don't miss it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You are not alone, "Lone Star"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    setiaselalu-setiawan8
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a complex movie, for sure. And i like it because of that. I watch this movie twice. At my first watch, i thought the movie is an okay, i rated it 6/10. But, it made me think, how could a movie this good is an okay for me? So, I decided to watch it again last night. And, ..... wow!!! The acting, the cinematography, the screenplay(the best part from this movie, i guess), and score match together like it made by heaven. It has more than one messages, but don't worry . John Sayles(Director) invited us in a believable way. In my opinion, the twist is one of the best. Bravo!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too many characters, too much dialog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wlee08
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At the risk of sounding like the music critic in the movie Amadeus, who referred to Mozart's music as having "too many notes", I'm inclined to judge this movie as having too much of everything: US-Mexican relations, racism, in depth family histories, US military policies, mixed-race relationships, lost love, Freudian father relationships,...it just goes on and on and on. The dialog is also excessive, with a lot of it sounding like characters from the show "Law and Order". Although there were a few really good/powerful scenes, I felt many scenes were hard to follow along with - making the movie itself very convoluted. (Its been 15 years since its release and nobody has written an IMDb synopsis. Think about it.) I think a lot of the dialog went over my head for several reasons. For one, the sound quality seemed poor (but this could be my TV), the accents made it difficult too. And I might have just stopped caring about every single sentence. It seemed like every character in the movie was named "Buddy", which didn't help either. Anyways, I'm willing to accept partial responsibility for not watching this with 115% concentration. Maybe I'll watch it again someday.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
