<filme>
 <id>
  1244
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119664
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Negociador
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Roper, a hostage negotiator catches a murderous bank robber after a blown heist. The bank robber escapes and immediately goes after the man who put him behind bars. The ending is played out... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Roper, a hostage negotiator catches a murderous bank robber after a blown heist. The bank robber escapes and immediately goes after the man who put him behind bars. The ending is played out with Roper and his partner McCall attempting to rescue Roper's kidnapped girlfriend. A major element in the plot is the relationship between Roper and his girlfriend.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   hostage
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hostage negotiator
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   chase
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   revenge
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   jewel thief
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Thomas Carter
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Randy Feldman
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Eddie Murphy
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Michael Rapaport
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kim Miyori
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In some ways average, other ways quite good.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashleybrownmedia
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For the first hour of this film all I could think of was how average it was, I even had an average review written in my head for it. However, there are certain scenes, thrills and aspects - e.g. the ending predicament that are actually pretty good and will throw you. Eddie Murphy plays a 'wisecracking' hostage negotiator, although tbh he's very much the 'serious' Eddie Murphy for most of the film. I prefer the fun Beverly Hills Cop guy, but there we go. There is a scene where he's talking about being in a thong and being seen by his mother's friends that is hilarious though. Plot-wise he basically gets on the wrong side of some nutter and his cousin and they conspire to make life hell for him and his English girlfriend. The female lead is a tad weak in this, and I must admit I've never ever heard of her (although I was 7 when this film came out - maybe she was big then) but she looked good - Carmen Ejogo she is. Michael Rapaport is in this as well, as an intelligent sniper who is paired up with Murphy. Now I thought, judging by the cover etc, this was gonna be a buddy cop movie but Rapaport (an actor I like) is underused really. Don't get me wrong he's in the film a fair bit but his character has next to no personality. All I learnt was he's polite, sharp, from the Swat team and is a sniper. That's it. The film could have been done without his character if they wanted to save whatever fee he commanded. Whoever plays Eddie Murphy and Carme Ejogo's dog is good in this though. Stellar, powerhouse performance reminded me of Hanks in The Green Mile or Orson Welles in Citizen Kane. So yeah, mixed bag really - there's hate for post-80s Murphy films sure, but this is one of the better ones. It's a solid watch (on netflix atm) and there's some good action and the bad guy is easy to hate, so there's a lot worse out there. I won't strongly recommend but I'll say it's worth a shot - you know what you're going to get.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a great eddie murphy movie, a throwback to 48 hrs and Beverly hills cop
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daworldismine
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i am a fan of eddie murphy when he is in the right vehicle's like 'coming to America' 'the nutty professor' and 'Beverly hills cop' but sometimes he makes some very bad movies like 'pluto nash' 'boomerang' and 'meet dave'. now metro is more like his older movies, raw, r rated action comedies, and its great, eddie murphy is very funny in this, and at times hes even quite serious, but the movie never loses its comedy, and at its core thats what this is, if i had to compare it to one eddie murphy film, it would have to be Beverly hills cop, the same sort of action and humour. the cast are grear and the action big and loud, its a great movie and i recommend to fans of eddie murphy and action films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not totally awful - Murphy takes a shot at semi-serious and just misses.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Metro Murphy plays a streetwise police negotiator in San Fransisco named Scott Roper, in fact the best negotiator on the force. Roper's track record in getting hostages out alive is the envy of his colleagues and allows him leeway with his superiors. Unfortunately the stress of the job meant that Roper became introverted and shut out everything around him, including his girlfriend Ronnie who ultimately left him when he started gambling heavily as an outlet. Enter new partner Kevin McCall (Michael Rappaport), a young rookie straight from training who despite being highly skilled is raw and un-streetwise  if that were a word. Metro has two good scenes and one decent character. The two good scenes are a long chase that takes place on the San Fransisco streets and uses their tram system to full advantage, the second such scene is a training montage that lasts maybe two minutes and allows Murphy the freedom to go a little wild by creating a made up criminal for McCall to negotiate with. The decent character I haven't touched on yet, but given that the film is about a hostage negotiator it seems fairly obvious that there need be someone for Roper to test his skills on. That someone is Michael Korda (Michael Wincott), a man with dark sunken eyes, the emaciated appearance of the undernourished and the gravelly voice of a chain smoker. His hard as nails, emotionless performance as a potentially insane, definitely dangerous Korda is thankfully lacking in hamminess or over-acting, but overflowing with menace and intensity. It is not the end of the world that the bad guy in a film is by far the best thing in it, but in an action comedy with not enough of either, where the bad guy in reality is the third or fourth banana it simply isn't good enough. The strength of Korda's characterisation and a fairly brutal development results in some genuine animosity between the pair, which makes the inevitable stand off near the end somewhat more bearable, even if it is laced with logic flaws and some mediocre action sequences. Ultimately Metro ended up only marginally better than A Vampire in Brooklyn, by trying to play against the 'typical' Eddie Murphy movie they managed to create a film only marginally different, but one lacking enough of anything to make it worthwhile. Final Rating  5 / 10. The perception of intensity, the illusion of humour and the delusion of adequacy. Eddie Murphy takes a stab at semi-serious and fails. I don't hate Metro, but aside from a cool villain there is nothing to love.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I just LOVED this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janai P Canada (Sidadressage)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm nor going to give any spoilers out, but this really was one of Eddie Murphy BEST roles! I only bought this one because of the two actors that I love are in it. Eddie & Michael Wincott. It really, for me was a Wincott buy. Being a woman I agree with the other member who said most women will find it boring. I'm not like most women who like film. I saw both Raider's and The Golden Child in the theaters 9-11 times. So that should tell you. I wish Murphy would do this type of quality again. Anyway, enough of my opinion. GOOD MOVIE!!! Fast paised, a few funny lines and. Murphy as well as Wincott was VERY strong. I love it when Wincott is a villain. He gives such a nasty SOB 'like' portrayal of the quintessential bad guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Die Hard as a Black Man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    arieliondotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a "Die Hard" movie with Eddie Murphy in the role of Bruce Willis. That sounds like a joke and that's the problem. Is it an action movie? Comedy? Comedy about an action movie? It keeps veering from one to another like one of the cars in the car chases. Eddie Murphy is a lot of things but no Bruce Willis. And the movie is always on the brink of being a parody rather than a straight action movie. There are screaming, helpless females (this is a 90's movie...those types of women aren't seen in movies these days), car chases & crashes, only very few intentional laughs. It's an anachronism but not a bad way to pass the time. It's Die Hard with a Black man. And it's A' ight...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Neked in Tahiti.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Scott Roper is a wise cracking hostage negotiator, he is however exceptionally good at his job. After bringing down a particularly nasty bank robber called Michael Korda, he sets about winning his old girlfriend back whilst breaking in a new partner, Kevin McCall. When Korda escapes from prison there is only one thing on his mind, revenge, can Roper outwit Korda once again?, and if so, at what cost?. There has always seemed to me to be something of a negative bias towards post 1980s Eddie Murphy {Roper} films, it appears that no matter what, nothing that comes close to his best 80s efforts will ever be deemed worthy. Now i'm not saying that Metro is a world beater, or even close to Beverly Hills Cop and Trading Places, but it's an accomplished thriller with classy bits of Murphy humour thrown in. It also boasts splendid support from Michael Rapaport as Roper's intelligent partner McCall, both men playing off each other to good effect, while Michael Wincott with his gravel voice used to full effect, is impressively devilish as the bad guy of the piece. Let down by a weak female lead in Carmen Ejogo, and certainly the familiarity of the genre loses the film any real sense of impending dread, but for a quick fix of nonsense entertainment on a blustery cold night, it's a more than OK viewing. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Routine cop action thriller.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Metro is set in San Francisco where Inspector Scott Roper (Eddie Murphy) works as a hostage negotiator, one night while questioning a suspect named Michael Korda (Michael Wincott) one of Roper's closest friends Lieutenant Sam Baffett (Art Evans) is brutally murdered. With a new partner named Kevin McCall (Michael Rapaport) to show the ropes too Roper becomes obsessed with tracking his friends killer down & eventually does so when he arrests Korda after he had robbed a jewellery store. However Korda wants revenge & targets Roper's girlfriend Veronica (Carmen Ejogo) when he breaks out of prison... Directed by Thomas Carter this run of the mill Hollywood action cop comedy thriller is an alright way to spend a couple of hours but isn't anything original or spectacular. The script by co-producer Randy Feldman includes every Hollywood comedy cop thriller clich&eacute;s you care to think of, there's the whole mismatched partner angle, there's a wise-cracking hot-shot lead cop character who plays by his own rules & seemingly does very little police work, there's the one-liners & comeback's, there's the disgruntled police Captain who gets annoyed a lot, there's a really nasty bad guy who kills someone close to said cop & thereby makes it personal, there's the whole vendetta thing that flows through the film & there's a typical climactic showdown in which the cop kills the bad guy & gets the girl. Yawn. There really isn't anything in Metro that any action fan wouldn't have seen before & I seriously doubt there's anything in Metro that the average person wouldn't have seen before either. At almost two hours in length the film goes on for too long & it's just all so predictable & routine but it is saved by some impressive big budget action set-pieces & a fairly fun performance by Murphy who has turned swearing into an art form. For the majority of the duration of Metro the film is unremarkable although it passes the time harmlessly enough but I will admit there are a few great action sequences in it. In particular there's a terrific part which starts with a jewellery story robbery, a spectacular car chase through San Francisco featuring a runaway tram & ending in some more car stunts & a stand off in a parking garage which lasts for a good fifteen or twenty minutes in total although I did wonder where all the other cops in San Francisco were. There's some more good car stunts & explosions at the end but how is Roper going to explain all the jewels he 'borrowed' to get his girlfriend back being blown to pieces in the truck along with Korda? Also doesn't Korda escape from prison a bit too easily? OK so he makes it into the laundry room but there are still plenty of locked doors & police guards to get past even at that point. There's some violence & plenty of bad language to help pass the time but it all felt like I had seen it many times before. With a supposed budget of about $55,000,000 Metro is well made with solid big budget Hollywood production values. The acting is alright, Murphy does his Beverly Hills Cop (1984) cop with attitude type thing & he comes out with a few amusing one-liners but his character is very thinly written & fleshed out. The only other cast members to stand out are Michael Wincott as Korda the bad guy & he puts in an intense performance & British actress Carmen Ejogo who I thought was terrible. Metro is a throughly routine & predictable comedy cop action thriller the likes of which we have all seen before & usually better, it's not the worst of it's kind & several impressive set-piece action scenes help a lot but it's not up there with the best of it's kind. Average at best but action film fans should still like it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mediocre crime thriller that has it's moments.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Panterken
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Randy Feldman, who worked as the writer and producer on this movie, has four theatrical releases on his belt, the other three being the painfully bad horror flick 'Hell Night', the Jean-Claude Van Damme vehicle 'Nowhere to Run' (which I have not seen but can only assume it's as bad as any other of Van Damme film) and the eighties cop flick 'Tango & Cash', which received some audience acclaim. To state 'Metro' is by far his most memorable attempt at a screenplay isn't really a compliment, it seems he always kept the 'screenplay writing for dummies' book by hand during his writing sessions. We have the typical hero-cop; underpaid, under-appreciated by his boss, personal problems galore,financial troubles to boost, a smirking sense of humor, and of course a personal investment in the investigation ('now it's personal :-)). So we have the good cop with a revenge motive, but the chase isn't enough to fill the runtime. No, we also are forced to suffer - surprise, surprise - the obligatory (but in this case unfortunately also clumsily set up) love interest played by a young Carmen Ejogo. Sure; she's very easy on the eyes but as an actress she's sub-par. Then we have a fellow cop, lifelessly portrayed by Art Evans, and it must be said the poor fellow's been typecast, his role in the script is mainly to be victimized(also see: Die Hard 2 for an almost identical role). His monotone delivery and robot-like autopilot acting certainly didn't lift this film to a higher level, neither did Denis Arndt's one-dimensional police chief, the villain whose dialog consisted primarily of grunting or the gross of the side-characters for that matter. They are mainly present for giving us some insight in our lead's personal life (and some perspective) and of course to pitch for Eddie Murphy's jokes. The only roles that still spring to mind as I recollect on the movie today are Michael Rapaport and Donal Logue, both competently playing their respective roles. Other clich&eacute;s for the fanatic clich&eacute;-spotters among you, the rain suddenly appearing when a tragic event happened: both when Murphy's friend is murdered, as when there's an attempted murder on his girlfriend. Speaking of which, there's one clich&eacute; scene to build up the tension before the attempt, where we see Ejogo in a shoulder-shot frame as she puts on perfume in front of a bathroom mirror. She opens and closes the mirror/cabinet two times, with tense music playing, as if any moment some creep will appear behind her (the best use of that sort of scene can be found at the end of 'Candyman'). The action scenes felt very standard. The soundtrack bugged me to a lesser degree, it really couldn't make up its mind. The other big flaws are an OD of love story, a waste of plot opportunities (a lot more tactical SWAT stuff would've been welcome) and a lack of funny scenes (especially with the cop partners). But it is precisely that humor that keeps 'Metro' from totally falling apart, I'll never be Murphy's biggest fan but as a comedian he's far from mediocre (although we don't see his best work in this movie). I did appreciate the way they threw us off track time after time: as to who (or what) Troy is, the restaurant scenes (with the implied marriage proposal) and the hostage negotiation training scene. Those scenes, and the opening hostage situation, made up 90% of the enjoyment level of 'metro' for me. In the end 'Metro' can be summed up as painfully (almost insultingly) mediocre but still enjoyable because of the humor involved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Although It's Nothing Special, Metro is a Solid Action Movie Regardless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    waiching liu
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Metro appears to be a low-budget action affair, which whilst it has nothing new to offer, shows us a different side to Eddie Murphy as an actor that we hadn't seen before in his previous films. People have in the past often compared this to Beverly Hills Cop 1, in terms of the fact that they are both your typical, run- of- the- mill cop movies, but the comparisons seem to come to an end when you compare that film to Metro, in terms of plot, character types and the fact that Eddie Murphy doesn't joke about as negotiator/cop Scott Roaper that often. Not like his predecessor, Axel Foley. Here, as Roaper he is much more serious and not as laid back in contrast to his most famous movie character. Metro plays out as a straight out action movie that isn't reliant on laughs, which in itself is no bad thing. One of the main problems that some of the audiences had, in regards to their expectations of Metro, was by assuming that it would be something similar on the lines of Beverly Hills Cop. It has its funny moments, but these are few and far between throughout the film, as the narrative in Metro is very much serious and the standard cop thriller we'd come to expect. Overall, Metro is not a bad effort and the action sequences are well executed. Murphy gives a surprising turn and performance as Roaper and thus it makes a change to see him in an almost completely non-comedic role, which he does well in. Not bad indeed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Over the top but fun comedy thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamiecostelo58
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy tries to act serious as well as funny as Detective Scott Roper, and he actually carries it off rather well. Wanting revenge for his partner's death, he's led on a dangerous cat-and-mouse game with Michael Wincott, who will not let him win easily... The main highlights of Metro are a thrilling car chase sequence and the explosive ending! This is not the best film I have ever seen, but Wincott is immensely good as criminal Korda, displaying an almost never-ending desire to bring Roper down, even if it means double murder.... Metro is a fast-paced thrilling (and funny) movie from start to finish containing many startling and cunning plots that may seem a little odd at first but smoothing out to a satisfactory conclusion. I can definitely understand why it was a huge success at the box-office: it is very enjoyable!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In some ways average, other ways quite good.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashleybrownmedia
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For the first hour of this film all I could think of was how average it was, I even had an average review written in my head for it. However, there are certain scenes, thrills and aspects - e.g. the ending predicament that are actually pretty good and will throw you. Eddie Murphy plays a 'wisecracking' hostage negotiator, although tbh he's very much the 'serious' Eddie Murphy for most of the film. I prefer the fun Beverly Hills Cop guy, but there we go. There is a scene where he's talking about being in a thong and being seen by his mother's friends that is hilarious though. Plot-wise he basically gets on the wrong side of some nutter and his cousin and they conspire to make life hell for him and his English girlfriend. The female lead is a tad weak in this, and I must admit I've never ever heard of her (although I was 7 when this film came out - maybe she was big then) but she looked good - Carmen Ejogo she is. Michael Rapaport is in this as well, as an intelligent sniper who is paired up with Murphy. Now I thought, judging by the cover etc, this was gonna be a buddy cop movie but Rapaport (an actor I like) is underused really. Don't get me wrong he's in the film a fair bit but his character has next to no personality. All I learnt was he's polite, sharp, from the Swat team and is a sniper. That's it. The film could have been done without his character if they wanted to save whatever fee he commanded. Whoever plays Eddie Murphy and Carme Ejogo's dog is good in this though. Stellar, powerhouse performance reminded me of Hanks in The Green Mile or Orson Welles in Citizen Kane. So yeah, mixed bag really - there's hate for post-80s Murphy films sure, but this is one of the better ones. It's a solid watch (on netflix atm) and there's some good action and the bad guy is easy to hate, so there's a lot worse out there. I won't strongly recommend but I'll say it's worth a shot - you know what you're going to get.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a great eddie murphy movie, a throwback to 48 hrs and Beverly hills cop
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daworldismine
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i am a fan of eddie murphy when he is in the right vehicle's like 'coming to America' 'the nutty professor' and 'Beverly hills cop' but sometimes he makes some very bad movies like 'pluto nash' 'boomerang' and 'meet dave'. now metro is more like his older movies, raw, r rated action comedies, and its great, eddie murphy is very funny in this, and at times hes even quite serious, but the movie never loses its comedy, and at its core thats what this is, if i had to compare it to one eddie murphy film, it would have to be Beverly hills cop, the same sort of action and humour. the cast are grear and the action big and loud, its a great movie and i recommend to fans of eddie murphy and action films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not totally awful - Murphy takes a shot at semi-serious and just misses.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Metro Murphy plays a streetwise police negotiator in San Fransisco named Scott Roper, in fact the best negotiator on the force. Roper's track record in getting hostages out alive is the envy of his colleagues and allows him leeway with his superiors. Unfortunately the stress of the job meant that Roper became introverted and shut out everything around him, including his girlfriend Ronnie who ultimately left him when he started gambling heavily as an outlet. Enter new partner Kevin McCall (Michael Rappaport), a young rookie straight from training who despite being highly skilled is raw and un-streetwise  if that were a word. Metro has two good scenes and one decent character. The two good scenes are a long chase that takes place on the San Fransisco streets and uses their tram system to full advantage, the second such scene is a training montage that lasts maybe two minutes and allows Murphy the freedom to go a little wild by creating a made up criminal for McCall to negotiate with. The decent character I haven't touched on yet, but given that the film is about a hostage negotiator it seems fairly obvious that there need be someone for Roper to test his skills on. That someone is Michael Korda (Michael Wincott), a man with dark sunken eyes, the emaciated appearance of the undernourished and the gravelly voice of a chain smoker. His hard as nails, emotionless performance as a potentially insane, definitely dangerous Korda is thankfully lacking in hamminess or over-acting, but overflowing with menace and intensity. It is not the end of the world that the bad guy in a film is by far the best thing in it, but in an action comedy with not enough of either, where the bad guy in reality is the third or fourth banana it simply isn't good enough. The strength of Korda's characterisation and a fairly brutal development results in some genuine animosity between the pair, which makes the inevitable stand off near the end somewhat more bearable, even if it is laced with logic flaws and some mediocre action sequences. Ultimately Metro ended up only marginally better than A Vampire in Brooklyn, by trying to play against the 'typical' Eddie Murphy movie they managed to create a film only marginally different, but one lacking enough of anything to make it worthwhile. Final Rating  5 / 10. The perception of intensity, the illusion of humour and the delusion of adequacy. Eddie Murphy takes a stab at semi-serious and fails. I don't hate Metro, but aside from a cool villain there is nothing to love.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I just LOVED this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janai P Canada (Sidadressage)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm nor going to give any spoilers out, but this really was one of Eddie Murphy BEST roles! I only bought this one because of the two actors that I love are in it. Eddie & Michael Wincott. It really, for me was a Wincott buy. Being a woman I agree with the other member who said most women will find it boring. I'm not like most women who like film. I saw both Raider's and The Golden Child in the theaters 9-11 times. So that should tell you. I wish Murphy would do this type of quality again. Anyway, enough of my opinion. GOOD MOVIE!!! Fast paised, a few funny lines and. Murphy as well as Wincott was VERY strong. I love it when Wincott is a villain. He gives such a nasty SOB 'like' portrayal of the quintessential bad guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Die Hard as a Black Man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    arieliondotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a "Die Hard" movie with Eddie Murphy in the role of Bruce Willis. That sounds like a joke and that's the problem. Is it an action movie? Comedy? Comedy about an action movie? It keeps veering from one to another like one of the cars in the car chases. Eddie Murphy is a lot of things but no Bruce Willis. And the movie is always on the brink of being a parody rather than a straight action movie. There are screaming, helpless females (this is a 90's movie...those types of women aren't seen in movies these days), car chases & crashes, only very few intentional laughs. It's an anachronism but not a bad way to pass the time. It's Die Hard with a Black man. And it's A' ight...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Neked in Tahiti.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Scott Roper is a wise cracking hostage negotiator, he is however exceptionally good at his job. After bringing down a particularly nasty bank robber called Michael Korda, he sets about winning his old girlfriend back whilst breaking in a new partner, Kevin McCall. When Korda escapes from prison there is only one thing on his mind, revenge, can Roper outwit Korda once again?, and if so, at what cost?. There has always seemed to me to be something of a negative bias towards post 1980s Eddie Murphy {Roper} films, it appears that no matter what, nothing that comes close to his best 80s efforts will ever be deemed worthy. Now i'm not saying that Metro is a world beater, or even close to Beverly Hills Cop and Trading Places, but it's an accomplished thriller with classy bits of Murphy humour thrown in. It also boasts splendid support from Michael Rapaport as Roper's intelligent partner McCall, both men playing off each other to good effect, while Michael Wincott with his gravel voice used to full effect, is impressively devilish as the bad guy of the piece. Let down by a weak female lead in Carmen Ejogo, and certainly the familiarity of the genre loses the film any real sense of impending dread, but for a quick fix of nonsense entertainment on a blustery cold night, it's a more than OK viewing. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Routine cop action thriller.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Metro is set in San Francisco where Inspector Scott Roper (Eddie Murphy) works as a hostage negotiator, one night while questioning a suspect named Michael Korda (Michael Wincott) one of Roper's closest friends Lieutenant Sam Baffett (Art Evans) is brutally murdered. With a new partner named Kevin McCall (Michael Rapaport) to show the ropes too Roper becomes obsessed with tracking his friends killer down & eventually does so when he arrests Korda after he had robbed a jewellery store. However Korda wants revenge & targets Roper's girlfriend Veronica (Carmen Ejogo) when he breaks out of prison... Directed by Thomas Carter this run of the mill Hollywood action cop comedy thriller is an alright way to spend a couple of hours but isn't anything original or spectacular. The script by co-producer Randy Feldman includes every Hollywood comedy cop thriller clich&eacute;s you care to think of, there's the whole mismatched partner angle, there's a wise-cracking hot-shot lead cop character who plays by his own rules & seemingly does very little police work, there's the one-liners & comeback's, there's the disgruntled police Captain who gets annoyed a lot, there's a really nasty bad guy who kills someone close to said cop & thereby makes it personal, there's the whole vendetta thing that flows through the film & there's a typical climactic showdown in which the cop kills the bad guy & gets the girl. Yawn. There really isn't anything in Metro that any action fan wouldn't have seen before & I seriously doubt there's anything in Metro that the average person wouldn't have seen before either. At almost two hours in length the film goes on for too long & it's just all so predictable & routine but it is saved by some impressive big budget action set-pieces & a fairly fun performance by Murphy who has turned swearing into an art form. For the majority of the duration of Metro the film is unremarkable although it passes the time harmlessly enough but I will admit there are a few great action sequences in it. In particular there's a terrific part which starts with a jewellery story robbery, a spectacular car chase through San Francisco featuring a runaway tram & ending in some more car stunts & a stand off in a parking garage which lasts for a good fifteen or twenty minutes in total although I did wonder where all the other cops in San Francisco were. There's some more good car stunts & explosions at the end but how is Roper going to explain all the jewels he 'borrowed' to get his girlfriend back being blown to pieces in the truck along with Korda? Also doesn't Korda escape from prison a bit too easily? OK so he makes it into the laundry room but there are still plenty of locked doors & police guards to get past even at that point. There's some violence & plenty of bad language to help pass the time but it all felt like I had seen it many times before. With a supposed budget of about $55,000,000 Metro is well made with solid big budget Hollywood production values. The acting is alright, Murphy does his Beverly Hills Cop (1984) cop with attitude type thing & he comes out with a few amusing one-liners but his character is very thinly written & fleshed out. The only other cast members to stand out are Michael Wincott as Korda the bad guy & he puts in an intense performance & British actress Carmen Ejogo who I thought was terrible. Metro is a throughly routine & predictable comedy cop action thriller the likes of which we have all seen before & usually better, it's not the worst of it's kind & several impressive set-piece action scenes help a lot but it's not up there with the best of it's kind. Average at best but action film fans should still like it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mediocre crime thriller that has it's moments.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Panterken
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Randy Feldman, who worked as the writer and producer on this movie, has four theatrical releases on his belt, the other three being the painfully bad horror flick 'Hell Night', the Jean-Claude Van Damme vehicle 'Nowhere to Run' (which I have not seen but can only assume it's as bad as any other of Van Damme film) and the eighties cop flick 'Tango & Cash', which received some audience acclaim. To state 'Metro' is by far his most memorable attempt at a screenplay isn't really a compliment, it seems he always kept the 'screenplay writing for dummies' book by hand during his writing sessions. We have the typical hero-cop; underpaid, under-appreciated by his boss, personal problems galore,financial troubles to boost, a smirking sense of humor, and of course a personal investment in the investigation ('now it's personal :-)). So we have the good cop with a revenge motive, but the chase isn't enough to fill the runtime. No, we also are forced to suffer - surprise, surprise - the obligatory (but in this case unfortunately also clumsily set up) love interest played by a young Carmen Ejogo. Sure; she's very easy on the eyes but as an actress she's sub-par. Then we have a fellow cop, lifelessly portrayed by Art Evans, and it must be said the poor fellow's been typecast, his role in the script is mainly to be victimized(also see: Die Hard 2 for an almost identical role). His monotone delivery and robot-like autopilot acting certainly didn't lift this film to a higher level, neither did Denis Arndt's one-dimensional police chief, the villain whose dialog consisted primarily of grunting or the gross of the side-characters for that matter. They are mainly present for giving us some insight in our lead's personal life (and some perspective) and of course to pitch for Eddie Murphy's jokes. The only roles that still spring to mind as I recollect on the movie today are Michael Rapaport and Donal Logue, both competently playing their respective roles. Other clich&eacute;s for the fanatic clich&eacute;-spotters among you, the rain suddenly appearing when a tragic event happened: both when Murphy's friend is murdered, as when there's an attempted murder on his girlfriend. Speaking of which, there's one clich&eacute; scene to build up the tension before the attempt, where we see Ejogo in a shoulder-shot frame as she puts on perfume in front of a bathroom mirror. She opens and closes the mirror/cabinet two times, with tense music playing, as if any moment some creep will appear behind her (the best use of that sort of scene can be found at the end of 'Candyman'). The action scenes felt very standard. The soundtrack bugged me to a lesser degree, it really couldn't make up its mind. The other big flaws are an OD of love story, a waste of plot opportunities (a lot more tactical SWAT stuff would've been welcome) and a lack of funny scenes (especially with the cop partners). But it is precisely that humor that keeps 'Metro' from totally falling apart, I'll never be Murphy's biggest fan but as a comedian he's far from mediocre (although we don't see his best work in this movie). I did appreciate the way they threw us off track time after time: as to who (or what) Troy is, the restaurant scenes (with the implied marriage proposal) and the hostage negotiation training scene. Those scenes, and the opening hostage situation, made up 90% of the enjoyment level of 'metro' for me. In the end 'Metro' can be summed up as painfully (almost insultingly) mediocre but still enjoyable because of the humor involved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Although It's Nothing Special, Metro is a Solid Action Movie Regardless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    waiching liu
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Metro appears to be a low-budget action affair, which whilst it has nothing new to offer, shows us a different side to Eddie Murphy as an actor that we hadn't seen before in his previous films. People have in the past often compared this to Beverly Hills Cop 1, in terms of the fact that they are both your typical, run- of- the- mill cop movies, but the comparisons seem to come to an end when you compare that film to Metro, in terms of plot, character types and the fact that Eddie Murphy doesn't joke about as negotiator/cop Scott Roaper that often. Not like his predecessor, Axel Foley. Here, as Roaper he is much more serious and not as laid back in contrast to his most famous movie character. Metro plays out as a straight out action movie that isn't reliant on laughs, which in itself is no bad thing. One of the main problems that some of the audiences had, in regards to their expectations of Metro, was by assuming that it would be something similar on the lines of Beverly Hills Cop. It has its funny moments, but these are few and far between throughout the film, as the narrative in Metro is very much serious and the standard cop thriller we'd come to expect. Overall, Metro is not a bad effort and the action sequences are well executed. Murphy gives a surprising turn and performance as Roaper and thus it makes a change to see him in an almost completely non-comedic role, which he does well in. Not bad indeed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Over the top but fun comedy thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamiecostelo58
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy tries to act serious as well as funny as Detective Scott Roper, and he actually carries it off rather well. Wanting revenge for his partner's death, he's led on a dangerous cat-and-mouse game with Michael Wincott, who will not let him win easily... The main highlights of Metro are a thrilling car chase sequence and the explosive ending! This is not the best film I have ever seen, but Wincott is immensely good as criminal Korda, displaying an almost never-ending desire to bring Roper down, even if it means double murder.... Metro is a fast-paced thrilling (and funny) movie from start to finish containing many startling and cunning plots that may seem a little odd at first but smoothing out to a satisfactory conclusion. I can definitely understand why it was a huge success at the box-office: it is very enjoyable!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In some ways average, other ways quite good.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashleybrownmedia
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For the first hour of this film all I could think of was how average it was, I even had an average review written in my head for it. However, there are certain scenes, thrills and aspects - e.g. the ending predicament that are actually pretty good and will throw you. Eddie Murphy plays a 'wisecracking' hostage negotiator, although tbh he's very much the 'serious' Eddie Murphy for most of the film. I prefer the fun Beverly Hills Cop guy, but there we go. There is a scene where he's talking about being in a thong and being seen by his mother's friends that is hilarious though. Plot-wise he basically gets on the wrong side of some nutter and his cousin and they conspire to make life hell for him and his English girlfriend. The female lead is a tad weak in this, and I must admit I've never ever heard of her (although I was 7 when this film came out - maybe she was big then) but she looked good - Carmen Ejogo she is. Michael Rapaport is in this as well, as an intelligent sniper who is paired up with Murphy. Now I thought, judging by the cover etc, this was gonna be a buddy cop movie but Rapaport (an actor I like) is underused really. Don't get me wrong he's in the film a fair bit but his character has next to no personality. All I learnt was he's polite, sharp, from the Swat team and is a sniper. That's it. The film could have been done without his character if they wanted to save whatever fee he commanded. Whoever plays Eddie Murphy and Carme Ejogo's dog is good in this though. Stellar, powerhouse performance reminded me of Hanks in The Green Mile or Orson Welles in Citizen Kane. So yeah, mixed bag really - there's hate for post-80s Murphy films sure, but this is one of the better ones. It's a solid watch (on netflix atm) and there's some good action and the bad guy is easy to hate, so there's a lot worse out there. I won't strongly recommend but I'll say it's worth a shot - you know what you're going to get.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a great eddie murphy movie, a throwback to 48 hrs and Beverly hills cop
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daworldismine
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i am a fan of eddie murphy when he is in the right vehicle's like 'coming to America' 'the nutty professor' and 'Beverly hills cop' but sometimes he makes some very bad movies like 'pluto nash' 'boomerang' and 'meet dave'. now metro is more like his older movies, raw, r rated action comedies, and its great, eddie murphy is very funny in this, and at times hes even quite serious, but the movie never loses its comedy, and at its core thats what this is, if i had to compare it to one eddie murphy film, it would have to be Beverly hills cop, the same sort of action and humour. the cast are grear and the action big and loud, its a great movie and i recommend to fans of eddie murphy and action films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not totally awful - Murphy takes a shot at semi-serious and just misses.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Metro Murphy plays a streetwise police negotiator in San Fransisco named Scott Roper, in fact the best negotiator on the force. Roper's track record in getting hostages out alive is the envy of his colleagues and allows him leeway with his superiors. Unfortunately the stress of the job meant that Roper became introverted and shut out everything around him, including his girlfriend Ronnie who ultimately left him when he started gambling heavily as an outlet. Enter new partner Kevin McCall (Michael Rappaport), a young rookie straight from training who despite being highly skilled is raw and un-streetwise  if that were a word. Metro has two good scenes and one decent character. The two good scenes are a long chase that takes place on the San Fransisco streets and uses their tram system to full advantage, the second such scene is a training montage that lasts maybe two minutes and allows Murphy the freedom to go a little wild by creating a made up criminal for McCall to negotiate with. The decent character I haven't touched on yet, but given that the film is about a hostage negotiator it seems fairly obvious that there need be someone for Roper to test his skills on. That someone is Michael Korda (Michael Wincott), a man with dark sunken eyes, the emaciated appearance of the undernourished and the gravelly voice of a chain smoker. His hard as nails, emotionless performance as a potentially insane, definitely dangerous Korda is thankfully lacking in hamminess or over-acting, but overflowing with menace and intensity. It is not the end of the world that the bad guy in a film is by far the best thing in it, but in an action comedy with not enough of either, where the bad guy in reality is the third or fourth banana it simply isn't good enough. The strength of Korda's characterisation and a fairly brutal development results in some genuine animosity between the pair, which makes the inevitable stand off near the end somewhat more bearable, even if it is laced with logic flaws and some mediocre action sequences. Ultimately Metro ended up only marginally better than A Vampire in Brooklyn, by trying to play against the 'typical' Eddie Murphy movie they managed to create a film only marginally different, but one lacking enough of anything to make it worthwhile. Final Rating  5 / 10. The perception of intensity, the illusion of humour and the delusion of adequacy. Eddie Murphy takes a stab at semi-serious and fails. I don't hate Metro, but aside from a cool villain there is nothing to love.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I just LOVED this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janai P Canada (Sidadressage)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm nor going to give any spoilers out, but this really was one of Eddie Murphy BEST roles! I only bought this one because of the two actors that I love are in it. Eddie & Michael Wincott. It really, for me was a Wincott buy. Being a woman I agree with the other member who said most women will find it boring. I'm not like most women who like film. I saw both Raider's and The Golden Child in the theaters 9-11 times. So that should tell you. I wish Murphy would do this type of quality again. Anyway, enough of my opinion. GOOD MOVIE!!! Fast paised, a few funny lines and. Murphy as well as Wincott was VERY strong. I love it when Wincott is a villain. He gives such a nasty SOB 'like' portrayal of the quintessential bad guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Die Hard as a Black Man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    arieliondotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a "Die Hard" movie with Eddie Murphy in the role of Bruce Willis. That sounds like a joke and that's the problem. Is it an action movie? Comedy? Comedy about an action movie? It keeps veering from one to another like one of the cars in the car chases. Eddie Murphy is a lot of things but no Bruce Willis. And the movie is always on the brink of being a parody rather than a straight action movie. There are screaming, helpless females (this is a 90's movie...those types of women aren't seen in movies these days), car chases & crashes, only very few intentional laughs. It's an anachronism but not a bad way to pass the time. It's Die Hard with a Black man. And it's A' ight...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Neked in Tahiti.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Scott Roper is a wise cracking hostage negotiator, he is however exceptionally good at his job. After bringing down a particularly nasty bank robber called Michael Korda, he sets about winning his old girlfriend back whilst breaking in a new partner, Kevin McCall. When Korda escapes from prison there is only one thing on his mind, revenge, can Roper outwit Korda once again?, and if so, at what cost?. There has always seemed to me to be something of a negative bias towards post 1980s Eddie Murphy {Roper} films, it appears that no matter what, nothing that comes close to his best 80s efforts will ever be deemed worthy. Now i'm not saying that Metro is a world beater, or even close to Beverly Hills Cop and Trading Places, but it's an accomplished thriller with classy bits of Murphy humour thrown in. It also boasts splendid support from Michael Rapaport as Roper's intelligent partner McCall, both men playing off each other to good effect, while Michael Wincott with his gravel voice used to full effect, is impressively devilish as the bad guy of the piece. Let down by a weak female lead in Carmen Ejogo, and certainly the familiarity of the genre loses the film any real sense of impending dread, but for a quick fix of nonsense entertainment on a blustery cold night, it's a more than OK viewing. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Routine cop action thriller.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Metro is set in San Francisco where Inspector Scott Roper (Eddie Murphy) works as a hostage negotiator, one night while questioning a suspect named Michael Korda (Michael Wincott) one of Roper's closest friends Lieutenant Sam Baffett (Art Evans) is brutally murdered. With a new partner named Kevin McCall (Michael Rapaport) to show the ropes too Roper becomes obsessed with tracking his friends killer down & eventually does so when he arrests Korda after he had robbed a jewellery store. However Korda wants revenge & targets Roper's girlfriend Veronica (Carmen Ejogo) when he breaks out of prison... Directed by Thomas Carter this run of the mill Hollywood action cop comedy thriller is an alright way to spend a couple of hours but isn't anything original or spectacular. The script by co-producer Randy Feldman includes every Hollywood comedy cop thriller clich&eacute;s you care to think of, there's the whole mismatched partner angle, there's a wise-cracking hot-shot lead cop character who plays by his own rules & seemingly does very little police work, there's the one-liners & comeback's, there's the disgruntled police Captain who gets annoyed a lot, there's a really nasty bad guy who kills someone close to said cop & thereby makes it personal, there's the whole vendetta thing that flows through the film & there's a typical climactic showdown in which the cop kills the bad guy & gets the girl. Yawn. There really isn't anything in Metro that any action fan wouldn't have seen before & I seriously doubt there's anything in Metro that the average person wouldn't have seen before either. At almost two hours in length the film goes on for too long & it's just all so predictable & routine but it is saved by some impressive big budget action set-pieces & a fairly fun performance by Murphy who has turned swearing into an art form. For the majority of the duration of Metro the film is unremarkable although it passes the time harmlessly enough but I will admit there are a few great action sequences in it. In particular there's a terrific part which starts with a jewellery story robbery, a spectacular car chase through San Francisco featuring a runaway tram & ending in some more car stunts & a stand off in a parking garage which lasts for a good fifteen or twenty minutes in total although I did wonder where all the other cops in San Francisco were. There's some more good car stunts & explosions at the end but how is Roper going to explain all the jewels he 'borrowed' to get his girlfriend back being blown to pieces in the truck along with Korda? Also doesn't Korda escape from prison a bit too easily? OK so he makes it into the laundry room but there are still plenty of locked doors & police guards to get past even at that point. There's some violence & plenty of bad language to help pass the time but it all felt like I had seen it many times before. With a supposed budget of about $55,000,000 Metro is well made with solid big budget Hollywood production values. The acting is alright, Murphy does his Beverly Hills Cop (1984) cop with attitude type thing & he comes out with a few amusing one-liners but his character is very thinly written & fleshed out. The only other cast members to stand out are Michael Wincott as Korda the bad guy & he puts in an intense performance & British actress Carmen Ejogo who I thought was terrible. Metro is a throughly routine & predictable comedy cop action thriller the likes of which we have all seen before & usually better, it's not the worst of it's kind & several impressive set-piece action scenes help a lot but it's not up there with the best of it's kind. Average at best but action film fans should still like it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mediocre crime thriller that has it's moments.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Panterken
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Randy Feldman, who worked as the writer and producer on this movie, has four theatrical releases on his belt, the other three being the painfully bad horror flick 'Hell Night', the Jean-Claude Van Damme vehicle 'Nowhere to Run' (which I have not seen but can only assume it's as bad as any other of Van Damme film) and the eighties cop flick 'Tango & Cash', which received some audience acclaim. To state 'Metro' is by far his most memorable attempt at a screenplay isn't really a compliment, it seems he always kept the 'screenplay writing for dummies' book by hand during his writing sessions. We have the typical hero-cop; underpaid, under-appreciated by his boss, personal problems galore,financial troubles to boost, a smirking sense of humor, and of course a personal investment in the investigation ('now it's personal :-)). So we have the good cop with a revenge motive, but the chase isn't enough to fill the runtime. No, we also are forced to suffer - surprise, surprise - the obligatory (but in this case unfortunately also clumsily set up) love interest played by a young Carmen Ejogo. Sure; she's very easy on the eyes but as an actress she's sub-par. Then we have a fellow cop, lifelessly portrayed by Art Evans, and it must be said the poor fellow's been typecast, his role in the script is mainly to be victimized(also see: Die Hard 2 for an almost identical role). His monotone delivery and robot-like autopilot acting certainly didn't lift this film to a higher level, neither did Denis Arndt's one-dimensional police chief, the villain whose dialog consisted primarily of grunting or the gross of the side-characters for that matter. They are mainly present for giving us some insight in our lead's personal life (and some perspective) and of course to pitch for Eddie Murphy's jokes. The only roles that still spring to mind as I recollect on the movie today are Michael Rapaport and Donal Logue, both competently playing their respective roles. Other clich&eacute;s for the fanatic clich&eacute;-spotters among you, the rain suddenly appearing when a tragic event happened: both when Murphy's friend is murdered, as when there's an attempted murder on his girlfriend. Speaking of which, there's one clich&eacute; scene to build up the tension before the attempt, where we see Ejogo in a shoulder-shot frame as she puts on perfume in front of a bathroom mirror. She opens and closes the mirror/cabinet two times, with tense music playing, as if any moment some creep will appear behind her (the best use of that sort of scene can be found at the end of 'Candyman'). The action scenes felt very standard. The soundtrack bugged me to a lesser degree, it really couldn't make up its mind. The other big flaws are an OD of love story, a waste of plot opportunities (a lot more tactical SWAT stuff would've been welcome) and a lack of funny scenes (especially with the cop partners). But it is precisely that humor that keeps 'Metro' from totally falling apart, I'll never be Murphy's biggest fan but as a comedian he's far from mediocre (although we don't see his best work in this movie). I did appreciate the way they threw us off track time after time: as to who (or what) Troy is, the restaurant scenes (with the implied marriage proposal) and the hostage negotiation training scene. Those scenes, and the opening hostage situation, made up 90% of the enjoyment level of 'metro' for me. In the end 'Metro' can be summed up as painfully (almost insultingly) mediocre but still enjoyable because of the humor involved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Although It's Nothing Special, Metro is a Solid Action Movie Regardless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    waiching liu
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Metro appears to be a low-budget action affair, which whilst it has nothing new to offer, shows us a different side to Eddie Murphy as an actor that we hadn't seen before in his previous films. People have in the past often compared this to Beverly Hills Cop 1, in terms of the fact that they are both your typical, run- of- the- mill cop movies, but the comparisons seem to come to an end when you compare that film to Metro, in terms of plot, character types and the fact that Eddie Murphy doesn't joke about as negotiator/cop Scott Roaper that often. Not like his predecessor, Axel Foley. Here, as Roaper he is much more serious and not as laid back in contrast to his most famous movie character. Metro plays out as a straight out action movie that isn't reliant on laughs, which in itself is no bad thing. One of the main problems that some of the audiences had, in regards to their expectations of Metro, was by assuming that it would be something similar on the lines of Beverly Hills Cop. It has its funny moments, but these are few and far between throughout the film, as the narrative in Metro is very much serious and the standard cop thriller we'd come to expect. Overall, Metro is not a bad effort and the action sequences are well executed. Murphy gives a surprising turn and performance as Roaper and thus it makes a change to see him in an almost completely non-comedic role, which he does well in. Not bad indeed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Over the top but fun comedy thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamiecostelo58
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy tries to act serious as well as funny as Detective Scott Roper, and he actually carries it off rather well. Wanting revenge for his partner's death, he's led on a dangerous cat-and-mouse game with Michael Wincott, who will not let him win easily... The main highlights of Metro are a thrilling car chase sequence and the explosive ending! This is not the best film I have ever seen, but Wincott is immensely good as criminal Korda, displaying an almost never-ending desire to bring Roper down, even if it means double murder.... Metro is a fast-paced thrilling (and funny) movie from start to finish containing many startling and cunning plots that may seem a little odd at first but smoothing out to a satisfactory conclusion. I can definitely understand why it was a huge success at the box-office: it is very enjoyable!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In some ways average, other ways quite good.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashleybrownmedia
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For the first hour of this film all I could think of was how average it was, I even had an average review written in my head for it. However, there are certain scenes, thrills and aspects - e.g. the ending predicament that are actually pretty good and will throw you. Eddie Murphy plays a 'wisecracking' hostage negotiator, although tbh he's very much the 'serious' Eddie Murphy for most of the film. I prefer the fun Beverly Hills Cop guy, but there we go. There is a scene where he's talking about being in a thong and being seen by his mother's friends that is hilarious though. Plot-wise he basically gets on the wrong side of some nutter and his cousin and they conspire to make life hell for him and his English girlfriend. The female lead is a tad weak in this, and I must admit I've never ever heard of her (although I was 7 when this film came out - maybe she was big then) but she looked good - Carmen Ejogo she is. Michael Rapaport is in this as well, as an intelligent sniper who is paired up with Murphy. Now I thought, judging by the cover etc, this was gonna be a buddy cop movie but Rapaport (an actor I like) is underused really. Don't get me wrong he's in the film a fair bit but his character has next to no personality. All I learnt was he's polite, sharp, from the Swat team and is a sniper. That's it. The film could have been done without his character if they wanted to save whatever fee he commanded. Whoever plays Eddie Murphy and Carme Ejogo's dog is good in this though. Stellar, powerhouse performance reminded me of Hanks in The Green Mile or Orson Welles in Citizen Kane. So yeah, mixed bag really - there's hate for post-80s Murphy films sure, but this is one of the better ones. It's a solid watch (on netflix atm) and there's some good action and the bad guy is easy to hate, so there's a lot worse out there. I won't strongly recommend but I'll say it's worth a shot - you know what you're going to get.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a great eddie murphy movie, a throwback to 48 hrs and Beverly hills cop
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daworldismine
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i am a fan of eddie murphy when he is in the right vehicle's like 'coming to America' 'the nutty professor' and 'Beverly hills cop' but sometimes he makes some very bad movies like 'pluto nash' 'boomerang' and 'meet dave'. now metro is more like his older movies, raw, r rated action comedies, and its great, eddie murphy is very funny in this, and at times hes even quite serious, but the movie never loses its comedy, and at its core thats what this is, if i had to compare it to one eddie murphy film, it would have to be Beverly hills cop, the same sort of action and humour. the cast are grear and the action big and loud, its a great movie and i recommend to fans of eddie murphy and action films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not totally awful - Murphy takes a shot at semi-serious and just misses.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Metro Murphy plays a streetwise police negotiator in San Fransisco named Scott Roper, in fact the best negotiator on the force. Roper's track record in getting hostages out alive is the envy of his colleagues and allows him leeway with his superiors. Unfortunately the stress of the job meant that Roper became introverted and shut out everything around him, including his girlfriend Ronnie who ultimately left him when he started gambling heavily as an outlet. Enter new partner Kevin McCall (Michael Rappaport), a young rookie straight from training who despite being highly skilled is raw and un-streetwise  if that were a word. Metro has two good scenes and one decent character. The two good scenes are a long chase that takes place on the San Fransisco streets and uses their tram system to full advantage, the second such scene is a training montage that lasts maybe two minutes and allows Murphy the freedom to go a little wild by creating a made up criminal for McCall to negotiate with. The decent character I haven't touched on yet, but given that the film is about a hostage negotiator it seems fairly obvious that there need be someone for Roper to test his skills on. That someone is Michael Korda (Michael Wincott), a man with dark sunken eyes, the emaciated appearance of the undernourished and the gravelly voice of a chain smoker. His hard as nails, emotionless performance as a potentially insane, definitely dangerous Korda is thankfully lacking in hamminess or over-acting, but overflowing with menace and intensity. It is not the end of the world that the bad guy in a film is by far the best thing in it, but in an action comedy with not enough of either, where the bad guy in reality is the third or fourth banana it simply isn't good enough. The strength of Korda's characterisation and a fairly brutal development results in some genuine animosity between the pair, which makes the inevitable stand off near the end somewhat more bearable, even if it is laced with logic flaws and some mediocre action sequences. Ultimately Metro ended up only marginally better than A Vampire in Brooklyn, by trying to play against the 'typical' Eddie Murphy movie they managed to create a film only marginally different, but one lacking enough of anything to make it worthwhile. Final Rating  5 / 10. The perception of intensity, the illusion of humour and the delusion of adequacy. Eddie Murphy takes a stab at semi-serious and fails. I don't hate Metro, but aside from a cool villain there is nothing to love.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I just LOVED this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janai P Canada (Sidadressage)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm nor going to give any spoilers out, but this really was one of Eddie Murphy BEST roles! I only bought this one because of the two actors that I love are in it. Eddie & Michael Wincott. It really, for me was a Wincott buy. Being a woman I agree with the other member who said most women will find it boring. I'm not like most women who like film. I saw both Raider's and The Golden Child in the theaters 9-11 times. So that should tell you. I wish Murphy would do this type of quality again. Anyway, enough of my opinion. GOOD MOVIE!!! Fast paised, a few funny lines and. Murphy as well as Wincott was VERY strong. I love it when Wincott is a villain. He gives such a nasty SOB 'like' portrayal of the quintessential bad guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Die Hard as a Black Man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    arieliondotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a "Die Hard" movie with Eddie Murphy in the role of Bruce Willis. That sounds like a joke and that's the problem. Is it an action movie? Comedy? Comedy about an action movie? It keeps veering from one to another like one of the cars in the car chases. Eddie Murphy is a lot of things but no Bruce Willis. And the movie is always on the brink of being a parody rather than a straight action movie. There are screaming, helpless females (this is a 90's movie...those types of women aren't seen in movies these days), car chases & crashes, only very few intentional laughs. It's an anachronism but not a bad way to pass the time. It's Die Hard with a Black man. And it's A' ight...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Neked in Tahiti.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Scott Roper is a wise cracking hostage negotiator, he is however exceptionally good at his job. After bringing down a particularly nasty bank robber called Michael Korda, he sets about winning his old girlfriend back whilst breaking in a new partner, Kevin McCall. When Korda escapes from prison there is only one thing on his mind, revenge, can Roper outwit Korda once again?, and if so, at what cost?. There has always seemed to me to be something of a negative bias towards post 1980s Eddie Murphy {Roper} films, it appears that no matter what, nothing that comes close to his best 80s efforts will ever be deemed worthy. Now i'm not saying that Metro is a world beater, or even close to Beverly Hills Cop and Trading Places, but it's an accomplished thriller with classy bits of Murphy humour thrown in. It also boasts splendid support from Michael Rapaport as Roper's intelligent partner McCall, both men playing off each other to good effect, while Michael Wincott with his gravel voice used to full effect, is impressively devilish as the bad guy of the piece. Let down by a weak female lead in Carmen Ejogo, and certainly the familiarity of the genre loses the film any real sense of impending dread, but for a quick fix of nonsense entertainment on a blustery cold night, it's a more than OK viewing. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Routine cop action thriller.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Metro is set in San Francisco where Inspector Scott Roper (Eddie Murphy) works as a hostage negotiator, one night while questioning a suspect named Michael Korda (Michael Wincott) one of Roper's closest friends Lieutenant Sam Baffett (Art Evans) is brutally murdered. With a new partner named Kevin McCall (Michael Rapaport) to show the ropes too Roper becomes obsessed with tracking his friends killer down & eventually does so when he arrests Korda after he had robbed a jewellery store. However Korda wants revenge & targets Roper's girlfriend Veronica (Carmen Ejogo) when he breaks out of prison... Directed by Thomas Carter this run of the mill Hollywood action cop comedy thriller is an alright way to spend a couple of hours but isn't anything original or spectacular. The script by co-producer Randy Feldman includes every Hollywood comedy cop thriller clich&eacute;s you care to think of, there's the whole mismatched partner angle, there's a wise-cracking hot-shot lead cop character who plays by his own rules & seemingly does very little police work, there's the one-liners & comeback's, there's the disgruntled police Captain who gets annoyed a lot, there's a really nasty bad guy who kills someone close to said cop & thereby makes it personal, there's the whole vendetta thing that flows through the film & there's a typical climactic showdown in which the cop kills the bad guy & gets the girl. Yawn. There really isn't anything in Metro that any action fan wouldn't have seen before & I seriously doubt there's anything in Metro that the average person wouldn't have seen before either. At almost two hours in length the film goes on for too long & it's just all so predictable & routine but it is saved by some impressive big budget action set-pieces & a fairly fun performance by Murphy who has turned swearing into an art form. For the majority of the duration of Metro the film is unremarkable although it passes the time harmlessly enough but I will admit there are a few great action sequences in it. In particular there's a terrific part which starts with a jewellery story robbery, a spectacular car chase through San Francisco featuring a runaway tram & ending in some more car stunts & a stand off in a parking garage which lasts for a good fifteen or twenty minutes in total although I did wonder where all the other cops in San Francisco were. There's some more good car stunts & explosions at the end but how is Roper going to explain all the jewels he 'borrowed' to get his girlfriend back being blown to pieces in the truck along with Korda? Also doesn't Korda escape from prison a bit too easily? OK so he makes it into the laundry room but there are still plenty of locked doors & police guards to get past even at that point. There's some violence & plenty of bad language to help pass the time but it all felt like I had seen it many times before. With a supposed budget of about $55,000,000 Metro is well made with solid big budget Hollywood production values. The acting is alright, Murphy does his Beverly Hills Cop (1984) cop with attitude type thing & he comes out with a few amusing one-liners but his character is very thinly written & fleshed out. The only other cast members to stand out are Michael Wincott as Korda the bad guy & he puts in an intense performance & British actress Carmen Ejogo who I thought was terrible. Metro is a throughly routine & predictable comedy cop action thriller the likes of which we have all seen before & usually better, it's not the worst of it's kind & several impressive set-piece action scenes help a lot but it's not up there with the best of it's kind. Average at best but action film fans should still like it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mediocre crime thriller that has it's moments.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Panterken
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Randy Feldman, who worked as the writer and producer on this movie, has four theatrical releases on his belt, the other three being the painfully bad horror flick 'Hell Night', the Jean-Claude Van Damme vehicle 'Nowhere to Run' (which I have not seen but can only assume it's as bad as any other of Van Damme film) and the eighties cop flick 'Tango & Cash', which received some audience acclaim. To state 'Metro' is by far his most memorable attempt at a screenplay isn't really a compliment, it seems he always kept the 'screenplay writing for dummies' book by hand during his writing sessions. We have the typical hero-cop; underpaid, under-appreciated by his boss, personal problems galore,financial troubles to boost, a smirking sense of humor, and of course a personal investment in the investigation ('now it's personal :-)). So we have the good cop with a revenge motive, but the chase isn't enough to fill the runtime. No, we also are forced to suffer - surprise, surprise - the obligatory (but in this case unfortunately also clumsily set up) love interest played by a young Carmen Ejogo. Sure; she's very easy on the eyes but as an actress she's sub-par. Then we have a fellow cop, lifelessly portrayed by Art Evans, and it must be said the poor fellow's been typecast, his role in the script is mainly to be victimized(also see: Die Hard 2 for an almost identical role). His monotone delivery and robot-like autopilot acting certainly didn't lift this film to a higher level, neither did Denis Arndt's one-dimensional police chief, the villain whose dialog consisted primarily of grunting or the gross of the side-characters for that matter. They are mainly present for giving us some insight in our lead's personal life (and some perspective) and of course to pitch for Eddie Murphy's jokes. The only roles that still spring to mind as I recollect on the movie today are Michael Rapaport and Donal Logue, both competently playing their respective roles. Other clich&eacute;s for the fanatic clich&eacute;-spotters among you, the rain suddenly appearing when a tragic event happened: both when Murphy's friend is murdered, as when there's an attempted murder on his girlfriend. Speaking of which, there's one clich&eacute; scene to build up the tension before the attempt, where we see Ejogo in a shoulder-shot frame as she puts on perfume in front of a bathroom mirror. She opens and closes the mirror/cabinet two times, with tense music playing, as if any moment some creep will appear behind her (the best use of that sort of scene can be found at the end of 'Candyman'). The action scenes felt very standard. The soundtrack bugged me to a lesser degree, it really couldn't make up its mind. The other big flaws are an OD of love story, a waste of plot opportunities (a lot more tactical SWAT stuff would've been welcome) and a lack of funny scenes (especially with the cop partners). But it is precisely that humor that keeps 'Metro' from totally falling apart, I'll never be Murphy's biggest fan but as a comedian he's far from mediocre (although we don't see his best work in this movie). I did appreciate the way they threw us off track time after time: as to who (or what) Troy is, the restaurant scenes (with the implied marriage proposal) and the hostage negotiation training scene. Those scenes, and the opening hostage situation, made up 90% of the enjoyment level of 'metro' for me. In the end 'Metro' can be summed up as painfully (almost insultingly) mediocre but still enjoyable because of the humor involved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Although It's Nothing Special, Metro is a Solid Action Movie Regardless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    waiching liu
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Metro appears to be a low-budget action affair, which whilst it has nothing new to offer, shows us a different side to Eddie Murphy as an actor that we hadn't seen before in his previous films. People have in the past often compared this to Beverly Hills Cop 1, in terms of the fact that they are both your typical, run- of- the- mill cop movies, but the comparisons seem to come to an end when you compare that film to Metro, in terms of plot, character types and the fact that Eddie Murphy doesn't joke about as negotiator/cop Scott Roaper that often. Not like his predecessor, Axel Foley. Here, as Roaper he is much more serious and not as laid back in contrast to his most famous movie character. Metro plays out as a straight out action movie that isn't reliant on laughs, which in itself is no bad thing. One of the main problems that some of the audiences had, in regards to their expectations of Metro, was by assuming that it would be something similar on the lines of Beverly Hills Cop. It has its funny moments, but these are few and far between throughout the film, as the narrative in Metro is very much serious and the standard cop thriller we'd come to expect. Overall, Metro is not a bad effort and the action sequences are well executed. Murphy gives a surprising turn and performance as Roaper and thus it makes a change to see him in an almost completely non-comedic role, which he does well in. Not bad indeed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Over the top but fun comedy thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamiecostelo58
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy tries to act serious as well as funny as Detective Scott Roper, and he actually carries it off rather well. Wanting revenge for his partner's death, he's led on a dangerous cat-and-mouse game with Michael Wincott, who will not let him win easily... The main highlights of Metro are a thrilling car chase sequence and the explosive ending! This is not the best film I have ever seen, but Wincott is immensely good as criminal Korda, displaying an almost never-ending desire to bring Roper down, even if it means double murder.... Metro is a fast-paced thrilling (and funny) movie from start to finish containing many startling and cunning plots that may seem a little odd at first but smoothing out to a satisfactory conclusion. I can definitely understand why it was a huge success at the box-office: it is very enjoyable!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In some ways average, other ways quite good.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashleybrownmedia
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For the first hour of this film all I could think of was how average it was, I even had an average review written in my head for it. However, there are certain scenes, thrills and aspects - e.g. the ending predicament that are actually pretty good and will throw you. Eddie Murphy plays a 'wisecracking' hostage negotiator, although tbh he's very much the 'serious' Eddie Murphy for most of the film. I prefer the fun Beverly Hills Cop guy, but there we go. There is a scene where he's talking about being in a thong and being seen by his mother's friends that is hilarious though. Plot-wise he basically gets on the wrong side of some nutter and his cousin and they conspire to make life hell for him and his English girlfriend. The female lead is a tad weak in this, and I must admit I've never ever heard of her (although I was 7 when this film came out - maybe she was big then) but she looked good - Carmen Ejogo she is. Michael Rapaport is in this as well, as an intelligent sniper who is paired up with Murphy. Now I thought, judging by the cover etc, this was gonna be a buddy cop movie but Rapaport (an actor I like) is underused really. Don't get me wrong he's in the film a fair bit but his character has next to no personality. All I learnt was he's polite, sharp, from the Swat team and is a sniper. That's it. The film could have been done without his character if they wanted to save whatever fee he commanded. Whoever plays Eddie Murphy and Carme Ejogo's dog is good in this though. Stellar, powerhouse performance reminded me of Hanks in The Green Mile or Orson Welles in Citizen Kane. So yeah, mixed bag really - there's hate for post-80s Murphy films sure, but this is one of the better ones. It's a solid watch (on netflix atm) and there's some good action and the bad guy is easy to hate, so there's a lot worse out there. I won't strongly recommend but I'll say it's worth a shot - you know what you're going to get.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a great eddie murphy movie, a throwback to 48 hrs and Beverly hills cop
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daworldismine
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i am a fan of eddie murphy when he is in the right vehicle's like 'coming to America' 'the nutty professor' and 'Beverly hills cop' but sometimes he makes some very bad movies like 'pluto nash' 'boomerang' and 'meet dave'. now metro is more like his older movies, raw, r rated action comedies, and its great, eddie murphy is very funny in this, and at times hes even quite serious, but the movie never loses its comedy, and at its core thats what this is, if i had to compare it to one eddie murphy film, it would have to be Beverly hills cop, the same sort of action and humour. the cast are grear and the action big and loud, its a great movie and i recommend to fans of eddie murphy and action films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not totally awful - Murphy takes a shot at semi-serious and just misses.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Metro Murphy plays a streetwise police negotiator in San Fransisco named Scott Roper, in fact the best negotiator on the force. Roper's track record in getting hostages out alive is the envy of his colleagues and allows him leeway with his superiors. Unfortunately the stress of the job meant that Roper became introverted and shut out everything around him, including his girlfriend Ronnie who ultimately left him when he started gambling heavily as an outlet. Enter new partner Kevin McCall (Michael Rappaport), a young rookie straight from training who despite being highly skilled is raw and un-streetwise  if that were a word. Metro has two good scenes and one decent character. The two good scenes are a long chase that takes place on the San Fransisco streets and uses their tram system to full advantage, the second such scene is a training montage that lasts maybe two minutes and allows Murphy the freedom to go a little wild by creating a made up criminal for McCall to negotiate with. The decent character I haven't touched on yet, but given that the film is about a hostage negotiator it seems fairly obvious that there need be someone for Roper to test his skills on. That someone is Michael Korda (Michael Wincott), a man with dark sunken eyes, the emaciated appearance of the undernourished and the gravelly voice of a chain smoker. His hard as nails, emotionless performance as a potentially insane, definitely dangerous Korda is thankfully lacking in hamminess or over-acting, but overflowing with menace and intensity. It is not the end of the world that the bad guy in a film is by far the best thing in it, but in an action comedy with not enough of either, where the bad guy in reality is the third or fourth banana it simply isn't good enough. The strength of Korda's characterisation and a fairly brutal development results in some genuine animosity between the pair, which makes the inevitable stand off near the end somewhat more bearable, even if it is laced with logic flaws and some mediocre action sequences. Ultimately Metro ended up only marginally better than A Vampire in Brooklyn, by trying to play against the 'typical' Eddie Murphy movie they managed to create a film only marginally different, but one lacking enough of anything to make it worthwhile. Final Rating  5 / 10. The perception of intensity, the illusion of humour and the delusion of adequacy. Eddie Murphy takes a stab at semi-serious and fails. I don't hate Metro, but aside from a cool villain there is nothing to love.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I just LOVED this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janai P Canada (Sidadressage)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm nor going to give any spoilers out, but this really was one of Eddie Murphy BEST roles! I only bought this one because of the two actors that I love are in it. Eddie & Michael Wincott. It really, for me was a Wincott buy. Being a woman I agree with the other member who said most women will find it boring. I'm not like most women who like film. I saw both Raider's and The Golden Child in the theaters 9-11 times. So that should tell you. I wish Murphy would do this type of quality again. Anyway, enough of my opinion. GOOD MOVIE!!! Fast paised, a few funny lines and. Murphy as well as Wincott was VERY strong. I love it when Wincott is a villain. He gives such a nasty SOB 'like' portrayal of the quintessential bad guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Die Hard as a Black Man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    arieliondotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a "Die Hard" movie with Eddie Murphy in the role of Bruce Willis. That sounds like a joke and that's the problem. Is it an action movie? Comedy? Comedy about an action movie? It keeps veering from one to another like one of the cars in the car chases. Eddie Murphy is a lot of things but no Bruce Willis. And the movie is always on the brink of being a parody rather than a straight action movie. There are screaming, helpless females (this is a 90's movie...those types of women aren't seen in movies these days), car chases & crashes, only very few intentional laughs. It's an anachronism but not a bad way to pass the time. It's Die Hard with a Black man. And it's A' ight...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Neked in Tahiti.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Scott Roper is a wise cracking hostage negotiator, he is however exceptionally good at his job. After bringing down a particularly nasty bank robber called Michael Korda, he sets about winning his old girlfriend back whilst breaking in a new partner, Kevin McCall. When Korda escapes from prison there is only one thing on his mind, revenge, can Roper outwit Korda once again?, and if so, at what cost?. There has always seemed to me to be something of a negative bias towards post 1980s Eddie Murphy {Roper} films, it appears that no matter what, nothing that comes close to his best 80s efforts will ever be deemed worthy. Now i'm not saying that Metro is a world beater, or even close to Beverly Hills Cop and Trading Places, but it's an accomplished thriller with classy bits of Murphy humour thrown in. It also boasts splendid support from Michael Rapaport as Roper's intelligent partner McCall, both men playing off each other to good effect, while Michael Wincott with his gravel voice used to full effect, is impressively devilish as the bad guy of the piece. Let down by a weak female lead in Carmen Ejogo, and certainly the familiarity of the genre loses the film any real sense of impending dread, but for a quick fix of nonsense entertainment on a blustery cold night, it's a more than OK viewing. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Routine cop action thriller.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Metro is set in San Francisco where Inspector Scott Roper (Eddie Murphy) works as a hostage negotiator, one night while questioning a suspect named Michael Korda (Michael Wincott) one of Roper's closest friends Lieutenant Sam Baffett (Art Evans) is brutally murdered. With a new partner named Kevin McCall (Michael Rapaport) to show the ropes too Roper becomes obsessed with tracking his friends killer down & eventually does so when he arrests Korda after he had robbed a jewellery store. However Korda wants revenge & targets Roper's girlfriend Veronica (Carmen Ejogo) when he breaks out of prison... Directed by Thomas Carter this run of the mill Hollywood action cop comedy thriller is an alright way to spend a couple of hours but isn't anything original or spectacular. The script by co-producer Randy Feldman includes every Hollywood comedy cop thriller clich&eacute;s you care to think of, there's the whole mismatched partner angle, there's a wise-cracking hot-shot lead cop character who plays by his own rules & seemingly does very little police work, there's the one-liners & comeback's, there's the disgruntled police Captain who gets annoyed a lot, there's a really nasty bad guy who kills someone close to said cop & thereby makes it personal, there's the whole vendetta thing that flows through the film & there's a typical climactic showdown in which the cop kills the bad guy & gets the girl. Yawn. There really isn't anything in Metro that any action fan wouldn't have seen before & I seriously doubt there's anything in Metro that the average person wouldn't have seen before either. At almost two hours in length the film goes on for too long & it's just all so predictable & routine but it is saved by some impressive big budget action set-pieces & a fairly fun performance by Murphy who has turned swearing into an art form. For the majority of the duration of Metro the film is unremarkable although it passes the time harmlessly enough but I will admit there are a few great action sequences in it. In particular there's a terrific part which starts with a jewellery story robbery, a spectacular car chase through San Francisco featuring a runaway tram & ending in some more car stunts & a stand off in a parking garage which lasts for a good fifteen or twenty minutes in total although I did wonder where all the other cops in San Francisco were. There's some more good car stunts & explosions at the end but how is Roper going to explain all the jewels he 'borrowed' to get his girlfriend back being blown to pieces in the truck along with Korda? Also doesn't Korda escape from prison a bit too easily? OK so he makes it into the laundry room but there are still plenty of locked doors & police guards to get past even at that point. There's some violence & plenty of bad language to help pass the time but it all felt like I had seen it many times before. With a supposed budget of about $55,000,000 Metro is well made with solid big budget Hollywood production values. The acting is alright, Murphy does his Beverly Hills Cop (1984) cop with attitude type thing & he comes out with a few amusing one-liners but his character is very thinly written & fleshed out. The only other cast members to stand out are Michael Wincott as Korda the bad guy & he puts in an intense performance & British actress Carmen Ejogo who I thought was terrible. Metro is a throughly routine & predictable comedy cop action thriller the likes of which we have all seen before & usually better, it's not the worst of it's kind & several impressive set-piece action scenes help a lot but it's not up there with the best of it's kind. Average at best but action film fans should still like it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mediocre crime thriller that has it's moments.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Panterken
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Randy Feldman, who worked as the writer and producer on this movie, has four theatrical releases on his belt, the other three being the painfully bad horror flick 'Hell Night', the Jean-Claude Van Damme vehicle 'Nowhere to Run' (which I have not seen but can only assume it's as bad as any other of Van Damme film) and the eighties cop flick 'Tango & Cash', which received some audience acclaim. To state 'Metro' is by far his most memorable attempt at a screenplay isn't really a compliment, it seems he always kept the 'screenplay writing for dummies' book by hand during his writing sessions. We have the typical hero-cop; underpaid, under-appreciated by his boss, personal problems galore,financial troubles to boost, a smirking sense of humor, and of course a personal investment in the investigation ('now it's personal :-)). So we have the good cop with a revenge motive, but the chase isn't enough to fill the runtime. No, we also are forced to suffer - surprise, surprise - the obligatory (but in this case unfortunately also clumsily set up) love interest played by a young Carmen Ejogo. Sure; she's very easy on the eyes but as an actress she's sub-par. Then we have a fellow cop, lifelessly portrayed by Art Evans, and it must be said the poor fellow's been typecast, his role in the script is mainly to be victimized(also see: Die Hard 2 for an almost identical role). His monotone delivery and robot-like autopilot acting certainly didn't lift this film to a higher level, neither did Denis Arndt's one-dimensional police chief, the villain whose dialog consisted primarily of grunting or the gross of the side-characters for that matter. They are mainly present for giving us some insight in our lead's personal life (and some perspective) and of course to pitch for Eddie Murphy's jokes. The only roles that still spring to mind as I recollect on the movie today are Michael Rapaport and Donal Logue, both competently playing their respective roles. Other clich&eacute;s for the fanatic clich&eacute;-spotters among you, the rain suddenly appearing when a tragic event happened: both when Murphy's friend is murdered, as when there's an attempted murder on his girlfriend. Speaking of which, there's one clich&eacute; scene to build up the tension before the attempt, where we see Ejogo in a shoulder-shot frame as she puts on perfume in front of a bathroom mirror. She opens and closes the mirror/cabinet two times, with tense music playing, as if any moment some creep will appear behind her (the best use of that sort of scene can be found at the end of 'Candyman'). The action scenes felt very standard. The soundtrack bugged me to a lesser degree, it really couldn't make up its mind. The other big flaws are an OD of love story, a waste of plot opportunities (a lot more tactical SWAT stuff would've been welcome) and a lack of funny scenes (especially with the cop partners). But it is precisely that humor that keeps 'Metro' from totally falling apart, I'll never be Murphy's biggest fan but as a comedian he's far from mediocre (although we don't see his best work in this movie). I did appreciate the way they threw us off track time after time: as to who (or what) Troy is, the restaurant scenes (with the implied marriage proposal) and the hostage negotiation training scene. Those scenes, and the opening hostage situation, made up 90% of the enjoyment level of 'metro' for me. In the end 'Metro' can be summed up as painfully (almost insultingly) mediocre but still enjoyable because of the humor involved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Although It's Nothing Special, Metro is a Solid Action Movie Regardless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    waiching liu
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Metro appears to be a low-budget action affair, which whilst it has nothing new to offer, shows us a different side to Eddie Murphy as an actor that we hadn't seen before in his previous films. People have in the past often compared this to Beverly Hills Cop 1, in terms of the fact that they are both your typical, run- of- the- mill cop movies, but the comparisons seem to come to an end when you compare that film to Metro, in terms of plot, character types and the fact that Eddie Murphy doesn't joke about as negotiator/cop Scott Roaper that often. Not like his predecessor, Axel Foley. Here, as Roaper he is much more serious and not as laid back in contrast to his most famous movie character. Metro plays out as a straight out action movie that isn't reliant on laughs, which in itself is no bad thing. One of the main problems that some of the audiences had, in regards to their expectations of Metro, was by assuming that it would be something similar on the lines of Beverly Hills Cop. It has its funny moments, but these are few and far between throughout the film, as the narrative in Metro is very much serious and the standard cop thriller we'd come to expect. Overall, Metro is not a bad effort and the action sequences are well executed. Murphy gives a surprising turn and performance as Roaper and thus it makes a change to see him in an almost completely non-comedic role, which he does well in. Not bad indeed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Over the top but fun comedy thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamiecostelo58
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy tries to act serious as well as funny as Detective Scott Roper, and he actually carries it off rather well. Wanting revenge for his partner's death, he's led on a dangerous cat-and-mouse game with Michael Wincott, who will not let him win easily... The main highlights of Metro are a thrilling car chase sequence and the explosive ending! This is not the best film I have ever seen, but Wincott is immensely good as criminal Korda, displaying an almost never-ending desire to bring Roper down, even if it means double murder.... Metro is a fast-paced thrilling (and funny) movie from start to finish containing many startling and cunning plots that may seem a little odd at first but smoothing out to a satisfactory conclusion. I can definitely understand why it was a huge success at the box-office: it is very enjoyable!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
