<filme>
 <id>
  1254
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119214
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Pescando Confus&atilde;o
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  4.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Two fishing fanatics get in trouble when their fishing boat gets stolen while on a trip.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Two working-class buddies, Joe and Gus, win a contest and get a free fishing trip. When they arrive, everything goes wrong - hurricanes, stolen car, blow-ups and other catastrophes follow them.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   fishing
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   boat
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   fishing trip
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   con man
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   alligator
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Christopher Cain
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Jill Mazursky
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   J.J. Abrams
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Joe Pesci
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Danny Glover
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Rosanna Arquette
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    samueljoewaugh
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is one of those innocent films you just love, the critics were a little harsh on the rating, i remember seeing this when i was 9, i absolutely loved it, lots of action and fishing! which is what really interested me, although there are a lot of goofs i still enjoy this one from time to time and brings back those good childhood memories!. it is sad though that one of the stunt men died though, the movie is pretty interesting as the main actors are well known and are absolutely hilarious, the first time i saw this movie i laughed so hard i choked, Danny gloves and Joe pesci really make great actors together as there funny antics will keep you entertained! just don't miss out and watch this great old movie
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No big fish caught...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, this is pretty much your basic slapstick goof ball comedy. You have two fairly dim-witted people who aren't too keen on their surroundings and the havoc they wreak around them, and they get into a bunch if jiffies along the way. There, that was pretty much the lay down of the general story. Now, the performances of Pesci and Glover, are as usual, right on. They both did a good job with their roles, and the chemistry between the two worked marvelous. There are lots of situations throughout the movie that makes you cringe your toes in awkwardness, but the movie only managed to get a couple of laughs out in me. Lots of pulling on the smiles, but not really the type of comedy that makes you cringe over and laugh so hard you have tears trickling down your cheeks. The supporting roles were nicely filled out as well, though many of the characters in the movie were somewhat quirky. The movie is fairly wholesome to watch and good for an entertaining evening, but I say it is hardly the type of movie you return to again a second time, unless you are a die-hard Glover or Pesci fan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Rated R Plot Taken in a PG Matter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When looked at at a specific perspective, you can see what the producers were trying to do with Gone Fishin'. Make it a quirky, not very serious, fun kids movie. It seems they picked the two most serious actors for the job though. Danny Glover and Joe Pesci are good in lots of things they have been in, but this is just neither of them at their best. I think the problem was the PG rating. This could have been a great film if it had an R rating. Its almost like Glover and Pesci are struggling to hold back the words they want to use. You can tell Pesci just wants to blow off steam at points in the film. If this was R, it could have been a quirky, funny, and all out Comedy. Glover and Pesci play Gus and Joe, two average guys who want to get away and have a simple, relaxing vacation at the Everglades. They get way more than they ask for after having their car stolen at a restaurant. They realize the man who stole their car is a crook and a killer so Gus and Joe pair up with two girls looking for the man, for a little while, then go off on their own getting into their own trouble. They embark in every which way to try and stop the crook, but they just dig themselves deeper in a hole. Their stupidity doesn't help the situation one bit has both the leads are clueless and naive. But they are dependent on catching the guy and still making it home for Thanksgiving with their family. Once again, sometimes their stupidity tends to drag the film on which I've never been a fan of. Its just like in Dinner for Schmucks and Dumb and Dumberer: When Harry Met Lloyd. Stupidity is one thing, overwhelmingly stupid is another. It wears on you and almost makes you believe the actors are as dumb as they appear. But, thankfully, Gone Fishin' knows its limits and doesn't make the characters brainy, smartasses or make them bumbling nitwits. So the film doesn't fail there. While being completely harmless, at the same time, its overly kiddish. We saw Joe Pesci play stupid in Home Alone, but now, after seeing Casino and Goodfellas, I don't want to see him in a PG rated kid movie. Id rather have him be in an R rated Comedy where he can be himself and the same goes with Danny Glover. If this was R, it would probably earn another star, and quite possibly, another star in a half. But at least we get a relaxing opening driving scene with a great Willie Nelson tune in the background and a delightful appearance by him as well. Gone Fishin' was panned at the time, but it should also be taken into mind Janet Wilder was killed during a scene in this movie, so that doesn't give the movie a get-out-of-harsh-words free card, but it should just be said and maybe go easy on the movie. While Im not praising Gone Fishin', Im neither recommending it very far. Keep that in mind. Starring: Danny Glover, Joe Pesci, Nick Brimble, Rosanna Arquette, Lynn Whitfield, and Willie Nelson. Directed by: Christopher Cain.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even a Sunday afternoon movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movie Guy
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was terrible, and not because it's a nice light hearted comedy because I love them (grumpy old men type film) but this film tried too hard particularly with character development relationship and things along those lines that makes you cringe through this film. Let me first state that I love Joe pesci I personally think his best and most funny film is "My cousin vinny" and also Danny Glover is good particularly in lethal weapon, but this film goes so wrong which is a shame because it could have been great. The main issue lies between the two characters, they over-emphasise the character relations by doing things like quoting past events way too often, saying there name to each other after every f**king sentence which makes your blood boil, and generally acting too goofy which is enough to put you off the film entirely which is a shame because I wanted to like this, I really did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Down in the Ever-Glades"!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    huntersrestkid1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is just a great film. Why on earth are people rating it so low and calling it bad? It's not a bad movie, its one of the best movies I've ever seen!! Joe Pesci and Danny Glover together on a fishing trip? Comedy awesomeness right there! I think the people that hated the awesome innocent family movies like this are just stupid. They go for the action shooter thriller WHATEVER movies, and thats cool but its not cool to hate on a film that is great just because of that. I have great taste in movies, so I know what I'm talking about. I like the modern movies, and know that most of the cutesy fun-filled family movies (that, not to mention, have music written specifically for them) are back in the 70s and 80s. I'm drawn to those types of movies the same as modern thrillers, if not more than. "Gone Fishin'" is a 1997 movie, and proof that the modern era still makes those fun filled great family films. PESCI AND GLOVER 4 LIFE!! Buy this film, and have fun Fishin'!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Childhood Favorite!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pumpkin_Man
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ever since I was a kid, I've loved this movie because of the hilarious situations that Gus & Joe would get into. Gus and Joe are bumbling best friends who are going on a fishing trip in The Everglades down in Florida. When they stop to get a bite to eat, they have friendly conversation with a man, who soon steals their car. From then on, nothing goes right like tying the boat wrong, to lighting a gas station on fire, to blowing up a fancy hotel, and much more. The man who stole their car is a murderer and a thief named Dekker Massey. When they finally find their car, there is a bloody knife and a map inside. They try to find the treasure, only to be taken hostage by Dekker. Will Gus and Joe stop Dekker and save the day? I highly recommend GONE FISHIN'!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No spoiler here gobshites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    noamshouseparty
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be honest I've never seen this film, but by the looks of it there's a fierce whiff o' paint off of it. Fook all that! I'm dead fuckkin' right! An almighty smell of paint. No room for paint. Joe Glover and Danny Pesci. I can review, AND use all the big words. Mmm-hmm, tis true I'll have ya know. Yep it is, it is true, very true. Oh indeed. Das right and Glover and Pesci agree with me on that one. A big old tin o' paint. What were they thinking'? There's no varnish in this film is there? I couldn't have that. Not that it would be any worse than paint, but still. It couldn't leave us any better off ya loony bastards. And here's a big long sentence, and there is ten lines of text. No serious reviews for this film fuckkers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bloody Brillo it is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brewphobe
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i think this film is absolutely incredible. the acting performances are really subtle but spell binding. people talk about taxi driver or raging bull as a classic but this is more my bag baby. the kings have arrived. move over Kubrick.... your nothing compared to the cinematic brilliance that is GONE FISHIN WOW WOWEE! Joe Pesci really excels with superb direction here. Danny Glover here is magnetic and plays the part immaculately justifying his performance considering Daniel Day Lewis and Sir Ian McKellen were turned down in favor of the Lethal weapon star..... and you thought he was too old for this s###. well f### you!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watchable but what a waste of Pesci and Glover's talent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spencer10
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think Joe Pesci and Danny Glover are very good actors. They can play great dramatic and comic roles. But with "Gone Fishin'" their first attempt at comedy together someone ought to encourage both Pesci and Glover not to make any other comedy movies together. It's obvious that the biggest problem with "Gone Fishin'" is its script. Pesci and Glover are not to blame they are trying to act good. Its the writers and director's fault. Some of the lines in this film are extremely annoying e.g. "This trip ain't even a one its a frigging zero", or when Pesci tells the film's villain that he is a freak about 10 times and tells him "why don't you join the army if your'e a tough guy you freak". The other problem is that with the exception of the first two "Home Alone" pictures you cannot give Joe Pesci a script that is PG rated and expect him to act funny with it. Joe Pesci needs stronger material. I am not saying they needed to make the film R rated with the f-word every other word, or extreme violence but why couldn't they make this like "Grumpy Old Men" and make it on a PG-13 rated level? If they would have done that this movie would have been ten times funnier. And why didn't they actually have Pesci and Glover actually go fishing in the movie instead of a million disasters preventing them from going fishing? They do not fish in the entire 94 minutes of the movie except for the finale. Danny Glover has made a few other movies since this one but I have only seen Joe Pesci do two other movies since this one. I am wondering if its because he was embarrassed by how he acted in this movie. "Gone Fishin'" certainly is not awful but its such a shame to see two exceptionally talented actors act with such an annoying awful script. Its the kind of movie you might want to watch if the weather is really bad outside and you have nothing better to do. But if you are a big fan of either Pesci or Glover you might want to avoid this one because they are trying to act good with a bad script and in the end they have made a pretty big mistake by making "Gone Fishin'"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its OK
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chesterfox40
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is not a big thing. Its just a regular comedy with a simple story. It has got good actors like Danny Glover and Joe Pesci. They do a good job playing the two fishermen Gus Green and Joe Waters. But everybody knows that both of them can do better. This movie is basically a story of two ordinary guys who face extraordinary situations. Like their car being stolen by a con artist, causing a fire in a hotel and fighting with a crocodile. This movie will bring some entertainment on a boring evening. You will have some laughs and be able to kill some time. However buying this movie is not a good idea, go rent it. If you saw it once its enough. 7/10 If you really want to see a good movie with Danny Glover and Joe Pesci then watch "Lethal Weapon 2". Joe Pesci is great in that movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    samueljoewaugh
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is one of those innocent films you just love, the critics were a little harsh on the rating, i remember seeing this when i was 9, i absolutely loved it, lots of action and fishing! which is what really interested me, although there are a lot of goofs i still enjoy this one from time to time and brings back those good childhood memories!. it is sad though that one of the stunt men died though, the movie is pretty interesting as the main actors are well known and are absolutely hilarious, the first time i saw this movie i laughed so hard i choked, Danny gloves and Joe pesci really make great actors together as there funny antics will keep you entertained! just don't miss out and watch this great old movie
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No big fish caught...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, this is pretty much your basic slapstick goof ball comedy. You have two fairly dim-witted people who aren't too keen on their surroundings and the havoc they wreak around them, and they get into a bunch if jiffies along the way. There, that was pretty much the lay down of the general story. Now, the performances of Pesci and Glover, are as usual, right on. They both did a good job with their roles, and the chemistry between the two worked marvelous. There are lots of situations throughout the movie that makes you cringe your toes in awkwardness, but the movie only managed to get a couple of laughs out in me. Lots of pulling on the smiles, but not really the type of comedy that makes you cringe over and laugh so hard you have tears trickling down your cheeks. The supporting roles were nicely filled out as well, though many of the characters in the movie were somewhat quirky. The movie is fairly wholesome to watch and good for an entertaining evening, but I say it is hardly the type of movie you return to again a second time, unless you are a die-hard Glover or Pesci fan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Rated R Plot Taken in a PG Matter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When looked at at a specific perspective, you can see what the producers were trying to do with Gone Fishin'. Make it a quirky, not very serious, fun kids movie. It seems they picked the two most serious actors for the job though. Danny Glover and Joe Pesci are good in lots of things they have been in, but this is just neither of them at their best. I think the problem was the PG rating. This could have been a great film if it had an R rating. Its almost like Glover and Pesci are struggling to hold back the words they want to use. You can tell Pesci just wants to blow off steam at points in the film. If this was R, it could have been a quirky, funny, and all out Comedy. Glover and Pesci play Gus and Joe, two average guys who want to get away and have a simple, relaxing vacation at the Everglades. They get way more than they ask for after having their car stolen at a restaurant. They realize the man who stole their car is a crook and a killer so Gus and Joe pair up with two girls looking for the man, for a little while, then go off on their own getting into their own trouble. They embark in every which way to try and stop the crook, but they just dig themselves deeper in a hole. Their stupidity doesn't help the situation one bit has both the leads are clueless and naive. But they are dependent on catching the guy and still making it home for Thanksgiving with their family. Once again, sometimes their stupidity tends to drag the film on which I've never been a fan of. Its just like in Dinner for Schmucks and Dumb and Dumberer: When Harry Met Lloyd. Stupidity is one thing, overwhelmingly stupid is another. It wears on you and almost makes you believe the actors are as dumb as they appear. But, thankfully, Gone Fishin' knows its limits and doesn't make the characters brainy, smartasses or make them bumbling nitwits. So the film doesn't fail there. While being completely harmless, at the same time, its overly kiddish. We saw Joe Pesci play stupid in Home Alone, but now, after seeing Casino and Goodfellas, I don't want to see him in a PG rated kid movie. Id rather have him be in an R rated Comedy where he can be himself and the same goes with Danny Glover. If this was R, it would probably earn another star, and quite possibly, another star in a half. But at least we get a relaxing opening driving scene with a great Willie Nelson tune in the background and a delightful appearance by him as well. Gone Fishin' was panned at the time, but it should also be taken into mind Janet Wilder was killed during a scene in this movie, so that doesn't give the movie a get-out-of-harsh-words free card, but it should just be said and maybe go easy on the movie. While Im not praising Gone Fishin', Im neither recommending it very far. Keep that in mind. Starring: Danny Glover, Joe Pesci, Nick Brimble, Rosanna Arquette, Lynn Whitfield, and Willie Nelson. Directed by: Christopher Cain.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even a Sunday afternoon movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movie Guy
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was terrible, and not because it's a nice light hearted comedy because I love them (grumpy old men type film) but this film tried too hard particularly with character development relationship and things along those lines that makes you cringe through this film. Let me first state that I love Joe pesci I personally think his best and most funny film is "My cousin vinny" and also Danny Glover is good particularly in lethal weapon, but this film goes so wrong which is a shame because it could have been great. The main issue lies between the two characters, they over-emphasise the character relations by doing things like quoting past events way too often, saying there name to each other after every f**king sentence which makes your blood boil, and generally acting too goofy which is enough to put you off the film entirely which is a shame because I wanted to like this, I really did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Down in the Ever-Glades"!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    huntersrestkid1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is just a great film. Why on earth are people rating it so low and calling it bad? It's not a bad movie, its one of the best movies I've ever seen!! Joe Pesci and Danny Glover together on a fishing trip? Comedy awesomeness right there! I think the people that hated the awesome innocent family movies like this are just stupid. They go for the action shooter thriller WHATEVER movies, and thats cool but its not cool to hate on a film that is great just because of that. I have great taste in movies, so I know what I'm talking about. I like the modern movies, and know that most of the cutesy fun-filled family movies (that, not to mention, have music written specifically for them) are back in the 70s and 80s. I'm drawn to those types of movies the same as modern thrillers, if not more than. "Gone Fishin'" is a 1997 movie, and proof that the modern era still makes those fun filled great family films. PESCI AND GLOVER 4 LIFE!! Buy this film, and have fun Fishin'!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Childhood Favorite!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pumpkin_Man
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ever since I was a kid, I've loved this movie because of the hilarious situations that Gus & Joe would get into. Gus and Joe are bumbling best friends who are going on a fishing trip in The Everglades down in Florida. When they stop to get a bite to eat, they have friendly conversation with a man, who soon steals their car. From then on, nothing goes right like tying the boat wrong, to lighting a gas station on fire, to blowing up a fancy hotel, and much more. The man who stole their car is a murderer and a thief named Dekker Massey. When they finally find their car, there is a bloody knife and a map inside. They try to find the treasure, only to be taken hostage by Dekker. Will Gus and Joe stop Dekker and save the day? I highly recommend GONE FISHIN'!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No spoiler here gobshites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    noamshouseparty
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be honest I've never seen this film, but by the looks of it there's a fierce whiff o' paint off of it. Fook all that! I'm dead fuckkin' right! An almighty smell of paint. No room for paint. Joe Glover and Danny Pesci. I can review, AND use all the big words. Mmm-hmm, tis true I'll have ya know. Yep it is, it is true, very true. Oh indeed. Das right and Glover and Pesci agree with me on that one. A big old tin o' paint. What were they thinking'? There's no varnish in this film is there? I couldn't have that. Not that it would be any worse than paint, but still. It couldn't leave us any better off ya loony bastards. And here's a big long sentence, and there is ten lines of text. No serious reviews for this film fuckkers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bloody Brillo it is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brewphobe
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i think this film is absolutely incredible. the acting performances are really subtle but spell binding. people talk about taxi driver or raging bull as a classic but this is more my bag baby. the kings have arrived. move over Kubrick.... your nothing compared to the cinematic brilliance that is GONE FISHIN WOW WOWEE! Joe Pesci really excels with superb direction here. Danny Glover here is magnetic and plays the part immaculately justifying his performance considering Daniel Day Lewis and Sir Ian McKellen were turned down in favor of the Lethal weapon star..... and you thought he was too old for this s###. well f### you!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watchable but what a waste of Pesci and Glover's talent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spencer10
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think Joe Pesci and Danny Glover are very good actors. They can play great dramatic and comic roles. But with "Gone Fishin'" their first attempt at comedy together someone ought to encourage both Pesci and Glover not to make any other comedy movies together. It's obvious that the biggest problem with "Gone Fishin'" is its script. Pesci and Glover are not to blame they are trying to act good. Its the writers and director's fault. Some of the lines in this film are extremely annoying e.g. "This trip ain't even a one its a frigging zero", or when Pesci tells the film's villain that he is a freak about 10 times and tells him "why don't you join the army if your'e a tough guy you freak". The other problem is that with the exception of the first two "Home Alone" pictures you cannot give Joe Pesci a script that is PG rated and expect him to act funny with it. Joe Pesci needs stronger material. I am not saying they needed to make the film R rated with the f-word every other word, or extreme violence but why couldn't they make this like "Grumpy Old Men" and make it on a PG-13 rated level? If they would have done that this movie would have been ten times funnier. And why didn't they actually have Pesci and Glover actually go fishing in the movie instead of a million disasters preventing them from going fishing? They do not fish in the entire 94 minutes of the movie except for the finale. Danny Glover has made a few other movies since this one but I have only seen Joe Pesci do two other movies since this one. I am wondering if its because he was embarrassed by how he acted in this movie. "Gone Fishin'" certainly is not awful but its such a shame to see two exceptionally talented actors act with such an annoying awful script. Its the kind of movie you might want to watch if the weather is really bad outside and you have nothing better to do. But if you are a big fan of either Pesci or Glover you might want to avoid this one because they are trying to act good with a bad script and in the end they have made a pretty big mistake by making "Gone Fishin'"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its OK
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chesterfox40
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is not a big thing. Its just a regular comedy with a simple story. It has got good actors like Danny Glover and Joe Pesci. They do a good job playing the two fishermen Gus Green and Joe Waters. But everybody knows that both of them can do better. This movie is basically a story of two ordinary guys who face extraordinary situations. Like their car being stolen by a con artist, causing a fire in a hotel and fighting with a crocodile. This movie will bring some entertainment on a boring evening. You will have some laughs and be able to kill some time. However buying this movie is not a good idea, go rent it. If you saw it once its enough. 7/10 If you really want to see a good movie with Danny Glover and Joe Pesci then watch "Lethal Weapon 2". Joe Pesci is great in that movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    samueljoewaugh
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is one of those innocent films you just love, the critics were a little harsh on the rating, i remember seeing this when i was 9, i absolutely loved it, lots of action and fishing! which is what really interested me, although there are a lot of goofs i still enjoy this one from time to time and brings back those good childhood memories!. it is sad though that one of the stunt men died though, the movie is pretty interesting as the main actors are well known and are absolutely hilarious, the first time i saw this movie i laughed so hard i choked, Danny gloves and Joe pesci really make great actors together as there funny antics will keep you entertained! just don't miss out and watch this great old movie
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No big fish caught...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, this is pretty much your basic slapstick goof ball comedy. You have two fairly dim-witted people who aren't too keen on their surroundings and the havoc they wreak around them, and they get into a bunch if jiffies along the way. There, that was pretty much the lay down of the general story. Now, the performances of Pesci and Glover, are as usual, right on. They both did a good job with their roles, and the chemistry between the two worked marvelous. There are lots of situations throughout the movie that makes you cringe your toes in awkwardness, but the movie only managed to get a couple of laughs out in me. Lots of pulling on the smiles, but not really the type of comedy that makes you cringe over and laugh so hard you have tears trickling down your cheeks. The supporting roles were nicely filled out as well, though many of the characters in the movie were somewhat quirky. The movie is fairly wholesome to watch and good for an entertaining evening, but I say it is hardly the type of movie you return to again a second time, unless you are a die-hard Glover or Pesci fan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Rated R Plot Taken in a PG Matter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When looked at at a specific perspective, you can see what the producers were trying to do with Gone Fishin'. Make it a quirky, not very serious, fun kids movie. It seems they picked the two most serious actors for the job though. Danny Glover and Joe Pesci are good in lots of things they have been in, but this is just neither of them at their best. I think the problem was the PG rating. This could have been a great film if it had an R rating. Its almost like Glover and Pesci are struggling to hold back the words they want to use. You can tell Pesci just wants to blow off steam at points in the film. If this was R, it could have been a quirky, funny, and all out Comedy. Glover and Pesci play Gus and Joe, two average guys who want to get away and have a simple, relaxing vacation at the Everglades. They get way more than they ask for after having their car stolen at a restaurant. They realize the man who stole their car is a crook and a killer so Gus and Joe pair up with two girls looking for the man, for a little while, then go off on their own getting into their own trouble. They embark in every which way to try and stop the crook, but they just dig themselves deeper in a hole. Their stupidity doesn't help the situation one bit has both the leads are clueless and naive. But they are dependent on catching the guy and still making it home for Thanksgiving with their family. Once again, sometimes their stupidity tends to drag the film on which I've never been a fan of. Its just like in Dinner for Schmucks and Dumb and Dumberer: When Harry Met Lloyd. Stupidity is one thing, overwhelmingly stupid is another. It wears on you and almost makes you believe the actors are as dumb as they appear. But, thankfully, Gone Fishin' knows its limits and doesn't make the characters brainy, smartasses or make them bumbling nitwits. So the film doesn't fail there. While being completely harmless, at the same time, its overly kiddish. We saw Joe Pesci play stupid in Home Alone, but now, after seeing Casino and Goodfellas, I don't want to see him in a PG rated kid movie. Id rather have him be in an R rated Comedy where he can be himself and the same goes with Danny Glover. If this was R, it would probably earn another star, and quite possibly, another star in a half. But at least we get a relaxing opening driving scene with a great Willie Nelson tune in the background and a delightful appearance by him as well. Gone Fishin' was panned at the time, but it should also be taken into mind Janet Wilder was killed during a scene in this movie, so that doesn't give the movie a get-out-of-harsh-words free card, but it should just be said and maybe go easy on the movie. While Im not praising Gone Fishin', Im neither recommending it very far. Keep that in mind. Starring: Danny Glover, Joe Pesci, Nick Brimble, Rosanna Arquette, Lynn Whitfield, and Willie Nelson. Directed by: Christopher Cain.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even a Sunday afternoon movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movie Guy
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was terrible, and not because it's a nice light hearted comedy because I love them (grumpy old men type film) but this film tried too hard particularly with character development relationship and things along those lines that makes you cringe through this film. Let me first state that I love Joe pesci I personally think his best and most funny film is "My cousin vinny" and also Danny Glover is good particularly in lethal weapon, but this film goes so wrong which is a shame because it could have been great. The main issue lies between the two characters, they over-emphasise the character relations by doing things like quoting past events way too often, saying there name to each other after every f**king sentence which makes your blood boil, and generally acting too goofy which is enough to put you off the film entirely which is a shame because I wanted to like this, I really did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Down in the Ever-Glades"!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    huntersrestkid1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is just a great film. Why on earth are people rating it so low and calling it bad? It's not a bad movie, its one of the best movies I've ever seen!! Joe Pesci and Danny Glover together on a fishing trip? Comedy awesomeness right there! I think the people that hated the awesome innocent family movies like this are just stupid. They go for the action shooter thriller WHATEVER movies, and thats cool but its not cool to hate on a film that is great just because of that. I have great taste in movies, so I know what I'm talking about. I like the modern movies, and know that most of the cutesy fun-filled family movies (that, not to mention, have music written specifically for them) are back in the 70s and 80s. I'm drawn to those types of movies the same as modern thrillers, if not more than. "Gone Fishin'" is a 1997 movie, and proof that the modern era still makes those fun filled great family films. PESCI AND GLOVER 4 LIFE!! Buy this film, and have fun Fishin'!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Childhood Favorite!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pumpkin_Man
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ever since I was a kid, I've loved this movie because of the hilarious situations that Gus & Joe would get into. Gus and Joe are bumbling best friends who are going on a fishing trip in The Everglades down in Florida. When they stop to get a bite to eat, they have friendly conversation with a man, who soon steals their car. From then on, nothing goes right like tying the boat wrong, to lighting a gas station on fire, to blowing up a fancy hotel, and much more. The man who stole their car is a murderer and a thief named Dekker Massey. When they finally find their car, there is a bloody knife and a map inside. They try to find the treasure, only to be taken hostage by Dekker. Will Gus and Joe stop Dekker and save the day? I highly recommend GONE FISHIN'!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No spoiler here gobshites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    noamshouseparty
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be honest I've never seen this film, but by the looks of it there's a fierce whiff o' paint off of it. Fook all that! I'm dead fuckkin' right! An almighty smell of paint. No room for paint. Joe Glover and Danny Pesci. I can review, AND use all the big words. Mmm-hmm, tis true I'll have ya know. Yep it is, it is true, very true. Oh indeed. Das right and Glover and Pesci agree with me on that one. A big old tin o' paint. What were they thinking'? There's no varnish in this film is there? I couldn't have that. Not that it would be any worse than paint, but still. It couldn't leave us any better off ya loony bastards. And here's a big long sentence, and there is ten lines of text. No serious reviews for this film fuckkers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bloody Brillo it is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brewphobe
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i think this film is absolutely incredible. the acting performances are really subtle but spell binding. people talk about taxi driver or raging bull as a classic but this is more my bag baby. the kings have arrived. move over Kubrick.... your nothing compared to the cinematic brilliance that is GONE FISHIN WOW WOWEE! Joe Pesci really excels with superb direction here. Danny Glover here is magnetic and plays the part immaculately justifying his performance considering Daniel Day Lewis and Sir Ian McKellen were turned down in favor of the Lethal weapon star..... and you thought he was too old for this s###. well f### you!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watchable but what a waste of Pesci and Glover's talent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spencer10
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think Joe Pesci and Danny Glover are very good actors. They can play great dramatic and comic roles. But with "Gone Fishin'" their first attempt at comedy together someone ought to encourage both Pesci and Glover not to make any other comedy movies together. It's obvious that the biggest problem with "Gone Fishin'" is its script. Pesci and Glover are not to blame they are trying to act good. Its the writers and director's fault. Some of the lines in this film are extremely annoying e.g. "This trip ain't even a one its a frigging zero", or when Pesci tells the film's villain that he is a freak about 10 times and tells him "why don't you join the army if your'e a tough guy you freak". The other problem is that with the exception of the first two "Home Alone" pictures you cannot give Joe Pesci a script that is PG rated and expect him to act funny with it. Joe Pesci needs stronger material. I am not saying they needed to make the film R rated with the f-word every other word, or extreme violence but why couldn't they make this like "Grumpy Old Men" and make it on a PG-13 rated level? If they would have done that this movie would have been ten times funnier. And why didn't they actually have Pesci and Glover actually go fishing in the movie instead of a million disasters preventing them from going fishing? They do not fish in the entire 94 minutes of the movie except for the finale. Danny Glover has made a few other movies since this one but I have only seen Joe Pesci do two other movies since this one. I am wondering if its because he was embarrassed by how he acted in this movie. "Gone Fishin'" certainly is not awful but its such a shame to see two exceptionally talented actors act with such an annoying awful script. Its the kind of movie you might want to watch if the weather is really bad outside and you have nothing better to do. But if you are a big fan of either Pesci or Glover you might want to avoid this one because they are trying to act good with a bad script and in the end they have made a pretty big mistake by making "Gone Fishin'"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its OK
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chesterfox40
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is not a big thing. Its just a regular comedy with a simple story. It has got good actors like Danny Glover and Joe Pesci. They do a good job playing the two fishermen Gus Green and Joe Waters. But everybody knows that both of them can do better. This movie is basically a story of two ordinary guys who face extraordinary situations. Like their car being stolen by a con artist, causing a fire in a hotel and fighting with a crocodile. This movie will bring some entertainment on a boring evening. You will have some laughs and be able to kill some time. However buying this movie is not a good idea, go rent it. If you saw it once its enough. 7/10 If you really want to see a good movie with Danny Glover and Joe Pesci then watch "Lethal Weapon 2". Joe Pesci is great in that movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    samueljoewaugh
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is one of those innocent films you just love, the critics were a little harsh on the rating, i remember seeing this when i was 9, i absolutely loved it, lots of action and fishing! which is what really interested me, although there are a lot of goofs i still enjoy this one from time to time and brings back those good childhood memories!. it is sad though that one of the stunt men died though, the movie is pretty interesting as the main actors are well known and are absolutely hilarious, the first time i saw this movie i laughed so hard i choked, Danny gloves and Joe pesci really make great actors together as there funny antics will keep you entertained! just don't miss out and watch this great old movie
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No big fish caught...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, this is pretty much your basic slapstick goof ball comedy. You have two fairly dim-witted people who aren't too keen on their surroundings and the havoc they wreak around them, and they get into a bunch if jiffies along the way. There, that was pretty much the lay down of the general story. Now, the performances of Pesci and Glover, are as usual, right on. They both did a good job with their roles, and the chemistry between the two worked marvelous. There are lots of situations throughout the movie that makes you cringe your toes in awkwardness, but the movie only managed to get a couple of laughs out in me. Lots of pulling on the smiles, but not really the type of comedy that makes you cringe over and laugh so hard you have tears trickling down your cheeks. The supporting roles were nicely filled out as well, though many of the characters in the movie were somewhat quirky. The movie is fairly wholesome to watch and good for an entertaining evening, but I say it is hardly the type of movie you return to again a second time, unless you are a die-hard Glover or Pesci fan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Rated R Plot Taken in a PG Matter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When looked at at a specific perspective, you can see what the producers were trying to do with Gone Fishin'. Make it a quirky, not very serious, fun kids movie. It seems they picked the two most serious actors for the job though. Danny Glover and Joe Pesci are good in lots of things they have been in, but this is just neither of them at their best. I think the problem was the PG rating. This could have been a great film if it had an R rating. Its almost like Glover and Pesci are struggling to hold back the words they want to use. You can tell Pesci just wants to blow off steam at points in the film. If this was R, it could have been a quirky, funny, and all out Comedy. Glover and Pesci play Gus and Joe, two average guys who want to get away and have a simple, relaxing vacation at the Everglades. They get way more than they ask for after having their car stolen at a restaurant. They realize the man who stole their car is a crook and a killer so Gus and Joe pair up with two girls looking for the man, for a little while, then go off on their own getting into their own trouble. They embark in every which way to try and stop the crook, but they just dig themselves deeper in a hole. Their stupidity doesn't help the situation one bit has both the leads are clueless and naive. But they are dependent on catching the guy and still making it home for Thanksgiving with their family. Once again, sometimes their stupidity tends to drag the film on which I've never been a fan of. Its just like in Dinner for Schmucks and Dumb and Dumberer: When Harry Met Lloyd. Stupidity is one thing, overwhelmingly stupid is another. It wears on you and almost makes you believe the actors are as dumb as they appear. But, thankfully, Gone Fishin' knows its limits and doesn't make the characters brainy, smartasses or make them bumbling nitwits. So the film doesn't fail there. While being completely harmless, at the same time, its overly kiddish. We saw Joe Pesci play stupid in Home Alone, but now, after seeing Casino and Goodfellas, I don't want to see him in a PG rated kid movie. Id rather have him be in an R rated Comedy where he can be himself and the same goes with Danny Glover. If this was R, it would probably earn another star, and quite possibly, another star in a half. But at least we get a relaxing opening driving scene with a great Willie Nelson tune in the background and a delightful appearance by him as well. Gone Fishin' was panned at the time, but it should also be taken into mind Janet Wilder was killed during a scene in this movie, so that doesn't give the movie a get-out-of-harsh-words free card, but it should just be said and maybe go easy on the movie. While Im not praising Gone Fishin', Im neither recommending it very far. Keep that in mind. Starring: Danny Glover, Joe Pesci, Nick Brimble, Rosanna Arquette, Lynn Whitfield, and Willie Nelson. Directed by: Christopher Cain.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even a Sunday afternoon movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movie Guy
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was terrible, and not because it's a nice light hearted comedy because I love them (grumpy old men type film) but this film tried too hard particularly with character development relationship and things along those lines that makes you cringe through this film. Let me first state that I love Joe pesci I personally think his best and most funny film is "My cousin vinny" and also Danny Glover is good particularly in lethal weapon, but this film goes so wrong which is a shame because it could have been great. The main issue lies between the two characters, they over-emphasise the character relations by doing things like quoting past events way too often, saying there name to each other after every f**king sentence which makes your blood boil, and generally acting too goofy which is enough to put you off the film entirely which is a shame because I wanted to like this, I really did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Down in the Ever-Glades"!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    huntersrestkid1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is just a great film. Why on earth are people rating it so low and calling it bad? It's not a bad movie, its one of the best movies I've ever seen!! Joe Pesci and Danny Glover together on a fishing trip? Comedy awesomeness right there! I think the people that hated the awesome innocent family movies like this are just stupid. They go for the action shooter thriller WHATEVER movies, and thats cool but its not cool to hate on a film that is great just because of that. I have great taste in movies, so I know what I'm talking about. I like the modern movies, and know that most of the cutesy fun-filled family movies (that, not to mention, have music written specifically for them) are back in the 70s and 80s. I'm drawn to those types of movies the same as modern thrillers, if not more than. "Gone Fishin'" is a 1997 movie, and proof that the modern era still makes those fun filled great family films. PESCI AND GLOVER 4 LIFE!! Buy this film, and have fun Fishin'!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Childhood Favorite!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pumpkin_Man
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ever since I was a kid, I've loved this movie because of the hilarious situations that Gus & Joe would get into. Gus and Joe are bumbling best friends who are going on a fishing trip in The Everglades down in Florida. When they stop to get a bite to eat, they have friendly conversation with a man, who soon steals their car. From then on, nothing goes right like tying the boat wrong, to lighting a gas station on fire, to blowing up a fancy hotel, and much more. The man who stole their car is a murderer and a thief named Dekker Massey. When they finally find their car, there is a bloody knife and a map inside. They try to find the treasure, only to be taken hostage by Dekker. Will Gus and Joe stop Dekker and save the day? I highly recommend GONE FISHIN'!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No spoiler here gobshites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    noamshouseparty
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be honest I've never seen this film, but by the looks of it there's a fierce whiff o' paint off of it. Fook all that! I'm dead fuckkin' right! An almighty smell of paint. No room for paint. Joe Glover and Danny Pesci. I can review, AND use all the big words. Mmm-hmm, tis true I'll have ya know. Yep it is, it is true, very true. Oh indeed. Das right and Glover and Pesci agree with me on that one. A big old tin o' paint. What were they thinking'? There's no varnish in this film is there? I couldn't have that. Not that it would be any worse than paint, but still. It couldn't leave us any better off ya loony bastards. And here's a big long sentence, and there is ten lines of text. No serious reviews for this film fuckkers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bloody Brillo it is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brewphobe
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i think this film is absolutely incredible. the acting performances are really subtle but spell binding. people talk about taxi driver or raging bull as a classic but this is more my bag baby. the kings have arrived. move over Kubrick.... your nothing compared to the cinematic brilliance that is GONE FISHIN WOW WOWEE! Joe Pesci really excels with superb direction here. Danny Glover here is magnetic and plays the part immaculately justifying his performance considering Daniel Day Lewis and Sir Ian McKellen were turned down in favor of the Lethal weapon star..... and you thought he was too old for this s###. well f### you!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watchable but what a waste of Pesci and Glover's talent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spencer10
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think Joe Pesci and Danny Glover are very good actors. They can play great dramatic and comic roles. But with "Gone Fishin'" their first attempt at comedy together someone ought to encourage both Pesci and Glover not to make any other comedy movies together. It's obvious that the biggest problem with "Gone Fishin'" is its script. Pesci and Glover are not to blame they are trying to act good. Its the writers and director's fault. Some of the lines in this film are extremely annoying e.g. "This trip ain't even a one its a frigging zero", or when Pesci tells the film's villain that he is a freak about 10 times and tells him "why don't you join the army if your'e a tough guy you freak". The other problem is that with the exception of the first two "Home Alone" pictures you cannot give Joe Pesci a script that is PG rated and expect him to act funny with it. Joe Pesci needs stronger material. I am not saying they needed to make the film R rated with the f-word every other word, or extreme violence but why couldn't they make this like "Grumpy Old Men" and make it on a PG-13 rated level? If they would have done that this movie would have been ten times funnier. And why didn't they actually have Pesci and Glover actually go fishing in the movie instead of a million disasters preventing them from going fishing? They do not fish in the entire 94 minutes of the movie except for the finale. Danny Glover has made a few other movies since this one but I have only seen Joe Pesci do two other movies since this one. I am wondering if its because he was embarrassed by how he acted in this movie. "Gone Fishin'" certainly is not awful but its such a shame to see two exceptionally talented actors act with such an annoying awful script. Its the kind of movie you might want to watch if the weather is really bad outside and you have nothing better to do. But if you are a big fan of either Pesci or Glover you might want to avoid this one because they are trying to act good with a bad script and in the end they have made a pretty big mistake by making "Gone Fishin'"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its OK
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chesterfox40
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is not a big thing. Its just a regular comedy with a simple story. It has got good actors like Danny Glover and Joe Pesci. They do a good job playing the two fishermen Gus Green and Joe Waters. But everybody knows that both of them can do better. This movie is basically a story of two ordinary guys who face extraordinary situations. Like their car being stolen by a con artist, causing a fire in a hotel and fighting with a crocodile. This movie will bring some entertainment on a boring evening. You will have some laughs and be able to kill some time. However buying this movie is not a good idea, go rent it. If you saw it once its enough. 7/10 If you really want to see a good movie with Danny Glover and Joe Pesci then watch "Lethal Weapon 2". Joe Pesci is great in that movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    samueljoewaugh
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is one of those innocent films you just love, the critics were a little harsh on the rating, i remember seeing this when i was 9, i absolutely loved it, lots of action and fishing! which is what really interested me, although there are a lot of goofs i still enjoy this one from time to time and brings back those good childhood memories!. it is sad though that one of the stunt men died though, the movie is pretty interesting as the main actors are well known and are absolutely hilarious, the first time i saw this movie i laughed so hard i choked, Danny gloves and Joe pesci really make great actors together as there funny antics will keep you entertained! just don't miss out and watch this great old movie
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No big fish caught...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, this is pretty much your basic slapstick goof ball comedy. You have two fairly dim-witted people who aren't too keen on their surroundings and the havoc they wreak around them, and they get into a bunch if jiffies along the way. There, that was pretty much the lay down of the general story. Now, the performances of Pesci and Glover, are as usual, right on. They both did a good job with their roles, and the chemistry between the two worked marvelous. There are lots of situations throughout the movie that makes you cringe your toes in awkwardness, but the movie only managed to get a couple of laughs out in me. Lots of pulling on the smiles, but not really the type of comedy that makes you cringe over and laugh so hard you have tears trickling down your cheeks. The supporting roles were nicely filled out as well, though many of the characters in the movie were somewhat quirky. The movie is fairly wholesome to watch and good for an entertaining evening, but I say it is hardly the type of movie you return to again a second time, unless you are a die-hard Glover or Pesci fan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Rated R Plot Taken in a PG Matter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When looked at at a specific perspective, you can see what the producers were trying to do with Gone Fishin'. Make it a quirky, not very serious, fun kids movie. It seems they picked the two most serious actors for the job though. Danny Glover and Joe Pesci are good in lots of things they have been in, but this is just neither of them at their best. I think the problem was the PG rating. This could have been a great film if it had an R rating. Its almost like Glover and Pesci are struggling to hold back the words they want to use. You can tell Pesci just wants to blow off steam at points in the film. If this was R, it could have been a quirky, funny, and all out Comedy. Glover and Pesci play Gus and Joe, two average guys who want to get away and have a simple, relaxing vacation at the Everglades. They get way more than they ask for after having their car stolen at a restaurant. They realize the man who stole their car is a crook and a killer so Gus and Joe pair up with two girls looking for the man, for a little while, then go off on their own getting into their own trouble. They embark in every which way to try and stop the crook, but they just dig themselves deeper in a hole. Their stupidity doesn't help the situation one bit has both the leads are clueless and naive. But they are dependent on catching the guy and still making it home for Thanksgiving with their family. Once again, sometimes their stupidity tends to drag the film on which I've never been a fan of. Its just like in Dinner for Schmucks and Dumb and Dumberer: When Harry Met Lloyd. Stupidity is one thing, overwhelmingly stupid is another. It wears on you and almost makes you believe the actors are as dumb as they appear. But, thankfully, Gone Fishin' knows its limits and doesn't make the characters brainy, smartasses or make them bumbling nitwits. So the film doesn't fail there. While being completely harmless, at the same time, its overly kiddish. We saw Joe Pesci play stupid in Home Alone, but now, after seeing Casino and Goodfellas, I don't want to see him in a PG rated kid movie. Id rather have him be in an R rated Comedy where he can be himself and the same goes with Danny Glover. If this was R, it would probably earn another star, and quite possibly, another star in a half. But at least we get a relaxing opening driving scene with a great Willie Nelson tune in the background and a delightful appearance by him as well. Gone Fishin' was panned at the time, but it should also be taken into mind Janet Wilder was killed during a scene in this movie, so that doesn't give the movie a get-out-of-harsh-words free card, but it should just be said and maybe go easy on the movie. While Im not praising Gone Fishin', Im neither recommending it very far. Keep that in mind. Starring: Danny Glover, Joe Pesci, Nick Brimble, Rosanna Arquette, Lynn Whitfield, and Willie Nelson. Directed by: Christopher Cain.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even a Sunday afternoon movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movie Guy
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was terrible, and not because it's a nice light hearted comedy because I love them (grumpy old men type film) but this film tried too hard particularly with character development relationship and things along those lines that makes you cringe through this film. Let me first state that I love Joe pesci I personally think his best and most funny film is "My cousin vinny" and also Danny Glover is good particularly in lethal weapon, but this film goes so wrong which is a shame because it could have been great. The main issue lies between the two characters, they over-emphasise the character relations by doing things like quoting past events way too often, saying there name to each other after every f**king sentence which makes your blood boil, and generally acting too goofy which is enough to put you off the film entirely which is a shame because I wanted to like this, I really did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Down in the Ever-Glades"!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    huntersrestkid1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is just a great film. Why on earth are people rating it so low and calling it bad? It's not a bad movie, its one of the best movies I've ever seen!! Joe Pesci and Danny Glover together on a fishing trip? Comedy awesomeness right there! I think the people that hated the awesome innocent family movies like this are just stupid. They go for the action shooter thriller WHATEVER movies, and thats cool but its not cool to hate on a film that is great just because of that. I have great taste in movies, so I know what I'm talking about. I like the modern movies, and know that most of the cutesy fun-filled family movies (that, not to mention, have music written specifically for them) are back in the 70s and 80s. I'm drawn to those types of movies the same as modern thrillers, if not more than. "Gone Fishin'" is a 1997 movie, and proof that the modern era still makes those fun filled great family films. PESCI AND GLOVER 4 LIFE!! Buy this film, and have fun Fishin'!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Childhood Favorite!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pumpkin_Man
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ever since I was a kid, I've loved this movie because of the hilarious situations that Gus & Joe would get into. Gus and Joe are bumbling best friends who are going on a fishing trip in The Everglades down in Florida. When they stop to get a bite to eat, they have friendly conversation with a man, who soon steals their car. From then on, nothing goes right like tying the boat wrong, to lighting a gas station on fire, to blowing up a fancy hotel, and much more. The man who stole their car is a murderer and a thief named Dekker Massey. When they finally find their car, there is a bloody knife and a map inside. They try to find the treasure, only to be taken hostage by Dekker. Will Gus and Joe stop Dekker and save the day? I highly recommend GONE FISHIN'!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No spoiler here gobshites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    noamshouseparty
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be honest I've never seen this film, but by the looks of it there's a fierce whiff o' paint off of it. Fook all that! I'm dead fuckkin' right! An almighty smell of paint. No room for paint. Joe Glover and Danny Pesci. I can review, AND use all the big words. Mmm-hmm, tis true I'll have ya know. Yep it is, it is true, very true. Oh indeed. Das right and Glover and Pesci agree with me on that one. A big old tin o' paint. What were they thinking'? There's no varnish in this film is there? I couldn't have that. Not that it would be any worse than paint, but still. It couldn't leave us any better off ya loony bastards. And here's a big long sentence, and there is ten lines of text. No serious reviews for this film fuckkers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bloody Brillo it is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brewphobe
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i think this film is absolutely incredible. the acting performances are really subtle but spell binding. people talk about taxi driver or raging bull as a classic but this is more my bag baby. the kings have arrived. move over Kubrick.... your nothing compared to the cinematic brilliance that is GONE FISHIN WOW WOWEE! Joe Pesci really excels with superb direction here. Danny Glover here is magnetic and plays the part immaculately justifying his performance considering Daniel Day Lewis and Sir Ian McKellen were turned down in favor of the Lethal weapon star..... and you thought he was too old for this s###. well f### you!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watchable but what a waste of Pesci and Glover's talent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spencer10
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think Joe Pesci and Danny Glover are very good actors. They can play great dramatic and comic roles. But with "Gone Fishin'" their first attempt at comedy together someone ought to encourage both Pesci and Glover not to make any other comedy movies together. It's obvious that the biggest problem with "Gone Fishin'" is its script. Pesci and Glover are not to blame they are trying to act good. Its the writers and director's fault. Some of the lines in this film are extremely annoying e.g. "This trip ain't even a one its a frigging zero", or when Pesci tells the film's villain that he is a freak about 10 times and tells him "why don't you join the army if your'e a tough guy you freak". The other problem is that with the exception of the first two "Home Alone" pictures you cannot give Joe Pesci a script that is PG rated and expect him to act funny with it. Joe Pesci needs stronger material. I am not saying they needed to make the film R rated with the f-word every other word, or extreme violence but why couldn't they make this like "Grumpy Old Men" and make it on a PG-13 rated level? If they would have done that this movie would have been ten times funnier. And why didn't they actually have Pesci and Glover actually go fishing in the movie instead of a million disasters preventing them from going fishing? They do not fish in the entire 94 minutes of the movie except for the finale. Danny Glover has made a few other movies since this one but I have only seen Joe Pesci do two other movies since this one. I am wondering if its because he was embarrassed by how he acted in this movie. "Gone Fishin'" certainly is not awful but its such a shame to see two exceptionally talented actors act with such an annoying awful script. Its the kind of movie you might want to watch if the weather is really bad outside and you have nothing better to do. But if you are a big fan of either Pesci or Glover you might want to avoid this one because they are trying to act good with a bad script and in the end they have made a pretty big mistake by making "Gone Fishin'"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its OK
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chesterfox40
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is not a big thing. Its just a regular comedy with a simple story. It has got good actors like Danny Glover and Joe Pesci. They do a good job playing the two fishermen Gus Green and Joe Waters. But everybody knows that both of them can do better. This movie is basically a story of two ordinary guys who face extraordinary situations. Like their car being stolen by a con artist, causing a fire in a hotel and fighting with a crocodile. This movie will bring some entertainment on a boring evening. You will have some laughs and be able to kill some time. However buying this movie is not a good idea, go rent it. If you saw it once its enough. 7/10 If you really want to see a good movie with Danny Glover and Joe Pesci then watch "Lethal Weapon 2". Joe Pesci is great in that movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    samueljoewaugh
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is one of those innocent films you just love, the critics were a little harsh on the rating, i remember seeing this when i was 9, i absolutely loved it, lots of action and fishing! which is what really interested me, although there are a lot of goofs i still enjoy this one from time to time and brings back those good childhood memories!. it is sad though that one of the stunt men died though, the movie is pretty interesting as the main actors are well known and are absolutely hilarious, the first time i saw this movie i laughed so hard i choked, Danny gloves and Joe pesci really make great actors together as there funny antics will keep you entertained! just don't miss out and watch this great old movie
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No big fish caught...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, this is pretty much your basic slapstick goof ball comedy. You have two fairly dim-witted people who aren't too keen on their surroundings and the havoc they wreak around them, and they get into a bunch if jiffies along the way. There, that was pretty much the lay down of the general story. Now, the performances of Pesci and Glover, are as usual, right on. They both did a good job with their roles, and the chemistry between the two worked marvelous. There are lots of situations throughout the movie that makes you cringe your toes in awkwardness, but the movie only managed to get a couple of laughs out in me. Lots of pulling on the smiles, but not really the type of comedy that makes you cringe over and laugh so hard you have tears trickling down your cheeks. The supporting roles were nicely filled out as well, though many of the characters in the movie were somewhat quirky. The movie is fairly wholesome to watch and good for an entertaining evening, but I say it is hardly the type of movie you return to again a second time, unless you are a die-hard Glover or Pesci fan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Rated R Plot Taken in a PG Matter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When looked at at a specific perspective, you can see what the producers were trying to do with Gone Fishin'. Make it a quirky, not very serious, fun kids movie. It seems they picked the two most serious actors for the job though. Danny Glover and Joe Pesci are good in lots of things they have been in, but this is just neither of them at their best. I think the problem was the PG rating. This could have been a great film if it had an R rating. Its almost like Glover and Pesci are struggling to hold back the words they want to use. You can tell Pesci just wants to blow off steam at points in the film. If this was R, it could have been a quirky, funny, and all out Comedy. Glover and Pesci play Gus and Joe, two average guys who want to get away and have a simple, relaxing vacation at the Everglades. They get way more than they ask for after having their car stolen at a restaurant. They realize the man who stole their car is a crook and a killer so Gus and Joe pair up with two girls looking for the man, for a little while, then go off on their own getting into their own trouble. They embark in every which way to try and stop the crook, but they just dig themselves deeper in a hole. Their stupidity doesn't help the situation one bit has both the leads are clueless and naive. But they are dependent on catching the guy and still making it home for Thanksgiving with their family. Once again, sometimes their stupidity tends to drag the film on which I've never been a fan of. Its just like in Dinner for Schmucks and Dumb and Dumberer: When Harry Met Lloyd. Stupidity is one thing, overwhelmingly stupid is another. It wears on you and almost makes you believe the actors are as dumb as they appear. But, thankfully, Gone Fishin' knows its limits and doesn't make the characters brainy, smartasses or make them bumbling nitwits. So the film doesn't fail there. While being completely harmless, at the same time, its overly kiddish. We saw Joe Pesci play stupid in Home Alone, but now, after seeing Casino and Goodfellas, I don't want to see him in a PG rated kid movie. Id rather have him be in an R rated Comedy where he can be himself and the same goes with Danny Glover. If this was R, it would probably earn another star, and quite possibly, another star in a half. But at least we get a relaxing opening driving scene with a great Willie Nelson tune in the background and a delightful appearance by him as well. Gone Fishin' was panned at the time, but it should also be taken into mind Janet Wilder was killed during a scene in this movie, so that doesn't give the movie a get-out-of-harsh-words free card, but it should just be said and maybe go easy on the movie. While Im not praising Gone Fishin', Im neither recommending it very far. Keep that in mind. Starring: Danny Glover, Joe Pesci, Nick Brimble, Rosanna Arquette, Lynn Whitfield, and Willie Nelson. Directed by: Christopher Cain.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even a Sunday afternoon movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movie Guy
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was terrible, and not because it's a nice light hearted comedy because I love them (grumpy old men type film) but this film tried too hard particularly with character development relationship and things along those lines that makes you cringe through this film. Let me first state that I love Joe pesci I personally think his best and most funny film is "My cousin vinny" and also Danny Glover is good particularly in lethal weapon, but this film goes so wrong which is a shame because it could have been great. The main issue lies between the two characters, they over-emphasise the character relations by doing things like quoting past events way too often, saying there name to each other after every f**king sentence which makes your blood boil, and generally acting too goofy which is enough to put you off the film entirely which is a shame because I wanted to like this, I really did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Down in the Ever-Glades"!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    huntersrestkid1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is just a great film. Why on earth are people rating it so low and calling it bad? It's not a bad movie, its one of the best movies I've ever seen!! Joe Pesci and Danny Glover together on a fishing trip? Comedy awesomeness right there! I think the people that hated the awesome innocent family movies like this are just stupid. They go for the action shooter thriller WHATEVER movies, and thats cool but its not cool to hate on a film that is great just because of that. I have great taste in movies, so I know what I'm talking about. I like the modern movies, and know that most of the cutesy fun-filled family movies (that, not to mention, have music written specifically for them) are back in the 70s and 80s. I'm drawn to those types of movies the same as modern thrillers, if not more than. "Gone Fishin'" is a 1997 movie, and proof that the modern era still makes those fun filled great family films. PESCI AND GLOVER 4 LIFE!! Buy this film, and have fun Fishin'!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Childhood Favorite!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pumpkin_Man
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ever since I was a kid, I've loved this movie because of the hilarious situations that Gus & Joe would get into. Gus and Joe are bumbling best friends who are going on a fishing trip in The Everglades down in Florida. When they stop to get a bite to eat, they have friendly conversation with a man, who soon steals their car. From then on, nothing goes right like tying the boat wrong, to lighting a gas station on fire, to blowing up a fancy hotel, and much more. The man who stole their car is a murderer and a thief named Dekker Massey. When they finally find their car, there is a bloody knife and a map inside. They try to find the treasure, only to be taken hostage by Dekker. Will Gus and Joe stop Dekker and save the day? I highly recommend GONE FISHIN'!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No spoiler here gobshites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    noamshouseparty
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be honest I've never seen this film, but by the looks of it there's a fierce whiff o' paint off of it. Fook all that! I'm dead fuckkin' right! An almighty smell of paint. No room for paint. Joe Glover and Danny Pesci. I can review, AND use all the big words. Mmm-hmm, tis true I'll have ya know. Yep it is, it is true, very true. Oh indeed. Das right and Glover and Pesci agree with me on that one. A big old tin o' paint. What were they thinking'? There's no varnish in this film is there? I couldn't have that. Not that it would be any worse than paint, but still. It couldn't leave us any better off ya loony bastards. And here's a big long sentence, and there is ten lines of text. No serious reviews for this film fuckkers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bloody Brillo it is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brewphobe
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i think this film is absolutely incredible. the acting performances are really subtle but spell binding. people talk about taxi driver or raging bull as a classic but this is more my bag baby. the kings have arrived. move over Kubrick.... your nothing compared to the cinematic brilliance that is GONE FISHIN WOW WOWEE! Joe Pesci really excels with superb direction here. Danny Glover here is magnetic and plays the part immaculately justifying his performance considering Daniel Day Lewis and Sir Ian McKellen were turned down in favor of the Lethal weapon star..... and you thought he was too old for this s###. well f### you!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watchable but what a waste of Pesci and Glover's talent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spencer10
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think Joe Pesci and Danny Glover are very good actors. They can play great dramatic and comic roles. But with "Gone Fishin'" their first attempt at comedy together someone ought to encourage both Pesci and Glover not to make any other comedy movies together. It's obvious that the biggest problem with "Gone Fishin'" is its script. Pesci and Glover are not to blame they are trying to act good. Its the writers and director's fault. Some of the lines in this film are extremely annoying e.g. "This trip ain't even a one its a frigging zero", or when Pesci tells the film's villain that he is a freak about 10 times and tells him "why don't you join the army if your'e a tough guy you freak". The other problem is that with the exception of the first two "Home Alone" pictures you cannot give Joe Pesci a script that is PG rated and expect him to act funny with it. Joe Pesci needs stronger material. I am not saying they needed to make the film R rated with the f-word every other word, or extreme violence but why couldn't they make this like "Grumpy Old Men" and make it on a PG-13 rated level? If they would have done that this movie would have been ten times funnier. And why didn't they actually have Pesci and Glover actually go fishing in the movie instead of a million disasters preventing them from going fishing? They do not fish in the entire 94 minutes of the movie except for the finale. Danny Glover has made a few other movies since this one but I have only seen Joe Pesci do two other movies since this one. I am wondering if its because he was embarrassed by how he acted in this movie. "Gone Fishin'" certainly is not awful but its such a shame to see two exceptionally talented actors act with such an annoying awful script. Its the kind of movie you might want to watch if the weather is really bad outside and you have nothing better to do. But if you are a big fan of either Pesci or Glover you might want to avoid this one because they are trying to act good with a bad script and in the end they have made a pretty big mistake by making "Gone Fishin'"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its OK
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chesterfox40
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is not a big thing. Its just a regular comedy with a simple story. It has got good actors like Danny Glover and Joe Pesci. They do a good job playing the two fishermen Gus Green and Joe Waters. But everybody knows that both of them can do better. This movie is basically a story of two ordinary guys who face extraordinary situations. Like their car being stolen by a con artist, causing a fire in a hotel and fighting with a crocodile. This movie will bring some entertainment on a boring evening. You will have some laughs and be able to kill some time. However buying this movie is not a good idea, go rent it. If you saw it once its enough. 7/10 If you really want to see a good movie with Danny Glover and Joe Pesci then watch "Lethal Weapon 2". Joe Pesci is great in that movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    samueljoewaugh
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is one of those innocent films you just love, the critics were a little harsh on the rating, i remember seeing this when i was 9, i absolutely loved it, lots of action and fishing! which is what really interested me, although there are a lot of goofs i still enjoy this one from time to time and brings back those good childhood memories!. it is sad though that one of the stunt men died though, the movie is pretty interesting as the main actors are well known and are absolutely hilarious, the first time i saw this movie i laughed so hard i choked, Danny gloves and Joe pesci really make great actors together as there funny antics will keep you entertained! just don't miss out and watch this great old movie
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No big fish caught...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, this is pretty much your basic slapstick goof ball comedy. You have two fairly dim-witted people who aren't too keen on their surroundings and the havoc they wreak around them, and they get into a bunch if jiffies along the way. There, that was pretty much the lay down of the general story. Now, the performances of Pesci and Glover, are as usual, right on. They both did a good job with their roles, and the chemistry between the two worked marvelous. There are lots of situations throughout the movie that makes you cringe your toes in awkwardness, but the movie only managed to get a couple of laughs out in me. Lots of pulling on the smiles, but not really the type of comedy that makes you cringe over and laugh so hard you have tears trickling down your cheeks. The supporting roles were nicely filled out as well, though many of the characters in the movie were somewhat quirky. The movie is fairly wholesome to watch and good for an entertaining evening, but I say it is hardly the type of movie you return to again a second time, unless you are a die-hard Glover or Pesci fan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Rated R Plot Taken in a PG Matter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When looked at at a specific perspective, you can see what the producers were trying to do with Gone Fishin'. Make it a quirky, not very serious, fun kids movie. It seems they picked the two most serious actors for the job though. Danny Glover and Joe Pesci are good in lots of things they have been in, but this is just neither of them at their best. I think the problem was the PG rating. This could have been a great film if it had an R rating. Its almost like Glover and Pesci are struggling to hold back the words they want to use. You can tell Pesci just wants to blow off steam at points in the film. If this was R, it could have been a quirky, funny, and all out Comedy. Glover and Pesci play Gus and Joe, two average guys who want to get away and have a simple, relaxing vacation at the Everglades. They get way more than they ask for after having their car stolen at a restaurant. They realize the man who stole their car is a crook and a killer so Gus and Joe pair up with two girls looking for the man, for a little while, then go off on their own getting into their own trouble. They embark in every which way to try and stop the crook, but they just dig themselves deeper in a hole. Their stupidity doesn't help the situation one bit has both the leads are clueless and naive. But they are dependent on catching the guy and still making it home for Thanksgiving with their family. Once again, sometimes their stupidity tends to drag the film on which I've never been a fan of. Its just like in Dinner for Schmucks and Dumb and Dumberer: When Harry Met Lloyd. Stupidity is one thing, overwhelmingly stupid is another. It wears on you and almost makes you believe the actors are as dumb as they appear. But, thankfully, Gone Fishin' knows its limits and doesn't make the characters brainy, smartasses or make them bumbling nitwits. So the film doesn't fail there. While being completely harmless, at the same time, its overly kiddish. We saw Joe Pesci play stupid in Home Alone, but now, after seeing Casino and Goodfellas, I don't want to see him in a PG rated kid movie. Id rather have him be in an R rated Comedy where he can be himself and the same goes with Danny Glover. If this was R, it would probably earn another star, and quite possibly, another star in a half. But at least we get a relaxing opening driving scene with a great Willie Nelson tune in the background and a delightful appearance by him as well. Gone Fishin' was panned at the time, but it should also be taken into mind Janet Wilder was killed during a scene in this movie, so that doesn't give the movie a get-out-of-harsh-words free card, but it should just be said and maybe go easy on the movie. While Im not praising Gone Fishin', Im neither recommending it very far. Keep that in mind. Starring: Danny Glover, Joe Pesci, Nick Brimble, Rosanna Arquette, Lynn Whitfield, and Willie Nelson. Directed by: Christopher Cain.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even a Sunday afternoon movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movie Guy
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was terrible, and not because it's a nice light hearted comedy because I love them (grumpy old men type film) but this film tried too hard particularly with character development relationship and things along those lines that makes you cringe through this film. Let me first state that I love Joe pesci I personally think his best and most funny film is "My cousin vinny" and also Danny Glover is good particularly in lethal weapon, but this film goes so wrong which is a shame because it could have been great. The main issue lies between the two characters, they over-emphasise the character relations by doing things like quoting past events way too often, saying there name to each other after every f**king sentence which makes your blood boil, and generally acting too goofy which is enough to put you off the film entirely which is a shame because I wanted to like this, I really did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Down in the Ever-Glades"!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    huntersrestkid1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is just a great film. Why on earth are people rating it so low and calling it bad? It's not a bad movie, its one of the best movies I've ever seen!! Joe Pesci and Danny Glover together on a fishing trip? Comedy awesomeness right there! I think the people that hated the awesome innocent family movies like this are just stupid. They go for the action shooter thriller WHATEVER movies, and thats cool but its not cool to hate on a film that is great just because of that. I have great taste in movies, so I know what I'm talking about. I like the modern movies, and know that most of the cutesy fun-filled family movies (that, not to mention, have music written specifically for them) are back in the 70s and 80s. I'm drawn to those types of movies the same as modern thrillers, if not more than. "Gone Fishin'" is a 1997 movie, and proof that the modern era still makes those fun filled great family films. PESCI AND GLOVER 4 LIFE!! Buy this film, and have fun Fishin'!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Childhood Favorite!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pumpkin_Man
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ever since I was a kid, I've loved this movie because of the hilarious situations that Gus & Joe would get into. Gus and Joe are bumbling best friends who are going on a fishing trip in The Everglades down in Florida. When they stop to get a bite to eat, they have friendly conversation with a man, who soon steals their car. From then on, nothing goes right like tying the boat wrong, to lighting a gas station on fire, to blowing up a fancy hotel, and much more. The man who stole their car is a murderer and a thief named Dekker Massey. When they finally find their car, there is a bloody knife and a map inside. They try to find the treasure, only to be taken hostage by Dekker. Will Gus and Joe stop Dekker and save the day? I highly recommend GONE FISHIN'!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No spoiler here gobshites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    noamshouseparty
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be honest I've never seen this film, but by the looks of it there's a fierce whiff o' paint off of it. Fook all that! I'm dead fuckkin' right! An almighty smell of paint. No room for paint. Joe Glover and Danny Pesci. I can review, AND use all the big words. Mmm-hmm, tis true I'll have ya know. Yep it is, it is true, very true. Oh indeed. Das right and Glover and Pesci agree with me on that one. A big old tin o' paint. What were they thinking'? There's no varnish in this film is there? I couldn't have that. Not that it would be any worse than paint, but still. It couldn't leave us any better off ya loony bastards. And here's a big long sentence, and there is ten lines of text. No serious reviews for this film fuckkers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bloody Brillo it is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brewphobe
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i think this film is absolutely incredible. the acting performances are really subtle but spell binding. people talk about taxi driver or raging bull as a classic but this is more my bag baby. the kings have arrived. move over Kubrick.... your nothing compared to the cinematic brilliance that is GONE FISHIN WOW WOWEE! Joe Pesci really excels with superb direction here. Danny Glover here is magnetic and plays the part immaculately justifying his performance considering Daniel Day Lewis and Sir Ian McKellen were turned down in favor of the Lethal weapon star..... and you thought he was too old for this s###. well f### you!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watchable but what a waste of Pesci and Glover's talent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spencer10
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think Joe Pesci and Danny Glover are very good actors. They can play great dramatic and comic roles. But with "Gone Fishin'" their first attempt at comedy together someone ought to encourage both Pesci and Glover not to make any other comedy movies together. It's obvious that the biggest problem with "Gone Fishin'" is its script. Pesci and Glover are not to blame they are trying to act good. Its the writers and director's fault. Some of the lines in this film are extremely annoying e.g. "This trip ain't even a one its a frigging zero", or when Pesci tells the film's villain that he is a freak about 10 times and tells him "why don't you join the army if your'e a tough guy you freak". The other problem is that with the exception of the first two "Home Alone" pictures you cannot give Joe Pesci a script that is PG rated and expect him to act funny with it. Joe Pesci needs stronger material. I am not saying they needed to make the film R rated with the f-word every other word, or extreme violence but why couldn't they make this like "Grumpy Old Men" and make it on a PG-13 rated level? If they would have done that this movie would have been ten times funnier. And why didn't they actually have Pesci and Glover actually go fishing in the movie instead of a million disasters preventing them from going fishing? They do not fish in the entire 94 minutes of the movie except for the finale. Danny Glover has made a few other movies since this one but I have only seen Joe Pesci do two other movies since this one. I am wondering if its because he was embarrassed by how he acted in this movie. "Gone Fishin'" certainly is not awful but its such a shame to see two exceptionally talented actors act with such an annoying awful script. Its the kind of movie you might want to watch if the weather is really bad outside and you have nothing better to do. But if you are a big fan of either Pesci or Glover you might want to avoid this one because they are trying to act good with a bad script and in the end they have made a pretty big mistake by making "Gone Fishin'"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its OK
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chesterfox40
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is not a big thing. Its just a regular comedy with a simple story. It has got good actors like Danny Glover and Joe Pesci. They do a good job playing the two fishermen Gus Green and Joe Waters. But everybody knows that both of them can do better. This movie is basically a story of two ordinary guys who face extraordinary situations. Like their car being stolen by a con artist, causing a fire in a hotel and fighting with a crocodile. This movie will bring some entertainment on a boring evening. You will have some laughs and be able to kill some time. However buying this movie is not a good idea, go rent it. If you saw it once its enough. 7/10 If you really want to see a good movie with Danny Glover and Joe Pesci then watch "Lethal Weapon 2". Joe Pesci is great in that movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    samueljoewaugh
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is one of those innocent films you just love, the critics were a little harsh on the rating, i remember seeing this when i was 9, i absolutely loved it, lots of action and fishing! which is what really interested me, although there are a lot of goofs i still enjoy this one from time to time and brings back those good childhood memories!. it is sad though that one of the stunt men died though, the movie is pretty interesting as the main actors are well known and are absolutely hilarious, the first time i saw this movie i laughed so hard i choked, Danny gloves and Joe pesci really make great actors together as there funny antics will keep you entertained! just don't miss out and watch this great old movie
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No big fish caught...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, this is pretty much your basic slapstick goof ball comedy. You have two fairly dim-witted people who aren't too keen on their surroundings and the havoc they wreak around them, and they get into a bunch if jiffies along the way. There, that was pretty much the lay down of the general story. Now, the performances of Pesci and Glover, are as usual, right on. They both did a good job with their roles, and the chemistry between the two worked marvelous. There are lots of situations throughout the movie that makes you cringe your toes in awkwardness, but the movie only managed to get a couple of laughs out in me. Lots of pulling on the smiles, but not really the type of comedy that makes you cringe over and laugh so hard you have tears trickling down your cheeks. The supporting roles were nicely filled out as well, though many of the characters in the movie were somewhat quirky. The movie is fairly wholesome to watch and good for an entertaining evening, but I say it is hardly the type of movie you return to again a second time, unless you are a die-hard Glover or Pesci fan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Rated R Plot Taken in a PG Matter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When looked at at a specific perspective, you can see what the producers were trying to do with Gone Fishin'. Make it a quirky, not very serious, fun kids movie. It seems they picked the two most serious actors for the job though. Danny Glover and Joe Pesci are good in lots of things they have been in, but this is just neither of them at their best. I think the problem was the PG rating. This could have been a great film if it had an R rating. Its almost like Glover and Pesci are struggling to hold back the words they want to use. You can tell Pesci just wants to blow off steam at points in the film. If this was R, it could have been a quirky, funny, and all out Comedy. Glover and Pesci play Gus and Joe, two average guys who want to get away and have a simple, relaxing vacation at the Everglades. They get way more than they ask for after having their car stolen at a restaurant. They realize the man who stole their car is a crook and a killer so Gus and Joe pair up with two girls looking for the man, for a little while, then go off on their own getting into their own trouble. They embark in every which way to try and stop the crook, but they just dig themselves deeper in a hole. Their stupidity doesn't help the situation one bit has both the leads are clueless and naive. But they are dependent on catching the guy and still making it home for Thanksgiving with their family. Once again, sometimes their stupidity tends to drag the film on which I've never been a fan of. Its just like in Dinner for Schmucks and Dumb and Dumberer: When Harry Met Lloyd. Stupidity is one thing, overwhelmingly stupid is another. It wears on you and almost makes you believe the actors are as dumb as they appear. But, thankfully, Gone Fishin' knows its limits and doesn't make the characters brainy, smartasses or make them bumbling nitwits. So the film doesn't fail there. While being completely harmless, at the same time, its overly kiddish. We saw Joe Pesci play stupid in Home Alone, but now, after seeing Casino and Goodfellas, I don't want to see him in a PG rated kid movie. Id rather have him be in an R rated Comedy where he can be himself and the same goes with Danny Glover. If this was R, it would probably earn another star, and quite possibly, another star in a half. But at least we get a relaxing opening driving scene with a great Willie Nelson tune in the background and a delightful appearance by him as well. Gone Fishin' was panned at the time, but it should also be taken into mind Janet Wilder was killed during a scene in this movie, so that doesn't give the movie a get-out-of-harsh-words free card, but it should just be said and maybe go easy on the movie. While Im not praising Gone Fishin', Im neither recommending it very far. Keep that in mind. Starring: Danny Glover, Joe Pesci, Nick Brimble, Rosanna Arquette, Lynn Whitfield, and Willie Nelson. Directed by: Christopher Cain.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even a Sunday afternoon movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movie Guy
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was terrible, and not because it's a nice light hearted comedy because I love them (grumpy old men type film) but this film tried too hard particularly with character development relationship and things along those lines that makes you cringe through this film. Let me first state that I love Joe pesci I personally think his best and most funny film is "My cousin vinny" and also Danny Glover is good particularly in lethal weapon, but this film goes so wrong which is a shame because it could have been great. The main issue lies between the two characters, they over-emphasise the character relations by doing things like quoting past events way too often, saying there name to each other after every f**king sentence which makes your blood boil, and generally acting too goofy which is enough to put you off the film entirely which is a shame because I wanted to like this, I really did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Down in the Ever-Glades"!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    huntersrestkid1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is just a great film. Why on earth are people rating it so low and calling it bad? It's not a bad movie, its one of the best movies I've ever seen!! Joe Pesci and Danny Glover together on a fishing trip? Comedy awesomeness right there! I think the people that hated the awesome innocent family movies like this are just stupid. They go for the action shooter thriller WHATEVER movies, and thats cool but its not cool to hate on a film that is great just because of that. I have great taste in movies, so I know what I'm talking about. I like the modern movies, and know that most of the cutesy fun-filled family movies (that, not to mention, have music written specifically for them) are back in the 70s and 80s. I'm drawn to those types of movies the same as modern thrillers, if not more than. "Gone Fishin'" is a 1997 movie, and proof that the modern era still makes those fun filled great family films. PESCI AND GLOVER 4 LIFE!! Buy this film, and have fun Fishin'!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Childhood Favorite!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pumpkin_Man
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ever since I was a kid, I've loved this movie because of the hilarious situations that Gus & Joe would get into. Gus and Joe are bumbling best friends who are going on a fishing trip in The Everglades down in Florida. When they stop to get a bite to eat, they have friendly conversation with a man, who soon steals their car. From then on, nothing goes right like tying the boat wrong, to lighting a gas station on fire, to blowing up a fancy hotel, and much more. The man who stole their car is a murderer and a thief named Dekker Massey. When they finally find their car, there is a bloody knife and a map inside. They try to find the treasure, only to be taken hostage by Dekker. Will Gus and Joe stop Dekker and save the day? I highly recommend GONE FISHIN'!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No spoiler here gobshites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    noamshouseparty
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be honest I've never seen this film, but by the looks of it there's a fierce whiff o' paint off of it. Fook all that! I'm dead fuckkin' right! An almighty smell of paint. No room for paint. Joe Glover and Danny Pesci. I can review, AND use all the big words. Mmm-hmm, tis true I'll have ya know. Yep it is, it is true, very true. Oh indeed. Das right and Glover and Pesci agree with me on that one. A big old tin o' paint. What were they thinking'? There's no varnish in this film is there? I couldn't have that. Not that it would be any worse than paint, but still. It couldn't leave us any better off ya loony bastards. And here's a big long sentence, and there is ten lines of text. No serious reviews for this film fuckkers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bloody Brillo it is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brewphobe
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i think this film is absolutely incredible. the acting performances are really subtle but spell binding. people talk about taxi driver or raging bull as a classic but this is more my bag baby. the kings have arrived. move over Kubrick.... your nothing compared to the cinematic brilliance that is GONE FISHIN WOW WOWEE! Joe Pesci really excels with superb direction here. Danny Glover here is magnetic and plays the part immaculately justifying his performance considering Daniel Day Lewis and Sir Ian McKellen were turned down in favor of the Lethal weapon star..... and you thought he was too old for this s###. well f### you!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watchable but what a waste of Pesci and Glover's talent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spencer10
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think Joe Pesci and Danny Glover are very good actors. They can play great dramatic and comic roles. But with "Gone Fishin'" their first attempt at comedy together someone ought to encourage both Pesci and Glover not to make any other comedy movies together. It's obvious that the biggest problem with "Gone Fishin'" is its script. Pesci and Glover are not to blame they are trying to act good. Its the writers and director's fault. Some of the lines in this film are extremely annoying e.g. "This trip ain't even a one its a frigging zero", or when Pesci tells the film's villain that he is a freak about 10 times and tells him "why don't you join the army if your'e a tough guy you freak". The other problem is that with the exception of the first two "Home Alone" pictures you cannot give Joe Pesci a script that is PG rated and expect him to act funny with it. Joe Pesci needs stronger material. I am not saying they needed to make the film R rated with the f-word every other word, or extreme violence but why couldn't they make this like "Grumpy Old Men" and make it on a PG-13 rated level? If they would have done that this movie would have been ten times funnier. And why didn't they actually have Pesci and Glover actually go fishing in the movie instead of a million disasters preventing them from going fishing? They do not fish in the entire 94 minutes of the movie except for the finale. Danny Glover has made a few other movies since this one but I have only seen Joe Pesci do two other movies since this one. I am wondering if its because he was embarrassed by how he acted in this movie. "Gone Fishin'" certainly is not awful but its such a shame to see two exceptionally talented actors act with such an annoying awful script. Its the kind of movie you might want to watch if the weather is really bad outside and you have nothing better to do. But if you are a big fan of either Pesci or Glover you might want to avoid this one because they are trying to act good with a bad script and in the end they have made a pretty big mistake by making "Gone Fishin'"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its OK
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chesterfox40
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is not a big thing. Its just a regular comedy with a simple story. It has got good actors like Danny Glover and Joe Pesci. They do a good job playing the two fishermen Gus Green and Joe Waters. But everybody knows that both of them can do better. This movie is basically a story of two ordinary guys who face extraordinary situations. Like their car being stolen by a con artist, causing a fire in a hotel and fighting with a crocodile. This movie will bring some entertainment on a boring evening. You will have some laughs and be able to kill some time. However buying this movie is not a good idea, go rent it. If you saw it once its enough. 7/10 If you really want to see a good movie with Danny Glover and Joe Pesci then watch "Lethal Weapon 2". Joe Pesci is great in that movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
