<filme>
 <id>
  126
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0117718
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  The Spitfire Grill - O Recome&ccedil;o
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Percy, upon being released from prison, goes to the small town of Gillead, to find a place where she can start over again. She is taken in by Hannah, to help out at her place, the Spitfire ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Percy, upon being released from prison, goes to the small town of Gillead, to find a place where she can start over again. She is taken in by Hannah, to help out at her place, the Spitfire Grill. Percy brings change to the small town, stirring resentment and fear in some, and growth in others.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   small town
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   prison
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   church
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   new england
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   telephone call
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Lee David Zlotoff
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Lee David Zlotoff
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Alison Elliott
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ellen Burstyn
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Marcia Gay Harden
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Male or Female, that is the only question you need ask
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    snafux7
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me make it simple for everyone... If you are a woman (especially if you happen to currently be menstruating) you will positively adore this movie. Just sit back with a glass of zinfandel and a box of tissues and enjoy. It is heavy-handed melodrama and clich&eacute; 'character' acting by all the usual female stereotypes but sometimes that isn't always a bad thing. I realize that this probably sounds condescending and insensitive so in advance let me apologize and recognize that everything I say is wrong anyway. If you are a dude on the other hand I hope and pray for you that you have a 2nd TV located in another room, preferably hooked up to a PS3 or XBOX so that you can properly recalibrate your testosterone level after watching the first 20 mins of this train wreck. It has absolutely nothing of interest to you, trust me. You know that feeling you get when you're alone in a room of women all talking at the same time and you can't leave? Now imagine an hour and a half of that with no respite, every time you think it cannot possibly go any further down the rabbit hole of "I do not give a f$*k" it somehow manages to kick it up a notch. As an aside, I was born and raised in the Northeast and the vast majority of 'Maine' accents in this film are about on par with the 'British' accents of Natalie Portman and Keanu Reeves, its pretty damn bad. Personally I think the average woman would give this 8-9 stars and the average guy would give it 1 or 2 so in all fairness I'm splitting the difference, we're it just up to me I'd give it either 1 or 0.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Over-hyped
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sir_brettley
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was allegedly a critical success but in reality it's a plodding, overwrought film that never really gets going. The characters are shallow and the alleged protagonist is a "Mary Sue". While I was led to believe that the film would be a wonderful account of people and complexities of relationships all I saw was bad writing and worse acting. While the written version and Biblical allegories of forgiveness and healing may work, this theatrical version misses the mark. I suppose if you have a pariah complex you can relate to this movie but for everyone else it's a waste of time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In Which a Woman is Saved by Being So Darn Plucky n Cute!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    someofusarebrave
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the kind of totally misogynistic movie that does such an excellent job of masquerading as a movie about female empowerment that it fools all but the most discerning types. There would be nothing wrong with that, except that it lulls us all into a false state of comfort. Police will always be kind, gentle folk, escaped convicts will always be 'really good' at heart, and a woman can be rescued from the worst types of spiritual and emotional pain by the 'power of the penis'. If only, right? Wrong. The world is not like that. In this world we all live in, police rape young homeless woman wandering around on their own as often as they help them out. Women who have been convicted of felonies rarely get second chances, regardless of how generous or good-hearted they happen to be. People are shaped by their circumstances and rarely manage to "rise above" them, instead dragging everyone else down with them often as not. There are no second chances. Nor should there be. Women who murder ought not to be let off the hook from the ramifications of their actions for "good behavior." Policemen ought not do the job of the non-government organizations and social programs which do not exist in the South for all intents and purposes. We ought not be able to work or charm our way out of being who we are. Everyone deserves the opportunity to start again, but part of that process MUST involve some acknowledgment of why things went so badly wrong in the first place. Teaching young girls that all they have to do to improve their lives is to trust the people around them unconditionally to help them out of any scrape they get into is morally bankrupt. Movies like this one do a terrible job of preparing young girls for the world they will actually be entering upon adulthood. It does a terrible job of describing the world they exist in now. We need to learn how to be less sweet and giving, rather than more so. Women are taught to be caring at the cost of everything we love about our lives and ourselves. Because we are so open-hearted, we are easily taken advantage of in our naivete. We need movie heroines who encourage us to be MORE wary, more suspicious of who we place our trust in, rather than less. We need heroines willing to stand on their own two feet and to work to accomplish their own dreams, rather than to fight for the dreams of those around them without a thought for themselves. In real life, this kind of goodness is boring...it is scrappiness, it is the willingness to stand one's ground and to fight for one's right to exist at all costs, that makes a life entertaining to watch and live. Instead, what this movie does is make us resent the people around us for achieving less than the perfection that the main characters of this movie achieve. We also hate ourselves for being less than wholly sweet. No man will ever solve all a woman's problems for her. No woman can work her way into redemption by serving the people around her rather than serving herself. There is no opportunity for healing without pride. No one can work themselves out of a pit of despair without honesty. May I live to see the day when movies all represent heroines of reality, rather than of male fantasies of what a 'real woman' should be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bittersweet look at small-town life and the vagaries of doing good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    has43
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I rated this movie 5/10 only because I truly hate the ending. Is the author saying Percy HAD to die to redeem everyone else? If so, that really stinks. God knows what her life was life before she took her tormentor out. AND after. Reminds me of "A Tree Grows In Brooklyn." The mother killed the man who raped her daughter, but after awhile all that anyone seems to remember is that she was convicted of murder. And then there's "Mystic River," wherein Tim Robbins' character was molested as a young boy by two priests, barely escapes with his life, such things were not discussed at that time, he lived with his pain, and then is taken out, and his murderer justifies the unfortunate wrongful murder, but we're left hanging as to any justice occurring, whatsoever. Also, I cannot abide Will Patton, in anything I've seen him in. Otherwise, I think the movie was pretty extraordinary, and I wish I'd walked out of the theater before the ending. If the author ever reads these reviews, I do wish he would explain the ending. Thank you for listening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bittersweet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alohahome
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very touching but bittersweet independent film. Slow and gentle. It concerns a young woman named Percy who wishes to reconcile her unsavory past in the small town of Giliad Maine but she is haunted by the very past that she wishes to overcome. Many people would like a chance to start over but life does not always afford then that opportunity. Nonetheless, we all still do affect others in ways that are not always seen. And therein lies the tale of redemption. A redemption that is sometimes too late in coming. Yet there is still hope in the unfairness all around us. And compassion to be found. Don't expect a Hollywood ending here. But who really wants one in this context? It's been said that Hollyweood films depict life as we would like to see it. But independent films depict life as it is. Small towns are hesitant enough about welcoming newcomers, yet Percy's arrival and her spirit is sensed as being something altogether different and the town finds itself changed forever. The inviting musical score by James Horner renders a sweet ambiance, consoling with a subdued drifty quality that lulls the soul in its wake.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spitfire Grill-Get The Charcoal Ready for this One ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whatever became of Alison Elliott, the heroine of this film? She gave an extremely believable performance here as a woman released from prison for killing the stepfather who had impregnated her and then had caused the death of the baby by beating the mother. Ellen Burstyn is the old lady who Elliott goes to work for. As always, Burstyn again proves that she is at her best when she does her mean, crotchety acting. It's another fine job. The story will tug at your heart since it's a tragic one. It again proves that you can't always judge people by what has happened in their lives. This misconception brings on the tragedy at the end that will drive you to tears. Note an interesting performance by Marcia Gay Harden, as a blond, worker of the Burstyn character who befriends Elliott. This is a very good study of rural life and human relationships.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gilead
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Furuya Shiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like movies that have lasting effect in my mind, and that make me think about the meaning of some scenes over and over. This movie is that kind. There may be many similar movies but this one is different from any of those. A young woman gets off a bus in a small excluded town Gilead in Mane, US. In this town, three women who have different kinds of psychological trauma as a mother work together in a restaurant "The Spitfire Grill". The protagonist is Percy (Alison Elliot). There are mysteries in her words and behavior. But as the story goes, the deep scar in her mind hidden behind the mystery is gradually revealed. The second woman is Hannah (Ellen Burstyn). She runs a restaurant "Spitfire Grill". She has her own, deep scar in her mind. The third is Shelby (Marcia Gay Harden). Though she is very warmhearted, her husband always insults her. Maybe she is the one you can easily empathize. Perhaps, there is a meaning in the name of the town, Gilead. At the near end of the movie, we hear a black spiritual song "There is a balm in Gilead". The name Gilead comes from biblical world, which produces frankincense that was much-prized as medicine. The first stanza of the song is as follows: There is a balm in Gilead / To make the wounded whole; / There is a balm in Gilead / To heal the sin sick soul. The key to understand the heart of the movie may be in the lyrics.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Burstyn's worth a look, but artificiality grills what's left over...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pure corn. A female ex-con in a small community in Maine gets waitressing job at the local diner, enlightening everyone there with her presence. Resolutely old-fashioned hokum is replete with pseudo-meaningful platitudes and female bonding (with divergent accents). Acquired at the Sundance Film Festival for what was reported to be a princely sum, Castle Rock barely distributed this after the reviews came in (they were probably hoping for another "Fried Green Tomatoes" but got rotten tomatoes instead). Trifling nonsense tries for a prestigious look, but even this fails as the moody ambiance resembles nothing more than encroaching mold. It at least gave work to Ellen Burstyn, whose professionalism and mere presence saves this from oblivion. Otherwise, a prime candidate for Lifetime's four a.m. movie. * from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The trepidation of accepting an ex-con in a country setting.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john-jennings-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I happen to love chick flicks-if that is what this film is categorized as.I love this movie, as do so many others who've made comments before me in the IMDb site. It was one of those films where I held my breath throughout, sensing an evil that would probably overtake the heroine before the picture ended.And so it did. The ending angered me greatly...here we have this wonderful character Percy who begins to grow on the residents and is finally being accepted,except for one mouthy,jealous bigot,- real-estate agent Nahum Goddard,who will not accept Percy into their midst.This misshapen belief finally leads to a grave misunderstanding by the citizenry who hunt Percy down, which ends in her drowning in a rushing stream. At the end Nahum admits he was wrong to judge Percy so harshly but darn it all the harm has been done. I was angry at director Lee David Zlotoff who had the "power" to make this a happy ending. He wrote the script!!! Let's say for example that Nahum Goddard had drowned saving Percy in that stream. The man would have gone to his death via an act of redemption (isn't that a religious quality held dear by a tight Christian community) and our heroine would have gone on living happily ever after in a comfortable setting. I saw this film when it came out, and I even have 2-3 copies of it on DVD and VHS but I can just not watch it again. I know how sad the ending will be. I still give the film a 9 1/2 though,it was still a great production.(I need to express my ratings in fractions). If Percy had not been killed off I would have given it a 10 for perfection, no question. I'm sorry, but if a beloved character is killed off "unnecssarily", then I can not give the film a 10. Too bad I had not been in one of the advance screenings to express my views. If film companies and the Director/Producer want a 10 from me they had better try for a happy,or at least satisfying ending if at all possible. So much of life is a tragedy and that's why in part we go to the movies to get away from reality, to get a quick shot of hope and to see some element of happiness, even in dramatic circumstances.Percy did not deserve to die after all of us had fallen so much in love with her persona. Could we stand a Spitfire Grill 2 where she miraculously appears one day alive and well? Probably not...Darn it all Lee David Zlotoff, what were you thinking?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once again Hollywood's reviews mean nothing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sam Poynter
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie got pretty bad reviews from the Hollywood Hype-mongers. I suppose because it didn't have a lot of flash. All it had was a well-written original story and superb acting with real characters. Anyone who has ever spent time in a small town can identify with nearly all the characters. I could practically name them all in the town I grew up in. I'm sure the only people who would NOT enjoy this movie are the ones who grew up in Hollywood and believe everyone is like them. If thats not you, rent this movie for a truly enjoyable evening. But you might want to bring tissues. It's a very warm and often funny movie, but it's also very sad in some places. Will Patton is incredible and I honestly don't understand why Alison Elliott hasn't been used more than she has since this movie. Ellen Burstyn was glorious as ever :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Male or Female, that is the only question you need ask
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    snafux7
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me make it simple for everyone... If you are a woman (especially if you happen to currently be menstruating) you will positively adore this movie. Just sit back with a glass of zinfandel and a box of tissues and enjoy. It is heavy-handed melodrama and clich&eacute; 'character' acting by all the usual female stereotypes but sometimes that isn't always a bad thing. I realize that this probably sounds condescending and insensitive so in advance let me apologize and recognize that everything I say is wrong anyway. If you are a dude on the other hand I hope and pray for you that you have a 2nd TV located in another room, preferably hooked up to a PS3 or XBOX so that you can properly recalibrate your testosterone level after watching the first 20 mins of this train wreck. It has absolutely nothing of interest to you, trust me. You know that feeling you get when you're alone in a room of women all talking at the same time and you can't leave? Now imagine an hour and a half of that with no respite, every time you think it cannot possibly go any further down the rabbit hole of "I do not give a f$*k" it somehow manages to kick it up a notch. As an aside, I was born and raised in the Northeast and the vast majority of 'Maine' accents in this film are about on par with the 'British' accents of Natalie Portman and Keanu Reeves, its pretty damn bad. Personally I think the average woman would give this 8-9 stars and the average guy would give it 1 or 2 so in all fairness I'm splitting the difference, we're it just up to me I'd give it either 1 or 0.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Over-hyped
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sir_brettley
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was allegedly a critical success but in reality it's a plodding, overwrought film that never really gets going. The characters are shallow and the alleged protagonist is a "Mary Sue". While I was led to believe that the film would be a wonderful account of people and complexities of relationships all I saw was bad writing and worse acting. While the written version and Biblical allegories of forgiveness and healing may work, this theatrical version misses the mark. I suppose if you have a pariah complex you can relate to this movie but for everyone else it's a waste of time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In Which a Woman is Saved by Being So Darn Plucky n Cute!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    someofusarebrave
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the kind of totally misogynistic movie that does such an excellent job of masquerading as a movie about female empowerment that it fools all but the most discerning types. There would be nothing wrong with that, except that it lulls us all into a false state of comfort. Police will always be kind, gentle folk, escaped convicts will always be 'really good' at heart, and a woman can be rescued from the worst types of spiritual and emotional pain by the 'power of the penis'. If only, right? Wrong. The world is not like that. In this world we all live in, police rape young homeless woman wandering around on their own as often as they help them out. Women who have been convicted of felonies rarely get second chances, regardless of how generous or good-hearted they happen to be. People are shaped by their circumstances and rarely manage to "rise above" them, instead dragging everyone else down with them often as not. There are no second chances. Nor should there be. Women who murder ought not to be let off the hook from the ramifications of their actions for "good behavior." Policemen ought not do the job of the non-government organizations and social programs which do not exist in the South for all intents and purposes. We ought not be able to work or charm our way out of being who we are. Everyone deserves the opportunity to start again, but part of that process MUST involve some acknowledgment of why things went so badly wrong in the first place. Teaching young girls that all they have to do to improve their lives is to trust the people around them unconditionally to help them out of any scrape they get into is morally bankrupt. Movies like this one do a terrible job of preparing young girls for the world they will actually be entering upon adulthood. It does a terrible job of describing the world they exist in now. We need to learn how to be less sweet and giving, rather than more so. Women are taught to be caring at the cost of everything we love about our lives and ourselves. Because we are so open-hearted, we are easily taken advantage of in our naivete. We need movie heroines who encourage us to be MORE wary, more suspicious of who we place our trust in, rather than less. We need heroines willing to stand on their own two feet and to work to accomplish their own dreams, rather than to fight for the dreams of those around them without a thought for themselves. In real life, this kind of goodness is boring...it is scrappiness, it is the willingness to stand one's ground and to fight for one's right to exist at all costs, that makes a life entertaining to watch and live. Instead, what this movie does is make us resent the people around us for achieving less than the perfection that the main characters of this movie achieve. We also hate ourselves for being less than wholly sweet. No man will ever solve all a woman's problems for her. No woman can work her way into redemption by serving the people around her rather than serving herself. There is no opportunity for healing without pride. No one can work themselves out of a pit of despair without honesty. May I live to see the day when movies all represent heroines of reality, rather than of male fantasies of what a 'real woman' should be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bittersweet look at small-town life and the vagaries of doing good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    has43
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I rated this movie 5/10 only because I truly hate the ending. Is the author saying Percy HAD to die to redeem everyone else? If so, that really stinks. God knows what her life was life before she took her tormentor out. AND after. Reminds me of "A Tree Grows In Brooklyn." The mother killed the man who raped her daughter, but after awhile all that anyone seems to remember is that she was convicted of murder. And then there's "Mystic River," wherein Tim Robbins' character was molested as a young boy by two priests, barely escapes with his life, such things were not discussed at that time, he lived with his pain, and then is taken out, and his murderer justifies the unfortunate wrongful murder, but we're left hanging as to any justice occurring, whatsoever. Also, I cannot abide Will Patton, in anything I've seen him in. Otherwise, I think the movie was pretty extraordinary, and I wish I'd walked out of the theater before the ending. If the author ever reads these reviews, I do wish he would explain the ending. Thank you for listening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bittersweet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alohahome
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very touching but bittersweet independent film. Slow and gentle. It concerns a young woman named Percy who wishes to reconcile her unsavory past in the small town of Giliad Maine but she is haunted by the very past that she wishes to overcome. Many people would like a chance to start over but life does not always afford then that opportunity. Nonetheless, we all still do affect others in ways that are not always seen. And therein lies the tale of redemption. A redemption that is sometimes too late in coming. Yet there is still hope in the unfairness all around us. And compassion to be found. Don't expect a Hollywood ending here. But who really wants one in this context? It's been said that Hollyweood films depict life as we would like to see it. But independent films depict life as it is. Small towns are hesitant enough about welcoming newcomers, yet Percy's arrival and her spirit is sensed as being something altogether different and the town finds itself changed forever. The inviting musical score by James Horner renders a sweet ambiance, consoling with a subdued drifty quality that lulls the soul in its wake.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spitfire Grill-Get The Charcoal Ready for this One ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whatever became of Alison Elliott, the heroine of this film? She gave an extremely believable performance here as a woman released from prison for killing the stepfather who had impregnated her and then had caused the death of the baby by beating the mother. Ellen Burstyn is the old lady who Elliott goes to work for. As always, Burstyn again proves that she is at her best when she does her mean, crotchety acting. It's another fine job. The story will tug at your heart since it's a tragic one. It again proves that you can't always judge people by what has happened in their lives. This misconception brings on the tragedy at the end that will drive you to tears. Note an interesting performance by Marcia Gay Harden, as a blond, worker of the Burstyn character who befriends Elliott. This is a very good study of rural life and human relationships.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gilead
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Furuya Shiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like movies that have lasting effect in my mind, and that make me think about the meaning of some scenes over and over. This movie is that kind. There may be many similar movies but this one is different from any of those. A young woman gets off a bus in a small excluded town Gilead in Mane, US. In this town, three women who have different kinds of psychological trauma as a mother work together in a restaurant "The Spitfire Grill". The protagonist is Percy (Alison Elliot). There are mysteries in her words and behavior. But as the story goes, the deep scar in her mind hidden behind the mystery is gradually revealed. The second woman is Hannah (Ellen Burstyn). She runs a restaurant "Spitfire Grill". She has her own, deep scar in her mind. The third is Shelby (Marcia Gay Harden). Though she is very warmhearted, her husband always insults her. Maybe she is the one you can easily empathize. Perhaps, there is a meaning in the name of the town, Gilead. At the near end of the movie, we hear a black spiritual song "There is a balm in Gilead". The name Gilead comes from biblical world, which produces frankincense that was much-prized as medicine. The first stanza of the song is as follows: There is a balm in Gilead / To make the wounded whole; / There is a balm in Gilead / To heal the sin sick soul. The key to understand the heart of the movie may be in the lyrics.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Burstyn's worth a look, but artificiality grills what's left over...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pure corn. A female ex-con in a small community in Maine gets waitressing job at the local diner, enlightening everyone there with her presence. Resolutely old-fashioned hokum is replete with pseudo-meaningful platitudes and female bonding (with divergent accents). Acquired at the Sundance Film Festival for what was reported to be a princely sum, Castle Rock barely distributed this after the reviews came in (they were probably hoping for another "Fried Green Tomatoes" but got rotten tomatoes instead). Trifling nonsense tries for a prestigious look, but even this fails as the moody ambiance resembles nothing more than encroaching mold. It at least gave work to Ellen Burstyn, whose professionalism and mere presence saves this from oblivion. Otherwise, a prime candidate for Lifetime's four a.m. movie. * from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The trepidation of accepting an ex-con in a country setting.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john-jennings-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I happen to love chick flicks-if that is what this film is categorized as.I love this movie, as do so many others who've made comments before me in the IMDb site. It was one of those films where I held my breath throughout, sensing an evil that would probably overtake the heroine before the picture ended.And so it did. The ending angered me greatly...here we have this wonderful character Percy who begins to grow on the residents and is finally being accepted,except for one mouthy,jealous bigot,- real-estate agent Nahum Goddard,who will not accept Percy into their midst.This misshapen belief finally leads to a grave misunderstanding by the citizenry who hunt Percy down, which ends in her drowning in a rushing stream. At the end Nahum admits he was wrong to judge Percy so harshly but darn it all the harm has been done. I was angry at director Lee David Zlotoff who had the "power" to make this a happy ending. He wrote the script!!! Let's say for example that Nahum Goddard had drowned saving Percy in that stream. The man would have gone to his death via an act of redemption (isn't that a religious quality held dear by a tight Christian community) and our heroine would have gone on living happily ever after in a comfortable setting. I saw this film when it came out, and I even have 2-3 copies of it on DVD and VHS but I can just not watch it again. I know how sad the ending will be. I still give the film a 9 1/2 though,it was still a great production.(I need to express my ratings in fractions). If Percy had not been killed off I would have given it a 10 for perfection, no question. I'm sorry, but if a beloved character is killed off "unnecssarily", then I can not give the film a 10. Too bad I had not been in one of the advance screenings to express my views. If film companies and the Director/Producer want a 10 from me they had better try for a happy,or at least satisfying ending if at all possible. So much of life is a tragedy and that's why in part we go to the movies to get away from reality, to get a quick shot of hope and to see some element of happiness, even in dramatic circumstances.Percy did not deserve to die after all of us had fallen so much in love with her persona. Could we stand a Spitfire Grill 2 where she miraculously appears one day alive and well? Probably not...Darn it all Lee David Zlotoff, what were you thinking?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once again Hollywood's reviews mean nothing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sam Poynter
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie got pretty bad reviews from the Hollywood Hype-mongers. I suppose because it didn't have a lot of flash. All it had was a well-written original story and superb acting with real characters. Anyone who has ever spent time in a small town can identify with nearly all the characters. I could practically name them all in the town I grew up in. I'm sure the only people who would NOT enjoy this movie are the ones who grew up in Hollywood and believe everyone is like them. If thats not you, rent this movie for a truly enjoyable evening. But you might want to bring tissues. It's a very warm and often funny movie, but it's also very sad in some places. Will Patton is incredible and I honestly don't understand why Alison Elliott hasn't been used more than she has since this movie. Ellen Burstyn was glorious as ever :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Male or Female, that is the only question you need ask
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    snafux7
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me make it simple for everyone... If you are a woman (especially if you happen to currently be menstruating) you will positively adore this movie. Just sit back with a glass of zinfandel and a box of tissues and enjoy. It is heavy-handed melodrama and clich&eacute; 'character' acting by all the usual female stereotypes but sometimes that isn't always a bad thing. I realize that this probably sounds condescending and insensitive so in advance let me apologize and recognize that everything I say is wrong anyway. If you are a dude on the other hand I hope and pray for you that you have a 2nd TV located in another room, preferably hooked up to a PS3 or XBOX so that you can properly recalibrate your testosterone level after watching the first 20 mins of this train wreck. It has absolutely nothing of interest to you, trust me. You know that feeling you get when you're alone in a room of women all talking at the same time and you can't leave? Now imagine an hour and a half of that with no respite, every time you think it cannot possibly go any further down the rabbit hole of "I do not give a f$*k" it somehow manages to kick it up a notch. As an aside, I was born and raised in the Northeast and the vast majority of 'Maine' accents in this film are about on par with the 'British' accents of Natalie Portman and Keanu Reeves, its pretty damn bad. Personally I think the average woman would give this 8-9 stars and the average guy would give it 1 or 2 so in all fairness I'm splitting the difference, we're it just up to me I'd give it either 1 or 0.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Over-hyped
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sir_brettley
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was allegedly a critical success but in reality it's a plodding, overwrought film that never really gets going. The characters are shallow and the alleged protagonist is a "Mary Sue". While I was led to believe that the film would be a wonderful account of people and complexities of relationships all I saw was bad writing and worse acting. While the written version and Biblical allegories of forgiveness and healing may work, this theatrical version misses the mark. I suppose if you have a pariah complex you can relate to this movie but for everyone else it's a waste of time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In Which a Woman is Saved by Being So Darn Plucky n Cute!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    someofusarebrave
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the kind of totally misogynistic movie that does such an excellent job of masquerading as a movie about female empowerment that it fools all but the most discerning types. There would be nothing wrong with that, except that it lulls us all into a false state of comfort. Police will always be kind, gentle folk, escaped convicts will always be 'really good' at heart, and a woman can be rescued from the worst types of spiritual and emotional pain by the 'power of the penis'. If only, right? Wrong. The world is not like that. In this world we all live in, police rape young homeless woman wandering around on their own as often as they help them out. Women who have been convicted of felonies rarely get second chances, regardless of how generous or good-hearted they happen to be. People are shaped by their circumstances and rarely manage to "rise above" them, instead dragging everyone else down with them often as not. There are no second chances. Nor should there be. Women who murder ought not to be let off the hook from the ramifications of their actions for "good behavior." Policemen ought not do the job of the non-government organizations and social programs which do not exist in the South for all intents and purposes. We ought not be able to work or charm our way out of being who we are. Everyone deserves the opportunity to start again, but part of that process MUST involve some acknowledgment of why things went so badly wrong in the first place. Teaching young girls that all they have to do to improve their lives is to trust the people around them unconditionally to help them out of any scrape they get into is morally bankrupt. Movies like this one do a terrible job of preparing young girls for the world they will actually be entering upon adulthood. It does a terrible job of describing the world they exist in now. We need to learn how to be less sweet and giving, rather than more so. Women are taught to be caring at the cost of everything we love about our lives and ourselves. Because we are so open-hearted, we are easily taken advantage of in our naivete. We need movie heroines who encourage us to be MORE wary, more suspicious of who we place our trust in, rather than less. We need heroines willing to stand on their own two feet and to work to accomplish their own dreams, rather than to fight for the dreams of those around them without a thought for themselves. In real life, this kind of goodness is boring...it is scrappiness, it is the willingness to stand one's ground and to fight for one's right to exist at all costs, that makes a life entertaining to watch and live. Instead, what this movie does is make us resent the people around us for achieving less than the perfection that the main characters of this movie achieve. We also hate ourselves for being less than wholly sweet. No man will ever solve all a woman's problems for her. No woman can work her way into redemption by serving the people around her rather than serving herself. There is no opportunity for healing without pride. No one can work themselves out of a pit of despair without honesty. May I live to see the day when movies all represent heroines of reality, rather than of male fantasies of what a 'real woman' should be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bittersweet look at small-town life and the vagaries of doing good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    has43
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I rated this movie 5/10 only because I truly hate the ending. Is the author saying Percy HAD to die to redeem everyone else? If so, that really stinks. God knows what her life was life before she took her tormentor out. AND after. Reminds me of "A Tree Grows In Brooklyn." The mother killed the man who raped her daughter, but after awhile all that anyone seems to remember is that she was convicted of murder. And then there's "Mystic River," wherein Tim Robbins' character was molested as a young boy by two priests, barely escapes with his life, such things were not discussed at that time, he lived with his pain, and then is taken out, and his murderer justifies the unfortunate wrongful murder, but we're left hanging as to any justice occurring, whatsoever. Also, I cannot abide Will Patton, in anything I've seen him in. Otherwise, I think the movie was pretty extraordinary, and I wish I'd walked out of the theater before the ending. If the author ever reads these reviews, I do wish he would explain the ending. Thank you for listening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bittersweet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alohahome
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very touching but bittersweet independent film. Slow and gentle. It concerns a young woman named Percy who wishes to reconcile her unsavory past in the small town of Giliad Maine but she is haunted by the very past that she wishes to overcome. Many people would like a chance to start over but life does not always afford then that opportunity. Nonetheless, we all still do affect others in ways that are not always seen. And therein lies the tale of redemption. A redemption that is sometimes too late in coming. Yet there is still hope in the unfairness all around us. And compassion to be found. Don't expect a Hollywood ending here. But who really wants one in this context? It's been said that Hollyweood films depict life as we would like to see it. But independent films depict life as it is. Small towns are hesitant enough about welcoming newcomers, yet Percy's arrival and her spirit is sensed as being something altogether different and the town finds itself changed forever. The inviting musical score by James Horner renders a sweet ambiance, consoling with a subdued drifty quality that lulls the soul in its wake.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spitfire Grill-Get The Charcoal Ready for this One ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whatever became of Alison Elliott, the heroine of this film? She gave an extremely believable performance here as a woman released from prison for killing the stepfather who had impregnated her and then had caused the death of the baby by beating the mother. Ellen Burstyn is the old lady who Elliott goes to work for. As always, Burstyn again proves that she is at her best when she does her mean, crotchety acting. It's another fine job. The story will tug at your heart since it's a tragic one. It again proves that you can't always judge people by what has happened in their lives. This misconception brings on the tragedy at the end that will drive you to tears. Note an interesting performance by Marcia Gay Harden, as a blond, worker of the Burstyn character who befriends Elliott. This is a very good study of rural life and human relationships.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gilead
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Furuya Shiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like movies that have lasting effect in my mind, and that make me think about the meaning of some scenes over and over. This movie is that kind. There may be many similar movies but this one is different from any of those. A young woman gets off a bus in a small excluded town Gilead in Mane, US. In this town, three women who have different kinds of psychological trauma as a mother work together in a restaurant "The Spitfire Grill". The protagonist is Percy (Alison Elliot). There are mysteries in her words and behavior. But as the story goes, the deep scar in her mind hidden behind the mystery is gradually revealed. The second woman is Hannah (Ellen Burstyn). She runs a restaurant "Spitfire Grill". She has her own, deep scar in her mind. The third is Shelby (Marcia Gay Harden). Though she is very warmhearted, her husband always insults her. Maybe she is the one you can easily empathize. Perhaps, there is a meaning in the name of the town, Gilead. At the near end of the movie, we hear a black spiritual song "There is a balm in Gilead". The name Gilead comes from biblical world, which produces frankincense that was much-prized as medicine. The first stanza of the song is as follows: There is a balm in Gilead / To make the wounded whole; / There is a balm in Gilead / To heal the sin sick soul. The key to understand the heart of the movie may be in the lyrics.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Burstyn's worth a look, but artificiality grills what's left over...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pure corn. A female ex-con in a small community in Maine gets waitressing job at the local diner, enlightening everyone there with her presence. Resolutely old-fashioned hokum is replete with pseudo-meaningful platitudes and female bonding (with divergent accents). Acquired at the Sundance Film Festival for what was reported to be a princely sum, Castle Rock barely distributed this after the reviews came in (they were probably hoping for another "Fried Green Tomatoes" but got rotten tomatoes instead). Trifling nonsense tries for a prestigious look, but even this fails as the moody ambiance resembles nothing more than encroaching mold. It at least gave work to Ellen Burstyn, whose professionalism and mere presence saves this from oblivion. Otherwise, a prime candidate for Lifetime's four a.m. movie. * from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The trepidation of accepting an ex-con in a country setting.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john-jennings-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I happen to love chick flicks-if that is what this film is categorized as.I love this movie, as do so many others who've made comments before me in the IMDb site. It was one of those films where I held my breath throughout, sensing an evil that would probably overtake the heroine before the picture ended.And so it did. The ending angered me greatly...here we have this wonderful character Percy who begins to grow on the residents and is finally being accepted,except for one mouthy,jealous bigot,- real-estate agent Nahum Goddard,who will not accept Percy into their midst.This misshapen belief finally leads to a grave misunderstanding by the citizenry who hunt Percy down, which ends in her drowning in a rushing stream. At the end Nahum admits he was wrong to judge Percy so harshly but darn it all the harm has been done. I was angry at director Lee David Zlotoff who had the "power" to make this a happy ending. He wrote the script!!! Let's say for example that Nahum Goddard had drowned saving Percy in that stream. The man would have gone to his death via an act of redemption (isn't that a religious quality held dear by a tight Christian community) and our heroine would have gone on living happily ever after in a comfortable setting. I saw this film when it came out, and I even have 2-3 copies of it on DVD and VHS but I can just not watch it again. I know how sad the ending will be. I still give the film a 9 1/2 though,it was still a great production.(I need to express my ratings in fractions). If Percy had not been killed off I would have given it a 10 for perfection, no question. I'm sorry, but if a beloved character is killed off "unnecssarily", then I can not give the film a 10. Too bad I had not been in one of the advance screenings to express my views. If film companies and the Director/Producer want a 10 from me they had better try for a happy,or at least satisfying ending if at all possible. So much of life is a tragedy and that's why in part we go to the movies to get away from reality, to get a quick shot of hope and to see some element of happiness, even in dramatic circumstances.Percy did not deserve to die after all of us had fallen so much in love with her persona. Could we stand a Spitfire Grill 2 where she miraculously appears one day alive and well? Probably not...Darn it all Lee David Zlotoff, what were you thinking?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once again Hollywood's reviews mean nothing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sam Poynter
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie got pretty bad reviews from the Hollywood Hype-mongers. I suppose because it didn't have a lot of flash. All it had was a well-written original story and superb acting with real characters. Anyone who has ever spent time in a small town can identify with nearly all the characters. I could practically name them all in the town I grew up in. I'm sure the only people who would NOT enjoy this movie are the ones who grew up in Hollywood and believe everyone is like them. If thats not you, rent this movie for a truly enjoyable evening. But you might want to bring tissues. It's a very warm and often funny movie, but it's also very sad in some places. Will Patton is incredible and I honestly don't understand why Alison Elliott hasn't been used more than she has since this movie. Ellen Burstyn was glorious as ever :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Male or Female, that is the only question you need ask
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    snafux7
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me make it simple for everyone... If you are a woman (especially if you happen to currently be menstruating) you will positively adore this movie. Just sit back with a glass of zinfandel and a box of tissues and enjoy. It is heavy-handed melodrama and clich&eacute; 'character' acting by all the usual female stereotypes but sometimes that isn't always a bad thing. I realize that this probably sounds condescending and insensitive so in advance let me apologize and recognize that everything I say is wrong anyway. If you are a dude on the other hand I hope and pray for you that you have a 2nd TV located in another room, preferably hooked up to a PS3 or XBOX so that you can properly recalibrate your testosterone level after watching the first 20 mins of this train wreck. It has absolutely nothing of interest to you, trust me. You know that feeling you get when you're alone in a room of women all talking at the same time and you can't leave? Now imagine an hour and a half of that with no respite, every time you think it cannot possibly go any further down the rabbit hole of "I do not give a f$*k" it somehow manages to kick it up a notch. As an aside, I was born and raised in the Northeast and the vast majority of 'Maine' accents in this film are about on par with the 'British' accents of Natalie Portman and Keanu Reeves, its pretty damn bad. Personally I think the average woman would give this 8-9 stars and the average guy would give it 1 or 2 so in all fairness I'm splitting the difference, we're it just up to me I'd give it either 1 or 0.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Over-hyped
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sir_brettley
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was allegedly a critical success but in reality it's a plodding, overwrought film that never really gets going. The characters are shallow and the alleged protagonist is a "Mary Sue". While I was led to believe that the film would be a wonderful account of people and complexities of relationships all I saw was bad writing and worse acting. While the written version and Biblical allegories of forgiveness and healing may work, this theatrical version misses the mark. I suppose if you have a pariah complex you can relate to this movie but for everyone else it's a waste of time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In Which a Woman is Saved by Being So Darn Plucky n Cute!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    someofusarebrave
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the kind of totally misogynistic movie that does such an excellent job of masquerading as a movie about female empowerment that it fools all but the most discerning types. There would be nothing wrong with that, except that it lulls us all into a false state of comfort. Police will always be kind, gentle folk, escaped convicts will always be 'really good' at heart, and a woman can be rescued from the worst types of spiritual and emotional pain by the 'power of the penis'. If only, right? Wrong. The world is not like that. In this world we all live in, police rape young homeless woman wandering around on their own as often as they help them out. Women who have been convicted of felonies rarely get second chances, regardless of how generous or good-hearted they happen to be. People are shaped by their circumstances and rarely manage to "rise above" them, instead dragging everyone else down with them often as not. There are no second chances. Nor should there be. Women who murder ought not to be let off the hook from the ramifications of their actions for "good behavior." Policemen ought not do the job of the non-government organizations and social programs which do not exist in the South for all intents and purposes. We ought not be able to work or charm our way out of being who we are. Everyone deserves the opportunity to start again, but part of that process MUST involve some acknowledgment of why things went so badly wrong in the first place. Teaching young girls that all they have to do to improve their lives is to trust the people around them unconditionally to help them out of any scrape they get into is morally bankrupt. Movies like this one do a terrible job of preparing young girls for the world they will actually be entering upon adulthood. It does a terrible job of describing the world they exist in now. We need to learn how to be less sweet and giving, rather than more so. Women are taught to be caring at the cost of everything we love about our lives and ourselves. Because we are so open-hearted, we are easily taken advantage of in our naivete. We need movie heroines who encourage us to be MORE wary, more suspicious of who we place our trust in, rather than less. We need heroines willing to stand on their own two feet and to work to accomplish their own dreams, rather than to fight for the dreams of those around them without a thought for themselves. In real life, this kind of goodness is boring...it is scrappiness, it is the willingness to stand one's ground and to fight for one's right to exist at all costs, that makes a life entertaining to watch and live. Instead, what this movie does is make us resent the people around us for achieving less than the perfection that the main characters of this movie achieve. We also hate ourselves for being less than wholly sweet. No man will ever solve all a woman's problems for her. No woman can work her way into redemption by serving the people around her rather than serving herself. There is no opportunity for healing without pride. No one can work themselves out of a pit of despair without honesty. May I live to see the day when movies all represent heroines of reality, rather than of male fantasies of what a 'real woman' should be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bittersweet look at small-town life and the vagaries of doing good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    has43
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I rated this movie 5/10 only because I truly hate the ending. Is the author saying Percy HAD to die to redeem everyone else? If so, that really stinks. God knows what her life was life before she took her tormentor out. AND after. Reminds me of "A Tree Grows In Brooklyn." The mother killed the man who raped her daughter, but after awhile all that anyone seems to remember is that she was convicted of murder. And then there's "Mystic River," wherein Tim Robbins' character was molested as a young boy by two priests, barely escapes with his life, such things were not discussed at that time, he lived with his pain, and then is taken out, and his murderer justifies the unfortunate wrongful murder, but we're left hanging as to any justice occurring, whatsoever. Also, I cannot abide Will Patton, in anything I've seen him in. Otherwise, I think the movie was pretty extraordinary, and I wish I'd walked out of the theater before the ending. If the author ever reads these reviews, I do wish he would explain the ending. Thank you for listening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bittersweet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alohahome
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very touching but bittersweet independent film. Slow and gentle. It concerns a young woman named Percy who wishes to reconcile her unsavory past in the small town of Giliad Maine but she is haunted by the very past that she wishes to overcome. Many people would like a chance to start over but life does not always afford then that opportunity. Nonetheless, we all still do affect others in ways that are not always seen. And therein lies the tale of redemption. A redemption that is sometimes too late in coming. Yet there is still hope in the unfairness all around us. And compassion to be found. Don't expect a Hollywood ending here. But who really wants one in this context? It's been said that Hollyweood films depict life as we would like to see it. But independent films depict life as it is. Small towns are hesitant enough about welcoming newcomers, yet Percy's arrival and her spirit is sensed as being something altogether different and the town finds itself changed forever. The inviting musical score by James Horner renders a sweet ambiance, consoling with a subdued drifty quality that lulls the soul in its wake.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spitfire Grill-Get The Charcoal Ready for this One ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whatever became of Alison Elliott, the heroine of this film? She gave an extremely believable performance here as a woman released from prison for killing the stepfather who had impregnated her and then had caused the death of the baby by beating the mother. Ellen Burstyn is the old lady who Elliott goes to work for. As always, Burstyn again proves that she is at her best when she does her mean, crotchety acting. It's another fine job. The story will tug at your heart since it's a tragic one. It again proves that you can't always judge people by what has happened in their lives. This misconception brings on the tragedy at the end that will drive you to tears. Note an interesting performance by Marcia Gay Harden, as a blond, worker of the Burstyn character who befriends Elliott. This is a very good study of rural life and human relationships.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gilead
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Furuya Shiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like movies that have lasting effect in my mind, and that make me think about the meaning of some scenes over and over. This movie is that kind. There may be many similar movies but this one is different from any of those. A young woman gets off a bus in a small excluded town Gilead in Mane, US. In this town, three women who have different kinds of psychological trauma as a mother work together in a restaurant "The Spitfire Grill". The protagonist is Percy (Alison Elliot). There are mysteries in her words and behavior. But as the story goes, the deep scar in her mind hidden behind the mystery is gradually revealed. The second woman is Hannah (Ellen Burstyn). She runs a restaurant "Spitfire Grill". She has her own, deep scar in her mind. The third is Shelby (Marcia Gay Harden). Though she is very warmhearted, her husband always insults her. Maybe she is the one you can easily empathize. Perhaps, there is a meaning in the name of the town, Gilead. At the near end of the movie, we hear a black spiritual song "There is a balm in Gilead". The name Gilead comes from biblical world, which produces frankincense that was much-prized as medicine. The first stanza of the song is as follows: There is a balm in Gilead / To make the wounded whole; / There is a balm in Gilead / To heal the sin sick soul. The key to understand the heart of the movie may be in the lyrics.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Burstyn's worth a look, but artificiality grills what's left over...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pure corn. A female ex-con in a small community in Maine gets waitressing job at the local diner, enlightening everyone there with her presence. Resolutely old-fashioned hokum is replete with pseudo-meaningful platitudes and female bonding (with divergent accents). Acquired at the Sundance Film Festival for what was reported to be a princely sum, Castle Rock barely distributed this after the reviews came in (they were probably hoping for another "Fried Green Tomatoes" but got rotten tomatoes instead). Trifling nonsense tries for a prestigious look, but even this fails as the moody ambiance resembles nothing more than encroaching mold. It at least gave work to Ellen Burstyn, whose professionalism and mere presence saves this from oblivion. Otherwise, a prime candidate for Lifetime's four a.m. movie. * from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The trepidation of accepting an ex-con in a country setting.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john-jennings-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I happen to love chick flicks-if that is what this film is categorized as.I love this movie, as do so many others who've made comments before me in the IMDb site. It was one of those films where I held my breath throughout, sensing an evil that would probably overtake the heroine before the picture ended.And so it did. The ending angered me greatly...here we have this wonderful character Percy who begins to grow on the residents and is finally being accepted,except for one mouthy,jealous bigot,- real-estate agent Nahum Goddard,who will not accept Percy into their midst.This misshapen belief finally leads to a grave misunderstanding by the citizenry who hunt Percy down, which ends in her drowning in a rushing stream. At the end Nahum admits he was wrong to judge Percy so harshly but darn it all the harm has been done. I was angry at director Lee David Zlotoff who had the "power" to make this a happy ending. He wrote the script!!! Let's say for example that Nahum Goddard had drowned saving Percy in that stream. The man would have gone to his death via an act of redemption (isn't that a religious quality held dear by a tight Christian community) and our heroine would have gone on living happily ever after in a comfortable setting. I saw this film when it came out, and I even have 2-3 copies of it on DVD and VHS but I can just not watch it again. I know how sad the ending will be. I still give the film a 9 1/2 though,it was still a great production.(I need to express my ratings in fractions). If Percy had not been killed off I would have given it a 10 for perfection, no question. I'm sorry, but if a beloved character is killed off "unnecssarily", then I can not give the film a 10. Too bad I had not been in one of the advance screenings to express my views. If film companies and the Director/Producer want a 10 from me they had better try for a happy,or at least satisfying ending if at all possible. So much of life is a tragedy and that's why in part we go to the movies to get away from reality, to get a quick shot of hope and to see some element of happiness, even in dramatic circumstances.Percy did not deserve to die after all of us had fallen so much in love with her persona. Could we stand a Spitfire Grill 2 where she miraculously appears one day alive and well? Probably not...Darn it all Lee David Zlotoff, what were you thinking?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once again Hollywood's reviews mean nothing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sam Poynter
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie got pretty bad reviews from the Hollywood Hype-mongers. I suppose because it didn't have a lot of flash. All it had was a well-written original story and superb acting with real characters. Anyone who has ever spent time in a small town can identify with nearly all the characters. I could practically name them all in the town I grew up in. I'm sure the only people who would NOT enjoy this movie are the ones who grew up in Hollywood and believe everyone is like them. If thats not you, rent this movie for a truly enjoyable evening. But you might want to bring tissues. It's a very warm and often funny movie, but it's also very sad in some places. Will Patton is incredible and I honestly don't understand why Alison Elliott hasn't been used more than she has since this movie. Ellen Burstyn was glorious as ever :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Male or Female, that is the only question you need ask
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    snafux7
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me make it simple for everyone... If you are a woman (especially if you happen to currently be menstruating) you will positively adore this movie. Just sit back with a glass of zinfandel and a box of tissues and enjoy. It is heavy-handed melodrama and clich&eacute; 'character' acting by all the usual female stereotypes but sometimes that isn't always a bad thing. I realize that this probably sounds condescending and insensitive so in advance let me apologize and recognize that everything I say is wrong anyway. If you are a dude on the other hand I hope and pray for you that you have a 2nd TV located in another room, preferably hooked up to a PS3 or XBOX so that you can properly recalibrate your testosterone level after watching the first 20 mins of this train wreck. It has absolutely nothing of interest to you, trust me. You know that feeling you get when you're alone in a room of women all talking at the same time and you can't leave? Now imagine an hour and a half of that with no respite, every time you think it cannot possibly go any further down the rabbit hole of "I do not give a f$*k" it somehow manages to kick it up a notch. As an aside, I was born and raised in the Northeast and the vast majority of 'Maine' accents in this film are about on par with the 'British' accents of Natalie Portman and Keanu Reeves, its pretty damn bad. Personally I think the average woman would give this 8-9 stars and the average guy would give it 1 or 2 so in all fairness I'm splitting the difference, we're it just up to me I'd give it either 1 or 0.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Over-hyped
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sir_brettley
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was allegedly a critical success but in reality it's a plodding, overwrought film that never really gets going. The characters are shallow and the alleged protagonist is a "Mary Sue". While I was led to believe that the film would be a wonderful account of people and complexities of relationships all I saw was bad writing and worse acting. While the written version and Biblical allegories of forgiveness and healing may work, this theatrical version misses the mark. I suppose if you have a pariah complex you can relate to this movie but for everyone else it's a waste of time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In Which a Woman is Saved by Being So Darn Plucky n Cute!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    someofusarebrave
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the kind of totally misogynistic movie that does such an excellent job of masquerading as a movie about female empowerment that it fools all but the most discerning types. There would be nothing wrong with that, except that it lulls us all into a false state of comfort. Police will always be kind, gentle folk, escaped convicts will always be 'really good' at heart, and a woman can be rescued from the worst types of spiritual and emotional pain by the 'power of the penis'. If only, right? Wrong. The world is not like that. In this world we all live in, police rape young homeless woman wandering around on their own as often as they help them out. Women who have been convicted of felonies rarely get second chances, regardless of how generous or good-hearted they happen to be. People are shaped by their circumstances and rarely manage to "rise above" them, instead dragging everyone else down with them often as not. There are no second chances. Nor should there be. Women who murder ought not to be let off the hook from the ramifications of their actions for "good behavior." Policemen ought not do the job of the non-government organizations and social programs which do not exist in the South for all intents and purposes. We ought not be able to work or charm our way out of being who we are. Everyone deserves the opportunity to start again, but part of that process MUST involve some acknowledgment of why things went so badly wrong in the first place. Teaching young girls that all they have to do to improve their lives is to trust the people around them unconditionally to help them out of any scrape they get into is morally bankrupt. Movies like this one do a terrible job of preparing young girls for the world they will actually be entering upon adulthood. It does a terrible job of describing the world they exist in now. We need to learn how to be less sweet and giving, rather than more so. Women are taught to be caring at the cost of everything we love about our lives and ourselves. Because we are so open-hearted, we are easily taken advantage of in our naivete. We need movie heroines who encourage us to be MORE wary, more suspicious of who we place our trust in, rather than less. We need heroines willing to stand on their own two feet and to work to accomplish their own dreams, rather than to fight for the dreams of those around them without a thought for themselves. In real life, this kind of goodness is boring...it is scrappiness, it is the willingness to stand one's ground and to fight for one's right to exist at all costs, that makes a life entertaining to watch and live. Instead, what this movie does is make us resent the people around us for achieving less than the perfection that the main characters of this movie achieve. We also hate ourselves for being less than wholly sweet. No man will ever solve all a woman's problems for her. No woman can work her way into redemption by serving the people around her rather than serving herself. There is no opportunity for healing without pride. No one can work themselves out of a pit of despair without honesty. May I live to see the day when movies all represent heroines of reality, rather than of male fantasies of what a 'real woman' should be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bittersweet look at small-town life and the vagaries of doing good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    has43
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I rated this movie 5/10 only because I truly hate the ending. Is the author saying Percy HAD to die to redeem everyone else? If so, that really stinks. God knows what her life was life before she took her tormentor out. AND after. Reminds me of "A Tree Grows In Brooklyn." The mother killed the man who raped her daughter, but after awhile all that anyone seems to remember is that she was convicted of murder. And then there's "Mystic River," wherein Tim Robbins' character was molested as a young boy by two priests, barely escapes with his life, such things were not discussed at that time, he lived with his pain, and then is taken out, and his murderer justifies the unfortunate wrongful murder, but we're left hanging as to any justice occurring, whatsoever. Also, I cannot abide Will Patton, in anything I've seen him in. Otherwise, I think the movie was pretty extraordinary, and I wish I'd walked out of the theater before the ending. If the author ever reads these reviews, I do wish he would explain the ending. Thank you for listening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bittersweet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alohahome
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very touching but bittersweet independent film. Slow and gentle. It concerns a young woman named Percy who wishes to reconcile her unsavory past in the small town of Giliad Maine but she is haunted by the very past that she wishes to overcome. Many people would like a chance to start over but life does not always afford then that opportunity. Nonetheless, we all still do affect others in ways that are not always seen. And therein lies the tale of redemption. A redemption that is sometimes too late in coming. Yet there is still hope in the unfairness all around us. And compassion to be found. Don't expect a Hollywood ending here. But who really wants one in this context? It's been said that Hollyweood films depict life as we would like to see it. But independent films depict life as it is. Small towns are hesitant enough about welcoming newcomers, yet Percy's arrival and her spirit is sensed as being something altogether different and the town finds itself changed forever. The inviting musical score by James Horner renders a sweet ambiance, consoling with a subdued drifty quality that lulls the soul in its wake.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spitfire Grill-Get The Charcoal Ready for this One ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whatever became of Alison Elliott, the heroine of this film? She gave an extremely believable performance here as a woman released from prison for killing the stepfather who had impregnated her and then had caused the death of the baby by beating the mother. Ellen Burstyn is the old lady who Elliott goes to work for. As always, Burstyn again proves that she is at her best when she does her mean, crotchety acting. It's another fine job. The story will tug at your heart since it's a tragic one. It again proves that you can't always judge people by what has happened in their lives. This misconception brings on the tragedy at the end that will drive you to tears. Note an interesting performance by Marcia Gay Harden, as a blond, worker of the Burstyn character who befriends Elliott. This is a very good study of rural life and human relationships.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gilead
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Furuya Shiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like movies that have lasting effect in my mind, and that make me think about the meaning of some scenes over and over. This movie is that kind. There may be many similar movies but this one is different from any of those. A young woman gets off a bus in a small excluded town Gilead in Mane, US. In this town, three women who have different kinds of psychological trauma as a mother work together in a restaurant "The Spitfire Grill". The protagonist is Percy (Alison Elliot). There are mysteries in her words and behavior. But as the story goes, the deep scar in her mind hidden behind the mystery is gradually revealed. The second woman is Hannah (Ellen Burstyn). She runs a restaurant "Spitfire Grill". She has her own, deep scar in her mind. The third is Shelby (Marcia Gay Harden). Though she is very warmhearted, her husband always insults her. Maybe she is the one you can easily empathize. Perhaps, there is a meaning in the name of the town, Gilead. At the near end of the movie, we hear a black spiritual song "There is a balm in Gilead". The name Gilead comes from biblical world, which produces frankincense that was much-prized as medicine. The first stanza of the song is as follows: There is a balm in Gilead / To make the wounded whole; / There is a balm in Gilead / To heal the sin sick soul. The key to understand the heart of the movie may be in the lyrics.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Burstyn's worth a look, but artificiality grills what's left over...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pure corn. A female ex-con in a small community in Maine gets waitressing job at the local diner, enlightening everyone there with her presence. Resolutely old-fashioned hokum is replete with pseudo-meaningful platitudes and female bonding (with divergent accents). Acquired at the Sundance Film Festival for what was reported to be a princely sum, Castle Rock barely distributed this after the reviews came in (they were probably hoping for another "Fried Green Tomatoes" but got rotten tomatoes instead). Trifling nonsense tries for a prestigious look, but even this fails as the moody ambiance resembles nothing more than encroaching mold. It at least gave work to Ellen Burstyn, whose professionalism and mere presence saves this from oblivion. Otherwise, a prime candidate for Lifetime's four a.m. movie. * from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The trepidation of accepting an ex-con in a country setting.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john-jennings-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I happen to love chick flicks-if that is what this film is categorized as.I love this movie, as do so many others who've made comments before me in the IMDb site. It was one of those films where I held my breath throughout, sensing an evil that would probably overtake the heroine before the picture ended.And so it did. The ending angered me greatly...here we have this wonderful character Percy who begins to grow on the residents and is finally being accepted,except for one mouthy,jealous bigot,- real-estate agent Nahum Goddard,who will not accept Percy into their midst.This misshapen belief finally leads to a grave misunderstanding by the citizenry who hunt Percy down, which ends in her drowning in a rushing stream. At the end Nahum admits he was wrong to judge Percy so harshly but darn it all the harm has been done. I was angry at director Lee David Zlotoff who had the "power" to make this a happy ending. He wrote the script!!! Let's say for example that Nahum Goddard had drowned saving Percy in that stream. The man would have gone to his death via an act of redemption (isn't that a religious quality held dear by a tight Christian community) and our heroine would have gone on living happily ever after in a comfortable setting. I saw this film when it came out, and I even have 2-3 copies of it on DVD and VHS but I can just not watch it again. I know how sad the ending will be. I still give the film a 9 1/2 though,it was still a great production.(I need to express my ratings in fractions). If Percy had not been killed off I would have given it a 10 for perfection, no question. I'm sorry, but if a beloved character is killed off "unnecssarily", then I can not give the film a 10. Too bad I had not been in one of the advance screenings to express my views. If film companies and the Director/Producer want a 10 from me they had better try for a happy,or at least satisfying ending if at all possible. So much of life is a tragedy and that's why in part we go to the movies to get away from reality, to get a quick shot of hope and to see some element of happiness, even in dramatic circumstances.Percy did not deserve to die after all of us had fallen so much in love with her persona. Could we stand a Spitfire Grill 2 where she miraculously appears one day alive and well? Probably not...Darn it all Lee David Zlotoff, what were you thinking?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once again Hollywood's reviews mean nothing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sam Poynter
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie got pretty bad reviews from the Hollywood Hype-mongers. I suppose because it didn't have a lot of flash. All it had was a well-written original story and superb acting with real characters. Anyone who has ever spent time in a small town can identify with nearly all the characters. I could practically name them all in the town I grew up in. I'm sure the only people who would NOT enjoy this movie are the ones who grew up in Hollywood and believe everyone is like them. If thats not you, rent this movie for a truly enjoyable evening. But you might want to bring tissues. It's a very warm and often funny movie, but it's also very sad in some places. Will Patton is incredible and I honestly don't understand why Alison Elliott hasn't been used more than she has since this movie. Ellen Burstyn was glorious as ever :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Male or Female, that is the only question you need ask
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    snafux7
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me make it simple for everyone... If you are a woman (especially if you happen to currently be menstruating) you will positively adore this movie. Just sit back with a glass of zinfandel and a box of tissues and enjoy. It is heavy-handed melodrama and clich&eacute; 'character' acting by all the usual female stereotypes but sometimes that isn't always a bad thing. I realize that this probably sounds condescending and insensitive so in advance let me apologize and recognize that everything I say is wrong anyway. If you are a dude on the other hand I hope and pray for you that you have a 2nd TV located in another room, preferably hooked up to a PS3 or XBOX so that you can properly recalibrate your testosterone level after watching the first 20 mins of this train wreck. It has absolutely nothing of interest to you, trust me. You know that feeling you get when you're alone in a room of women all talking at the same time and you can't leave? Now imagine an hour and a half of that with no respite, every time you think it cannot possibly go any further down the rabbit hole of "I do not give a f$*k" it somehow manages to kick it up a notch. As an aside, I was born and raised in the Northeast and the vast majority of 'Maine' accents in this film are about on par with the 'British' accents of Natalie Portman and Keanu Reeves, its pretty damn bad. Personally I think the average woman would give this 8-9 stars and the average guy would give it 1 or 2 so in all fairness I'm splitting the difference, we're it just up to me I'd give it either 1 or 0.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Over-hyped
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sir_brettley
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was allegedly a critical success but in reality it's a plodding, overwrought film that never really gets going. The characters are shallow and the alleged protagonist is a "Mary Sue". While I was led to believe that the film would be a wonderful account of people and complexities of relationships all I saw was bad writing and worse acting. While the written version and Biblical allegories of forgiveness and healing may work, this theatrical version misses the mark. I suppose if you have a pariah complex you can relate to this movie but for everyone else it's a waste of time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In Which a Woman is Saved by Being So Darn Plucky n Cute!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    someofusarebrave
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the kind of totally misogynistic movie that does such an excellent job of masquerading as a movie about female empowerment that it fools all but the most discerning types. There would be nothing wrong with that, except that it lulls us all into a false state of comfort. Police will always be kind, gentle folk, escaped convicts will always be 'really good' at heart, and a woman can be rescued from the worst types of spiritual and emotional pain by the 'power of the penis'. If only, right? Wrong. The world is not like that. In this world we all live in, police rape young homeless woman wandering around on their own as often as they help them out. Women who have been convicted of felonies rarely get second chances, regardless of how generous or good-hearted they happen to be. People are shaped by their circumstances and rarely manage to "rise above" them, instead dragging everyone else down with them often as not. There are no second chances. Nor should there be. Women who murder ought not to be let off the hook from the ramifications of their actions for "good behavior." Policemen ought not do the job of the non-government organizations and social programs which do not exist in the South for all intents and purposes. We ought not be able to work or charm our way out of being who we are. Everyone deserves the opportunity to start again, but part of that process MUST involve some acknowledgment of why things went so badly wrong in the first place. Teaching young girls that all they have to do to improve their lives is to trust the people around them unconditionally to help them out of any scrape they get into is morally bankrupt. Movies like this one do a terrible job of preparing young girls for the world they will actually be entering upon adulthood. It does a terrible job of describing the world they exist in now. We need to learn how to be less sweet and giving, rather than more so. Women are taught to be caring at the cost of everything we love about our lives and ourselves. Because we are so open-hearted, we are easily taken advantage of in our naivete. We need movie heroines who encourage us to be MORE wary, more suspicious of who we place our trust in, rather than less. We need heroines willing to stand on their own two feet and to work to accomplish their own dreams, rather than to fight for the dreams of those around them without a thought for themselves. In real life, this kind of goodness is boring...it is scrappiness, it is the willingness to stand one's ground and to fight for one's right to exist at all costs, that makes a life entertaining to watch and live. Instead, what this movie does is make us resent the people around us for achieving less than the perfection that the main characters of this movie achieve. We also hate ourselves for being less than wholly sweet. No man will ever solve all a woman's problems for her. No woman can work her way into redemption by serving the people around her rather than serving herself. There is no opportunity for healing without pride. No one can work themselves out of a pit of despair without honesty. May I live to see the day when movies all represent heroines of reality, rather than of male fantasies of what a 'real woman' should be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bittersweet look at small-town life and the vagaries of doing good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    has43
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I rated this movie 5/10 only because I truly hate the ending. Is the author saying Percy HAD to die to redeem everyone else? If so, that really stinks. God knows what her life was life before she took her tormentor out. AND after. Reminds me of "A Tree Grows In Brooklyn." The mother killed the man who raped her daughter, but after awhile all that anyone seems to remember is that she was convicted of murder. And then there's "Mystic River," wherein Tim Robbins' character was molested as a young boy by two priests, barely escapes with his life, such things were not discussed at that time, he lived with his pain, and then is taken out, and his murderer justifies the unfortunate wrongful murder, but we're left hanging as to any justice occurring, whatsoever. Also, I cannot abide Will Patton, in anything I've seen him in. Otherwise, I think the movie was pretty extraordinary, and I wish I'd walked out of the theater before the ending. If the author ever reads these reviews, I do wish he would explain the ending. Thank you for listening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bittersweet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alohahome
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very touching but bittersweet independent film. Slow and gentle. It concerns a young woman named Percy who wishes to reconcile her unsavory past in the small town of Giliad Maine but she is haunted by the very past that she wishes to overcome. Many people would like a chance to start over but life does not always afford then that opportunity. Nonetheless, we all still do affect others in ways that are not always seen. And therein lies the tale of redemption. A redemption that is sometimes too late in coming. Yet there is still hope in the unfairness all around us. And compassion to be found. Don't expect a Hollywood ending here. But who really wants one in this context? It's been said that Hollyweood films depict life as we would like to see it. But independent films depict life as it is. Small towns are hesitant enough about welcoming newcomers, yet Percy's arrival and her spirit is sensed as being something altogether different and the town finds itself changed forever. The inviting musical score by James Horner renders a sweet ambiance, consoling with a subdued drifty quality that lulls the soul in its wake.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spitfire Grill-Get The Charcoal Ready for this One ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whatever became of Alison Elliott, the heroine of this film? She gave an extremely believable performance here as a woman released from prison for killing the stepfather who had impregnated her and then had caused the death of the baby by beating the mother. Ellen Burstyn is the old lady who Elliott goes to work for. As always, Burstyn again proves that she is at her best when she does her mean, crotchety acting. It's another fine job. The story will tug at your heart since it's a tragic one. It again proves that you can't always judge people by what has happened in their lives. This misconception brings on the tragedy at the end that will drive you to tears. Note an interesting performance by Marcia Gay Harden, as a blond, worker of the Burstyn character who befriends Elliott. This is a very good study of rural life and human relationships.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gilead
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Furuya Shiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like movies that have lasting effect in my mind, and that make me think about the meaning of some scenes over and over. This movie is that kind. There may be many similar movies but this one is different from any of those. A young woman gets off a bus in a small excluded town Gilead in Mane, US. In this town, three women who have different kinds of psychological trauma as a mother work together in a restaurant "The Spitfire Grill". The protagonist is Percy (Alison Elliot). There are mysteries in her words and behavior. But as the story goes, the deep scar in her mind hidden behind the mystery is gradually revealed. The second woman is Hannah (Ellen Burstyn). She runs a restaurant "Spitfire Grill". She has her own, deep scar in her mind. The third is Shelby (Marcia Gay Harden). Though she is very warmhearted, her husband always insults her. Maybe she is the one you can easily empathize. Perhaps, there is a meaning in the name of the town, Gilead. At the near end of the movie, we hear a black spiritual song "There is a balm in Gilead". The name Gilead comes from biblical world, which produces frankincense that was much-prized as medicine. The first stanza of the song is as follows: There is a balm in Gilead / To make the wounded whole; / There is a balm in Gilead / To heal the sin sick soul. The key to understand the heart of the movie may be in the lyrics.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Burstyn's worth a look, but artificiality grills what's left over...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pure corn. A female ex-con in a small community in Maine gets waitressing job at the local diner, enlightening everyone there with her presence. Resolutely old-fashioned hokum is replete with pseudo-meaningful platitudes and female bonding (with divergent accents). Acquired at the Sundance Film Festival for what was reported to be a princely sum, Castle Rock barely distributed this after the reviews came in (they were probably hoping for another "Fried Green Tomatoes" but got rotten tomatoes instead). Trifling nonsense tries for a prestigious look, but even this fails as the moody ambiance resembles nothing more than encroaching mold. It at least gave work to Ellen Burstyn, whose professionalism and mere presence saves this from oblivion. Otherwise, a prime candidate for Lifetime's four a.m. movie. * from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The trepidation of accepting an ex-con in a country setting.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john-jennings-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I happen to love chick flicks-if that is what this film is categorized as.I love this movie, as do so many others who've made comments before me in the IMDb site. It was one of those films where I held my breath throughout, sensing an evil that would probably overtake the heroine before the picture ended.And so it did. The ending angered me greatly...here we have this wonderful character Percy who begins to grow on the residents and is finally being accepted,except for one mouthy,jealous bigot,- real-estate agent Nahum Goddard,who will not accept Percy into their midst.This misshapen belief finally leads to a grave misunderstanding by the citizenry who hunt Percy down, which ends in her drowning in a rushing stream. At the end Nahum admits he was wrong to judge Percy so harshly but darn it all the harm has been done. I was angry at director Lee David Zlotoff who had the "power" to make this a happy ending. He wrote the script!!! Let's say for example that Nahum Goddard had drowned saving Percy in that stream. The man would have gone to his death via an act of redemption (isn't that a religious quality held dear by a tight Christian community) and our heroine would have gone on living happily ever after in a comfortable setting. I saw this film when it came out, and I even have 2-3 copies of it on DVD and VHS but I can just not watch it again. I know how sad the ending will be. I still give the film a 9 1/2 though,it was still a great production.(I need to express my ratings in fractions). If Percy had not been killed off I would have given it a 10 for perfection, no question. I'm sorry, but if a beloved character is killed off "unnecssarily", then I can not give the film a 10. Too bad I had not been in one of the advance screenings to express my views. If film companies and the Director/Producer want a 10 from me they had better try for a happy,or at least satisfying ending if at all possible. So much of life is a tragedy and that's why in part we go to the movies to get away from reality, to get a quick shot of hope and to see some element of happiness, even in dramatic circumstances.Percy did not deserve to die after all of us had fallen so much in love with her persona. Could we stand a Spitfire Grill 2 where she miraculously appears one day alive and well? Probably not...Darn it all Lee David Zlotoff, what were you thinking?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once again Hollywood's reviews mean nothing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sam Poynter
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie got pretty bad reviews from the Hollywood Hype-mongers. I suppose because it didn't have a lot of flash. All it had was a well-written original story and superb acting with real characters. Anyone who has ever spent time in a small town can identify with nearly all the characters. I could practically name them all in the town I grew up in. I'm sure the only people who would NOT enjoy this movie are the ones who grew up in Hollywood and believe everyone is like them. If thats not you, rent this movie for a truly enjoyable evening. But you might want to bring tissues. It's a very warm and often funny movie, but it's also very sad in some places. Will Patton is incredible and I honestly don't understand why Alison Elliott hasn't been used more than she has since this movie. Ellen Burstyn was glorious as ever :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Male or Female, that is the only question you need ask
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    snafux7
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me make it simple for everyone... If you are a woman (especially if you happen to currently be menstruating) you will positively adore this movie. Just sit back with a glass of zinfandel and a box of tissues and enjoy. It is heavy-handed melodrama and clich&eacute; 'character' acting by all the usual female stereotypes but sometimes that isn't always a bad thing. I realize that this probably sounds condescending and insensitive so in advance let me apologize and recognize that everything I say is wrong anyway. If you are a dude on the other hand I hope and pray for you that you have a 2nd TV located in another room, preferably hooked up to a PS3 or XBOX so that you can properly recalibrate your testosterone level after watching the first 20 mins of this train wreck. It has absolutely nothing of interest to you, trust me. You know that feeling you get when you're alone in a room of women all talking at the same time and you can't leave? Now imagine an hour and a half of that with no respite, every time you think it cannot possibly go any further down the rabbit hole of "I do not give a f$*k" it somehow manages to kick it up a notch. As an aside, I was born and raised in the Northeast and the vast majority of 'Maine' accents in this film are about on par with the 'British' accents of Natalie Portman and Keanu Reeves, its pretty damn bad. Personally I think the average woman would give this 8-9 stars and the average guy would give it 1 or 2 so in all fairness I'm splitting the difference, we're it just up to me I'd give it either 1 or 0.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Over-hyped
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sir_brettley
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was allegedly a critical success but in reality it's a plodding, overwrought film that never really gets going. The characters are shallow and the alleged protagonist is a "Mary Sue". While I was led to believe that the film would be a wonderful account of people and complexities of relationships all I saw was bad writing and worse acting. While the written version and Biblical allegories of forgiveness and healing may work, this theatrical version misses the mark. I suppose if you have a pariah complex you can relate to this movie but for everyone else it's a waste of time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In Which a Woman is Saved by Being So Darn Plucky n Cute!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    someofusarebrave
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the kind of totally misogynistic movie that does such an excellent job of masquerading as a movie about female empowerment that it fools all but the most discerning types. There would be nothing wrong with that, except that it lulls us all into a false state of comfort. Police will always be kind, gentle folk, escaped convicts will always be 'really good' at heart, and a woman can be rescued from the worst types of spiritual and emotional pain by the 'power of the penis'. If only, right? Wrong. The world is not like that. In this world we all live in, police rape young homeless woman wandering around on their own as often as they help them out. Women who have been convicted of felonies rarely get second chances, regardless of how generous or good-hearted they happen to be. People are shaped by their circumstances and rarely manage to "rise above" them, instead dragging everyone else down with them often as not. There are no second chances. Nor should there be. Women who murder ought not to be let off the hook from the ramifications of their actions for "good behavior." Policemen ought not do the job of the non-government organizations and social programs which do not exist in the South for all intents and purposes. We ought not be able to work or charm our way out of being who we are. Everyone deserves the opportunity to start again, but part of that process MUST involve some acknowledgment of why things went so badly wrong in the first place. Teaching young girls that all they have to do to improve their lives is to trust the people around them unconditionally to help them out of any scrape they get into is morally bankrupt. Movies like this one do a terrible job of preparing young girls for the world they will actually be entering upon adulthood. It does a terrible job of describing the world they exist in now. We need to learn how to be less sweet and giving, rather than more so. Women are taught to be caring at the cost of everything we love about our lives and ourselves. Because we are so open-hearted, we are easily taken advantage of in our naivete. We need movie heroines who encourage us to be MORE wary, more suspicious of who we place our trust in, rather than less. We need heroines willing to stand on their own two feet and to work to accomplish their own dreams, rather than to fight for the dreams of those around them without a thought for themselves. In real life, this kind of goodness is boring...it is scrappiness, it is the willingness to stand one's ground and to fight for one's right to exist at all costs, that makes a life entertaining to watch and live. Instead, what this movie does is make us resent the people around us for achieving less than the perfection that the main characters of this movie achieve. We also hate ourselves for being less than wholly sweet. No man will ever solve all a woman's problems for her. No woman can work her way into redemption by serving the people around her rather than serving herself. There is no opportunity for healing without pride. No one can work themselves out of a pit of despair without honesty. May I live to see the day when movies all represent heroines of reality, rather than of male fantasies of what a 'real woman' should be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bittersweet look at small-town life and the vagaries of doing good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    has43
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I rated this movie 5/10 only because I truly hate the ending. Is the author saying Percy HAD to die to redeem everyone else? If so, that really stinks. God knows what her life was life before she took her tormentor out. AND after. Reminds me of "A Tree Grows In Brooklyn." The mother killed the man who raped her daughter, but after awhile all that anyone seems to remember is that she was convicted of murder. And then there's "Mystic River," wherein Tim Robbins' character was molested as a young boy by two priests, barely escapes with his life, such things were not discussed at that time, he lived with his pain, and then is taken out, and his murderer justifies the unfortunate wrongful murder, but we're left hanging as to any justice occurring, whatsoever. Also, I cannot abide Will Patton, in anything I've seen him in. Otherwise, I think the movie was pretty extraordinary, and I wish I'd walked out of the theater before the ending. If the author ever reads these reviews, I do wish he would explain the ending. Thank you for listening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bittersweet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alohahome
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very touching but bittersweet independent film. Slow and gentle. It concerns a young woman named Percy who wishes to reconcile her unsavory past in the small town of Giliad Maine but she is haunted by the very past that she wishes to overcome. Many people would like a chance to start over but life does not always afford then that opportunity. Nonetheless, we all still do affect others in ways that are not always seen. And therein lies the tale of redemption. A redemption that is sometimes too late in coming. Yet there is still hope in the unfairness all around us. And compassion to be found. Don't expect a Hollywood ending here. But who really wants one in this context? It's been said that Hollyweood films depict life as we would like to see it. But independent films depict life as it is. Small towns are hesitant enough about welcoming newcomers, yet Percy's arrival and her spirit is sensed as being something altogether different and the town finds itself changed forever. The inviting musical score by James Horner renders a sweet ambiance, consoling with a subdued drifty quality that lulls the soul in its wake.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spitfire Grill-Get The Charcoal Ready for this One ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whatever became of Alison Elliott, the heroine of this film? She gave an extremely believable performance here as a woman released from prison for killing the stepfather who had impregnated her and then had caused the death of the baby by beating the mother. Ellen Burstyn is the old lady who Elliott goes to work for. As always, Burstyn again proves that she is at her best when she does her mean, crotchety acting. It's another fine job. The story will tug at your heart since it's a tragic one. It again proves that you can't always judge people by what has happened in their lives. This misconception brings on the tragedy at the end that will drive you to tears. Note an interesting performance by Marcia Gay Harden, as a blond, worker of the Burstyn character who befriends Elliott. This is a very good study of rural life and human relationships.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gilead
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Furuya Shiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like movies that have lasting effect in my mind, and that make me think about the meaning of some scenes over and over. This movie is that kind. There may be many similar movies but this one is different from any of those. A young woman gets off a bus in a small excluded town Gilead in Mane, US. In this town, three women who have different kinds of psychological trauma as a mother work together in a restaurant "The Spitfire Grill". The protagonist is Percy (Alison Elliot). There are mysteries in her words and behavior. But as the story goes, the deep scar in her mind hidden behind the mystery is gradually revealed. The second woman is Hannah (Ellen Burstyn). She runs a restaurant "Spitfire Grill". She has her own, deep scar in her mind. The third is Shelby (Marcia Gay Harden). Though she is very warmhearted, her husband always insults her. Maybe she is the one you can easily empathize. Perhaps, there is a meaning in the name of the town, Gilead. At the near end of the movie, we hear a black spiritual song "There is a balm in Gilead". The name Gilead comes from biblical world, which produces frankincense that was much-prized as medicine. The first stanza of the song is as follows: There is a balm in Gilead / To make the wounded whole; / There is a balm in Gilead / To heal the sin sick soul. The key to understand the heart of the movie may be in the lyrics.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Burstyn's worth a look, but artificiality grills what's left over...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pure corn. A female ex-con in a small community in Maine gets waitressing job at the local diner, enlightening everyone there with her presence. Resolutely old-fashioned hokum is replete with pseudo-meaningful platitudes and female bonding (with divergent accents). Acquired at the Sundance Film Festival for what was reported to be a princely sum, Castle Rock barely distributed this after the reviews came in (they were probably hoping for another "Fried Green Tomatoes" but got rotten tomatoes instead). Trifling nonsense tries for a prestigious look, but even this fails as the moody ambiance resembles nothing more than encroaching mold. It at least gave work to Ellen Burstyn, whose professionalism and mere presence saves this from oblivion. Otherwise, a prime candidate for Lifetime's four a.m. movie. * from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The trepidation of accepting an ex-con in a country setting.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john-jennings-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I happen to love chick flicks-if that is what this film is categorized as.I love this movie, as do so many others who've made comments before me in the IMDb site. It was one of those films where I held my breath throughout, sensing an evil that would probably overtake the heroine before the picture ended.And so it did. The ending angered me greatly...here we have this wonderful character Percy who begins to grow on the residents and is finally being accepted,except for one mouthy,jealous bigot,- real-estate agent Nahum Goddard,who will not accept Percy into their midst.This misshapen belief finally leads to a grave misunderstanding by the citizenry who hunt Percy down, which ends in her drowning in a rushing stream. At the end Nahum admits he was wrong to judge Percy so harshly but darn it all the harm has been done. I was angry at director Lee David Zlotoff who had the "power" to make this a happy ending. He wrote the script!!! Let's say for example that Nahum Goddard had drowned saving Percy in that stream. The man would have gone to his death via an act of redemption (isn't that a religious quality held dear by a tight Christian community) and our heroine would have gone on living happily ever after in a comfortable setting. I saw this film when it came out, and I even have 2-3 copies of it on DVD and VHS but I can just not watch it again. I know how sad the ending will be. I still give the film a 9 1/2 though,it was still a great production.(I need to express my ratings in fractions). If Percy had not been killed off I would have given it a 10 for perfection, no question. I'm sorry, but if a beloved character is killed off "unnecssarily", then I can not give the film a 10. Too bad I had not been in one of the advance screenings to express my views. If film companies and the Director/Producer want a 10 from me they had better try for a happy,or at least satisfying ending if at all possible. So much of life is a tragedy and that's why in part we go to the movies to get away from reality, to get a quick shot of hope and to see some element of happiness, even in dramatic circumstances.Percy did not deserve to die after all of us had fallen so much in love with her persona. Could we stand a Spitfire Grill 2 where she miraculously appears one day alive and well? Probably not...Darn it all Lee David Zlotoff, what were you thinking?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once again Hollywood's reviews mean nothing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sam Poynter
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie got pretty bad reviews from the Hollywood Hype-mongers. I suppose because it didn't have a lot of flash. All it had was a well-written original story and superb acting with real characters. Anyone who has ever spent time in a small town can identify with nearly all the characters. I could practically name them all in the town I grew up in. I'm sure the only people who would NOT enjoy this movie are the ones who grew up in Hollywood and believe everyone is like them. If thats not you, rent this movie for a truly enjoyable evening. But you might want to bring tissues. It's a very warm and often funny movie, but it's also very sad in some places. Will Patton is incredible and I honestly don't understand why Alison Elliott hasn't been used more than she has since this movie. Ellen Burstyn was glorious as ever :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Male or Female, that is the only question you need ask
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    snafux7
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me make it simple for everyone... If you are a woman (especially if you happen to currently be menstruating) you will positively adore this movie. Just sit back with a glass of zinfandel and a box of tissues and enjoy. It is heavy-handed melodrama and clich&eacute; 'character' acting by all the usual female stereotypes but sometimes that isn't always a bad thing. I realize that this probably sounds condescending and insensitive so in advance let me apologize and recognize that everything I say is wrong anyway. If you are a dude on the other hand I hope and pray for you that you have a 2nd TV located in another room, preferably hooked up to a PS3 or XBOX so that you can properly recalibrate your testosterone level after watching the first 20 mins of this train wreck. It has absolutely nothing of interest to you, trust me. You know that feeling you get when you're alone in a room of women all talking at the same time and you can't leave? Now imagine an hour and a half of that with no respite, every time you think it cannot possibly go any further down the rabbit hole of "I do not give a f$*k" it somehow manages to kick it up a notch. As an aside, I was born and raised in the Northeast and the vast majority of 'Maine' accents in this film are about on par with the 'British' accents of Natalie Portman and Keanu Reeves, its pretty damn bad. Personally I think the average woman would give this 8-9 stars and the average guy would give it 1 or 2 so in all fairness I'm splitting the difference, we're it just up to me I'd give it either 1 or 0.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Over-hyped
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sir_brettley
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was allegedly a critical success but in reality it's a plodding, overwrought film that never really gets going. The characters are shallow and the alleged protagonist is a "Mary Sue". While I was led to believe that the film would be a wonderful account of people and complexities of relationships all I saw was bad writing and worse acting. While the written version and Biblical allegories of forgiveness and healing may work, this theatrical version misses the mark. I suppose if you have a pariah complex you can relate to this movie but for everyone else it's a waste of time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In Which a Woman is Saved by Being So Darn Plucky n Cute!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    someofusarebrave
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the kind of totally misogynistic movie that does such an excellent job of masquerading as a movie about female empowerment that it fools all but the most discerning types. There would be nothing wrong with that, except that it lulls us all into a false state of comfort. Police will always be kind, gentle folk, escaped convicts will always be 'really good' at heart, and a woman can be rescued from the worst types of spiritual and emotional pain by the 'power of the penis'. If only, right? Wrong. The world is not like that. In this world we all live in, police rape young homeless woman wandering around on their own as often as they help them out. Women who have been convicted of felonies rarely get second chances, regardless of how generous or good-hearted they happen to be. People are shaped by their circumstances and rarely manage to "rise above" them, instead dragging everyone else down with them often as not. There are no second chances. Nor should there be. Women who murder ought not to be let off the hook from the ramifications of their actions for "good behavior." Policemen ought not do the job of the non-government organizations and social programs which do not exist in the South for all intents and purposes. We ought not be able to work or charm our way out of being who we are. Everyone deserves the opportunity to start again, but part of that process MUST involve some acknowledgment of why things went so badly wrong in the first place. Teaching young girls that all they have to do to improve their lives is to trust the people around them unconditionally to help them out of any scrape they get into is morally bankrupt. Movies like this one do a terrible job of preparing young girls for the world they will actually be entering upon adulthood. It does a terrible job of describing the world they exist in now. We need to learn how to be less sweet and giving, rather than more so. Women are taught to be caring at the cost of everything we love about our lives and ourselves. Because we are so open-hearted, we are easily taken advantage of in our naivete. We need movie heroines who encourage us to be MORE wary, more suspicious of who we place our trust in, rather than less. We need heroines willing to stand on their own two feet and to work to accomplish their own dreams, rather than to fight for the dreams of those around them without a thought for themselves. In real life, this kind of goodness is boring...it is scrappiness, it is the willingness to stand one's ground and to fight for one's right to exist at all costs, that makes a life entertaining to watch and live. Instead, what this movie does is make us resent the people around us for achieving less than the perfection that the main characters of this movie achieve. We also hate ourselves for being less than wholly sweet. No man will ever solve all a woman's problems for her. No woman can work her way into redemption by serving the people around her rather than serving herself. There is no opportunity for healing without pride. No one can work themselves out of a pit of despair without honesty. May I live to see the day when movies all represent heroines of reality, rather than of male fantasies of what a 'real woman' should be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bittersweet look at small-town life and the vagaries of doing good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    has43
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I rated this movie 5/10 only because I truly hate the ending. Is the author saying Percy HAD to die to redeem everyone else? If so, that really stinks. God knows what her life was life before she took her tormentor out. AND after. Reminds me of "A Tree Grows In Brooklyn." The mother killed the man who raped her daughter, but after awhile all that anyone seems to remember is that she was convicted of murder. And then there's "Mystic River," wherein Tim Robbins' character was molested as a young boy by two priests, barely escapes with his life, such things were not discussed at that time, he lived with his pain, and then is taken out, and his murderer justifies the unfortunate wrongful murder, but we're left hanging as to any justice occurring, whatsoever. Also, I cannot abide Will Patton, in anything I've seen him in. Otherwise, I think the movie was pretty extraordinary, and I wish I'd walked out of the theater before the ending. If the author ever reads these reviews, I do wish he would explain the ending. Thank you for listening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bittersweet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alohahome
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very touching but bittersweet independent film. Slow and gentle. It concerns a young woman named Percy who wishes to reconcile her unsavory past in the small town of Giliad Maine but she is haunted by the very past that she wishes to overcome. Many people would like a chance to start over but life does not always afford then that opportunity. Nonetheless, we all still do affect others in ways that are not always seen. And therein lies the tale of redemption. A redemption that is sometimes too late in coming. Yet there is still hope in the unfairness all around us. And compassion to be found. Don't expect a Hollywood ending here. But who really wants one in this context? It's been said that Hollyweood films depict life as we would like to see it. But independent films depict life as it is. Small towns are hesitant enough about welcoming newcomers, yet Percy's arrival and her spirit is sensed as being something altogether different and the town finds itself changed forever. The inviting musical score by James Horner renders a sweet ambiance, consoling with a subdued drifty quality that lulls the soul in its wake.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spitfire Grill-Get The Charcoal Ready for this One ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whatever became of Alison Elliott, the heroine of this film? She gave an extremely believable performance here as a woman released from prison for killing the stepfather who had impregnated her and then had caused the death of the baby by beating the mother. Ellen Burstyn is the old lady who Elliott goes to work for. As always, Burstyn again proves that she is at her best when she does her mean, crotchety acting. It's another fine job. The story will tug at your heart since it's a tragic one. It again proves that you can't always judge people by what has happened in their lives. This misconception brings on the tragedy at the end that will drive you to tears. Note an interesting performance by Marcia Gay Harden, as a blond, worker of the Burstyn character who befriends Elliott. This is a very good study of rural life and human relationships.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gilead
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Furuya Shiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like movies that have lasting effect in my mind, and that make me think about the meaning of some scenes over and over. This movie is that kind. There may be many similar movies but this one is different from any of those. A young woman gets off a bus in a small excluded town Gilead in Mane, US. In this town, three women who have different kinds of psychological trauma as a mother work together in a restaurant "The Spitfire Grill". The protagonist is Percy (Alison Elliot). There are mysteries in her words and behavior. But as the story goes, the deep scar in her mind hidden behind the mystery is gradually revealed. The second woman is Hannah (Ellen Burstyn). She runs a restaurant "Spitfire Grill". She has her own, deep scar in her mind. The third is Shelby (Marcia Gay Harden). Though she is very warmhearted, her husband always insults her. Maybe she is the one you can easily empathize. Perhaps, there is a meaning in the name of the town, Gilead. At the near end of the movie, we hear a black spiritual song "There is a balm in Gilead". The name Gilead comes from biblical world, which produces frankincense that was much-prized as medicine. The first stanza of the song is as follows: There is a balm in Gilead / To make the wounded whole; / There is a balm in Gilead / To heal the sin sick soul. The key to understand the heart of the movie may be in the lyrics.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Burstyn's worth a look, but artificiality grills what's left over...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pure corn. A female ex-con in a small community in Maine gets waitressing job at the local diner, enlightening everyone there with her presence. Resolutely old-fashioned hokum is replete with pseudo-meaningful platitudes and female bonding (with divergent accents). Acquired at the Sundance Film Festival for what was reported to be a princely sum, Castle Rock barely distributed this after the reviews came in (they were probably hoping for another "Fried Green Tomatoes" but got rotten tomatoes instead). Trifling nonsense tries for a prestigious look, but even this fails as the moody ambiance resembles nothing more than encroaching mold. It at least gave work to Ellen Burstyn, whose professionalism and mere presence saves this from oblivion. Otherwise, a prime candidate for Lifetime's four a.m. movie. * from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The trepidation of accepting an ex-con in a country setting.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john-jennings-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I happen to love chick flicks-if that is what this film is categorized as.I love this movie, as do so many others who've made comments before me in the IMDb site. It was one of those films where I held my breath throughout, sensing an evil that would probably overtake the heroine before the picture ended.And so it did. The ending angered me greatly...here we have this wonderful character Percy who begins to grow on the residents and is finally being accepted,except for one mouthy,jealous bigot,- real-estate agent Nahum Goddard,who will not accept Percy into their midst.This misshapen belief finally leads to a grave misunderstanding by the citizenry who hunt Percy down, which ends in her drowning in a rushing stream. At the end Nahum admits he was wrong to judge Percy so harshly but darn it all the harm has been done. I was angry at director Lee David Zlotoff who had the "power" to make this a happy ending. He wrote the script!!! Let's say for example that Nahum Goddard had drowned saving Percy in that stream. The man would have gone to his death via an act of redemption (isn't that a religious quality held dear by a tight Christian community) and our heroine would have gone on living happily ever after in a comfortable setting. I saw this film when it came out, and I even have 2-3 copies of it on DVD and VHS but I can just not watch it again. I know how sad the ending will be. I still give the film a 9 1/2 though,it was still a great production.(I need to express my ratings in fractions). If Percy had not been killed off I would have given it a 10 for perfection, no question. I'm sorry, but if a beloved character is killed off "unnecssarily", then I can not give the film a 10. Too bad I had not been in one of the advance screenings to express my views. If film companies and the Director/Producer want a 10 from me they had better try for a happy,or at least satisfying ending if at all possible. So much of life is a tragedy and that's why in part we go to the movies to get away from reality, to get a quick shot of hope and to see some element of happiness, even in dramatic circumstances.Percy did not deserve to die after all of us had fallen so much in love with her persona. Could we stand a Spitfire Grill 2 where she miraculously appears one day alive and well? Probably not...Darn it all Lee David Zlotoff, what were you thinking?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once again Hollywood's reviews mean nothing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sam Poynter
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie got pretty bad reviews from the Hollywood Hype-mongers. I suppose because it didn't have a lot of flash. All it had was a well-written original story and superb acting with real characters. Anyone who has ever spent time in a small town can identify with nearly all the characters. I could practically name them all in the town I grew up in. I'm sure the only people who would NOT enjoy this movie are the ones who grew up in Hollywood and believe everyone is like them. If thats not you, rent this movie for a truly enjoyable evening. But you might want to bring tissues. It's a very warm and often funny movie, but it's also very sad in some places. Will Patton is incredible and I honestly don't understand why Alison Elliott hasn't been used more than she has since this movie. Ellen Burstyn was glorious as ever :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
