<filme>
 <id>
  1263
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116353
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Rebeldes
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The story of five teenage girls who form an unlikely bond after beating up a teacher who has sexually harassed them. They build a solid friendship but their wild ways begin to get out of ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  The story of five teenage girls who form an unlikely bond after beating up a teacher who has sexually harassed them. They build a solid friendship but their wild ways begin to get out of control.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   teenage girl
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   friendship
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   teacher
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   tomboy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   convention center pinnacles
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Annette Haywood-Carter
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Joyce Carol Oates
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Elizabeth White
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Hedy Burress
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Angelina Jolie
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jenny Lewis
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really loved this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lisa Mu&Atilde;&plusmn;oz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a great movie! Despite the low rating, this is a terrific 90's film with Angelina Jolie as Legs before she was famous, and even then, she was starting to show something very special. After a group of girls take revenge on a sadistic pedophile teacher, they get suspended by the dumb principal. They decide to stick together and move into an abandoned house. There, after they almost set fire to the school while trying to get the main character Maddy's portfolio, Legs tattoos herself and the other girls with a flame, bonding them all together for life. The film seemed to have a lot to do with the Riot Grrrl movement (an underground feminist punk music genre that helped girls making a name for themselves in a male dominated punk scene) In the film, the teenage girls are oppressed and abused while trying to stand up for themselves, even though they do things that aren't exactly right. The strong female bondage is brilliantly portrayed and I also loved the guitar solos in the music score, typical of the 90s. While some aspects of the film are a little clich&eacute;d and some situations are unrealistic, it's easier to tell ourselves that it's just a movie. I for one really enjoyed it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    stupid Jolie film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guilfisher-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once more this so called actress annoys the XXXX out of me. Her blowfish mouth looks like she should be blowing bubbles. I have never liked this actress and am in an amazement that she is so popular. I was hoping she'd jump earlier in the film and save us all the painful watching of this film. The other girls in this ridiculous flick deserve whatever happens to them. A collection of the most unattractive women ever put together in one film. There is no justice when they are continually allowed to get away with all the trouble they cause those around them. I have no sympathy for any of them. To me they should all be put away somewhere to rot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    savanah_17
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great movie. one of the best of Angelina Jolie. I love her. She does an excellent job of portraying the bad girl, and even better of making the movie what it is. She helps to push it to its full potential. Angelina has amazing talent. This movie is recommended for any girl who has never been the wild child. any girl who has never had the guts to do anything too drastic. excellent movie. I like Maddy. She is unique in that she is not your average teenage girl, but she is not drastic like legs. And who has a name like legs. It's like, once these girls have stood up for themselves, they can never go back. Like they are changed some how. I love this move and give it a excellent rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not an accurate novel adaptation but a great addition to the girl gang genre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mybluehooloovoo
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Firstly to correct an earlier reviewer this film is not based on a novel from the fifties, it's (very) loosely based on a Joyce Carol Oates novel that is set in the fifties but was first published in the nineties. The film isn't perfect, but no film is. The plot surrounds a group of teenage girls who are brought together by the arrival of a rebellious stranger named Legs. Like other girl gang films before it, such as Foxes (1980), the film employs certain character types regularly seen in movies of this sort, although this can hardly be considered an attempt to copy other movies. The film belongs to a specific sub-genre and as such it employs the conventions of that sub-genre. While some may simply pass this film off as clich&eacute;d others will look a little deeper and appreciate the film for what it is. Foxfire puts across a message rarely seen in American cinema - one that emphasizes the importance of teenage girls forming close friendships in order to assist their development into well-adjusted adults. And while the film may employ certain clich&eacute;s in order to get that message across (such as the somewhat one-dimensional secondary characters) the message itself is not a clich&eacute; and is an important one for girls of all ages.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Long, Boring, Silly
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    janetlee
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am totally shocked that so many here have raved about what a wonderful movie this is! It was so choppy and the more the story went on, the less I cared about the characters! The only good thing about the movie was Jolie (considering what she had to work with, but even she can't produce a miracle!) I must admit that I liked the cool house they hung out in. Otherwise, all I can say is run, run as fast as you can away from this junk!! Don't waste your time on this. It's a shame they didn't stay true to the book. It could've worked if there'd been a better script. It would've also been nice if they set it in the 50's or 60's. The characters would've been more believable in a different time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Girls just want to have tattoos.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Son_of_Mansfield
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Joyce Carol Oates 1950's era novel, Foxfire, is transplanted, unsuccessfully, into the modern age. Girls will still find a lot to like about the story, but it makes more sense in the repressed and repulsing era when sexual abuse was considered a "don't ask, don't tell" kind of an issue, where the girls where the sinners, simply because they were girls. Moving the story to the modern age only serves to take away that depth. As is, Angelina Jolie, Hedy Burress, and Jenny Shimizu are all good in this, with Jolie and Burress making, what could have been, a good couple as Legs and Maddy. The scene where the three take off their tops to get tattoos of a flame from Legs is powerful. It's not about sex or nudity, although their is a lot of the latter, it's about having a mark to identify each other. It's a great scene, most of the scenes with Jolie and Burress are, though the movie isn't quite.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the most genuine tale of friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FatesEmbrace
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this movie when I was 13. And even then found it to be an accurate display of what teens feel when in distress. I related a lot to "Legs" being the initial flame, Angelina was great in this movie. I have yet to see a pioneer in this genre that has matched in realism and the drama that consists of a teen's problems... when life seems to be in reverse and the world is against your every move...This movie has an underlying morale and for first time watchers, that morale will be completely different for each and every one of you. I find this movie true to it's intent, and would go back in time to see it for the first time, it left an impression on me that has yet to be surpassed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    comparing to the book is unfair to both
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dayna
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    but do read the book. especially if you did not like this movie. this movie was dumb, but angelina jolie and hedy burgess make it okay to not be too ashamed by the fact that you like it. it is much like 'center stage' in that regard. but in every other respect, it is much like someone tried to adapt a novel about girl gangs in the 50s into a movie about giggly juvenile delinquents in the 90s. it doesn't work, but like i said no one is watching it for the incredible story or acting chops. we're watching it to see if maddy will ever grow some metaphorical balls and kiss legs already!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solidarity At It's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alexandra Johnson
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have loved this movie ever since I first saw it. It forces you to think for yourself. What would happen if you acted on the impulses in your heart, instead of what you were told was right? Jolie gives a stunning performance as the free-spirited Legs, and Hedy Buress (Maddie) portrays the coming-out-of-her-shell part of us all extraordinarily well. The other characters are well thought out, but don't overwhelm the script. This movie speaks to the rebel in all of us, and it will make you laugh, cry, yearn, and hope. I believe that every generation of girls should see this movie, and realize that they have the ability to think for themselves as well. There is nudity on the part of 3 out of the five actresses, and partial nudity in the very beginning, but it is not distasteful or even sexual at all. It's more about being comfortable. Bless you, FoxFire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Movie To Remember
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tommkat666
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At first i wasn't quite sure about the movie, i had just rented it for something to do on a Saturday night and the next thing i know i was falling in love with all the characters. I guess it just hit home, i was especially jealous of Angelina Jolie's character and how fearless she was. Its one of those movie types that just stick with you and the emotion you feel at the time of viewing the film haunts you when you look back on it. The girls quickly became some of my favourite fictional heroes and i know i will always remember them. I would definitely recommend it especially if you enjoyed watching the Films 'The Dead Poets Society' or even 'Breakfast Club' or 'Stand by Me'. It is more darker then those movies but it was more real to me then anything i've seen. However there was one scene i would have to protest to the realism of it and being a girl i am fully aware on what girls do over at sleepover parties, even ones celebrating on an escape from the law and it doesn't happen. I won't go into any further details on the matter i'm sure you'll know the scene that i am talking about when you view the film. Anyways if you have issues with harsh language, sex scene types then i would avoid this film. Enjoy viewing. ;D
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really loved this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lisa Mu&Atilde;&plusmn;oz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a great movie! Despite the low rating, this is a terrific 90's film with Angelina Jolie as Legs before she was famous, and even then, she was starting to show something very special. After a group of girls take revenge on a sadistic pedophile teacher, they get suspended by the dumb principal. They decide to stick together and move into an abandoned house. There, after they almost set fire to the school while trying to get the main character Maddy's portfolio, Legs tattoos herself and the other girls with a flame, bonding them all together for life. The film seemed to have a lot to do with the Riot Grrrl movement (an underground feminist punk music genre that helped girls making a name for themselves in a male dominated punk scene) In the film, the teenage girls are oppressed and abused while trying to stand up for themselves, even though they do things that aren't exactly right. The strong female bondage is brilliantly portrayed and I also loved the guitar solos in the music score, typical of the 90s. While some aspects of the film are a little clich&eacute;d and some situations are unrealistic, it's easier to tell ourselves that it's just a movie. I for one really enjoyed it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    stupid Jolie film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guilfisher-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once more this so called actress annoys the XXXX out of me. Her blowfish mouth looks like she should be blowing bubbles. I have never liked this actress and am in an amazement that she is so popular. I was hoping she'd jump earlier in the film and save us all the painful watching of this film. The other girls in this ridiculous flick deserve whatever happens to them. A collection of the most unattractive women ever put together in one film. There is no justice when they are continually allowed to get away with all the trouble they cause those around them. I have no sympathy for any of them. To me they should all be put away somewhere to rot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    savanah_17
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great movie. one of the best of Angelina Jolie. I love her. She does an excellent job of portraying the bad girl, and even better of making the movie what it is. She helps to push it to its full potential. Angelina has amazing talent. This movie is recommended for any girl who has never been the wild child. any girl who has never had the guts to do anything too drastic. excellent movie. I like Maddy. She is unique in that she is not your average teenage girl, but she is not drastic like legs. And who has a name like legs. It's like, once these girls have stood up for themselves, they can never go back. Like they are changed some how. I love this move and give it a excellent rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not an accurate novel adaptation but a great addition to the girl gang genre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mybluehooloovoo
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Firstly to correct an earlier reviewer this film is not based on a novel from the fifties, it's (very) loosely based on a Joyce Carol Oates novel that is set in the fifties but was first published in the nineties. The film isn't perfect, but no film is. The plot surrounds a group of teenage girls who are brought together by the arrival of a rebellious stranger named Legs. Like other girl gang films before it, such as Foxes (1980), the film employs certain character types regularly seen in movies of this sort, although this can hardly be considered an attempt to copy other movies. The film belongs to a specific sub-genre and as such it employs the conventions of that sub-genre. While some may simply pass this film off as clich&eacute;d others will look a little deeper and appreciate the film for what it is. Foxfire puts across a message rarely seen in American cinema - one that emphasizes the importance of teenage girls forming close friendships in order to assist their development into well-adjusted adults. And while the film may employ certain clich&eacute;s in order to get that message across (such as the somewhat one-dimensional secondary characters) the message itself is not a clich&eacute; and is an important one for girls of all ages.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Long, Boring, Silly
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    janetlee
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am totally shocked that so many here have raved about what a wonderful movie this is! It was so choppy and the more the story went on, the less I cared about the characters! The only good thing about the movie was Jolie (considering what she had to work with, but even she can't produce a miracle!) I must admit that I liked the cool house they hung out in. Otherwise, all I can say is run, run as fast as you can away from this junk!! Don't waste your time on this. It's a shame they didn't stay true to the book. It could've worked if there'd been a better script. It would've also been nice if they set it in the 50's or 60's. The characters would've been more believable in a different time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Girls just want to have tattoos.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Son_of_Mansfield
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Joyce Carol Oates 1950's era novel, Foxfire, is transplanted, unsuccessfully, into the modern age. Girls will still find a lot to like about the story, but it makes more sense in the repressed and repulsing era when sexual abuse was considered a "don't ask, don't tell" kind of an issue, where the girls where the sinners, simply because they were girls. Moving the story to the modern age only serves to take away that depth. As is, Angelina Jolie, Hedy Burress, and Jenny Shimizu are all good in this, with Jolie and Burress making, what could have been, a good couple as Legs and Maddy. The scene where the three take off their tops to get tattoos of a flame from Legs is powerful. It's not about sex or nudity, although their is a lot of the latter, it's about having a mark to identify each other. It's a great scene, most of the scenes with Jolie and Burress are, though the movie isn't quite.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the most genuine tale of friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FatesEmbrace
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this movie when I was 13. And even then found it to be an accurate display of what teens feel when in distress. I related a lot to "Legs" being the initial flame, Angelina was great in this movie. I have yet to see a pioneer in this genre that has matched in realism and the drama that consists of a teen's problems... when life seems to be in reverse and the world is against your every move...This movie has an underlying morale and for first time watchers, that morale will be completely different for each and every one of you. I find this movie true to it's intent, and would go back in time to see it for the first time, it left an impression on me that has yet to be surpassed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    comparing to the book is unfair to both
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dayna
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    but do read the book. especially if you did not like this movie. this movie was dumb, but angelina jolie and hedy burgess make it okay to not be too ashamed by the fact that you like it. it is much like 'center stage' in that regard. but in every other respect, it is much like someone tried to adapt a novel about girl gangs in the 50s into a movie about giggly juvenile delinquents in the 90s. it doesn't work, but like i said no one is watching it for the incredible story or acting chops. we're watching it to see if maddy will ever grow some metaphorical balls and kiss legs already!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solidarity At It's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alexandra Johnson
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have loved this movie ever since I first saw it. It forces you to think for yourself. What would happen if you acted on the impulses in your heart, instead of what you were told was right? Jolie gives a stunning performance as the free-spirited Legs, and Hedy Buress (Maddie) portrays the coming-out-of-her-shell part of us all extraordinarily well. The other characters are well thought out, but don't overwhelm the script. This movie speaks to the rebel in all of us, and it will make you laugh, cry, yearn, and hope. I believe that every generation of girls should see this movie, and realize that they have the ability to think for themselves as well. There is nudity on the part of 3 out of the five actresses, and partial nudity in the very beginning, but it is not distasteful or even sexual at all. It's more about being comfortable. Bless you, FoxFire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Movie To Remember
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tommkat666
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At first i wasn't quite sure about the movie, i had just rented it for something to do on a Saturday night and the next thing i know i was falling in love with all the characters. I guess it just hit home, i was especially jealous of Angelina Jolie's character and how fearless she was. Its one of those movie types that just stick with you and the emotion you feel at the time of viewing the film haunts you when you look back on it. The girls quickly became some of my favourite fictional heroes and i know i will always remember them. I would definitely recommend it especially if you enjoyed watching the Films 'The Dead Poets Society' or even 'Breakfast Club' or 'Stand by Me'. It is more darker then those movies but it was more real to me then anything i've seen. However there was one scene i would have to protest to the realism of it and being a girl i am fully aware on what girls do over at sleepover parties, even ones celebrating on an escape from the law and it doesn't happen. I won't go into any further details on the matter i'm sure you'll know the scene that i am talking about when you view the film. Anyways if you have issues with harsh language, sex scene types then i would avoid this film. Enjoy viewing. ;D
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really loved this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lisa Mu&Atilde;&plusmn;oz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a great movie! Despite the low rating, this is a terrific 90's film with Angelina Jolie as Legs before she was famous, and even then, she was starting to show something very special. After a group of girls take revenge on a sadistic pedophile teacher, they get suspended by the dumb principal. They decide to stick together and move into an abandoned house. There, after they almost set fire to the school while trying to get the main character Maddy's portfolio, Legs tattoos herself and the other girls with a flame, bonding them all together for life. The film seemed to have a lot to do with the Riot Grrrl movement (an underground feminist punk music genre that helped girls making a name for themselves in a male dominated punk scene) In the film, the teenage girls are oppressed and abused while trying to stand up for themselves, even though they do things that aren't exactly right. The strong female bondage is brilliantly portrayed and I also loved the guitar solos in the music score, typical of the 90s. While some aspects of the film are a little clich&eacute;d and some situations are unrealistic, it's easier to tell ourselves that it's just a movie. I for one really enjoyed it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    stupid Jolie film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guilfisher-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once more this so called actress annoys the XXXX out of me. Her blowfish mouth looks like she should be blowing bubbles. I have never liked this actress and am in an amazement that she is so popular. I was hoping she'd jump earlier in the film and save us all the painful watching of this film. The other girls in this ridiculous flick deserve whatever happens to them. A collection of the most unattractive women ever put together in one film. There is no justice when they are continually allowed to get away with all the trouble they cause those around them. I have no sympathy for any of them. To me they should all be put away somewhere to rot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    savanah_17
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great movie. one of the best of Angelina Jolie. I love her. She does an excellent job of portraying the bad girl, and even better of making the movie what it is. She helps to push it to its full potential. Angelina has amazing talent. This movie is recommended for any girl who has never been the wild child. any girl who has never had the guts to do anything too drastic. excellent movie. I like Maddy. She is unique in that she is not your average teenage girl, but she is not drastic like legs. And who has a name like legs. It's like, once these girls have stood up for themselves, they can never go back. Like they are changed some how. I love this move and give it a excellent rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not an accurate novel adaptation but a great addition to the girl gang genre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mybluehooloovoo
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Firstly to correct an earlier reviewer this film is not based on a novel from the fifties, it's (very) loosely based on a Joyce Carol Oates novel that is set in the fifties but was first published in the nineties. The film isn't perfect, but no film is. The plot surrounds a group of teenage girls who are brought together by the arrival of a rebellious stranger named Legs. Like other girl gang films before it, such as Foxes (1980), the film employs certain character types regularly seen in movies of this sort, although this can hardly be considered an attempt to copy other movies. The film belongs to a specific sub-genre and as such it employs the conventions of that sub-genre. While some may simply pass this film off as clich&eacute;d others will look a little deeper and appreciate the film for what it is. Foxfire puts across a message rarely seen in American cinema - one that emphasizes the importance of teenage girls forming close friendships in order to assist their development into well-adjusted adults. And while the film may employ certain clich&eacute;s in order to get that message across (such as the somewhat one-dimensional secondary characters) the message itself is not a clich&eacute; and is an important one for girls of all ages.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Long, Boring, Silly
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    janetlee
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am totally shocked that so many here have raved about what a wonderful movie this is! It was so choppy and the more the story went on, the less I cared about the characters! The only good thing about the movie was Jolie (considering what she had to work with, but even she can't produce a miracle!) I must admit that I liked the cool house they hung out in. Otherwise, all I can say is run, run as fast as you can away from this junk!! Don't waste your time on this. It's a shame they didn't stay true to the book. It could've worked if there'd been a better script. It would've also been nice if they set it in the 50's or 60's. The characters would've been more believable in a different time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Girls just want to have tattoos.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Son_of_Mansfield
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Joyce Carol Oates 1950's era novel, Foxfire, is transplanted, unsuccessfully, into the modern age. Girls will still find a lot to like about the story, but it makes more sense in the repressed and repulsing era when sexual abuse was considered a "don't ask, don't tell" kind of an issue, where the girls where the sinners, simply because they were girls. Moving the story to the modern age only serves to take away that depth. As is, Angelina Jolie, Hedy Burress, and Jenny Shimizu are all good in this, with Jolie and Burress making, what could have been, a good couple as Legs and Maddy. The scene where the three take off their tops to get tattoos of a flame from Legs is powerful. It's not about sex or nudity, although their is a lot of the latter, it's about having a mark to identify each other. It's a great scene, most of the scenes with Jolie and Burress are, though the movie isn't quite.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the most genuine tale of friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FatesEmbrace
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this movie when I was 13. And even then found it to be an accurate display of what teens feel when in distress. I related a lot to "Legs" being the initial flame, Angelina was great in this movie. I have yet to see a pioneer in this genre that has matched in realism and the drama that consists of a teen's problems... when life seems to be in reverse and the world is against your every move...This movie has an underlying morale and for first time watchers, that morale will be completely different for each and every one of you. I find this movie true to it's intent, and would go back in time to see it for the first time, it left an impression on me that has yet to be surpassed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    comparing to the book is unfair to both
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dayna
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    but do read the book. especially if you did not like this movie. this movie was dumb, but angelina jolie and hedy burgess make it okay to not be too ashamed by the fact that you like it. it is much like 'center stage' in that regard. but in every other respect, it is much like someone tried to adapt a novel about girl gangs in the 50s into a movie about giggly juvenile delinquents in the 90s. it doesn't work, but like i said no one is watching it for the incredible story or acting chops. we're watching it to see if maddy will ever grow some metaphorical balls and kiss legs already!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solidarity At It's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alexandra Johnson
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have loved this movie ever since I first saw it. It forces you to think for yourself. What would happen if you acted on the impulses in your heart, instead of what you were told was right? Jolie gives a stunning performance as the free-spirited Legs, and Hedy Buress (Maddie) portrays the coming-out-of-her-shell part of us all extraordinarily well. The other characters are well thought out, but don't overwhelm the script. This movie speaks to the rebel in all of us, and it will make you laugh, cry, yearn, and hope. I believe that every generation of girls should see this movie, and realize that they have the ability to think for themselves as well. There is nudity on the part of 3 out of the five actresses, and partial nudity in the very beginning, but it is not distasteful or even sexual at all. It's more about being comfortable. Bless you, FoxFire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Movie To Remember
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tommkat666
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At first i wasn't quite sure about the movie, i had just rented it for something to do on a Saturday night and the next thing i know i was falling in love with all the characters. I guess it just hit home, i was especially jealous of Angelina Jolie's character and how fearless she was. Its one of those movie types that just stick with you and the emotion you feel at the time of viewing the film haunts you when you look back on it. The girls quickly became some of my favourite fictional heroes and i know i will always remember them. I would definitely recommend it especially if you enjoyed watching the Films 'The Dead Poets Society' or even 'Breakfast Club' or 'Stand by Me'. It is more darker then those movies but it was more real to me then anything i've seen. However there was one scene i would have to protest to the realism of it and being a girl i am fully aware on what girls do over at sleepover parties, even ones celebrating on an escape from the law and it doesn't happen. I won't go into any further details on the matter i'm sure you'll know the scene that i am talking about when you view the film. Anyways if you have issues with harsh language, sex scene types then i would avoid this film. Enjoy viewing. ;D
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really loved this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lisa Mu&Atilde;&plusmn;oz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a great movie! Despite the low rating, this is a terrific 90's film with Angelina Jolie as Legs before she was famous, and even then, she was starting to show something very special. After a group of girls take revenge on a sadistic pedophile teacher, they get suspended by the dumb principal. They decide to stick together and move into an abandoned house. There, after they almost set fire to the school while trying to get the main character Maddy's portfolio, Legs tattoos herself and the other girls with a flame, bonding them all together for life. The film seemed to have a lot to do with the Riot Grrrl movement (an underground feminist punk music genre that helped girls making a name for themselves in a male dominated punk scene) In the film, the teenage girls are oppressed and abused while trying to stand up for themselves, even though they do things that aren't exactly right. The strong female bondage is brilliantly portrayed and I also loved the guitar solos in the music score, typical of the 90s. While some aspects of the film are a little clich&eacute;d and some situations are unrealistic, it's easier to tell ourselves that it's just a movie. I for one really enjoyed it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    stupid Jolie film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guilfisher-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once more this so called actress annoys the XXXX out of me. Her blowfish mouth looks like she should be blowing bubbles. I have never liked this actress and am in an amazement that she is so popular. I was hoping she'd jump earlier in the film and save us all the painful watching of this film. The other girls in this ridiculous flick deserve whatever happens to them. A collection of the most unattractive women ever put together in one film. There is no justice when they are continually allowed to get away with all the trouble they cause those around them. I have no sympathy for any of them. To me they should all be put away somewhere to rot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    savanah_17
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great movie. one of the best of Angelina Jolie. I love her. She does an excellent job of portraying the bad girl, and even better of making the movie what it is. She helps to push it to its full potential. Angelina has amazing talent. This movie is recommended for any girl who has never been the wild child. any girl who has never had the guts to do anything too drastic. excellent movie. I like Maddy. She is unique in that she is not your average teenage girl, but she is not drastic like legs. And who has a name like legs. It's like, once these girls have stood up for themselves, they can never go back. Like they are changed some how. I love this move and give it a excellent rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not an accurate novel adaptation but a great addition to the girl gang genre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mybluehooloovoo
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Firstly to correct an earlier reviewer this film is not based on a novel from the fifties, it's (very) loosely based on a Joyce Carol Oates novel that is set in the fifties but was first published in the nineties. The film isn't perfect, but no film is. The plot surrounds a group of teenage girls who are brought together by the arrival of a rebellious stranger named Legs. Like other girl gang films before it, such as Foxes (1980), the film employs certain character types regularly seen in movies of this sort, although this can hardly be considered an attempt to copy other movies. The film belongs to a specific sub-genre and as such it employs the conventions of that sub-genre. While some may simply pass this film off as clich&eacute;d others will look a little deeper and appreciate the film for what it is. Foxfire puts across a message rarely seen in American cinema - one that emphasizes the importance of teenage girls forming close friendships in order to assist their development into well-adjusted adults. And while the film may employ certain clich&eacute;s in order to get that message across (such as the somewhat one-dimensional secondary characters) the message itself is not a clich&eacute; and is an important one for girls of all ages.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Long, Boring, Silly
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    janetlee
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am totally shocked that so many here have raved about what a wonderful movie this is! It was so choppy and the more the story went on, the less I cared about the characters! The only good thing about the movie was Jolie (considering what she had to work with, but even she can't produce a miracle!) I must admit that I liked the cool house they hung out in. Otherwise, all I can say is run, run as fast as you can away from this junk!! Don't waste your time on this. It's a shame they didn't stay true to the book. It could've worked if there'd been a better script. It would've also been nice if they set it in the 50's or 60's. The characters would've been more believable in a different time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Girls just want to have tattoos.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Son_of_Mansfield
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Joyce Carol Oates 1950's era novel, Foxfire, is transplanted, unsuccessfully, into the modern age. Girls will still find a lot to like about the story, but it makes more sense in the repressed and repulsing era when sexual abuse was considered a "don't ask, don't tell" kind of an issue, where the girls where the sinners, simply because they were girls. Moving the story to the modern age only serves to take away that depth. As is, Angelina Jolie, Hedy Burress, and Jenny Shimizu are all good in this, with Jolie and Burress making, what could have been, a good couple as Legs and Maddy. The scene where the three take off their tops to get tattoos of a flame from Legs is powerful. It's not about sex or nudity, although their is a lot of the latter, it's about having a mark to identify each other. It's a great scene, most of the scenes with Jolie and Burress are, though the movie isn't quite.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the most genuine tale of friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FatesEmbrace
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this movie when I was 13. And even then found it to be an accurate display of what teens feel when in distress. I related a lot to "Legs" being the initial flame, Angelina was great in this movie. I have yet to see a pioneer in this genre that has matched in realism and the drama that consists of a teen's problems... when life seems to be in reverse and the world is against your every move...This movie has an underlying morale and for first time watchers, that morale will be completely different for each and every one of you. I find this movie true to it's intent, and would go back in time to see it for the first time, it left an impression on me that has yet to be surpassed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    comparing to the book is unfair to both
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dayna
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    but do read the book. especially if you did not like this movie. this movie was dumb, but angelina jolie and hedy burgess make it okay to not be too ashamed by the fact that you like it. it is much like 'center stage' in that regard. but in every other respect, it is much like someone tried to adapt a novel about girl gangs in the 50s into a movie about giggly juvenile delinquents in the 90s. it doesn't work, but like i said no one is watching it for the incredible story or acting chops. we're watching it to see if maddy will ever grow some metaphorical balls and kiss legs already!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solidarity At It's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alexandra Johnson
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have loved this movie ever since I first saw it. It forces you to think for yourself. What would happen if you acted on the impulses in your heart, instead of what you were told was right? Jolie gives a stunning performance as the free-spirited Legs, and Hedy Buress (Maddie) portrays the coming-out-of-her-shell part of us all extraordinarily well. The other characters are well thought out, but don't overwhelm the script. This movie speaks to the rebel in all of us, and it will make you laugh, cry, yearn, and hope. I believe that every generation of girls should see this movie, and realize that they have the ability to think for themselves as well. There is nudity on the part of 3 out of the five actresses, and partial nudity in the very beginning, but it is not distasteful or even sexual at all. It's more about being comfortable. Bless you, FoxFire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Movie To Remember
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tommkat666
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At first i wasn't quite sure about the movie, i had just rented it for something to do on a Saturday night and the next thing i know i was falling in love with all the characters. I guess it just hit home, i was especially jealous of Angelina Jolie's character and how fearless she was. Its one of those movie types that just stick with you and the emotion you feel at the time of viewing the film haunts you when you look back on it. The girls quickly became some of my favourite fictional heroes and i know i will always remember them. I would definitely recommend it especially if you enjoyed watching the Films 'The Dead Poets Society' or even 'Breakfast Club' or 'Stand by Me'. It is more darker then those movies but it was more real to me then anything i've seen. However there was one scene i would have to protest to the realism of it and being a girl i am fully aware on what girls do over at sleepover parties, even ones celebrating on an escape from the law and it doesn't happen. I won't go into any further details on the matter i'm sure you'll know the scene that i am talking about when you view the film. Anyways if you have issues with harsh language, sex scene types then i would avoid this film. Enjoy viewing. ;D
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really loved this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lisa Mu&Atilde;&plusmn;oz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a great movie! Despite the low rating, this is a terrific 90's film with Angelina Jolie as Legs before she was famous, and even then, she was starting to show something very special. After a group of girls take revenge on a sadistic pedophile teacher, they get suspended by the dumb principal. They decide to stick together and move into an abandoned house. There, after they almost set fire to the school while trying to get the main character Maddy's portfolio, Legs tattoos herself and the other girls with a flame, bonding them all together for life. The film seemed to have a lot to do with the Riot Grrrl movement (an underground feminist punk music genre that helped girls making a name for themselves in a male dominated punk scene) In the film, the teenage girls are oppressed and abused while trying to stand up for themselves, even though they do things that aren't exactly right. The strong female bondage is brilliantly portrayed and I also loved the guitar solos in the music score, typical of the 90s. While some aspects of the film are a little clich&eacute;d and some situations are unrealistic, it's easier to tell ourselves that it's just a movie. I for one really enjoyed it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    stupid Jolie film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guilfisher-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once more this so called actress annoys the XXXX out of me. Her blowfish mouth looks like she should be blowing bubbles. I have never liked this actress and am in an amazement that she is so popular. I was hoping she'd jump earlier in the film and save us all the painful watching of this film. The other girls in this ridiculous flick deserve whatever happens to them. A collection of the most unattractive women ever put together in one film. There is no justice when they are continually allowed to get away with all the trouble they cause those around them. I have no sympathy for any of them. To me they should all be put away somewhere to rot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    savanah_17
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great movie. one of the best of Angelina Jolie. I love her. She does an excellent job of portraying the bad girl, and even better of making the movie what it is. She helps to push it to its full potential. Angelina has amazing talent. This movie is recommended for any girl who has never been the wild child. any girl who has never had the guts to do anything too drastic. excellent movie. I like Maddy. She is unique in that she is not your average teenage girl, but she is not drastic like legs. And who has a name like legs. It's like, once these girls have stood up for themselves, they can never go back. Like they are changed some how. I love this move and give it a excellent rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not an accurate novel adaptation but a great addition to the girl gang genre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mybluehooloovoo
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Firstly to correct an earlier reviewer this film is not based on a novel from the fifties, it's (very) loosely based on a Joyce Carol Oates novel that is set in the fifties but was first published in the nineties. The film isn't perfect, but no film is. The plot surrounds a group of teenage girls who are brought together by the arrival of a rebellious stranger named Legs. Like other girl gang films before it, such as Foxes (1980), the film employs certain character types regularly seen in movies of this sort, although this can hardly be considered an attempt to copy other movies. The film belongs to a specific sub-genre and as such it employs the conventions of that sub-genre. While some may simply pass this film off as clich&eacute;d others will look a little deeper and appreciate the film for what it is. Foxfire puts across a message rarely seen in American cinema - one that emphasizes the importance of teenage girls forming close friendships in order to assist their development into well-adjusted adults. And while the film may employ certain clich&eacute;s in order to get that message across (such as the somewhat one-dimensional secondary characters) the message itself is not a clich&eacute; and is an important one for girls of all ages.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Long, Boring, Silly
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    janetlee
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am totally shocked that so many here have raved about what a wonderful movie this is! It was so choppy and the more the story went on, the less I cared about the characters! The only good thing about the movie was Jolie (considering what she had to work with, but even she can't produce a miracle!) I must admit that I liked the cool house they hung out in. Otherwise, all I can say is run, run as fast as you can away from this junk!! Don't waste your time on this. It's a shame they didn't stay true to the book. It could've worked if there'd been a better script. It would've also been nice if they set it in the 50's or 60's. The characters would've been more believable in a different time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Girls just want to have tattoos.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Son_of_Mansfield
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Joyce Carol Oates 1950's era novel, Foxfire, is transplanted, unsuccessfully, into the modern age. Girls will still find a lot to like about the story, but it makes more sense in the repressed and repulsing era when sexual abuse was considered a "don't ask, don't tell" kind of an issue, where the girls where the sinners, simply because they were girls. Moving the story to the modern age only serves to take away that depth. As is, Angelina Jolie, Hedy Burress, and Jenny Shimizu are all good in this, with Jolie and Burress making, what could have been, a good couple as Legs and Maddy. The scene where the three take off their tops to get tattoos of a flame from Legs is powerful. It's not about sex or nudity, although their is a lot of the latter, it's about having a mark to identify each other. It's a great scene, most of the scenes with Jolie and Burress are, though the movie isn't quite.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the most genuine tale of friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FatesEmbrace
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this movie when I was 13. And even then found it to be an accurate display of what teens feel when in distress. I related a lot to "Legs" being the initial flame, Angelina was great in this movie. I have yet to see a pioneer in this genre that has matched in realism and the drama that consists of a teen's problems... when life seems to be in reverse and the world is against your every move...This movie has an underlying morale and for first time watchers, that morale will be completely different for each and every one of you. I find this movie true to it's intent, and would go back in time to see it for the first time, it left an impression on me that has yet to be surpassed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    comparing to the book is unfair to both
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dayna
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    but do read the book. especially if you did not like this movie. this movie was dumb, but angelina jolie and hedy burgess make it okay to not be too ashamed by the fact that you like it. it is much like 'center stage' in that regard. but in every other respect, it is much like someone tried to adapt a novel about girl gangs in the 50s into a movie about giggly juvenile delinquents in the 90s. it doesn't work, but like i said no one is watching it for the incredible story or acting chops. we're watching it to see if maddy will ever grow some metaphorical balls and kiss legs already!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solidarity At It's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alexandra Johnson
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have loved this movie ever since I first saw it. It forces you to think for yourself. What would happen if you acted on the impulses in your heart, instead of what you were told was right? Jolie gives a stunning performance as the free-spirited Legs, and Hedy Buress (Maddie) portrays the coming-out-of-her-shell part of us all extraordinarily well. The other characters are well thought out, but don't overwhelm the script. This movie speaks to the rebel in all of us, and it will make you laugh, cry, yearn, and hope. I believe that every generation of girls should see this movie, and realize that they have the ability to think for themselves as well. There is nudity on the part of 3 out of the five actresses, and partial nudity in the very beginning, but it is not distasteful or even sexual at all. It's more about being comfortable. Bless you, FoxFire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Movie To Remember
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tommkat666
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At first i wasn't quite sure about the movie, i had just rented it for something to do on a Saturday night and the next thing i know i was falling in love with all the characters. I guess it just hit home, i was especially jealous of Angelina Jolie's character and how fearless she was. Its one of those movie types that just stick with you and the emotion you feel at the time of viewing the film haunts you when you look back on it. The girls quickly became some of my favourite fictional heroes and i know i will always remember them. I would definitely recommend it especially if you enjoyed watching the Films 'The Dead Poets Society' or even 'Breakfast Club' or 'Stand by Me'. It is more darker then those movies but it was more real to me then anything i've seen. However there was one scene i would have to protest to the realism of it and being a girl i am fully aware on what girls do over at sleepover parties, even ones celebrating on an escape from the law and it doesn't happen. I won't go into any further details on the matter i'm sure you'll know the scene that i am talking about when you view the film. Anyways if you have issues with harsh language, sex scene types then i would avoid this film. Enjoy viewing. ;D
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really loved this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lisa Mu&Atilde;&plusmn;oz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a great movie! Despite the low rating, this is a terrific 90's film with Angelina Jolie as Legs before she was famous, and even then, she was starting to show something very special. After a group of girls take revenge on a sadistic pedophile teacher, they get suspended by the dumb principal. They decide to stick together and move into an abandoned house. There, after they almost set fire to the school while trying to get the main character Maddy's portfolio, Legs tattoos herself and the other girls with a flame, bonding them all together for life. The film seemed to have a lot to do with the Riot Grrrl movement (an underground feminist punk music genre that helped girls making a name for themselves in a male dominated punk scene) In the film, the teenage girls are oppressed and abused while trying to stand up for themselves, even though they do things that aren't exactly right. The strong female bondage is brilliantly portrayed and I also loved the guitar solos in the music score, typical of the 90s. While some aspects of the film are a little clich&eacute;d and some situations are unrealistic, it's easier to tell ourselves that it's just a movie. I for one really enjoyed it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    stupid Jolie film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guilfisher-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once more this so called actress annoys the XXXX out of me. Her blowfish mouth looks like she should be blowing bubbles. I have never liked this actress and am in an amazement that she is so popular. I was hoping she'd jump earlier in the film and save us all the painful watching of this film. The other girls in this ridiculous flick deserve whatever happens to them. A collection of the most unattractive women ever put together in one film. There is no justice when they are continually allowed to get away with all the trouble they cause those around them. I have no sympathy for any of them. To me they should all be put away somewhere to rot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    savanah_17
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great movie. one of the best of Angelina Jolie. I love her. She does an excellent job of portraying the bad girl, and even better of making the movie what it is. She helps to push it to its full potential. Angelina has amazing talent. This movie is recommended for any girl who has never been the wild child. any girl who has never had the guts to do anything too drastic. excellent movie. I like Maddy. She is unique in that she is not your average teenage girl, but she is not drastic like legs. And who has a name like legs. It's like, once these girls have stood up for themselves, they can never go back. Like they are changed some how. I love this move and give it a excellent rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not an accurate novel adaptation but a great addition to the girl gang genre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mybluehooloovoo
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Firstly to correct an earlier reviewer this film is not based on a novel from the fifties, it's (very) loosely based on a Joyce Carol Oates novel that is set in the fifties but was first published in the nineties. The film isn't perfect, but no film is. The plot surrounds a group of teenage girls who are brought together by the arrival of a rebellious stranger named Legs. Like other girl gang films before it, such as Foxes (1980), the film employs certain character types regularly seen in movies of this sort, although this can hardly be considered an attempt to copy other movies. The film belongs to a specific sub-genre and as such it employs the conventions of that sub-genre. While some may simply pass this film off as clich&eacute;d others will look a little deeper and appreciate the film for what it is. Foxfire puts across a message rarely seen in American cinema - one that emphasizes the importance of teenage girls forming close friendships in order to assist their development into well-adjusted adults. And while the film may employ certain clich&eacute;s in order to get that message across (such as the somewhat one-dimensional secondary characters) the message itself is not a clich&eacute; and is an important one for girls of all ages.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Long, Boring, Silly
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    janetlee
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am totally shocked that so many here have raved about what a wonderful movie this is! It was so choppy and the more the story went on, the less I cared about the characters! The only good thing about the movie was Jolie (considering what she had to work with, but even she can't produce a miracle!) I must admit that I liked the cool house they hung out in. Otherwise, all I can say is run, run as fast as you can away from this junk!! Don't waste your time on this. It's a shame they didn't stay true to the book. It could've worked if there'd been a better script. It would've also been nice if they set it in the 50's or 60's. The characters would've been more believable in a different time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Girls just want to have tattoos.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Son_of_Mansfield
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Joyce Carol Oates 1950's era novel, Foxfire, is transplanted, unsuccessfully, into the modern age. Girls will still find a lot to like about the story, but it makes more sense in the repressed and repulsing era when sexual abuse was considered a "don't ask, don't tell" kind of an issue, where the girls where the sinners, simply because they were girls. Moving the story to the modern age only serves to take away that depth. As is, Angelina Jolie, Hedy Burress, and Jenny Shimizu are all good in this, with Jolie and Burress making, what could have been, a good couple as Legs and Maddy. The scene where the three take off their tops to get tattoos of a flame from Legs is powerful. It's not about sex or nudity, although their is a lot of the latter, it's about having a mark to identify each other. It's a great scene, most of the scenes with Jolie and Burress are, though the movie isn't quite.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the most genuine tale of friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FatesEmbrace
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this movie when I was 13. And even then found it to be an accurate display of what teens feel when in distress. I related a lot to "Legs" being the initial flame, Angelina was great in this movie. I have yet to see a pioneer in this genre that has matched in realism and the drama that consists of a teen's problems... when life seems to be in reverse and the world is against your every move...This movie has an underlying morale and for first time watchers, that morale will be completely different for each and every one of you. I find this movie true to it's intent, and would go back in time to see it for the first time, it left an impression on me that has yet to be surpassed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    comparing to the book is unfair to both
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dayna
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    but do read the book. especially if you did not like this movie. this movie was dumb, but angelina jolie and hedy burgess make it okay to not be too ashamed by the fact that you like it. it is much like 'center stage' in that regard. but in every other respect, it is much like someone tried to adapt a novel about girl gangs in the 50s into a movie about giggly juvenile delinquents in the 90s. it doesn't work, but like i said no one is watching it for the incredible story or acting chops. we're watching it to see if maddy will ever grow some metaphorical balls and kiss legs already!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solidarity At It's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alexandra Johnson
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have loved this movie ever since I first saw it. It forces you to think for yourself. What would happen if you acted on the impulses in your heart, instead of what you were told was right? Jolie gives a stunning performance as the free-spirited Legs, and Hedy Buress (Maddie) portrays the coming-out-of-her-shell part of us all extraordinarily well. The other characters are well thought out, but don't overwhelm the script. This movie speaks to the rebel in all of us, and it will make you laugh, cry, yearn, and hope. I believe that every generation of girls should see this movie, and realize that they have the ability to think for themselves as well. There is nudity on the part of 3 out of the five actresses, and partial nudity in the very beginning, but it is not distasteful or even sexual at all. It's more about being comfortable. Bless you, FoxFire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Movie To Remember
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tommkat666
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At first i wasn't quite sure about the movie, i had just rented it for something to do on a Saturday night and the next thing i know i was falling in love with all the characters. I guess it just hit home, i was especially jealous of Angelina Jolie's character and how fearless she was. Its one of those movie types that just stick with you and the emotion you feel at the time of viewing the film haunts you when you look back on it. The girls quickly became some of my favourite fictional heroes and i know i will always remember them. I would definitely recommend it especially if you enjoyed watching the Films 'The Dead Poets Society' or even 'Breakfast Club' or 'Stand by Me'. It is more darker then those movies but it was more real to me then anything i've seen. However there was one scene i would have to protest to the realism of it and being a girl i am fully aware on what girls do over at sleepover parties, even ones celebrating on an escape from the law and it doesn't happen. I won't go into any further details on the matter i'm sure you'll know the scene that i am talking about when you view the film. Anyways if you have issues with harsh language, sex scene types then i would avoid this film. Enjoy viewing. ;D
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
