<filme>
 <id>
  1264
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110693
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Nothing to Lose
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   social worker
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   boxer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   female nudity
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   cult film
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hooker
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Izidore K. Musallam
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Kremlin Films
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Alexandra Paul
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Youssef Abed-Alnour
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Paul Gleason
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I can't believe I was in this...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ralpheous
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What's worse, it's my only feature film credit. I was the guy behind the camera reading the lines while the actors auditioned for the director. The director liked my line readings so much he gave me a part. It's the same way Harrison Ford got the part of Han Solo. I just wish my career had a little more in common with Harrison's. My sister (who plays the forensic scientist at the crime scene early on) went from being a production assistant to assistant producer to line producer on this turkey. My fondest memory of being on set (other than accidentally being set on fire) was sitting with the hero in the BMW giving him phonetic line readings since he barely spoke English. Hey, at least I was in a movie with the vice principal from the Breakfast Club. People should probably avoid this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I WAS AN EXTRA
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JRHARV2001
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie, which lasted about a day at Toronto Eaton Centre cinemas, was shot mostly in a downtown Toronto bar. I know this because I was one of the extras (unpaid no less) in the dance floor fight scene, and a voice in the background during one of the stage fights. Is this a spoiler? I think not, having never seen the film I took part in. If you have seen it, or know where to find it, I want it. In case anybody remembers the dance floor brawl, I am the cowboy boot wearing guy he falls in front of several times. Our chant during the brawl was for the opponent ("Chinaman") and you may hear me yell "Ref!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mike Gazzo's last film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William (williamnorton316@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2000
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gazzo who is good at playing gruffy old italian bad guy looks very ill in the film. The film basic plot is a street fighter's family is wiped out by Gazzo, so he goes on a revenge by destroying his drug operation. Alexandra Paul is wasted as a social worker, and Gleason is cast in a diffrent role as a hard edge cop. Some intresting moments and not too many killing in this canadian shot action film. It's too bad Gazzo, Gleason, and Paul couldn't be in a better film. Not recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
