<filme>
 <id>
  1267
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112688
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Irm&atilde;os de Sangue
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Young drug pushers in the projects of Brooklyn live hard dangerous lives, trapped between their drug bosses and the detectives out to stop them.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Strike is a young city drug pusher under the tutelage of drug-lord Rodney Little, who, when not playing with model trains or drinking Moo for his ulcer, just likes to chill with his brothers near the benches outside the project houses. When a night man at a fast-food restaurant is found with four bullets in his body, Strike's older brother turns himself in as the killer. Det. Rocco Klein doesn't buy the story, however, and sets out to find the truth, and it seems that all the fingers point toward Strike & Rodney.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Mystery
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   drugs
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   drug lord
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   train
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   role model
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   new york city
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Spike Lee
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Richard Price
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Spike Lee
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Harvey Keitel
  </ator>
  <ator>
   John Turturro
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Delroy Lindo
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When you don't help people because you like them, but because you hate enough their world enough to let them triumph over it ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The title might give you a hint, "Clockers" is about routine, and not the most pleasant one. Indeed, this routine is made of drug-dealing and occasional murders. And if you think that you've been desensitized enough by police procedural and gangster movies, "Clockers" will be a powerful wake-up call. Honestly, I can't recall a film that dealt so straightforwardly with real-life violence apart from David Cronenberg's "A History of Violence" but that was 10 years after ''Clockers". The opening credits set the tone. Shots of young black persons' murdered are shown, blood staining the pavement and deadpan expression proving they didn't see what was coming to them. Lee doesn't stylize for aesthetic purposes but intelligently guide our expectations, loudly shouting what gangster films timidly whispers: this is an ugly word with no redeeming appeal whatsoever. No matter what it involves, it either ends up with jail of being the unintentional poser of bloody aftermaths' pictures. And their purpose is echoed in the murder scene, where lies Darryl Adams, a restaurant manager, shot four times. The sight of the body is disturbing but no more than the total detachment of the two assigned detectives played by Harvey Keitel and John Turturro. They comment the body with shocking detachment and cynical wisecracks such as "the kid had brains" while blood spilled over a hole in his head I don't think Lee's intent is to portray these cops as racist or cynical, but to underline how routinely these murders became. This is not to brandish the 'racism' flag (Lee is above these clich&eacute;s) but to remind us that these crimes are committed within the black community. So, no matter what you'd think of the cops, they're not the ones who pulled the trigger. We're used of that ambiguity regarding racism and this is a credit to Spike Lee's co-writing with Richard Price, who wrote the original novel. "Clockers" depicts a slice of people's life that encapsulates all the factors that lead to the opening 'pictures'. And that no-way-out situation is embodied by the main protagonist, Strike (Mekhi Phifer), a clocker working for Rodney (Delroy Lindo), the crime lord of the neighborhood. His job mainly consists on standing in the park and waiting for customers coming to buy crack. The process is well-elaborated, as there is a watcher to check for cop's arrivals, but eventual strip-searches are also part of this routine. The point is that clockers are at the bottom of the hierarchy, but that's their way of living. The issue of money is another layer of subtlety the film provides. Strike doesn't use money to date girls, buy a car or new clothes. Electric trains are his hobbies. Why? Why not? But we understand that he's trapped in that job for the simple reason is that it earns him enough money to fulfill his passion. On the other hand, his brother Victor (Isaiah Washington) is a honest, two-job worker and decent father forced to constantly swallow the bitter taste of frustration while watching brothers making easy money while he gets no respect and that's his routine. These brothers live in a world where money buys enough power to ooze respect. Both feel pressure in their lives, and the result is Victor's arrest and confession that he murdered Adams, claiming it was for self-defense, but there's something wrong in that murder Keitel's character can't get off his head. The case is even more complex because it was Strike who was supposed to kill Adams, to make his bones with Rodney and climb the 'social ladder'. The seemingly fatherly affection between Rodney and Strike is finally distorted when Rodney reveals the first time he killed a man, threatened with a gun on his mouth by Errol (Thomas Jefferson Byrd) a tough killer before he became the local AIDS-stricken psycho. Like for Rodney, Strike had to have blood on his hands, the point of no-return meaning trust. So, we get it, there are no feelings in such a dirty business. And as the investigation proceeds, Keitel gets more and more interested in Strike's case and wonder why he'd let his brother covering him, and why would a man like Victor kill Adams in the first place? To spare Strike the burden of belonging to Rodney, and in the process, vent all his anger? The procedural leaves to a satisfying resolution but it wasn't "Clockers' main point. The film is more about complex human interactions, because while Keitel and Phifer get closer one another, their mutual affection feel more real and genuine than with Rodney, and might pave the road to Strike's redemption. I know this 'redemption' word is kind of hackneyed, but I know Scorsese co-produced the film, and I felt some intense Scorsesian vibes in that gritty depiction of an underworld and the torment poisoning the main character's life, in the real meaning of the world since Strike is also victim of chronicle ulcer that gets bloodier as the film progresses, like a metaphor of his moral downfall and an imminent deadly conclusion. But there's a third significant character to enrich the film: Tyrone, a kid who admires Strike and imitates him to the point of shaving his head and wearing the same clothes. The kid is a younger version of Strike with Strike playing Rodney's mentor role, and ironically, the disciple shows more zeal and competence than his master. Tyrone's arc is a light of hope illuminating possible ways out of the hell given you don't act like people acted with you. Tyrone evolves from the embodiment of Strike's disgrace to his redemption. And Strike is given the same chance, the possibility to count on people who don't help him because they like him, but because they hate that world enough to triumph over it by getting someone out of it. Indeed, there might be a right way and a wrong way but when trapped in such blinding routine, everybody needs a sign, or guidance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Justice is never black and white
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dope dealing on the Nelson Mandela projects in Brooklyn is the everyday bread of local hoodlum Ronald Dunham aka Strike (Mekhi Phifer). Staking the local park the line of work is relentlessly stressful causing a stress-induced ulcer, which he deals with by drinking down yoo-hoos by the litres. At night respite is found in the form of a trainset hobby, an voyeuristic escape from the reality he has accepted. When his boss Rodney Little (Delroy Lindo) hints towards the necessity of cropping one of his less trustworthy workers Strike confides to his brother Victor (Isaiah Washington). Soon after the murder is committed and Victor steps up to claim self defence. However hardliner detective Rocco Klein (Harvey Keitel) quickly assumes this is a cover up for the true culprit. One of Spike Lee's most accomplished works and a worryingly underrated gem bordering on a masterpiece. While showing artistic restraint in symbols and style, Spike Lee offers a well-devised structure, which lets the strength of the story carry itself. Especially in the final act Lee's well-tuned reserve makes for a heart-felt conclusion full of poignant suggestions, as to the nature of violence. Even the innocent can be corrupted needing a vent for their endless victimisation, while the corrupt seek innocence by befriending children reminiscent of them in their youth and dreaming about a life with 'no more packing'. The ultimately compassionate Rocco, previously shown as a no nonsense cop with a strong moral compass ultimately rejects 'Justice in Black and White', deciding that even the guilty are seldom dealt justice and takes on the role of a benevolent judge and jury - the antithesis of Dirty Harry and Judge Dredd, one more attuned to understand human faults, accept them, than issue warrants. Nonetheless this self-conscious style of storytelling does backlash during build-up, as the convoluted plot mires midway with mild bouts of oversentimentilisation and underwritten character motivations, before finally hitting back with an astoundingly well-rounded finale. Nonetheless a brilliant and captivating movie, which ranks up there with Spike Lee's best with high probability of future rewatching pleasure. A big part of the success comes from disposing of the preacher like stance so predominant in many of Lee's weaker works. Albeit mostly low-key and pretty standard the most significant scenes feature sudden detachment from traditional cinematography to a more detached, surreal focus, as if suggesting a detachment from the grim everyday reality of the protagonists offering escapist release from hardships. This offers some extremely imaginative cinematography by Malik Hassan Sayeed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most of the time remains stuck between good and great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is no denying it that this is a good and well made movie but at the same time I also still had loads of problems with it! The way I see it, this is being a pretty good portrayal of live on the streets in the '90's. It picks a mostly realistic approach but still I just can't really 'feel' this movie. I never felt involved with any of the characters in it or to any of the dramatic events and developments. It doesn't make this movie bad but it does indeed make this movie a bit of a one dimensional experience. And remember, this is an 1995 movie. So everything that was considered to be hip and 'thug life' might seem a bit ridicules and less cool in today's perspective. The whole attitude and way of talking and the way everyone dresses makes this movie really a product of its time. In that regard this movie also really reminded me of "Kids", which coincidentally or not, got made in the same year as this movie. It makes this movie less relevant to watch now days but really, it's nothing I was holding against the movie. I would had most definitely preferred it if this movie was using a more straightforward style of storytelling. The movie as it is seems to be wanting to focus on far too many different characters and tries to do and tell too much. It also really has its own style to it, when it comes down to its storytelling, which was nice and helped to give this movie an unique feeling but at the same time it also made the movie unnecessary hard and not all that pleasant to follow at times. Another thing I also disliked about this movie was its pick of music. The movie mad some bad music choices, in which the music often would swell and become melodramatic at moments that really were uncalled for. It absolutely distracted and most of the time didn't suit what was happening on the screen at the time. But really, I though this movie still had some hints of a great movie in it as well. One thing was its already earlier mentioned unique and distinctive style. Spike Lee always has had an unique and distinctive style of his own and he manages to put a lot of that in this movie successfully. There are some interesting moments in this movie, from a more technical and movie-making perspective. There was some good camera-work for instance and also very little wrong with the movie its editing and pacing. The movie its story in essence also really seemed to be a solid one but I do feel that they perhaps should had picked some different perspectives to keep- and make things a bit more interesting and effective. Wouldn't this movie for instance had been better and more interesting if it told things more from the Harvey Keitel's character perspective? Who knows and it's not like the movie bad or interesting as it is right now but while watching this movie it constantly gave me the feeling it had more potential and things could had been done better. I don't know, perhaps the movie was also being a bit stuck between being a gangster movie and a more realistic one. It never felt like a true gangster flick and it never felt like a true realistic movie neither. Producer Martin Scorsese perhaps should had stepped in a bit more often, since he definitely is a kind of director who can more successfully blend realism with tough and tense gangster/crime movies. Not trying to sound too negative. The movie is good enough as it is but it doesn't ever reaches its full potential. 7/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brothers killin' other brothers ain't no big thing. Blas&eacute;, blas&eacute;.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Clockers is directed by Spike Lee who also co-adapts the screenplay with Richard Price from Price's own novel of the same name. It stars Harvey Keitel, John Turturro, Delroy Lindo, Mekhi Phifer, Isaiah Washington, Keith David, Peewee Love and Regina Taylor. Music is scored by Terence Blanchard and cinematography by Malik Hassan Sayeed. Young drug pushers in the projects of Brooklyn (Clockers) are caught between loyalty to their drug boss and the detectives out to stop them. It's not as incendiary as one might expect of a Spike Lee joint, but the director's concerns and astute knack for story telling are very prominent features. It was originally going to be a Martin Scorses film, but he chose to make Casino instead, he does, however, get a producing credit and you can see in the material why Scorsese was interested in directing. Pic is basically a take on urban drug dealing in the Brooklyn projects and the impact said dealing has on anyone who comes into contact with it. From the downward spiral of life for young men earning their pay by illegal means, to fretful mothers desperately trying to keep pe-teen kiddies from joining the ranks of what they think are cool operators, the morality of the play is forcibly rammed home by Lee. Unfortunately this comes at a cost to the white cop characters, who are too thinly drawn to offer up a law and order counter point to the illegal activity involving drugs and murder, they serve only as the "man", and damn the "man" at that. The Rocco Klein (Keitel) of the book is not evident here, sadly, while Torturo may as well not be in it! Cast performances are well in tune with the material, with Lindo as the "black godfather" turning in a scary one, and Lee's camera-work, coupled with Sayeed's moody photography, has a nifty grasp of realism. Soundtracking is soulful and pleasant. A mixed bag for sure, but it's a story that needs to be told. Bleak and brutal at times, but still offering hope, it's middle tier Spike Lee that always remains intriguing. Even if it at times feels like he was bored telling yet another "black on black is bad" message movie. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tribal Study.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this complicated tale of the pressures on Mekhi Phifer in the Brooklyn projects, director Spike Lee captures the values and the iconography of the African-American community well, as he usually does. You get a genuine sense of the simmering anger, the shifting allegiances, and the small reward system of the social world these pathetic people live in. Pfifer is the central figure and he sweats a lot. No brighter or better than he should be, he's pressured from one side into dealing cocaine by local mogul Delroy Lindo. On the other side, he's pushed by the manipulative but well-intentioned detectives Harvey Keitel and Stanley Turturro. Pfifer's handsome and upright brother is under arrest for murder but Keitel believes that Pfifer is the culprit. Pfifer's brother is simply too good, too compliant, to have done the deed. Nice ambiguity. Lee convincingly nails the diversity and solidarity of the community. It's like John Ford in the ghetto. Pfifer may be innocent of the crime of which Keitel is convinced he's guilty but he also deals dope. Keitel, for all his ploying the system, is determined to bring the guilty party to justice, though he may play a little dirty in getting the job done. And when he finds out that he's been wrong about who committed the murder, he does what such a person would do in real life. He hides his guilt behind a tirade of threats. In a way, it's an improvement over Spike Lee's "Do The Right Thing." It doesn't turn all the cops into heavies. And it doesn't end with an ominous quote from Malcolm X. The weakness of the film lies in Lee's allowing conversations to go on for too long. Pfifer gets a lot of screen time and when he's not chewing out his young brother (who will save his life) he's whining about his innocence. The exchanges, sometimes rising to shouts, go on too long and become tiring. It's a devalued life these people lead. They wear clothes and they groom themselves in ways that appeal only to those in their immediate and limited social worlds. I'm beginning to develop an idea. The more you resemble someone who is upper class and British, the more your social worth. The farther removed you are from this model, the lower your status. If you could take Pfifer, dress him in riding clothes and teach him to play polo, and have him say "eck-tually" instead of "aks," and have him grow some hair on his shaved and shiny skull, he might not be thought guilty of anything except being too polite.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oscar-worthy. Incredible film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tpaladino
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no idea why this film wasn't nominated for an Oscar, and I especially have no idea why it's been seventeen years since the film was released and I'm just now seeing it. I've always been vaguely aware of it's existence as one of the 'other' Spike Lee films, but not much more. I certainly wasn't expecting to see some of his all-time best work, which it is. This film should be mandatory viewing for every single high school in America, that's how important it is. Spike Lee paints a devastatingly realistic picture of inner-city life and the mortal perils that it's inhabitants face on a daily basis. There are no heroes, no angels, and no caricatures. It's all laid bare for the viewer to draw their own conclusion. Lee treats the audience with a level of respect and maturity that is almost unheard of in films that deal in such explosive and controversial subject matter. He trusts that the audience will understand the big picture and take away the appropriate lesson without being evangelized, and without resorting to the kind of cheap gimmickry and pandering that can often plague films of this genre. Everyone should see this film. Literally everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such an overwhelming disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johndeckbose
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm glad that Spike Lee has apparently outgrown his need for polemics. Inside Man was a wonderful mature film that focused on character and motivation far beyond the Afro-centric purview of earlier Spike films. And while Clockers is perfectly serviceable for anyone coming to the story without having read the novel, I submit that Spike's attempt to refocus Richard Price's 1992 masterpiece as a singular black story, with a bone-throwing portrayal of white Detective Rocco Klein within an indictment of white police tactics, short-changes the audience of the profound respect, balance and humanity that made Price's novel so unforgettable. It is truly one of the five best novels I have ever read, while Spike managed to produce one of 1000 best movies I have ever seen. Read the book. It will stun, shock, amaze and delight you. The movie, on the other hand, might just keep you from falling asleep.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is WEAK...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gveltman1
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although I have only seen a few of Spike Lee's films, I am already beginning to place him very low on the ladder of the best directors alive today. Clockers fails, in my opinion, because the film's premise is lacking substance to begin with; the story is lackluster to the max. On top of this, where the film had its opportunities to reel in the audience emotionally, it instead dropped the ball. Moments where energy, tension, and suspense were supposed to effused were disappointingly overridden with anticlimactic slumps in action. The choking scene in the car as well as when Mekhi is being beat up in the park, with their odd selection of music, seem unfulfilled in their potential to capitalize on emotional appeal. I will say the denouement is shot with expert precision. Lee's patented cinematographic maneuver, the double dolly, is on full display. Moreover, his use of low-key lighting in some specific scenes that illustrate the proliferation of drugs inside the projects are done in a professionally haunting manor. Unfortunately, these instances are rare, overshadowed by the weak portions previously discussed. With regards to Lee's film style in Clockers, I like to point out two of his techniques that I find terribly annoying: 1) Those stupid circling gliding shots around characters when they are talking. 2) His persistent use of intense music to compliment serious(at least Lee thinks they must be) scenes. When put together, these two devices serve to create the ultimate exaggeration of the weight a scene carries in this film. Doing a flashy gliding pan across the park accompanied by pounding sound while Tyrone's mother yells at Mekhi and his boys about his haircut is a little excessive. Instead, I think Clocker's would benefit from a greater variation in the levels of stress and emotion we experience in each scene. This way, when the film actually does come to a TRULY significant moment, the audience will become more invested in the action. P.S. I don't think anyone from the projects would actually where a complete Arizona wildcats uniform. Just the jersey, not the shorts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder mystery and race mixed into one great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Take a murder mystery story, mix it into a contemporary vulgar urban setting, then sprinkle some racial tension into the mix and you've got the highly intellectual and intense Spike Lee film Clockers. Clockers is about Strike, a young black man living in Brooklyn, dealing drugs for his ruthless drug lord Rodney Little. Strike deals drugs for the money, but all he really wants to do is hang out with his brothers in the park and play with model train sets. But things start to get rough when a night manager at a local fast food joint is murdered and Strike's brother Victor turns himself in. Det. Rocco Klein is the lead detective on the case and he doesn't buy Victor's story, which sets him on an obsessive hunt to unmask the truth behind this whole ordeal. The film is loaded with spirited yet vulgar dialouge, artistic and vibrant direction, and plenty of memorable characters. Clockers is witty, intelligent, and a lot of fun. It isn't your typical murder mystery or racial tension film. It is a beautiful blend of the two genres that turns into something very unique and very exciting. Spike Lee adds a lot of visual flair to this film and the way he directs it is something you can't quite pinpoint. The panoramic visual style is something you can't exactly describe in words and it is really something you have to see for yourself. There is something obviously unique going on in the way Lee directs this film, it is just difficult to articulate what exactly that is. But the visuals do work in a whole plethora of unique films, allowing the film to succeed on multiple levels. The film ranges from intense and gripping to quirky and fun. From one scene to the next the film grows more fun and more enthralling. Rarely do I care this much about what happens to the characters of a film and I'm not always so compelled to learn the motivations of the very well written characters of a film. All that being said I can't say that I loved the main character, Strike. The actor, Mekhi Phifer, wasn't great and the character himself had some odd moments. I eventually learned to like him and his character thankfully didn't deter too much from my liking of the film. Besides, a lot of the film actually focuses on Harvey Keitel's character and his unending search for the truth behind the murder. There are also numerous subplots that all end up being more interesting than the main character's story. It helps that this is just an all around well written film that is just smarter than your average crime film. Clockers is very different from any murder mystery crime film, as well as any racial tension film. But it provides plenty of great work on both sides of this spectrum. Spike Lee has created a visually interesting film with a fantastic story. The main character is the only low point of the film, but everything else is very good. Clockers is a very worthwhile watch for fans of Spike Lee or the multiple genres this film spans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Modern urban classic - Spike's greatest 'joint'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesxgamble
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my all-time favourite films. Director Spike Lee adapts the Richard Price Novel, set in New Jersey, to his hometown and favourite movie backdrop: Brooklyn. It is often said that films never live up to the books on which they are based, but in this case I think the movie out performs the novel. This is because the book can be slow moving at times, and the action is separated by long passages of writing. However, the film chops all of these slow parts out, and the result is a film that keeps you engaged from start to finish. Spike Lee uses music perfectly to compliment the tone and mood of each scene, be it hip-hop in the urban playground, the acoustic interludes of Seal and Des'ree, or minor key, intense jazz to accompany drug use in doorways and nooks, and the final scene's soundtrack is absolutely inspired. Delroy Lindo plays his king-pin character with such comfort, at times it is hard to imagine that he isn't that person in reality! Harvey Keitel and John Turturro work well as the detective double-team, conflicting over whether to take the easy close-by-arrest, or the moral crusade to find the truth behind the case at the heart of the film. Mekhi Phifer is impressive in many of his scenes as the central character, who keeps you guessing to the end on whether he deserves your sympathy or not. For me, Lindo's performance is the standout turn. The cinematography is luscious, and the colours and compositions make this film a visual feast. But more importantly, the natural dialogue of the film and the delivery of nearly every line really reinforce the fact that you are watching a film about real situations. Overall, I give this film my maximum rating of 9.5 stars. If you like this film, you'll love The Wire Season One, and you also might want to check out another overlooked film, Jason's Lyric.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When you don't help people because you like them, but because you hate enough their world enough to let them triumph over it ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The title might give you a hint, "Clockers" is about routine, and not the most pleasant one. Indeed, this routine is made of drug-dealing and occasional murders. And if you think that you've been desensitized enough by police procedural and gangster movies, "Clockers" will be a powerful wake-up call. Honestly, I can't recall a film that dealt so straightforwardly with real-life violence apart from David Cronenberg's "A History of Violence" but that was 10 years after ''Clockers". The opening credits set the tone. Shots of young black persons' murdered are shown, blood staining the pavement and deadpan expression proving they didn't see what was coming to them. Lee doesn't stylize for aesthetic purposes but intelligently guide our expectations, loudly shouting what gangster films timidly whispers: this is an ugly word with no redeeming appeal whatsoever. No matter what it involves, it either ends up with jail of being the unintentional poser of bloody aftermaths' pictures. And their purpose is echoed in the murder scene, where lies Darryl Adams, a restaurant manager, shot four times. The sight of the body is disturbing but no more than the total detachment of the two assigned detectives played by Harvey Keitel and John Turturro. They comment the body with shocking detachment and cynical wisecracks such as "the kid had brains" while blood spilled over a hole in his head I don't think Lee's intent is to portray these cops as racist or cynical, but to underline how routinely these murders became. This is not to brandish the 'racism' flag (Lee is above these clich&eacute;s) but to remind us that these crimes are committed within the black community. So, no matter what you'd think of the cops, they're not the ones who pulled the trigger. We're used of that ambiguity regarding racism and this is a credit to Spike Lee's co-writing with Richard Price, who wrote the original novel. "Clockers" depicts a slice of people's life that encapsulates all the factors that lead to the opening 'pictures'. And that no-way-out situation is embodied by the main protagonist, Strike (Mekhi Phifer), a clocker working for Rodney (Delroy Lindo), the crime lord of the neighborhood. His job mainly consists on standing in the park and waiting for customers coming to buy crack. The process is well-elaborated, as there is a watcher to check for cop's arrivals, but eventual strip-searches are also part of this routine. The point is that clockers are at the bottom of the hierarchy, but that's their way of living. The issue of money is another layer of subtlety the film provides. Strike doesn't use money to date girls, buy a car or new clothes. Electric trains are his hobbies. Why? Why not? But we understand that he's trapped in that job for the simple reason is that it earns him enough money to fulfill his passion. On the other hand, his brother Victor (Isaiah Washington) is a honest, two-job worker and decent father forced to constantly swallow the bitter taste of frustration while watching brothers making easy money while he gets no respect and that's his routine. These brothers live in a world where money buys enough power to ooze respect. Both feel pressure in their lives, and the result is Victor's arrest and confession that he murdered Adams, claiming it was for self-defense, but there's something wrong in that murder Keitel's character can't get off his head. The case is even more complex because it was Strike who was supposed to kill Adams, to make his bones with Rodney and climb the 'social ladder'. The seemingly fatherly affection between Rodney and Strike is finally distorted when Rodney reveals the first time he killed a man, threatened with a gun on his mouth by Errol (Thomas Jefferson Byrd) a tough killer before he became the local AIDS-stricken psycho. Like for Rodney, Strike had to have blood on his hands, the point of no-return meaning trust. So, we get it, there are no feelings in such a dirty business. And as the investigation proceeds, Keitel gets more and more interested in Strike's case and wonder why he'd let his brother covering him, and why would a man like Victor kill Adams in the first place? To spare Strike the burden of belonging to Rodney, and in the process, vent all his anger? The procedural leaves to a satisfying resolution but it wasn't "Clockers' main point. The film is more about complex human interactions, because while Keitel and Phifer get closer one another, their mutual affection feel more real and genuine than with Rodney, and might pave the road to Strike's redemption. I know this 'redemption' word is kind of hackneyed, but I know Scorsese co-produced the film, and I felt some intense Scorsesian vibes in that gritty depiction of an underworld and the torment poisoning the main character's life, in the real meaning of the world since Strike is also victim of chronicle ulcer that gets bloodier as the film progresses, like a metaphor of his moral downfall and an imminent deadly conclusion. But there's a third significant character to enrich the film: Tyrone, a kid who admires Strike and imitates him to the point of shaving his head and wearing the same clothes. The kid is a younger version of Strike with Strike playing Rodney's mentor role, and ironically, the disciple shows more zeal and competence than his master. Tyrone's arc is a light of hope illuminating possible ways out of the hell given you don't act like people acted with you. Tyrone evolves from the embodiment of Strike's disgrace to his redemption. And Strike is given the same chance, the possibility to count on people who don't help him because they like him, but because they hate that world enough to triumph over it by getting someone out of it. Indeed, there might be a right way and a wrong way but when trapped in such blinding routine, everybody needs a sign, or guidance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Justice is never black and white
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dope dealing on the Nelson Mandela projects in Brooklyn is the everyday bread of local hoodlum Ronald Dunham aka Strike (Mekhi Phifer). Staking the local park the line of work is relentlessly stressful causing a stress-induced ulcer, which he deals with by drinking down yoo-hoos by the litres. At night respite is found in the form of a trainset hobby, an voyeuristic escape from the reality he has accepted. When his boss Rodney Little (Delroy Lindo) hints towards the necessity of cropping one of his less trustworthy workers Strike confides to his brother Victor (Isaiah Washington). Soon after the murder is committed and Victor steps up to claim self defence. However hardliner detective Rocco Klein (Harvey Keitel) quickly assumes this is a cover up for the true culprit. One of Spike Lee's most accomplished works and a worryingly underrated gem bordering on a masterpiece. While showing artistic restraint in symbols and style, Spike Lee offers a well-devised structure, which lets the strength of the story carry itself. Especially in the final act Lee's well-tuned reserve makes for a heart-felt conclusion full of poignant suggestions, as to the nature of violence. Even the innocent can be corrupted needing a vent for their endless victimisation, while the corrupt seek innocence by befriending children reminiscent of them in their youth and dreaming about a life with 'no more packing'. The ultimately compassionate Rocco, previously shown as a no nonsense cop with a strong moral compass ultimately rejects 'Justice in Black and White', deciding that even the guilty are seldom dealt justice and takes on the role of a benevolent judge and jury - the antithesis of Dirty Harry and Judge Dredd, one more attuned to understand human faults, accept them, than issue warrants. Nonetheless this self-conscious style of storytelling does backlash during build-up, as the convoluted plot mires midway with mild bouts of oversentimentilisation and underwritten character motivations, before finally hitting back with an astoundingly well-rounded finale. Nonetheless a brilliant and captivating movie, which ranks up there with Spike Lee's best with high probability of future rewatching pleasure. A big part of the success comes from disposing of the preacher like stance so predominant in many of Lee's weaker works. Albeit mostly low-key and pretty standard the most significant scenes feature sudden detachment from traditional cinematography to a more detached, surreal focus, as if suggesting a detachment from the grim everyday reality of the protagonists offering escapist release from hardships. This offers some extremely imaginative cinematography by Malik Hassan Sayeed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most of the time remains stuck between good and great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is no denying it that this is a good and well made movie but at the same time I also still had loads of problems with it! The way I see it, this is being a pretty good portrayal of live on the streets in the '90's. It picks a mostly realistic approach but still I just can't really 'feel' this movie. I never felt involved with any of the characters in it or to any of the dramatic events and developments. It doesn't make this movie bad but it does indeed make this movie a bit of a one dimensional experience. And remember, this is an 1995 movie. So everything that was considered to be hip and 'thug life' might seem a bit ridicules and less cool in today's perspective. The whole attitude and way of talking and the way everyone dresses makes this movie really a product of its time. In that regard this movie also really reminded me of "Kids", which coincidentally or not, got made in the same year as this movie. It makes this movie less relevant to watch now days but really, it's nothing I was holding against the movie. I would had most definitely preferred it if this movie was using a more straightforward style of storytelling. The movie as it is seems to be wanting to focus on far too many different characters and tries to do and tell too much. It also really has its own style to it, when it comes down to its storytelling, which was nice and helped to give this movie an unique feeling but at the same time it also made the movie unnecessary hard and not all that pleasant to follow at times. Another thing I also disliked about this movie was its pick of music. The movie mad some bad music choices, in which the music often would swell and become melodramatic at moments that really were uncalled for. It absolutely distracted and most of the time didn't suit what was happening on the screen at the time. But really, I though this movie still had some hints of a great movie in it as well. One thing was its already earlier mentioned unique and distinctive style. Spike Lee always has had an unique and distinctive style of his own and he manages to put a lot of that in this movie successfully. There are some interesting moments in this movie, from a more technical and movie-making perspective. There was some good camera-work for instance and also very little wrong with the movie its editing and pacing. The movie its story in essence also really seemed to be a solid one but I do feel that they perhaps should had picked some different perspectives to keep- and make things a bit more interesting and effective. Wouldn't this movie for instance had been better and more interesting if it told things more from the Harvey Keitel's character perspective? Who knows and it's not like the movie bad or interesting as it is right now but while watching this movie it constantly gave me the feeling it had more potential and things could had been done better. I don't know, perhaps the movie was also being a bit stuck between being a gangster movie and a more realistic one. It never felt like a true gangster flick and it never felt like a true realistic movie neither. Producer Martin Scorsese perhaps should had stepped in a bit more often, since he definitely is a kind of director who can more successfully blend realism with tough and tense gangster/crime movies. Not trying to sound too negative. The movie is good enough as it is but it doesn't ever reaches its full potential. 7/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brothers killin' other brothers ain't no big thing. Blas&eacute;, blas&eacute;.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Clockers is directed by Spike Lee who also co-adapts the screenplay with Richard Price from Price's own novel of the same name. It stars Harvey Keitel, John Turturro, Delroy Lindo, Mekhi Phifer, Isaiah Washington, Keith David, Peewee Love and Regina Taylor. Music is scored by Terence Blanchard and cinematography by Malik Hassan Sayeed. Young drug pushers in the projects of Brooklyn (Clockers) are caught between loyalty to their drug boss and the detectives out to stop them. It's not as incendiary as one might expect of a Spike Lee joint, but the director's concerns and astute knack for story telling are very prominent features. It was originally going to be a Martin Scorses film, but he chose to make Casino instead, he does, however, get a producing credit and you can see in the material why Scorsese was interested in directing. Pic is basically a take on urban drug dealing in the Brooklyn projects and the impact said dealing has on anyone who comes into contact with it. From the downward spiral of life for young men earning their pay by illegal means, to fretful mothers desperately trying to keep pe-teen kiddies from joining the ranks of what they think are cool operators, the morality of the play is forcibly rammed home by Lee. Unfortunately this comes at a cost to the white cop characters, who are too thinly drawn to offer up a law and order counter point to the illegal activity involving drugs and murder, they serve only as the "man", and damn the "man" at that. The Rocco Klein (Keitel) of the book is not evident here, sadly, while Torturo may as well not be in it! Cast performances are well in tune with the material, with Lindo as the "black godfather" turning in a scary one, and Lee's camera-work, coupled with Sayeed's moody photography, has a nifty grasp of realism. Soundtracking is soulful and pleasant. A mixed bag for sure, but it's a story that needs to be told. Bleak and brutal at times, but still offering hope, it's middle tier Spike Lee that always remains intriguing. Even if it at times feels like he was bored telling yet another "black on black is bad" message movie. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tribal Study.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this complicated tale of the pressures on Mekhi Phifer in the Brooklyn projects, director Spike Lee captures the values and the iconography of the African-American community well, as he usually does. You get a genuine sense of the simmering anger, the shifting allegiances, and the small reward system of the social world these pathetic people live in. Pfifer is the central figure and he sweats a lot. No brighter or better than he should be, he's pressured from one side into dealing cocaine by local mogul Delroy Lindo. On the other side, he's pushed by the manipulative but well-intentioned detectives Harvey Keitel and Stanley Turturro. Pfifer's handsome and upright brother is under arrest for murder but Keitel believes that Pfifer is the culprit. Pfifer's brother is simply too good, too compliant, to have done the deed. Nice ambiguity. Lee convincingly nails the diversity and solidarity of the community. It's like John Ford in the ghetto. Pfifer may be innocent of the crime of which Keitel is convinced he's guilty but he also deals dope. Keitel, for all his ploying the system, is determined to bring the guilty party to justice, though he may play a little dirty in getting the job done. And when he finds out that he's been wrong about who committed the murder, he does what such a person would do in real life. He hides his guilt behind a tirade of threats. In a way, it's an improvement over Spike Lee's "Do The Right Thing." It doesn't turn all the cops into heavies. And it doesn't end with an ominous quote from Malcolm X. The weakness of the film lies in Lee's allowing conversations to go on for too long. Pfifer gets a lot of screen time and when he's not chewing out his young brother (who will save his life) he's whining about his innocence. The exchanges, sometimes rising to shouts, go on too long and become tiring. It's a devalued life these people lead. They wear clothes and they groom themselves in ways that appeal only to those in their immediate and limited social worlds. I'm beginning to develop an idea. The more you resemble someone who is upper class and British, the more your social worth. The farther removed you are from this model, the lower your status. If you could take Pfifer, dress him in riding clothes and teach him to play polo, and have him say "eck-tually" instead of "aks," and have him grow some hair on his shaved and shiny skull, he might not be thought guilty of anything except being too polite.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oscar-worthy. Incredible film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tpaladino
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no idea why this film wasn't nominated for an Oscar, and I especially have no idea why it's been seventeen years since the film was released and I'm just now seeing it. I've always been vaguely aware of it's existence as one of the 'other' Spike Lee films, but not much more. I certainly wasn't expecting to see some of his all-time best work, which it is. This film should be mandatory viewing for every single high school in America, that's how important it is. Spike Lee paints a devastatingly realistic picture of inner-city life and the mortal perils that it's inhabitants face on a daily basis. There are no heroes, no angels, and no caricatures. It's all laid bare for the viewer to draw their own conclusion. Lee treats the audience with a level of respect and maturity that is almost unheard of in films that deal in such explosive and controversial subject matter. He trusts that the audience will understand the big picture and take away the appropriate lesson without being evangelized, and without resorting to the kind of cheap gimmickry and pandering that can often plague films of this genre. Everyone should see this film. Literally everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such an overwhelming disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johndeckbose
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm glad that Spike Lee has apparently outgrown his need for polemics. Inside Man was a wonderful mature film that focused on character and motivation far beyond the Afro-centric purview of earlier Spike films. And while Clockers is perfectly serviceable for anyone coming to the story without having read the novel, I submit that Spike's attempt to refocus Richard Price's 1992 masterpiece as a singular black story, with a bone-throwing portrayal of white Detective Rocco Klein within an indictment of white police tactics, short-changes the audience of the profound respect, balance and humanity that made Price's novel so unforgettable. It is truly one of the five best novels I have ever read, while Spike managed to produce one of 1000 best movies I have ever seen. Read the book. It will stun, shock, amaze and delight you. The movie, on the other hand, might just keep you from falling asleep.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is WEAK...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gveltman1
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although I have only seen a few of Spike Lee's films, I am already beginning to place him very low on the ladder of the best directors alive today. Clockers fails, in my opinion, because the film's premise is lacking substance to begin with; the story is lackluster to the max. On top of this, where the film had its opportunities to reel in the audience emotionally, it instead dropped the ball. Moments where energy, tension, and suspense were supposed to effused were disappointingly overridden with anticlimactic slumps in action. The choking scene in the car as well as when Mekhi is being beat up in the park, with their odd selection of music, seem unfulfilled in their potential to capitalize on emotional appeal. I will say the denouement is shot with expert precision. Lee's patented cinematographic maneuver, the double dolly, is on full display. Moreover, his use of low-key lighting in some specific scenes that illustrate the proliferation of drugs inside the projects are done in a professionally haunting manor. Unfortunately, these instances are rare, overshadowed by the weak portions previously discussed. With regards to Lee's film style in Clockers, I like to point out two of his techniques that I find terribly annoying: 1) Those stupid circling gliding shots around characters when they are talking. 2) His persistent use of intense music to compliment serious(at least Lee thinks they must be) scenes. When put together, these two devices serve to create the ultimate exaggeration of the weight a scene carries in this film. Doing a flashy gliding pan across the park accompanied by pounding sound while Tyrone's mother yells at Mekhi and his boys about his haircut is a little excessive. Instead, I think Clocker's would benefit from a greater variation in the levels of stress and emotion we experience in each scene. This way, when the film actually does come to a TRULY significant moment, the audience will become more invested in the action. P.S. I don't think anyone from the projects would actually where a complete Arizona wildcats uniform. Just the jersey, not the shorts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder mystery and race mixed into one great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Take a murder mystery story, mix it into a contemporary vulgar urban setting, then sprinkle some racial tension into the mix and you've got the highly intellectual and intense Spike Lee film Clockers. Clockers is about Strike, a young black man living in Brooklyn, dealing drugs for his ruthless drug lord Rodney Little. Strike deals drugs for the money, but all he really wants to do is hang out with his brothers in the park and play with model train sets. But things start to get rough when a night manager at a local fast food joint is murdered and Strike's brother Victor turns himself in. Det. Rocco Klein is the lead detective on the case and he doesn't buy Victor's story, which sets him on an obsessive hunt to unmask the truth behind this whole ordeal. The film is loaded with spirited yet vulgar dialouge, artistic and vibrant direction, and plenty of memorable characters. Clockers is witty, intelligent, and a lot of fun. It isn't your typical murder mystery or racial tension film. It is a beautiful blend of the two genres that turns into something very unique and very exciting. Spike Lee adds a lot of visual flair to this film and the way he directs it is something you can't quite pinpoint. The panoramic visual style is something you can't exactly describe in words and it is really something you have to see for yourself. There is something obviously unique going on in the way Lee directs this film, it is just difficult to articulate what exactly that is. But the visuals do work in a whole plethora of unique films, allowing the film to succeed on multiple levels. The film ranges from intense and gripping to quirky and fun. From one scene to the next the film grows more fun and more enthralling. Rarely do I care this much about what happens to the characters of a film and I'm not always so compelled to learn the motivations of the very well written characters of a film. All that being said I can't say that I loved the main character, Strike. The actor, Mekhi Phifer, wasn't great and the character himself had some odd moments. I eventually learned to like him and his character thankfully didn't deter too much from my liking of the film. Besides, a lot of the film actually focuses on Harvey Keitel's character and his unending search for the truth behind the murder. There are also numerous subplots that all end up being more interesting than the main character's story. It helps that this is just an all around well written film that is just smarter than your average crime film. Clockers is very different from any murder mystery crime film, as well as any racial tension film. But it provides plenty of great work on both sides of this spectrum. Spike Lee has created a visually interesting film with a fantastic story. The main character is the only low point of the film, but everything else is very good. Clockers is a very worthwhile watch for fans of Spike Lee or the multiple genres this film spans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Modern urban classic - Spike's greatest 'joint'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesxgamble
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my all-time favourite films. Director Spike Lee adapts the Richard Price Novel, set in New Jersey, to his hometown and favourite movie backdrop: Brooklyn. It is often said that films never live up to the books on which they are based, but in this case I think the movie out performs the novel. This is because the book can be slow moving at times, and the action is separated by long passages of writing. However, the film chops all of these slow parts out, and the result is a film that keeps you engaged from start to finish. Spike Lee uses music perfectly to compliment the tone and mood of each scene, be it hip-hop in the urban playground, the acoustic interludes of Seal and Des'ree, or minor key, intense jazz to accompany drug use in doorways and nooks, and the final scene's soundtrack is absolutely inspired. Delroy Lindo plays his king-pin character with such comfort, at times it is hard to imagine that he isn't that person in reality! Harvey Keitel and John Turturro work well as the detective double-team, conflicting over whether to take the easy close-by-arrest, or the moral crusade to find the truth behind the case at the heart of the film. Mekhi Phifer is impressive in many of his scenes as the central character, who keeps you guessing to the end on whether he deserves your sympathy or not. For me, Lindo's performance is the standout turn. The cinematography is luscious, and the colours and compositions make this film a visual feast. But more importantly, the natural dialogue of the film and the delivery of nearly every line really reinforce the fact that you are watching a film about real situations. Overall, I give this film my maximum rating of 9.5 stars. If you like this film, you'll love The Wire Season One, and you also might want to check out another overlooked film, Jason's Lyric.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When you don't help people because you like them, but because you hate enough their world enough to let them triumph over it ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The title might give you a hint, "Clockers" is about routine, and not the most pleasant one. Indeed, this routine is made of drug-dealing and occasional murders. And if you think that you've been desensitized enough by police procedural and gangster movies, "Clockers" will be a powerful wake-up call. Honestly, I can't recall a film that dealt so straightforwardly with real-life violence apart from David Cronenberg's "A History of Violence" but that was 10 years after ''Clockers". The opening credits set the tone. Shots of young black persons' murdered are shown, blood staining the pavement and deadpan expression proving they didn't see what was coming to them. Lee doesn't stylize for aesthetic purposes but intelligently guide our expectations, loudly shouting what gangster films timidly whispers: this is an ugly word with no redeeming appeal whatsoever. No matter what it involves, it either ends up with jail of being the unintentional poser of bloody aftermaths' pictures. And their purpose is echoed in the murder scene, where lies Darryl Adams, a restaurant manager, shot four times. The sight of the body is disturbing but no more than the total detachment of the two assigned detectives played by Harvey Keitel and John Turturro. They comment the body with shocking detachment and cynical wisecracks such as "the kid had brains" while blood spilled over a hole in his head I don't think Lee's intent is to portray these cops as racist or cynical, but to underline how routinely these murders became. This is not to brandish the 'racism' flag (Lee is above these clich&eacute;s) but to remind us that these crimes are committed within the black community. So, no matter what you'd think of the cops, they're not the ones who pulled the trigger. We're used of that ambiguity regarding racism and this is a credit to Spike Lee's co-writing with Richard Price, who wrote the original novel. "Clockers" depicts a slice of people's life that encapsulates all the factors that lead to the opening 'pictures'. And that no-way-out situation is embodied by the main protagonist, Strike (Mekhi Phifer), a clocker working for Rodney (Delroy Lindo), the crime lord of the neighborhood. His job mainly consists on standing in the park and waiting for customers coming to buy crack. The process is well-elaborated, as there is a watcher to check for cop's arrivals, but eventual strip-searches are also part of this routine. The point is that clockers are at the bottom of the hierarchy, but that's their way of living. The issue of money is another layer of subtlety the film provides. Strike doesn't use money to date girls, buy a car or new clothes. Electric trains are his hobbies. Why? Why not? But we understand that he's trapped in that job for the simple reason is that it earns him enough money to fulfill his passion. On the other hand, his brother Victor (Isaiah Washington) is a honest, two-job worker and decent father forced to constantly swallow the bitter taste of frustration while watching brothers making easy money while he gets no respect and that's his routine. These brothers live in a world where money buys enough power to ooze respect. Both feel pressure in their lives, and the result is Victor's arrest and confession that he murdered Adams, claiming it was for self-defense, but there's something wrong in that murder Keitel's character can't get off his head. The case is even more complex because it was Strike who was supposed to kill Adams, to make his bones with Rodney and climb the 'social ladder'. The seemingly fatherly affection between Rodney and Strike is finally distorted when Rodney reveals the first time he killed a man, threatened with a gun on his mouth by Errol (Thomas Jefferson Byrd) a tough killer before he became the local AIDS-stricken psycho. Like for Rodney, Strike had to have blood on his hands, the point of no-return meaning trust. So, we get it, there are no feelings in such a dirty business. And as the investigation proceeds, Keitel gets more and more interested in Strike's case and wonder why he'd let his brother covering him, and why would a man like Victor kill Adams in the first place? To spare Strike the burden of belonging to Rodney, and in the process, vent all his anger? The procedural leaves to a satisfying resolution but it wasn't "Clockers' main point. The film is more about complex human interactions, because while Keitel and Phifer get closer one another, their mutual affection feel more real and genuine than with Rodney, and might pave the road to Strike's redemption. I know this 'redemption' word is kind of hackneyed, but I know Scorsese co-produced the film, and I felt some intense Scorsesian vibes in that gritty depiction of an underworld and the torment poisoning the main character's life, in the real meaning of the world since Strike is also victim of chronicle ulcer that gets bloodier as the film progresses, like a metaphor of his moral downfall and an imminent deadly conclusion. But there's a third significant character to enrich the film: Tyrone, a kid who admires Strike and imitates him to the point of shaving his head and wearing the same clothes. The kid is a younger version of Strike with Strike playing Rodney's mentor role, and ironically, the disciple shows more zeal and competence than his master. Tyrone's arc is a light of hope illuminating possible ways out of the hell given you don't act like people acted with you. Tyrone evolves from the embodiment of Strike's disgrace to his redemption. And Strike is given the same chance, the possibility to count on people who don't help him because they like him, but because they hate that world enough to triumph over it by getting someone out of it. Indeed, there might be a right way and a wrong way but when trapped in such blinding routine, everybody needs a sign, or guidance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Justice is never black and white
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dope dealing on the Nelson Mandela projects in Brooklyn is the everyday bread of local hoodlum Ronald Dunham aka Strike (Mekhi Phifer). Staking the local park the line of work is relentlessly stressful causing a stress-induced ulcer, which he deals with by drinking down yoo-hoos by the litres. At night respite is found in the form of a trainset hobby, an voyeuristic escape from the reality he has accepted. When his boss Rodney Little (Delroy Lindo) hints towards the necessity of cropping one of his less trustworthy workers Strike confides to his brother Victor (Isaiah Washington). Soon after the murder is committed and Victor steps up to claim self defence. However hardliner detective Rocco Klein (Harvey Keitel) quickly assumes this is a cover up for the true culprit. One of Spike Lee's most accomplished works and a worryingly underrated gem bordering on a masterpiece. While showing artistic restraint in symbols and style, Spike Lee offers a well-devised structure, which lets the strength of the story carry itself. Especially in the final act Lee's well-tuned reserve makes for a heart-felt conclusion full of poignant suggestions, as to the nature of violence. Even the innocent can be corrupted needing a vent for their endless victimisation, while the corrupt seek innocence by befriending children reminiscent of them in their youth and dreaming about a life with 'no more packing'. The ultimately compassionate Rocco, previously shown as a no nonsense cop with a strong moral compass ultimately rejects 'Justice in Black and White', deciding that even the guilty are seldom dealt justice and takes on the role of a benevolent judge and jury - the antithesis of Dirty Harry and Judge Dredd, one more attuned to understand human faults, accept them, than issue warrants. Nonetheless this self-conscious style of storytelling does backlash during build-up, as the convoluted plot mires midway with mild bouts of oversentimentilisation and underwritten character motivations, before finally hitting back with an astoundingly well-rounded finale. Nonetheless a brilliant and captivating movie, which ranks up there with Spike Lee's best with high probability of future rewatching pleasure. A big part of the success comes from disposing of the preacher like stance so predominant in many of Lee's weaker works. Albeit mostly low-key and pretty standard the most significant scenes feature sudden detachment from traditional cinematography to a more detached, surreal focus, as if suggesting a detachment from the grim everyday reality of the protagonists offering escapist release from hardships. This offers some extremely imaginative cinematography by Malik Hassan Sayeed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most of the time remains stuck between good and great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is no denying it that this is a good and well made movie but at the same time I also still had loads of problems with it! The way I see it, this is being a pretty good portrayal of live on the streets in the '90's. It picks a mostly realistic approach but still I just can't really 'feel' this movie. I never felt involved with any of the characters in it or to any of the dramatic events and developments. It doesn't make this movie bad but it does indeed make this movie a bit of a one dimensional experience. And remember, this is an 1995 movie. So everything that was considered to be hip and 'thug life' might seem a bit ridicules and less cool in today's perspective. The whole attitude and way of talking and the way everyone dresses makes this movie really a product of its time. In that regard this movie also really reminded me of "Kids", which coincidentally or not, got made in the same year as this movie. It makes this movie less relevant to watch now days but really, it's nothing I was holding against the movie. I would had most definitely preferred it if this movie was using a more straightforward style of storytelling. The movie as it is seems to be wanting to focus on far too many different characters and tries to do and tell too much. It also really has its own style to it, when it comes down to its storytelling, which was nice and helped to give this movie an unique feeling but at the same time it also made the movie unnecessary hard and not all that pleasant to follow at times. Another thing I also disliked about this movie was its pick of music. The movie mad some bad music choices, in which the music often would swell and become melodramatic at moments that really were uncalled for. It absolutely distracted and most of the time didn't suit what was happening on the screen at the time. But really, I though this movie still had some hints of a great movie in it as well. One thing was its already earlier mentioned unique and distinctive style. Spike Lee always has had an unique and distinctive style of his own and he manages to put a lot of that in this movie successfully. There are some interesting moments in this movie, from a more technical and movie-making perspective. There was some good camera-work for instance and also very little wrong with the movie its editing and pacing. The movie its story in essence also really seemed to be a solid one but I do feel that they perhaps should had picked some different perspectives to keep- and make things a bit more interesting and effective. Wouldn't this movie for instance had been better and more interesting if it told things more from the Harvey Keitel's character perspective? Who knows and it's not like the movie bad or interesting as it is right now but while watching this movie it constantly gave me the feeling it had more potential and things could had been done better. I don't know, perhaps the movie was also being a bit stuck between being a gangster movie and a more realistic one. It never felt like a true gangster flick and it never felt like a true realistic movie neither. Producer Martin Scorsese perhaps should had stepped in a bit more often, since he definitely is a kind of director who can more successfully blend realism with tough and tense gangster/crime movies. Not trying to sound too negative. The movie is good enough as it is but it doesn't ever reaches its full potential. 7/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brothers killin' other brothers ain't no big thing. Blas&eacute;, blas&eacute;.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Clockers is directed by Spike Lee who also co-adapts the screenplay with Richard Price from Price's own novel of the same name. It stars Harvey Keitel, John Turturro, Delroy Lindo, Mekhi Phifer, Isaiah Washington, Keith David, Peewee Love and Regina Taylor. Music is scored by Terence Blanchard and cinematography by Malik Hassan Sayeed. Young drug pushers in the projects of Brooklyn (Clockers) are caught between loyalty to their drug boss and the detectives out to stop them. It's not as incendiary as one might expect of a Spike Lee joint, but the director's concerns and astute knack for story telling are very prominent features. It was originally going to be a Martin Scorses film, but he chose to make Casino instead, he does, however, get a producing credit and you can see in the material why Scorsese was interested in directing. Pic is basically a take on urban drug dealing in the Brooklyn projects and the impact said dealing has on anyone who comes into contact with it. From the downward spiral of life for young men earning their pay by illegal means, to fretful mothers desperately trying to keep pe-teen kiddies from joining the ranks of what they think are cool operators, the morality of the play is forcibly rammed home by Lee. Unfortunately this comes at a cost to the white cop characters, who are too thinly drawn to offer up a law and order counter point to the illegal activity involving drugs and murder, they serve only as the "man", and damn the "man" at that. The Rocco Klein (Keitel) of the book is not evident here, sadly, while Torturo may as well not be in it! Cast performances are well in tune with the material, with Lindo as the "black godfather" turning in a scary one, and Lee's camera-work, coupled with Sayeed's moody photography, has a nifty grasp of realism. Soundtracking is soulful and pleasant. A mixed bag for sure, but it's a story that needs to be told. Bleak and brutal at times, but still offering hope, it's middle tier Spike Lee that always remains intriguing. Even if it at times feels like he was bored telling yet another "black on black is bad" message movie. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tribal Study.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this complicated tale of the pressures on Mekhi Phifer in the Brooklyn projects, director Spike Lee captures the values and the iconography of the African-American community well, as he usually does. You get a genuine sense of the simmering anger, the shifting allegiances, and the small reward system of the social world these pathetic people live in. Pfifer is the central figure and he sweats a lot. No brighter or better than he should be, he's pressured from one side into dealing cocaine by local mogul Delroy Lindo. On the other side, he's pushed by the manipulative but well-intentioned detectives Harvey Keitel and Stanley Turturro. Pfifer's handsome and upright brother is under arrest for murder but Keitel believes that Pfifer is the culprit. Pfifer's brother is simply too good, too compliant, to have done the deed. Nice ambiguity. Lee convincingly nails the diversity and solidarity of the community. It's like John Ford in the ghetto. Pfifer may be innocent of the crime of which Keitel is convinced he's guilty but he also deals dope. Keitel, for all his ploying the system, is determined to bring the guilty party to justice, though he may play a little dirty in getting the job done. And when he finds out that he's been wrong about who committed the murder, he does what such a person would do in real life. He hides his guilt behind a tirade of threats. In a way, it's an improvement over Spike Lee's "Do The Right Thing." It doesn't turn all the cops into heavies. And it doesn't end with an ominous quote from Malcolm X. The weakness of the film lies in Lee's allowing conversations to go on for too long. Pfifer gets a lot of screen time and when he's not chewing out his young brother (who will save his life) he's whining about his innocence. The exchanges, sometimes rising to shouts, go on too long and become tiring. It's a devalued life these people lead. They wear clothes and they groom themselves in ways that appeal only to those in their immediate and limited social worlds. I'm beginning to develop an idea. The more you resemble someone who is upper class and British, the more your social worth. The farther removed you are from this model, the lower your status. If you could take Pfifer, dress him in riding clothes and teach him to play polo, and have him say "eck-tually" instead of "aks," and have him grow some hair on his shaved and shiny skull, he might not be thought guilty of anything except being too polite.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oscar-worthy. Incredible film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tpaladino
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no idea why this film wasn't nominated for an Oscar, and I especially have no idea why it's been seventeen years since the film was released and I'm just now seeing it. I've always been vaguely aware of it's existence as one of the 'other' Spike Lee films, but not much more. I certainly wasn't expecting to see some of his all-time best work, which it is. This film should be mandatory viewing for every single high school in America, that's how important it is. Spike Lee paints a devastatingly realistic picture of inner-city life and the mortal perils that it's inhabitants face on a daily basis. There are no heroes, no angels, and no caricatures. It's all laid bare for the viewer to draw their own conclusion. Lee treats the audience with a level of respect and maturity that is almost unheard of in films that deal in such explosive and controversial subject matter. He trusts that the audience will understand the big picture and take away the appropriate lesson without being evangelized, and without resorting to the kind of cheap gimmickry and pandering that can often plague films of this genre. Everyone should see this film. Literally everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such an overwhelming disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johndeckbose
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm glad that Spike Lee has apparently outgrown his need for polemics. Inside Man was a wonderful mature film that focused on character and motivation far beyond the Afro-centric purview of earlier Spike films. And while Clockers is perfectly serviceable for anyone coming to the story without having read the novel, I submit that Spike's attempt to refocus Richard Price's 1992 masterpiece as a singular black story, with a bone-throwing portrayal of white Detective Rocco Klein within an indictment of white police tactics, short-changes the audience of the profound respect, balance and humanity that made Price's novel so unforgettable. It is truly one of the five best novels I have ever read, while Spike managed to produce one of 1000 best movies I have ever seen. Read the book. It will stun, shock, amaze and delight you. The movie, on the other hand, might just keep you from falling asleep.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is WEAK...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gveltman1
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although I have only seen a few of Spike Lee's films, I am already beginning to place him very low on the ladder of the best directors alive today. Clockers fails, in my opinion, because the film's premise is lacking substance to begin with; the story is lackluster to the max. On top of this, where the film had its opportunities to reel in the audience emotionally, it instead dropped the ball. Moments where energy, tension, and suspense were supposed to effused were disappointingly overridden with anticlimactic slumps in action. The choking scene in the car as well as when Mekhi is being beat up in the park, with their odd selection of music, seem unfulfilled in their potential to capitalize on emotional appeal. I will say the denouement is shot with expert precision. Lee's patented cinematographic maneuver, the double dolly, is on full display. Moreover, his use of low-key lighting in some specific scenes that illustrate the proliferation of drugs inside the projects are done in a professionally haunting manor. Unfortunately, these instances are rare, overshadowed by the weak portions previously discussed. With regards to Lee's film style in Clockers, I like to point out two of his techniques that I find terribly annoying: 1) Those stupid circling gliding shots around characters when they are talking. 2) His persistent use of intense music to compliment serious(at least Lee thinks they must be) scenes. When put together, these two devices serve to create the ultimate exaggeration of the weight a scene carries in this film. Doing a flashy gliding pan across the park accompanied by pounding sound while Tyrone's mother yells at Mekhi and his boys about his haircut is a little excessive. Instead, I think Clocker's would benefit from a greater variation in the levels of stress and emotion we experience in each scene. This way, when the film actually does come to a TRULY significant moment, the audience will become more invested in the action. P.S. I don't think anyone from the projects would actually where a complete Arizona wildcats uniform. Just the jersey, not the shorts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder mystery and race mixed into one great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Take a murder mystery story, mix it into a contemporary vulgar urban setting, then sprinkle some racial tension into the mix and you've got the highly intellectual and intense Spike Lee film Clockers. Clockers is about Strike, a young black man living in Brooklyn, dealing drugs for his ruthless drug lord Rodney Little. Strike deals drugs for the money, but all he really wants to do is hang out with his brothers in the park and play with model train sets. But things start to get rough when a night manager at a local fast food joint is murdered and Strike's brother Victor turns himself in. Det. Rocco Klein is the lead detective on the case and he doesn't buy Victor's story, which sets him on an obsessive hunt to unmask the truth behind this whole ordeal. The film is loaded with spirited yet vulgar dialouge, artistic and vibrant direction, and plenty of memorable characters. Clockers is witty, intelligent, and a lot of fun. It isn't your typical murder mystery or racial tension film. It is a beautiful blend of the two genres that turns into something very unique and very exciting. Spike Lee adds a lot of visual flair to this film and the way he directs it is something you can't quite pinpoint. The panoramic visual style is something you can't exactly describe in words and it is really something you have to see for yourself. There is something obviously unique going on in the way Lee directs this film, it is just difficult to articulate what exactly that is. But the visuals do work in a whole plethora of unique films, allowing the film to succeed on multiple levels. The film ranges from intense and gripping to quirky and fun. From one scene to the next the film grows more fun and more enthralling. Rarely do I care this much about what happens to the characters of a film and I'm not always so compelled to learn the motivations of the very well written characters of a film. All that being said I can't say that I loved the main character, Strike. The actor, Mekhi Phifer, wasn't great and the character himself had some odd moments. I eventually learned to like him and his character thankfully didn't deter too much from my liking of the film. Besides, a lot of the film actually focuses on Harvey Keitel's character and his unending search for the truth behind the murder. There are also numerous subplots that all end up being more interesting than the main character's story. It helps that this is just an all around well written film that is just smarter than your average crime film. Clockers is very different from any murder mystery crime film, as well as any racial tension film. But it provides plenty of great work on both sides of this spectrum. Spike Lee has created a visually interesting film with a fantastic story. The main character is the only low point of the film, but everything else is very good. Clockers is a very worthwhile watch for fans of Spike Lee or the multiple genres this film spans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Modern urban classic - Spike's greatest 'joint'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesxgamble
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my all-time favourite films. Director Spike Lee adapts the Richard Price Novel, set in New Jersey, to his hometown and favourite movie backdrop: Brooklyn. It is often said that films never live up to the books on which they are based, but in this case I think the movie out performs the novel. This is because the book can be slow moving at times, and the action is separated by long passages of writing. However, the film chops all of these slow parts out, and the result is a film that keeps you engaged from start to finish. Spike Lee uses music perfectly to compliment the tone and mood of each scene, be it hip-hop in the urban playground, the acoustic interludes of Seal and Des'ree, or minor key, intense jazz to accompany drug use in doorways and nooks, and the final scene's soundtrack is absolutely inspired. Delroy Lindo plays his king-pin character with such comfort, at times it is hard to imagine that he isn't that person in reality! Harvey Keitel and John Turturro work well as the detective double-team, conflicting over whether to take the easy close-by-arrest, or the moral crusade to find the truth behind the case at the heart of the film. Mekhi Phifer is impressive in many of his scenes as the central character, who keeps you guessing to the end on whether he deserves your sympathy or not. For me, Lindo's performance is the standout turn. The cinematography is luscious, and the colours and compositions make this film a visual feast. But more importantly, the natural dialogue of the film and the delivery of nearly every line really reinforce the fact that you are watching a film about real situations. Overall, I give this film my maximum rating of 9.5 stars. If you like this film, you'll love The Wire Season One, and you also might want to check out another overlooked film, Jason's Lyric.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When you don't help people because you like them, but because you hate enough their world enough to let them triumph over it ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The title might give you a hint, "Clockers" is about routine, and not the most pleasant one. Indeed, this routine is made of drug-dealing and occasional murders. And if you think that you've been desensitized enough by police procedural and gangster movies, "Clockers" will be a powerful wake-up call. Honestly, I can't recall a film that dealt so straightforwardly with real-life violence apart from David Cronenberg's "A History of Violence" but that was 10 years after ''Clockers". The opening credits set the tone. Shots of young black persons' murdered are shown, blood staining the pavement and deadpan expression proving they didn't see what was coming to them. Lee doesn't stylize for aesthetic purposes but intelligently guide our expectations, loudly shouting what gangster films timidly whispers: this is an ugly word with no redeeming appeal whatsoever. No matter what it involves, it either ends up with jail of being the unintentional poser of bloody aftermaths' pictures. And their purpose is echoed in the murder scene, where lies Darryl Adams, a restaurant manager, shot four times. The sight of the body is disturbing but no more than the total detachment of the two assigned detectives played by Harvey Keitel and John Turturro. They comment the body with shocking detachment and cynical wisecracks such as "the kid had brains" while blood spilled over a hole in his head I don't think Lee's intent is to portray these cops as racist or cynical, but to underline how routinely these murders became. This is not to brandish the 'racism' flag (Lee is above these clich&eacute;s) but to remind us that these crimes are committed within the black community. So, no matter what you'd think of the cops, they're not the ones who pulled the trigger. We're used of that ambiguity regarding racism and this is a credit to Spike Lee's co-writing with Richard Price, who wrote the original novel. "Clockers" depicts a slice of people's life that encapsulates all the factors that lead to the opening 'pictures'. And that no-way-out situation is embodied by the main protagonist, Strike (Mekhi Phifer), a clocker working for Rodney (Delroy Lindo), the crime lord of the neighborhood. His job mainly consists on standing in the park and waiting for customers coming to buy crack. The process is well-elaborated, as there is a watcher to check for cop's arrivals, but eventual strip-searches are also part of this routine. The point is that clockers are at the bottom of the hierarchy, but that's their way of living. The issue of money is another layer of subtlety the film provides. Strike doesn't use money to date girls, buy a car or new clothes. Electric trains are his hobbies. Why? Why not? But we understand that he's trapped in that job for the simple reason is that it earns him enough money to fulfill his passion. On the other hand, his brother Victor (Isaiah Washington) is a honest, two-job worker and decent father forced to constantly swallow the bitter taste of frustration while watching brothers making easy money while he gets no respect and that's his routine. These brothers live in a world where money buys enough power to ooze respect. Both feel pressure in their lives, and the result is Victor's arrest and confession that he murdered Adams, claiming it was for self-defense, but there's something wrong in that murder Keitel's character can't get off his head. The case is even more complex because it was Strike who was supposed to kill Adams, to make his bones with Rodney and climb the 'social ladder'. The seemingly fatherly affection between Rodney and Strike is finally distorted when Rodney reveals the first time he killed a man, threatened with a gun on his mouth by Errol (Thomas Jefferson Byrd) a tough killer before he became the local AIDS-stricken psycho. Like for Rodney, Strike had to have blood on his hands, the point of no-return meaning trust. So, we get it, there are no feelings in such a dirty business. And as the investigation proceeds, Keitel gets more and more interested in Strike's case and wonder why he'd let his brother covering him, and why would a man like Victor kill Adams in the first place? To spare Strike the burden of belonging to Rodney, and in the process, vent all his anger? The procedural leaves to a satisfying resolution but it wasn't "Clockers' main point. The film is more about complex human interactions, because while Keitel and Phifer get closer one another, their mutual affection feel more real and genuine than with Rodney, and might pave the road to Strike's redemption. I know this 'redemption' word is kind of hackneyed, but I know Scorsese co-produced the film, and I felt some intense Scorsesian vibes in that gritty depiction of an underworld and the torment poisoning the main character's life, in the real meaning of the world since Strike is also victim of chronicle ulcer that gets bloodier as the film progresses, like a metaphor of his moral downfall and an imminent deadly conclusion. But there's a third significant character to enrich the film: Tyrone, a kid who admires Strike and imitates him to the point of shaving his head and wearing the same clothes. The kid is a younger version of Strike with Strike playing Rodney's mentor role, and ironically, the disciple shows more zeal and competence than his master. Tyrone's arc is a light of hope illuminating possible ways out of the hell given you don't act like people acted with you. Tyrone evolves from the embodiment of Strike's disgrace to his redemption. And Strike is given the same chance, the possibility to count on people who don't help him because they like him, but because they hate that world enough to triumph over it by getting someone out of it. Indeed, there might be a right way and a wrong way but when trapped in such blinding routine, everybody needs a sign, or guidance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Justice is never black and white
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dope dealing on the Nelson Mandela projects in Brooklyn is the everyday bread of local hoodlum Ronald Dunham aka Strike (Mekhi Phifer). Staking the local park the line of work is relentlessly stressful causing a stress-induced ulcer, which he deals with by drinking down yoo-hoos by the litres. At night respite is found in the form of a trainset hobby, an voyeuristic escape from the reality he has accepted. When his boss Rodney Little (Delroy Lindo) hints towards the necessity of cropping one of his less trustworthy workers Strike confides to his brother Victor (Isaiah Washington). Soon after the murder is committed and Victor steps up to claim self defence. However hardliner detective Rocco Klein (Harvey Keitel) quickly assumes this is a cover up for the true culprit. One of Spike Lee's most accomplished works and a worryingly underrated gem bordering on a masterpiece. While showing artistic restraint in symbols and style, Spike Lee offers a well-devised structure, which lets the strength of the story carry itself. Especially in the final act Lee's well-tuned reserve makes for a heart-felt conclusion full of poignant suggestions, as to the nature of violence. Even the innocent can be corrupted needing a vent for their endless victimisation, while the corrupt seek innocence by befriending children reminiscent of them in their youth and dreaming about a life with 'no more packing'. The ultimately compassionate Rocco, previously shown as a no nonsense cop with a strong moral compass ultimately rejects 'Justice in Black and White', deciding that even the guilty are seldom dealt justice and takes on the role of a benevolent judge and jury - the antithesis of Dirty Harry and Judge Dredd, one more attuned to understand human faults, accept them, than issue warrants. Nonetheless this self-conscious style of storytelling does backlash during build-up, as the convoluted plot mires midway with mild bouts of oversentimentilisation and underwritten character motivations, before finally hitting back with an astoundingly well-rounded finale. Nonetheless a brilliant and captivating movie, which ranks up there with Spike Lee's best with high probability of future rewatching pleasure. A big part of the success comes from disposing of the preacher like stance so predominant in many of Lee's weaker works. Albeit mostly low-key and pretty standard the most significant scenes feature sudden detachment from traditional cinematography to a more detached, surreal focus, as if suggesting a detachment from the grim everyday reality of the protagonists offering escapist release from hardships. This offers some extremely imaginative cinematography by Malik Hassan Sayeed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most of the time remains stuck between good and great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is no denying it that this is a good and well made movie but at the same time I also still had loads of problems with it! The way I see it, this is being a pretty good portrayal of live on the streets in the '90's. It picks a mostly realistic approach but still I just can't really 'feel' this movie. I never felt involved with any of the characters in it or to any of the dramatic events and developments. It doesn't make this movie bad but it does indeed make this movie a bit of a one dimensional experience. And remember, this is an 1995 movie. So everything that was considered to be hip and 'thug life' might seem a bit ridicules and less cool in today's perspective. The whole attitude and way of talking and the way everyone dresses makes this movie really a product of its time. In that regard this movie also really reminded me of "Kids", which coincidentally or not, got made in the same year as this movie. It makes this movie less relevant to watch now days but really, it's nothing I was holding against the movie. I would had most definitely preferred it if this movie was using a more straightforward style of storytelling. The movie as it is seems to be wanting to focus on far too many different characters and tries to do and tell too much. It also really has its own style to it, when it comes down to its storytelling, which was nice and helped to give this movie an unique feeling but at the same time it also made the movie unnecessary hard and not all that pleasant to follow at times. Another thing I also disliked about this movie was its pick of music. The movie mad some bad music choices, in which the music often would swell and become melodramatic at moments that really were uncalled for. It absolutely distracted and most of the time didn't suit what was happening on the screen at the time. But really, I though this movie still had some hints of a great movie in it as well. One thing was its already earlier mentioned unique and distinctive style. Spike Lee always has had an unique and distinctive style of his own and he manages to put a lot of that in this movie successfully. There are some interesting moments in this movie, from a more technical and movie-making perspective. There was some good camera-work for instance and also very little wrong with the movie its editing and pacing. The movie its story in essence also really seemed to be a solid one but I do feel that they perhaps should had picked some different perspectives to keep- and make things a bit more interesting and effective. Wouldn't this movie for instance had been better and more interesting if it told things more from the Harvey Keitel's character perspective? Who knows and it's not like the movie bad or interesting as it is right now but while watching this movie it constantly gave me the feeling it had more potential and things could had been done better. I don't know, perhaps the movie was also being a bit stuck between being a gangster movie and a more realistic one. It never felt like a true gangster flick and it never felt like a true realistic movie neither. Producer Martin Scorsese perhaps should had stepped in a bit more often, since he definitely is a kind of director who can more successfully blend realism with tough and tense gangster/crime movies. Not trying to sound too negative. The movie is good enough as it is but it doesn't ever reaches its full potential. 7/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brothers killin' other brothers ain't no big thing. Blas&eacute;, blas&eacute;.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Clockers is directed by Spike Lee who also co-adapts the screenplay with Richard Price from Price's own novel of the same name. It stars Harvey Keitel, John Turturro, Delroy Lindo, Mekhi Phifer, Isaiah Washington, Keith David, Peewee Love and Regina Taylor. Music is scored by Terence Blanchard and cinematography by Malik Hassan Sayeed. Young drug pushers in the projects of Brooklyn (Clockers) are caught between loyalty to their drug boss and the detectives out to stop them. It's not as incendiary as one might expect of a Spike Lee joint, but the director's concerns and astute knack for story telling are very prominent features. It was originally going to be a Martin Scorses film, but he chose to make Casino instead, he does, however, get a producing credit and you can see in the material why Scorsese was interested in directing. Pic is basically a take on urban drug dealing in the Brooklyn projects and the impact said dealing has on anyone who comes into contact with it. From the downward spiral of life for young men earning their pay by illegal means, to fretful mothers desperately trying to keep pe-teen kiddies from joining the ranks of what they think are cool operators, the morality of the play is forcibly rammed home by Lee. Unfortunately this comes at a cost to the white cop characters, who are too thinly drawn to offer up a law and order counter point to the illegal activity involving drugs and murder, they serve only as the "man", and damn the "man" at that. The Rocco Klein (Keitel) of the book is not evident here, sadly, while Torturo may as well not be in it! Cast performances are well in tune with the material, with Lindo as the "black godfather" turning in a scary one, and Lee's camera-work, coupled with Sayeed's moody photography, has a nifty grasp of realism. Soundtracking is soulful and pleasant. A mixed bag for sure, but it's a story that needs to be told. Bleak and brutal at times, but still offering hope, it's middle tier Spike Lee that always remains intriguing. Even if it at times feels like he was bored telling yet another "black on black is bad" message movie. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tribal Study.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this complicated tale of the pressures on Mekhi Phifer in the Brooklyn projects, director Spike Lee captures the values and the iconography of the African-American community well, as he usually does. You get a genuine sense of the simmering anger, the shifting allegiances, and the small reward system of the social world these pathetic people live in. Pfifer is the central figure and he sweats a lot. No brighter or better than he should be, he's pressured from one side into dealing cocaine by local mogul Delroy Lindo. On the other side, he's pushed by the manipulative but well-intentioned detectives Harvey Keitel and Stanley Turturro. Pfifer's handsome and upright brother is under arrest for murder but Keitel believes that Pfifer is the culprit. Pfifer's brother is simply too good, too compliant, to have done the deed. Nice ambiguity. Lee convincingly nails the diversity and solidarity of the community. It's like John Ford in the ghetto. Pfifer may be innocent of the crime of which Keitel is convinced he's guilty but he also deals dope. Keitel, for all his ploying the system, is determined to bring the guilty party to justice, though he may play a little dirty in getting the job done. And when he finds out that he's been wrong about who committed the murder, he does what such a person would do in real life. He hides his guilt behind a tirade of threats. In a way, it's an improvement over Spike Lee's "Do The Right Thing." It doesn't turn all the cops into heavies. And it doesn't end with an ominous quote from Malcolm X. The weakness of the film lies in Lee's allowing conversations to go on for too long. Pfifer gets a lot of screen time and when he's not chewing out his young brother (who will save his life) he's whining about his innocence. The exchanges, sometimes rising to shouts, go on too long and become tiring. It's a devalued life these people lead. They wear clothes and they groom themselves in ways that appeal only to those in their immediate and limited social worlds. I'm beginning to develop an idea. The more you resemble someone who is upper class and British, the more your social worth. The farther removed you are from this model, the lower your status. If you could take Pfifer, dress him in riding clothes and teach him to play polo, and have him say "eck-tually" instead of "aks," and have him grow some hair on his shaved and shiny skull, he might not be thought guilty of anything except being too polite.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oscar-worthy. Incredible film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tpaladino
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no idea why this film wasn't nominated for an Oscar, and I especially have no idea why it's been seventeen years since the film was released and I'm just now seeing it. I've always been vaguely aware of it's existence as one of the 'other' Spike Lee films, but not much more. I certainly wasn't expecting to see some of his all-time best work, which it is. This film should be mandatory viewing for every single high school in America, that's how important it is. Spike Lee paints a devastatingly realistic picture of inner-city life and the mortal perils that it's inhabitants face on a daily basis. There are no heroes, no angels, and no caricatures. It's all laid bare for the viewer to draw their own conclusion. Lee treats the audience with a level of respect and maturity that is almost unheard of in films that deal in such explosive and controversial subject matter. He trusts that the audience will understand the big picture and take away the appropriate lesson without being evangelized, and without resorting to the kind of cheap gimmickry and pandering that can often plague films of this genre. Everyone should see this film. Literally everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such an overwhelming disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johndeckbose
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm glad that Spike Lee has apparently outgrown his need for polemics. Inside Man was a wonderful mature film that focused on character and motivation far beyond the Afro-centric purview of earlier Spike films. And while Clockers is perfectly serviceable for anyone coming to the story without having read the novel, I submit that Spike's attempt to refocus Richard Price's 1992 masterpiece as a singular black story, with a bone-throwing portrayal of white Detective Rocco Klein within an indictment of white police tactics, short-changes the audience of the profound respect, balance and humanity that made Price's novel so unforgettable. It is truly one of the five best novels I have ever read, while Spike managed to produce one of 1000 best movies I have ever seen. Read the book. It will stun, shock, amaze and delight you. The movie, on the other hand, might just keep you from falling asleep.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is WEAK...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gveltman1
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although I have only seen a few of Spike Lee's films, I am already beginning to place him very low on the ladder of the best directors alive today. Clockers fails, in my opinion, because the film's premise is lacking substance to begin with; the story is lackluster to the max. On top of this, where the film had its opportunities to reel in the audience emotionally, it instead dropped the ball. Moments where energy, tension, and suspense were supposed to effused were disappointingly overridden with anticlimactic slumps in action. The choking scene in the car as well as when Mekhi is being beat up in the park, with their odd selection of music, seem unfulfilled in their potential to capitalize on emotional appeal. I will say the denouement is shot with expert precision. Lee's patented cinematographic maneuver, the double dolly, is on full display. Moreover, his use of low-key lighting in some specific scenes that illustrate the proliferation of drugs inside the projects are done in a professionally haunting manor. Unfortunately, these instances are rare, overshadowed by the weak portions previously discussed. With regards to Lee's film style in Clockers, I like to point out two of his techniques that I find terribly annoying: 1) Those stupid circling gliding shots around characters when they are talking. 2) His persistent use of intense music to compliment serious(at least Lee thinks they must be) scenes. When put together, these two devices serve to create the ultimate exaggeration of the weight a scene carries in this film. Doing a flashy gliding pan across the park accompanied by pounding sound while Tyrone's mother yells at Mekhi and his boys about his haircut is a little excessive. Instead, I think Clocker's would benefit from a greater variation in the levels of stress and emotion we experience in each scene. This way, when the film actually does come to a TRULY significant moment, the audience will become more invested in the action. P.S. I don't think anyone from the projects would actually where a complete Arizona wildcats uniform. Just the jersey, not the shorts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder mystery and race mixed into one great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Take a murder mystery story, mix it into a contemporary vulgar urban setting, then sprinkle some racial tension into the mix and you've got the highly intellectual and intense Spike Lee film Clockers. Clockers is about Strike, a young black man living in Brooklyn, dealing drugs for his ruthless drug lord Rodney Little. Strike deals drugs for the money, but all he really wants to do is hang out with his brothers in the park and play with model train sets. But things start to get rough when a night manager at a local fast food joint is murdered and Strike's brother Victor turns himself in. Det. Rocco Klein is the lead detective on the case and he doesn't buy Victor's story, which sets him on an obsessive hunt to unmask the truth behind this whole ordeal. The film is loaded with spirited yet vulgar dialouge, artistic and vibrant direction, and plenty of memorable characters. Clockers is witty, intelligent, and a lot of fun. It isn't your typical murder mystery or racial tension film. It is a beautiful blend of the two genres that turns into something very unique and very exciting. Spike Lee adds a lot of visual flair to this film and the way he directs it is something you can't quite pinpoint. The panoramic visual style is something you can't exactly describe in words and it is really something you have to see for yourself. There is something obviously unique going on in the way Lee directs this film, it is just difficult to articulate what exactly that is. But the visuals do work in a whole plethora of unique films, allowing the film to succeed on multiple levels. The film ranges from intense and gripping to quirky and fun. From one scene to the next the film grows more fun and more enthralling. Rarely do I care this much about what happens to the characters of a film and I'm not always so compelled to learn the motivations of the very well written characters of a film. All that being said I can't say that I loved the main character, Strike. The actor, Mekhi Phifer, wasn't great and the character himself had some odd moments. I eventually learned to like him and his character thankfully didn't deter too much from my liking of the film. Besides, a lot of the film actually focuses on Harvey Keitel's character and his unending search for the truth behind the murder. There are also numerous subplots that all end up being more interesting than the main character's story. It helps that this is just an all around well written film that is just smarter than your average crime film. Clockers is very different from any murder mystery crime film, as well as any racial tension film. But it provides plenty of great work on both sides of this spectrum. Spike Lee has created a visually interesting film with a fantastic story. The main character is the only low point of the film, but everything else is very good. Clockers is a very worthwhile watch for fans of Spike Lee or the multiple genres this film spans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Modern urban classic - Spike's greatest 'joint'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesxgamble
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my all-time favourite films. Director Spike Lee adapts the Richard Price Novel, set in New Jersey, to his hometown and favourite movie backdrop: Brooklyn. It is often said that films never live up to the books on which they are based, but in this case I think the movie out performs the novel. This is because the book can be slow moving at times, and the action is separated by long passages of writing. However, the film chops all of these slow parts out, and the result is a film that keeps you engaged from start to finish. Spike Lee uses music perfectly to compliment the tone and mood of each scene, be it hip-hop in the urban playground, the acoustic interludes of Seal and Des'ree, or minor key, intense jazz to accompany drug use in doorways and nooks, and the final scene's soundtrack is absolutely inspired. Delroy Lindo plays his king-pin character with such comfort, at times it is hard to imagine that he isn't that person in reality! Harvey Keitel and John Turturro work well as the detective double-team, conflicting over whether to take the easy close-by-arrest, or the moral crusade to find the truth behind the case at the heart of the film. Mekhi Phifer is impressive in many of his scenes as the central character, who keeps you guessing to the end on whether he deserves your sympathy or not. For me, Lindo's performance is the standout turn. The cinematography is luscious, and the colours and compositions make this film a visual feast. But more importantly, the natural dialogue of the film and the delivery of nearly every line really reinforce the fact that you are watching a film about real situations. Overall, I give this film my maximum rating of 9.5 stars. If you like this film, you'll love The Wire Season One, and you also might want to check out another overlooked film, Jason's Lyric.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When you don't help people because you like them, but because you hate enough their world enough to let them triumph over it ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The title might give you a hint, "Clockers" is about routine, and not the most pleasant one. Indeed, this routine is made of drug-dealing and occasional murders. And if you think that you've been desensitized enough by police procedural and gangster movies, "Clockers" will be a powerful wake-up call. Honestly, I can't recall a film that dealt so straightforwardly with real-life violence apart from David Cronenberg's "A History of Violence" but that was 10 years after ''Clockers". The opening credits set the tone. Shots of young black persons' murdered are shown, blood staining the pavement and deadpan expression proving they didn't see what was coming to them. Lee doesn't stylize for aesthetic purposes but intelligently guide our expectations, loudly shouting what gangster films timidly whispers: this is an ugly word with no redeeming appeal whatsoever. No matter what it involves, it either ends up with jail of being the unintentional poser of bloody aftermaths' pictures. And their purpose is echoed in the murder scene, where lies Darryl Adams, a restaurant manager, shot four times. The sight of the body is disturbing but no more than the total detachment of the two assigned detectives played by Harvey Keitel and John Turturro. They comment the body with shocking detachment and cynical wisecracks such as "the kid had brains" while blood spilled over a hole in his head I don't think Lee's intent is to portray these cops as racist or cynical, but to underline how routinely these murders became. This is not to brandish the 'racism' flag (Lee is above these clich&eacute;s) but to remind us that these crimes are committed within the black community. So, no matter what you'd think of the cops, they're not the ones who pulled the trigger. We're used of that ambiguity regarding racism and this is a credit to Spike Lee's co-writing with Richard Price, who wrote the original novel. "Clockers" depicts a slice of people's life that encapsulates all the factors that lead to the opening 'pictures'. And that no-way-out situation is embodied by the main protagonist, Strike (Mekhi Phifer), a clocker working for Rodney (Delroy Lindo), the crime lord of the neighborhood. His job mainly consists on standing in the park and waiting for customers coming to buy crack. The process is well-elaborated, as there is a watcher to check for cop's arrivals, but eventual strip-searches are also part of this routine. The point is that clockers are at the bottom of the hierarchy, but that's their way of living. The issue of money is another layer of subtlety the film provides. Strike doesn't use money to date girls, buy a car or new clothes. Electric trains are his hobbies. Why? Why not? But we understand that he's trapped in that job for the simple reason is that it earns him enough money to fulfill his passion. On the other hand, his brother Victor (Isaiah Washington) is a honest, two-job worker and decent father forced to constantly swallow the bitter taste of frustration while watching brothers making easy money while he gets no respect and that's his routine. These brothers live in a world where money buys enough power to ooze respect. Both feel pressure in their lives, and the result is Victor's arrest and confession that he murdered Adams, claiming it was for self-defense, but there's something wrong in that murder Keitel's character can't get off his head. The case is even more complex because it was Strike who was supposed to kill Adams, to make his bones with Rodney and climb the 'social ladder'. The seemingly fatherly affection between Rodney and Strike is finally distorted when Rodney reveals the first time he killed a man, threatened with a gun on his mouth by Errol (Thomas Jefferson Byrd) a tough killer before he became the local AIDS-stricken psycho. Like for Rodney, Strike had to have blood on his hands, the point of no-return meaning trust. So, we get it, there are no feelings in such a dirty business. And as the investigation proceeds, Keitel gets more and more interested in Strike's case and wonder why he'd let his brother covering him, and why would a man like Victor kill Adams in the first place? To spare Strike the burden of belonging to Rodney, and in the process, vent all his anger? The procedural leaves to a satisfying resolution but it wasn't "Clockers' main point. The film is more about complex human interactions, because while Keitel and Phifer get closer one another, their mutual affection feel more real and genuine than with Rodney, and might pave the road to Strike's redemption. I know this 'redemption' word is kind of hackneyed, but I know Scorsese co-produced the film, and I felt some intense Scorsesian vibes in that gritty depiction of an underworld and the torment poisoning the main character's life, in the real meaning of the world since Strike is also victim of chronicle ulcer that gets bloodier as the film progresses, like a metaphor of his moral downfall and an imminent deadly conclusion. But there's a third significant character to enrich the film: Tyrone, a kid who admires Strike and imitates him to the point of shaving his head and wearing the same clothes. The kid is a younger version of Strike with Strike playing Rodney's mentor role, and ironically, the disciple shows more zeal and competence than his master. Tyrone's arc is a light of hope illuminating possible ways out of the hell given you don't act like people acted with you. Tyrone evolves from the embodiment of Strike's disgrace to his redemption. And Strike is given the same chance, the possibility to count on people who don't help him because they like him, but because they hate that world enough to triumph over it by getting someone out of it. Indeed, there might be a right way and a wrong way but when trapped in such blinding routine, everybody needs a sign, or guidance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Justice is never black and white
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dope dealing on the Nelson Mandela projects in Brooklyn is the everyday bread of local hoodlum Ronald Dunham aka Strike (Mekhi Phifer). Staking the local park the line of work is relentlessly stressful causing a stress-induced ulcer, which he deals with by drinking down yoo-hoos by the litres. At night respite is found in the form of a trainset hobby, an voyeuristic escape from the reality he has accepted. When his boss Rodney Little (Delroy Lindo) hints towards the necessity of cropping one of his less trustworthy workers Strike confides to his brother Victor (Isaiah Washington). Soon after the murder is committed and Victor steps up to claim self defence. However hardliner detective Rocco Klein (Harvey Keitel) quickly assumes this is a cover up for the true culprit. One of Spike Lee's most accomplished works and a worryingly underrated gem bordering on a masterpiece. While showing artistic restraint in symbols and style, Spike Lee offers a well-devised structure, which lets the strength of the story carry itself. Especially in the final act Lee's well-tuned reserve makes for a heart-felt conclusion full of poignant suggestions, as to the nature of violence. Even the innocent can be corrupted needing a vent for their endless victimisation, while the corrupt seek innocence by befriending children reminiscent of them in their youth and dreaming about a life with 'no more packing'. The ultimately compassionate Rocco, previously shown as a no nonsense cop with a strong moral compass ultimately rejects 'Justice in Black and White', deciding that even the guilty are seldom dealt justice and takes on the role of a benevolent judge and jury - the antithesis of Dirty Harry and Judge Dredd, one more attuned to understand human faults, accept them, than issue warrants. Nonetheless this self-conscious style of storytelling does backlash during build-up, as the convoluted plot mires midway with mild bouts of oversentimentilisation and underwritten character motivations, before finally hitting back with an astoundingly well-rounded finale. Nonetheless a brilliant and captivating movie, which ranks up there with Spike Lee's best with high probability of future rewatching pleasure. A big part of the success comes from disposing of the preacher like stance so predominant in many of Lee's weaker works. Albeit mostly low-key and pretty standard the most significant scenes feature sudden detachment from traditional cinematography to a more detached, surreal focus, as if suggesting a detachment from the grim everyday reality of the protagonists offering escapist release from hardships. This offers some extremely imaginative cinematography by Malik Hassan Sayeed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most of the time remains stuck between good and great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is no denying it that this is a good and well made movie but at the same time I also still had loads of problems with it! The way I see it, this is being a pretty good portrayal of live on the streets in the '90's. It picks a mostly realistic approach but still I just can't really 'feel' this movie. I never felt involved with any of the characters in it or to any of the dramatic events and developments. It doesn't make this movie bad but it does indeed make this movie a bit of a one dimensional experience. And remember, this is an 1995 movie. So everything that was considered to be hip and 'thug life' might seem a bit ridicules and less cool in today's perspective. The whole attitude and way of talking and the way everyone dresses makes this movie really a product of its time. In that regard this movie also really reminded me of "Kids", which coincidentally or not, got made in the same year as this movie. It makes this movie less relevant to watch now days but really, it's nothing I was holding against the movie. I would had most definitely preferred it if this movie was using a more straightforward style of storytelling. The movie as it is seems to be wanting to focus on far too many different characters and tries to do and tell too much. It also really has its own style to it, when it comes down to its storytelling, which was nice and helped to give this movie an unique feeling but at the same time it also made the movie unnecessary hard and not all that pleasant to follow at times. Another thing I also disliked about this movie was its pick of music. The movie mad some bad music choices, in which the music often would swell and become melodramatic at moments that really were uncalled for. It absolutely distracted and most of the time didn't suit what was happening on the screen at the time. But really, I though this movie still had some hints of a great movie in it as well. One thing was its already earlier mentioned unique and distinctive style. Spike Lee always has had an unique and distinctive style of his own and he manages to put a lot of that in this movie successfully. There are some interesting moments in this movie, from a more technical and movie-making perspective. There was some good camera-work for instance and also very little wrong with the movie its editing and pacing. The movie its story in essence also really seemed to be a solid one but I do feel that they perhaps should had picked some different perspectives to keep- and make things a bit more interesting and effective. Wouldn't this movie for instance had been better and more interesting if it told things more from the Harvey Keitel's character perspective? Who knows and it's not like the movie bad or interesting as it is right now but while watching this movie it constantly gave me the feeling it had more potential and things could had been done better. I don't know, perhaps the movie was also being a bit stuck between being a gangster movie and a more realistic one. It never felt like a true gangster flick and it never felt like a true realistic movie neither. Producer Martin Scorsese perhaps should had stepped in a bit more often, since he definitely is a kind of director who can more successfully blend realism with tough and tense gangster/crime movies. Not trying to sound too negative. The movie is good enough as it is but it doesn't ever reaches its full potential. 7/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brothers killin' other brothers ain't no big thing. Blas&eacute;, blas&eacute;.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Clockers is directed by Spike Lee who also co-adapts the screenplay with Richard Price from Price's own novel of the same name. It stars Harvey Keitel, John Turturro, Delroy Lindo, Mekhi Phifer, Isaiah Washington, Keith David, Peewee Love and Regina Taylor. Music is scored by Terence Blanchard and cinematography by Malik Hassan Sayeed. Young drug pushers in the projects of Brooklyn (Clockers) are caught between loyalty to their drug boss and the detectives out to stop them. It's not as incendiary as one might expect of a Spike Lee joint, but the director's concerns and astute knack for story telling are very prominent features. It was originally going to be a Martin Scorses film, but he chose to make Casino instead, he does, however, get a producing credit and you can see in the material why Scorsese was interested in directing. Pic is basically a take on urban drug dealing in the Brooklyn projects and the impact said dealing has on anyone who comes into contact with it. From the downward spiral of life for young men earning their pay by illegal means, to fretful mothers desperately trying to keep pe-teen kiddies from joining the ranks of what they think are cool operators, the morality of the play is forcibly rammed home by Lee. Unfortunately this comes at a cost to the white cop characters, who are too thinly drawn to offer up a law and order counter point to the illegal activity involving drugs and murder, they serve only as the "man", and damn the "man" at that. The Rocco Klein (Keitel) of the book is not evident here, sadly, while Torturo may as well not be in it! Cast performances are well in tune with the material, with Lindo as the "black godfather" turning in a scary one, and Lee's camera-work, coupled with Sayeed's moody photography, has a nifty grasp of realism. Soundtracking is soulful and pleasant. A mixed bag for sure, but it's a story that needs to be told. Bleak and brutal at times, but still offering hope, it's middle tier Spike Lee that always remains intriguing. Even if it at times feels like he was bored telling yet another "black on black is bad" message movie. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tribal Study.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this complicated tale of the pressures on Mekhi Phifer in the Brooklyn projects, director Spike Lee captures the values and the iconography of the African-American community well, as he usually does. You get a genuine sense of the simmering anger, the shifting allegiances, and the small reward system of the social world these pathetic people live in. Pfifer is the central figure and he sweats a lot. No brighter or better than he should be, he's pressured from one side into dealing cocaine by local mogul Delroy Lindo. On the other side, he's pushed by the manipulative but well-intentioned detectives Harvey Keitel and Stanley Turturro. Pfifer's handsome and upright brother is under arrest for murder but Keitel believes that Pfifer is the culprit. Pfifer's brother is simply too good, too compliant, to have done the deed. Nice ambiguity. Lee convincingly nails the diversity and solidarity of the community. It's like John Ford in the ghetto. Pfifer may be innocent of the crime of which Keitel is convinced he's guilty but he also deals dope. Keitel, for all his ploying the system, is determined to bring the guilty party to justice, though he may play a little dirty in getting the job done. And when he finds out that he's been wrong about who committed the murder, he does what such a person would do in real life. He hides his guilt behind a tirade of threats. In a way, it's an improvement over Spike Lee's "Do The Right Thing." It doesn't turn all the cops into heavies. And it doesn't end with an ominous quote from Malcolm X. The weakness of the film lies in Lee's allowing conversations to go on for too long. Pfifer gets a lot of screen time and when he's not chewing out his young brother (who will save his life) he's whining about his innocence. The exchanges, sometimes rising to shouts, go on too long and become tiring. It's a devalued life these people lead. They wear clothes and they groom themselves in ways that appeal only to those in their immediate and limited social worlds. I'm beginning to develop an idea. The more you resemble someone who is upper class and British, the more your social worth. The farther removed you are from this model, the lower your status. If you could take Pfifer, dress him in riding clothes and teach him to play polo, and have him say "eck-tually" instead of "aks," and have him grow some hair on his shaved and shiny skull, he might not be thought guilty of anything except being too polite.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oscar-worthy. Incredible film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tpaladino
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no idea why this film wasn't nominated for an Oscar, and I especially have no idea why it's been seventeen years since the film was released and I'm just now seeing it. I've always been vaguely aware of it's existence as one of the 'other' Spike Lee films, but not much more. I certainly wasn't expecting to see some of his all-time best work, which it is. This film should be mandatory viewing for every single high school in America, that's how important it is. Spike Lee paints a devastatingly realistic picture of inner-city life and the mortal perils that it's inhabitants face on a daily basis. There are no heroes, no angels, and no caricatures. It's all laid bare for the viewer to draw their own conclusion. Lee treats the audience with a level of respect and maturity that is almost unheard of in films that deal in such explosive and controversial subject matter. He trusts that the audience will understand the big picture and take away the appropriate lesson without being evangelized, and without resorting to the kind of cheap gimmickry and pandering that can often plague films of this genre. Everyone should see this film. Literally everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such an overwhelming disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johndeckbose
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm glad that Spike Lee has apparently outgrown his need for polemics. Inside Man was a wonderful mature film that focused on character and motivation far beyond the Afro-centric purview of earlier Spike films. And while Clockers is perfectly serviceable for anyone coming to the story without having read the novel, I submit that Spike's attempt to refocus Richard Price's 1992 masterpiece as a singular black story, with a bone-throwing portrayal of white Detective Rocco Klein within an indictment of white police tactics, short-changes the audience of the profound respect, balance and humanity that made Price's novel so unforgettable. It is truly one of the five best novels I have ever read, while Spike managed to produce one of 1000 best movies I have ever seen. Read the book. It will stun, shock, amaze and delight you. The movie, on the other hand, might just keep you from falling asleep.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is WEAK...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gveltman1
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although I have only seen a few of Spike Lee's films, I am already beginning to place him very low on the ladder of the best directors alive today. Clockers fails, in my opinion, because the film's premise is lacking substance to begin with; the story is lackluster to the max. On top of this, where the film had its opportunities to reel in the audience emotionally, it instead dropped the ball. Moments where energy, tension, and suspense were supposed to effused were disappointingly overridden with anticlimactic slumps in action. The choking scene in the car as well as when Mekhi is being beat up in the park, with their odd selection of music, seem unfulfilled in their potential to capitalize on emotional appeal. I will say the denouement is shot with expert precision. Lee's patented cinematographic maneuver, the double dolly, is on full display. Moreover, his use of low-key lighting in some specific scenes that illustrate the proliferation of drugs inside the projects are done in a professionally haunting manor. Unfortunately, these instances are rare, overshadowed by the weak portions previously discussed. With regards to Lee's film style in Clockers, I like to point out two of his techniques that I find terribly annoying: 1) Those stupid circling gliding shots around characters when they are talking. 2) His persistent use of intense music to compliment serious(at least Lee thinks they must be) scenes. When put together, these two devices serve to create the ultimate exaggeration of the weight a scene carries in this film. Doing a flashy gliding pan across the park accompanied by pounding sound while Tyrone's mother yells at Mekhi and his boys about his haircut is a little excessive. Instead, I think Clocker's would benefit from a greater variation in the levels of stress and emotion we experience in each scene. This way, when the film actually does come to a TRULY significant moment, the audience will become more invested in the action. P.S. I don't think anyone from the projects would actually where a complete Arizona wildcats uniform. Just the jersey, not the shorts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder mystery and race mixed into one great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Take a murder mystery story, mix it into a contemporary vulgar urban setting, then sprinkle some racial tension into the mix and you've got the highly intellectual and intense Spike Lee film Clockers. Clockers is about Strike, a young black man living in Brooklyn, dealing drugs for his ruthless drug lord Rodney Little. Strike deals drugs for the money, but all he really wants to do is hang out with his brothers in the park and play with model train sets. But things start to get rough when a night manager at a local fast food joint is murdered and Strike's brother Victor turns himself in. Det. Rocco Klein is the lead detective on the case and he doesn't buy Victor's story, which sets him on an obsessive hunt to unmask the truth behind this whole ordeal. The film is loaded with spirited yet vulgar dialouge, artistic and vibrant direction, and plenty of memorable characters. Clockers is witty, intelligent, and a lot of fun. It isn't your typical murder mystery or racial tension film. It is a beautiful blend of the two genres that turns into something very unique and very exciting. Spike Lee adds a lot of visual flair to this film and the way he directs it is something you can't quite pinpoint. The panoramic visual style is something you can't exactly describe in words and it is really something you have to see for yourself. There is something obviously unique going on in the way Lee directs this film, it is just difficult to articulate what exactly that is. But the visuals do work in a whole plethora of unique films, allowing the film to succeed on multiple levels. The film ranges from intense and gripping to quirky and fun. From one scene to the next the film grows more fun and more enthralling. Rarely do I care this much about what happens to the characters of a film and I'm not always so compelled to learn the motivations of the very well written characters of a film. All that being said I can't say that I loved the main character, Strike. The actor, Mekhi Phifer, wasn't great and the character himself had some odd moments. I eventually learned to like him and his character thankfully didn't deter too much from my liking of the film. Besides, a lot of the film actually focuses on Harvey Keitel's character and his unending search for the truth behind the murder. There are also numerous subplots that all end up being more interesting than the main character's story. It helps that this is just an all around well written film that is just smarter than your average crime film. Clockers is very different from any murder mystery crime film, as well as any racial tension film. But it provides plenty of great work on both sides of this spectrum. Spike Lee has created a visually interesting film with a fantastic story. The main character is the only low point of the film, but everything else is very good. Clockers is a very worthwhile watch for fans of Spike Lee or the multiple genres this film spans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Modern urban classic - Spike's greatest 'joint'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesxgamble
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my all-time favourite films. Director Spike Lee adapts the Richard Price Novel, set in New Jersey, to his hometown and favourite movie backdrop: Brooklyn. It is often said that films never live up to the books on which they are based, but in this case I think the movie out performs the novel. This is because the book can be slow moving at times, and the action is separated by long passages of writing. However, the film chops all of these slow parts out, and the result is a film that keeps you engaged from start to finish. Spike Lee uses music perfectly to compliment the tone and mood of each scene, be it hip-hop in the urban playground, the acoustic interludes of Seal and Des'ree, or minor key, intense jazz to accompany drug use in doorways and nooks, and the final scene's soundtrack is absolutely inspired. Delroy Lindo plays his king-pin character with such comfort, at times it is hard to imagine that he isn't that person in reality! Harvey Keitel and John Turturro work well as the detective double-team, conflicting over whether to take the easy close-by-arrest, or the moral crusade to find the truth behind the case at the heart of the film. Mekhi Phifer is impressive in many of his scenes as the central character, who keeps you guessing to the end on whether he deserves your sympathy or not. For me, Lindo's performance is the standout turn. The cinematography is luscious, and the colours and compositions make this film a visual feast. But more importantly, the natural dialogue of the film and the delivery of nearly every line really reinforce the fact that you are watching a film about real situations. Overall, I give this film my maximum rating of 9.5 stars. If you like this film, you'll love The Wire Season One, and you also might want to check out another overlooked film, Jason's Lyric.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When you don't help people because you like them, but because you hate enough their world enough to let them triumph over it ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The title might give you a hint, "Clockers" is about routine, and not the most pleasant one. Indeed, this routine is made of drug-dealing and occasional murders. And if you think that you've been desensitized enough by police procedural and gangster movies, "Clockers" will be a powerful wake-up call. Honestly, I can't recall a film that dealt so straightforwardly with real-life violence apart from David Cronenberg's "A History of Violence" but that was 10 years after ''Clockers". The opening credits set the tone. Shots of young black persons' murdered are shown, blood staining the pavement and deadpan expression proving they didn't see what was coming to them. Lee doesn't stylize for aesthetic purposes but intelligently guide our expectations, loudly shouting what gangster films timidly whispers: this is an ugly word with no redeeming appeal whatsoever. No matter what it involves, it either ends up with jail of being the unintentional poser of bloody aftermaths' pictures. And their purpose is echoed in the murder scene, where lies Darryl Adams, a restaurant manager, shot four times. The sight of the body is disturbing but no more than the total detachment of the two assigned detectives played by Harvey Keitel and John Turturro. They comment the body with shocking detachment and cynical wisecracks such as "the kid had brains" while blood spilled over a hole in his head I don't think Lee's intent is to portray these cops as racist or cynical, but to underline how routinely these murders became. This is not to brandish the 'racism' flag (Lee is above these clich&eacute;s) but to remind us that these crimes are committed within the black community. So, no matter what you'd think of the cops, they're not the ones who pulled the trigger. We're used of that ambiguity regarding racism and this is a credit to Spike Lee's co-writing with Richard Price, who wrote the original novel. "Clockers" depicts a slice of people's life that encapsulates all the factors that lead to the opening 'pictures'. And that no-way-out situation is embodied by the main protagonist, Strike (Mekhi Phifer), a clocker working for Rodney (Delroy Lindo), the crime lord of the neighborhood. His job mainly consists on standing in the park and waiting for customers coming to buy crack. The process is well-elaborated, as there is a watcher to check for cop's arrivals, but eventual strip-searches are also part of this routine. The point is that clockers are at the bottom of the hierarchy, but that's their way of living. The issue of money is another layer of subtlety the film provides. Strike doesn't use money to date girls, buy a car or new clothes. Electric trains are his hobbies. Why? Why not? But we understand that he's trapped in that job for the simple reason is that it earns him enough money to fulfill his passion. On the other hand, his brother Victor (Isaiah Washington) is a honest, two-job worker and decent father forced to constantly swallow the bitter taste of frustration while watching brothers making easy money while he gets no respect and that's his routine. These brothers live in a world where money buys enough power to ooze respect. Both feel pressure in their lives, and the result is Victor's arrest and confession that he murdered Adams, claiming it was for self-defense, but there's something wrong in that murder Keitel's character can't get off his head. The case is even more complex because it was Strike who was supposed to kill Adams, to make his bones with Rodney and climb the 'social ladder'. The seemingly fatherly affection between Rodney and Strike is finally distorted when Rodney reveals the first time he killed a man, threatened with a gun on his mouth by Errol (Thomas Jefferson Byrd) a tough killer before he became the local AIDS-stricken psycho. Like for Rodney, Strike had to have blood on his hands, the point of no-return meaning trust. So, we get it, there are no feelings in such a dirty business. And as the investigation proceeds, Keitel gets more and more interested in Strike's case and wonder why he'd let his brother covering him, and why would a man like Victor kill Adams in the first place? To spare Strike the burden of belonging to Rodney, and in the process, vent all his anger? The procedural leaves to a satisfying resolution but it wasn't "Clockers' main point. The film is more about complex human interactions, because while Keitel and Phifer get closer one another, their mutual affection feel more real and genuine than with Rodney, and might pave the road to Strike's redemption. I know this 'redemption' word is kind of hackneyed, but I know Scorsese co-produced the film, and I felt some intense Scorsesian vibes in that gritty depiction of an underworld and the torment poisoning the main character's life, in the real meaning of the world since Strike is also victim of chronicle ulcer that gets bloodier as the film progresses, like a metaphor of his moral downfall and an imminent deadly conclusion. But there's a third significant character to enrich the film: Tyrone, a kid who admires Strike and imitates him to the point of shaving his head and wearing the same clothes. The kid is a younger version of Strike with Strike playing Rodney's mentor role, and ironically, the disciple shows more zeal and competence than his master. Tyrone's arc is a light of hope illuminating possible ways out of the hell given you don't act like people acted with you. Tyrone evolves from the embodiment of Strike's disgrace to his redemption. And Strike is given the same chance, the possibility to count on people who don't help him because they like him, but because they hate that world enough to triumph over it by getting someone out of it. Indeed, there might be a right way and a wrong way but when trapped in such blinding routine, everybody needs a sign, or guidance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Justice is never black and white
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dope dealing on the Nelson Mandela projects in Brooklyn is the everyday bread of local hoodlum Ronald Dunham aka Strike (Mekhi Phifer). Staking the local park the line of work is relentlessly stressful causing a stress-induced ulcer, which he deals with by drinking down yoo-hoos by the litres. At night respite is found in the form of a trainset hobby, an voyeuristic escape from the reality he has accepted. When his boss Rodney Little (Delroy Lindo) hints towards the necessity of cropping one of his less trustworthy workers Strike confides to his brother Victor (Isaiah Washington). Soon after the murder is committed and Victor steps up to claim self defence. However hardliner detective Rocco Klein (Harvey Keitel) quickly assumes this is a cover up for the true culprit. One of Spike Lee's most accomplished works and a worryingly underrated gem bordering on a masterpiece. While showing artistic restraint in symbols and style, Spike Lee offers a well-devised structure, which lets the strength of the story carry itself. Especially in the final act Lee's well-tuned reserve makes for a heart-felt conclusion full of poignant suggestions, as to the nature of violence. Even the innocent can be corrupted needing a vent for their endless victimisation, while the corrupt seek innocence by befriending children reminiscent of them in their youth and dreaming about a life with 'no more packing'. The ultimately compassionate Rocco, previously shown as a no nonsense cop with a strong moral compass ultimately rejects 'Justice in Black and White', deciding that even the guilty are seldom dealt justice and takes on the role of a benevolent judge and jury - the antithesis of Dirty Harry and Judge Dredd, one more attuned to understand human faults, accept them, than issue warrants. Nonetheless this self-conscious style of storytelling does backlash during build-up, as the convoluted plot mires midway with mild bouts of oversentimentilisation and underwritten character motivations, before finally hitting back with an astoundingly well-rounded finale. Nonetheless a brilliant and captivating movie, which ranks up there with Spike Lee's best with high probability of future rewatching pleasure. A big part of the success comes from disposing of the preacher like stance so predominant in many of Lee's weaker works. Albeit mostly low-key and pretty standard the most significant scenes feature sudden detachment from traditional cinematography to a more detached, surreal focus, as if suggesting a detachment from the grim everyday reality of the protagonists offering escapist release from hardships. This offers some extremely imaginative cinematography by Malik Hassan Sayeed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most of the time remains stuck between good and great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is no denying it that this is a good and well made movie but at the same time I also still had loads of problems with it! The way I see it, this is being a pretty good portrayal of live on the streets in the '90's. It picks a mostly realistic approach but still I just can't really 'feel' this movie. I never felt involved with any of the characters in it or to any of the dramatic events and developments. It doesn't make this movie bad but it does indeed make this movie a bit of a one dimensional experience. And remember, this is an 1995 movie. So everything that was considered to be hip and 'thug life' might seem a bit ridicules and less cool in today's perspective. The whole attitude and way of talking and the way everyone dresses makes this movie really a product of its time. In that regard this movie also really reminded me of "Kids", which coincidentally or not, got made in the same year as this movie. It makes this movie less relevant to watch now days but really, it's nothing I was holding against the movie. I would had most definitely preferred it if this movie was using a more straightforward style of storytelling. The movie as it is seems to be wanting to focus on far too many different characters and tries to do and tell too much. It also really has its own style to it, when it comes down to its storytelling, which was nice and helped to give this movie an unique feeling but at the same time it also made the movie unnecessary hard and not all that pleasant to follow at times. Another thing I also disliked about this movie was its pick of music. The movie mad some bad music choices, in which the music often would swell and become melodramatic at moments that really were uncalled for. It absolutely distracted and most of the time didn't suit what was happening on the screen at the time. But really, I though this movie still had some hints of a great movie in it as well. One thing was its already earlier mentioned unique and distinctive style. Spike Lee always has had an unique and distinctive style of his own and he manages to put a lot of that in this movie successfully. There are some interesting moments in this movie, from a more technical and movie-making perspective. There was some good camera-work for instance and also very little wrong with the movie its editing and pacing. The movie its story in essence also really seemed to be a solid one but I do feel that they perhaps should had picked some different perspectives to keep- and make things a bit more interesting and effective. Wouldn't this movie for instance had been better and more interesting if it told things more from the Harvey Keitel's character perspective? Who knows and it's not like the movie bad or interesting as it is right now but while watching this movie it constantly gave me the feeling it had more potential and things could had been done better. I don't know, perhaps the movie was also being a bit stuck between being a gangster movie and a more realistic one. It never felt like a true gangster flick and it never felt like a true realistic movie neither. Producer Martin Scorsese perhaps should had stepped in a bit more often, since he definitely is a kind of director who can more successfully blend realism with tough and tense gangster/crime movies. Not trying to sound too negative. The movie is good enough as it is but it doesn't ever reaches its full potential. 7/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brothers killin' other brothers ain't no big thing. Blas&eacute;, blas&eacute;.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Clockers is directed by Spike Lee who also co-adapts the screenplay with Richard Price from Price's own novel of the same name. It stars Harvey Keitel, John Turturro, Delroy Lindo, Mekhi Phifer, Isaiah Washington, Keith David, Peewee Love and Regina Taylor. Music is scored by Terence Blanchard and cinematography by Malik Hassan Sayeed. Young drug pushers in the projects of Brooklyn (Clockers) are caught between loyalty to their drug boss and the detectives out to stop them. It's not as incendiary as one might expect of a Spike Lee joint, but the director's concerns and astute knack for story telling are very prominent features. It was originally going to be a Martin Scorses film, but he chose to make Casino instead, he does, however, get a producing credit and you can see in the material why Scorsese was interested in directing. Pic is basically a take on urban drug dealing in the Brooklyn projects and the impact said dealing has on anyone who comes into contact with it. From the downward spiral of life for young men earning their pay by illegal means, to fretful mothers desperately trying to keep pe-teen kiddies from joining the ranks of what they think are cool operators, the morality of the play is forcibly rammed home by Lee. Unfortunately this comes at a cost to the white cop characters, who are too thinly drawn to offer up a law and order counter point to the illegal activity involving drugs and murder, they serve only as the "man", and damn the "man" at that. The Rocco Klein (Keitel) of the book is not evident here, sadly, while Torturo may as well not be in it! Cast performances are well in tune with the material, with Lindo as the "black godfather" turning in a scary one, and Lee's camera-work, coupled with Sayeed's moody photography, has a nifty grasp of realism. Soundtracking is soulful and pleasant. A mixed bag for sure, but it's a story that needs to be told. Bleak and brutal at times, but still offering hope, it's middle tier Spike Lee that always remains intriguing. Even if it at times feels like he was bored telling yet another "black on black is bad" message movie. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tribal Study.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this complicated tale of the pressures on Mekhi Phifer in the Brooklyn projects, director Spike Lee captures the values and the iconography of the African-American community well, as he usually does. You get a genuine sense of the simmering anger, the shifting allegiances, and the small reward system of the social world these pathetic people live in. Pfifer is the central figure and he sweats a lot. No brighter or better than he should be, he's pressured from one side into dealing cocaine by local mogul Delroy Lindo. On the other side, he's pushed by the manipulative but well-intentioned detectives Harvey Keitel and Stanley Turturro. Pfifer's handsome and upright brother is under arrest for murder but Keitel believes that Pfifer is the culprit. Pfifer's brother is simply too good, too compliant, to have done the deed. Nice ambiguity. Lee convincingly nails the diversity and solidarity of the community. It's like John Ford in the ghetto. Pfifer may be innocent of the crime of which Keitel is convinced he's guilty but he also deals dope. Keitel, for all his ploying the system, is determined to bring the guilty party to justice, though he may play a little dirty in getting the job done. And when he finds out that he's been wrong about who committed the murder, he does what such a person would do in real life. He hides his guilt behind a tirade of threats. In a way, it's an improvement over Spike Lee's "Do The Right Thing." It doesn't turn all the cops into heavies. And it doesn't end with an ominous quote from Malcolm X. The weakness of the film lies in Lee's allowing conversations to go on for too long. Pfifer gets a lot of screen time and when he's not chewing out his young brother (who will save his life) he's whining about his innocence. The exchanges, sometimes rising to shouts, go on too long and become tiring. It's a devalued life these people lead. They wear clothes and they groom themselves in ways that appeal only to those in their immediate and limited social worlds. I'm beginning to develop an idea. The more you resemble someone who is upper class and British, the more your social worth. The farther removed you are from this model, the lower your status. If you could take Pfifer, dress him in riding clothes and teach him to play polo, and have him say "eck-tually" instead of "aks," and have him grow some hair on his shaved and shiny skull, he might not be thought guilty of anything except being too polite.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oscar-worthy. Incredible film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tpaladino
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no idea why this film wasn't nominated for an Oscar, and I especially have no idea why it's been seventeen years since the film was released and I'm just now seeing it. I've always been vaguely aware of it's existence as one of the 'other' Spike Lee films, but not much more. I certainly wasn't expecting to see some of his all-time best work, which it is. This film should be mandatory viewing for every single high school in America, that's how important it is. Spike Lee paints a devastatingly realistic picture of inner-city life and the mortal perils that it's inhabitants face on a daily basis. There are no heroes, no angels, and no caricatures. It's all laid bare for the viewer to draw their own conclusion. Lee treats the audience with a level of respect and maturity that is almost unheard of in films that deal in such explosive and controversial subject matter. He trusts that the audience will understand the big picture and take away the appropriate lesson without being evangelized, and without resorting to the kind of cheap gimmickry and pandering that can often plague films of this genre. Everyone should see this film. Literally everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such an overwhelming disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johndeckbose
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm glad that Spike Lee has apparently outgrown his need for polemics. Inside Man was a wonderful mature film that focused on character and motivation far beyond the Afro-centric purview of earlier Spike films. And while Clockers is perfectly serviceable for anyone coming to the story without having read the novel, I submit that Spike's attempt to refocus Richard Price's 1992 masterpiece as a singular black story, with a bone-throwing portrayal of white Detective Rocco Klein within an indictment of white police tactics, short-changes the audience of the profound respect, balance and humanity that made Price's novel so unforgettable. It is truly one of the five best novels I have ever read, while Spike managed to produce one of 1000 best movies I have ever seen. Read the book. It will stun, shock, amaze and delight you. The movie, on the other hand, might just keep you from falling asleep.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is WEAK...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gveltman1
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although I have only seen a few of Spike Lee's films, I am already beginning to place him very low on the ladder of the best directors alive today. Clockers fails, in my opinion, because the film's premise is lacking substance to begin with; the story is lackluster to the max. On top of this, where the film had its opportunities to reel in the audience emotionally, it instead dropped the ball. Moments where energy, tension, and suspense were supposed to effused were disappointingly overridden with anticlimactic slumps in action. The choking scene in the car as well as when Mekhi is being beat up in the park, with their odd selection of music, seem unfulfilled in their potential to capitalize on emotional appeal. I will say the denouement is shot with expert precision. Lee's patented cinematographic maneuver, the double dolly, is on full display. Moreover, his use of low-key lighting in some specific scenes that illustrate the proliferation of drugs inside the projects are done in a professionally haunting manor. Unfortunately, these instances are rare, overshadowed by the weak portions previously discussed. With regards to Lee's film style in Clockers, I like to point out two of his techniques that I find terribly annoying: 1) Those stupid circling gliding shots around characters when they are talking. 2) His persistent use of intense music to compliment serious(at least Lee thinks they must be) scenes. When put together, these two devices serve to create the ultimate exaggeration of the weight a scene carries in this film. Doing a flashy gliding pan across the park accompanied by pounding sound while Tyrone's mother yells at Mekhi and his boys about his haircut is a little excessive. Instead, I think Clocker's would benefit from a greater variation in the levels of stress and emotion we experience in each scene. This way, when the film actually does come to a TRULY significant moment, the audience will become more invested in the action. P.S. I don't think anyone from the projects would actually where a complete Arizona wildcats uniform. Just the jersey, not the shorts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder mystery and race mixed into one great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Take a murder mystery story, mix it into a contemporary vulgar urban setting, then sprinkle some racial tension into the mix and you've got the highly intellectual and intense Spike Lee film Clockers. Clockers is about Strike, a young black man living in Brooklyn, dealing drugs for his ruthless drug lord Rodney Little. Strike deals drugs for the money, but all he really wants to do is hang out with his brothers in the park and play with model train sets. But things start to get rough when a night manager at a local fast food joint is murdered and Strike's brother Victor turns himself in. Det. Rocco Klein is the lead detective on the case and he doesn't buy Victor's story, which sets him on an obsessive hunt to unmask the truth behind this whole ordeal. The film is loaded with spirited yet vulgar dialouge, artistic and vibrant direction, and plenty of memorable characters. Clockers is witty, intelligent, and a lot of fun. It isn't your typical murder mystery or racial tension film. It is a beautiful blend of the two genres that turns into something very unique and very exciting. Spike Lee adds a lot of visual flair to this film and the way he directs it is something you can't quite pinpoint. The panoramic visual style is something you can't exactly describe in words and it is really something you have to see for yourself. There is something obviously unique going on in the way Lee directs this film, it is just difficult to articulate what exactly that is. But the visuals do work in a whole plethora of unique films, allowing the film to succeed on multiple levels. The film ranges from intense and gripping to quirky and fun. From one scene to the next the film grows more fun and more enthralling. Rarely do I care this much about what happens to the characters of a film and I'm not always so compelled to learn the motivations of the very well written characters of a film. All that being said I can't say that I loved the main character, Strike. The actor, Mekhi Phifer, wasn't great and the character himself had some odd moments. I eventually learned to like him and his character thankfully didn't deter too much from my liking of the film. Besides, a lot of the film actually focuses on Harvey Keitel's character and his unending search for the truth behind the murder. There are also numerous subplots that all end up being more interesting than the main character's story. It helps that this is just an all around well written film that is just smarter than your average crime film. Clockers is very different from any murder mystery crime film, as well as any racial tension film. But it provides plenty of great work on both sides of this spectrum. Spike Lee has created a visually interesting film with a fantastic story. The main character is the only low point of the film, but everything else is very good. Clockers is a very worthwhile watch for fans of Spike Lee or the multiple genres this film spans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Modern urban classic - Spike's greatest 'joint'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesxgamble
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my all-time favourite films. Director Spike Lee adapts the Richard Price Novel, set in New Jersey, to his hometown and favourite movie backdrop: Brooklyn. It is often said that films never live up to the books on which they are based, but in this case I think the movie out performs the novel. This is because the book can be slow moving at times, and the action is separated by long passages of writing. However, the film chops all of these slow parts out, and the result is a film that keeps you engaged from start to finish. Spike Lee uses music perfectly to compliment the tone and mood of each scene, be it hip-hop in the urban playground, the acoustic interludes of Seal and Des'ree, or minor key, intense jazz to accompany drug use in doorways and nooks, and the final scene's soundtrack is absolutely inspired. Delroy Lindo plays his king-pin character with such comfort, at times it is hard to imagine that he isn't that person in reality! Harvey Keitel and John Turturro work well as the detective double-team, conflicting over whether to take the easy close-by-arrest, or the moral crusade to find the truth behind the case at the heart of the film. Mekhi Phifer is impressive in many of his scenes as the central character, who keeps you guessing to the end on whether he deserves your sympathy or not. For me, Lindo's performance is the standout turn. The cinematography is luscious, and the colours and compositions make this film a visual feast. But more importantly, the natural dialogue of the film and the delivery of nearly every line really reinforce the fact that you are watching a film about real situations. Overall, I give this film my maximum rating of 9.5 stars. If you like this film, you'll love The Wire Season One, and you also might want to check out another overlooked film, Jason's Lyric.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When you don't help people because you like them, but because you hate enough their world enough to let them triumph over it ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The title might give you a hint, "Clockers" is about routine, and not the most pleasant one. Indeed, this routine is made of drug-dealing and occasional murders. And if you think that you've been desensitized enough by police procedural and gangster movies, "Clockers" will be a powerful wake-up call. Honestly, I can't recall a film that dealt so straightforwardly with real-life violence apart from David Cronenberg's "A History of Violence" but that was 10 years after ''Clockers". The opening credits set the tone. Shots of young black persons' murdered are shown, blood staining the pavement and deadpan expression proving they didn't see what was coming to them. Lee doesn't stylize for aesthetic purposes but intelligently guide our expectations, loudly shouting what gangster films timidly whispers: this is an ugly word with no redeeming appeal whatsoever. No matter what it involves, it either ends up with jail of being the unintentional poser of bloody aftermaths' pictures. And their purpose is echoed in the murder scene, where lies Darryl Adams, a restaurant manager, shot four times. The sight of the body is disturbing but no more than the total detachment of the two assigned detectives played by Harvey Keitel and John Turturro. They comment the body with shocking detachment and cynical wisecracks such as "the kid had brains" while blood spilled over a hole in his head I don't think Lee's intent is to portray these cops as racist or cynical, but to underline how routinely these murders became. This is not to brandish the 'racism' flag (Lee is above these clich&eacute;s) but to remind us that these crimes are committed within the black community. So, no matter what you'd think of the cops, they're not the ones who pulled the trigger. We're used of that ambiguity regarding racism and this is a credit to Spike Lee's co-writing with Richard Price, who wrote the original novel. "Clockers" depicts a slice of people's life that encapsulates all the factors that lead to the opening 'pictures'. And that no-way-out situation is embodied by the main protagonist, Strike (Mekhi Phifer), a clocker working for Rodney (Delroy Lindo), the crime lord of the neighborhood. His job mainly consists on standing in the park and waiting for customers coming to buy crack. The process is well-elaborated, as there is a watcher to check for cop's arrivals, but eventual strip-searches are also part of this routine. The point is that clockers are at the bottom of the hierarchy, but that's their way of living. The issue of money is another layer of subtlety the film provides. Strike doesn't use money to date girls, buy a car or new clothes. Electric trains are his hobbies. Why? Why not? But we understand that he's trapped in that job for the simple reason is that it earns him enough money to fulfill his passion. On the other hand, his brother Victor (Isaiah Washington) is a honest, two-job worker and decent father forced to constantly swallow the bitter taste of frustration while watching brothers making easy money while he gets no respect and that's his routine. These brothers live in a world where money buys enough power to ooze respect. Both feel pressure in their lives, and the result is Victor's arrest and confession that he murdered Adams, claiming it was for self-defense, but there's something wrong in that murder Keitel's character can't get off his head. The case is even more complex because it was Strike who was supposed to kill Adams, to make his bones with Rodney and climb the 'social ladder'. The seemingly fatherly affection between Rodney and Strike is finally distorted when Rodney reveals the first time he killed a man, threatened with a gun on his mouth by Errol (Thomas Jefferson Byrd) a tough killer before he became the local AIDS-stricken psycho. Like for Rodney, Strike had to have blood on his hands, the point of no-return meaning trust. So, we get it, there are no feelings in such a dirty business. And as the investigation proceeds, Keitel gets more and more interested in Strike's case and wonder why he'd let his brother covering him, and why would a man like Victor kill Adams in the first place? To spare Strike the burden of belonging to Rodney, and in the process, vent all his anger? The procedural leaves to a satisfying resolution but it wasn't "Clockers' main point. The film is more about complex human interactions, because while Keitel and Phifer get closer one another, their mutual affection feel more real and genuine than with Rodney, and might pave the road to Strike's redemption. I know this 'redemption' word is kind of hackneyed, but I know Scorsese co-produced the film, and I felt some intense Scorsesian vibes in that gritty depiction of an underworld and the torment poisoning the main character's life, in the real meaning of the world since Strike is also victim of chronicle ulcer that gets bloodier as the film progresses, like a metaphor of his moral downfall and an imminent deadly conclusion. But there's a third significant character to enrich the film: Tyrone, a kid who admires Strike and imitates him to the point of shaving his head and wearing the same clothes. The kid is a younger version of Strike with Strike playing Rodney's mentor role, and ironically, the disciple shows more zeal and competence than his master. Tyrone's arc is a light of hope illuminating possible ways out of the hell given you don't act like people acted with you. Tyrone evolves from the embodiment of Strike's disgrace to his redemption. And Strike is given the same chance, the possibility to count on people who don't help him because they like him, but because they hate that world enough to triumph over it by getting someone out of it. Indeed, there might be a right way and a wrong way but when trapped in such blinding routine, everybody needs a sign, or guidance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Justice is never black and white
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dope dealing on the Nelson Mandela projects in Brooklyn is the everyday bread of local hoodlum Ronald Dunham aka Strike (Mekhi Phifer). Staking the local park the line of work is relentlessly stressful causing a stress-induced ulcer, which he deals with by drinking down yoo-hoos by the litres. At night respite is found in the form of a trainset hobby, an voyeuristic escape from the reality he has accepted. When his boss Rodney Little (Delroy Lindo) hints towards the necessity of cropping one of his less trustworthy workers Strike confides to his brother Victor (Isaiah Washington). Soon after the murder is committed and Victor steps up to claim self defence. However hardliner detective Rocco Klein (Harvey Keitel) quickly assumes this is a cover up for the true culprit. One of Spike Lee's most accomplished works and a worryingly underrated gem bordering on a masterpiece. While showing artistic restraint in symbols and style, Spike Lee offers a well-devised structure, which lets the strength of the story carry itself. Especially in the final act Lee's well-tuned reserve makes for a heart-felt conclusion full of poignant suggestions, as to the nature of violence. Even the innocent can be corrupted needing a vent for their endless victimisation, while the corrupt seek innocence by befriending children reminiscent of them in their youth and dreaming about a life with 'no more packing'. The ultimately compassionate Rocco, previously shown as a no nonsense cop with a strong moral compass ultimately rejects 'Justice in Black and White', deciding that even the guilty are seldom dealt justice and takes on the role of a benevolent judge and jury - the antithesis of Dirty Harry and Judge Dredd, one more attuned to understand human faults, accept them, than issue warrants. Nonetheless this self-conscious style of storytelling does backlash during build-up, as the convoluted plot mires midway with mild bouts of oversentimentilisation and underwritten character motivations, before finally hitting back with an astoundingly well-rounded finale. Nonetheless a brilliant and captivating movie, which ranks up there with Spike Lee's best with high probability of future rewatching pleasure. A big part of the success comes from disposing of the preacher like stance so predominant in many of Lee's weaker works. Albeit mostly low-key and pretty standard the most significant scenes feature sudden detachment from traditional cinematography to a more detached, surreal focus, as if suggesting a detachment from the grim everyday reality of the protagonists offering escapist release from hardships. This offers some extremely imaginative cinematography by Malik Hassan Sayeed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most of the time remains stuck between good and great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is no denying it that this is a good and well made movie but at the same time I also still had loads of problems with it! The way I see it, this is being a pretty good portrayal of live on the streets in the '90's. It picks a mostly realistic approach but still I just can't really 'feel' this movie. I never felt involved with any of the characters in it or to any of the dramatic events and developments. It doesn't make this movie bad but it does indeed make this movie a bit of a one dimensional experience. And remember, this is an 1995 movie. So everything that was considered to be hip and 'thug life' might seem a bit ridicules and less cool in today's perspective. The whole attitude and way of talking and the way everyone dresses makes this movie really a product of its time. In that regard this movie also really reminded me of "Kids", which coincidentally or not, got made in the same year as this movie. It makes this movie less relevant to watch now days but really, it's nothing I was holding against the movie. I would had most definitely preferred it if this movie was using a more straightforward style of storytelling. The movie as it is seems to be wanting to focus on far too many different characters and tries to do and tell too much. It also really has its own style to it, when it comes down to its storytelling, which was nice and helped to give this movie an unique feeling but at the same time it also made the movie unnecessary hard and not all that pleasant to follow at times. Another thing I also disliked about this movie was its pick of music. The movie mad some bad music choices, in which the music often would swell and become melodramatic at moments that really were uncalled for. It absolutely distracted and most of the time didn't suit what was happening on the screen at the time. But really, I though this movie still had some hints of a great movie in it as well. One thing was its already earlier mentioned unique and distinctive style. Spike Lee always has had an unique and distinctive style of his own and he manages to put a lot of that in this movie successfully. There are some interesting moments in this movie, from a more technical and movie-making perspective. There was some good camera-work for instance and also very little wrong with the movie its editing and pacing. The movie its story in essence also really seemed to be a solid one but I do feel that they perhaps should had picked some different perspectives to keep- and make things a bit more interesting and effective. Wouldn't this movie for instance had been better and more interesting if it told things more from the Harvey Keitel's character perspective? Who knows and it's not like the movie bad or interesting as it is right now but while watching this movie it constantly gave me the feeling it had more potential and things could had been done better. I don't know, perhaps the movie was also being a bit stuck between being a gangster movie and a more realistic one. It never felt like a true gangster flick and it never felt like a true realistic movie neither. Producer Martin Scorsese perhaps should had stepped in a bit more often, since he definitely is a kind of director who can more successfully blend realism with tough and tense gangster/crime movies. Not trying to sound too negative. The movie is good enough as it is but it doesn't ever reaches its full potential. 7/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brothers killin' other brothers ain't no big thing. Blas&eacute;, blas&eacute;.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Clockers is directed by Spike Lee who also co-adapts the screenplay with Richard Price from Price's own novel of the same name. It stars Harvey Keitel, John Turturro, Delroy Lindo, Mekhi Phifer, Isaiah Washington, Keith David, Peewee Love and Regina Taylor. Music is scored by Terence Blanchard and cinematography by Malik Hassan Sayeed. Young drug pushers in the projects of Brooklyn (Clockers) are caught between loyalty to their drug boss and the detectives out to stop them. It's not as incendiary as one might expect of a Spike Lee joint, but the director's concerns and astute knack for story telling are very prominent features. It was originally going to be a Martin Scorses film, but he chose to make Casino instead, he does, however, get a producing credit and you can see in the material why Scorsese was interested in directing. Pic is basically a take on urban drug dealing in the Brooklyn projects and the impact said dealing has on anyone who comes into contact with it. From the downward spiral of life for young men earning their pay by illegal means, to fretful mothers desperately trying to keep pe-teen kiddies from joining the ranks of what they think are cool operators, the morality of the play is forcibly rammed home by Lee. Unfortunately this comes at a cost to the white cop characters, who are too thinly drawn to offer up a law and order counter point to the illegal activity involving drugs and murder, they serve only as the "man", and damn the "man" at that. The Rocco Klein (Keitel) of the book is not evident here, sadly, while Torturo may as well not be in it! Cast performances are well in tune with the material, with Lindo as the "black godfather" turning in a scary one, and Lee's camera-work, coupled with Sayeed's moody photography, has a nifty grasp of realism. Soundtracking is soulful and pleasant. A mixed bag for sure, but it's a story that needs to be told. Bleak and brutal at times, but still offering hope, it's middle tier Spike Lee that always remains intriguing. Even if it at times feels like he was bored telling yet another "black on black is bad" message movie. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tribal Study.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this complicated tale of the pressures on Mekhi Phifer in the Brooklyn projects, director Spike Lee captures the values and the iconography of the African-American community well, as he usually does. You get a genuine sense of the simmering anger, the shifting allegiances, and the small reward system of the social world these pathetic people live in. Pfifer is the central figure and he sweats a lot. No brighter or better than he should be, he's pressured from one side into dealing cocaine by local mogul Delroy Lindo. On the other side, he's pushed by the manipulative but well-intentioned detectives Harvey Keitel and Stanley Turturro. Pfifer's handsome and upright brother is under arrest for murder but Keitel believes that Pfifer is the culprit. Pfifer's brother is simply too good, too compliant, to have done the deed. Nice ambiguity. Lee convincingly nails the diversity and solidarity of the community. It's like John Ford in the ghetto. Pfifer may be innocent of the crime of which Keitel is convinced he's guilty but he also deals dope. Keitel, for all his ploying the system, is determined to bring the guilty party to justice, though he may play a little dirty in getting the job done. And when he finds out that he's been wrong about who committed the murder, he does what such a person would do in real life. He hides his guilt behind a tirade of threats. In a way, it's an improvement over Spike Lee's "Do The Right Thing." It doesn't turn all the cops into heavies. And it doesn't end with an ominous quote from Malcolm X. The weakness of the film lies in Lee's allowing conversations to go on for too long. Pfifer gets a lot of screen time and when he's not chewing out his young brother (who will save his life) he's whining about his innocence. The exchanges, sometimes rising to shouts, go on too long and become tiring. It's a devalued life these people lead. They wear clothes and they groom themselves in ways that appeal only to those in their immediate and limited social worlds. I'm beginning to develop an idea. The more you resemble someone who is upper class and British, the more your social worth. The farther removed you are from this model, the lower your status. If you could take Pfifer, dress him in riding clothes and teach him to play polo, and have him say "eck-tually" instead of "aks," and have him grow some hair on his shaved and shiny skull, he might not be thought guilty of anything except being too polite.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oscar-worthy. Incredible film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tpaladino
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no idea why this film wasn't nominated for an Oscar, and I especially have no idea why it's been seventeen years since the film was released and I'm just now seeing it. I've always been vaguely aware of it's existence as one of the 'other' Spike Lee films, but not much more. I certainly wasn't expecting to see some of his all-time best work, which it is. This film should be mandatory viewing for every single high school in America, that's how important it is. Spike Lee paints a devastatingly realistic picture of inner-city life and the mortal perils that it's inhabitants face on a daily basis. There are no heroes, no angels, and no caricatures. It's all laid bare for the viewer to draw their own conclusion. Lee treats the audience with a level of respect and maturity that is almost unheard of in films that deal in such explosive and controversial subject matter. He trusts that the audience will understand the big picture and take away the appropriate lesson without being evangelized, and without resorting to the kind of cheap gimmickry and pandering that can often plague films of this genre. Everyone should see this film. Literally everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such an overwhelming disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johndeckbose
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm glad that Spike Lee has apparently outgrown his need for polemics. Inside Man was a wonderful mature film that focused on character and motivation far beyond the Afro-centric purview of earlier Spike films. And while Clockers is perfectly serviceable for anyone coming to the story without having read the novel, I submit that Spike's attempt to refocus Richard Price's 1992 masterpiece as a singular black story, with a bone-throwing portrayal of white Detective Rocco Klein within an indictment of white police tactics, short-changes the audience of the profound respect, balance and humanity that made Price's novel so unforgettable. It is truly one of the five best novels I have ever read, while Spike managed to produce one of 1000 best movies I have ever seen. Read the book. It will stun, shock, amaze and delight you. The movie, on the other hand, might just keep you from falling asleep.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is WEAK...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gveltman1
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although I have only seen a few of Spike Lee's films, I am already beginning to place him very low on the ladder of the best directors alive today. Clockers fails, in my opinion, because the film's premise is lacking substance to begin with; the story is lackluster to the max. On top of this, where the film had its opportunities to reel in the audience emotionally, it instead dropped the ball. Moments where energy, tension, and suspense were supposed to effused were disappointingly overridden with anticlimactic slumps in action. The choking scene in the car as well as when Mekhi is being beat up in the park, with their odd selection of music, seem unfulfilled in their potential to capitalize on emotional appeal. I will say the denouement is shot with expert precision. Lee's patented cinematographic maneuver, the double dolly, is on full display. Moreover, his use of low-key lighting in some specific scenes that illustrate the proliferation of drugs inside the projects are done in a professionally haunting manor. Unfortunately, these instances are rare, overshadowed by the weak portions previously discussed. With regards to Lee's film style in Clockers, I like to point out two of his techniques that I find terribly annoying: 1) Those stupid circling gliding shots around characters when they are talking. 2) His persistent use of intense music to compliment serious(at least Lee thinks they must be) scenes. When put together, these two devices serve to create the ultimate exaggeration of the weight a scene carries in this film. Doing a flashy gliding pan across the park accompanied by pounding sound while Tyrone's mother yells at Mekhi and his boys about his haircut is a little excessive. Instead, I think Clocker's would benefit from a greater variation in the levels of stress and emotion we experience in each scene. This way, when the film actually does come to a TRULY significant moment, the audience will become more invested in the action. P.S. I don't think anyone from the projects would actually where a complete Arizona wildcats uniform. Just the jersey, not the shorts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder mystery and race mixed into one great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Take a murder mystery story, mix it into a contemporary vulgar urban setting, then sprinkle some racial tension into the mix and you've got the highly intellectual and intense Spike Lee film Clockers. Clockers is about Strike, a young black man living in Brooklyn, dealing drugs for his ruthless drug lord Rodney Little. Strike deals drugs for the money, but all he really wants to do is hang out with his brothers in the park and play with model train sets. But things start to get rough when a night manager at a local fast food joint is murdered and Strike's brother Victor turns himself in. Det. Rocco Klein is the lead detective on the case and he doesn't buy Victor's story, which sets him on an obsessive hunt to unmask the truth behind this whole ordeal. The film is loaded with spirited yet vulgar dialouge, artistic and vibrant direction, and plenty of memorable characters. Clockers is witty, intelligent, and a lot of fun. It isn't your typical murder mystery or racial tension film. It is a beautiful blend of the two genres that turns into something very unique and very exciting. Spike Lee adds a lot of visual flair to this film and the way he directs it is something you can't quite pinpoint. The panoramic visual style is something you can't exactly describe in words and it is really something you have to see for yourself. There is something obviously unique going on in the way Lee directs this film, it is just difficult to articulate what exactly that is. But the visuals do work in a whole plethora of unique films, allowing the film to succeed on multiple levels. The film ranges from intense and gripping to quirky and fun. From one scene to the next the film grows more fun and more enthralling. Rarely do I care this much about what happens to the characters of a film and I'm not always so compelled to learn the motivations of the very well written characters of a film. All that being said I can't say that I loved the main character, Strike. The actor, Mekhi Phifer, wasn't great and the character himself had some odd moments. I eventually learned to like him and his character thankfully didn't deter too much from my liking of the film. Besides, a lot of the film actually focuses on Harvey Keitel's character and his unending search for the truth behind the murder. There are also numerous subplots that all end up being more interesting than the main character's story. It helps that this is just an all around well written film that is just smarter than your average crime film. Clockers is very different from any murder mystery crime film, as well as any racial tension film. But it provides plenty of great work on both sides of this spectrum. Spike Lee has created a visually interesting film with a fantastic story. The main character is the only low point of the film, but everything else is very good. Clockers is a very worthwhile watch for fans of Spike Lee or the multiple genres this film spans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Modern urban classic - Spike's greatest 'joint'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesxgamble
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my all-time favourite films. Director Spike Lee adapts the Richard Price Novel, set in New Jersey, to his hometown and favourite movie backdrop: Brooklyn. It is often said that films never live up to the books on which they are based, but in this case I think the movie out performs the novel. This is because the book can be slow moving at times, and the action is separated by long passages of writing. However, the film chops all of these slow parts out, and the result is a film that keeps you engaged from start to finish. Spike Lee uses music perfectly to compliment the tone and mood of each scene, be it hip-hop in the urban playground, the acoustic interludes of Seal and Des'ree, or minor key, intense jazz to accompany drug use in doorways and nooks, and the final scene's soundtrack is absolutely inspired. Delroy Lindo plays his king-pin character with such comfort, at times it is hard to imagine that he isn't that person in reality! Harvey Keitel and John Turturro work well as the detective double-team, conflicting over whether to take the easy close-by-arrest, or the moral crusade to find the truth behind the case at the heart of the film. Mekhi Phifer is impressive in many of his scenes as the central character, who keeps you guessing to the end on whether he deserves your sympathy or not. For me, Lindo's performance is the standout turn. The cinematography is luscious, and the colours and compositions make this film a visual feast. But more importantly, the natural dialogue of the film and the delivery of nearly every line really reinforce the fact that you are watching a film about real situations. Overall, I give this film my maximum rating of 9.5 stars. If you like this film, you'll love The Wire Season One, and you also might want to check out another overlooked film, Jason's Lyric.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When you don't help people because you like them, but because you hate enough their world enough to let them triumph over it ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The title might give you a hint, "Clockers" is about routine, and not the most pleasant one. Indeed, this routine is made of drug-dealing and occasional murders. And if you think that you've been desensitized enough by police procedural and gangster movies, "Clockers" will be a powerful wake-up call. Honestly, I can't recall a film that dealt so straightforwardly with real-life violence apart from David Cronenberg's "A History of Violence" but that was 10 years after ''Clockers". The opening credits set the tone. Shots of young black persons' murdered are shown, blood staining the pavement and deadpan expression proving they didn't see what was coming to them. Lee doesn't stylize for aesthetic purposes but intelligently guide our expectations, loudly shouting what gangster films timidly whispers: this is an ugly word with no redeeming appeal whatsoever. No matter what it involves, it either ends up with jail of being the unintentional poser of bloody aftermaths' pictures. And their purpose is echoed in the murder scene, where lies Darryl Adams, a restaurant manager, shot four times. The sight of the body is disturbing but no more than the total detachment of the two assigned detectives played by Harvey Keitel and John Turturro. They comment the body with shocking detachment and cynical wisecracks such as "the kid had brains" while blood spilled over a hole in his head I don't think Lee's intent is to portray these cops as racist or cynical, but to underline how routinely these murders became. This is not to brandish the 'racism' flag (Lee is above these clich&eacute;s) but to remind us that these crimes are committed within the black community. So, no matter what you'd think of the cops, they're not the ones who pulled the trigger. We're used of that ambiguity regarding racism and this is a credit to Spike Lee's co-writing with Richard Price, who wrote the original novel. "Clockers" depicts a slice of people's life that encapsulates all the factors that lead to the opening 'pictures'. And that no-way-out situation is embodied by the main protagonist, Strike (Mekhi Phifer), a clocker working for Rodney (Delroy Lindo), the crime lord of the neighborhood. His job mainly consists on standing in the park and waiting for customers coming to buy crack. The process is well-elaborated, as there is a watcher to check for cop's arrivals, but eventual strip-searches are also part of this routine. The point is that clockers are at the bottom of the hierarchy, but that's their way of living. The issue of money is another layer of subtlety the film provides. Strike doesn't use money to date girls, buy a car or new clothes. Electric trains are his hobbies. Why? Why not? But we understand that he's trapped in that job for the simple reason is that it earns him enough money to fulfill his passion. On the other hand, his brother Victor (Isaiah Washington) is a honest, two-job worker and decent father forced to constantly swallow the bitter taste of frustration while watching brothers making easy money while he gets no respect and that's his routine. These brothers live in a world where money buys enough power to ooze respect. Both feel pressure in their lives, and the result is Victor's arrest and confession that he murdered Adams, claiming it was for self-defense, but there's something wrong in that murder Keitel's character can't get off his head. The case is even more complex because it was Strike who was supposed to kill Adams, to make his bones with Rodney and climb the 'social ladder'. The seemingly fatherly affection between Rodney and Strike is finally distorted when Rodney reveals the first time he killed a man, threatened with a gun on his mouth by Errol (Thomas Jefferson Byrd) a tough killer before he became the local AIDS-stricken psycho. Like for Rodney, Strike had to have blood on his hands, the point of no-return meaning trust. So, we get it, there are no feelings in such a dirty business. And as the investigation proceeds, Keitel gets more and more interested in Strike's case and wonder why he'd let his brother covering him, and why would a man like Victor kill Adams in the first place? To spare Strike the burden of belonging to Rodney, and in the process, vent all his anger? The procedural leaves to a satisfying resolution but it wasn't "Clockers' main point. The film is more about complex human interactions, because while Keitel and Phifer get closer one another, their mutual affection feel more real and genuine than with Rodney, and might pave the road to Strike's redemption. I know this 'redemption' word is kind of hackneyed, but I know Scorsese co-produced the film, and I felt some intense Scorsesian vibes in that gritty depiction of an underworld and the torment poisoning the main character's life, in the real meaning of the world since Strike is also victim of chronicle ulcer that gets bloodier as the film progresses, like a metaphor of his moral downfall and an imminent deadly conclusion. But there's a third significant character to enrich the film: Tyrone, a kid who admires Strike and imitates him to the point of shaving his head and wearing the same clothes. The kid is a younger version of Strike with Strike playing Rodney's mentor role, and ironically, the disciple shows more zeal and competence than his master. Tyrone's arc is a light of hope illuminating possible ways out of the hell given you don't act like people acted with you. Tyrone evolves from the embodiment of Strike's disgrace to his redemption. And Strike is given the same chance, the possibility to count on people who don't help him because they like him, but because they hate that world enough to triumph over it by getting someone out of it. Indeed, there might be a right way and a wrong way but when trapped in such blinding routine, everybody needs a sign, or guidance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Justice is never black and white
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dope dealing on the Nelson Mandela projects in Brooklyn is the everyday bread of local hoodlum Ronald Dunham aka Strike (Mekhi Phifer). Staking the local park the line of work is relentlessly stressful causing a stress-induced ulcer, which he deals with by drinking down yoo-hoos by the litres. At night respite is found in the form of a trainset hobby, an voyeuristic escape from the reality he has accepted. When his boss Rodney Little (Delroy Lindo) hints towards the necessity of cropping one of his less trustworthy workers Strike confides to his brother Victor (Isaiah Washington). Soon after the murder is committed and Victor steps up to claim self defence. However hardliner detective Rocco Klein (Harvey Keitel) quickly assumes this is a cover up for the true culprit. One of Spike Lee's most accomplished works and a worryingly underrated gem bordering on a masterpiece. While showing artistic restraint in symbols and style, Spike Lee offers a well-devised structure, which lets the strength of the story carry itself. Especially in the final act Lee's well-tuned reserve makes for a heart-felt conclusion full of poignant suggestions, as to the nature of violence. Even the innocent can be corrupted needing a vent for their endless victimisation, while the corrupt seek innocence by befriending children reminiscent of them in their youth and dreaming about a life with 'no more packing'. The ultimately compassionate Rocco, previously shown as a no nonsense cop with a strong moral compass ultimately rejects 'Justice in Black and White', deciding that even the guilty are seldom dealt justice and takes on the role of a benevolent judge and jury - the antithesis of Dirty Harry and Judge Dredd, one more attuned to understand human faults, accept them, than issue warrants. Nonetheless this self-conscious style of storytelling does backlash during build-up, as the convoluted plot mires midway with mild bouts of oversentimentilisation and underwritten character motivations, before finally hitting back with an astoundingly well-rounded finale. Nonetheless a brilliant and captivating movie, which ranks up there with Spike Lee's best with high probability of future rewatching pleasure. A big part of the success comes from disposing of the preacher like stance so predominant in many of Lee's weaker works. Albeit mostly low-key and pretty standard the most significant scenes feature sudden detachment from traditional cinematography to a more detached, surreal focus, as if suggesting a detachment from the grim everyday reality of the protagonists offering escapist release from hardships. This offers some extremely imaginative cinematography by Malik Hassan Sayeed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most of the time remains stuck between good and great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is no denying it that this is a good and well made movie but at the same time I also still had loads of problems with it! The way I see it, this is being a pretty good portrayal of live on the streets in the '90's. It picks a mostly realistic approach but still I just can't really 'feel' this movie. I never felt involved with any of the characters in it or to any of the dramatic events and developments. It doesn't make this movie bad but it does indeed make this movie a bit of a one dimensional experience. And remember, this is an 1995 movie. So everything that was considered to be hip and 'thug life' might seem a bit ridicules and less cool in today's perspective. The whole attitude and way of talking and the way everyone dresses makes this movie really a product of its time. In that regard this movie also really reminded me of "Kids", which coincidentally or not, got made in the same year as this movie. It makes this movie less relevant to watch now days but really, it's nothing I was holding against the movie. I would had most definitely preferred it if this movie was using a more straightforward style of storytelling. The movie as it is seems to be wanting to focus on far too many different characters and tries to do and tell too much. It also really has its own style to it, when it comes down to its storytelling, which was nice and helped to give this movie an unique feeling but at the same time it also made the movie unnecessary hard and not all that pleasant to follow at times. Another thing I also disliked about this movie was its pick of music. The movie mad some bad music choices, in which the music often would swell and become melodramatic at moments that really were uncalled for. It absolutely distracted and most of the time didn't suit what was happening on the screen at the time. But really, I though this movie still had some hints of a great movie in it as well. One thing was its already earlier mentioned unique and distinctive style. Spike Lee always has had an unique and distinctive style of his own and he manages to put a lot of that in this movie successfully. There are some interesting moments in this movie, from a more technical and movie-making perspective. There was some good camera-work for instance and also very little wrong with the movie its editing and pacing. The movie its story in essence also really seemed to be a solid one but I do feel that they perhaps should had picked some different perspectives to keep- and make things a bit more interesting and effective. Wouldn't this movie for instance had been better and more interesting if it told things more from the Harvey Keitel's character perspective? Who knows and it's not like the movie bad or interesting as it is right now but while watching this movie it constantly gave me the feeling it had more potential and things could had been done better. I don't know, perhaps the movie was also being a bit stuck between being a gangster movie and a more realistic one. It never felt like a true gangster flick and it never felt like a true realistic movie neither. Producer Martin Scorsese perhaps should had stepped in a bit more often, since he definitely is a kind of director who can more successfully blend realism with tough and tense gangster/crime movies. Not trying to sound too negative. The movie is good enough as it is but it doesn't ever reaches its full potential. 7/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brothers killin' other brothers ain't no big thing. Blas&eacute;, blas&eacute;.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Clockers is directed by Spike Lee who also co-adapts the screenplay with Richard Price from Price's own novel of the same name. It stars Harvey Keitel, John Turturro, Delroy Lindo, Mekhi Phifer, Isaiah Washington, Keith David, Peewee Love and Regina Taylor. Music is scored by Terence Blanchard and cinematography by Malik Hassan Sayeed. Young drug pushers in the projects of Brooklyn (Clockers) are caught between loyalty to their drug boss and the detectives out to stop them. It's not as incendiary as one might expect of a Spike Lee joint, but the director's concerns and astute knack for story telling are very prominent features. It was originally going to be a Martin Scorses film, but he chose to make Casino instead, he does, however, get a producing credit and you can see in the material why Scorsese was interested in directing. Pic is basically a take on urban drug dealing in the Brooklyn projects and the impact said dealing has on anyone who comes into contact with it. From the downward spiral of life for young men earning their pay by illegal means, to fretful mothers desperately trying to keep pe-teen kiddies from joining the ranks of what they think are cool operators, the morality of the play is forcibly rammed home by Lee. Unfortunately this comes at a cost to the white cop characters, who are too thinly drawn to offer up a law and order counter point to the illegal activity involving drugs and murder, they serve only as the "man", and damn the "man" at that. The Rocco Klein (Keitel) of the book is not evident here, sadly, while Torturo may as well not be in it! Cast performances are well in tune with the material, with Lindo as the "black godfather" turning in a scary one, and Lee's camera-work, coupled with Sayeed's moody photography, has a nifty grasp of realism. Soundtracking is soulful and pleasant. A mixed bag for sure, but it's a story that needs to be told. Bleak and brutal at times, but still offering hope, it's middle tier Spike Lee that always remains intriguing. Even if it at times feels like he was bored telling yet another "black on black is bad" message movie. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tribal Study.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this complicated tale of the pressures on Mekhi Phifer in the Brooklyn projects, director Spike Lee captures the values and the iconography of the African-American community well, as he usually does. You get a genuine sense of the simmering anger, the shifting allegiances, and the small reward system of the social world these pathetic people live in. Pfifer is the central figure and he sweats a lot. No brighter or better than he should be, he's pressured from one side into dealing cocaine by local mogul Delroy Lindo. On the other side, he's pushed by the manipulative but well-intentioned detectives Harvey Keitel and Stanley Turturro. Pfifer's handsome and upright brother is under arrest for murder but Keitel believes that Pfifer is the culprit. Pfifer's brother is simply too good, too compliant, to have done the deed. Nice ambiguity. Lee convincingly nails the diversity and solidarity of the community. It's like John Ford in the ghetto. Pfifer may be innocent of the crime of which Keitel is convinced he's guilty but he also deals dope. Keitel, for all his ploying the system, is determined to bring the guilty party to justice, though he may play a little dirty in getting the job done. And when he finds out that he's been wrong about who committed the murder, he does what such a person would do in real life. He hides his guilt behind a tirade of threats. In a way, it's an improvement over Spike Lee's "Do The Right Thing." It doesn't turn all the cops into heavies. And it doesn't end with an ominous quote from Malcolm X. The weakness of the film lies in Lee's allowing conversations to go on for too long. Pfifer gets a lot of screen time and when he's not chewing out his young brother (who will save his life) he's whining about his innocence. The exchanges, sometimes rising to shouts, go on too long and become tiring. It's a devalued life these people lead. They wear clothes and they groom themselves in ways that appeal only to those in their immediate and limited social worlds. I'm beginning to develop an idea. The more you resemble someone who is upper class and British, the more your social worth. The farther removed you are from this model, the lower your status. If you could take Pfifer, dress him in riding clothes and teach him to play polo, and have him say "eck-tually" instead of "aks," and have him grow some hair on his shaved and shiny skull, he might not be thought guilty of anything except being too polite.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oscar-worthy. Incredible film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tpaladino
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no idea why this film wasn't nominated for an Oscar, and I especially have no idea why it's been seventeen years since the film was released and I'm just now seeing it. I've always been vaguely aware of it's existence as one of the 'other' Spike Lee films, but not much more. I certainly wasn't expecting to see some of his all-time best work, which it is. This film should be mandatory viewing for every single high school in America, that's how important it is. Spike Lee paints a devastatingly realistic picture of inner-city life and the mortal perils that it's inhabitants face on a daily basis. There are no heroes, no angels, and no caricatures. It's all laid bare for the viewer to draw their own conclusion. Lee treats the audience with a level of respect and maturity that is almost unheard of in films that deal in such explosive and controversial subject matter. He trusts that the audience will understand the big picture and take away the appropriate lesson without being evangelized, and without resorting to the kind of cheap gimmickry and pandering that can often plague films of this genre. Everyone should see this film. Literally everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such an overwhelming disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johndeckbose
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm glad that Spike Lee has apparently outgrown his need for polemics. Inside Man was a wonderful mature film that focused on character and motivation far beyond the Afro-centric purview of earlier Spike films. And while Clockers is perfectly serviceable for anyone coming to the story without having read the novel, I submit that Spike's attempt to refocus Richard Price's 1992 masterpiece as a singular black story, with a bone-throwing portrayal of white Detective Rocco Klein within an indictment of white police tactics, short-changes the audience of the profound respect, balance and humanity that made Price's novel so unforgettable. It is truly one of the five best novels I have ever read, while Spike managed to produce one of 1000 best movies I have ever seen. Read the book. It will stun, shock, amaze and delight you. The movie, on the other hand, might just keep you from falling asleep.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is WEAK...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gveltman1
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although I have only seen a few of Spike Lee's films, I am already beginning to place him very low on the ladder of the best directors alive today. Clockers fails, in my opinion, because the film's premise is lacking substance to begin with; the story is lackluster to the max. On top of this, where the film had its opportunities to reel in the audience emotionally, it instead dropped the ball. Moments where energy, tension, and suspense were supposed to effused were disappointingly overridden with anticlimactic slumps in action. The choking scene in the car as well as when Mekhi is being beat up in the park, with their odd selection of music, seem unfulfilled in their potential to capitalize on emotional appeal. I will say the denouement is shot with expert precision. Lee's patented cinematographic maneuver, the double dolly, is on full display. Moreover, his use of low-key lighting in some specific scenes that illustrate the proliferation of drugs inside the projects are done in a professionally haunting manor. Unfortunately, these instances are rare, overshadowed by the weak portions previously discussed. With regards to Lee's film style in Clockers, I like to point out two of his techniques that I find terribly annoying: 1) Those stupid circling gliding shots around characters when they are talking. 2) His persistent use of intense music to compliment serious(at least Lee thinks they must be) scenes. When put together, these two devices serve to create the ultimate exaggeration of the weight a scene carries in this film. Doing a flashy gliding pan across the park accompanied by pounding sound while Tyrone's mother yells at Mekhi and his boys about his haircut is a little excessive. Instead, I think Clocker's would benefit from a greater variation in the levels of stress and emotion we experience in each scene. This way, when the film actually does come to a TRULY significant moment, the audience will become more invested in the action. P.S. I don't think anyone from the projects would actually where a complete Arizona wildcats uniform. Just the jersey, not the shorts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder mystery and race mixed into one great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Take a murder mystery story, mix it into a contemporary vulgar urban setting, then sprinkle some racial tension into the mix and you've got the highly intellectual and intense Spike Lee film Clockers. Clockers is about Strike, a young black man living in Brooklyn, dealing drugs for his ruthless drug lord Rodney Little. Strike deals drugs for the money, but all he really wants to do is hang out with his brothers in the park and play with model train sets. But things start to get rough when a night manager at a local fast food joint is murdered and Strike's brother Victor turns himself in. Det. Rocco Klein is the lead detective on the case and he doesn't buy Victor's story, which sets him on an obsessive hunt to unmask the truth behind this whole ordeal. The film is loaded with spirited yet vulgar dialouge, artistic and vibrant direction, and plenty of memorable characters. Clockers is witty, intelligent, and a lot of fun. It isn't your typical murder mystery or racial tension film. It is a beautiful blend of the two genres that turns into something very unique and very exciting. Spike Lee adds a lot of visual flair to this film and the way he directs it is something you can't quite pinpoint. The panoramic visual style is something you can't exactly describe in words and it is really something you have to see for yourself. There is something obviously unique going on in the way Lee directs this film, it is just difficult to articulate what exactly that is. But the visuals do work in a whole plethora of unique films, allowing the film to succeed on multiple levels. The film ranges from intense and gripping to quirky and fun. From one scene to the next the film grows more fun and more enthralling. Rarely do I care this much about what happens to the characters of a film and I'm not always so compelled to learn the motivations of the very well written characters of a film. All that being said I can't say that I loved the main character, Strike. The actor, Mekhi Phifer, wasn't great and the character himself had some odd moments. I eventually learned to like him and his character thankfully didn't deter too much from my liking of the film. Besides, a lot of the film actually focuses on Harvey Keitel's character and his unending search for the truth behind the murder. There are also numerous subplots that all end up being more interesting than the main character's story. It helps that this is just an all around well written film that is just smarter than your average crime film. Clockers is very different from any murder mystery crime film, as well as any racial tension film. But it provides plenty of great work on both sides of this spectrum. Spike Lee has created a visually interesting film with a fantastic story. The main character is the only low point of the film, but everything else is very good. Clockers is a very worthwhile watch for fans of Spike Lee or the multiple genres this film spans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Modern urban classic - Spike's greatest 'joint'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jamesxgamble
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my all-time favourite films. Director Spike Lee adapts the Richard Price Novel, set in New Jersey, to his hometown and favourite movie backdrop: Brooklyn. It is often said that films never live up to the books on which they are based, but in this case I think the movie out performs the novel. This is because the book can be slow moving at times, and the action is separated by long passages of writing. However, the film chops all of these slow parts out, and the result is a film that keeps you engaged from start to finish. Spike Lee uses music perfectly to compliment the tone and mood of each scene, be it hip-hop in the urban playground, the acoustic interludes of Seal and Des'ree, or minor key, intense jazz to accompany drug use in doorways and nooks, and the final scene's soundtrack is absolutely inspired. Delroy Lindo plays his king-pin character with such comfort, at times it is hard to imagine that he isn't that person in reality! Harvey Keitel and John Turturro work well as the detective double-team, conflicting over whether to take the easy close-by-arrest, or the moral crusade to find the truth behind the case at the heart of the film. Mekhi Phifer is impressive in many of his scenes as the central character, who keeps you guessing to the end on whether he deserves your sympathy or not. For me, Lindo's performance is the standout turn. The cinematography is luscious, and the colours and compositions make this film a visual feast. But more importantly, the natural dialogue of the film and the delivery of nearly every line really reinforce the fact that you are watching a film about real situations. Overall, I give this film my maximum rating of 9.5 stars. If you like this film, you'll love The Wire Season One, and you also might want to check out another overlooked film, Jason's Lyric.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
