<filme>
 <id>
  1270
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0107413
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1993
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Um Talento Muito Especial
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Michael J. Fox stars as a child actor who has grown up, and grown out of his popularity. He now runs a talent agency with his brother, specializing in child acts, trying to discover the ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Michael J. Fox stars as a child actor who has grown up, and grown out of his popularity. He now runs a talent agency with his brother, specializing in child acts, trying to discover the next child star. He gets more than he bargained for when he recruits a child pickpocket to be his next "star."
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   happy birthday to you
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   audition
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   new york city
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   vegetarian
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   precocious child
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   James Lapine
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Marc Lawrence
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Michael J. Fox
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Christina Vidal
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Nathan Lane
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From Rude to Riches
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Former "Life with Mikey" kid Michael J. Fox (as Michael "Mikey" Chapman) is now a thirty-something New York City agent for young performers. The ex-TV sit-com star is the slacker half of a partnership with brother Nathan Lane (as Ed Chapman). Their receptionist is loyal Cyndi Lauper (as Geena), who most memorably sang "Girls Just Want to Have Fun" (1984) as a pop star. Presently, Mr. Fox and Mr. Lane survive mainly due to the success of obnoxious David Krumholtz (as Barry Corman); this film parallels Mr. Krumholtz' scripted contribution as his is the most satisfying characterization... Fox hopes their fortunes increase with the signing of mature 10-year-old Christina Vidal (as Angela "Angie" Vega), a girl he meets under odd circumstances. A violent street thief, young Vidal includes Fox in a round of pick-pocketing. Fox figures her out and tries to retrieve his wallet. Vidal assaults Fox and threatens him with a knife. Wounded from a kick, Fox manages to catch up with Vidal and is impressed with her acting. He estimates she will make $250,000, including his 10% commission... However, there are complications... Throughout the story, youngsters audition poorly. Late in the running time, listen for one, Anaysha Figueroa (as Kimberly Denise Jackson), to end the unrelentingly awful auditions with a fine vocal. Most of the other kids must be better than they sound here. Vidal is cute, though her character's flaws make her unworthy of fame and fortune. However, she is a vegetarian. Fox performs capably, as he knows how to do in comedy situations. It's not enough to lift this flat material. As you might be expecting with this sort of film, Vidal and Fox learn from each other and get on with their lives. You should, too. *** Life with Mikey (6/4/93) James Lapine ~ Michael J. Fox, Christina Vidal, Nathan Lane, David Krumholtz
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A happy, feel-good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nimstic
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie - Michael J Fox and Nathan Lane, you wouldn't expect anything but genuine comedy. The entry of this movie is one of the reasons why I do not want to give much respect to IMDb ratings. Everyone wants to be an arty or an intellect here, when movies like these (though not very intellectual, having brilliant entertainment value sans rubbish) get lost with low ratings. There are some insanely funny scenes - at the same time there are some wonderfully touching moments as well. I watched this movie 10 yrs ago - I love it now as much as I loved it back then. The atmosphere of the film is simple, entertaining and funny. This is a must watch, if you enjoy light-hearted, genuinely funny comedies. Very good movie 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent. As Long As There Are Kids In The Industry This will Always Remain Timely Subject Matter.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnstonjames
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    very good film. don't let the light touch and the cute humor fool you. this film is actually about something more relevant than it appears at first, and especially in the wake (not a pun) of child star Gary Coleman's unfortunate passing. very timely. i've always thought Michael j Fox was an excellent actor who is capable of both humorous and serious performances. whichever the case he is always good. and despite his small stature, we know in real life he is a great man fighting a really big battle and doing big things. love the actor and the real life man. getting back to the movie. 'Mikey' on a superficial level seems like overly light family entertainment made to appeal to the crowd that likes "celebrity family films". you know the kind of family fare that features big name stars in modest kid friendly films. movies like Sandler's 'Big Daddy' or Eddie Murphy in something like 'Daddy Day Care'. 'Mikey' is deeper and has more thoughtful subject matter than these films usually have although it doesn't try to be overt or pretentious about it. the film covers all the bases about child actors in the media. Mikey himself is a former child actor in the film, it shows how the situation can corrupt the kid and make him greedy,it spoofs stage parents and overly precocious kids, it even makes fun of the whole "catch phrase" thing that is often popular in child star sitcoms. and it manages to do it all without becoming too preachy or depressing and cynical. it's also great to see Cyndi Lauper in a movie role (just about her only one as far as i know). Cyndi looks great and is very likable, cute and charming. it would have been nice to see her offered more roles like Madonna was (Lauper, i always thought, was the more talented musician). this was a fun movie and it offered genuine insights into kids (and adults for that matter), and it was a film that tells us in it's message to introspect our experiences rather than simply letting them just happen to us or control us. nice film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    May have excited Mr Fox's sense of deja-vu but did little for me..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ianlouisiana
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Life with Mikey" covers similar territory to "Broadway Danny Rose" except the "Talent" are stagestruck juveniles rather than worn-out wannabes.Marooned at the bottom of the showbiz foodchain,agent Michael J. Fox is basically living on long memories and sympathy from his own time as a child star.When a cute kiddie down on her luck tries to pick his pocket he thinks he recognises potential star material in her. He gets her a role in a cookie commercial and sits back to count the cash-but things don't quite go according to plan........ Mr Fox is convincingly slobbed out and seedy and his clients as hopeless as you might expect,but there is very little spark to this movie. The scenes in the TV studio just aren't funny because the commercials are so self-aware that they are beyond parody.Mr Fox's cute little poppet herself is 11 going on 25 and Miss Cindy Lauper looks and sounds as though she was auditioning for a part in "Roxie Hart". I had never heard of this movie when it popped up on the digital channels the other afternoon and,to be honest,it won't stay long in my memory,but it does have its moments,mostly involving the child actor playing "The Cereal King" who possesses an awfulness that is,in it's own way,quite spellbinding. Made when the excellent Mr Fox's career was in the doldrums,"Life with Mikey" may well have excited his sense of deja-vu,but,for me,it belongs in that odd category of movies I file under the heading "Curate's Egg".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sentimental mix of moods; not very funny...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disappointing comedy-drama with sentimental coating has Michael J. Fox ideally cast as a former child star who now runs a talent agency for thespian tots; Nathan Lane and Cyndi Lauper are his assistants. This all sounds as if it can't miss, however too much of the scenario is given over to strident Christina Vidal as a streetwise tyke whom Fox believes will be the next big thing. They lock quickly lock heads, and the bantering dialogue takes them back and forth to an uninteresting, formula finish. Fox and Lane are both appealing, but the energy of the early scenes gives way to treacle. Slickly produced, but ultimately stale. *1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complete Turkey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    matukonyc1
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can only imagine that the rave reviews here are solely due to fanatic adoration of Michael J. Fox. This is the worst sort of movie-making, no better than than the worst amateur effort. It's embarrassing to think that Fox had to do this sort of thing, and that in the 80's-90's Hollywood failed him and us so miserably. It's dull, poorly conceived, and poorly executed. Miscast, misguided and miscarried. Bad writing, no story, no production values, no plot. It's not even about anything, much less what it aims to be about: show business. Hands down, it's the worst movie Fox ever made, and that's saying a lot, because most of his movies were unworthy and unforgiving of a great talent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Tailor-Made Role for Michael J. Fox
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Isaac5855
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael J. Fox's considerable on screen charm was used to good advantage in LIFE WITH MIKEY, in which he played the former child star of a sitcom called "Life with Mikey" who now is partnered with his brother (Nathan Lane) in running a children's talent agency, even though his brother does most of the work. Things look up when Mike literally bumps into 10-year old shoplifter (Kristina Vidal)who Mike sees as a possible gold mine for their agency and does manage to get her a lucrative commercial deal as cookie salesgirl. This movie is watchable thanks to a charming performance by Fox, who imbues his own experience as a former child star into this character and this performance. It's very sad whenever you watch Mike go into one of his stories about his days on the sitcom and how whoever he's sharing it with looks completely bored. Lane offers comic relief as Mike's brother and Cyndi Lauper steals every scene she is in as the agency's receptionist. There are also some laugh-out-loud hysterical sequences of children with varying levels of talent auditioning for the agency. Between these scenes and Fox's performance, this film can hold your interest.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Life With Mikey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fyyona
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ahh yes, "Life With Mikey". It's a cutesy little film about a former child star, Michael Chapman, who is now working in a talent agency alongside his brother, Ed Chapman. However, Michael has been neglecting the agency and piles pretty much all of the work on poor Ed. He also lives in a messy apartment, appears to be a heavy smoker and has missed out on a lot of education from his childhood due to his stardom. His adult life is a wreck. One day Michael is pick-pocketed by a young girl, Angie. He sees her again later and she appears to have been caught attempting to pick-pocket somebody else. At this point she bursts into tears and blurts out some dramatic dribble about her family, winning the sympathy of passers-by. Michael witnesses her performance and tells her that she could use her acting skills to become wealthy. Later we discover that Angie does, in fact, have domestic problems. Her mother is dead and her father is at a rehabilitation centre. She has to live with her older sister and her boyfriend who push her aside, and do not take good care of her at all. Angie decides to go and live with Michael, giving him the responsibility of taking care of her. This film has its high points and low points. It appealed to me because Michael J. Fox, Nathan Lane and Cyndi Lauper are in it. It was lovely to see these familiar faces, and they each gave a good performance. However, the plot itself was a bit all-over-the-place. It is difficult to give the full summary of what happens but I think that Michael's responsibility for Angie is where the majority of the plot lies. I also found some scenes in this film painfully cheesy. The "happy birthday" scenes, the auditions and the wrestling scene in particular were a bit of a let-down for me. Overall, I think this film is alright. It's not exactly a must-see film but, hey, you might enjoy some of it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    May not be so exciting but fit your eyes.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    w1cht3l
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is a film that is about a former kid-star (Mikey Chapman by MJF) who become kid-star-manager. he had met Angie (Christina Vidal, Freaky Friday's red hair girl, "u make me cry out, I want to get out") coz angie steal his wallet in a street...then mikey find angie have talent... it's a very touching film that you should try watch once. some words inside may not be good to hear...like one scene when mikey return home, angie say a adult male item. don't say here coz comments better not contain sex or sth like that. I don't think that this film is very boring but some ppl may feel it boring. that is your own tolerance ... This may not be a very exciting or very interesting film but at least it's decent to watch and not contain nudity. I suggest all my friend to watch. one thing to show to you why I love this movie, My christian name is Mikey. hahaha...but anyways, read once...watch once and you will say why don't you enjoy this film b4. though frighteners is 1000 times better than mikey, life with mikey is also being easily forgotten !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good to watch if there's nothing else on tv
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sarajb16
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I still and always will enjoy watching Michael J. Fox. Some of the children auditioning were well, obnoxious! Lane and Lauper are entertaning, but the girl who played Angie was an ugly annoying little troll who thought she knew everything. I didn't think she came off as natural either. On a scale of 1 to 10, I give this movie 6.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From Rude to Riches
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Former "Life with Mikey" kid Michael J. Fox (as Michael "Mikey" Chapman) is now a thirty-something New York City agent for young performers. The ex-TV sit-com star is the slacker half of a partnership with brother Nathan Lane (as Ed Chapman). Their receptionist is loyal Cyndi Lauper (as Geena), who most memorably sang "Girls Just Want to Have Fun" (1984) as a pop star. Presently, Mr. Fox and Mr. Lane survive mainly due to the success of obnoxious David Krumholtz (as Barry Corman); this film parallels Mr. Krumholtz' scripted contribution as his is the most satisfying characterization... Fox hopes their fortunes increase with the signing of mature 10-year-old Christina Vidal (as Angela "Angie" Vega), a girl he meets under odd circumstances. A violent street thief, young Vidal includes Fox in a round of pick-pocketing. Fox figures her out and tries to retrieve his wallet. Vidal assaults Fox and threatens him with a knife. Wounded from a kick, Fox manages to catch up with Vidal and is impressed with her acting. He estimates she will make $250,000, including his 10% commission... However, there are complications... Throughout the story, youngsters audition poorly. Late in the running time, listen for one, Anaysha Figueroa (as Kimberly Denise Jackson), to end the unrelentingly awful auditions with a fine vocal. Most of the other kids must be better than they sound here. Vidal is cute, though her character's flaws make her unworthy of fame and fortune. However, she is a vegetarian. Fox performs capably, as he knows how to do in comedy situations. It's not enough to lift this flat material. As you might be expecting with this sort of film, Vidal and Fox learn from each other and get on with their lives. You should, too. *** Life with Mikey (6/4/93) James Lapine ~ Michael J. Fox, Christina Vidal, Nathan Lane, David Krumholtz
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A happy, feel-good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nimstic
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie - Michael J Fox and Nathan Lane, you wouldn't expect anything but genuine comedy. The entry of this movie is one of the reasons why I do not want to give much respect to IMDb ratings. Everyone wants to be an arty or an intellect here, when movies like these (though not very intellectual, having brilliant entertainment value sans rubbish) get lost with low ratings. There are some insanely funny scenes - at the same time there are some wonderfully touching moments as well. I watched this movie 10 yrs ago - I love it now as much as I loved it back then. The atmosphere of the film is simple, entertaining and funny. This is a must watch, if you enjoy light-hearted, genuinely funny comedies. Very good movie 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent. As Long As There Are Kids In The Industry This will Always Remain Timely Subject Matter.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnstonjames
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    very good film. don't let the light touch and the cute humor fool you. this film is actually about something more relevant than it appears at first, and especially in the wake (not a pun) of child star Gary Coleman's unfortunate passing. very timely. i've always thought Michael j Fox was an excellent actor who is capable of both humorous and serious performances. whichever the case he is always good. and despite his small stature, we know in real life he is a great man fighting a really big battle and doing big things. love the actor and the real life man. getting back to the movie. 'Mikey' on a superficial level seems like overly light family entertainment made to appeal to the crowd that likes "celebrity family films". you know the kind of family fare that features big name stars in modest kid friendly films. movies like Sandler's 'Big Daddy' or Eddie Murphy in something like 'Daddy Day Care'. 'Mikey' is deeper and has more thoughtful subject matter than these films usually have although it doesn't try to be overt or pretentious about it. the film covers all the bases about child actors in the media. Mikey himself is a former child actor in the film, it shows how the situation can corrupt the kid and make him greedy,it spoofs stage parents and overly precocious kids, it even makes fun of the whole "catch phrase" thing that is often popular in child star sitcoms. and it manages to do it all without becoming too preachy or depressing and cynical. it's also great to see Cyndi Lauper in a movie role (just about her only one as far as i know). Cyndi looks great and is very likable, cute and charming. it would have been nice to see her offered more roles like Madonna was (Lauper, i always thought, was the more talented musician). this was a fun movie and it offered genuine insights into kids (and adults for that matter), and it was a film that tells us in it's message to introspect our experiences rather than simply letting them just happen to us or control us. nice film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    May have excited Mr Fox's sense of deja-vu but did little for me..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ianlouisiana
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Life with Mikey" covers similar territory to "Broadway Danny Rose" except the "Talent" are stagestruck juveniles rather than worn-out wannabes.Marooned at the bottom of the showbiz foodchain,agent Michael J. Fox is basically living on long memories and sympathy from his own time as a child star.When a cute kiddie down on her luck tries to pick his pocket he thinks he recognises potential star material in her. He gets her a role in a cookie commercial and sits back to count the cash-but things don't quite go according to plan........ Mr Fox is convincingly slobbed out and seedy and his clients as hopeless as you might expect,but there is very little spark to this movie. The scenes in the TV studio just aren't funny because the commercials are so self-aware that they are beyond parody.Mr Fox's cute little poppet herself is 11 going on 25 and Miss Cindy Lauper looks and sounds as though she was auditioning for a part in "Roxie Hart". I had never heard of this movie when it popped up on the digital channels the other afternoon and,to be honest,it won't stay long in my memory,but it does have its moments,mostly involving the child actor playing "The Cereal King" who possesses an awfulness that is,in it's own way,quite spellbinding. Made when the excellent Mr Fox's career was in the doldrums,"Life with Mikey" may well have excited his sense of deja-vu,but,for me,it belongs in that odd category of movies I file under the heading "Curate's Egg".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sentimental mix of moods; not very funny...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disappointing comedy-drama with sentimental coating has Michael J. Fox ideally cast as a former child star who now runs a talent agency for thespian tots; Nathan Lane and Cyndi Lauper are his assistants. This all sounds as if it can't miss, however too much of the scenario is given over to strident Christina Vidal as a streetwise tyke whom Fox believes will be the next big thing. They lock quickly lock heads, and the bantering dialogue takes them back and forth to an uninteresting, formula finish. Fox and Lane are both appealing, but the energy of the early scenes gives way to treacle. Slickly produced, but ultimately stale. *1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complete Turkey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    matukonyc1
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can only imagine that the rave reviews here are solely due to fanatic adoration of Michael J. Fox. This is the worst sort of movie-making, no better than than the worst amateur effort. It's embarrassing to think that Fox had to do this sort of thing, and that in the 80's-90's Hollywood failed him and us so miserably. It's dull, poorly conceived, and poorly executed. Miscast, misguided and miscarried. Bad writing, no story, no production values, no plot. It's not even about anything, much less what it aims to be about: show business. Hands down, it's the worst movie Fox ever made, and that's saying a lot, because most of his movies were unworthy and unforgiving of a great talent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Tailor-Made Role for Michael J. Fox
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Isaac5855
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael J. Fox's considerable on screen charm was used to good advantage in LIFE WITH MIKEY, in which he played the former child star of a sitcom called "Life with Mikey" who now is partnered with his brother (Nathan Lane) in running a children's talent agency, even though his brother does most of the work. Things look up when Mike literally bumps into 10-year old shoplifter (Kristina Vidal)who Mike sees as a possible gold mine for their agency and does manage to get her a lucrative commercial deal as cookie salesgirl. This movie is watchable thanks to a charming performance by Fox, who imbues his own experience as a former child star into this character and this performance. It's very sad whenever you watch Mike go into one of his stories about his days on the sitcom and how whoever he's sharing it with looks completely bored. Lane offers comic relief as Mike's brother and Cyndi Lauper steals every scene she is in as the agency's receptionist. There are also some laugh-out-loud hysterical sequences of children with varying levels of talent auditioning for the agency. Between these scenes and Fox's performance, this film can hold your interest.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Life With Mikey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fyyona
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ahh yes, "Life With Mikey". It's a cutesy little film about a former child star, Michael Chapman, who is now working in a talent agency alongside his brother, Ed Chapman. However, Michael has been neglecting the agency and piles pretty much all of the work on poor Ed. He also lives in a messy apartment, appears to be a heavy smoker and has missed out on a lot of education from his childhood due to his stardom. His adult life is a wreck. One day Michael is pick-pocketed by a young girl, Angie. He sees her again later and she appears to have been caught attempting to pick-pocket somebody else. At this point she bursts into tears and blurts out some dramatic dribble about her family, winning the sympathy of passers-by. Michael witnesses her performance and tells her that she could use her acting skills to become wealthy. Later we discover that Angie does, in fact, have domestic problems. Her mother is dead and her father is at a rehabilitation centre. She has to live with her older sister and her boyfriend who push her aside, and do not take good care of her at all. Angie decides to go and live with Michael, giving him the responsibility of taking care of her. This film has its high points and low points. It appealed to me because Michael J. Fox, Nathan Lane and Cyndi Lauper are in it. It was lovely to see these familiar faces, and they each gave a good performance. However, the plot itself was a bit all-over-the-place. It is difficult to give the full summary of what happens but I think that Michael's responsibility for Angie is where the majority of the plot lies. I also found some scenes in this film painfully cheesy. The "happy birthday" scenes, the auditions and the wrestling scene in particular were a bit of a let-down for me. Overall, I think this film is alright. It's not exactly a must-see film but, hey, you might enjoy some of it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    May not be so exciting but fit your eyes.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    w1cht3l
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is a film that is about a former kid-star (Mikey Chapman by MJF) who become kid-star-manager. he had met Angie (Christina Vidal, Freaky Friday's red hair girl, "u make me cry out, I want to get out") coz angie steal his wallet in a street...then mikey find angie have talent... it's a very touching film that you should try watch once. some words inside may not be good to hear...like one scene when mikey return home, angie say a adult male item. don't say here coz comments better not contain sex or sth like that. I don't think that this film is very boring but some ppl may feel it boring. that is your own tolerance ... This may not be a very exciting or very interesting film but at least it's decent to watch and not contain nudity. I suggest all my friend to watch. one thing to show to you why I love this movie, My christian name is Mikey. hahaha...but anyways, read once...watch once and you will say why don't you enjoy this film b4. though frighteners is 1000 times better than mikey, life with mikey is also being easily forgotten !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good to watch if there's nothing else on tv
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sarajb16
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I still and always will enjoy watching Michael J. Fox. Some of the children auditioning were well, obnoxious! Lane and Lauper are entertaning, but the girl who played Angie was an ugly annoying little troll who thought she knew everything. I didn't think she came off as natural either. On a scale of 1 to 10, I give this movie 6.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From Rude to Riches
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Former "Life with Mikey" kid Michael J. Fox (as Michael "Mikey" Chapman) is now a thirty-something New York City agent for young performers. The ex-TV sit-com star is the slacker half of a partnership with brother Nathan Lane (as Ed Chapman). Their receptionist is loyal Cyndi Lauper (as Geena), who most memorably sang "Girls Just Want to Have Fun" (1984) as a pop star. Presently, Mr. Fox and Mr. Lane survive mainly due to the success of obnoxious David Krumholtz (as Barry Corman); this film parallels Mr. Krumholtz' scripted contribution as his is the most satisfying characterization... Fox hopes their fortunes increase with the signing of mature 10-year-old Christina Vidal (as Angela "Angie" Vega), a girl he meets under odd circumstances. A violent street thief, young Vidal includes Fox in a round of pick-pocketing. Fox figures her out and tries to retrieve his wallet. Vidal assaults Fox and threatens him with a knife. Wounded from a kick, Fox manages to catch up with Vidal and is impressed with her acting. He estimates she will make $250,000, including his 10% commission... However, there are complications... Throughout the story, youngsters audition poorly. Late in the running time, listen for one, Anaysha Figueroa (as Kimberly Denise Jackson), to end the unrelentingly awful auditions with a fine vocal. Most of the other kids must be better than they sound here. Vidal is cute, though her character's flaws make her unworthy of fame and fortune. However, she is a vegetarian. Fox performs capably, as he knows how to do in comedy situations. It's not enough to lift this flat material. As you might be expecting with this sort of film, Vidal and Fox learn from each other and get on with their lives. You should, too. *** Life with Mikey (6/4/93) James Lapine ~ Michael J. Fox, Christina Vidal, Nathan Lane, David Krumholtz
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A happy, feel-good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nimstic
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie - Michael J Fox and Nathan Lane, you wouldn't expect anything but genuine comedy. The entry of this movie is one of the reasons why I do not want to give much respect to IMDb ratings. Everyone wants to be an arty or an intellect here, when movies like these (though not very intellectual, having brilliant entertainment value sans rubbish) get lost with low ratings. There are some insanely funny scenes - at the same time there are some wonderfully touching moments as well. I watched this movie 10 yrs ago - I love it now as much as I loved it back then. The atmosphere of the film is simple, entertaining and funny. This is a must watch, if you enjoy light-hearted, genuinely funny comedies. Very good movie 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent. As Long As There Are Kids In The Industry This will Always Remain Timely Subject Matter.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnstonjames
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    very good film. don't let the light touch and the cute humor fool you. this film is actually about something more relevant than it appears at first, and especially in the wake (not a pun) of child star Gary Coleman's unfortunate passing. very timely. i've always thought Michael j Fox was an excellent actor who is capable of both humorous and serious performances. whichever the case he is always good. and despite his small stature, we know in real life he is a great man fighting a really big battle and doing big things. love the actor and the real life man. getting back to the movie. 'Mikey' on a superficial level seems like overly light family entertainment made to appeal to the crowd that likes "celebrity family films". you know the kind of family fare that features big name stars in modest kid friendly films. movies like Sandler's 'Big Daddy' or Eddie Murphy in something like 'Daddy Day Care'. 'Mikey' is deeper and has more thoughtful subject matter than these films usually have although it doesn't try to be overt or pretentious about it. the film covers all the bases about child actors in the media. Mikey himself is a former child actor in the film, it shows how the situation can corrupt the kid and make him greedy,it spoofs stage parents and overly precocious kids, it even makes fun of the whole "catch phrase" thing that is often popular in child star sitcoms. and it manages to do it all without becoming too preachy or depressing and cynical. it's also great to see Cyndi Lauper in a movie role (just about her only one as far as i know). Cyndi looks great and is very likable, cute and charming. it would have been nice to see her offered more roles like Madonna was (Lauper, i always thought, was the more talented musician). this was a fun movie and it offered genuine insights into kids (and adults for that matter), and it was a film that tells us in it's message to introspect our experiences rather than simply letting them just happen to us or control us. nice film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    May have excited Mr Fox's sense of deja-vu but did little for me..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ianlouisiana
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Life with Mikey" covers similar territory to "Broadway Danny Rose" except the "Talent" are stagestruck juveniles rather than worn-out wannabes.Marooned at the bottom of the showbiz foodchain,agent Michael J. Fox is basically living on long memories and sympathy from his own time as a child star.When a cute kiddie down on her luck tries to pick his pocket he thinks he recognises potential star material in her. He gets her a role in a cookie commercial and sits back to count the cash-but things don't quite go according to plan........ Mr Fox is convincingly slobbed out and seedy and his clients as hopeless as you might expect,but there is very little spark to this movie. The scenes in the TV studio just aren't funny because the commercials are so self-aware that they are beyond parody.Mr Fox's cute little poppet herself is 11 going on 25 and Miss Cindy Lauper looks and sounds as though she was auditioning for a part in "Roxie Hart". I had never heard of this movie when it popped up on the digital channels the other afternoon and,to be honest,it won't stay long in my memory,but it does have its moments,mostly involving the child actor playing "The Cereal King" who possesses an awfulness that is,in it's own way,quite spellbinding. Made when the excellent Mr Fox's career was in the doldrums,"Life with Mikey" may well have excited his sense of deja-vu,but,for me,it belongs in that odd category of movies I file under the heading "Curate's Egg".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sentimental mix of moods; not very funny...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disappointing comedy-drama with sentimental coating has Michael J. Fox ideally cast as a former child star who now runs a talent agency for thespian tots; Nathan Lane and Cyndi Lauper are his assistants. This all sounds as if it can't miss, however too much of the scenario is given over to strident Christina Vidal as a streetwise tyke whom Fox believes will be the next big thing. They lock quickly lock heads, and the bantering dialogue takes them back and forth to an uninteresting, formula finish. Fox and Lane are both appealing, but the energy of the early scenes gives way to treacle. Slickly produced, but ultimately stale. *1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complete Turkey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    matukonyc1
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can only imagine that the rave reviews here are solely due to fanatic adoration of Michael J. Fox. This is the worst sort of movie-making, no better than than the worst amateur effort. It's embarrassing to think that Fox had to do this sort of thing, and that in the 80's-90's Hollywood failed him and us so miserably. It's dull, poorly conceived, and poorly executed. Miscast, misguided and miscarried. Bad writing, no story, no production values, no plot. It's not even about anything, much less what it aims to be about: show business. Hands down, it's the worst movie Fox ever made, and that's saying a lot, because most of his movies were unworthy and unforgiving of a great talent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Tailor-Made Role for Michael J. Fox
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Isaac5855
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael J. Fox's considerable on screen charm was used to good advantage in LIFE WITH MIKEY, in which he played the former child star of a sitcom called "Life with Mikey" who now is partnered with his brother (Nathan Lane) in running a children's talent agency, even though his brother does most of the work. Things look up when Mike literally bumps into 10-year old shoplifter (Kristina Vidal)who Mike sees as a possible gold mine for their agency and does manage to get her a lucrative commercial deal as cookie salesgirl. This movie is watchable thanks to a charming performance by Fox, who imbues his own experience as a former child star into this character and this performance. It's very sad whenever you watch Mike go into one of his stories about his days on the sitcom and how whoever he's sharing it with looks completely bored. Lane offers comic relief as Mike's brother and Cyndi Lauper steals every scene she is in as the agency's receptionist. There are also some laugh-out-loud hysterical sequences of children with varying levels of talent auditioning for the agency. Between these scenes and Fox's performance, this film can hold your interest.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Life With Mikey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fyyona
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ahh yes, "Life With Mikey". It's a cutesy little film about a former child star, Michael Chapman, who is now working in a talent agency alongside his brother, Ed Chapman. However, Michael has been neglecting the agency and piles pretty much all of the work on poor Ed. He also lives in a messy apartment, appears to be a heavy smoker and has missed out on a lot of education from his childhood due to his stardom. His adult life is a wreck. One day Michael is pick-pocketed by a young girl, Angie. He sees her again later and she appears to have been caught attempting to pick-pocket somebody else. At this point she bursts into tears and blurts out some dramatic dribble about her family, winning the sympathy of passers-by. Michael witnesses her performance and tells her that she could use her acting skills to become wealthy. Later we discover that Angie does, in fact, have domestic problems. Her mother is dead and her father is at a rehabilitation centre. She has to live with her older sister and her boyfriend who push her aside, and do not take good care of her at all. Angie decides to go and live with Michael, giving him the responsibility of taking care of her. This film has its high points and low points. It appealed to me because Michael J. Fox, Nathan Lane and Cyndi Lauper are in it. It was lovely to see these familiar faces, and they each gave a good performance. However, the plot itself was a bit all-over-the-place. It is difficult to give the full summary of what happens but I think that Michael's responsibility for Angie is where the majority of the plot lies. I also found some scenes in this film painfully cheesy. The "happy birthday" scenes, the auditions and the wrestling scene in particular were a bit of a let-down for me. Overall, I think this film is alright. It's not exactly a must-see film but, hey, you might enjoy some of it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    May not be so exciting but fit your eyes.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    w1cht3l
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is a film that is about a former kid-star (Mikey Chapman by MJF) who become kid-star-manager. he had met Angie (Christina Vidal, Freaky Friday's red hair girl, "u make me cry out, I want to get out") coz angie steal his wallet in a street...then mikey find angie have talent... it's a very touching film that you should try watch once. some words inside may not be good to hear...like one scene when mikey return home, angie say a adult male item. don't say here coz comments better not contain sex or sth like that. I don't think that this film is very boring but some ppl may feel it boring. that is your own tolerance ... This may not be a very exciting or very interesting film but at least it's decent to watch and not contain nudity. I suggest all my friend to watch. one thing to show to you why I love this movie, My christian name is Mikey. hahaha...but anyways, read once...watch once and you will say why don't you enjoy this film b4. though frighteners is 1000 times better than mikey, life with mikey is also being easily forgotten !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good to watch if there's nothing else on tv
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sarajb16
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I still and always will enjoy watching Michael J. Fox. Some of the children auditioning were well, obnoxious! Lane and Lauper are entertaning, but the girl who played Angie was an ugly annoying little troll who thought she knew everything. I didn't think she came off as natural either. On a scale of 1 to 10, I give this movie 6.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From Rude to Riches
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Former "Life with Mikey" kid Michael J. Fox (as Michael "Mikey" Chapman) is now a thirty-something New York City agent for young performers. The ex-TV sit-com star is the slacker half of a partnership with brother Nathan Lane (as Ed Chapman). Their receptionist is loyal Cyndi Lauper (as Geena), who most memorably sang "Girls Just Want to Have Fun" (1984) as a pop star. Presently, Mr. Fox and Mr. Lane survive mainly due to the success of obnoxious David Krumholtz (as Barry Corman); this film parallels Mr. Krumholtz' scripted contribution as his is the most satisfying characterization... Fox hopes their fortunes increase with the signing of mature 10-year-old Christina Vidal (as Angela "Angie" Vega), a girl he meets under odd circumstances. A violent street thief, young Vidal includes Fox in a round of pick-pocketing. Fox figures her out and tries to retrieve his wallet. Vidal assaults Fox and threatens him with a knife. Wounded from a kick, Fox manages to catch up with Vidal and is impressed with her acting. He estimates she will make $250,000, including his 10% commission... However, there are complications... Throughout the story, youngsters audition poorly. Late in the running time, listen for one, Anaysha Figueroa (as Kimberly Denise Jackson), to end the unrelentingly awful auditions with a fine vocal. Most of the other kids must be better than they sound here. Vidal is cute, though her character's flaws make her unworthy of fame and fortune. However, she is a vegetarian. Fox performs capably, as he knows how to do in comedy situations. It's not enough to lift this flat material. As you might be expecting with this sort of film, Vidal and Fox learn from each other and get on with their lives. You should, too. *** Life with Mikey (6/4/93) James Lapine ~ Michael J. Fox, Christina Vidal, Nathan Lane, David Krumholtz
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A happy, feel-good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nimstic
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie - Michael J Fox and Nathan Lane, you wouldn't expect anything but genuine comedy. The entry of this movie is one of the reasons why I do not want to give much respect to IMDb ratings. Everyone wants to be an arty or an intellect here, when movies like these (though not very intellectual, having brilliant entertainment value sans rubbish) get lost with low ratings. There are some insanely funny scenes - at the same time there are some wonderfully touching moments as well. I watched this movie 10 yrs ago - I love it now as much as I loved it back then. The atmosphere of the film is simple, entertaining and funny. This is a must watch, if you enjoy light-hearted, genuinely funny comedies. Very good movie 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent. As Long As There Are Kids In The Industry This will Always Remain Timely Subject Matter.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnstonjames
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    very good film. don't let the light touch and the cute humor fool you. this film is actually about something more relevant than it appears at first, and especially in the wake (not a pun) of child star Gary Coleman's unfortunate passing. very timely. i've always thought Michael j Fox was an excellent actor who is capable of both humorous and serious performances. whichever the case he is always good. and despite his small stature, we know in real life he is a great man fighting a really big battle and doing big things. love the actor and the real life man. getting back to the movie. 'Mikey' on a superficial level seems like overly light family entertainment made to appeal to the crowd that likes "celebrity family films". you know the kind of family fare that features big name stars in modest kid friendly films. movies like Sandler's 'Big Daddy' or Eddie Murphy in something like 'Daddy Day Care'. 'Mikey' is deeper and has more thoughtful subject matter than these films usually have although it doesn't try to be overt or pretentious about it. the film covers all the bases about child actors in the media. Mikey himself is a former child actor in the film, it shows how the situation can corrupt the kid and make him greedy,it spoofs stage parents and overly precocious kids, it even makes fun of the whole "catch phrase" thing that is often popular in child star sitcoms. and it manages to do it all without becoming too preachy or depressing and cynical. it's also great to see Cyndi Lauper in a movie role (just about her only one as far as i know). Cyndi looks great and is very likable, cute and charming. it would have been nice to see her offered more roles like Madonna was (Lauper, i always thought, was the more talented musician). this was a fun movie and it offered genuine insights into kids (and adults for that matter), and it was a film that tells us in it's message to introspect our experiences rather than simply letting them just happen to us or control us. nice film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    May have excited Mr Fox's sense of deja-vu but did little for me..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ianlouisiana
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Life with Mikey" covers similar territory to "Broadway Danny Rose" except the "Talent" are stagestruck juveniles rather than worn-out wannabes.Marooned at the bottom of the showbiz foodchain,agent Michael J. Fox is basically living on long memories and sympathy from his own time as a child star.When a cute kiddie down on her luck tries to pick his pocket he thinks he recognises potential star material in her. He gets her a role in a cookie commercial and sits back to count the cash-but things don't quite go according to plan........ Mr Fox is convincingly slobbed out and seedy and his clients as hopeless as you might expect,but there is very little spark to this movie. The scenes in the TV studio just aren't funny because the commercials are so self-aware that they are beyond parody.Mr Fox's cute little poppet herself is 11 going on 25 and Miss Cindy Lauper looks and sounds as though she was auditioning for a part in "Roxie Hart". I had never heard of this movie when it popped up on the digital channels the other afternoon and,to be honest,it won't stay long in my memory,but it does have its moments,mostly involving the child actor playing "The Cereal King" who possesses an awfulness that is,in it's own way,quite spellbinding. Made when the excellent Mr Fox's career was in the doldrums,"Life with Mikey" may well have excited his sense of deja-vu,but,for me,it belongs in that odd category of movies I file under the heading "Curate's Egg".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sentimental mix of moods; not very funny...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disappointing comedy-drama with sentimental coating has Michael J. Fox ideally cast as a former child star who now runs a talent agency for thespian tots; Nathan Lane and Cyndi Lauper are his assistants. This all sounds as if it can't miss, however too much of the scenario is given over to strident Christina Vidal as a streetwise tyke whom Fox believes will be the next big thing. They lock quickly lock heads, and the bantering dialogue takes them back and forth to an uninteresting, formula finish. Fox and Lane are both appealing, but the energy of the early scenes gives way to treacle. Slickly produced, but ultimately stale. *1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complete Turkey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    matukonyc1
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can only imagine that the rave reviews here are solely due to fanatic adoration of Michael J. Fox. This is the worst sort of movie-making, no better than than the worst amateur effort. It's embarrassing to think that Fox had to do this sort of thing, and that in the 80's-90's Hollywood failed him and us so miserably. It's dull, poorly conceived, and poorly executed. Miscast, misguided and miscarried. Bad writing, no story, no production values, no plot. It's not even about anything, much less what it aims to be about: show business. Hands down, it's the worst movie Fox ever made, and that's saying a lot, because most of his movies were unworthy and unforgiving of a great talent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Tailor-Made Role for Michael J. Fox
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Isaac5855
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael J. Fox's considerable on screen charm was used to good advantage in LIFE WITH MIKEY, in which he played the former child star of a sitcom called "Life with Mikey" who now is partnered with his brother (Nathan Lane) in running a children's talent agency, even though his brother does most of the work. Things look up when Mike literally bumps into 10-year old shoplifter (Kristina Vidal)who Mike sees as a possible gold mine for their agency and does manage to get her a lucrative commercial deal as cookie salesgirl. This movie is watchable thanks to a charming performance by Fox, who imbues his own experience as a former child star into this character and this performance. It's very sad whenever you watch Mike go into one of his stories about his days on the sitcom and how whoever he's sharing it with looks completely bored. Lane offers comic relief as Mike's brother and Cyndi Lauper steals every scene she is in as the agency's receptionist. There are also some laugh-out-loud hysterical sequences of children with varying levels of talent auditioning for the agency. Between these scenes and Fox's performance, this film can hold your interest.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Life With Mikey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fyyona
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ahh yes, "Life With Mikey". It's a cutesy little film about a former child star, Michael Chapman, who is now working in a talent agency alongside his brother, Ed Chapman. However, Michael has been neglecting the agency and piles pretty much all of the work on poor Ed. He also lives in a messy apartment, appears to be a heavy smoker and has missed out on a lot of education from his childhood due to his stardom. His adult life is a wreck. One day Michael is pick-pocketed by a young girl, Angie. He sees her again later and she appears to have been caught attempting to pick-pocket somebody else. At this point she bursts into tears and blurts out some dramatic dribble about her family, winning the sympathy of passers-by. Michael witnesses her performance and tells her that she could use her acting skills to become wealthy. Later we discover that Angie does, in fact, have domestic problems. Her mother is dead and her father is at a rehabilitation centre. She has to live with her older sister and her boyfriend who push her aside, and do not take good care of her at all. Angie decides to go and live with Michael, giving him the responsibility of taking care of her. This film has its high points and low points. It appealed to me because Michael J. Fox, Nathan Lane and Cyndi Lauper are in it. It was lovely to see these familiar faces, and they each gave a good performance. However, the plot itself was a bit all-over-the-place. It is difficult to give the full summary of what happens but I think that Michael's responsibility for Angie is where the majority of the plot lies. I also found some scenes in this film painfully cheesy. The "happy birthday" scenes, the auditions and the wrestling scene in particular were a bit of a let-down for me. Overall, I think this film is alright. It's not exactly a must-see film but, hey, you might enjoy some of it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    May not be so exciting but fit your eyes.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    w1cht3l
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is a film that is about a former kid-star (Mikey Chapman by MJF) who become kid-star-manager. he had met Angie (Christina Vidal, Freaky Friday's red hair girl, "u make me cry out, I want to get out") coz angie steal his wallet in a street...then mikey find angie have talent... it's a very touching film that you should try watch once. some words inside may not be good to hear...like one scene when mikey return home, angie say a adult male item. don't say here coz comments better not contain sex or sth like that. I don't think that this film is very boring but some ppl may feel it boring. that is your own tolerance ... This may not be a very exciting or very interesting film but at least it's decent to watch and not contain nudity. I suggest all my friend to watch. one thing to show to you why I love this movie, My christian name is Mikey. hahaha...but anyways, read once...watch once and you will say why don't you enjoy this film b4. though frighteners is 1000 times better than mikey, life with mikey is also being easily forgotten !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good to watch if there's nothing else on tv
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sarajb16
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I still and always will enjoy watching Michael J. Fox. Some of the children auditioning were well, obnoxious! Lane and Lauper are entertaning, but the girl who played Angie was an ugly annoying little troll who thought she knew everything. I didn't think she came off as natural either. On a scale of 1 to 10, I give this movie 6.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
