<filme>
 <id>
  1277
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0117603
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  At&eacute; as &Uacute;ltimas Conseq&uuml;&ecirc;ncias
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Four Black women, all of whom have suffered for lack of money and at the hands of the majority, undertake to rob banks. While initially successful, a policeman who was involved in shooting ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Four Black women, all of whom have suffered for lack of money and at the hands of the majority, undertake to rob banks. While initially successful, a policeman who was involved in shooting one of the women's brothers is on their trail. As the women add to the loot, their tastes and interests begin to change and their suspicions of each other increase on the way to a climactic robbery.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   money
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bank
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   robbery
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   tragedy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   machine gun
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   F. Gary Gray
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Takashi Bufford
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Kate Lanier
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jada Pinkett Smith
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Queen Latifah
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Vivica A. Fox
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vero1994
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very touching and exciting movie! You really get to feel for the characters and the image of movie sticks with you for a while. There is a combination of strong, emancipated but hopeless women, drama, tension, romance and Queen Latifah as a lesbian ;) You follow the life of four women who have financial problems, most of them due to injustice caused by police and government. They also have lost or are bout to lose their loved ones. This pushes them over the edge and they decide to rob a bank. When watching the movie you really feel their inner struggle and how they feel they have no other choice. I loved every part of it. Definitely worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch if you want to get back at "whitey"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charlesbeutt
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you take 0 responsibility for getting an education and trying to succeed, then this movie is for you. Simply blame "the system" for why you are poor, stupid, and unqualified for a higher paying job and sit back in your easy chair and watch some African Americans "stick it to da man". I wonder, do African Americans watch movies like this and think its racist against blacks? Sure the "heroes" are all black and you knew the lead cop would be white. But escaping the Ghetto because you are tired of robbing and murder, by committing robbing and murder? All while cackling every 5 seconds, and saying "we probably gonna die anyway", or you're "mad at society". "Get rich or die trying" doesn't always end with people getting rich.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If Darnell Could Take A Bank We Could Take A Bank.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kylehaines96
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    F. Gary Gray the director of Friday takes a turn from comedy to drama in a film people call a rip off of The Town. I disagree because this came out 14 years earlier. This a very underrated film that sadly a lot of people have dismissed. The film is about a group of four women played by Vivica A. Fox, Queen Latifa, Jada Pinkett Smith and Kimberly Elise who rob a bank to get money for Kimberly Elise because her child has been taken away by child protective services. After getting the thrill from robbing a bank for the first time and decide to do again this time they get more money. They then want to rob one last bank this time running away to another country with the money. This is a underrated gem. The film is very well paced and has great suspense. The group of 4 leading ladies have great chemistry together and has a very nice storyline to go along with it. Definnetly check this one out. Rated R For Strong Graphic Violence, Pervasive Language, Some Sex And Drug Use. Theatrical Cut: 2hrs 1min/121min. Directors Cut: 2hrs 4min/124min. 126 uses of the F-word. ****/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When Babes Rob Banks . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director F. Gary Gary treats the the plight of a quartet of blue-collar African-American women with great sympathy in "Set It Off." Each of these women have experienced adversity first hand and the idea is that they have been dealt a bad hand by destiny. One woman prostitutes herself to ensure that her brother gets to go to college, but she finds out later that her efforts were for naught. Another woman is implicated in a bank robbery simply because she knew the man who robbed her bank and didn't follow the procedures that she had been drilled in. Another woman is a single parent who has to work one job to pay the babysitter. Finally, the fourth member who is the least sympathetic is a lesbian who has been restoring her car since the seventh grade. These closely-knit friends take their lumps but decide that whatever a man can do, they can do better. Consequently, they embark on a life of crime in this predictable, often contrived, but nevertheless entertaining crime thriller. Clearly, the moral of the story is don't rob banks. If you know somebody robbing a bank, you must behave as if you don't know them. Never, never, never--if you are a single-parent--ever bring your unattended infant to the workplace. Crime doesn't pay and "Set It Off" makes it abundantly clearly as three out of the four survive. The fourth escapes because somebody on the other side allows them to getaway. The performances are sometimes a little too over the top, especially Jada Pinkett and Vivica A. Fox. If you abhor profanity, prepare yourself for an onslaught of the F-bomb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Action Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaguar_alignment
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember that i saw this movie when it launched in 1996. The appealing performance of the characters introduced a new area for action drama. The performance of the women Is marvelous and the story line Is breath taking. I watched this movie again yesterday and the story never gets doll. It's safe to say that this Is one of the greatest action 'movies out there. I'm looking forward seeing more of these dramatic action movies, since they portrait a more realistic image and get you to empathizes with the characters - even when there villains! Many compliments to the directors and total cast of this movie production.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Four Stooges Rob a Bank
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kvatter
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A coincidental but unlikely stream of bad luck among four women leads them all to the only solution to their problems--rob a bank. And so begins a tale of silliness. Things happen in this film that just can't be believed no matter how much one tries to check the brain at the door. Four women are doing janitorial work. One brings her kid to the job. All four turn their backs together and as quick as you can say, "contrived", the kid is under a sink drinking ammonia. The main detective character knows exactly who is behind it and wants permission to follow up on the suspects but the boss says no because the police have accidentally killed the one suspect's brother. We wouldn't want to upset them despite the overwhelming evidence against them. And then they are never watched as they enter bank after bank to rob them. In one ridiculous scene, they stand in the hallway adjusting their wigs and dark glasses disguises arguing whether or not to rob the place. No one is suspicious of these characters outside the bank entrance?? And one very glaring goof-up is when they have breakfast and then head right off to the robbery(Vivica Fox is sporting a designer baseball cap turned backwards so you know she means business) . As soon as they finish the robbery,it's suddenly night time. The flick is chock full of clich&eacute; lines and actions. The tough Queen Latifah has just driven through a line of heavily armed police who open fire on her car, turning it into swiss cheese, yet she manages to take a very long pause and then emerge with a machine gun blazing. You'll slap a knee at that scene. EVERYONE in this movie is trigger happy. All the cops and security guards shoot to kill at the blink of an eye. The main detective spends several scenes just trying to get people to hold their fire. I gave it three stars because it's so darned goofy that you will probably be entertained at the implausibility of it all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slang is a big 'thang'...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Howlin Wolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    All of the women were "hoodrats", (term borrowed from an IMDb boards user; it isn't my own... ) which was a shame, because they didn't need to be. Why does the only black main character who has any kind of class or sophistication have to be a GUY?! (In a film that's primarily about four women, no less!) I'm pretty sure it does a great disservice to the many black women out there who do manage to be articulate whatever their circumstances happen to be. ... and don't tell me that if they weren't hoodrats then they wouldn't be robbing banks. People at the end of their tether do desperate things. (John Q. for example; again a guy.) The film was good and enjoyable, but they had a big chance to give us some intelligent female characterisations for a change; only with the dialogue they gave them to speak, they blew it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm all for fantasy films but not when it's supposed to be taken seriously as an action film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stephanie Gilleland
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this film a long time ago (aprox 10 years or so) and liked it then. I remembered it the other day and decided to watch it again. The second time around was not pleasant. The acting is 'so,so', the plot is illogical, unreasonable and predictable. The acting...I'm sure it wasn't a stretch for those actresses to play those characters. The plot...there's no way in hell those women would have gotten away with the first robbery much less the 2nd. (side note: Why did TT not realise that even if she came up with a load of money for her court date they would ask where she got it and she would have no logical answer! Ding, Ding...we have a crook!). It horribly stereotyped black women in saying basically that the only way black women can 'beat the system' or obtain a large amount of money was to steal it and not use their intelligence or other resources. It plays too much on sympathy b/c all of them die in the end (bar Jada) but it's not sad (you're thinking 'They were so stupid; they deserve to die). You just don't really care about the characters unless you're a shallow person. I can't believe this film rates over a 5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visceral, hard-hitting action film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sonya90028
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set It Off is an explosive drama about four young black women, who are best friends. Living in the Los Angeles ghetto, each of them struggles with economic and emotional hardships. All of them suffer deeply, due to injustices perpetrated against them by their employers, trigger-happy cops, and the welfare bureaucracy. Fed-up with how life has knocked them around, and desperate to escape the ghetto, the four friends decide to resort to robbing banks together. This film is very fast-paced, with gripping suspense throughout the course of the movie. There's scarcely a dull moment. This movie is overflowing with tire-screeching car chases, blazing gunfire, and volatile interactions between the characters. The breath-taking action sequences really draw you in to the precarious world, of the criminal quartet. It's good that Hollywood finally decided to make a film, that has African-American female characters who make such a deep impact. They're just as rough, vulgar, and determined to change their lives for the better, as any of the male characters are. They're deadly serious about being willing to risk their lives, to take up criminal activities. The women in the film, don't depend on men to determine their course of action. They know that it's up to them alone, to work together to accomplish their bank heists. The four actresses who played the main characters, all give strong performances. Especially Queen Latifah as the hardened butch lesbian, Cleo Simms. She really makes the viewer believe that Cleo can fearlessly handle just about anything, that she's up against. Jada Pinkett also gives a compelling performance as Stoney. Pinkett shows an amazing emotional range, and is able to convey the contradictory moods of Stoney with ease. Vivica Fox as Frankie, is vivid in her role, but not quite as charismatic as either Queen Latifah, or Jada Pinkett. Kimberley Elise as the desperate single mother, Tisean, gives a heartrending performance. This film crackles with a heady intensity, that's rare in films with women as the main characters. These sistahs prove that they are forces to be reckoned with, as they fight for their dreams in a male dominated world. This cutting-edge action film, delivers jolt-after-jolt of exciting entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great action flick, despite its flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviesleuth2
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies like this don't come across very often. A movie that makes you care about the characters and what happens to them. It's especially rare in this genre. But what makes "Set it Off," F. Gary Gray's second feature, stand out is that it does what few films take the time to do: it develops its characters and makes the audience care about them. Stoney (Jada Pinkett Smith), Cleo (Queen Latifah), Frankie (Vivica A. Fox) and Tisean (Kimberly Elise) have been close friends for years. At the movie's beginning, we find that each one of them has been wronged by society because of money. Desperate to get out of their minimum-wage lives, the four turn to bank robbery to help them get out. "Set it Off" would be another dull, violent action movie had it not been for four superlative performances. Jada Pinkett Smith is one of the strongest actresses out there, and here she gets to flex the acting muscles that she showed in "Menace II Society." It's a terrific performance. She is the most developed (and human) of the characters. It's not perfect; Smith is at her best when she's low-key, so she's not as effective when she has to really emote (though she is by no means "bad" when she does. Likewise, Vivica A. Fox is terrific as the single-minded and bitter Frankie; she was wronged and she wants revenge. Fox wisely doesn't try to get the audience to SYMPATHIZE with her (that sort of happens naturally), but she tries, and succeeds, to get the audience to EMPATHIZE with her. Queen Latifah is a strong actress, and despite being made nearly a decade before her Oscar-nominated turn in "Chicago" where she really make it into the big time, her performance here shows why it is a shame why her acting ability wasn't recognized earlier in her career. Newcomer Kimberly Elise shines as the shy, meek Tisean; she's so good it's hard to believe that this is her debut film performance, and her later work shows that it wasn't a fluke. The supporting actors are great as well. Blair Underwood finds the perfect note for Stoney's romantic foil. He's charming, but not smothering; romantic, but not straight out of a soap opera. He's intelligent, and knows he has nothing in common with Stoney. But he really tries to win her heart, and that's what makes him so likable. John C. McGinley is less successful as the cop who ties everything together. While he's not bad, in fact he's pretty good (his scenes where he has to admit his wrongdoings are terrific), he's not up to par with the other actors. But considering the strength in the performances by the four leads, this shouldn't be construed to indicate that his performance is subpar. Also of note is Charles Robinson, who despite being on screen for only two scenes, creates one of the most despicable and disgusting characters I have ever seen. He's so vile that his character sticks with you for a long time. This is not a chick flick. Despite what it seems like it might be, I can't stress this enough: "Set it Off" is NOT A CHICK FLICK! It's an action movie, and director F. Gary Gray keeps it that way. He develops his characters so that everyone can grow to care about them. His direction is fresh and alive, especially in the action sequences which are expertly choreographed. This is a no-holds-barred action thriller and all the better for it. "Set it Off" isn't perfect. Some of the plot elements are quite contrived, and one of the scenes features a catalyst so dumb its appalling that someone didn't require a rewrite (even the clich&eacute; for what normally happens in this situation is more believable). Still, it's a great movie, and an excellent choice if you're looking for an intense action thriller.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vero1994
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very touching and exciting movie! You really get to feel for the characters and the image of movie sticks with you for a while. There is a combination of strong, emancipated but hopeless women, drama, tension, romance and Queen Latifah as a lesbian ;) You follow the life of four women who have financial problems, most of them due to injustice caused by police and government. They also have lost or are bout to lose their loved ones. This pushes them over the edge and they decide to rob a bank. When watching the movie you really feel their inner struggle and how they feel they have no other choice. I loved every part of it. Definitely worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch if you want to get back at "whitey"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charlesbeutt
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you take 0 responsibility for getting an education and trying to succeed, then this movie is for you. Simply blame "the system" for why you are poor, stupid, and unqualified for a higher paying job and sit back in your easy chair and watch some African Americans "stick it to da man". I wonder, do African Americans watch movies like this and think its racist against blacks? Sure the "heroes" are all black and you knew the lead cop would be white. But escaping the Ghetto because you are tired of robbing and murder, by committing robbing and murder? All while cackling every 5 seconds, and saying "we probably gonna die anyway", or you're "mad at society". "Get rich or die trying" doesn't always end with people getting rich.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If Darnell Could Take A Bank We Could Take A Bank.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kylehaines96
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    F. Gary Gray the director of Friday takes a turn from comedy to drama in a film people call a rip off of The Town. I disagree because this came out 14 years earlier. This a very underrated film that sadly a lot of people have dismissed. The film is about a group of four women played by Vivica A. Fox, Queen Latifa, Jada Pinkett Smith and Kimberly Elise who rob a bank to get money for Kimberly Elise because her child has been taken away by child protective services. After getting the thrill from robbing a bank for the first time and decide to do again this time they get more money. They then want to rob one last bank this time running away to another country with the money. This is a underrated gem. The film is very well paced and has great suspense. The group of 4 leading ladies have great chemistry together and has a very nice storyline to go along with it. Definnetly check this one out. Rated R For Strong Graphic Violence, Pervasive Language, Some Sex And Drug Use. Theatrical Cut: 2hrs 1min/121min. Directors Cut: 2hrs 4min/124min. 126 uses of the F-word. ****/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When Babes Rob Banks . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director F. Gary Gary treats the the plight of a quartet of blue-collar African-American women with great sympathy in "Set It Off." Each of these women have experienced adversity first hand and the idea is that they have been dealt a bad hand by destiny. One woman prostitutes herself to ensure that her brother gets to go to college, but she finds out later that her efforts were for naught. Another woman is implicated in a bank robbery simply because she knew the man who robbed her bank and didn't follow the procedures that she had been drilled in. Another woman is a single parent who has to work one job to pay the babysitter. Finally, the fourth member who is the least sympathetic is a lesbian who has been restoring her car since the seventh grade. These closely-knit friends take their lumps but decide that whatever a man can do, they can do better. Consequently, they embark on a life of crime in this predictable, often contrived, but nevertheless entertaining crime thriller. Clearly, the moral of the story is don't rob banks. If you know somebody robbing a bank, you must behave as if you don't know them. Never, never, never--if you are a single-parent--ever bring your unattended infant to the workplace. Crime doesn't pay and "Set It Off" makes it abundantly clearly as three out of the four survive. The fourth escapes because somebody on the other side allows them to getaway. The performances are sometimes a little too over the top, especially Jada Pinkett and Vivica A. Fox. If you abhor profanity, prepare yourself for an onslaught of the F-bomb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Action Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaguar_alignment
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember that i saw this movie when it launched in 1996. The appealing performance of the characters introduced a new area for action drama. The performance of the women Is marvelous and the story line Is breath taking. I watched this movie again yesterday and the story never gets doll. It's safe to say that this Is one of the greatest action 'movies out there. I'm looking forward seeing more of these dramatic action movies, since they portrait a more realistic image and get you to empathizes with the characters - even when there villains! Many compliments to the directors and total cast of this movie production.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Four Stooges Rob a Bank
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kvatter
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A coincidental but unlikely stream of bad luck among four women leads them all to the only solution to their problems--rob a bank. And so begins a tale of silliness. Things happen in this film that just can't be believed no matter how much one tries to check the brain at the door. Four women are doing janitorial work. One brings her kid to the job. All four turn their backs together and as quick as you can say, "contrived", the kid is under a sink drinking ammonia. The main detective character knows exactly who is behind it and wants permission to follow up on the suspects but the boss says no because the police have accidentally killed the one suspect's brother. We wouldn't want to upset them despite the overwhelming evidence against them. And then they are never watched as they enter bank after bank to rob them. In one ridiculous scene, they stand in the hallway adjusting their wigs and dark glasses disguises arguing whether or not to rob the place. No one is suspicious of these characters outside the bank entrance?? And one very glaring goof-up is when they have breakfast and then head right off to the robbery(Vivica Fox is sporting a designer baseball cap turned backwards so you know she means business) . As soon as they finish the robbery,it's suddenly night time. The flick is chock full of clich&eacute; lines and actions. The tough Queen Latifah has just driven through a line of heavily armed police who open fire on her car, turning it into swiss cheese, yet she manages to take a very long pause and then emerge with a machine gun blazing. You'll slap a knee at that scene. EVERYONE in this movie is trigger happy. All the cops and security guards shoot to kill at the blink of an eye. The main detective spends several scenes just trying to get people to hold their fire. I gave it three stars because it's so darned goofy that you will probably be entertained at the implausibility of it all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slang is a big 'thang'...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Howlin Wolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    All of the women were "hoodrats", (term borrowed from an IMDb boards user; it isn't my own... ) which was a shame, because they didn't need to be. Why does the only black main character who has any kind of class or sophistication have to be a GUY?! (In a film that's primarily about four women, no less!) I'm pretty sure it does a great disservice to the many black women out there who do manage to be articulate whatever their circumstances happen to be. ... and don't tell me that if they weren't hoodrats then they wouldn't be robbing banks. People at the end of their tether do desperate things. (John Q. for example; again a guy.) The film was good and enjoyable, but they had a big chance to give us some intelligent female characterisations for a change; only with the dialogue they gave them to speak, they blew it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm all for fantasy films but not when it's supposed to be taken seriously as an action film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stephanie Gilleland
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this film a long time ago (aprox 10 years or so) and liked it then. I remembered it the other day and decided to watch it again. The second time around was not pleasant. The acting is 'so,so', the plot is illogical, unreasonable and predictable. The acting...I'm sure it wasn't a stretch for those actresses to play those characters. The plot...there's no way in hell those women would have gotten away with the first robbery much less the 2nd. (side note: Why did TT not realise that even if she came up with a load of money for her court date they would ask where she got it and she would have no logical answer! Ding, Ding...we have a crook!). It horribly stereotyped black women in saying basically that the only way black women can 'beat the system' or obtain a large amount of money was to steal it and not use their intelligence or other resources. It plays too much on sympathy b/c all of them die in the end (bar Jada) but it's not sad (you're thinking 'They were so stupid; they deserve to die). You just don't really care about the characters unless you're a shallow person. I can't believe this film rates over a 5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visceral, hard-hitting action film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sonya90028
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set It Off is an explosive drama about four young black women, who are best friends. Living in the Los Angeles ghetto, each of them struggles with economic and emotional hardships. All of them suffer deeply, due to injustices perpetrated against them by their employers, trigger-happy cops, and the welfare bureaucracy. Fed-up with how life has knocked them around, and desperate to escape the ghetto, the four friends decide to resort to robbing banks together. This film is very fast-paced, with gripping suspense throughout the course of the movie. There's scarcely a dull moment. This movie is overflowing with tire-screeching car chases, blazing gunfire, and volatile interactions between the characters. The breath-taking action sequences really draw you in to the precarious world, of the criminal quartet. It's good that Hollywood finally decided to make a film, that has African-American female characters who make such a deep impact. They're just as rough, vulgar, and determined to change their lives for the better, as any of the male characters are. They're deadly serious about being willing to risk their lives, to take up criminal activities. The women in the film, don't depend on men to determine their course of action. They know that it's up to them alone, to work together to accomplish their bank heists. The four actresses who played the main characters, all give strong performances. Especially Queen Latifah as the hardened butch lesbian, Cleo Simms. She really makes the viewer believe that Cleo can fearlessly handle just about anything, that she's up against. Jada Pinkett also gives a compelling performance as Stoney. Pinkett shows an amazing emotional range, and is able to convey the contradictory moods of Stoney with ease. Vivica Fox as Frankie, is vivid in her role, but not quite as charismatic as either Queen Latifah, or Jada Pinkett. Kimberley Elise as the desperate single mother, Tisean, gives a heartrending performance. This film crackles with a heady intensity, that's rare in films with women as the main characters. These sistahs prove that they are forces to be reckoned with, as they fight for their dreams in a male dominated world. This cutting-edge action film, delivers jolt-after-jolt of exciting entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great action flick, despite its flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviesleuth2
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies like this don't come across very often. A movie that makes you care about the characters and what happens to them. It's especially rare in this genre. But what makes "Set it Off," F. Gary Gray's second feature, stand out is that it does what few films take the time to do: it develops its characters and makes the audience care about them. Stoney (Jada Pinkett Smith), Cleo (Queen Latifah), Frankie (Vivica A. Fox) and Tisean (Kimberly Elise) have been close friends for years. At the movie's beginning, we find that each one of them has been wronged by society because of money. Desperate to get out of their minimum-wage lives, the four turn to bank robbery to help them get out. "Set it Off" would be another dull, violent action movie had it not been for four superlative performances. Jada Pinkett Smith is one of the strongest actresses out there, and here she gets to flex the acting muscles that she showed in "Menace II Society." It's a terrific performance. She is the most developed (and human) of the characters. It's not perfect; Smith is at her best when she's low-key, so she's not as effective when she has to really emote (though she is by no means "bad" when she does. Likewise, Vivica A. Fox is terrific as the single-minded and bitter Frankie; she was wronged and she wants revenge. Fox wisely doesn't try to get the audience to SYMPATHIZE with her (that sort of happens naturally), but she tries, and succeeds, to get the audience to EMPATHIZE with her. Queen Latifah is a strong actress, and despite being made nearly a decade before her Oscar-nominated turn in "Chicago" where she really make it into the big time, her performance here shows why it is a shame why her acting ability wasn't recognized earlier in her career. Newcomer Kimberly Elise shines as the shy, meek Tisean; she's so good it's hard to believe that this is her debut film performance, and her later work shows that it wasn't a fluke. The supporting actors are great as well. Blair Underwood finds the perfect note for Stoney's romantic foil. He's charming, but not smothering; romantic, but not straight out of a soap opera. He's intelligent, and knows he has nothing in common with Stoney. But he really tries to win her heart, and that's what makes him so likable. John C. McGinley is less successful as the cop who ties everything together. While he's not bad, in fact he's pretty good (his scenes where he has to admit his wrongdoings are terrific), he's not up to par with the other actors. But considering the strength in the performances by the four leads, this shouldn't be construed to indicate that his performance is subpar. Also of note is Charles Robinson, who despite being on screen for only two scenes, creates one of the most despicable and disgusting characters I have ever seen. He's so vile that his character sticks with you for a long time. This is not a chick flick. Despite what it seems like it might be, I can't stress this enough: "Set it Off" is NOT A CHICK FLICK! It's an action movie, and director F. Gary Gray keeps it that way. He develops his characters so that everyone can grow to care about them. His direction is fresh and alive, especially in the action sequences which are expertly choreographed. This is a no-holds-barred action thriller and all the better for it. "Set it Off" isn't perfect. Some of the plot elements are quite contrived, and one of the scenes features a catalyst so dumb its appalling that someone didn't require a rewrite (even the clich&eacute; for what normally happens in this situation is more believable). Still, it's a great movie, and an excellent choice if you're looking for an intense action thriller.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vero1994
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very touching and exciting movie! You really get to feel for the characters and the image of movie sticks with you for a while. There is a combination of strong, emancipated but hopeless women, drama, tension, romance and Queen Latifah as a lesbian ;) You follow the life of four women who have financial problems, most of them due to injustice caused by police and government. They also have lost or are bout to lose their loved ones. This pushes them over the edge and they decide to rob a bank. When watching the movie you really feel their inner struggle and how they feel they have no other choice. I loved every part of it. Definitely worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch if you want to get back at "whitey"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charlesbeutt
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you take 0 responsibility for getting an education and trying to succeed, then this movie is for you. Simply blame "the system" for why you are poor, stupid, and unqualified for a higher paying job and sit back in your easy chair and watch some African Americans "stick it to da man". I wonder, do African Americans watch movies like this and think its racist against blacks? Sure the "heroes" are all black and you knew the lead cop would be white. But escaping the Ghetto because you are tired of robbing and murder, by committing robbing and murder? All while cackling every 5 seconds, and saying "we probably gonna die anyway", or you're "mad at society". "Get rich or die trying" doesn't always end with people getting rich.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If Darnell Could Take A Bank We Could Take A Bank.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kylehaines96
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    F. Gary Gray the director of Friday takes a turn from comedy to drama in a film people call a rip off of The Town. I disagree because this came out 14 years earlier. This a very underrated film that sadly a lot of people have dismissed. The film is about a group of four women played by Vivica A. Fox, Queen Latifa, Jada Pinkett Smith and Kimberly Elise who rob a bank to get money for Kimberly Elise because her child has been taken away by child protective services. After getting the thrill from robbing a bank for the first time and decide to do again this time they get more money. They then want to rob one last bank this time running away to another country with the money. This is a underrated gem. The film is very well paced and has great suspense. The group of 4 leading ladies have great chemistry together and has a very nice storyline to go along with it. Definnetly check this one out. Rated R For Strong Graphic Violence, Pervasive Language, Some Sex And Drug Use. Theatrical Cut: 2hrs 1min/121min. Directors Cut: 2hrs 4min/124min. 126 uses of the F-word. ****/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When Babes Rob Banks . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director F. Gary Gary treats the the plight of a quartet of blue-collar African-American women with great sympathy in "Set It Off." Each of these women have experienced adversity first hand and the idea is that they have been dealt a bad hand by destiny. One woman prostitutes herself to ensure that her brother gets to go to college, but she finds out later that her efforts were for naught. Another woman is implicated in a bank robbery simply because she knew the man who robbed her bank and didn't follow the procedures that she had been drilled in. Another woman is a single parent who has to work one job to pay the babysitter. Finally, the fourth member who is the least sympathetic is a lesbian who has been restoring her car since the seventh grade. These closely-knit friends take their lumps but decide that whatever a man can do, they can do better. Consequently, they embark on a life of crime in this predictable, often contrived, but nevertheless entertaining crime thriller. Clearly, the moral of the story is don't rob banks. If you know somebody robbing a bank, you must behave as if you don't know them. Never, never, never--if you are a single-parent--ever bring your unattended infant to the workplace. Crime doesn't pay and "Set It Off" makes it abundantly clearly as three out of the four survive. The fourth escapes because somebody on the other side allows them to getaway. The performances are sometimes a little too over the top, especially Jada Pinkett and Vivica A. Fox. If you abhor profanity, prepare yourself for an onslaught of the F-bomb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Action Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaguar_alignment
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember that i saw this movie when it launched in 1996. The appealing performance of the characters introduced a new area for action drama. The performance of the women Is marvelous and the story line Is breath taking. I watched this movie again yesterday and the story never gets doll. It's safe to say that this Is one of the greatest action 'movies out there. I'm looking forward seeing more of these dramatic action movies, since they portrait a more realistic image and get you to empathizes with the characters - even when there villains! Many compliments to the directors and total cast of this movie production.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Four Stooges Rob a Bank
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kvatter
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A coincidental but unlikely stream of bad luck among four women leads them all to the only solution to their problems--rob a bank. And so begins a tale of silliness. Things happen in this film that just can't be believed no matter how much one tries to check the brain at the door. Four women are doing janitorial work. One brings her kid to the job. All four turn their backs together and as quick as you can say, "contrived", the kid is under a sink drinking ammonia. The main detective character knows exactly who is behind it and wants permission to follow up on the suspects but the boss says no because the police have accidentally killed the one suspect's brother. We wouldn't want to upset them despite the overwhelming evidence against them. And then they are never watched as they enter bank after bank to rob them. In one ridiculous scene, they stand in the hallway adjusting their wigs and dark glasses disguises arguing whether or not to rob the place. No one is suspicious of these characters outside the bank entrance?? And one very glaring goof-up is when they have breakfast and then head right off to the robbery(Vivica Fox is sporting a designer baseball cap turned backwards so you know she means business) . As soon as they finish the robbery,it's suddenly night time. The flick is chock full of clich&eacute; lines and actions. The tough Queen Latifah has just driven through a line of heavily armed police who open fire on her car, turning it into swiss cheese, yet she manages to take a very long pause and then emerge with a machine gun blazing. You'll slap a knee at that scene. EVERYONE in this movie is trigger happy. All the cops and security guards shoot to kill at the blink of an eye. The main detective spends several scenes just trying to get people to hold their fire. I gave it three stars because it's so darned goofy that you will probably be entertained at the implausibility of it all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slang is a big 'thang'...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Howlin Wolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    All of the women were "hoodrats", (term borrowed from an IMDb boards user; it isn't my own... ) which was a shame, because they didn't need to be. Why does the only black main character who has any kind of class or sophistication have to be a GUY?! (In a film that's primarily about four women, no less!) I'm pretty sure it does a great disservice to the many black women out there who do manage to be articulate whatever their circumstances happen to be. ... and don't tell me that if they weren't hoodrats then they wouldn't be robbing banks. People at the end of their tether do desperate things. (John Q. for example; again a guy.) The film was good and enjoyable, but they had a big chance to give us some intelligent female characterisations for a change; only with the dialogue they gave them to speak, they blew it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm all for fantasy films but not when it's supposed to be taken seriously as an action film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stephanie Gilleland
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this film a long time ago (aprox 10 years or so) and liked it then. I remembered it the other day and decided to watch it again. The second time around was not pleasant. The acting is 'so,so', the plot is illogical, unreasonable and predictable. The acting...I'm sure it wasn't a stretch for those actresses to play those characters. The plot...there's no way in hell those women would have gotten away with the first robbery much less the 2nd. (side note: Why did TT not realise that even if she came up with a load of money for her court date they would ask where she got it and she would have no logical answer! Ding, Ding...we have a crook!). It horribly stereotyped black women in saying basically that the only way black women can 'beat the system' or obtain a large amount of money was to steal it and not use their intelligence or other resources. It plays too much on sympathy b/c all of them die in the end (bar Jada) but it's not sad (you're thinking 'They were so stupid; they deserve to die). You just don't really care about the characters unless you're a shallow person. I can't believe this film rates over a 5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visceral, hard-hitting action film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sonya90028
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set It Off is an explosive drama about four young black women, who are best friends. Living in the Los Angeles ghetto, each of them struggles with economic and emotional hardships. All of them suffer deeply, due to injustices perpetrated against them by their employers, trigger-happy cops, and the welfare bureaucracy. Fed-up with how life has knocked them around, and desperate to escape the ghetto, the four friends decide to resort to robbing banks together. This film is very fast-paced, with gripping suspense throughout the course of the movie. There's scarcely a dull moment. This movie is overflowing with tire-screeching car chases, blazing gunfire, and volatile interactions between the characters. The breath-taking action sequences really draw you in to the precarious world, of the criminal quartet. It's good that Hollywood finally decided to make a film, that has African-American female characters who make such a deep impact. They're just as rough, vulgar, and determined to change their lives for the better, as any of the male characters are. They're deadly serious about being willing to risk their lives, to take up criminal activities. The women in the film, don't depend on men to determine their course of action. They know that it's up to them alone, to work together to accomplish their bank heists. The four actresses who played the main characters, all give strong performances. Especially Queen Latifah as the hardened butch lesbian, Cleo Simms. She really makes the viewer believe that Cleo can fearlessly handle just about anything, that she's up against. Jada Pinkett also gives a compelling performance as Stoney. Pinkett shows an amazing emotional range, and is able to convey the contradictory moods of Stoney with ease. Vivica Fox as Frankie, is vivid in her role, but not quite as charismatic as either Queen Latifah, or Jada Pinkett. Kimberley Elise as the desperate single mother, Tisean, gives a heartrending performance. This film crackles with a heady intensity, that's rare in films with women as the main characters. These sistahs prove that they are forces to be reckoned with, as they fight for their dreams in a male dominated world. This cutting-edge action film, delivers jolt-after-jolt of exciting entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great action flick, despite its flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviesleuth2
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies like this don't come across very often. A movie that makes you care about the characters and what happens to them. It's especially rare in this genre. But what makes "Set it Off," F. Gary Gray's second feature, stand out is that it does what few films take the time to do: it develops its characters and makes the audience care about them. Stoney (Jada Pinkett Smith), Cleo (Queen Latifah), Frankie (Vivica A. Fox) and Tisean (Kimberly Elise) have been close friends for years. At the movie's beginning, we find that each one of them has been wronged by society because of money. Desperate to get out of their minimum-wage lives, the four turn to bank robbery to help them get out. "Set it Off" would be another dull, violent action movie had it not been for four superlative performances. Jada Pinkett Smith is one of the strongest actresses out there, and here she gets to flex the acting muscles that she showed in "Menace II Society." It's a terrific performance. She is the most developed (and human) of the characters. It's not perfect; Smith is at her best when she's low-key, so she's not as effective when she has to really emote (though she is by no means "bad" when she does. Likewise, Vivica A. Fox is terrific as the single-minded and bitter Frankie; she was wronged and she wants revenge. Fox wisely doesn't try to get the audience to SYMPATHIZE with her (that sort of happens naturally), but she tries, and succeeds, to get the audience to EMPATHIZE with her. Queen Latifah is a strong actress, and despite being made nearly a decade before her Oscar-nominated turn in "Chicago" where she really make it into the big time, her performance here shows why it is a shame why her acting ability wasn't recognized earlier in her career. Newcomer Kimberly Elise shines as the shy, meek Tisean; she's so good it's hard to believe that this is her debut film performance, and her later work shows that it wasn't a fluke. The supporting actors are great as well. Blair Underwood finds the perfect note for Stoney's romantic foil. He's charming, but not smothering; romantic, but not straight out of a soap opera. He's intelligent, and knows he has nothing in common with Stoney. But he really tries to win her heart, and that's what makes him so likable. John C. McGinley is less successful as the cop who ties everything together. While he's not bad, in fact he's pretty good (his scenes where he has to admit his wrongdoings are terrific), he's not up to par with the other actors. But considering the strength in the performances by the four leads, this shouldn't be construed to indicate that his performance is subpar. Also of note is Charles Robinson, who despite being on screen for only two scenes, creates one of the most despicable and disgusting characters I have ever seen. He's so vile that his character sticks with you for a long time. This is not a chick flick. Despite what it seems like it might be, I can't stress this enough: "Set it Off" is NOT A CHICK FLICK! It's an action movie, and director F. Gary Gray keeps it that way. He develops his characters so that everyone can grow to care about them. His direction is fresh and alive, especially in the action sequences which are expertly choreographed. This is a no-holds-barred action thriller and all the better for it. "Set it Off" isn't perfect. Some of the plot elements are quite contrived, and one of the scenes features a catalyst so dumb its appalling that someone didn't require a rewrite (even the clich&eacute; for what normally happens in this situation is more believable). Still, it's a great movie, and an excellent choice if you're looking for an intense action thriller.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vero1994
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very touching and exciting movie! You really get to feel for the characters and the image of movie sticks with you for a while. There is a combination of strong, emancipated but hopeless women, drama, tension, romance and Queen Latifah as a lesbian ;) You follow the life of four women who have financial problems, most of them due to injustice caused by police and government. They also have lost or are bout to lose their loved ones. This pushes them over the edge and they decide to rob a bank. When watching the movie you really feel their inner struggle and how they feel they have no other choice. I loved every part of it. Definitely worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch if you want to get back at "whitey"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charlesbeutt
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you take 0 responsibility for getting an education and trying to succeed, then this movie is for you. Simply blame "the system" for why you are poor, stupid, and unqualified for a higher paying job and sit back in your easy chair and watch some African Americans "stick it to da man". I wonder, do African Americans watch movies like this and think its racist against blacks? Sure the "heroes" are all black and you knew the lead cop would be white. But escaping the Ghetto because you are tired of robbing and murder, by committing robbing and murder? All while cackling every 5 seconds, and saying "we probably gonna die anyway", or you're "mad at society". "Get rich or die trying" doesn't always end with people getting rich.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If Darnell Could Take A Bank We Could Take A Bank.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kylehaines96
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    F. Gary Gray the director of Friday takes a turn from comedy to drama in a film people call a rip off of The Town. I disagree because this came out 14 years earlier. This a very underrated film that sadly a lot of people have dismissed. The film is about a group of four women played by Vivica A. Fox, Queen Latifa, Jada Pinkett Smith and Kimberly Elise who rob a bank to get money for Kimberly Elise because her child has been taken away by child protective services. After getting the thrill from robbing a bank for the first time and decide to do again this time they get more money. They then want to rob one last bank this time running away to another country with the money. This is a underrated gem. The film is very well paced and has great suspense. The group of 4 leading ladies have great chemistry together and has a very nice storyline to go along with it. Definnetly check this one out. Rated R For Strong Graphic Violence, Pervasive Language, Some Sex And Drug Use. Theatrical Cut: 2hrs 1min/121min. Directors Cut: 2hrs 4min/124min. 126 uses of the F-word. ****/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When Babes Rob Banks . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director F. Gary Gary treats the the plight of a quartet of blue-collar African-American women with great sympathy in "Set It Off." Each of these women have experienced adversity first hand and the idea is that they have been dealt a bad hand by destiny. One woman prostitutes herself to ensure that her brother gets to go to college, but she finds out later that her efforts were for naught. Another woman is implicated in a bank robbery simply because she knew the man who robbed her bank and didn't follow the procedures that she had been drilled in. Another woman is a single parent who has to work one job to pay the babysitter. Finally, the fourth member who is the least sympathetic is a lesbian who has been restoring her car since the seventh grade. These closely-knit friends take their lumps but decide that whatever a man can do, they can do better. Consequently, they embark on a life of crime in this predictable, often contrived, but nevertheless entertaining crime thriller. Clearly, the moral of the story is don't rob banks. If you know somebody robbing a bank, you must behave as if you don't know them. Never, never, never--if you are a single-parent--ever bring your unattended infant to the workplace. Crime doesn't pay and "Set It Off" makes it abundantly clearly as three out of the four survive. The fourth escapes because somebody on the other side allows them to getaway. The performances are sometimes a little too over the top, especially Jada Pinkett and Vivica A. Fox. If you abhor profanity, prepare yourself for an onslaught of the F-bomb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Action Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaguar_alignment
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember that i saw this movie when it launched in 1996. The appealing performance of the characters introduced a new area for action drama. The performance of the women Is marvelous and the story line Is breath taking. I watched this movie again yesterday and the story never gets doll. It's safe to say that this Is one of the greatest action 'movies out there. I'm looking forward seeing more of these dramatic action movies, since they portrait a more realistic image and get you to empathizes with the characters - even when there villains! Many compliments to the directors and total cast of this movie production.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Four Stooges Rob a Bank
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kvatter
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A coincidental but unlikely stream of bad luck among four women leads them all to the only solution to their problems--rob a bank. And so begins a tale of silliness. Things happen in this film that just can't be believed no matter how much one tries to check the brain at the door. Four women are doing janitorial work. One brings her kid to the job. All four turn their backs together and as quick as you can say, "contrived", the kid is under a sink drinking ammonia. The main detective character knows exactly who is behind it and wants permission to follow up on the suspects but the boss says no because the police have accidentally killed the one suspect's brother. We wouldn't want to upset them despite the overwhelming evidence against them. And then they are never watched as they enter bank after bank to rob them. In one ridiculous scene, they stand in the hallway adjusting their wigs and dark glasses disguises arguing whether or not to rob the place. No one is suspicious of these characters outside the bank entrance?? And one very glaring goof-up is when they have breakfast and then head right off to the robbery(Vivica Fox is sporting a designer baseball cap turned backwards so you know she means business) . As soon as they finish the robbery,it's suddenly night time. The flick is chock full of clich&eacute; lines and actions. The tough Queen Latifah has just driven through a line of heavily armed police who open fire on her car, turning it into swiss cheese, yet she manages to take a very long pause and then emerge with a machine gun blazing. You'll slap a knee at that scene. EVERYONE in this movie is trigger happy. All the cops and security guards shoot to kill at the blink of an eye. The main detective spends several scenes just trying to get people to hold their fire. I gave it three stars because it's so darned goofy that you will probably be entertained at the implausibility of it all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slang is a big 'thang'...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Howlin Wolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    All of the women were "hoodrats", (term borrowed from an IMDb boards user; it isn't my own... ) which was a shame, because they didn't need to be. Why does the only black main character who has any kind of class or sophistication have to be a GUY?! (In a film that's primarily about four women, no less!) I'm pretty sure it does a great disservice to the many black women out there who do manage to be articulate whatever their circumstances happen to be. ... and don't tell me that if they weren't hoodrats then they wouldn't be robbing banks. People at the end of their tether do desperate things. (John Q. for example; again a guy.) The film was good and enjoyable, but they had a big chance to give us some intelligent female characterisations for a change; only with the dialogue they gave them to speak, they blew it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm all for fantasy films but not when it's supposed to be taken seriously as an action film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stephanie Gilleland
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this film a long time ago (aprox 10 years or so) and liked it then. I remembered it the other day and decided to watch it again. The second time around was not pleasant. The acting is 'so,so', the plot is illogical, unreasonable and predictable. The acting...I'm sure it wasn't a stretch for those actresses to play those characters. The plot...there's no way in hell those women would have gotten away with the first robbery much less the 2nd. (side note: Why did TT not realise that even if she came up with a load of money for her court date they would ask where she got it and she would have no logical answer! Ding, Ding...we have a crook!). It horribly stereotyped black women in saying basically that the only way black women can 'beat the system' or obtain a large amount of money was to steal it and not use their intelligence or other resources. It plays too much on sympathy b/c all of them die in the end (bar Jada) but it's not sad (you're thinking 'They were so stupid; they deserve to die). You just don't really care about the characters unless you're a shallow person. I can't believe this film rates over a 5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visceral, hard-hitting action film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sonya90028
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set It Off is an explosive drama about four young black women, who are best friends. Living in the Los Angeles ghetto, each of them struggles with economic and emotional hardships. All of them suffer deeply, due to injustices perpetrated against them by their employers, trigger-happy cops, and the welfare bureaucracy. Fed-up with how life has knocked them around, and desperate to escape the ghetto, the four friends decide to resort to robbing banks together. This film is very fast-paced, with gripping suspense throughout the course of the movie. There's scarcely a dull moment. This movie is overflowing with tire-screeching car chases, blazing gunfire, and volatile interactions between the characters. The breath-taking action sequences really draw you in to the precarious world, of the criminal quartet. It's good that Hollywood finally decided to make a film, that has African-American female characters who make such a deep impact. They're just as rough, vulgar, and determined to change their lives for the better, as any of the male characters are. They're deadly serious about being willing to risk their lives, to take up criminal activities. The women in the film, don't depend on men to determine their course of action. They know that it's up to them alone, to work together to accomplish their bank heists. The four actresses who played the main characters, all give strong performances. Especially Queen Latifah as the hardened butch lesbian, Cleo Simms. She really makes the viewer believe that Cleo can fearlessly handle just about anything, that she's up against. Jada Pinkett also gives a compelling performance as Stoney. Pinkett shows an amazing emotional range, and is able to convey the contradictory moods of Stoney with ease. Vivica Fox as Frankie, is vivid in her role, but not quite as charismatic as either Queen Latifah, or Jada Pinkett. Kimberley Elise as the desperate single mother, Tisean, gives a heartrending performance. This film crackles with a heady intensity, that's rare in films with women as the main characters. These sistahs prove that they are forces to be reckoned with, as they fight for their dreams in a male dominated world. This cutting-edge action film, delivers jolt-after-jolt of exciting entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great action flick, despite its flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviesleuth2
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies like this don't come across very often. A movie that makes you care about the characters and what happens to them. It's especially rare in this genre. But what makes "Set it Off," F. Gary Gray's second feature, stand out is that it does what few films take the time to do: it develops its characters and makes the audience care about them. Stoney (Jada Pinkett Smith), Cleo (Queen Latifah), Frankie (Vivica A. Fox) and Tisean (Kimberly Elise) have been close friends for years. At the movie's beginning, we find that each one of them has been wronged by society because of money. Desperate to get out of their minimum-wage lives, the four turn to bank robbery to help them get out. "Set it Off" would be another dull, violent action movie had it not been for four superlative performances. Jada Pinkett Smith is one of the strongest actresses out there, and here she gets to flex the acting muscles that she showed in "Menace II Society." It's a terrific performance. She is the most developed (and human) of the characters. It's not perfect; Smith is at her best when she's low-key, so she's not as effective when she has to really emote (though she is by no means "bad" when she does. Likewise, Vivica A. Fox is terrific as the single-minded and bitter Frankie; she was wronged and she wants revenge. Fox wisely doesn't try to get the audience to SYMPATHIZE with her (that sort of happens naturally), but she tries, and succeeds, to get the audience to EMPATHIZE with her. Queen Latifah is a strong actress, and despite being made nearly a decade before her Oscar-nominated turn in "Chicago" where she really make it into the big time, her performance here shows why it is a shame why her acting ability wasn't recognized earlier in her career. Newcomer Kimberly Elise shines as the shy, meek Tisean; she's so good it's hard to believe that this is her debut film performance, and her later work shows that it wasn't a fluke. The supporting actors are great as well. Blair Underwood finds the perfect note for Stoney's romantic foil. He's charming, but not smothering; romantic, but not straight out of a soap opera. He's intelligent, and knows he has nothing in common with Stoney. But he really tries to win her heart, and that's what makes him so likable. John C. McGinley is less successful as the cop who ties everything together. While he's not bad, in fact he's pretty good (his scenes where he has to admit his wrongdoings are terrific), he's not up to par with the other actors. But considering the strength in the performances by the four leads, this shouldn't be construed to indicate that his performance is subpar. Also of note is Charles Robinson, who despite being on screen for only two scenes, creates one of the most despicable and disgusting characters I have ever seen. He's so vile that his character sticks with you for a long time. This is not a chick flick. Despite what it seems like it might be, I can't stress this enough: "Set it Off" is NOT A CHICK FLICK! It's an action movie, and director F. Gary Gray keeps it that way. He develops his characters so that everyone can grow to care about them. His direction is fresh and alive, especially in the action sequences which are expertly choreographed. This is a no-holds-barred action thriller and all the better for it. "Set it Off" isn't perfect. Some of the plot elements are quite contrived, and one of the scenes features a catalyst so dumb its appalling that someone didn't require a rewrite (even the clich&eacute; for what normally happens in this situation is more believable). Still, it's a great movie, and an excellent choice if you're looking for an intense action thriller.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vero1994
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very touching and exciting movie! You really get to feel for the characters and the image of movie sticks with you for a while. There is a combination of strong, emancipated but hopeless women, drama, tension, romance and Queen Latifah as a lesbian ;) You follow the life of four women who have financial problems, most of them due to injustice caused by police and government. They also have lost or are bout to lose their loved ones. This pushes them over the edge and they decide to rob a bank. When watching the movie you really feel their inner struggle and how they feel they have no other choice. I loved every part of it. Definitely worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch if you want to get back at "whitey"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charlesbeutt
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you take 0 responsibility for getting an education and trying to succeed, then this movie is for you. Simply blame "the system" for why you are poor, stupid, and unqualified for a higher paying job and sit back in your easy chair and watch some African Americans "stick it to da man". I wonder, do African Americans watch movies like this and think its racist against blacks? Sure the "heroes" are all black and you knew the lead cop would be white. But escaping the Ghetto because you are tired of robbing and murder, by committing robbing and murder? All while cackling every 5 seconds, and saying "we probably gonna die anyway", or you're "mad at society". "Get rich or die trying" doesn't always end with people getting rich.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If Darnell Could Take A Bank We Could Take A Bank.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kylehaines96
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    F. Gary Gray the director of Friday takes a turn from comedy to drama in a film people call a rip off of The Town. I disagree because this came out 14 years earlier. This a very underrated film that sadly a lot of people have dismissed. The film is about a group of four women played by Vivica A. Fox, Queen Latifa, Jada Pinkett Smith and Kimberly Elise who rob a bank to get money for Kimberly Elise because her child has been taken away by child protective services. After getting the thrill from robbing a bank for the first time and decide to do again this time they get more money. They then want to rob one last bank this time running away to another country with the money. This is a underrated gem. The film is very well paced and has great suspense. The group of 4 leading ladies have great chemistry together and has a very nice storyline to go along with it. Definnetly check this one out. Rated R For Strong Graphic Violence, Pervasive Language, Some Sex And Drug Use. Theatrical Cut: 2hrs 1min/121min. Directors Cut: 2hrs 4min/124min. 126 uses of the F-word. ****/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When Babes Rob Banks . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director F. Gary Gary treats the the plight of a quartet of blue-collar African-American women with great sympathy in "Set It Off." Each of these women have experienced adversity first hand and the idea is that they have been dealt a bad hand by destiny. One woman prostitutes herself to ensure that her brother gets to go to college, but she finds out later that her efforts were for naught. Another woman is implicated in a bank robbery simply because she knew the man who robbed her bank and didn't follow the procedures that she had been drilled in. Another woman is a single parent who has to work one job to pay the babysitter. Finally, the fourth member who is the least sympathetic is a lesbian who has been restoring her car since the seventh grade. These closely-knit friends take their lumps but decide that whatever a man can do, they can do better. Consequently, they embark on a life of crime in this predictable, often contrived, but nevertheless entertaining crime thriller. Clearly, the moral of the story is don't rob banks. If you know somebody robbing a bank, you must behave as if you don't know them. Never, never, never--if you are a single-parent--ever bring your unattended infant to the workplace. Crime doesn't pay and "Set It Off" makes it abundantly clearly as three out of the four survive. The fourth escapes because somebody on the other side allows them to getaway. The performances are sometimes a little too over the top, especially Jada Pinkett and Vivica A. Fox. If you abhor profanity, prepare yourself for an onslaught of the F-bomb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Action Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaguar_alignment
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember that i saw this movie when it launched in 1996. The appealing performance of the characters introduced a new area for action drama. The performance of the women Is marvelous and the story line Is breath taking. I watched this movie again yesterday and the story never gets doll. It's safe to say that this Is one of the greatest action 'movies out there. I'm looking forward seeing more of these dramatic action movies, since they portrait a more realistic image and get you to empathizes with the characters - even when there villains! Many compliments to the directors and total cast of this movie production.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Four Stooges Rob a Bank
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kvatter
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A coincidental but unlikely stream of bad luck among four women leads them all to the only solution to their problems--rob a bank. And so begins a tale of silliness. Things happen in this film that just can't be believed no matter how much one tries to check the brain at the door. Four women are doing janitorial work. One brings her kid to the job. All four turn their backs together and as quick as you can say, "contrived", the kid is under a sink drinking ammonia. The main detective character knows exactly who is behind it and wants permission to follow up on the suspects but the boss says no because the police have accidentally killed the one suspect's brother. We wouldn't want to upset them despite the overwhelming evidence against them. And then they are never watched as they enter bank after bank to rob them. In one ridiculous scene, they stand in the hallway adjusting their wigs and dark glasses disguises arguing whether or not to rob the place. No one is suspicious of these characters outside the bank entrance?? And one very glaring goof-up is when they have breakfast and then head right off to the robbery(Vivica Fox is sporting a designer baseball cap turned backwards so you know she means business) . As soon as they finish the robbery,it's suddenly night time. The flick is chock full of clich&eacute; lines and actions. The tough Queen Latifah has just driven through a line of heavily armed police who open fire on her car, turning it into swiss cheese, yet she manages to take a very long pause and then emerge with a machine gun blazing. You'll slap a knee at that scene. EVERYONE in this movie is trigger happy. All the cops and security guards shoot to kill at the blink of an eye. The main detective spends several scenes just trying to get people to hold their fire. I gave it three stars because it's so darned goofy that you will probably be entertained at the implausibility of it all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slang is a big 'thang'...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Howlin Wolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    All of the women were "hoodrats", (term borrowed from an IMDb boards user; it isn't my own... ) which was a shame, because they didn't need to be. Why does the only black main character who has any kind of class or sophistication have to be a GUY?! (In a film that's primarily about four women, no less!) I'm pretty sure it does a great disservice to the many black women out there who do manage to be articulate whatever their circumstances happen to be. ... and don't tell me that if they weren't hoodrats then they wouldn't be robbing banks. People at the end of their tether do desperate things. (John Q. for example; again a guy.) The film was good and enjoyable, but they had a big chance to give us some intelligent female characterisations for a change; only with the dialogue they gave them to speak, they blew it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm all for fantasy films but not when it's supposed to be taken seriously as an action film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stephanie Gilleland
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this film a long time ago (aprox 10 years or so) and liked it then. I remembered it the other day and decided to watch it again. The second time around was not pleasant. The acting is 'so,so', the plot is illogical, unreasonable and predictable. The acting...I'm sure it wasn't a stretch for those actresses to play those characters. The plot...there's no way in hell those women would have gotten away with the first robbery much less the 2nd. (side note: Why did TT not realise that even if she came up with a load of money for her court date they would ask where she got it and she would have no logical answer! Ding, Ding...we have a crook!). It horribly stereotyped black women in saying basically that the only way black women can 'beat the system' or obtain a large amount of money was to steal it and not use their intelligence or other resources. It plays too much on sympathy b/c all of them die in the end (bar Jada) but it's not sad (you're thinking 'They were so stupid; they deserve to die). You just don't really care about the characters unless you're a shallow person. I can't believe this film rates over a 5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visceral, hard-hitting action film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sonya90028
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set It Off is an explosive drama about four young black women, who are best friends. Living in the Los Angeles ghetto, each of them struggles with economic and emotional hardships. All of them suffer deeply, due to injustices perpetrated against them by their employers, trigger-happy cops, and the welfare bureaucracy. Fed-up with how life has knocked them around, and desperate to escape the ghetto, the four friends decide to resort to robbing banks together. This film is very fast-paced, with gripping suspense throughout the course of the movie. There's scarcely a dull moment. This movie is overflowing with tire-screeching car chases, blazing gunfire, and volatile interactions between the characters. The breath-taking action sequences really draw you in to the precarious world, of the criminal quartet. It's good that Hollywood finally decided to make a film, that has African-American female characters who make such a deep impact. They're just as rough, vulgar, and determined to change their lives for the better, as any of the male characters are. They're deadly serious about being willing to risk their lives, to take up criminal activities. The women in the film, don't depend on men to determine their course of action. They know that it's up to them alone, to work together to accomplish their bank heists. The four actresses who played the main characters, all give strong performances. Especially Queen Latifah as the hardened butch lesbian, Cleo Simms. She really makes the viewer believe that Cleo can fearlessly handle just about anything, that she's up against. Jada Pinkett also gives a compelling performance as Stoney. Pinkett shows an amazing emotional range, and is able to convey the contradictory moods of Stoney with ease. Vivica Fox as Frankie, is vivid in her role, but not quite as charismatic as either Queen Latifah, or Jada Pinkett. Kimberley Elise as the desperate single mother, Tisean, gives a heartrending performance. This film crackles with a heady intensity, that's rare in films with women as the main characters. These sistahs prove that they are forces to be reckoned with, as they fight for their dreams in a male dominated world. This cutting-edge action film, delivers jolt-after-jolt of exciting entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great action flick, despite its flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviesleuth2
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies like this don't come across very often. A movie that makes you care about the characters and what happens to them. It's especially rare in this genre. But what makes "Set it Off," F. Gary Gray's second feature, stand out is that it does what few films take the time to do: it develops its characters and makes the audience care about them. Stoney (Jada Pinkett Smith), Cleo (Queen Latifah), Frankie (Vivica A. Fox) and Tisean (Kimberly Elise) have been close friends for years. At the movie's beginning, we find that each one of them has been wronged by society because of money. Desperate to get out of their minimum-wage lives, the four turn to bank robbery to help them get out. "Set it Off" would be another dull, violent action movie had it not been for four superlative performances. Jada Pinkett Smith is one of the strongest actresses out there, and here she gets to flex the acting muscles that she showed in "Menace II Society." It's a terrific performance. She is the most developed (and human) of the characters. It's not perfect; Smith is at her best when she's low-key, so she's not as effective when she has to really emote (though she is by no means "bad" when she does. Likewise, Vivica A. Fox is terrific as the single-minded and bitter Frankie; she was wronged and she wants revenge. Fox wisely doesn't try to get the audience to SYMPATHIZE with her (that sort of happens naturally), but she tries, and succeeds, to get the audience to EMPATHIZE with her. Queen Latifah is a strong actress, and despite being made nearly a decade before her Oscar-nominated turn in "Chicago" where she really make it into the big time, her performance here shows why it is a shame why her acting ability wasn't recognized earlier in her career. Newcomer Kimberly Elise shines as the shy, meek Tisean; she's so good it's hard to believe that this is her debut film performance, and her later work shows that it wasn't a fluke. The supporting actors are great as well. Blair Underwood finds the perfect note for Stoney's romantic foil. He's charming, but not smothering; romantic, but not straight out of a soap opera. He's intelligent, and knows he has nothing in common with Stoney. But he really tries to win her heart, and that's what makes him so likable. John C. McGinley is less successful as the cop who ties everything together. While he's not bad, in fact he's pretty good (his scenes where he has to admit his wrongdoings are terrific), he's not up to par with the other actors. But considering the strength in the performances by the four leads, this shouldn't be construed to indicate that his performance is subpar. Also of note is Charles Robinson, who despite being on screen for only two scenes, creates one of the most despicable and disgusting characters I have ever seen. He's so vile that his character sticks with you for a long time. This is not a chick flick. Despite what it seems like it might be, I can't stress this enough: "Set it Off" is NOT A CHICK FLICK! It's an action movie, and director F. Gary Gray keeps it that way. He develops his characters so that everyone can grow to care about them. His direction is fresh and alive, especially in the action sequences which are expertly choreographed. This is a no-holds-barred action thriller and all the better for it. "Set it Off" isn't perfect. Some of the plot elements are quite contrived, and one of the scenes features a catalyst so dumb its appalling that someone didn't require a rewrite (even the clich&eacute; for what normally happens in this situation is more believable). Still, it's a great movie, and an excellent choice if you're looking for an intense action thriller.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vero1994
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very touching and exciting movie! You really get to feel for the characters and the image of movie sticks with you for a while. There is a combination of strong, emancipated but hopeless women, drama, tension, romance and Queen Latifah as a lesbian ;) You follow the life of four women who have financial problems, most of them due to injustice caused by police and government. They also have lost or are bout to lose their loved ones. This pushes them over the edge and they decide to rob a bank. When watching the movie you really feel their inner struggle and how they feel they have no other choice. I loved every part of it. Definitely worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch if you want to get back at "whitey"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charlesbeutt
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you take 0 responsibility for getting an education and trying to succeed, then this movie is for you. Simply blame "the system" for why you are poor, stupid, and unqualified for a higher paying job and sit back in your easy chair and watch some African Americans "stick it to da man". I wonder, do African Americans watch movies like this and think its racist against blacks? Sure the "heroes" are all black and you knew the lead cop would be white. But escaping the Ghetto because you are tired of robbing and murder, by committing robbing and murder? All while cackling every 5 seconds, and saying "we probably gonna die anyway", or you're "mad at society". "Get rich or die trying" doesn't always end with people getting rich.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If Darnell Could Take A Bank We Could Take A Bank.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kylehaines96
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    F. Gary Gray the director of Friday takes a turn from comedy to drama in a film people call a rip off of The Town. I disagree because this came out 14 years earlier. This a very underrated film that sadly a lot of people have dismissed. The film is about a group of four women played by Vivica A. Fox, Queen Latifa, Jada Pinkett Smith and Kimberly Elise who rob a bank to get money for Kimberly Elise because her child has been taken away by child protective services. After getting the thrill from robbing a bank for the first time and decide to do again this time they get more money. They then want to rob one last bank this time running away to another country with the money. This is a underrated gem. The film is very well paced and has great suspense. The group of 4 leading ladies have great chemistry together and has a very nice storyline to go along with it. Definnetly check this one out. Rated R For Strong Graphic Violence, Pervasive Language, Some Sex And Drug Use. Theatrical Cut: 2hrs 1min/121min. Directors Cut: 2hrs 4min/124min. 126 uses of the F-word. ****/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When Babes Rob Banks . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director F. Gary Gary treats the the plight of a quartet of blue-collar African-American women with great sympathy in "Set It Off." Each of these women have experienced adversity first hand and the idea is that they have been dealt a bad hand by destiny. One woman prostitutes herself to ensure that her brother gets to go to college, but she finds out later that her efforts were for naught. Another woman is implicated in a bank robbery simply because she knew the man who robbed her bank and didn't follow the procedures that she had been drilled in. Another woman is a single parent who has to work one job to pay the babysitter. Finally, the fourth member who is the least sympathetic is a lesbian who has been restoring her car since the seventh grade. These closely-knit friends take their lumps but decide that whatever a man can do, they can do better. Consequently, they embark on a life of crime in this predictable, often contrived, but nevertheless entertaining crime thriller. Clearly, the moral of the story is don't rob banks. If you know somebody robbing a bank, you must behave as if you don't know them. Never, never, never--if you are a single-parent--ever bring your unattended infant to the workplace. Crime doesn't pay and "Set It Off" makes it abundantly clearly as three out of the four survive. The fourth escapes because somebody on the other side allows them to getaway. The performances are sometimes a little too over the top, especially Jada Pinkett and Vivica A. Fox. If you abhor profanity, prepare yourself for an onslaught of the F-bomb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Action Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaguar_alignment
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember that i saw this movie when it launched in 1996. The appealing performance of the characters introduced a new area for action drama. The performance of the women Is marvelous and the story line Is breath taking. I watched this movie again yesterday and the story never gets doll. It's safe to say that this Is one of the greatest action 'movies out there. I'm looking forward seeing more of these dramatic action movies, since they portrait a more realistic image and get you to empathizes with the characters - even when there villains! Many compliments to the directors and total cast of this movie production.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Four Stooges Rob a Bank
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kvatter
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A coincidental but unlikely stream of bad luck among four women leads them all to the only solution to their problems--rob a bank. And so begins a tale of silliness. Things happen in this film that just can't be believed no matter how much one tries to check the brain at the door. Four women are doing janitorial work. One brings her kid to the job. All four turn their backs together and as quick as you can say, "contrived", the kid is under a sink drinking ammonia. The main detective character knows exactly who is behind it and wants permission to follow up on the suspects but the boss says no because the police have accidentally killed the one suspect's brother. We wouldn't want to upset them despite the overwhelming evidence against them. And then they are never watched as they enter bank after bank to rob them. In one ridiculous scene, they stand in the hallway adjusting their wigs and dark glasses disguises arguing whether or not to rob the place. No one is suspicious of these characters outside the bank entrance?? And one very glaring goof-up is when they have breakfast and then head right off to the robbery(Vivica Fox is sporting a designer baseball cap turned backwards so you know she means business) . As soon as they finish the robbery,it's suddenly night time. The flick is chock full of clich&eacute; lines and actions. The tough Queen Latifah has just driven through a line of heavily armed police who open fire on her car, turning it into swiss cheese, yet she manages to take a very long pause and then emerge with a machine gun blazing. You'll slap a knee at that scene. EVERYONE in this movie is trigger happy. All the cops and security guards shoot to kill at the blink of an eye. The main detective spends several scenes just trying to get people to hold their fire. I gave it three stars because it's so darned goofy that you will probably be entertained at the implausibility of it all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slang is a big 'thang'...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Howlin Wolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    All of the women were "hoodrats", (term borrowed from an IMDb boards user; it isn't my own... ) which was a shame, because they didn't need to be. Why does the only black main character who has any kind of class or sophistication have to be a GUY?! (In a film that's primarily about four women, no less!) I'm pretty sure it does a great disservice to the many black women out there who do manage to be articulate whatever their circumstances happen to be. ... and don't tell me that if they weren't hoodrats then they wouldn't be robbing banks. People at the end of their tether do desperate things. (John Q. for example; again a guy.) The film was good and enjoyable, but they had a big chance to give us some intelligent female characterisations for a change; only with the dialogue they gave them to speak, they blew it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm all for fantasy films but not when it's supposed to be taken seriously as an action film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stephanie Gilleland
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this film a long time ago (aprox 10 years or so) and liked it then. I remembered it the other day and decided to watch it again. The second time around was not pleasant. The acting is 'so,so', the plot is illogical, unreasonable and predictable. The acting...I'm sure it wasn't a stretch for those actresses to play those characters. The plot...there's no way in hell those women would have gotten away with the first robbery much less the 2nd. (side note: Why did TT not realise that even if she came up with a load of money for her court date they would ask where she got it and she would have no logical answer! Ding, Ding...we have a crook!). It horribly stereotyped black women in saying basically that the only way black women can 'beat the system' or obtain a large amount of money was to steal it and not use their intelligence or other resources. It plays too much on sympathy b/c all of them die in the end (bar Jada) but it's not sad (you're thinking 'They were so stupid; they deserve to die). You just don't really care about the characters unless you're a shallow person. I can't believe this film rates over a 5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visceral, hard-hitting action film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sonya90028
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set It Off is an explosive drama about four young black women, who are best friends. Living in the Los Angeles ghetto, each of them struggles with economic and emotional hardships. All of them suffer deeply, due to injustices perpetrated against them by their employers, trigger-happy cops, and the welfare bureaucracy. Fed-up with how life has knocked them around, and desperate to escape the ghetto, the four friends decide to resort to robbing banks together. This film is very fast-paced, with gripping suspense throughout the course of the movie. There's scarcely a dull moment. This movie is overflowing with tire-screeching car chases, blazing gunfire, and volatile interactions between the characters. The breath-taking action sequences really draw you in to the precarious world, of the criminal quartet. It's good that Hollywood finally decided to make a film, that has African-American female characters who make such a deep impact. They're just as rough, vulgar, and determined to change their lives for the better, as any of the male characters are. They're deadly serious about being willing to risk their lives, to take up criminal activities. The women in the film, don't depend on men to determine their course of action. They know that it's up to them alone, to work together to accomplish their bank heists. The four actresses who played the main characters, all give strong performances. Especially Queen Latifah as the hardened butch lesbian, Cleo Simms. She really makes the viewer believe that Cleo can fearlessly handle just about anything, that she's up against. Jada Pinkett also gives a compelling performance as Stoney. Pinkett shows an amazing emotional range, and is able to convey the contradictory moods of Stoney with ease. Vivica Fox as Frankie, is vivid in her role, but not quite as charismatic as either Queen Latifah, or Jada Pinkett. Kimberley Elise as the desperate single mother, Tisean, gives a heartrending performance. This film crackles with a heady intensity, that's rare in films with women as the main characters. These sistahs prove that they are forces to be reckoned with, as they fight for their dreams in a male dominated world. This cutting-edge action film, delivers jolt-after-jolt of exciting entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great action flick, despite its flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviesleuth2
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies like this don't come across very often. A movie that makes you care about the characters and what happens to them. It's especially rare in this genre. But what makes "Set it Off," F. Gary Gray's second feature, stand out is that it does what few films take the time to do: it develops its characters and makes the audience care about them. Stoney (Jada Pinkett Smith), Cleo (Queen Latifah), Frankie (Vivica A. Fox) and Tisean (Kimberly Elise) have been close friends for years. At the movie's beginning, we find that each one of them has been wronged by society because of money. Desperate to get out of their minimum-wage lives, the four turn to bank robbery to help them get out. "Set it Off" would be another dull, violent action movie had it not been for four superlative performances. Jada Pinkett Smith is one of the strongest actresses out there, and here she gets to flex the acting muscles that she showed in "Menace II Society." It's a terrific performance. She is the most developed (and human) of the characters. It's not perfect; Smith is at her best when she's low-key, so she's not as effective when she has to really emote (though she is by no means "bad" when she does. Likewise, Vivica A. Fox is terrific as the single-minded and bitter Frankie; she was wronged and she wants revenge. Fox wisely doesn't try to get the audience to SYMPATHIZE with her (that sort of happens naturally), but she tries, and succeeds, to get the audience to EMPATHIZE with her. Queen Latifah is a strong actress, and despite being made nearly a decade before her Oscar-nominated turn in "Chicago" where she really make it into the big time, her performance here shows why it is a shame why her acting ability wasn't recognized earlier in her career. Newcomer Kimberly Elise shines as the shy, meek Tisean; she's so good it's hard to believe that this is her debut film performance, and her later work shows that it wasn't a fluke. The supporting actors are great as well. Blair Underwood finds the perfect note for Stoney's romantic foil. He's charming, but not smothering; romantic, but not straight out of a soap opera. He's intelligent, and knows he has nothing in common with Stoney. But he really tries to win her heart, and that's what makes him so likable. John C. McGinley is less successful as the cop who ties everything together. While he's not bad, in fact he's pretty good (his scenes where he has to admit his wrongdoings are terrific), he's not up to par with the other actors. But considering the strength in the performances by the four leads, this shouldn't be construed to indicate that his performance is subpar. Also of note is Charles Robinson, who despite being on screen for only two scenes, creates one of the most despicable and disgusting characters I have ever seen. He's so vile that his character sticks with you for a long time. This is not a chick flick. Despite what it seems like it might be, I can't stress this enough: "Set it Off" is NOT A CHICK FLICK! It's an action movie, and director F. Gary Gray keeps it that way. He develops his characters so that everyone can grow to care about them. His direction is fresh and alive, especially in the action sequences which are expertly choreographed. This is a no-holds-barred action thriller and all the better for it. "Set it Off" isn't perfect. Some of the plot elements are quite contrived, and one of the scenes features a catalyst so dumb its appalling that someone didn't require a rewrite (even the clich&eacute; for what normally happens in this situation is more believable). Still, it's a great movie, and an excellent choice if you're looking for an intense action thriller.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vero1994
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very touching and exciting movie! You really get to feel for the characters and the image of movie sticks with you for a while. There is a combination of strong, emancipated but hopeless women, drama, tension, romance and Queen Latifah as a lesbian ;) You follow the life of four women who have financial problems, most of them due to injustice caused by police and government. They also have lost or are bout to lose their loved ones. This pushes them over the edge and they decide to rob a bank. When watching the movie you really feel their inner struggle and how they feel they have no other choice. I loved every part of it. Definitely worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch if you want to get back at "whitey"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charlesbeutt
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you take 0 responsibility for getting an education and trying to succeed, then this movie is for you. Simply blame "the system" for why you are poor, stupid, and unqualified for a higher paying job and sit back in your easy chair and watch some African Americans "stick it to da man". I wonder, do African Americans watch movies like this and think its racist against blacks? Sure the "heroes" are all black and you knew the lead cop would be white. But escaping the Ghetto because you are tired of robbing and murder, by committing robbing and murder? All while cackling every 5 seconds, and saying "we probably gonna die anyway", or you're "mad at society". "Get rich or die trying" doesn't always end with people getting rich.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If Darnell Could Take A Bank We Could Take A Bank.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kylehaines96
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    F. Gary Gray the director of Friday takes a turn from comedy to drama in a film people call a rip off of The Town. I disagree because this came out 14 years earlier. This a very underrated film that sadly a lot of people have dismissed. The film is about a group of four women played by Vivica A. Fox, Queen Latifa, Jada Pinkett Smith and Kimberly Elise who rob a bank to get money for Kimberly Elise because her child has been taken away by child protective services. After getting the thrill from robbing a bank for the first time and decide to do again this time they get more money. They then want to rob one last bank this time running away to another country with the money. This is a underrated gem. The film is very well paced and has great suspense. The group of 4 leading ladies have great chemistry together and has a very nice storyline to go along with it. Definnetly check this one out. Rated R For Strong Graphic Violence, Pervasive Language, Some Sex And Drug Use. Theatrical Cut: 2hrs 1min/121min. Directors Cut: 2hrs 4min/124min. 126 uses of the F-word. ****/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    When Babes Rob Banks . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director F. Gary Gary treats the the plight of a quartet of blue-collar African-American women with great sympathy in "Set It Off." Each of these women have experienced adversity first hand and the idea is that they have been dealt a bad hand by destiny. One woman prostitutes herself to ensure that her brother gets to go to college, but she finds out later that her efforts were for naught. Another woman is implicated in a bank robbery simply because she knew the man who robbed her bank and didn't follow the procedures that she had been drilled in. Another woman is a single parent who has to work one job to pay the babysitter. Finally, the fourth member who is the least sympathetic is a lesbian who has been restoring her car since the seventh grade. These closely-knit friends take their lumps but decide that whatever a man can do, they can do better. Consequently, they embark on a life of crime in this predictable, often contrived, but nevertheless entertaining crime thriller. Clearly, the moral of the story is don't rob banks. If you know somebody robbing a bank, you must behave as if you don't know them. Never, never, never--if you are a single-parent--ever bring your unattended infant to the workplace. Crime doesn't pay and "Set It Off" makes it abundantly clearly as three out of the four survive. The fourth escapes because somebody on the other side allows them to getaway. The performances are sometimes a little too over the top, especially Jada Pinkett and Vivica A. Fox. If you abhor profanity, prepare yourself for an onslaught of the F-bomb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Action Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaguar_alignment
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember that i saw this movie when it launched in 1996. The appealing performance of the characters introduced a new area for action drama. The performance of the women Is marvelous and the story line Is breath taking. I watched this movie again yesterday and the story never gets doll. It's safe to say that this Is one of the greatest action 'movies out there. I'm looking forward seeing more of these dramatic action movies, since they portrait a more realistic image and get you to empathizes with the characters - even when there villains! Many compliments to the directors and total cast of this movie production.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Four Stooges Rob a Bank
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kvatter
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A coincidental but unlikely stream of bad luck among four women leads them all to the only solution to their problems--rob a bank. And so begins a tale of silliness. Things happen in this film that just can't be believed no matter how much one tries to check the brain at the door. Four women are doing janitorial work. One brings her kid to the job. All four turn their backs together and as quick as you can say, "contrived", the kid is under a sink drinking ammonia. The main detective character knows exactly who is behind it and wants permission to follow up on the suspects but the boss says no because the police have accidentally killed the one suspect's brother. We wouldn't want to upset them despite the overwhelming evidence against them. And then they are never watched as they enter bank after bank to rob them. In one ridiculous scene, they stand in the hallway adjusting their wigs and dark glasses disguises arguing whether or not to rob the place. No one is suspicious of these characters outside the bank entrance?? And one very glaring goof-up is when they have breakfast and then head right off to the robbery(Vivica Fox is sporting a designer baseball cap turned backwards so you know she means business) . As soon as they finish the robbery,it's suddenly night time. The flick is chock full of clich&eacute; lines and actions. The tough Queen Latifah has just driven through a line of heavily armed police who open fire on her car, turning it into swiss cheese, yet she manages to take a very long pause and then emerge with a machine gun blazing. You'll slap a knee at that scene. EVERYONE in this movie is trigger happy. All the cops and security guards shoot to kill at the blink of an eye. The main detective spends several scenes just trying to get people to hold their fire. I gave it three stars because it's so darned goofy that you will probably be entertained at the implausibility of it all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slang is a big 'thang'...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Howlin Wolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    All of the women were "hoodrats", (term borrowed from an IMDb boards user; it isn't my own... ) which was a shame, because they didn't need to be. Why does the only black main character who has any kind of class or sophistication have to be a GUY?! (In a film that's primarily about four women, no less!) I'm pretty sure it does a great disservice to the many black women out there who do manage to be articulate whatever their circumstances happen to be. ... and don't tell me that if they weren't hoodrats then they wouldn't be robbing banks. People at the end of their tether do desperate things. (John Q. for example; again a guy.) The film was good and enjoyable, but they had a big chance to give us some intelligent female characterisations for a change; only with the dialogue they gave them to speak, they blew it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm all for fantasy films but not when it's supposed to be taken seriously as an action film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stephanie Gilleland
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this film a long time ago (aprox 10 years or so) and liked it then. I remembered it the other day and decided to watch it again. The second time around was not pleasant. The acting is 'so,so', the plot is illogical, unreasonable and predictable. The acting...I'm sure it wasn't a stretch for those actresses to play those characters. The plot...there's no way in hell those women would have gotten away with the first robbery much less the 2nd. (side note: Why did TT not realise that even if she came up with a load of money for her court date they would ask where she got it and she would have no logical answer! Ding, Ding...we have a crook!). It horribly stereotyped black women in saying basically that the only way black women can 'beat the system' or obtain a large amount of money was to steal it and not use their intelligence or other resources. It plays too much on sympathy b/c all of them die in the end (bar Jada) but it's not sad (you're thinking 'They were so stupid; they deserve to die). You just don't really care about the characters unless you're a shallow person. I can't believe this film rates over a 5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visceral, hard-hitting action film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sonya90028
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set It Off is an explosive drama about four young black women, who are best friends. Living in the Los Angeles ghetto, each of them struggles with economic and emotional hardships. All of them suffer deeply, due to injustices perpetrated against them by their employers, trigger-happy cops, and the welfare bureaucracy. Fed-up with how life has knocked them around, and desperate to escape the ghetto, the four friends decide to resort to robbing banks together. This film is very fast-paced, with gripping suspense throughout the course of the movie. There's scarcely a dull moment. This movie is overflowing with tire-screeching car chases, blazing gunfire, and volatile interactions between the characters. The breath-taking action sequences really draw you in to the precarious world, of the criminal quartet. It's good that Hollywood finally decided to make a film, that has African-American female characters who make such a deep impact. They're just as rough, vulgar, and determined to change their lives for the better, as any of the male characters are. They're deadly serious about being willing to risk their lives, to take up criminal activities. The women in the film, don't depend on men to determine their course of action. They know that it's up to them alone, to work together to accomplish their bank heists. The four actresses who played the main characters, all give strong performances. Especially Queen Latifah as the hardened butch lesbian, Cleo Simms. She really makes the viewer believe that Cleo can fearlessly handle just about anything, that she's up against. Jada Pinkett also gives a compelling performance as Stoney. Pinkett shows an amazing emotional range, and is able to convey the contradictory moods of Stoney with ease. Vivica Fox as Frankie, is vivid in her role, but not quite as charismatic as either Queen Latifah, or Jada Pinkett. Kimberley Elise as the desperate single mother, Tisean, gives a heartrending performance. This film crackles with a heady intensity, that's rare in films with women as the main characters. These sistahs prove that they are forces to be reckoned with, as they fight for their dreams in a male dominated world. This cutting-edge action film, delivers jolt-after-jolt of exciting entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great action flick, despite its flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviesleuth2
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies like this don't come across very often. A movie that makes you care about the characters and what happens to them. It's especially rare in this genre. But what makes "Set it Off," F. Gary Gray's second feature, stand out is that it does what few films take the time to do: it develops its characters and makes the audience care about them. Stoney (Jada Pinkett Smith), Cleo (Queen Latifah), Frankie (Vivica A. Fox) and Tisean (Kimberly Elise) have been close friends for years. At the movie's beginning, we find that each one of them has been wronged by society because of money. Desperate to get out of their minimum-wage lives, the four turn to bank robbery to help them get out. "Set it Off" would be another dull, violent action movie had it not been for four superlative performances. Jada Pinkett Smith is one of the strongest actresses out there, and here she gets to flex the acting muscles that she showed in "Menace II Society." It's a terrific performance. She is the most developed (and human) of the characters. It's not perfect; Smith is at her best when she's low-key, so she's not as effective when she has to really emote (though she is by no means "bad" when she does. Likewise, Vivica A. Fox is terrific as the single-minded and bitter Frankie; she was wronged and she wants revenge. Fox wisely doesn't try to get the audience to SYMPATHIZE with her (that sort of happens naturally), but she tries, and succeeds, to get the audience to EMPATHIZE with her. Queen Latifah is a strong actress, and despite being made nearly a decade before her Oscar-nominated turn in "Chicago" where she really make it into the big time, her performance here shows why it is a shame why her acting ability wasn't recognized earlier in her career. Newcomer Kimberly Elise shines as the shy, meek Tisean; she's so good it's hard to believe that this is her debut film performance, and her later work shows that it wasn't a fluke. The supporting actors are great as well. Blair Underwood finds the perfect note for Stoney's romantic foil. He's charming, but not smothering; romantic, but not straight out of a soap opera. He's intelligent, and knows he has nothing in common with Stoney. But he really tries to win her heart, and that's what makes him so likable. John C. McGinley is less successful as the cop who ties everything together. While he's not bad, in fact he's pretty good (his scenes where he has to admit his wrongdoings are terrific), he's not up to par with the other actors. But considering the strength in the performances by the four leads, this shouldn't be construed to indicate that his performance is subpar. Also of note is Charles Robinson, who despite being on screen for only two scenes, creates one of the most despicable and disgusting characters I have ever seen. He's so vile that his character sticks with you for a long time. This is not a chick flick. Despite what it seems like it might be, I can't stress this enough: "Set it Off" is NOT A CHICK FLICK! It's an action movie, and director F. Gary Gray keeps it that way. He develops his characters so that everyone can grow to care about them. His direction is fresh and alive, especially in the action sequences which are expertly choreographed. This is a no-holds-barred action thriller and all the better for it. "Set it Off" isn't perfect. Some of the plot elements are quite contrived, and one of the scenes features a catalyst so dumb its appalling that someone didn't require a rewrite (even the clich&eacute; for what normally happens in this situation is more believable). Still, it's a great movie, and an excellent choice if you're looking for an intense action thriller.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
