<filme>
 <id>
  1278
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120094
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Selena
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The true story of Selena Quintanilla-Perez, a Texas-born Tejano singer who rose from cult status to performing at the Astrodome, as well as having chart topping albums on the Latin music charts.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  The film tells the story of the life of Mexican "Tejano" style singer Selena Quintanilla-Perez and the progress of her career resulting in her No. 1 US album.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Biography
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Music
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   singer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   tejano
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   texas
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   marriage
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   racial segregation
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Gregory Nava
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Gregory Nava
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jennifer Lopez
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Edward James Olmos
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jon Seda
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jennifer Lopez Shines As Selena
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Selena is a biographical drama about the life and career of the late Tejano music star Selena, a recording artist who was well known in the United States and Mexico before she was shot to death.It stars Jennifer Lopez as Selena.Edward James Olmos and Constance Marie co-stars.It was written and directed by Gregory Nava. This film concentrates on Selena's relationship with her family and her rise to fame, dealing only briefly with her tragic death. Abraham Quintanilla is a veteran musician who leads a family-based singing group, The Dinos. At a young age, he notices that his daughter Selena has a strong singing voice, and he works her into the act. However, as she grows older, Selena wants to establish her own musical identity; while her heritage is Mexican-American, her primary language is English, and her favorite artists are American pop acts like Donna Summer. While Selena and Abraham sometimes argue about the musical direction of the group, he always respects and supports her talent, and her blend of Tejano roots music and danceable pop rhythms soon sparks a revolution in Latin music. Selena later earns the wrath of her father when she becomes romantically involved with Chris Perez, a rebellious and long-haired guitarist hired to play with the group, but when they elope and Selena convinces Abraham that their love is sincere, Chris is welcomed into the family. After a long string of successes on the Latin charts and playing to a sellout crowd at the Houston Astrodome and a crowd of 100,000 at a stadium in Monterey, Mexico, Selena begins recording her first album in English, which is expected to make her a mainstream star. However, the fates decreed it was an album she would never complete. The movie surmounts its connect-the-dots approach to its heroine's life to create an appealing, energetic look at a too-briefly soaring musical star.Also,it is a simple story of hope and triumph, of one girl with the drive to succeed defying the odds and following her dream that could truly inspire the viewer to achieve their goals.Finally,Jennifer Lopez truly shines in her performance in the title role as she elevates the film immensely with her radiant and energetic performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Selena Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lexi Philip-Neri
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I never really knew of Selena until I first watched the Selena movie. I must say I was very young when she died so I didn't know much of what happened until I saw the movie. From the first time I saw Selena I fell in love with this movie. Selena is one of my all time favorite movies. The movie Selena starts with her at a young age and ends with the day she dies. I really like how the movie incorporated her childhood and how her music business started because it is an important key part of her life. In the movie they also incorporated the use of the real Selena's voice when they show her making her music and in her concerts--I thought that was a brilliant idea. Since I have seen the movie Selena, I now enjoy listening to Selena's Tejano music. Overall the movie is very well put together and shows the most significant parts of her life to show her success. I highly recommend this movie to anyone who has not seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Selena: When Fairy Tales End With A Bullet ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fairy-tale of Mexican-American singer Selena, whose life was cut short by her bookkeeper. There is still another wonderful Edward James Olmos performance as her protective father. As he did as Jaime Escalante, an LA high school math teacher, Olmos commands the screen as the dominant force in his daughter's life. A hard worker who strove for more, the Olmos character did know when it was time to relent. The film is often clich&eacute;. Presto, and Selena was a star of great magnitude. While Jennifer Lopez did an admirable job, she is still Jennifer and in some scenes, she sounded as she did up against Ralph Fiennes in "Maid in Manhattan."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Muy...Muy....Exciting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    terrellrobinson71
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was afraid of this movie when I was a kid, but when I grew up, I realized that "hay mas a esta historia que el ojo" (Translation: "There's more to this story than meets the eye".) The biopic Selena is one of my favorite movies. The reason why is because in the 90's, Jennifer Lopez was a Fly Girl in the sketch comedy show "In Living Color", was co-starring in "Money Train" and "Blood and Wine" and made her biggest starring role yet, even before her music career went big. There was a few controversies involving the movie, where Lopez was a Puerto Rican from New York, and the real Selena was a Mexican-American from Texas. But then again, all of us accepted Lopez playing Selena and we enjoyed the way she made Selena a real star. In Gregory Nava's film, it begins and ends at the big concert for Selena to become a very huge crossover star at the Houston Astrodome in 1995. Then it really ends with the death of Selena being done by her insane employer (Lupe Ontiveros). (No name spoiler here, but you already know.) In the good ol' days in Corpus Christi, young Selena (Rebecca Lee Meza) was raised well by her father, Abraham (Edward James Olmos) who was in a failed band called the Dinos with two other friends back in the 50's. After hearing Selena sing "We Belong Together" with him, this sparks Abraham to bring The Dinos back to life. Who knew that years later, we get to meet Selena, all grown up and living "la vida dulce" (Translation: "The sweet life") as a Tejano star who would be the biggest Tejano star ever. During the movie, we get to see everything in a condensed, but fast, pace of 127 minutes, the relationship involving her family including mama Marcela (George Lopez's Constance Marie), her romantic relationship between the rock-and-roll guitar player, Chris Perez (Jon Seda), her music (done by the real Selena, not Lopez) and yes, we do get to meet Yolanda herself, with a lot of character developing. Lopez gave a really great performance as Selena, and with the help of Miranda Garrison's choreography, captures the essence of Selena, the way she talks, the way she moves and the way she delivers the energy. The same can be said for Olmos, who can be both funny and dramatic at the same time. (Please pay attention to the argument between Selena, Abraham and Chris.) He also delivers what should've been a washed-down speech about Mexican-Americans into a very smart and charismatic speech. Selena is "muy, muy entretenido" (Translation: "Very, very entertaining.") However, when you do get to the end of the film, there are hankies to be of good use when the candlelight vigils and the archival footage shows and the mourning of a fabulous star comes on-screen. It's very heartbreaking and very emotional in the way that has been done and the final image will make you cry in a good way to prove that she was still there with us after all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A biopic of an exceptional talent.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the heart-felt story of 23-year-old Selena Quintanilla-Perez,played flawlessly by Jennifer Lopez. Selena was a Texas born singer of Tejano music and going from a cult attraction to breaking into an international phenomenon. How factual this film is can be questionable; but very interesting nonetheless.As the rising star was showing brilliance, she was gunned down by the very president of her own fan club in 1995. Shown through flashbacks her father Abraham(Edward James Olmos), a typical stage father/manager, finally realizes how enormously talented and loved his daughter is. There is the extreme closeness of her family, the marriage to guitarist Chris Perez(Jon Seda)and the snowballing success being ended by tragedy(only dealt with via taped news reports). Actual Selena concert footage is used; and this film overflows with music. Enough can't be said of Lopez in her portrayal...she is so enjoyable, lovable and s-e-x-y! Others featured in the cast: Jackie Guerra, Constance Marle, Jacob Vargas, Rebecca Lee Mezza, Alex Meneses and Sal Lopez.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good movie..missing info
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Morenita052169
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They could have added more into background of saldivar and murder.... And leticia miller would have been a great choice to play Selena she has an eerie resemblance to Selena see for yourself Google leticia miller it's scary other than that pretty good flick, does Selena justice ....rest in peace Selena. burn in hell Yolanda. I think this is overall a good movie if your a Selena fan like me you will like it,I just wish it got more to the nitty gritty. Jennifer Lopez does her best job in this movie I think this is her best film. The costume design is also great.................................Selena was a great performer and a great person she will Be missed
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jennifer Lopez deserved an Oscar for this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    les6969
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought that Jennifer Lopez portrayal of Selena Quintanilla was nothing short of outstanding! Just how good it was can be seen at the very end where we see the real Selena Quintanilla and the likeness and movements that Ms Lopez carries off in the film can be seen in full. But there is much more to the film than a good impression. Jennifer Lopez goes through the full range of emotions and is very believable in every scene she is in. All the other cast members are also superb. My only criticism is why they changed the way she was actually shot? Selena Quintanilla was shot in a motel room and not on stage, but I guess this was done for dramatic effect?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sad, heartfelt, and funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scoobydoo1992-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When i first saw this movie, i did not know who Selena was, and of course i cried at the end but this movie was way more then a movie that you sit and watch you get into it and realize that this really happened and that you want to just cry. It is a sad movie and because it was true you really just want to cry more.I absolutely love the tag-line of the movie, you could not be more dead on with what the movie is really about. I am giving this movie 9/10 because it is truly amazing Go Jennifer Lopez Go Selena. Please go out and rent this movie because it was absolutely amazing and see one of the greatest singers this world has been blessed to hear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie sucked horribly!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruce McLaren
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Selena was not all that to begin with. I lived in the same neighborhood she did. I didn't know her personally, but heard enough about her to dislike her. When she died, I didn't much care. She was treated like a goddess here. Murels, paintings, renaming of the convention center, etc. Enough is enough. Her music was mediocre at best. Her dad was twice the ass he was portrayed in this movie. He was a selfish man who cared about no one but himself. His daughter died, and he used the opportunity to make an extra buck. This movie sucked, and was misleading as to the true nature of the incident and circumstances surrounding it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    false advertisement!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    taoseagle
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie did NOT portray the real Selena nor her family. They are very inconsiderate people. Very money hungry. They will literally "hurt" someone for it as well. Being in the tejano business, you know every band (since it is such a small market). I know bands that were involved with the Q Productions, and every band has been burned in one way or another. They did not get any royalties what so ever, contracts were breached, and the list goes on. At a show in Amarillo, Selena refused to sign autographs and her 1 1/2 hour concert turned into 25 mins because the concert hall was only half full. She was not dedicated to her fans, (it was even written in the Amarillo Globe News the day after). The movie really makes her and her family out to be generous and tight-knit. In actuality, A.B and his father do not get along. Lots of curse words thrown at each other(I witnessed it first hand). Poorly made. Made only for the money that would generate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jennifer Lopez Shines As Selena
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Selena is a biographical drama about the life and career of the late Tejano music star Selena, a recording artist who was well known in the United States and Mexico before she was shot to death.It stars Jennifer Lopez as Selena.Edward James Olmos and Constance Marie co-stars.It was written and directed by Gregory Nava. This film concentrates on Selena's relationship with her family and her rise to fame, dealing only briefly with her tragic death. Abraham Quintanilla is a veteran musician who leads a family-based singing group, The Dinos. At a young age, he notices that his daughter Selena has a strong singing voice, and he works her into the act. However, as she grows older, Selena wants to establish her own musical identity; while her heritage is Mexican-American, her primary language is English, and her favorite artists are American pop acts like Donna Summer. While Selena and Abraham sometimes argue about the musical direction of the group, he always respects and supports her talent, and her blend of Tejano roots music and danceable pop rhythms soon sparks a revolution in Latin music. Selena later earns the wrath of her father when she becomes romantically involved with Chris Perez, a rebellious and long-haired guitarist hired to play with the group, but when they elope and Selena convinces Abraham that their love is sincere, Chris is welcomed into the family. After a long string of successes on the Latin charts and playing to a sellout crowd at the Houston Astrodome and a crowd of 100,000 at a stadium in Monterey, Mexico, Selena begins recording her first album in English, which is expected to make her a mainstream star. However, the fates decreed it was an album she would never complete. The movie surmounts its connect-the-dots approach to its heroine's life to create an appealing, energetic look at a too-briefly soaring musical star.Also,it is a simple story of hope and triumph, of one girl with the drive to succeed defying the odds and following her dream that could truly inspire the viewer to achieve their goals.Finally,Jennifer Lopez truly shines in her performance in the title role as she elevates the film immensely with her radiant and energetic performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Selena Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lexi Philip-Neri
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I never really knew of Selena until I first watched the Selena movie. I must say I was very young when she died so I didn't know much of what happened until I saw the movie. From the first time I saw Selena I fell in love with this movie. Selena is one of my all time favorite movies. The movie Selena starts with her at a young age and ends with the day she dies. I really like how the movie incorporated her childhood and how her music business started because it is an important key part of her life. In the movie they also incorporated the use of the real Selena's voice when they show her making her music and in her concerts--I thought that was a brilliant idea. Since I have seen the movie Selena, I now enjoy listening to Selena's Tejano music. Overall the movie is very well put together and shows the most significant parts of her life to show her success. I highly recommend this movie to anyone who has not seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Selena: When Fairy Tales End With A Bullet ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fairy-tale of Mexican-American singer Selena, whose life was cut short by her bookkeeper. There is still another wonderful Edward James Olmos performance as her protective father. As he did as Jaime Escalante, an LA high school math teacher, Olmos commands the screen as the dominant force in his daughter's life. A hard worker who strove for more, the Olmos character did know when it was time to relent. The film is often clich&eacute;. Presto, and Selena was a star of great magnitude. While Jennifer Lopez did an admirable job, she is still Jennifer and in some scenes, she sounded as she did up against Ralph Fiennes in "Maid in Manhattan."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Muy...Muy....Exciting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    terrellrobinson71
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was afraid of this movie when I was a kid, but when I grew up, I realized that "hay mas a esta historia que el ojo" (Translation: "There's more to this story than meets the eye".) The biopic Selena is one of my favorite movies. The reason why is because in the 90's, Jennifer Lopez was a Fly Girl in the sketch comedy show "In Living Color", was co-starring in "Money Train" and "Blood and Wine" and made her biggest starring role yet, even before her music career went big. There was a few controversies involving the movie, where Lopez was a Puerto Rican from New York, and the real Selena was a Mexican-American from Texas. But then again, all of us accepted Lopez playing Selena and we enjoyed the way she made Selena a real star. In Gregory Nava's film, it begins and ends at the big concert for Selena to become a very huge crossover star at the Houston Astrodome in 1995. Then it really ends with the death of Selena being done by her insane employer (Lupe Ontiveros). (No name spoiler here, but you already know.) In the good ol' days in Corpus Christi, young Selena (Rebecca Lee Meza) was raised well by her father, Abraham (Edward James Olmos) who was in a failed band called the Dinos with two other friends back in the 50's. After hearing Selena sing "We Belong Together" with him, this sparks Abraham to bring The Dinos back to life. Who knew that years later, we get to meet Selena, all grown up and living "la vida dulce" (Translation: "The sweet life") as a Tejano star who would be the biggest Tejano star ever. During the movie, we get to see everything in a condensed, but fast, pace of 127 minutes, the relationship involving her family including mama Marcela (George Lopez's Constance Marie), her romantic relationship between the rock-and-roll guitar player, Chris Perez (Jon Seda), her music (done by the real Selena, not Lopez) and yes, we do get to meet Yolanda herself, with a lot of character developing. Lopez gave a really great performance as Selena, and with the help of Miranda Garrison's choreography, captures the essence of Selena, the way she talks, the way she moves and the way she delivers the energy. The same can be said for Olmos, who can be both funny and dramatic at the same time. (Please pay attention to the argument between Selena, Abraham and Chris.) He also delivers what should've been a washed-down speech about Mexican-Americans into a very smart and charismatic speech. Selena is "muy, muy entretenido" (Translation: "Very, very entertaining.") However, when you do get to the end of the film, there are hankies to be of good use when the candlelight vigils and the archival footage shows and the mourning of a fabulous star comes on-screen. It's very heartbreaking and very emotional in the way that has been done and the final image will make you cry in a good way to prove that she was still there with us after all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A biopic of an exceptional talent.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the heart-felt story of 23-year-old Selena Quintanilla-Perez,played flawlessly by Jennifer Lopez. Selena was a Texas born singer of Tejano music and going from a cult attraction to breaking into an international phenomenon. How factual this film is can be questionable; but very interesting nonetheless.As the rising star was showing brilliance, she was gunned down by the very president of her own fan club in 1995. Shown through flashbacks her father Abraham(Edward James Olmos), a typical stage father/manager, finally realizes how enormously talented and loved his daughter is. There is the extreme closeness of her family, the marriage to guitarist Chris Perez(Jon Seda)and the snowballing success being ended by tragedy(only dealt with via taped news reports). Actual Selena concert footage is used; and this film overflows with music. Enough can't be said of Lopez in her portrayal...she is so enjoyable, lovable and s-e-x-y! Others featured in the cast: Jackie Guerra, Constance Marle, Jacob Vargas, Rebecca Lee Mezza, Alex Meneses and Sal Lopez.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good movie..missing info
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Morenita052169
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They could have added more into background of saldivar and murder.... And leticia miller would have been a great choice to play Selena she has an eerie resemblance to Selena see for yourself Google leticia miller it's scary other than that pretty good flick, does Selena justice ....rest in peace Selena. burn in hell Yolanda. I think this is overall a good movie if your a Selena fan like me you will like it,I just wish it got more to the nitty gritty. Jennifer Lopez does her best job in this movie I think this is her best film. The costume design is also great.................................Selena was a great performer and a great person she will Be missed
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jennifer Lopez deserved an Oscar for this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    les6969
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought that Jennifer Lopez portrayal of Selena Quintanilla was nothing short of outstanding! Just how good it was can be seen at the very end where we see the real Selena Quintanilla and the likeness and movements that Ms Lopez carries off in the film can be seen in full. But there is much more to the film than a good impression. Jennifer Lopez goes through the full range of emotions and is very believable in every scene she is in. All the other cast members are also superb. My only criticism is why they changed the way she was actually shot? Selena Quintanilla was shot in a motel room and not on stage, but I guess this was done for dramatic effect?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sad, heartfelt, and funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scoobydoo1992-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When i first saw this movie, i did not know who Selena was, and of course i cried at the end but this movie was way more then a movie that you sit and watch you get into it and realize that this really happened and that you want to just cry. It is a sad movie and because it was true you really just want to cry more.I absolutely love the tag-line of the movie, you could not be more dead on with what the movie is really about. I am giving this movie 9/10 because it is truly amazing Go Jennifer Lopez Go Selena. Please go out and rent this movie because it was absolutely amazing and see one of the greatest singers this world has been blessed to hear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie sucked horribly!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruce McLaren
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Selena was not all that to begin with. I lived in the same neighborhood she did. I didn't know her personally, but heard enough about her to dislike her. When she died, I didn't much care. She was treated like a goddess here. Murels, paintings, renaming of the convention center, etc. Enough is enough. Her music was mediocre at best. Her dad was twice the ass he was portrayed in this movie. He was a selfish man who cared about no one but himself. His daughter died, and he used the opportunity to make an extra buck. This movie sucked, and was misleading as to the true nature of the incident and circumstances surrounding it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    false advertisement!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    taoseagle
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie did NOT portray the real Selena nor her family. They are very inconsiderate people. Very money hungry. They will literally "hurt" someone for it as well. Being in the tejano business, you know every band (since it is such a small market). I know bands that were involved with the Q Productions, and every band has been burned in one way or another. They did not get any royalties what so ever, contracts were breached, and the list goes on. At a show in Amarillo, Selena refused to sign autographs and her 1 1/2 hour concert turned into 25 mins because the concert hall was only half full. She was not dedicated to her fans, (it was even written in the Amarillo Globe News the day after). The movie really makes her and her family out to be generous and tight-knit. In actuality, A.B and his father do not get along. Lots of curse words thrown at each other(I witnessed it first hand). Poorly made. Made only for the money that would generate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jennifer Lopez Shines As Selena
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Selena is a biographical drama about the life and career of the late Tejano music star Selena, a recording artist who was well known in the United States and Mexico before she was shot to death.It stars Jennifer Lopez as Selena.Edward James Olmos and Constance Marie co-stars.It was written and directed by Gregory Nava. This film concentrates on Selena's relationship with her family and her rise to fame, dealing only briefly with her tragic death. Abraham Quintanilla is a veteran musician who leads a family-based singing group, The Dinos. At a young age, he notices that his daughter Selena has a strong singing voice, and he works her into the act. However, as she grows older, Selena wants to establish her own musical identity; while her heritage is Mexican-American, her primary language is English, and her favorite artists are American pop acts like Donna Summer. While Selena and Abraham sometimes argue about the musical direction of the group, he always respects and supports her talent, and her blend of Tejano roots music and danceable pop rhythms soon sparks a revolution in Latin music. Selena later earns the wrath of her father when she becomes romantically involved with Chris Perez, a rebellious and long-haired guitarist hired to play with the group, but when they elope and Selena convinces Abraham that their love is sincere, Chris is welcomed into the family. After a long string of successes on the Latin charts and playing to a sellout crowd at the Houston Astrodome and a crowd of 100,000 at a stadium in Monterey, Mexico, Selena begins recording her first album in English, which is expected to make her a mainstream star. However, the fates decreed it was an album she would never complete. The movie surmounts its connect-the-dots approach to its heroine's life to create an appealing, energetic look at a too-briefly soaring musical star.Also,it is a simple story of hope and triumph, of one girl with the drive to succeed defying the odds and following her dream that could truly inspire the viewer to achieve their goals.Finally,Jennifer Lopez truly shines in her performance in the title role as she elevates the film immensely with her radiant and energetic performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Selena Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lexi Philip-Neri
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I never really knew of Selena until I first watched the Selena movie. I must say I was very young when she died so I didn't know much of what happened until I saw the movie. From the first time I saw Selena I fell in love with this movie. Selena is one of my all time favorite movies. The movie Selena starts with her at a young age and ends with the day she dies. I really like how the movie incorporated her childhood and how her music business started because it is an important key part of her life. In the movie they also incorporated the use of the real Selena's voice when they show her making her music and in her concerts--I thought that was a brilliant idea. Since I have seen the movie Selena, I now enjoy listening to Selena's Tejano music. Overall the movie is very well put together and shows the most significant parts of her life to show her success. I highly recommend this movie to anyone who has not seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Selena: When Fairy Tales End With A Bullet ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fairy-tale of Mexican-American singer Selena, whose life was cut short by her bookkeeper. There is still another wonderful Edward James Olmos performance as her protective father. As he did as Jaime Escalante, an LA high school math teacher, Olmos commands the screen as the dominant force in his daughter's life. A hard worker who strove for more, the Olmos character did know when it was time to relent. The film is often clich&eacute;. Presto, and Selena was a star of great magnitude. While Jennifer Lopez did an admirable job, she is still Jennifer and in some scenes, she sounded as she did up against Ralph Fiennes in "Maid in Manhattan."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Muy...Muy....Exciting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    terrellrobinson71
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was afraid of this movie when I was a kid, but when I grew up, I realized that "hay mas a esta historia que el ojo" (Translation: "There's more to this story than meets the eye".) The biopic Selena is one of my favorite movies. The reason why is because in the 90's, Jennifer Lopez was a Fly Girl in the sketch comedy show "In Living Color", was co-starring in "Money Train" and "Blood and Wine" and made her biggest starring role yet, even before her music career went big. There was a few controversies involving the movie, where Lopez was a Puerto Rican from New York, and the real Selena was a Mexican-American from Texas. But then again, all of us accepted Lopez playing Selena and we enjoyed the way she made Selena a real star. In Gregory Nava's film, it begins and ends at the big concert for Selena to become a very huge crossover star at the Houston Astrodome in 1995. Then it really ends with the death of Selena being done by her insane employer (Lupe Ontiveros). (No name spoiler here, but you already know.) In the good ol' days in Corpus Christi, young Selena (Rebecca Lee Meza) was raised well by her father, Abraham (Edward James Olmos) who was in a failed band called the Dinos with two other friends back in the 50's. After hearing Selena sing "We Belong Together" with him, this sparks Abraham to bring The Dinos back to life. Who knew that years later, we get to meet Selena, all grown up and living "la vida dulce" (Translation: "The sweet life") as a Tejano star who would be the biggest Tejano star ever. During the movie, we get to see everything in a condensed, but fast, pace of 127 minutes, the relationship involving her family including mama Marcela (George Lopez's Constance Marie), her romantic relationship between the rock-and-roll guitar player, Chris Perez (Jon Seda), her music (done by the real Selena, not Lopez) and yes, we do get to meet Yolanda herself, with a lot of character developing. Lopez gave a really great performance as Selena, and with the help of Miranda Garrison's choreography, captures the essence of Selena, the way she talks, the way she moves and the way she delivers the energy. The same can be said for Olmos, who can be both funny and dramatic at the same time. (Please pay attention to the argument between Selena, Abraham and Chris.) He also delivers what should've been a washed-down speech about Mexican-Americans into a very smart and charismatic speech. Selena is "muy, muy entretenido" (Translation: "Very, very entertaining.") However, when you do get to the end of the film, there are hankies to be of good use when the candlelight vigils and the archival footage shows and the mourning of a fabulous star comes on-screen. It's very heartbreaking and very emotional in the way that has been done and the final image will make you cry in a good way to prove that she was still there with us after all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A biopic of an exceptional talent.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the heart-felt story of 23-year-old Selena Quintanilla-Perez,played flawlessly by Jennifer Lopez. Selena was a Texas born singer of Tejano music and going from a cult attraction to breaking into an international phenomenon. How factual this film is can be questionable; but very interesting nonetheless.As the rising star was showing brilliance, she was gunned down by the very president of her own fan club in 1995. Shown through flashbacks her father Abraham(Edward James Olmos), a typical stage father/manager, finally realizes how enormously talented and loved his daughter is. There is the extreme closeness of her family, the marriage to guitarist Chris Perez(Jon Seda)and the snowballing success being ended by tragedy(only dealt with via taped news reports). Actual Selena concert footage is used; and this film overflows with music. Enough can't be said of Lopez in her portrayal...she is so enjoyable, lovable and s-e-x-y! Others featured in the cast: Jackie Guerra, Constance Marle, Jacob Vargas, Rebecca Lee Mezza, Alex Meneses and Sal Lopez.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good movie..missing info
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Morenita052169
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They could have added more into background of saldivar and murder.... And leticia miller would have been a great choice to play Selena she has an eerie resemblance to Selena see for yourself Google leticia miller it's scary other than that pretty good flick, does Selena justice ....rest in peace Selena. burn in hell Yolanda. I think this is overall a good movie if your a Selena fan like me you will like it,I just wish it got more to the nitty gritty. Jennifer Lopez does her best job in this movie I think this is her best film. The costume design is also great.................................Selena was a great performer and a great person she will Be missed
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jennifer Lopez deserved an Oscar for this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    les6969
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought that Jennifer Lopez portrayal of Selena Quintanilla was nothing short of outstanding! Just how good it was can be seen at the very end where we see the real Selena Quintanilla and the likeness and movements that Ms Lopez carries off in the film can be seen in full. But there is much more to the film than a good impression. Jennifer Lopez goes through the full range of emotions and is very believable in every scene she is in. All the other cast members are also superb. My only criticism is why they changed the way she was actually shot? Selena Quintanilla was shot in a motel room and not on stage, but I guess this was done for dramatic effect?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sad, heartfelt, and funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scoobydoo1992-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When i first saw this movie, i did not know who Selena was, and of course i cried at the end but this movie was way more then a movie that you sit and watch you get into it and realize that this really happened and that you want to just cry. It is a sad movie and because it was true you really just want to cry more.I absolutely love the tag-line of the movie, you could not be more dead on with what the movie is really about. I am giving this movie 9/10 because it is truly amazing Go Jennifer Lopez Go Selena. Please go out and rent this movie because it was absolutely amazing and see one of the greatest singers this world has been blessed to hear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie sucked horribly!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruce McLaren
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Selena was not all that to begin with. I lived in the same neighborhood she did. I didn't know her personally, but heard enough about her to dislike her. When she died, I didn't much care. She was treated like a goddess here. Murels, paintings, renaming of the convention center, etc. Enough is enough. Her music was mediocre at best. Her dad was twice the ass he was portrayed in this movie. He was a selfish man who cared about no one but himself. His daughter died, and he used the opportunity to make an extra buck. This movie sucked, and was misleading as to the true nature of the incident and circumstances surrounding it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    false advertisement!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    taoseagle
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie did NOT portray the real Selena nor her family. They are very inconsiderate people. Very money hungry. They will literally "hurt" someone for it as well. Being in the tejano business, you know every band (since it is such a small market). I know bands that were involved with the Q Productions, and every band has been burned in one way or another. They did not get any royalties what so ever, contracts were breached, and the list goes on. At a show in Amarillo, Selena refused to sign autographs and her 1 1/2 hour concert turned into 25 mins because the concert hall was only half full. She was not dedicated to her fans, (it was even written in the Amarillo Globe News the day after). The movie really makes her and her family out to be generous and tight-knit. In actuality, A.B and his father do not get along. Lots of curse words thrown at each other(I witnessed it first hand). Poorly made. Made only for the money that would generate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jennifer Lopez Shines As Selena
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Selena is a biographical drama about the life and career of the late Tejano music star Selena, a recording artist who was well known in the United States and Mexico before she was shot to death.It stars Jennifer Lopez as Selena.Edward James Olmos and Constance Marie co-stars.It was written and directed by Gregory Nava. This film concentrates on Selena's relationship with her family and her rise to fame, dealing only briefly with her tragic death. Abraham Quintanilla is a veteran musician who leads a family-based singing group, The Dinos. At a young age, he notices that his daughter Selena has a strong singing voice, and he works her into the act. However, as she grows older, Selena wants to establish her own musical identity; while her heritage is Mexican-American, her primary language is English, and her favorite artists are American pop acts like Donna Summer. While Selena and Abraham sometimes argue about the musical direction of the group, he always respects and supports her talent, and her blend of Tejano roots music and danceable pop rhythms soon sparks a revolution in Latin music. Selena later earns the wrath of her father when she becomes romantically involved with Chris Perez, a rebellious and long-haired guitarist hired to play with the group, but when they elope and Selena convinces Abraham that their love is sincere, Chris is welcomed into the family. After a long string of successes on the Latin charts and playing to a sellout crowd at the Houston Astrodome and a crowd of 100,000 at a stadium in Monterey, Mexico, Selena begins recording her first album in English, which is expected to make her a mainstream star. However, the fates decreed it was an album she would never complete. The movie surmounts its connect-the-dots approach to its heroine's life to create an appealing, energetic look at a too-briefly soaring musical star.Also,it is a simple story of hope and triumph, of one girl with the drive to succeed defying the odds and following her dream that could truly inspire the viewer to achieve their goals.Finally,Jennifer Lopez truly shines in her performance in the title role as she elevates the film immensely with her radiant and energetic performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Selena Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lexi Philip-Neri
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I never really knew of Selena until I first watched the Selena movie. I must say I was very young when she died so I didn't know much of what happened until I saw the movie. From the first time I saw Selena I fell in love with this movie. Selena is one of my all time favorite movies. The movie Selena starts with her at a young age and ends with the day she dies. I really like how the movie incorporated her childhood and how her music business started because it is an important key part of her life. In the movie they also incorporated the use of the real Selena's voice when they show her making her music and in her concerts--I thought that was a brilliant idea. Since I have seen the movie Selena, I now enjoy listening to Selena's Tejano music. Overall the movie is very well put together and shows the most significant parts of her life to show her success. I highly recommend this movie to anyone who has not seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Selena: When Fairy Tales End With A Bullet ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fairy-tale of Mexican-American singer Selena, whose life was cut short by her bookkeeper. There is still another wonderful Edward James Olmos performance as her protective father. As he did as Jaime Escalante, an LA high school math teacher, Olmos commands the screen as the dominant force in his daughter's life. A hard worker who strove for more, the Olmos character did know when it was time to relent. The film is often clich&eacute;. Presto, and Selena was a star of great magnitude. While Jennifer Lopez did an admirable job, she is still Jennifer and in some scenes, she sounded as she did up against Ralph Fiennes in "Maid in Manhattan."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Muy...Muy....Exciting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    terrellrobinson71
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was afraid of this movie when I was a kid, but when I grew up, I realized that "hay mas a esta historia que el ojo" (Translation: "There's more to this story than meets the eye".) The biopic Selena is one of my favorite movies. The reason why is because in the 90's, Jennifer Lopez was a Fly Girl in the sketch comedy show "In Living Color", was co-starring in "Money Train" and "Blood and Wine" and made her biggest starring role yet, even before her music career went big. There was a few controversies involving the movie, where Lopez was a Puerto Rican from New York, and the real Selena was a Mexican-American from Texas. But then again, all of us accepted Lopez playing Selena and we enjoyed the way she made Selena a real star. In Gregory Nava's film, it begins and ends at the big concert for Selena to become a very huge crossover star at the Houston Astrodome in 1995. Then it really ends with the death of Selena being done by her insane employer (Lupe Ontiveros). (No name spoiler here, but you already know.) In the good ol' days in Corpus Christi, young Selena (Rebecca Lee Meza) was raised well by her father, Abraham (Edward James Olmos) who was in a failed band called the Dinos with two other friends back in the 50's. After hearing Selena sing "We Belong Together" with him, this sparks Abraham to bring The Dinos back to life. Who knew that years later, we get to meet Selena, all grown up and living "la vida dulce" (Translation: "The sweet life") as a Tejano star who would be the biggest Tejano star ever. During the movie, we get to see everything in a condensed, but fast, pace of 127 minutes, the relationship involving her family including mama Marcela (George Lopez's Constance Marie), her romantic relationship between the rock-and-roll guitar player, Chris Perez (Jon Seda), her music (done by the real Selena, not Lopez) and yes, we do get to meet Yolanda herself, with a lot of character developing. Lopez gave a really great performance as Selena, and with the help of Miranda Garrison's choreography, captures the essence of Selena, the way she talks, the way she moves and the way she delivers the energy. The same can be said for Olmos, who can be both funny and dramatic at the same time. (Please pay attention to the argument between Selena, Abraham and Chris.) He also delivers what should've been a washed-down speech about Mexican-Americans into a very smart and charismatic speech. Selena is "muy, muy entretenido" (Translation: "Very, very entertaining.") However, when you do get to the end of the film, there are hankies to be of good use when the candlelight vigils and the archival footage shows and the mourning of a fabulous star comes on-screen. It's very heartbreaking and very emotional in the way that has been done and the final image will make you cry in a good way to prove that she was still there with us after all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A biopic of an exceptional talent.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the heart-felt story of 23-year-old Selena Quintanilla-Perez,played flawlessly by Jennifer Lopez. Selena was a Texas born singer of Tejano music and going from a cult attraction to breaking into an international phenomenon. How factual this film is can be questionable; but very interesting nonetheless.As the rising star was showing brilliance, she was gunned down by the very president of her own fan club in 1995. Shown through flashbacks her father Abraham(Edward James Olmos), a typical stage father/manager, finally realizes how enormously talented and loved his daughter is. There is the extreme closeness of her family, the marriage to guitarist Chris Perez(Jon Seda)and the snowballing success being ended by tragedy(only dealt with via taped news reports). Actual Selena concert footage is used; and this film overflows with music. Enough can't be said of Lopez in her portrayal...she is so enjoyable, lovable and s-e-x-y! Others featured in the cast: Jackie Guerra, Constance Marle, Jacob Vargas, Rebecca Lee Mezza, Alex Meneses and Sal Lopez.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good movie..missing info
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Morenita052169
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They could have added more into background of saldivar and murder.... And leticia miller would have been a great choice to play Selena she has an eerie resemblance to Selena see for yourself Google leticia miller it's scary other than that pretty good flick, does Selena justice ....rest in peace Selena. burn in hell Yolanda. I think this is overall a good movie if your a Selena fan like me you will like it,I just wish it got more to the nitty gritty. Jennifer Lopez does her best job in this movie I think this is her best film. The costume design is also great.................................Selena was a great performer and a great person she will Be missed
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jennifer Lopez deserved an Oscar for this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    les6969
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought that Jennifer Lopez portrayal of Selena Quintanilla was nothing short of outstanding! Just how good it was can be seen at the very end where we see the real Selena Quintanilla and the likeness and movements that Ms Lopez carries off in the film can be seen in full. But there is much more to the film than a good impression. Jennifer Lopez goes through the full range of emotions and is very believable in every scene she is in. All the other cast members are also superb. My only criticism is why they changed the way she was actually shot? Selena Quintanilla was shot in a motel room and not on stage, but I guess this was done for dramatic effect?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sad, heartfelt, and funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scoobydoo1992-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When i first saw this movie, i did not know who Selena was, and of course i cried at the end but this movie was way more then a movie that you sit and watch you get into it and realize that this really happened and that you want to just cry. It is a sad movie and because it was true you really just want to cry more.I absolutely love the tag-line of the movie, you could not be more dead on with what the movie is really about. I am giving this movie 9/10 because it is truly amazing Go Jennifer Lopez Go Selena. Please go out and rent this movie because it was absolutely amazing and see one of the greatest singers this world has been blessed to hear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie sucked horribly!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruce McLaren
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Selena was not all that to begin with. I lived in the same neighborhood she did. I didn't know her personally, but heard enough about her to dislike her. When she died, I didn't much care. She was treated like a goddess here. Murels, paintings, renaming of the convention center, etc. Enough is enough. Her music was mediocre at best. Her dad was twice the ass he was portrayed in this movie. He was a selfish man who cared about no one but himself. His daughter died, and he used the opportunity to make an extra buck. This movie sucked, and was misleading as to the true nature of the incident and circumstances surrounding it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    false advertisement!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    taoseagle
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie did NOT portray the real Selena nor her family. They are very inconsiderate people. Very money hungry. They will literally "hurt" someone for it as well. Being in the tejano business, you know every band (since it is such a small market). I know bands that were involved with the Q Productions, and every band has been burned in one way or another. They did not get any royalties what so ever, contracts were breached, and the list goes on. At a show in Amarillo, Selena refused to sign autographs and her 1 1/2 hour concert turned into 25 mins because the concert hall was only half full. She was not dedicated to her fans, (it was even written in the Amarillo Globe News the day after). The movie really makes her and her family out to be generous and tight-knit. In actuality, A.B and his father do not get along. Lots of curse words thrown at each other(I witnessed it first hand). Poorly made. Made only for the money that would generate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jennifer Lopez Shines As Selena
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Selena is a biographical drama about the life and career of the late Tejano music star Selena, a recording artist who was well known in the United States and Mexico before she was shot to death.It stars Jennifer Lopez as Selena.Edward James Olmos and Constance Marie co-stars.It was written and directed by Gregory Nava. This film concentrates on Selena's relationship with her family and her rise to fame, dealing only briefly with her tragic death. Abraham Quintanilla is a veteran musician who leads a family-based singing group, The Dinos. At a young age, he notices that his daughter Selena has a strong singing voice, and he works her into the act. However, as she grows older, Selena wants to establish her own musical identity; while her heritage is Mexican-American, her primary language is English, and her favorite artists are American pop acts like Donna Summer. While Selena and Abraham sometimes argue about the musical direction of the group, he always respects and supports her talent, and her blend of Tejano roots music and danceable pop rhythms soon sparks a revolution in Latin music. Selena later earns the wrath of her father when she becomes romantically involved with Chris Perez, a rebellious and long-haired guitarist hired to play with the group, but when they elope and Selena convinces Abraham that their love is sincere, Chris is welcomed into the family. After a long string of successes on the Latin charts and playing to a sellout crowd at the Houston Astrodome and a crowd of 100,000 at a stadium in Monterey, Mexico, Selena begins recording her first album in English, which is expected to make her a mainstream star. However, the fates decreed it was an album she would never complete. The movie surmounts its connect-the-dots approach to its heroine's life to create an appealing, energetic look at a too-briefly soaring musical star.Also,it is a simple story of hope and triumph, of one girl with the drive to succeed defying the odds and following her dream that could truly inspire the viewer to achieve their goals.Finally,Jennifer Lopez truly shines in her performance in the title role as she elevates the film immensely with her radiant and energetic performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Selena Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lexi Philip-Neri
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I never really knew of Selena until I first watched the Selena movie. I must say I was very young when she died so I didn't know much of what happened until I saw the movie. From the first time I saw Selena I fell in love with this movie. Selena is one of my all time favorite movies. The movie Selena starts with her at a young age and ends with the day she dies. I really like how the movie incorporated her childhood and how her music business started because it is an important key part of her life. In the movie they also incorporated the use of the real Selena's voice when they show her making her music and in her concerts--I thought that was a brilliant idea. Since I have seen the movie Selena, I now enjoy listening to Selena's Tejano music. Overall the movie is very well put together and shows the most significant parts of her life to show her success. I highly recommend this movie to anyone who has not seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Selena: When Fairy Tales End With A Bullet ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fairy-tale of Mexican-American singer Selena, whose life was cut short by her bookkeeper. There is still another wonderful Edward James Olmos performance as her protective father. As he did as Jaime Escalante, an LA high school math teacher, Olmos commands the screen as the dominant force in his daughter's life. A hard worker who strove for more, the Olmos character did know when it was time to relent. The film is often clich&eacute;. Presto, and Selena was a star of great magnitude. While Jennifer Lopez did an admirable job, she is still Jennifer and in some scenes, she sounded as she did up against Ralph Fiennes in "Maid in Manhattan."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Muy...Muy....Exciting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    terrellrobinson71
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was afraid of this movie when I was a kid, but when I grew up, I realized that "hay mas a esta historia que el ojo" (Translation: "There's more to this story than meets the eye".) The biopic Selena is one of my favorite movies. The reason why is because in the 90's, Jennifer Lopez was a Fly Girl in the sketch comedy show "In Living Color", was co-starring in "Money Train" and "Blood and Wine" and made her biggest starring role yet, even before her music career went big. There was a few controversies involving the movie, where Lopez was a Puerto Rican from New York, and the real Selena was a Mexican-American from Texas. But then again, all of us accepted Lopez playing Selena and we enjoyed the way she made Selena a real star. In Gregory Nava's film, it begins and ends at the big concert for Selena to become a very huge crossover star at the Houston Astrodome in 1995. Then it really ends with the death of Selena being done by her insane employer (Lupe Ontiveros). (No name spoiler here, but you already know.) In the good ol' days in Corpus Christi, young Selena (Rebecca Lee Meza) was raised well by her father, Abraham (Edward James Olmos) who was in a failed band called the Dinos with two other friends back in the 50's. After hearing Selena sing "We Belong Together" with him, this sparks Abraham to bring The Dinos back to life. Who knew that years later, we get to meet Selena, all grown up and living "la vida dulce" (Translation: "The sweet life") as a Tejano star who would be the biggest Tejano star ever. During the movie, we get to see everything in a condensed, but fast, pace of 127 minutes, the relationship involving her family including mama Marcela (George Lopez's Constance Marie), her romantic relationship between the rock-and-roll guitar player, Chris Perez (Jon Seda), her music (done by the real Selena, not Lopez) and yes, we do get to meet Yolanda herself, with a lot of character developing. Lopez gave a really great performance as Selena, and with the help of Miranda Garrison's choreography, captures the essence of Selena, the way she talks, the way she moves and the way she delivers the energy. The same can be said for Olmos, who can be both funny and dramatic at the same time. (Please pay attention to the argument between Selena, Abraham and Chris.) He also delivers what should've been a washed-down speech about Mexican-Americans into a very smart and charismatic speech. Selena is "muy, muy entretenido" (Translation: "Very, very entertaining.") However, when you do get to the end of the film, there are hankies to be of good use when the candlelight vigils and the archival footage shows and the mourning of a fabulous star comes on-screen. It's very heartbreaking and very emotional in the way that has been done and the final image will make you cry in a good way to prove that she was still there with us after all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A biopic of an exceptional talent.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the heart-felt story of 23-year-old Selena Quintanilla-Perez,played flawlessly by Jennifer Lopez. Selena was a Texas born singer of Tejano music and going from a cult attraction to breaking into an international phenomenon. How factual this film is can be questionable; but very interesting nonetheless.As the rising star was showing brilliance, she was gunned down by the very president of her own fan club in 1995. Shown through flashbacks her father Abraham(Edward James Olmos), a typical stage father/manager, finally realizes how enormously talented and loved his daughter is. There is the extreme closeness of her family, the marriage to guitarist Chris Perez(Jon Seda)and the snowballing success being ended by tragedy(only dealt with via taped news reports). Actual Selena concert footage is used; and this film overflows with music. Enough can't be said of Lopez in her portrayal...she is so enjoyable, lovable and s-e-x-y! Others featured in the cast: Jackie Guerra, Constance Marle, Jacob Vargas, Rebecca Lee Mezza, Alex Meneses and Sal Lopez.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good movie..missing info
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Morenita052169
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They could have added more into background of saldivar and murder.... And leticia miller would have been a great choice to play Selena she has an eerie resemblance to Selena see for yourself Google leticia miller it's scary other than that pretty good flick, does Selena justice ....rest in peace Selena. burn in hell Yolanda. I think this is overall a good movie if your a Selena fan like me you will like it,I just wish it got more to the nitty gritty. Jennifer Lopez does her best job in this movie I think this is her best film. The costume design is also great.................................Selena was a great performer and a great person she will Be missed
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jennifer Lopez deserved an Oscar for this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    les6969
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought that Jennifer Lopez portrayal of Selena Quintanilla was nothing short of outstanding! Just how good it was can be seen at the very end where we see the real Selena Quintanilla and the likeness and movements that Ms Lopez carries off in the film can be seen in full. But there is much more to the film than a good impression. Jennifer Lopez goes through the full range of emotions and is very believable in every scene she is in. All the other cast members are also superb. My only criticism is why they changed the way she was actually shot? Selena Quintanilla was shot in a motel room and not on stage, but I guess this was done for dramatic effect?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sad, heartfelt, and funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scoobydoo1992-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When i first saw this movie, i did not know who Selena was, and of course i cried at the end but this movie was way more then a movie that you sit and watch you get into it and realize that this really happened and that you want to just cry. It is a sad movie and because it was true you really just want to cry more.I absolutely love the tag-line of the movie, you could not be more dead on with what the movie is really about. I am giving this movie 9/10 because it is truly amazing Go Jennifer Lopez Go Selena. Please go out and rent this movie because it was absolutely amazing and see one of the greatest singers this world has been blessed to hear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie sucked horribly!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruce McLaren
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Selena was not all that to begin with. I lived in the same neighborhood she did. I didn't know her personally, but heard enough about her to dislike her. When she died, I didn't much care. She was treated like a goddess here. Murels, paintings, renaming of the convention center, etc. Enough is enough. Her music was mediocre at best. Her dad was twice the ass he was portrayed in this movie. He was a selfish man who cared about no one but himself. His daughter died, and he used the opportunity to make an extra buck. This movie sucked, and was misleading as to the true nature of the incident and circumstances surrounding it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    false advertisement!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    taoseagle
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie did NOT portray the real Selena nor her family. They are very inconsiderate people. Very money hungry. They will literally "hurt" someone for it as well. Being in the tejano business, you know every band (since it is such a small market). I know bands that were involved with the Q Productions, and every band has been burned in one way or another. They did not get any royalties what so ever, contracts were breached, and the list goes on. At a show in Amarillo, Selena refused to sign autographs and her 1 1/2 hour concert turned into 25 mins because the concert hall was only half full. She was not dedicated to her fans, (it was even written in the Amarillo Globe News the day after). The movie really makes her and her family out to be generous and tight-knit. In actuality, A.B and his father do not get along. Lots of curse words thrown at each other(I witnessed it first hand). Poorly made. Made only for the money that would generate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jennifer Lopez Shines As Selena
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Selena is a biographical drama about the life and career of the late Tejano music star Selena, a recording artist who was well known in the United States and Mexico before she was shot to death.It stars Jennifer Lopez as Selena.Edward James Olmos and Constance Marie co-stars.It was written and directed by Gregory Nava. This film concentrates on Selena's relationship with her family and her rise to fame, dealing only briefly with her tragic death. Abraham Quintanilla is a veteran musician who leads a family-based singing group, The Dinos. At a young age, he notices that his daughter Selena has a strong singing voice, and he works her into the act. However, as she grows older, Selena wants to establish her own musical identity; while her heritage is Mexican-American, her primary language is English, and her favorite artists are American pop acts like Donna Summer. While Selena and Abraham sometimes argue about the musical direction of the group, he always respects and supports her talent, and her blend of Tejano roots music and danceable pop rhythms soon sparks a revolution in Latin music. Selena later earns the wrath of her father when she becomes romantically involved with Chris Perez, a rebellious and long-haired guitarist hired to play with the group, but when they elope and Selena convinces Abraham that their love is sincere, Chris is welcomed into the family. After a long string of successes on the Latin charts and playing to a sellout crowd at the Houston Astrodome and a crowd of 100,000 at a stadium in Monterey, Mexico, Selena begins recording her first album in English, which is expected to make her a mainstream star. However, the fates decreed it was an album she would never complete. The movie surmounts its connect-the-dots approach to its heroine's life to create an appealing, energetic look at a too-briefly soaring musical star.Also,it is a simple story of hope and triumph, of one girl with the drive to succeed defying the odds and following her dream that could truly inspire the viewer to achieve their goals.Finally,Jennifer Lopez truly shines in her performance in the title role as she elevates the film immensely with her radiant and energetic performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Selena Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lexi Philip-Neri
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I never really knew of Selena until I first watched the Selena movie. I must say I was very young when she died so I didn't know much of what happened until I saw the movie. From the first time I saw Selena I fell in love with this movie. Selena is one of my all time favorite movies. The movie Selena starts with her at a young age and ends with the day she dies. I really like how the movie incorporated her childhood and how her music business started because it is an important key part of her life. In the movie they also incorporated the use of the real Selena's voice when they show her making her music and in her concerts--I thought that was a brilliant idea. Since I have seen the movie Selena, I now enjoy listening to Selena's Tejano music. Overall the movie is very well put together and shows the most significant parts of her life to show her success. I highly recommend this movie to anyone who has not seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Selena: When Fairy Tales End With A Bullet ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fairy-tale of Mexican-American singer Selena, whose life was cut short by her bookkeeper. There is still another wonderful Edward James Olmos performance as her protective father. As he did as Jaime Escalante, an LA high school math teacher, Olmos commands the screen as the dominant force in his daughter's life. A hard worker who strove for more, the Olmos character did know when it was time to relent. The film is often clich&eacute;. Presto, and Selena was a star of great magnitude. While Jennifer Lopez did an admirable job, she is still Jennifer and in some scenes, she sounded as she did up against Ralph Fiennes in "Maid in Manhattan."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Muy...Muy....Exciting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    terrellrobinson71
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was afraid of this movie when I was a kid, but when I grew up, I realized that "hay mas a esta historia que el ojo" (Translation: "There's more to this story than meets the eye".) The biopic Selena is one of my favorite movies. The reason why is because in the 90's, Jennifer Lopez was a Fly Girl in the sketch comedy show "In Living Color", was co-starring in "Money Train" and "Blood and Wine" and made her biggest starring role yet, even before her music career went big. There was a few controversies involving the movie, where Lopez was a Puerto Rican from New York, and the real Selena was a Mexican-American from Texas. But then again, all of us accepted Lopez playing Selena and we enjoyed the way she made Selena a real star. In Gregory Nava's film, it begins and ends at the big concert for Selena to become a very huge crossover star at the Houston Astrodome in 1995. Then it really ends with the death of Selena being done by her insane employer (Lupe Ontiveros). (No name spoiler here, but you already know.) In the good ol' days in Corpus Christi, young Selena (Rebecca Lee Meza) was raised well by her father, Abraham (Edward James Olmos) who was in a failed band called the Dinos with two other friends back in the 50's. After hearing Selena sing "We Belong Together" with him, this sparks Abraham to bring The Dinos back to life. Who knew that years later, we get to meet Selena, all grown up and living "la vida dulce" (Translation: "The sweet life") as a Tejano star who would be the biggest Tejano star ever. During the movie, we get to see everything in a condensed, but fast, pace of 127 minutes, the relationship involving her family including mama Marcela (George Lopez's Constance Marie), her romantic relationship between the rock-and-roll guitar player, Chris Perez (Jon Seda), her music (done by the real Selena, not Lopez) and yes, we do get to meet Yolanda herself, with a lot of character developing. Lopez gave a really great performance as Selena, and with the help of Miranda Garrison's choreography, captures the essence of Selena, the way she talks, the way she moves and the way she delivers the energy. The same can be said for Olmos, who can be both funny and dramatic at the same time. (Please pay attention to the argument between Selena, Abraham and Chris.) He also delivers what should've been a washed-down speech about Mexican-Americans into a very smart and charismatic speech. Selena is "muy, muy entretenido" (Translation: "Very, very entertaining.") However, when you do get to the end of the film, there are hankies to be of good use when the candlelight vigils and the archival footage shows and the mourning of a fabulous star comes on-screen. It's very heartbreaking and very emotional in the way that has been done and the final image will make you cry in a good way to prove that she was still there with us after all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A biopic of an exceptional talent.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the heart-felt story of 23-year-old Selena Quintanilla-Perez,played flawlessly by Jennifer Lopez. Selena was a Texas born singer of Tejano music and going from a cult attraction to breaking into an international phenomenon. How factual this film is can be questionable; but very interesting nonetheless.As the rising star was showing brilliance, she was gunned down by the very president of her own fan club in 1995. Shown through flashbacks her father Abraham(Edward James Olmos), a typical stage father/manager, finally realizes how enormously talented and loved his daughter is. There is the extreme closeness of her family, the marriage to guitarist Chris Perez(Jon Seda)and the snowballing success being ended by tragedy(only dealt with via taped news reports). Actual Selena concert footage is used; and this film overflows with music. Enough can't be said of Lopez in her portrayal...she is so enjoyable, lovable and s-e-x-y! Others featured in the cast: Jackie Guerra, Constance Marle, Jacob Vargas, Rebecca Lee Mezza, Alex Meneses and Sal Lopez.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good movie..missing info
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Morenita052169
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They could have added more into background of saldivar and murder.... And leticia miller would have been a great choice to play Selena she has an eerie resemblance to Selena see for yourself Google leticia miller it's scary other than that pretty good flick, does Selena justice ....rest in peace Selena. burn in hell Yolanda. I think this is overall a good movie if your a Selena fan like me you will like it,I just wish it got more to the nitty gritty. Jennifer Lopez does her best job in this movie I think this is her best film. The costume design is also great.................................Selena was a great performer and a great person she will Be missed
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jennifer Lopez deserved an Oscar for this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    les6969
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought that Jennifer Lopez portrayal of Selena Quintanilla was nothing short of outstanding! Just how good it was can be seen at the very end where we see the real Selena Quintanilla and the likeness and movements that Ms Lopez carries off in the film can be seen in full. But there is much more to the film than a good impression. Jennifer Lopez goes through the full range of emotions and is very believable in every scene she is in. All the other cast members are also superb. My only criticism is why they changed the way she was actually shot? Selena Quintanilla was shot in a motel room and not on stage, but I guess this was done for dramatic effect?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sad, heartfelt, and funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scoobydoo1992-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When i first saw this movie, i did not know who Selena was, and of course i cried at the end but this movie was way more then a movie that you sit and watch you get into it and realize that this really happened and that you want to just cry. It is a sad movie and because it was true you really just want to cry more.I absolutely love the tag-line of the movie, you could not be more dead on with what the movie is really about. I am giving this movie 9/10 because it is truly amazing Go Jennifer Lopez Go Selena. Please go out and rent this movie because it was absolutely amazing and see one of the greatest singers this world has been blessed to hear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie sucked horribly!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruce McLaren
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Selena was not all that to begin with. I lived in the same neighborhood she did. I didn't know her personally, but heard enough about her to dislike her. When she died, I didn't much care. She was treated like a goddess here. Murels, paintings, renaming of the convention center, etc. Enough is enough. Her music was mediocre at best. Her dad was twice the ass he was portrayed in this movie. He was a selfish man who cared about no one but himself. His daughter died, and he used the opportunity to make an extra buck. This movie sucked, and was misleading as to the true nature of the incident and circumstances surrounding it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    false advertisement!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    taoseagle
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie did NOT portray the real Selena nor her family. They are very inconsiderate people. Very money hungry. They will literally "hurt" someone for it as well. Being in the tejano business, you know every band (since it is such a small market). I know bands that were involved with the Q Productions, and every band has been burned in one way or another. They did not get any royalties what so ever, contracts were breached, and the list goes on. At a show in Amarillo, Selena refused to sign autographs and her 1 1/2 hour concert turned into 25 mins because the concert hall was only half full. She was not dedicated to her fans, (it was even written in the Amarillo Globe News the day after). The movie really makes her and her family out to be generous and tight-knit. In actuality, A.B and his father do not get along. Lots of curse words thrown at each other(I witnessed it first hand). Poorly made. Made only for the money that would generate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jennifer Lopez Shines As Selena
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Selena is a biographical drama about the life and career of the late Tejano music star Selena, a recording artist who was well known in the United States and Mexico before she was shot to death.It stars Jennifer Lopez as Selena.Edward James Olmos and Constance Marie co-stars.It was written and directed by Gregory Nava. This film concentrates on Selena's relationship with her family and her rise to fame, dealing only briefly with her tragic death. Abraham Quintanilla is a veteran musician who leads a family-based singing group, The Dinos. At a young age, he notices that his daughter Selena has a strong singing voice, and he works her into the act. However, as she grows older, Selena wants to establish her own musical identity; while her heritage is Mexican-American, her primary language is English, and her favorite artists are American pop acts like Donna Summer. While Selena and Abraham sometimes argue about the musical direction of the group, he always respects and supports her talent, and her blend of Tejano roots music and danceable pop rhythms soon sparks a revolution in Latin music. Selena later earns the wrath of her father when she becomes romantically involved with Chris Perez, a rebellious and long-haired guitarist hired to play with the group, but when they elope and Selena convinces Abraham that their love is sincere, Chris is welcomed into the family. After a long string of successes on the Latin charts and playing to a sellout crowd at the Houston Astrodome and a crowd of 100,000 at a stadium in Monterey, Mexico, Selena begins recording her first album in English, which is expected to make her a mainstream star. However, the fates decreed it was an album she would never complete. The movie surmounts its connect-the-dots approach to its heroine's life to create an appealing, energetic look at a too-briefly soaring musical star.Also,it is a simple story of hope and triumph, of one girl with the drive to succeed defying the odds and following her dream that could truly inspire the viewer to achieve their goals.Finally,Jennifer Lopez truly shines in her performance in the title role as she elevates the film immensely with her radiant and energetic performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Selena Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lexi Philip-Neri
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I never really knew of Selena until I first watched the Selena movie. I must say I was very young when she died so I didn't know much of what happened until I saw the movie. From the first time I saw Selena I fell in love with this movie. Selena is one of my all time favorite movies. The movie Selena starts with her at a young age and ends with the day she dies. I really like how the movie incorporated her childhood and how her music business started because it is an important key part of her life. In the movie they also incorporated the use of the real Selena's voice when they show her making her music and in her concerts--I thought that was a brilliant idea. Since I have seen the movie Selena, I now enjoy listening to Selena's Tejano music. Overall the movie is very well put together and shows the most significant parts of her life to show her success. I highly recommend this movie to anyone who has not seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Selena: When Fairy Tales End With A Bullet ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fairy-tale of Mexican-American singer Selena, whose life was cut short by her bookkeeper. There is still another wonderful Edward James Olmos performance as her protective father. As he did as Jaime Escalante, an LA high school math teacher, Olmos commands the screen as the dominant force in his daughter's life. A hard worker who strove for more, the Olmos character did know when it was time to relent. The film is often clich&eacute;. Presto, and Selena was a star of great magnitude. While Jennifer Lopez did an admirable job, she is still Jennifer and in some scenes, she sounded as she did up against Ralph Fiennes in "Maid in Manhattan."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Muy...Muy....Exciting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    terrellrobinson71
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was afraid of this movie when I was a kid, but when I grew up, I realized that "hay mas a esta historia que el ojo" (Translation: "There's more to this story than meets the eye".) The biopic Selena is one of my favorite movies. The reason why is because in the 90's, Jennifer Lopez was a Fly Girl in the sketch comedy show "In Living Color", was co-starring in "Money Train" and "Blood and Wine" and made her biggest starring role yet, even before her music career went big. There was a few controversies involving the movie, where Lopez was a Puerto Rican from New York, and the real Selena was a Mexican-American from Texas. But then again, all of us accepted Lopez playing Selena and we enjoyed the way she made Selena a real star. In Gregory Nava's film, it begins and ends at the big concert for Selena to become a very huge crossover star at the Houston Astrodome in 1995. Then it really ends with the death of Selena being done by her insane employer (Lupe Ontiveros). (No name spoiler here, but you already know.) In the good ol' days in Corpus Christi, young Selena (Rebecca Lee Meza) was raised well by her father, Abraham (Edward James Olmos) who was in a failed band called the Dinos with two other friends back in the 50's. After hearing Selena sing "We Belong Together" with him, this sparks Abraham to bring The Dinos back to life. Who knew that years later, we get to meet Selena, all grown up and living "la vida dulce" (Translation: "The sweet life") as a Tejano star who would be the biggest Tejano star ever. During the movie, we get to see everything in a condensed, but fast, pace of 127 minutes, the relationship involving her family including mama Marcela (George Lopez's Constance Marie), her romantic relationship between the rock-and-roll guitar player, Chris Perez (Jon Seda), her music (done by the real Selena, not Lopez) and yes, we do get to meet Yolanda herself, with a lot of character developing. Lopez gave a really great performance as Selena, and with the help of Miranda Garrison's choreography, captures the essence of Selena, the way she talks, the way she moves and the way she delivers the energy. The same can be said for Olmos, who can be both funny and dramatic at the same time. (Please pay attention to the argument between Selena, Abraham and Chris.) He also delivers what should've been a washed-down speech about Mexican-Americans into a very smart and charismatic speech. Selena is "muy, muy entretenido" (Translation: "Very, very entertaining.") However, when you do get to the end of the film, there are hankies to be of good use when the candlelight vigils and the archival footage shows and the mourning of a fabulous star comes on-screen. It's very heartbreaking and very emotional in the way that has been done and the final image will make you cry in a good way to prove that she was still there with us after all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A biopic of an exceptional talent.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the heart-felt story of 23-year-old Selena Quintanilla-Perez,played flawlessly by Jennifer Lopez. Selena was a Texas born singer of Tejano music and going from a cult attraction to breaking into an international phenomenon. How factual this film is can be questionable; but very interesting nonetheless.As the rising star was showing brilliance, she was gunned down by the very president of her own fan club in 1995. Shown through flashbacks her father Abraham(Edward James Olmos), a typical stage father/manager, finally realizes how enormously talented and loved his daughter is. There is the extreme closeness of her family, the marriage to guitarist Chris Perez(Jon Seda)and the snowballing success being ended by tragedy(only dealt with via taped news reports). Actual Selena concert footage is used; and this film overflows with music. Enough can't be said of Lopez in her portrayal...she is so enjoyable, lovable and s-e-x-y! Others featured in the cast: Jackie Guerra, Constance Marle, Jacob Vargas, Rebecca Lee Mezza, Alex Meneses and Sal Lopez.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good movie..missing info
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Morenita052169
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They could have added more into background of saldivar and murder.... And leticia miller would have been a great choice to play Selena she has an eerie resemblance to Selena see for yourself Google leticia miller it's scary other than that pretty good flick, does Selena justice ....rest in peace Selena. burn in hell Yolanda. I think this is overall a good movie if your a Selena fan like me you will like it,I just wish it got more to the nitty gritty. Jennifer Lopez does her best job in this movie I think this is her best film. The costume design is also great.................................Selena was a great performer and a great person she will Be missed
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jennifer Lopez deserved an Oscar for this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    les6969
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought that Jennifer Lopez portrayal of Selena Quintanilla was nothing short of outstanding! Just how good it was can be seen at the very end where we see the real Selena Quintanilla and the likeness and movements that Ms Lopez carries off in the film can be seen in full. But there is much more to the film than a good impression. Jennifer Lopez goes through the full range of emotions and is very believable in every scene she is in. All the other cast members are also superb. My only criticism is why they changed the way she was actually shot? Selena Quintanilla was shot in a motel room and not on stage, but I guess this was done for dramatic effect?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sad, heartfelt, and funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scoobydoo1992-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When i first saw this movie, i did not know who Selena was, and of course i cried at the end but this movie was way more then a movie that you sit and watch you get into it and realize that this really happened and that you want to just cry. It is a sad movie and because it was true you really just want to cry more.I absolutely love the tag-line of the movie, you could not be more dead on with what the movie is really about. I am giving this movie 9/10 because it is truly amazing Go Jennifer Lopez Go Selena. Please go out and rent this movie because it was absolutely amazing and see one of the greatest singers this world has been blessed to hear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie sucked horribly!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruce McLaren
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Selena was not all that to begin with. I lived in the same neighborhood she did. I didn't know her personally, but heard enough about her to dislike her. When she died, I didn't much care. She was treated like a goddess here. Murels, paintings, renaming of the convention center, etc. Enough is enough. Her music was mediocre at best. Her dad was twice the ass he was portrayed in this movie. He was a selfish man who cared about no one but himself. His daughter died, and he used the opportunity to make an extra buck. This movie sucked, and was misleading as to the true nature of the incident and circumstances surrounding it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    false advertisement!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    taoseagle
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie did NOT portray the real Selena nor her family. They are very inconsiderate people. Very money hungry. They will literally "hurt" someone for it as well. Being in the tejano business, you know every band (since it is such a small market). I know bands that were involved with the Q Productions, and every band has been burned in one way or another. They did not get any royalties what so ever, contracts were breached, and the list goes on. At a show in Amarillo, Selena refused to sign autographs and her 1 1/2 hour concert turned into 25 mins because the concert hall was only half full. She was not dedicated to her fans, (it was even written in the Amarillo Globe News the day after). The movie really makes her and her family out to be generous and tight-knit. In actuality, A.B and his father do not get along. Lots of curse words thrown at each other(I witnessed it first hand). Poorly made. Made only for the money that would generate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jennifer Lopez Shines As Selena
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Selena is a biographical drama about the life and career of the late Tejano music star Selena, a recording artist who was well known in the United States and Mexico before she was shot to death.It stars Jennifer Lopez as Selena.Edward James Olmos and Constance Marie co-stars.It was written and directed by Gregory Nava. This film concentrates on Selena's relationship with her family and her rise to fame, dealing only briefly with her tragic death. Abraham Quintanilla is a veteran musician who leads a family-based singing group, The Dinos. At a young age, he notices that his daughter Selena has a strong singing voice, and he works her into the act. However, as she grows older, Selena wants to establish her own musical identity; while her heritage is Mexican-American, her primary language is English, and her favorite artists are American pop acts like Donna Summer. While Selena and Abraham sometimes argue about the musical direction of the group, he always respects and supports her talent, and her blend of Tejano roots music and danceable pop rhythms soon sparks a revolution in Latin music. Selena later earns the wrath of her father when she becomes romantically involved with Chris Perez, a rebellious and long-haired guitarist hired to play with the group, but when they elope and Selena convinces Abraham that their love is sincere, Chris is welcomed into the family. After a long string of successes on the Latin charts and playing to a sellout crowd at the Houston Astrodome and a crowd of 100,000 at a stadium in Monterey, Mexico, Selena begins recording her first album in English, which is expected to make her a mainstream star. However, the fates decreed it was an album she would never complete. The movie surmounts its connect-the-dots approach to its heroine's life to create an appealing, energetic look at a too-briefly soaring musical star.Also,it is a simple story of hope and triumph, of one girl with the drive to succeed defying the odds and following her dream that could truly inspire the viewer to achieve their goals.Finally,Jennifer Lopez truly shines in her performance in the title role as she elevates the film immensely with her radiant and energetic performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Selena Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lexi Philip-Neri
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I never really knew of Selena until I first watched the Selena movie. I must say I was very young when she died so I didn't know much of what happened until I saw the movie. From the first time I saw Selena I fell in love with this movie. Selena is one of my all time favorite movies. The movie Selena starts with her at a young age and ends with the day she dies. I really like how the movie incorporated her childhood and how her music business started because it is an important key part of her life. In the movie they also incorporated the use of the real Selena's voice when they show her making her music and in her concerts--I thought that was a brilliant idea. Since I have seen the movie Selena, I now enjoy listening to Selena's Tejano music. Overall the movie is very well put together and shows the most significant parts of her life to show her success. I highly recommend this movie to anyone who has not seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Selena: When Fairy Tales End With A Bullet ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fairy-tale of Mexican-American singer Selena, whose life was cut short by her bookkeeper. There is still another wonderful Edward James Olmos performance as her protective father. As he did as Jaime Escalante, an LA high school math teacher, Olmos commands the screen as the dominant force in his daughter's life. A hard worker who strove for more, the Olmos character did know when it was time to relent. The film is often clich&eacute;. Presto, and Selena was a star of great magnitude. While Jennifer Lopez did an admirable job, she is still Jennifer and in some scenes, she sounded as she did up against Ralph Fiennes in "Maid in Manhattan."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Muy...Muy....Exciting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    terrellrobinson71
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was afraid of this movie when I was a kid, but when I grew up, I realized that "hay mas a esta historia que el ojo" (Translation: "There's more to this story than meets the eye".) The biopic Selena is one of my favorite movies. The reason why is because in the 90's, Jennifer Lopez was a Fly Girl in the sketch comedy show "In Living Color", was co-starring in "Money Train" and "Blood and Wine" and made her biggest starring role yet, even before her music career went big. There was a few controversies involving the movie, where Lopez was a Puerto Rican from New York, and the real Selena was a Mexican-American from Texas. But then again, all of us accepted Lopez playing Selena and we enjoyed the way she made Selena a real star. In Gregory Nava's film, it begins and ends at the big concert for Selena to become a very huge crossover star at the Houston Astrodome in 1995. Then it really ends with the death of Selena being done by her insane employer (Lupe Ontiveros). (No name spoiler here, but you already know.) In the good ol' days in Corpus Christi, young Selena (Rebecca Lee Meza) was raised well by her father, Abraham (Edward James Olmos) who was in a failed band called the Dinos with two other friends back in the 50's. After hearing Selena sing "We Belong Together" with him, this sparks Abraham to bring The Dinos back to life. Who knew that years later, we get to meet Selena, all grown up and living "la vida dulce" (Translation: "The sweet life") as a Tejano star who would be the biggest Tejano star ever. During the movie, we get to see everything in a condensed, but fast, pace of 127 minutes, the relationship involving her family including mama Marcela (George Lopez's Constance Marie), her romantic relationship between the rock-and-roll guitar player, Chris Perez (Jon Seda), her music (done by the real Selena, not Lopez) and yes, we do get to meet Yolanda herself, with a lot of character developing. Lopez gave a really great performance as Selena, and with the help of Miranda Garrison's choreography, captures the essence of Selena, the way she talks, the way she moves and the way she delivers the energy. The same can be said for Olmos, who can be both funny and dramatic at the same time. (Please pay attention to the argument between Selena, Abraham and Chris.) He also delivers what should've been a washed-down speech about Mexican-Americans into a very smart and charismatic speech. Selena is "muy, muy entretenido" (Translation: "Very, very entertaining.") However, when you do get to the end of the film, there are hankies to be of good use when the candlelight vigils and the archival footage shows and the mourning of a fabulous star comes on-screen. It's very heartbreaking and very emotional in the way that has been done and the final image will make you cry in a good way to prove that she was still there with us after all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A biopic of an exceptional talent.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the heart-felt story of 23-year-old Selena Quintanilla-Perez,played flawlessly by Jennifer Lopez. Selena was a Texas born singer of Tejano music and going from a cult attraction to breaking into an international phenomenon. How factual this film is can be questionable; but very interesting nonetheless.As the rising star was showing brilliance, she was gunned down by the very president of her own fan club in 1995. Shown through flashbacks her father Abraham(Edward James Olmos), a typical stage father/manager, finally realizes how enormously talented and loved his daughter is. There is the extreme closeness of her family, the marriage to guitarist Chris Perez(Jon Seda)and the snowballing success being ended by tragedy(only dealt with via taped news reports). Actual Selena concert footage is used; and this film overflows with music. Enough can't be said of Lopez in her portrayal...she is so enjoyable, lovable and s-e-x-y! Others featured in the cast: Jackie Guerra, Constance Marle, Jacob Vargas, Rebecca Lee Mezza, Alex Meneses and Sal Lopez.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good movie..missing info
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Morenita052169
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They could have added more into background of saldivar and murder.... And leticia miller would have been a great choice to play Selena she has an eerie resemblance to Selena see for yourself Google leticia miller it's scary other than that pretty good flick, does Selena justice ....rest in peace Selena. burn in hell Yolanda. I think this is overall a good movie if your a Selena fan like me you will like it,I just wish it got more to the nitty gritty. Jennifer Lopez does her best job in this movie I think this is her best film. The costume design is also great.................................Selena was a great performer and a great person she will Be missed
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jennifer Lopez deserved an Oscar for this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    les6969
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought that Jennifer Lopez portrayal of Selena Quintanilla was nothing short of outstanding! Just how good it was can be seen at the very end where we see the real Selena Quintanilla and the likeness and movements that Ms Lopez carries off in the film can be seen in full. But there is much more to the film than a good impression. Jennifer Lopez goes through the full range of emotions and is very believable in every scene she is in. All the other cast members are also superb. My only criticism is why they changed the way she was actually shot? Selena Quintanilla was shot in a motel room and not on stage, but I guess this was done for dramatic effect?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sad, heartfelt, and funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scoobydoo1992-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When i first saw this movie, i did not know who Selena was, and of course i cried at the end but this movie was way more then a movie that you sit and watch you get into it and realize that this really happened and that you want to just cry. It is a sad movie and because it was true you really just want to cry more.I absolutely love the tag-line of the movie, you could not be more dead on with what the movie is really about. I am giving this movie 9/10 because it is truly amazing Go Jennifer Lopez Go Selena. Please go out and rent this movie because it was absolutely amazing and see one of the greatest singers this world has been blessed to hear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie sucked horribly!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruce McLaren
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Selena was not all that to begin with. I lived in the same neighborhood she did. I didn't know her personally, but heard enough about her to dislike her. When she died, I didn't much care. She was treated like a goddess here. Murels, paintings, renaming of the convention center, etc. Enough is enough. Her music was mediocre at best. Her dad was twice the ass he was portrayed in this movie. He was a selfish man who cared about no one but himself. His daughter died, and he used the opportunity to make an extra buck. This movie sucked, and was misleading as to the true nature of the incident and circumstances surrounding it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    false advertisement!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    taoseagle
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie did NOT portray the real Selena nor her family. They are very inconsiderate people. Very money hungry. They will literally "hurt" someone for it as well. Being in the tejano business, you know every band (since it is such a small market). I know bands that were involved with the Q Productions, and every band has been burned in one way or another. They did not get any royalties what so ever, contracts were breached, and the list goes on. At a show in Amarillo, Selena refused to sign autographs and her 1 1/2 hour concert turned into 25 mins because the concert hall was only half full. She was not dedicated to her fans, (it was even written in the Amarillo Globe News the day after). The movie really makes her and her family out to be generous and tight-knit. In actuality, A.B and his father do not get along. Lots of curse words thrown at each other(I witnessed it first hand). Poorly made. Made only for the money that would generate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jennifer Lopez Shines As Selena
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Selena is a biographical drama about the life and career of the late Tejano music star Selena, a recording artist who was well known in the United States and Mexico before she was shot to death.It stars Jennifer Lopez as Selena.Edward James Olmos and Constance Marie co-stars.It was written and directed by Gregory Nava. This film concentrates on Selena's relationship with her family and her rise to fame, dealing only briefly with her tragic death. Abraham Quintanilla is a veteran musician who leads a family-based singing group, The Dinos. At a young age, he notices that his daughter Selena has a strong singing voice, and he works her into the act. However, as she grows older, Selena wants to establish her own musical identity; while her heritage is Mexican-American, her primary language is English, and her favorite artists are American pop acts like Donna Summer. While Selena and Abraham sometimes argue about the musical direction of the group, he always respects and supports her talent, and her blend of Tejano roots music and danceable pop rhythms soon sparks a revolution in Latin music. Selena later earns the wrath of her father when she becomes romantically involved with Chris Perez, a rebellious and long-haired guitarist hired to play with the group, but when they elope and Selena convinces Abraham that their love is sincere, Chris is welcomed into the family. After a long string of successes on the Latin charts and playing to a sellout crowd at the Houston Astrodome and a crowd of 100,000 at a stadium in Monterey, Mexico, Selena begins recording her first album in English, which is expected to make her a mainstream star. However, the fates decreed it was an album she would never complete. The movie surmounts its connect-the-dots approach to its heroine's life to create an appealing, energetic look at a too-briefly soaring musical star.Also,it is a simple story of hope and triumph, of one girl with the drive to succeed defying the odds and following her dream that could truly inspire the viewer to achieve their goals.Finally,Jennifer Lopez truly shines in her performance in the title role as she elevates the film immensely with her radiant and energetic performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Selena Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lexi Philip-Neri
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I never really knew of Selena until I first watched the Selena movie. I must say I was very young when she died so I didn't know much of what happened until I saw the movie. From the first time I saw Selena I fell in love with this movie. Selena is one of my all time favorite movies. The movie Selena starts with her at a young age and ends with the day she dies. I really like how the movie incorporated her childhood and how her music business started because it is an important key part of her life. In the movie they also incorporated the use of the real Selena's voice when they show her making her music and in her concerts--I thought that was a brilliant idea. Since I have seen the movie Selena, I now enjoy listening to Selena's Tejano music. Overall the movie is very well put together and shows the most significant parts of her life to show her success. I highly recommend this movie to anyone who has not seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Selena: When Fairy Tales End With A Bullet ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fairy-tale of Mexican-American singer Selena, whose life was cut short by her bookkeeper. There is still another wonderful Edward James Olmos performance as her protective father. As he did as Jaime Escalante, an LA high school math teacher, Olmos commands the screen as the dominant force in his daughter's life. A hard worker who strove for more, the Olmos character did know when it was time to relent. The film is often clich&eacute;. Presto, and Selena was a star of great magnitude. While Jennifer Lopez did an admirable job, she is still Jennifer and in some scenes, she sounded as she did up against Ralph Fiennes in "Maid in Manhattan."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Muy...Muy....Exciting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    terrellrobinson71
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was afraid of this movie when I was a kid, but when I grew up, I realized that "hay mas a esta historia que el ojo" (Translation: "There's more to this story than meets the eye".) The biopic Selena is one of my favorite movies. The reason why is because in the 90's, Jennifer Lopez was a Fly Girl in the sketch comedy show "In Living Color", was co-starring in "Money Train" and "Blood and Wine" and made her biggest starring role yet, even before her music career went big. There was a few controversies involving the movie, where Lopez was a Puerto Rican from New York, and the real Selena was a Mexican-American from Texas. But then again, all of us accepted Lopez playing Selena and we enjoyed the way she made Selena a real star. In Gregory Nava's film, it begins and ends at the big concert for Selena to become a very huge crossover star at the Houston Astrodome in 1995. Then it really ends with the death of Selena being done by her insane employer (Lupe Ontiveros). (No name spoiler here, but you already know.) In the good ol' days in Corpus Christi, young Selena (Rebecca Lee Meza) was raised well by her father, Abraham (Edward James Olmos) who was in a failed band called the Dinos with two other friends back in the 50's. After hearing Selena sing "We Belong Together" with him, this sparks Abraham to bring The Dinos back to life. Who knew that years later, we get to meet Selena, all grown up and living "la vida dulce" (Translation: "The sweet life") as a Tejano star who would be the biggest Tejano star ever. During the movie, we get to see everything in a condensed, but fast, pace of 127 minutes, the relationship involving her family including mama Marcela (George Lopez's Constance Marie), her romantic relationship between the rock-and-roll guitar player, Chris Perez (Jon Seda), her music (done by the real Selena, not Lopez) and yes, we do get to meet Yolanda herself, with a lot of character developing. Lopez gave a really great performance as Selena, and with the help of Miranda Garrison's choreography, captures the essence of Selena, the way she talks, the way she moves and the way she delivers the energy. The same can be said for Olmos, who can be both funny and dramatic at the same time. (Please pay attention to the argument between Selena, Abraham and Chris.) He also delivers what should've been a washed-down speech about Mexican-Americans into a very smart and charismatic speech. Selena is "muy, muy entretenido" (Translation: "Very, very entertaining.") However, when you do get to the end of the film, there are hankies to be of good use when the candlelight vigils and the archival footage shows and the mourning of a fabulous star comes on-screen. It's very heartbreaking and very emotional in the way that has been done and the final image will make you cry in a good way to prove that she was still there with us after all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A biopic of an exceptional talent.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the heart-felt story of 23-year-old Selena Quintanilla-Perez,played flawlessly by Jennifer Lopez. Selena was a Texas born singer of Tejano music and going from a cult attraction to breaking into an international phenomenon. How factual this film is can be questionable; but very interesting nonetheless.As the rising star was showing brilliance, she was gunned down by the very president of her own fan club in 1995. Shown through flashbacks her father Abraham(Edward James Olmos), a typical stage father/manager, finally realizes how enormously talented and loved his daughter is. There is the extreme closeness of her family, the marriage to guitarist Chris Perez(Jon Seda)and the snowballing success being ended by tragedy(only dealt with via taped news reports). Actual Selena concert footage is used; and this film overflows with music. Enough can't be said of Lopez in her portrayal...she is so enjoyable, lovable and s-e-x-y! Others featured in the cast: Jackie Guerra, Constance Marle, Jacob Vargas, Rebecca Lee Mezza, Alex Meneses and Sal Lopez.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good movie..missing info
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Morenita052169
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They could have added more into background of saldivar and murder.... And leticia miller would have been a great choice to play Selena she has an eerie resemblance to Selena see for yourself Google leticia miller it's scary other than that pretty good flick, does Selena justice ....rest in peace Selena. burn in hell Yolanda. I think this is overall a good movie if your a Selena fan like me you will like it,I just wish it got more to the nitty gritty. Jennifer Lopez does her best job in this movie I think this is her best film. The costume design is also great.................................Selena was a great performer and a great person she will Be missed
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jennifer Lopez deserved an Oscar for this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    les6969
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought that Jennifer Lopez portrayal of Selena Quintanilla was nothing short of outstanding! Just how good it was can be seen at the very end where we see the real Selena Quintanilla and the likeness and movements that Ms Lopez carries off in the film can be seen in full. But there is much more to the film than a good impression. Jennifer Lopez goes through the full range of emotions and is very believable in every scene she is in. All the other cast members are also superb. My only criticism is why they changed the way she was actually shot? Selena Quintanilla was shot in a motel room and not on stage, but I guess this was done for dramatic effect?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sad, heartfelt, and funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scoobydoo1992-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When i first saw this movie, i did not know who Selena was, and of course i cried at the end but this movie was way more then a movie that you sit and watch you get into it and realize that this really happened and that you want to just cry. It is a sad movie and because it was true you really just want to cry more.I absolutely love the tag-line of the movie, you could not be more dead on with what the movie is really about. I am giving this movie 9/10 because it is truly amazing Go Jennifer Lopez Go Selena. Please go out and rent this movie because it was absolutely amazing and see one of the greatest singers this world has been blessed to hear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie sucked horribly!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruce McLaren
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Selena was not all that to begin with. I lived in the same neighborhood she did. I didn't know her personally, but heard enough about her to dislike her. When she died, I didn't much care. She was treated like a goddess here. Murels, paintings, renaming of the convention center, etc. Enough is enough. Her music was mediocre at best. Her dad was twice the ass he was portrayed in this movie. He was a selfish man who cared about no one but himself. His daughter died, and he used the opportunity to make an extra buck. This movie sucked, and was misleading as to the true nature of the incident and circumstances surrounding it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    false advertisement!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    taoseagle
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie did NOT portray the real Selena nor her family. They are very inconsiderate people. Very money hungry. They will literally "hurt" someone for it as well. Being in the tejano business, you know every band (since it is such a small market). I know bands that were involved with the Q Productions, and every band has been burned in one way or another. They did not get any royalties what so ever, contracts were breached, and the list goes on. At a show in Amarillo, Selena refused to sign autographs and her 1 1/2 hour concert turned into 25 mins because the concert hall was only half full. She was not dedicated to her fans, (it was even written in the Amarillo Globe News the day after). The movie really makes her and her family out to be generous and tight-knit. In actuality, A.B and his father do not get along. Lots of curse words thrown at each other(I witnessed it first hand). Poorly made. Made only for the money that would generate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jennifer Lopez Shines As Selena
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Selena is a biographical drama about the life and career of the late Tejano music star Selena, a recording artist who was well known in the United States and Mexico before she was shot to death.It stars Jennifer Lopez as Selena.Edward James Olmos and Constance Marie co-stars.It was written and directed by Gregory Nava. This film concentrates on Selena's relationship with her family and her rise to fame, dealing only briefly with her tragic death. Abraham Quintanilla is a veteran musician who leads a family-based singing group, The Dinos. At a young age, he notices that his daughter Selena has a strong singing voice, and he works her into the act. However, as she grows older, Selena wants to establish her own musical identity; while her heritage is Mexican-American, her primary language is English, and her favorite artists are American pop acts like Donna Summer. While Selena and Abraham sometimes argue about the musical direction of the group, he always respects and supports her talent, and her blend of Tejano roots music and danceable pop rhythms soon sparks a revolution in Latin music. Selena later earns the wrath of her father when she becomes romantically involved with Chris Perez, a rebellious and long-haired guitarist hired to play with the group, but when they elope and Selena convinces Abraham that their love is sincere, Chris is welcomed into the family. After a long string of successes on the Latin charts and playing to a sellout crowd at the Houston Astrodome and a crowd of 100,000 at a stadium in Monterey, Mexico, Selena begins recording her first album in English, which is expected to make her a mainstream star. However, the fates decreed it was an album she would never complete. The movie surmounts its connect-the-dots approach to its heroine's life to create an appealing, energetic look at a too-briefly soaring musical star.Also,it is a simple story of hope and triumph, of one girl with the drive to succeed defying the odds and following her dream that could truly inspire the viewer to achieve their goals.Finally,Jennifer Lopez truly shines in her performance in the title role as she elevates the film immensely with her radiant and energetic performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Selena Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lexi Philip-Neri
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I never really knew of Selena until I first watched the Selena movie. I must say I was very young when she died so I didn't know much of what happened until I saw the movie. From the first time I saw Selena I fell in love with this movie. Selena is one of my all time favorite movies. The movie Selena starts with her at a young age and ends with the day she dies. I really like how the movie incorporated her childhood and how her music business started because it is an important key part of her life. In the movie they also incorporated the use of the real Selena's voice when they show her making her music and in her concerts--I thought that was a brilliant idea. Since I have seen the movie Selena, I now enjoy listening to Selena's Tejano music. Overall the movie is very well put together and shows the most significant parts of her life to show her success. I highly recommend this movie to anyone who has not seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Selena: When Fairy Tales End With A Bullet ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fairy-tale of Mexican-American singer Selena, whose life was cut short by her bookkeeper. There is still another wonderful Edward James Olmos performance as her protective father. As he did as Jaime Escalante, an LA high school math teacher, Olmos commands the screen as the dominant force in his daughter's life. A hard worker who strove for more, the Olmos character did know when it was time to relent. The film is often clich&eacute;. Presto, and Selena was a star of great magnitude. While Jennifer Lopez did an admirable job, she is still Jennifer and in some scenes, she sounded as she did up against Ralph Fiennes in "Maid in Manhattan."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Muy...Muy....Exciting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    terrellrobinson71
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was afraid of this movie when I was a kid, but when I grew up, I realized that "hay mas a esta historia que el ojo" (Translation: "There's more to this story than meets the eye".) The biopic Selena is one of my favorite movies. The reason why is because in the 90's, Jennifer Lopez was a Fly Girl in the sketch comedy show "In Living Color", was co-starring in "Money Train" and "Blood and Wine" and made her biggest starring role yet, even before her music career went big. There was a few controversies involving the movie, where Lopez was a Puerto Rican from New York, and the real Selena was a Mexican-American from Texas. But then again, all of us accepted Lopez playing Selena and we enjoyed the way she made Selena a real star. In Gregory Nava's film, it begins and ends at the big concert for Selena to become a very huge crossover star at the Houston Astrodome in 1995. Then it really ends with the death of Selena being done by her insane employer (Lupe Ontiveros). (No name spoiler here, but you already know.) In the good ol' days in Corpus Christi, young Selena (Rebecca Lee Meza) was raised well by her father, Abraham (Edward James Olmos) who was in a failed band called the Dinos with two other friends back in the 50's. After hearing Selena sing "We Belong Together" with him, this sparks Abraham to bring The Dinos back to life. Who knew that years later, we get to meet Selena, all grown up and living "la vida dulce" (Translation: "The sweet life") as a Tejano star who would be the biggest Tejano star ever. During the movie, we get to see everything in a condensed, but fast, pace of 127 minutes, the relationship involving her family including mama Marcela (George Lopez's Constance Marie), her romantic relationship between the rock-and-roll guitar player, Chris Perez (Jon Seda), her music (done by the real Selena, not Lopez) and yes, we do get to meet Yolanda herself, with a lot of character developing. Lopez gave a really great performance as Selena, and with the help of Miranda Garrison's choreography, captures the essence of Selena, the way she talks, the way she moves and the way she delivers the energy. The same can be said for Olmos, who can be both funny and dramatic at the same time. (Please pay attention to the argument between Selena, Abraham and Chris.) He also delivers what should've been a washed-down speech about Mexican-Americans into a very smart and charismatic speech. Selena is "muy, muy entretenido" (Translation: "Very, very entertaining.") However, when you do get to the end of the film, there are hankies to be of good use when the candlelight vigils and the archival footage shows and the mourning of a fabulous star comes on-screen. It's very heartbreaking and very emotional in the way that has been done and the final image will make you cry in a good way to prove that she was still there with us after all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A biopic of an exceptional talent.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the heart-felt story of 23-year-old Selena Quintanilla-Perez,played flawlessly by Jennifer Lopez. Selena was a Texas born singer of Tejano music and going from a cult attraction to breaking into an international phenomenon. How factual this film is can be questionable; but very interesting nonetheless.As the rising star was showing brilliance, she was gunned down by the very president of her own fan club in 1995. Shown through flashbacks her father Abraham(Edward James Olmos), a typical stage father/manager, finally realizes how enormously talented and loved his daughter is. There is the extreme closeness of her family, the marriage to guitarist Chris Perez(Jon Seda)and the snowballing success being ended by tragedy(only dealt with via taped news reports). Actual Selena concert footage is used; and this film overflows with music. Enough can't be said of Lopez in her portrayal...she is so enjoyable, lovable and s-e-x-y! Others featured in the cast: Jackie Guerra, Constance Marle, Jacob Vargas, Rebecca Lee Mezza, Alex Meneses and Sal Lopez.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good movie..missing info
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Morenita052169
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They could have added more into background of saldivar and murder.... And leticia miller would have been a great choice to play Selena she has an eerie resemblance to Selena see for yourself Google leticia miller it's scary other than that pretty good flick, does Selena justice ....rest in peace Selena. burn in hell Yolanda. I think this is overall a good movie if your a Selena fan like me you will like it,I just wish it got more to the nitty gritty. Jennifer Lopez does her best job in this movie I think this is her best film. The costume design is also great.................................Selena was a great performer and a great person she will Be missed
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jennifer Lopez deserved an Oscar for this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    les6969
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought that Jennifer Lopez portrayal of Selena Quintanilla was nothing short of outstanding! Just how good it was can be seen at the very end where we see the real Selena Quintanilla and the likeness and movements that Ms Lopez carries off in the film can be seen in full. But there is much more to the film than a good impression. Jennifer Lopez goes through the full range of emotions and is very believable in every scene she is in. All the other cast members are also superb. My only criticism is why they changed the way she was actually shot? Selena Quintanilla was shot in a motel room and not on stage, but I guess this was done for dramatic effect?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sad, heartfelt, and funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scoobydoo1992-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When i first saw this movie, i did not know who Selena was, and of course i cried at the end but this movie was way more then a movie that you sit and watch you get into it and realize that this really happened and that you want to just cry. It is a sad movie and because it was true you really just want to cry more.I absolutely love the tag-line of the movie, you could not be more dead on with what the movie is really about. I am giving this movie 9/10 because it is truly amazing Go Jennifer Lopez Go Selena. Please go out and rent this movie because it was absolutely amazing and see one of the greatest singers this world has been blessed to hear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie sucked horribly!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruce McLaren
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Selena was not all that to begin with. I lived in the same neighborhood she did. I didn't know her personally, but heard enough about her to dislike her. When she died, I didn't much care. She was treated like a goddess here. Murels, paintings, renaming of the convention center, etc. Enough is enough. Her music was mediocre at best. Her dad was twice the ass he was portrayed in this movie. He was a selfish man who cared about no one but himself. His daughter died, and he used the opportunity to make an extra buck. This movie sucked, and was misleading as to the true nature of the incident and circumstances surrounding it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    false advertisement!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    taoseagle
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie did NOT portray the real Selena nor her family. They are very inconsiderate people. Very money hungry. They will literally "hurt" someone for it as well. Being in the tejano business, you know every band (since it is such a small market). I know bands that were involved with the Q Productions, and every band has been burned in one way or another. They did not get any royalties what so ever, contracts were breached, and the list goes on. At a show in Amarillo, Selena refused to sign autographs and her 1 1/2 hour concert turned into 25 mins because the concert hall was only half full. She was not dedicated to her fans, (it was even written in the Amarillo Globe News the day after). The movie really makes her and her family out to be generous and tight-knit. In actuality, A.B and his father do not get along. Lots of curse words thrown at each other(I witnessed it first hand). Poorly made. Made only for the money that would generate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
