<filme>
 <id>
  1279
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120512
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Uma Aventura na Am&eacute;rica Selvagem
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Three brothers - Marshall, Marty and Mark dream of becoming naturalists and portraying animal life of America. One summer their dream comes true, they travel through America, filming ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Three brothers - Marshall, Marty and Mark dream of becoming naturalists and portraying animal life of America. One summer their dream comes true, they travel through America, filming alligators, bears and moose.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   bear
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   moose
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   alligator
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   owl
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   swamp
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   William Dear
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   David Michael Wieger
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jonathan Taylor Thomas
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Devon Sawa
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Scott Bairstow
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Something To Remember
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sharan S
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay.. So, this is my first review without a spoiler. It's because I watched a Nat.Geo documentary called Wild America in 1998 in my 5th grade classroom and wanted to watch it at home. Unfortunately my dad got the VHS of the movie called Wild America and I had no choice but to watch it. But, I was delighted as the youngest kid in the film was at that time my age and I could really connect some events. Yes, there are some immature moments in the film and it is heavily relied on the fact that this film is pure fiction as no parent would allow their kids to go on an expedition. Now, I have watched thousands of movies and I know that watching a movie like this would make you twitch as you've seen better. But, this movie is meant to be seen at the appropriate age -- the early teen years. There's no way you can really enjoy it unless you see it at that time. I don't know if I will enjoy this if I watch it now. But, as my title reads, I will remember this film as one that I watched when I was young and innocent, because that's what the movie's characters are, young and innocent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good clean family fun, and pretty funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William Porter
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I believe in grading movies on a curve. This one is not in the same class as Citizen Kane or Fargo or Some Like It Hot. Instead this is a low-budget and somewhat cornyokay, pretty cornyfamily film like, oh, Because of Winn-Dixie. And graded on the curve appropriate for that class, this is at least an 8 out of 10. I'll be honest, my wife is the one who ordered this from Netflix and I didn't want to see it. I had Gosford Park in the DVD tray ready to go. But my wife thought our 15-year old would enjoy Wild America more, and our daughter agreed. I was outnumbered. So we watched this film. I didn't know anything about it. We were a good 10 minutes or more into the film before I put the family's last name (Stouffer) together with the first name of the oldest son (Marty) and realized, "Hey, I know who this kid is: It's Marty Stouffer of..." D'oh. Anyway, I expect that the real adventures of the real Marty and his brothers weren't quite as colorful as those of the characters in the film. But there were a good combination of excitement (and from some unlikely sources, like F-14 jets dropping bombs) and genuine humor. I laughed hard again and again. Special effects? Well, I'll just say, it ain't Jurassic Park. I think the animal props were rented from a budget prop store in Atlanta. But it didn't matter. I enjoyed the film a lot. Do what I did, get some fresh hot pizza, sit back with your spouse and a kid or two, and enjoy it yourself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    braves-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wild America is a great movie! It is the story of three brothers, Marshall (Johnathan Taylor Thomas), Mark (Devon Sawa), and Marty Stouffer (Scott Bairstow) who go on the road in various locations across America putting their lives in danger as they learn to depend and trust each other while filming endangered wildlife with the dreams of becoming nature filmmakers. All kinds of animals are filmed in this movie from alligators, wolves, deer, wild horses, moose, a cave of raging grizzly bears and more! I saw a little bit of this when it aired on WGN one Saturday afternoon and the parts I saw made me want to watch the whole movie. I first saw the whole movie on Encore Wam about two months ago and I loved it. Since then, it has become one of my favorite movies. I don't have this one yet, but I hope to get it soon. If you're looking for adventure, action, love nature, or you need a movie to watch with the whole family, I highly recommend this. This is not a Disney movie; it is from Warner Bros., so just to warn you, there is some language in this film despite its PG rating. Rating for Wild America: 10/10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome family movie depicting one of America's best loved filmographer!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justajarofclay
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is an absolute classic! It's Disney at its best for the wild at heart it is timeless. The relationship between the brothers makes the movie. Each character is beautifully woven and "real". Inspired by imperfect but truly loving and good old American idealist parents, the boys leap out of the nest and clamor after their own dreams. It rings true to any wise parent, who knows that someday they will have to let go. Great movie for the whole family! A beautiful story of family ties, courage, perseverance and imperfect but admirable characters who each learn their very own lesson. It truly captures the essence of true American spirit! Watch for - The real Stouffer brothers who have cameos in the film as three "uncredited" ruffians (in the scene where the boys are driving to snow country).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Based on a true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ractajeno
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I started making VHS tapes of Marty Stouffer's Wild America TV show as a young adult. Back then, the series was aired on the local PBS station. It became one of the shows I was most glad to support with my PBS membership. If you liked the TV series as much as I, you will no doubt enjoy this movie about Marty and his brothers as well. Mark Stouffer worked with Marty on the TV series as an assistant director and Marty's wife and kids shared the spotlight with Marty at times as well. Mark has also done work on other television shows including some that have ties to nature like Wild America.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    pretty decent family viewing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this movie has the based on a true story tag,but i'm sure there were dramatic licenses taken.the people in the story are real and some of them are probably still around.that much is certain.beyond that,this movie makes for light,though pretty entertaining viewing.it does seem a bit far fetched at times,though.and the story is pretty thin.there is really nothing offensive about the movie that i can tell.there's is no foul language or nudity.there are a few intense scenes with animals that might be a bit too much for young children.i think the movie would be suitable for kids 10 or older,but parents should always use their discretion.overall,this is a fun movie the family could enjoy.for me,Wild America is 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it! Loved it! Loved it!!!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jacquelr
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My husband found a box of old VHS movies after moving into a new home recently. I finally decided to watch this and thought it would be like a "Free Willy" or something. I planned to watch it with my toddler but she fell asleep and I'm glad she did. I thought it was going to be a really kiddie movie but it turned out to be great! I loved the story line, the adventure, it kept my interest to the very end. The reason I didn't give it a 10 was because it did seem a tad bit too long...my hubby kept popping in saying is that movie still on? Nevertheless, I was thoroughly entertained. I found it delightful and wholesome but with an edge. It's nice to escape with a good film that makes u feel good especially with so much garbage that's out there today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty Darned Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fiendish_Dramaturgy
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was done towards the end of Jonathan Taylor Thomas's "cute" years, and was probably around the end of his childhood career. After this dreck, I can only hope he has spent the last 10 years concentrating on his education, and perhaps he can arrange a come back in his late twenties. Otherwise, this film still offers few redeeming qualities, and little to no entertainment value. Three brothers journey into the wilderness to help Marty initiate his nature film-making career. Sounds mildly interesting, doesn't it? Let me be the one to warn you, it is not. The "fun" scenes herein are the most idiotic form of popular tripe, and the suspension of belief required here is wholly impossible. This is just terrible. Aside from a few good vistas, some nice camera angles, and a strong bit part by Danny Glover, there isn't really any reason to bother with this one. It rates a 1.7/10 from... the Fiend :.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild America
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paula122452
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although this is an old movie, I just saw it on television for the first time. It is a great Saturday afternoon movie to watch with kids. I didn't remember Jonathan Taylor Thomas (Weiss) in any other shows, but he has a very commanding presence on screen. The director really knew how capture his very cherub face with his captivating blond hair and haunting blue eyes.For a while I was just mesmerized watching how he moved throughout the film. I could actually 'see' his maturity and growth as he encountered many antics with his brothers. It was very believable and the theme is definitely something I would encourage my students to evaluate and analyze as their own lives reflect some of the same things these young men experienced. It had action, adventure, love and caring parents -for once! The family structure was secure and I was happy to see that. Our kids see so much violence and family destruction- they need to see something positive. I will definitely add this one to my list of videos my students can watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I can watch this movie over and over!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brittybritt631
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was very good!! Jonathan Taylor Thomas is why i decided to see to it!! And to my surprise it was very good!! That is why my family bought!! If your a JTT fan you will love it and if your not it is still an good movie!! The movie is about three brothers in the 60s achieving their dreams!! IT is based on a true story but they do all this wild stuff it is hard to believe this actually happen!!! This is perfect for a movie night!!! They go to so many places and do all this stuff you probably wont want to get up for a bathroom break!! IT has humor, adventure, and a pretty good story for the little ones!! When you are at blockbuster or something and your out of ideas you should try Wild America if your seeking adventure!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Something To Remember
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sharan S
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay.. So, this is my first review without a spoiler. It's because I watched a Nat.Geo documentary called Wild America in 1998 in my 5th grade classroom and wanted to watch it at home. Unfortunately my dad got the VHS of the movie called Wild America and I had no choice but to watch it. But, I was delighted as the youngest kid in the film was at that time my age and I could really connect some events. Yes, there are some immature moments in the film and it is heavily relied on the fact that this film is pure fiction as no parent would allow their kids to go on an expedition. Now, I have watched thousands of movies and I know that watching a movie like this would make you twitch as you've seen better. But, this movie is meant to be seen at the appropriate age -- the early teen years. There's no way you can really enjoy it unless you see it at that time. I don't know if I will enjoy this if I watch it now. But, as my title reads, I will remember this film as one that I watched when I was young and innocent, because that's what the movie's characters are, young and innocent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good clean family fun, and pretty funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William Porter
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I believe in grading movies on a curve. This one is not in the same class as Citizen Kane or Fargo or Some Like It Hot. Instead this is a low-budget and somewhat cornyokay, pretty cornyfamily film like, oh, Because of Winn-Dixie. And graded on the curve appropriate for that class, this is at least an 8 out of 10. I'll be honest, my wife is the one who ordered this from Netflix and I didn't want to see it. I had Gosford Park in the DVD tray ready to go. But my wife thought our 15-year old would enjoy Wild America more, and our daughter agreed. I was outnumbered. So we watched this film. I didn't know anything about it. We were a good 10 minutes or more into the film before I put the family's last name (Stouffer) together with the first name of the oldest son (Marty) and realized, "Hey, I know who this kid is: It's Marty Stouffer of..." D'oh. Anyway, I expect that the real adventures of the real Marty and his brothers weren't quite as colorful as those of the characters in the film. But there were a good combination of excitement (and from some unlikely sources, like F-14 jets dropping bombs) and genuine humor. I laughed hard again and again. Special effects? Well, I'll just say, it ain't Jurassic Park. I think the animal props were rented from a budget prop store in Atlanta. But it didn't matter. I enjoyed the film a lot. Do what I did, get some fresh hot pizza, sit back with your spouse and a kid or two, and enjoy it yourself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    braves-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wild America is a great movie! It is the story of three brothers, Marshall (Johnathan Taylor Thomas), Mark (Devon Sawa), and Marty Stouffer (Scott Bairstow) who go on the road in various locations across America putting their lives in danger as they learn to depend and trust each other while filming endangered wildlife with the dreams of becoming nature filmmakers. All kinds of animals are filmed in this movie from alligators, wolves, deer, wild horses, moose, a cave of raging grizzly bears and more! I saw a little bit of this when it aired on WGN one Saturday afternoon and the parts I saw made me want to watch the whole movie. I first saw the whole movie on Encore Wam about two months ago and I loved it. Since then, it has become one of my favorite movies. I don't have this one yet, but I hope to get it soon. If you're looking for adventure, action, love nature, or you need a movie to watch with the whole family, I highly recommend this. This is not a Disney movie; it is from Warner Bros., so just to warn you, there is some language in this film despite its PG rating. Rating for Wild America: 10/10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome family movie depicting one of America's best loved filmographer!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justajarofclay
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is an absolute classic! It's Disney at its best for the wild at heart it is timeless. The relationship between the brothers makes the movie. Each character is beautifully woven and "real". Inspired by imperfect but truly loving and good old American idealist parents, the boys leap out of the nest and clamor after their own dreams. It rings true to any wise parent, who knows that someday they will have to let go. Great movie for the whole family! A beautiful story of family ties, courage, perseverance and imperfect but admirable characters who each learn their very own lesson. It truly captures the essence of true American spirit! Watch for - The real Stouffer brothers who have cameos in the film as three "uncredited" ruffians (in the scene where the boys are driving to snow country).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Based on a true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ractajeno
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I started making VHS tapes of Marty Stouffer's Wild America TV show as a young adult. Back then, the series was aired on the local PBS station. It became one of the shows I was most glad to support with my PBS membership. If you liked the TV series as much as I, you will no doubt enjoy this movie about Marty and his brothers as well. Mark Stouffer worked with Marty on the TV series as an assistant director and Marty's wife and kids shared the spotlight with Marty at times as well. Mark has also done work on other television shows including some that have ties to nature like Wild America.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    pretty decent family viewing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this movie has the based on a true story tag,but i'm sure there were dramatic licenses taken.the people in the story are real and some of them are probably still around.that much is certain.beyond that,this movie makes for light,though pretty entertaining viewing.it does seem a bit far fetched at times,though.and the story is pretty thin.there is really nothing offensive about the movie that i can tell.there's is no foul language or nudity.there are a few intense scenes with animals that might be a bit too much for young children.i think the movie would be suitable for kids 10 or older,but parents should always use their discretion.overall,this is a fun movie the family could enjoy.for me,Wild America is 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it! Loved it! Loved it!!!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jacquelr
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My husband found a box of old VHS movies after moving into a new home recently. I finally decided to watch this and thought it would be like a "Free Willy" or something. I planned to watch it with my toddler but she fell asleep and I'm glad she did. I thought it was going to be a really kiddie movie but it turned out to be great! I loved the story line, the adventure, it kept my interest to the very end. The reason I didn't give it a 10 was because it did seem a tad bit too long...my hubby kept popping in saying is that movie still on? Nevertheless, I was thoroughly entertained. I found it delightful and wholesome but with an edge. It's nice to escape with a good film that makes u feel good especially with so much garbage that's out there today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty Darned Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fiendish_Dramaturgy
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was done towards the end of Jonathan Taylor Thomas's "cute" years, and was probably around the end of his childhood career. After this dreck, I can only hope he has spent the last 10 years concentrating on his education, and perhaps he can arrange a come back in his late twenties. Otherwise, this film still offers few redeeming qualities, and little to no entertainment value. Three brothers journey into the wilderness to help Marty initiate his nature film-making career. Sounds mildly interesting, doesn't it? Let me be the one to warn you, it is not. The "fun" scenes herein are the most idiotic form of popular tripe, and the suspension of belief required here is wholly impossible. This is just terrible. Aside from a few good vistas, some nice camera angles, and a strong bit part by Danny Glover, there isn't really any reason to bother with this one. It rates a 1.7/10 from... the Fiend :.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild America
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paula122452
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although this is an old movie, I just saw it on television for the first time. It is a great Saturday afternoon movie to watch with kids. I didn't remember Jonathan Taylor Thomas (Weiss) in any other shows, but he has a very commanding presence on screen. The director really knew how capture his very cherub face with his captivating blond hair and haunting blue eyes.For a while I was just mesmerized watching how he moved throughout the film. I could actually 'see' his maturity and growth as he encountered many antics with his brothers. It was very believable and the theme is definitely something I would encourage my students to evaluate and analyze as their own lives reflect some of the same things these young men experienced. It had action, adventure, love and caring parents -for once! The family structure was secure and I was happy to see that. Our kids see so much violence and family destruction- they need to see something positive. I will definitely add this one to my list of videos my students can watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I can watch this movie over and over!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brittybritt631
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was very good!! Jonathan Taylor Thomas is why i decided to see to it!! And to my surprise it was very good!! That is why my family bought!! If your a JTT fan you will love it and if your not it is still an good movie!! The movie is about three brothers in the 60s achieving their dreams!! IT is based on a true story but they do all this wild stuff it is hard to believe this actually happen!!! This is perfect for a movie night!!! They go to so many places and do all this stuff you probably wont want to get up for a bathroom break!! IT has humor, adventure, and a pretty good story for the little ones!! When you are at blockbuster or something and your out of ideas you should try Wild America if your seeking adventure!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Something To Remember
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sharan S
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay.. So, this is my first review without a spoiler. It's because I watched a Nat.Geo documentary called Wild America in 1998 in my 5th grade classroom and wanted to watch it at home. Unfortunately my dad got the VHS of the movie called Wild America and I had no choice but to watch it. But, I was delighted as the youngest kid in the film was at that time my age and I could really connect some events. Yes, there are some immature moments in the film and it is heavily relied on the fact that this film is pure fiction as no parent would allow their kids to go on an expedition. Now, I have watched thousands of movies and I know that watching a movie like this would make you twitch as you've seen better. But, this movie is meant to be seen at the appropriate age -- the early teen years. There's no way you can really enjoy it unless you see it at that time. I don't know if I will enjoy this if I watch it now. But, as my title reads, I will remember this film as one that I watched when I was young and innocent, because that's what the movie's characters are, young and innocent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good clean family fun, and pretty funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William Porter
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I believe in grading movies on a curve. This one is not in the same class as Citizen Kane or Fargo or Some Like It Hot. Instead this is a low-budget and somewhat cornyokay, pretty cornyfamily film like, oh, Because of Winn-Dixie. And graded on the curve appropriate for that class, this is at least an 8 out of 10. I'll be honest, my wife is the one who ordered this from Netflix and I didn't want to see it. I had Gosford Park in the DVD tray ready to go. But my wife thought our 15-year old would enjoy Wild America more, and our daughter agreed. I was outnumbered. So we watched this film. I didn't know anything about it. We were a good 10 minutes or more into the film before I put the family's last name (Stouffer) together with the first name of the oldest son (Marty) and realized, "Hey, I know who this kid is: It's Marty Stouffer of..." D'oh. Anyway, I expect that the real adventures of the real Marty and his brothers weren't quite as colorful as those of the characters in the film. But there were a good combination of excitement (and from some unlikely sources, like F-14 jets dropping bombs) and genuine humor. I laughed hard again and again. Special effects? Well, I'll just say, it ain't Jurassic Park. I think the animal props were rented from a budget prop store in Atlanta. But it didn't matter. I enjoyed the film a lot. Do what I did, get some fresh hot pizza, sit back with your spouse and a kid or two, and enjoy it yourself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    braves-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wild America is a great movie! It is the story of three brothers, Marshall (Johnathan Taylor Thomas), Mark (Devon Sawa), and Marty Stouffer (Scott Bairstow) who go on the road in various locations across America putting their lives in danger as they learn to depend and trust each other while filming endangered wildlife with the dreams of becoming nature filmmakers. All kinds of animals are filmed in this movie from alligators, wolves, deer, wild horses, moose, a cave of raging grizzly bears and more! I saw a little bit of this when it aired on WGN one Saturday afternoon and the parts I saw made me want to watch the whole movie. I first saw the whole movie on Encore Wam about two months ago and I loved it. Since then, it has become one of my favorite movies. I don't have this one yet, but I hope to get it soon. If you're looking for adventure, action, love nature, or you need a movie to watch with the whole family, I highly recommend this. This is not a Disney movie; it is from Warner Bros., so just to warn you, there is some language in this film despite its PG rating. Rating for Wild America: 10/10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome family movie depicting one of America's best loved filmographer!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justajarofclay
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is an absolute classic! It's Disney at its best for the wild at heart it is timeless. The relationship between the brothers makes the movie. Each character is beautifully woven and "real". Inspired by imperfect but truly loving and good old American idealist parents, the boys leap out of the nest and clamor after their own dreams. It rings true to any wise parent, who knows that someday they will have to let go. Great movie for the whole family! A beautiful story of family ties, courage, perseverance and imperfect but admirable characters who each learn their very own lesson. It truly captures the essence of true American spirit! Watch for - The real Stouffer brothers who have cameos in the film as three "uncredited" ruffians (in the scene where the boys are driving to snow country).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Based on a true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ractajeno
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I started making VHS tapes of Marty Stouffer's Wild America TV show as a young adult. Back then, the series was aired on the local PBS station. It became one of the shows I was most glad to support with my PBS membership. If you liked the TV series as much as I, you will no doubt enjoy this movie about Marty and his brothers as well. Mark Stouffer worked with Marty on the TV series as an assistant director and Marty's wife and kids shared the spotlight with Marty at times as well. Mark has also done work on other television shows including some that have ties to nature like Wild America.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    pretty decent family viewing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this movie has the based on a true story tag,but i'm sure there were dramatic licenses taken.the people in the story are real and some of them are probably still around.that much is certain.beyond that,this movie makes for light,though pretty entertaining viewing.it does seem a bit far fetched at times,though.and the story is pretty thin.there is really nothing offensive about the movie that i can tell.there's is no foul language or nudity.there are a few intense scenes with animals that might be a bit too much for young children.i think the movie would be suitable for kids 10 or older,but parents should always use their discretion.overall,this is a fun movie the family could enjoy.for me,Wild America is 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it! Loved it! Loved it!!!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jacquelr
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My husband found a box of old VHS movies after moving into a new home recently. I finally decided to watch this and thought it would be like a "Free Willy" or something. I planned to watch it with my toddler but she fell asleep and I'm glad she did. I thought it was going to be a really kiddie movie but it turned out to be great! I loved the story line, the adventure, it kept my interest to the very end. The reason I didn't give it a 10 was because it did seem a tad bit too long...my hubby kept popping in saying is that movie still on? Nevertheless, I was thoroughly entertained. I found it delightful and wholesome but with an edge. It's nice to escape with a good film that makes u feel good especially with so much garbage that's out there today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty Darned Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fiendish_Dramaturgy
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was done towards the end of Jonathan Taylor Thomas's "cute" years, and was probably around the end of his childhood career. After this dreck, I can only hope he has spent the last 10 years concentrating on his education, and perhaps he can arrange a come back in his late twenties. Otherwise, this film still offers few redeeming qualities, and little to no entertainment value. Three brothers journey into the wilderness to help Marty initiate his nature film-making career. Sounds mildly interesting, doesn't it? Let me be the one to warn you, it is not. The "fun" scenes herein are the most idiotic form of popular tripe, and the suspension of belief required here is wholly impossible. This is just terrible. Aside from a few good vistas, some nice camera angles, and a strong bit part by Danny Glover, there isn't really any reason to bother with this one. It rates a 1.7/10 from... the Fiend :.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild America
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paula122452
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although this is an old movie, I just saw it on television for the first time. It is a great Saturday afternoon movie to watch with kids. I didn't remember Jonathan Taylor Thomas (Weiss) in any other shows, but he has a very commanding presence on screen. The director really knew how capture his very cherub face with his captivating blond hair and haunting blue eyes.For a while I was just mesmerized watching how he moved throughout the film. I could actually 'see' his maturity and growth as he encountered many antics with his brothers. It was very believable and the theme is definitely something I would encourage my students to evaluate and analyze as their own lives reflect some of the same things these young men experienced. It had action, adventure, love and caring parents -for once! The family structure was secure and I was happy to see that. Our kids see so much violence and family destruction- they need to see something positive. I will definitely add this one to my list of videos my students can watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I can watch this movie over and over!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brittybritt631
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was very good!! Jonathan Taylor Thomas is why i decided to see to it!! And to my surprise it was very good!! That is why my family bought!! If your a JTT fan you will love it and if your not it is still an good movie!! The movie is about three brothers in the 60s achieving their dreams!! IT is based on a true story but they do all this wild stuff it is hard to believe this actually happen!!! This is perfect for a movie night!!! They go to so many places and do all this stuff you probably wont want to get up for a bathroom break!! IT has humor, adventure, and a pretty good story for the little ones!! When you are at blockbuster or something and your out of ideas you should try Wild America if your seeking adventure!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Something To Remember
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sharan S
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay.. So, this is my first review without a spoiler. It's because I watched a Nat.Geo documentary called Wild America in 1998 in my 5th grade classroom and wanted to watch it at home. Unfortunately my dad got the VHS of the movie called Wild America and I had no choice but to watch it. But, I was delighted as the youngest kid in the film was at that time my age and I could really connect some events. Yes, there are some immature moments in the film and it is heavily relied on the fact that this film is pure fiction as no parent would allow their kids to go on an expedition. Now, I have watched thousands of movies and I know that watching a movie like this would make you twitch as you've seen better. But, this movie is meant to be seen at the appropriate age -- the early teen years. There's no way you can really enjoy it unless you see it at that time. I don't know if I will enjoy this if I watch it now. But, as my title reads, I will remember this film as one that I watched when I was young and innocent, because that's what the movie's characters are, young and innocent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good clean family fun, and pretty funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William Porter
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I believe in grading movies on a curve. This one is not in the same class as Citizen Kane or Fargo or Some Like It Hot. Instead this is a low-budget and somewhat cornyokay, pretty cornyfamily film like, oh, Because of Winn-Dixie. And graded on the curve appropriate for that class, this is at least an 8 out of 10. I'll be honest, my wife is the one who ordered this from Netflix and I didn't want to see it. I had Gosford Park in the DVD tray ready to go. But my wife thought our 15-year old would enjoy Wild America more, and our daughter agreed. I was outnumbered. So we watched this film. I didn't know anything about it. We were a good 10 minutes or more into the film before I put the family's last name (Stouffer) together with the first name of the oldest son (Marty) and realized, "Hey, I know who this kid is: It's Marty Stouffer of..." D'oh. Anyway, I expect that the real adventures of the real Marty and his brothers weren't quite as colorful as those of the characters in the film. But there were a good combination of excitement (and from some unlikely sources, like F-14 jets dropping bombs) and genuine humor. I laughed hard again and again. Special effects? Well, I'll just say, it ain't Jurassic Park. I think the animal props were rented from a budget prop store in Atlanta. But it didn't matter. I enjoyed the film a lot. Do what I did, get some fresh hot pizza, sit back with your spouse and a kid or two, and enjoy it yourself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    braves-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wild America is a great movie! It is the story of three brothers, Marshall (Johnathan Taylor Thomas), Mark (Devon Sawa), and Marty Stouffer (Scott Bairstow) who go on the road in various locations across America putting their lives in danger as they learn to depend and trust each other while filming endangered wildlife with the dreams of becoming nature filmmakers. All kinds of animals are filmed in this movie from alligators, wolves, deer, wild horses, moose, a cave of raging grizzly bears and more! I saw a little bit of this when it aired on WGN one Saturday afternoon and the parts I saw made me want to watch the whole movie. I first saw the whole movie on Encore Wam about two months ago and I loved it. Since then, it has become one of my favorite movies. I don't have this one yet, but I hope to get it soon. If you're looking for adventure, action, love nature, or you need a movie to watch with the whole family, I highly recommend this. This is not a Disney movie; it is from Warner Bros., so just to warn you, there is some language in this film despite its PG rating. Rating for Wild America: 10/10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome family movie depicting one of America's best loved filmographer!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justajarofclay
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is an absolute classic! It's Disney at its best for the wild at heart it is timeless. The relationship between the brothers makes the movie. Each character is beautifully woven and "real". Inspired by imperfect but truly loving and good old American idealist parents, the boys leap out of the nest and clamor after their own dreams. It rings true to any wise parent, who knows that someday they will have to let go. Great movie for the whole family! A beautiful story of family ties, courage, perseverance and imperfect but admirable characters who each learn their very own lesson. It truly captures the essence of true American spirit! Watch for - The real Stouffer brothers who have cameos in the film as three "uncredited" ruffians (in the scene where the boys are driving to snow country).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Based on a true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ractajeno
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I started making VHS tapes of Marty Stouffer's Wild America TV show as a young adult. Back then, the series was aired on the local PBS station. It became one of the shows I was most glad to support with my PBS membership. If you liked the TV series as much as I, you will no doubt enjoy this movie about Marty and his brothers as well. Mark Stouffer worked with Marty on the TV series as an assistant director and Marty's wife and kids shared the spotlight with Marty at times as well. Mark has also done work on other television shows including some that have ties to nature like Wild America.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    pretty decent family viewing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this movie has the based on a true story tag,but i'm sure there were dramatic licenses taken.the people in the story are real and some of them are probably still around.that much is certain.beyond that,this movie makes for light,though pretty entertaining viewing.it does seem a bit far fetched at times,though.and the story is pretty thin.there is really nothing offensive about the movie that i can tell.there's is no foul language or nudity.there are a few intense scenes with animals that might be a bit too much for young children.i think the movie would be suitable for kids 10 or older,but parents should always use their discretion.overall,this is a fun movie the family could enjoy.for me,Wild America is 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it! Loved it! Loved it!!!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jacquelr
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My husband found a box of old VHS movies after moving into a new home recently. I finally decided to watch this and thought it would be like a "Free Willy" or something. I planned to watch it with my toddler but she fell asleep and I'm glad she did. I thought it was going to be a really kiddie movie but it turned out to be great! I loved the story line, the adventure, it kept my interest to the very end. The reason I didn't give it a 10 was because it did seem a tad bit too long...my hubby kept popping in saying is that movie still on? Nevertheless, I was thoroughly entertained. I found it delightful and wholesome but with an edge. It's nice to escape with a good film that makes u feel good especially with so much garbage that's out there today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty Darned Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fiendish_Dramaturgy
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was done towards the end of Jonathan Taylor Thomas's "cute" years, and was probably around the end of his childhood career. After this dreck, I can only hope he has spent the last 10 years concentrating on his education, and perhaps he can arrange a come back in his late twenties. Otherwise, this film still offers few redeeming qualities, and little to no entertainment value. Three brothers journey into the wilderness to help Marty initiate his nature film-making career. Sounds mildly interesting, doesn't it? Let me be the one to warn you, it is not. The "fun" scenes herein are the most idiotic form of popular tripe, and the suspension of belief required here is wholly impossible. This is just terrible. Aside from a few good vistas, some nice camera angles, and a strong bit part by Danny Glover, there isn't really any reason to bother with this one. It rates a 1.7/10 from... the Fiend :.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild America
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paula122452
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although this is an old movie, I just saw it on television for the first time. It is a great Saturday afternoon movie to watch with kids. I didn't remember Jonathan Taylor Thomas (Weiss) in any other shows, but he has a very commanding presence on screen. The director really knew how capture his very cherub face with his captivating blond hair and haunting blue eyes.For a while I was just mesmerized watching how he moved throughout the film. I could actually 'see' his maturity and growth as he encountered many antics with his brothers. It was very believable and the theme is definitely something I would encourage my students to evaluate and analyze as their own lives reflect some of the same things these young men experienced. It had action, adventure, love and caring parents -for once! The family structure was secure and I was happy to see that. Our kids see so much violence and family destruction- they need to see something positive. I will definitely add this one to my list of videos my students can watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I can watch this movie over and over!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brittybritt631
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was very good!! Jonathan Taylor Thomas is why i decided to see to it!! And to my surprise it was very good!! That is why my family bought!! If your a JTT fan you will love it and if your not it is still an good movie!! The movie is about three brothers in the 60s achieving their dreams!! IT is based on a true story but they do all this wild stuff it is hard to believe this actually happen!!! This is perfect for a movie night!!! They go to so many places and do all this stuff you probably wont want to get up for a bathroom break!! IT has humor, adventure, and a pretty good story for the little ones!! When you are at blockbuster or something and your out of ideas you should try Wild America if your seeking adventure!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
