<filme>
 <id>
  1287
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116165
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Ed - Um Macaco Muito Louco
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  2.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A trained chimpanzee plays third base for a minor-league baseball team.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A trained chimpanzee plays third base for a minor-league baseball team.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sport
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   chimpanzee
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   critically bashed
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   monkey
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   baseball
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sports team
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Bill Couturi&eacute;
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Ken Richards
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Janus Cercone
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Matt LeBlanc
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jayne Brook
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Gene Ross
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great movie for people who need to practice looking disapproving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Twetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Im not sure I have enough to say about "Ed" to fill the mandatory ten lines but here goes. I spent the first 56 minutes of the movie feeling an intense loathing of everything on the screen, by which point my face got tired from constantly having a disapproving look; so I had to go for an ironic smile for about fourteen minutes. At one hour and nine minutes the movie apparently got tired of itself and decided to start the plot which lasted for about ten minutes, after which it went back being loathsome. Shortly after the end happened but I still feel bitter about having seen it. It's not cute, it's not funny, it' just bad.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh dear...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A56T
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film deserves it's place in the bottom 100 on this site. Matt Le Blanc was at the height of his fame when he made this movie but even he cannot save it from being a flop. It's the sort of movie we'd expect his character Joey Tribbiani to star in because it's so bad. It's difficult to find any redeeming features in this film and I can only say that somewhere in the world a child must have enjoyed it due to the humour and the fact that Le Blanc is clearly trying to make the material appear as natural as possible but failing miserably. In years to come it may end up being a cult classic but even then it will probably be for all the wrong reasons. Le Blanc never has had much luck with movies and this may be an example of why if he read this script and thought it would be a good career move.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nobody Spanks This Monkey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the family farm, handsome "Charlotte's Web" reader Matt LeBlanc (as Jack "Deuce" Cooper) sleeps with his big dog. A strong pitching arm gets Mr. LeBlanc on the "Santa Rosa Rockets" team. After a slow start, LeBlanc is ordered to room with Edward "Ed" Sullivan, a large chimpanzee who winds up playing third base for the season. "Ed" doesn't monkey around, and is soon the team's star player. LeBlanc is nonplussed by the chimp, but see if they don't soon share bed and bathroom... "Ed" eventually helps LeBlanc play hide the banana with attractive Jayne Brook (as Lydia), picking up his cues from her precociously cute daughter Doren Fein (as Lizzie). Monkey see, monkey do. Everything here is cute but the monkey. But, with the lamest material to work with, the monkey had to be cute. Highlighted by brown teeth and red eyes, "Ed" looks like he belongs in a horror movie, and often sounds like he's passing gas. Otherwise, this might have appealed to young children. ** Ed (3/15/96) Bill Couturie ~ Matt LeBlanc, Jayne Brook, Jack Warden, Bill Cobbs
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excruciatingly embarrassing!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love movies and have done for as long as I can remember, but when I saw Ed for the first time recently I found it excruciatingly embarrassing. It isn't even so bad it's good or a mess that is worth watching. It is an excruciatingly embarrassing film that has next to no redeeming features. When it comes to talking about what makes Ed so bad, I honestly do not know where to begin. The film is ridden with clich&eacute;s, and what is worse these clich&eacute;s are badly explored and written. Ed is also a very poorly written film, the humour is crude(which I didn't mind) but it is also very, very unfunny with minimal laughs and cringeworthy dialogue. The story is predictable too, sometimes that isn't always a bad thing, but it is when nothing of interest happens and you can smell events like the ending a mile off. The direction is flat as well, the production values didn't do anything for me and the soundtrack was annoying and too jaunty. The acting is absolutely awful, and it certainly doesn't help that none of the characters are likable in any way. Matt LeBlanc can be good and endearing, but he and his character aren't here. LeBlanc's character is so irritating you want to strangle him, and the less said about that monkey the better. Overall, an unfunny and embarrassing mess and possibly the worst movie of 1996, only Bio Dome comes close to being worse. 1/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing even the least bit funny here, and the monkey is a major part of this!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I distinctly remember that it was at a family gathering in the autumn of 1996, when I was told about "Ed", a movie which I had never heard of before. I also got to see at least a bit of the film at that gathering, and it must have been pretty new to the home video format at the time. I was ten years old when this happened, and I guess I was pretty much indifferent to what I saw, most of which I wouldn't remember. I don't think I ever heard anything about this big time flop again until at least nearly a decade later, when I noticed that it was in the IMDb bottom 100. Before discovering that, I knew nothing about the family sports comedy's general reception, but for several years now, I have known that it's generally considered to be atrocious, so I was not too surprised by its lameness when I finally watched it all, fifteen years after its theatrical release. Jack "Deuce" Cooper proves to be a very talented baseball pitcher while playing on his farm, and his skills get him into the minor leagues, playing for the Santa Rosa Rockets, but it turns out that he doesn't do so well while playing in front of a crowd. Soon after he joins the team, they get another new player, one who happens to be a chimpanzee named Ed! One would likely believe that a monkey couldn't possibly play baseball, but surprisingly, this one is a natural on the field! This unusual baseball player becomes Jack's new roommate, and unfortunately, he soon ends up causing a lot of trouble for the human baseball player in the home, making big messes and doing things Jack wishes he wouldn't do. However, despite Ed's sometimes reckless behaviour, he turns out to be a really good friend to Jack, and a big help to the Rockets during games, but somebody has other plans for this popular minor league player! I don't know what the humour here is like for kids, but while watching the film after growing up, there wasn't a single moment I was unable to keep a straight face through! Ed is one unconvincing monkey, and is also very unfunny with his antics! The sight gags involving this character causing trouble and being messy, plus the ones involving his bodily functions, are perfect examples of the movie's poor attempts to be humorous. Ed may be the weakest aspect of the film, but any other character that is supposed to be funny, including more than one human Santa Rosa Rockets player and the Liz character, also fails miserably. In addition to being consistently unfunny, "Ed" also has a dull plot (one could easily call that an understatement), and whether Jack "Deuce" Cooper is out on the baseball field with Ed, at home or on the road having problems with the chimp's behaviour, dating the Lydia character, etc., it's generally not entertaining at all. I should probably mention that the story sure is predictable as well, with no big surprises, and if the writers ever tried to be touching here, they also failed at that. All I could remember from what I saw of this movie back when I was ten years old was a baseball player saying Ed is Curious George, shaking his hand, and telling him he has read all his books, and the trouble the monkey causes as Jack's roommate making the struggling baseball player say, "I'm gonna spank that monkey!" Well, after watching what I saw all those years ago, along with the rest of the film, I'm going to remember a lot more, not that these memories will do me much good. If I hadn't been introduced to the film in my childhood, I doubt it would have really caught my attention when I found it in the bottom 100, and I wouldn't have ever seen it, but wouldn't have missed out on much had that been the case. Unlike so many other voters, I can't give "Ed" the lowest rating possible, and am not even 100% sure about my 2/10 rating, but see no really good reason why I should rate it any higher, since I agree with the vast majority that it's thoroughly unfunny and badly written. I may not have said much about this 1996 flop that others have already pointed out, but I agree with these criticisms, and would say there's absolutely nothing to make "Ed" worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chewy Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I personally thought it was one of the best movies I have seen in a while. I watched it recently on HBO, and I thought the plot was absolutely great. Whoever wrote the screenplay did an astounding job. Matt LeBlanc's acting was great in my opinion, and his chemistry with Ed was undeniably amazing. I couldn't even tell that Ed was a fake chimp because of the great editing and special effects in this movie. I am planning to watch this movie later while I enjoy a buttery bowl of Orville Redenbacher's popcorn. If you are reading this review, please do not listen to the other user reviews. The movie was great and a fun-filled family comedy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hands down the worst movie I've ever seen!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (mk3_@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this for my 12th birthday party because my mom wouldn't take us to anything rated PG-13 or higher. So I had to pick between Ed and Homeward Bound 2. I wasn't excited about either but I went with Ed because of the baseball angle. To this day, 14 years later everyone who was at that party, kids and adults, are united in agreement that it was the worst movie we've ever seen. I've tried to rewatch it a few times and show it to my fianc&eacute;' just to laugh at how bad it is but I can't even do that. We made it through 15 minutes and she couldn't take anymore. It's completely devoid of entertainment and all the other reviews have captured the reasons why. Every now and then I like to read the comments about it and chuckle because we still talk about how bad that movie was all these years later.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I want you to meet Mickey Mantle's monkey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Read my one line summary. Out loud, if it helps. More than once, if you need to. Do you honestly believe that it can be spoken, and that individual retaining just a smidgen of dignity, and continue to be respected? I wish I could claim that it is the only of its kind in this. Oh, how I would love to claim that this does not deserve its low rating... as I type this, it is #82 on the Bottom 100 on the site. This is irritating and intolerable from start to finish. No, I am not the intended viewer for this, but I maintain that this isn't likely to appeal to all that many. Simply put, unless you find chimps adorable and hilarious, there's nothing in this for you. It's well-trained, I'll give 'em that. I frankly wanted Ed to go nuts and kill everyone, which may be because the last 8 days, I've watched the Halloween films. If this is for children, then what's with the numerous crude jokes that are not appropriate for them? The material is atrocious, utterly devoid of creativity and the delivery is outrageously poor. If you laugh even once during this, it will probably be a reflex, or one of the kind that comes from a desperation that you can no longer contain, that you must *express*. The lead is annoying, and every "acting performance" is horrible. Jim Caviezel? Are you kidding me? Every character is one-note and stereotypical, and that girl is ridiculously precocious. The cartoon sound effects and "goofy music" try way too hard, and it winds up being embarrassing. Editing and cinematography are unimpressive. This mess manages to squeeze in every clich&eacute; in the book. I recommend this audience-insulting crap solely to those who have no taste, or those who *have to* see for themselves how awful it is. Your movie sucks, Matt. 1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I think the writers were usin' 'wacky tobacky'--that's the only thing that might explain this plot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even for a kids' movie, the premise to ED is incredibly lame. So lame that it boggles the mind to imagine that this film was made in the first place. I can only assume that the writers and execs at the studio were under the influence of some mind-altering drug while they were watching a re-run of a "Francis the Mule" film or else had loved ones kidnapped in order to force this film to be made. This is the only way you could understand this film. Even the worst of the most contrived Disney films of the 1960s and 70s look like "Gone With the Wind" compared to this! Matt LeBlanc stars as a guy who has a great pitching arm. However, when his game stinks, the manager punishes him by sending him to pick someone up at the bus stop. That 'someone' turns out to be a baseball playing chimp who is the team's new mascot. When I first saw this chimp, he really looked creepy--and I assume it was just a midget in an ape suit. It looked more realistic than chimps looked in films in 1940, but still looked bizarre and a bit scary! Well, only in a movie would it turn out that the chimp was a fantastic baseball player--with an arm like a rocket AND a thorough knowledge of how to play ball! How all the actors were able to participate in this farce of a film with straight faces is beyond me. Talk about an insane plot! Even small children would find this tough to swallow. However, given that he ultimately is SMARTER than LeBlanc isn't quite as hard to believe (at least in light of his role on "Friends"). Some of the low-points in this dreadful film include frequent fart jokes, snot jokes, Ed and LeBlanc both peeing together at the same toilet, belching, Ed driving a truck at what appears to be 400 mph, more fart jokes and Ed plying dress-up with grandma's clothes. At no point in the film is it clever or does it poke fun of itself (the only way this MIGHT have worked). Overall, a sorry mess of a film that is so inexplicably dumb that I can't believe it was made in the first place. Practically every clich&eacute; known to baseball is in this film and its only entertainment value is for people who want to laugh at the sheer inanity of the movie. Clearly, this film has earned its place on IMDb's Bottom 100 list!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It really is a secret stoner movie.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    westcor
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ed, what can you say about this movie that hasn't already been said? As the 3-bannanna reviewer stated, it contains all that is needed in a great movie. 1)Monkeys 2)Baseball 3)Someone from the show 'Friends.' If you pay to watch this movie you are a fool, luckily U-verse had it on for demand for free. Though on second thought, I remembered I did ask for my girlfriend to get it for me on Blu-ray if it ever came out; should a miracle like that ever happen. The reason people didn't find this movie funny, is because everyone thinks its a kid's movie. It's not. It's a movie for someone who just smoked a lot of bud. I laughed so hard at some points I was crying, and literally nothing would be happening except the Monkey farting or doing a flip while catching a ball. This movie would of been a complete disaster if they would have used a real monkey. It still is a disaster of sorts, but it is much funnier with a robotic monkey than the real thing. I have no idea how to even rate this movie, as it obviously is a horrible piece of cinema (OK that gives it too much credit, a horrible piece of film); but at the same time made me laugh more than any movie I can think of in recent history. I will meet in the middle and give it a 5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great movie for people who need to practice looking disapproving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Twetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Im not sure I have enough to say about "Ed" to fill the mandatory ten lines but here goes. I spent the first 56 minutes of the movie feeling an intense loathing of everything on the screen, by which point my face got tired from constantly having a disapproving look; so I had to go for an ironic smile for about fourteen minutes. At one hour and nine minutes the movie apparently got tired of itself and decided to start the plot which lasted for about ten minutes, after which it went back being loathsome. Shortly after the end happened but I still feel bitter about having seen it. It's not cute, it's not funny, it' just bad.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh dear...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A56T
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film deserves it's place in the bottom 100 on this site. Matt Le Blanc was at the height of his fame when he made this movie but even he cannot save it from being a flop. It's the sort of movie we'd expect his character Joey Tribbiani to star in because it's so bad. It's difficult to find any redeeming features in this film and I can only say that somewhere in the world a child must have enjoyed it due to the humour and the fact that Le Blanc is clearly trying to make the material appear as natural as possible but failing miserably. In years to come it may end up being a cult classic but even then it will probably be for all the wrong reasons. Le Blanc never has had much luck with movies and this may be an example of why if he read this script and thought it would be a good career move.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nobody Spanks This Monkey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the family farm, handsome "Charlotte's Web" reader Matt LeBlanc (as Jack "Deuce" Cooper) sleeps with his big dog. A strong pitching arm gets Mr. LeBlanc on the "Santa Rosa Rockets" team. After a slow start, LeBlanc is ordered to room with Edward "Ed" Sullivan, a large chimpanzee who winds up playing third base for the season. "Ed" doesn't monkey around, and is soon the team's star player. LeBlanc is nonplussed by the chimp, but see if they don't soon share bed and bathroom... "Ed" eventually helps LeBlanc play hide the banana with attractive Jayne Brook (as Lydia), picking up his cues from her precociously cute daughter Doren Fein (as Lizzie). Monkey see, monkey do. Everything here is cute but the monkey. But, with the lamest material to work with, the monkey had to be cute. Highlighted by brown teeth and red eyes, "Ed" looks like he belongs in a horror movie, and often sounds like he's passing gas. Otherwise, this might have appealed to young children. ** Ed (3/15/96) Bill Couturie ~ Matt LeBlanc, Jayne Brook, Jack Warden, Bill Cobbs
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excruciatingly embarrassing!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love movies and have done for as long as I can remember, but when I saw Ed for the first time recently I found it excruciatingly embarrassing. It isn't even so bad it's good or a mess that is worth watching. It is an excruciatingly embarrassing film that has next to no redeeming features. When it comes to talking about what makes Ed so bad, I honestly do not know where to begin. The film is ridden with clich&eacute;s, and what is worse these clich&eacute;s are badly explored and written. Ed is also a very poorly written film, the humour is crude(which I didn't mind) but it is also very, very unfunny with minimal laughs and cringeworthy dialogue. The story is predictable too, sometimes that isn't always a bad thing, but it is when nothing of interest happens and you can smell events like the ending a mile off. The direction is flat as well, the production values didn't do anything for me and the soundtrack was annoying and too jaunty. The acting is absolutely awful, and it certainly doesn't help that none of the characters are likable in any way. Matt LeBlanc can be good and endearing, but he and his character aren't here. LeBlanc's character is so irritating you want to strangle him, and the less said about that monkey the better. Overall, an unfunny and embarrassing mess and possibly the worst movie of 1996, only Bio Dome comes close to being worse. 1/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing even the least bit funny here, and the monkey is a major part of this!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I distinctly remember that it was at a family gathering in the autumn of 1996, when I was told about "Ed", a movie which I had never heard of before. I also got to see at least a bit of the film at that gathering, and it must have been pretty new to the home video format at the time. I was ten years old when this happened, and I guess I was pretty much indifferent to what I saw, most of which I wouldn't remember. I don't think I ever heard anything about this big time flop again until at least nearly a decade later, when I noticed that it was in the IMDb bottom 100. Before discovering that, I knew nothing about the family sports comedy's general reception, but for several years now, I have known that it's generally considered to be atrocious, so I was not too surprised by its lameness when I finally watched it all, fifteen years after its theatrical release. Jack "Deuce" Cooper proves to be a very talented baseball pitcher while playing on his farm, and his skills get him into the minor leagues, playing for the Santa Rosa Rockets, but it turns out that he doesn't do so well while playing in front of a crowd. Soon after he joins the team, they get another new player, one who happens to be a chimpanzee named Ed! One would likely believe that a monkey couldn't possibly play baseball, but surprisingly, this one is a natural on the field! This unusual baseball player becomes Jack's new roommate, and unfortunately, he soon ends up causing a lot of trouble for the human baseball player in the home, making big messes and doing things Jack wishes he wouldn't do. However, despite Ed's sometimes reckless behaviour, he turns out to be a really good friend to Jack, and a big help to the Rockets during games, but somebody has other plans for this popular minor league player! I don't know what the humour here is like for kids, but while watching the film after growing up, there wasn't a single moment I was unable to keep a straight face through! Ed is one unconvincing monkey, and is also very unfunny with his antics! The sight gags involving this character causing trouble and being messy, plus the ones involving his bodily functions, are perfect examples of the movie's poor attempts to be humorous. Ed may be the weakest aspect of the film, but any other character that is supposed to be funny, including more than one human Santa Rosa Rockets player and the Liz character, also fails miserably. In addition to being consistently unfunny, "Ed" also has a dull plot (one could easily call that an understatement), and whether Jack "Deuce" Cooper is out on the baseball field with Ed, at home or on the road having problems with the chimp's behaviour, dating the Lydia character, etc., it's generally not entertaining at all. I should probably mention that the story sure is predictable as well, with no big surprises, and if the writers ever tried to be touching here, they also failed at that. All I could remember from what I saw of this movie back when I was ten years old was a baseball player saying Ed is Curious George, shaking his hand, and telling him he has read all his books, and the trouble the monkey causes as Jack's roommate making the struggling baseball player say, "I'm gonna spank that monkey!" Well, after watching what I saw all those years ago, along with the rest of the film, I'm going to remember a lot more, not that these memories will do me much good. If I hadn't been introduced to the film in my childhood, I doubt it would have really caught my attention when I found it in the bottom 100, and I wouldn't have ever seen it, but wouldn't have missed out on much had that been the case. Unlike so many other voters, I can't give "Ed" the lowest rating possible, and am not even 100% sure about my 2/10 rating, but see no really good reason why I should rate it any higher, since I agree with the vast majority that it's thoroughly unfunny and badly written. I may not have said much about this 1996 flop that others have already pointed out, but I agree with these criticisms, and would say there's absolutely nothing to make "Ed" worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chewy Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I personally thought it was one of the best movies I have seen in a while. I watched it recently on HBO, and I thought the plot was absolutely great. Whoever wrote the screenplay did an astounding job. Matt LeBlanc's acting was great in my opinion, and his chemistry with Ed was undeniably amazing. I couldn't even tell that Ed was a fake chimp because of the great editing and special effects in this movie. I am planning to watch this movie later while I enjoy a buttery bowl of Orville Redenbacher's popcorn. If you are reading this review, please do not listen to the other user reviews. The movie was great and a fun-filled family comedy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hands down the worst movie I've ever seen!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (mk3_@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this for my 12th birthday party because my mom wouldn't take us to anything rated PG-13 or higher. So I had to pick between Ed and Homeward Bound 2. I wasn't excited about either but I went with Ed because of the baseball angle. To this day, 14 years later everyone who was at that party, kids and adults, are united in agreement that it was the worst movie we've ever seen. I've tried to rewatch it a few times and show it to my fianc&eacute;' just to laugh at how bad it is but I can't even do that. We made it through 15 minutes and she couldn't take anymore. It's completely devoid of entertainment and all the other reviews have captured the reasons why. Every now and then I like to read the comments about it and chuckle because we still talk about how bad that movie was all these years later.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I want you to meet Mickey Mantle's monkey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Read my one line summary. Out loud, if it helps. More than once, if you need to. Do you honestly believe that it can be spoken, and that individual retaining just a smidgen of dignity, and continue to be respected? I wish I could claim that it is the only of its kind in this. Oh, how I would love to claim that this does not deserve its low rating... as I type this, it is #82 on the Bottom 100 on the site. This is irritating and intolerable from start to finish. No, I am not the intended viewer for this, but I maintain that this isn't likely to appeal to all that many. Simply put, unless you find chimps adorable and hilarious, there's nothing in this for you. It's well-trained, I'll give 'em that. I frankly wanted Ed to go nuts and kill everyone, which may be because the last 8 days, I've watched the Halloween films. If this is for children, then what's with the numerous crude jokes that are not appropriate for them? The material is atrocious, utterly devoid of creativity and the delivery is outrageously poor. If you laugh even once during this, it will probably be a reflex, or one of the kind that comes from a desperation that you can no longer contain, that you must *express*. The lead is annoying, and every "acting performance" is horrible. Jim Caviezel? Are you kidding me? Every character is one-note and stereotypical, and that girl is ridiculously precocious. The cartoon sound effects and "goofy music" try way too hard, and it winds up being embarrassing. Editing and cinematography are unimpressive. This mess manages to squeeze in every clich&eacute; in the book. I recommend this audience-insulting crap solely to those who have no taste, or those who *have to* see for themselves how awful it is. Your movie sucks, Matt. 1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I think the writers were usin' 'wacky tobacky'--that's the only thing that might explain this plot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even for a kids' movie, the premise to ED is incredibly lame. So lame that it boggles the mind to imagine that this film was made in the first place. I can only assume that the writers and execs at the studio were under the influence of some mind-altering drug while they were watching a re-run of a "Francis the Mule" film or else had loved ones kidnapped in order to force this film to be made. This is the only way you could understand this film. Even the worst of the most contrived Disney films of the 1960s and 70s look like "Gone With the Wind" compared to this! Matt LeBlanc stars as a guy who has a great pitching arm. However, when his game stinks, the manager punishes him by sending him to pick someone up at the bus stop. That 'someone' turns out to be a baseball playing chimp who is the team's new mascot. When I first saw this chimp, he really looked creepy--and I assume it was just a midget in an ape suit. It looked more realistic than chimps looked in films in 1940, but still looked bizarre and a bit scary! Well, only in a movie would it turn out that the chimp was a fantastic baseball player--with an arm like a rocket AND a thorough knowledge of how to play ball! How all the actors were able to participate in this farce of a film with straight faces is beyond me. Talk about an insane plot! Even small children would find this tough to swallow. However, given that he ultimately is SMARTER than LeBlanc isn't quite as hard to believe (at least in light of his role on "Friends"). Some of the low-points in this dreadful film include frequent fart jokes, snot jokes, Ed and LeBlanc both peeing together at the same toilet, belching, Ed driving a truck at what appears to be 400 mph, more fart jokes and Ed plying dress-up with grandma's clothes. At no point in the film is it clever or does it poke fun of itself (the only way this MIGHT have worked). Overall, a sorry mess of a film that is so inexplicably dumb that I can't believe it was made in the first place. Practically every clich&eacute; known to baseball is in this film and its only entertainment value is for people who want to laugh at the sheer inanity of the movie. Clearly, this film has earned its place on IMDb's Bottom 100 list!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It really is a secret stoner movie.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    westcor
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ed, what can you say about this movie that hasn't already been said? As the 3-bannanna reviewer stated, it contains all that is needed in a great movie. 1)Monkeys 2)Baseball 3)Someone from the show 'Friends.' If you pay to watch this movie you are a fool, luckily U-verse had it on for demand for free. Though on second thought, I remembered I did ask for my girlfriend to get it for me on Blu-ray if it ever came out; should a miracle like that ever happen. The reason people didn't find this movie funny, is because everyone thinks its a kid's movie. It's not. It's a movie for someone who just smoked a lot of bud. I laughed so hard at some points I was crying, and literally nothing would be happening except the Monkey farting or doing a flip while catching a ball. This movie would of been a complete disaster if they would have used a real monkey. It still is a disaster of sorts, but it is much funnier with a robotic monkey than the real thing. I have no idea how to even rate this movie, as it obviously is a horrible piece of cinema (OK that gives it too much credit, a horrible piece of film); but at the same time made me laugh more than any movie I can think of in recent history. I will meet in the middle and give it a 5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great movie for people who need to practice looking disapproving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Twetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Im not sure I have enough to say about "Ed" to fill the mandatory ten lines but here goes. I spent the first 56 minutes of the movie feeling an intense loathing of everything on the screen, by which point my face got tired from constantly having a disapproving look; so I had to go for an ironic smile for about fourteen minutes. At one hour and nine minutes the movie apparently got tired of itself and decided to start the plot which lasted for about ten minutes, after which it went back being loathsome. Shortly after the end happened but I still feel bitter about having seen it. It's not cute, it's not funny, it' just bad.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh dear...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A56T
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film deserves it's place in the bottom 100 on this site. Matt Le Blanc was at the height of his fame when he made this movie but even he cannot save it from being a flop. It's the sort of movie we'd expect his character Joey Tribbiani to star in because it's so bad. It's difficult to find any redeeming features in this film and I can only say that somewhere in the world a child must have enjoyed it due to the humour and the fact that Le Blanc is clearly trying to make the material appear as natural as possible but failing miserably. In years to come it may end up being a cult classic but even then it will probably be for all the wrong reasons. Le Blanc never has had much luck with movies and this may be an example of why if he read this script and thought it would be a good career move.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nobody Spanks This Monkey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the family farm, handsome "Charlotte's Web" reader Matt LeBlanc (as Jack "Deuce" Cooper) sleeps with his big dog. A strong pitching arm gets Mr. LeBlanc on the "Santa Rosa Rockets" team. After a slow start, LeBlanc is ordered to room with Edward "Ed" Sullivan, a large chimpanzee who winds up playing third base for the season. "Ed" doesn't monkey around, and is soon the team's star player. LeBlanc is nonplussed by the chimp, but see if they don't soon share bed and bathroom... "Ed" eventually helps LeBlanc play hide the banana with attractive Jayne Brook (as Lydia), picking up his cues from her precociously cute daughter Doren Fein (as Lizzie). Monkey see, monkey do. Everything here is cute but the monkey. But, with the lamest material to work with, the monkey had to be cute. Highlighted by brown teeth and red eyes, "Ed" looks like he belongs in a horror movie, and often sounds like he's passing gas. Otherwise, this might have appealed to young children. ** Ed (3/15/96) Bill Couturie ~ Matt LeBlanc, Jayne Brook, Jack Warden, Bill Cobbs
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excruciatingly embarrassing!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love movies and have done for as long as I can remember, but when I saw Ed for the first time recently I found it excruciatingly embarrassing. It isn't even so bad it's good or a mess that is worth watching. It is an excruciatingly embarrassing film that has next to no redeeming features. When it comes to talking about what makes Ed so bad, I honestly do not know where to begin. The film is ridden with clich&eacute;s, and what is worse these clich&eacute;s are badly explored and written. Ed is also a very poorly written film, the humour is crude(which I didn't mind) but it is also very, very unfunny with minimal laughs and cringeworthy dialogue. The story is predictable too, sometimes that isn't always a bad thing, but it is when nothing of interest happens and you can smell events like the ending a mile off. The direction is flat as well, the production values didn't do anything for me and the soundtrack was annoying and too jaunty. The acting is absolutely awful, and it certainly doesn't help that none of the characters are likable in any way. Matt LeBlanc can be good and endearing, but he and his character aren't here. LeBlanc's character is so irritating you want to strangle him, and the less said about that monkey the better. Overall, an unfunny and embarrassing mess and possibly the worst movie of 1996, only Bio Dome comes close to being worse. 1/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing even the least bit funny here, and the monkey is a major part of this!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I distinctly remember that it was at a family gathering in the autumn of 1996, when I was told about "Ed", a movie which I had never heard of before. I also got to see at least a bit of the film at that gathering, and it must have been pretty new to the home video format at the time. I was ten years old when this happened, and I guess I was pretty much indifferent to what I saw, most of which I wouldn't remember. I don't think I ever heard anything about this big time flop again until at least nearly a decade later, when I noticed that it was in the IMDb bottom 100. Before discovering that, I knew nothing about the family sports comedy's general reception, but for several years now, I have known that it's generally considered to be atrocious, so I was not too surprised by its lameness when I finally watched it all, fifteen years after its theatrical release. Jack "Deuce" Cooper proves to be a very talented baseball pitcher while playing on his farm, and his skills get him into the minor leagues, playing for the Santa Rosa Rockets, but it turns out that he doesn't do so well while playing in front of a crowd. Soon after he joins the team, they get another new player, one who happens to be a chimpanzee named Ed! One would likely believe that a monkey couldn't possibly play baseball, but surprisingly, this one is a natural on the field! This unusual baseball player becomes Jack's new roommate, and unfortunately, he soon ends up causing a lot of trouble for the human baseball player in the home, making big messes and doing things Jack wishes he wouldn't do. However, despite Ed's sometimes reckless behaviour, he turns out to be a really good friend to Jack, and a big help to the Rockets during games, but somebody has other plans for this popular minor league player! I don't know what the humour here is like for kids, but while watching the film after growing up, there wasn't a single moment I was unable to keep a straight face through! Ed is one unconvincing monkey, and is also very unfunny with his antics! The sight gags involving this character causing trouble and being messy, plus the ones involving his bodily functions, are perfect examples of the movie's poor attempts to be humorous. Ed may be the weakest aspect of the film, but any other character that is supposed to be funny, including more than one human Santa Rosa Rockets player and the Liz character, also fails miserably. In addition to being consistently unfunny, "Ed" also has a dull plot (one could easily call that an understatement), and whether Jack "Deuce" Cooper is out on the baseball field with Ed, at home or on the road having problems with the chimp's behaviour, dating the Lydia character, etc., it's generally not entertaining at all. I should probably mention that the story sure is predictable as well, with no big surprises, and if the writers ever tried to be touching here, they also failed at that. All I could remember from what I saw of this movie back when I was ten years old was a baseball player saying Ed is Curious George, shaking his hand, and telling him he has read all his books, and the trouble the monkey causes as Jack's roommate making the struggling baseball player say, "I'm gonna spank that monkey!" Well, after watching what I saw all those years ago, along with the rest of the film, I'm going to remember a lot more, not that these memories will do me much good. If I hadn't been introduced to the film in my childhood, I doubt it would have really caught my attention when I found it in the bottom 100, and I wouldn't have ever seen it, but wouldn't have missed out on much had that been the case. Unlike so many other voters, I can't give "Ed" the lowest rating possible, and am not even 100% sure about my 2/10 rating, but see no really good reason why I should rate it any higher, since I agree with the vast majority that it's thoroughly unfunny and badly written. I may not have said much about this 1996 flop that others have already pointed out, but I agree with these criticisms, and would say there's absolutely nothing to make "Ed" worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chewy Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I personally thought it was one of the best movies I have seen in a while. I watched it recently on HBO, and I thought the plot was absolutely great. Whoever wrote the screenplay did an astounding job. Matt LeBlanc's acting was great in my opinion, and his chemistry with Ed was undeniably amazing. I couldn't even tell that Ed was a fake chimp because of the great editing and special effects in this movie. I am planning to watch this movie later while I enjoy a buttery bowl of Orville Redenbacher's popcorn. If you are reading this review, please do not listen to the other user reviews. The movie was great and a fun-filled family comedy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hands down the worst movie I've ever seen!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (mk3_@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this for my 12th birthday party because my mom wouldn't take us to anything rated PG-13 or higher. So I had to pick between Ed and Homeward Bound 2. I wasn't excited about either but I went with Ed because of the baseball angle. To this day, 14 years later everyone who was at that party, kids and adults, are united in agreement that it was the worst movie we've ever seen. I've tried to rewatch it a few times and show it to my fianc&eacute;' just to laugh at how bad it is but I can't even do that. We made it through 15 minutes and she couldn't take anymore. It's completely devoid of entertainment and all the other reviews have captured the reasons why. Every now and then I like to read the comments about it and chuckle because we still talk about how bad that movie was all these years later.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I want you to meet Mickey Mantle's monkey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Read my one line summary. Out loud, if it helps. More than once, if you need to. Do you honestly believe that it can be spoken, and that individual retaining just a smidgen of dignity, and continue to be respected? I wish I could claim that it is the only of its kind in this. Oh, how I would love to claim that this does not deserve its low rating... as I type this, it is #82 on the Bottom 100 on the site. This is irritating and intolerable from start to finish. No, I am not the intended viewer for this, but I maintain that this isn't likely to appeal to all that many. Simply put, unless you find chimps adorable and hilarious, there's nothing in this for you. It's well-trained, I'll give 'em that. I frankly wanted Ed to go nuts and kill everyone, which may be because the last 8 days, I've watched the Halloween films. If this is for children, then what's with the numerous crude jokes that are not appropriate for them? The material is atrocious, utterly devoid of creativity and the delivery is outrageously poor. If you laugh even once during this, it will probably be a reflex, or one of the kind that comes from a desperation that you can no longer contain, that you must *express*. The lead is annoying, and every "acting performance" is horrible. Jim Caviezel? Are you kidding me? Every character is one-note and stereotypical, and that girl is ridiculously precocious. The cartoon sound effects and "goofy music" try way too hard, and it winds up being embarrassing. Editing and cinematography are unimpressive. This mess manages to squeeze in every clich&eacute; in the book. I recommend this audience-insulting crap solely to those who have no taste, or those who *have to* see for themselves how awful it is. Your movie sucks, Matt. 1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I think the writers were usin' 'wacky tobacky'--that's the only thing that might explain this plot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even for a kids' movie, the premise to ED is incredibly lame. So lame that it boggles the mind to imagine that this film was made in the first place. I can only assume that the writers and execs at the studio were under the influence of some mind-altering drug while they were watching a re-run of a "Francis the Mule" film or else had loved ones kidnapped in order to force this film to be made. This is the only way you could understand this film. Even the worst of the most contrived Disney films of the 1960s and 70s look like "Gone With the Wind" compared to this! Matt LeBlanc stars as a guy who has a great pitching arm. However, when his game stinks, the manager punishes him by sending him to pick someone up at the bus stop. That 'someone' turns out to be a baseball playing chimp who is the team's new mascot. When I first saw this chimp, he really looked creepy--and I assume it was just a midget in an ape suit. It looked more realistic than chimps looked in films in 1940, but still looked bizarre and a bit scary! Well, only in a movie would it turn out that the chimp was a fantastic baseball player--with an arm like a rocket AND a thorough knowledge of how to play ball! How all the actors were able to participate in this farce of a film with straight faces is beyond me. Talk about an insane plot! Even small children would find this tough to swallow. However, given that he ultimately is SMARTER than LeBlanc isn't quite as hard to believe (at least in light of his role on "Friends"). Some of the low-points in this dreadful film include frequent fart jokes, snot jokes, Ed and LeBlanc both peeing together at the same toilet, belching, Ed driving a truck at what appears to be 400 mph, more fart jokes and Ed plying dress-up with grandma's clothes. At no point in the film is it clever or does it poke fun of itself (the only way this MIGHT have worked). Overall, a sorry mess of a film that is so inexplicably dumb that I can't believe it was made in the first place. Practically every clich&eacute; known to baseball is in this film and its only entertainment value is for people who want to laugh at the sheer inanity of the movie. Clearly, this film has earned its place on IMDb's Bottom 100 list!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It really is a secret stoner movie.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    westcor
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ed, what can you say about this movie that hasn't already been said? As the 3-bannanna reviewer stated, it contains all that is needed in a great movie. 1)Monkeys 2)Baseball 3)Someone from the show 'Friends.' If you pay to watch this movie you are a fool, luckily U-verse had it on for demand for free. Though on second thought, I remembered I did ask for my girlfriend to get it for me on Blu-ray if it ever came out; should a miracle like that ever happen. The reason people didn't find this movie funny, is because everyone thinks its a kid's movie. It's not. It's a movie for someone who just smoked a lot of bud. I laughed so hard at some points I was crying, and literally nothing would be happening except the Monkey farting or doing a flip while catching a ball. This movie would of been a complete disaster if they would have used a real monkey. It still is a disaster of sorts, but it is much funnier with a robotic monkey than the real thing. I have no idea how to even rate this movie, as it obviously is a horrible piece of cinema (OK that gives it too much credit, a horrible piece of film); but at the same time made me laugh more than any movie I can think of in recent history. I will meet in the middle and give it a 5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great movie for people who need to practice looking disapproving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Twetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Im not sure I have enough to say about "Ed" to fill the mandatory ten lines but here goes. I spent the first 56 minutes of the movie feeling an intense loathing of everything on the screen, by which point my face got tired from constantly having a disapproving look; so I had to go for an ironic smile for about fourteen minutes. At one hour and nine minutes the movie apparently got tired of itself and decided to start the plot which lasted for about ten minutes, after which it went back being loathsome. Shortly after the end happened but I still feel bitter about having seen it. It's not cute, it's not funny, it' just bad.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh dear...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A56T
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film deserves it's place in the bottom 100 on this site. Matt Le Blanc was at the height of his fame when he made this movie but even he cannot save it from being a flop. It's the sort of movie we'd expect his character Joey Tribbiani to star in because it's so bad. It's difficult to find any redeeming features in this film and I can only say that somewhere in the world a child must have enjoyed it due to the humour and the fact that Le Blanc is clearly trying to make the material appear as natural as possible but failing miserably. In years to come it may end up being a cult classic but even then it will probably be for all the wrong reasons. Le Blanc never has had much luck with movies and this may be an example of why if he read this script and thought it would be a good career move.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nobody Spanks This Monkey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the family farm, handsome "Charlotte's Web" reader Matt LeBlanc (as Jack "Deuce" Cooper) sleeps with his big dog. A strong pitching arm gets Mr. LeBlanc on the "Santa Rosa Rockets" team. After a slow start, LeBlanc is ordered to room with Edward "Ed" Sullivan, a large chimpanzee who winds up playing third base for the season. "Ed" doesn't monkey around, and is soon the team's star player. LeBlanc is nonplussed by the chimp, but see if they don't soon share bed and bathroom... "Ed" eventually helps LeBlanc play hide the banana with attractive Jayne Brook (as Lydia), picking up his cues from her precociously cute daughter Doren Fein (as Lizzie). Monkey see, monkey do. Everything here is cute but the monkey. But, with the lamest material to work with, the monkey had to be cute. Highlighted by brown teeth and red eyes, "Ed" looks like he belongs in a horror movie, and often sounds like he's passing gas. Otherwise, this might have appealed to young children. ** Ed (3/15/96) Bill Couturie ~ Matt LeBlanc, Jayne Brook, Jack Warden, Bill Cobbs
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excruciatingly embarrassing!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love movies and have done for as long as I can remember, but when I saw Ed for the first time recently I found it excruciatingly embarrassing. It isn't even so bad it's good or a mess that is worth watching. It is an excruciatingly embarrassing film that has next to no redeeming features. When it comes to talking about what makes Ed so bad, I honestly do not know where to begin. The film is ridden with clich&eacute;s, and what is worse these clich&eacute;s are badly explored and written. Ed is also a very poorly written film, the humour is crude(which I didn't mind) but it is also very, very unfunny with minimal laughs and cringeworthy dialogue. The story is predictable too, sometimes that isn't always a bad thing, but it is when nothing of interest happens and you can smell events like the ending a mile off. The direction is flat as well, the production values didn't do anything for me and the soundtrack was annoying and too jaunty. The acting is absolutely awful, and it certainly doesn't help that none of the characters are likable in any way. Matt LeBlanc can be good and endearing, but he and his character aren't here. LeBlanc's character is so irritating you want to strangle him, and the less said about that monkey the better. Overall, an unfunny and embarrassing mess and possibly the worst movie of 1996, only Bio Dome comes close to being worse. 1/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing even the least bit funny here, and the monkey is a major part of this!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I distinctly remember that it was at a family gathering in the autumn of 1996, when I was told about "Ed", a movie which I had never heard of before. I also got to see at least a bit of the film at that gathering, and it must have been pretty new to the home video format at the time. I was ten years old when this happened, and I guess I was pretty much indifferent to what I saw, most of which I wouldn't remember. I don't think I ever heard anything about this big time flop again until at least nearly a decade later, when I noticed that it was in the IMDb bottom 100. Before discovering that, I knew nothing about the family sports comedy's general reception, but for several years now, I have known that it's generally considered to be atrocious, so I was not too surprised by its lameness when I finally watched it all, fifteen years after its theatrical release. Jack "Deuce" Cooper proves to be a very talented baseball pitcher while playing on his farm, and his skills get him into the minor leagues, playing for the Santa Rosa Rockets, but it turns out that he doesn't do so well while playing in front of a crowd. Soon after he joins the team, they get another new player, one who happens to be a chimpanzee named Ed! One would likely believe that a monkey couldn't possibly play baseball, but surprisingly, this one is a natural on the field! This unusual baseball player becomes Jack's new roommate, and unfortunately, he soon ends up causing a lot of trouble for the human baseball player in the home, making big messes and doing things Jack wishes he wouldn't do. However, despite Ed's sometimes reckless behaviour, he turns out to be a really good friend to Jack, and a big help to the Rockets during games, but somebody has other plans for this popular minor league player! I don't know what the humour here is like for kids, but while watching the film after growing up, there wasn't a single moment I was unable to keep a straight face through! Ed is one unconvincing monkey, and is also very unfunny with his antics! The sight gags involving this character causing trouble and being messy, plus the ones involving his bodily functions, are perfect examples of the movie's poor attempts to be humorous. Ed may be the weakest aspect of the film, but any other character that is supposed to be funny, including more than one human Santa Rosa Rockets player and the Liz character, also fails miserably. In addition to being consistently unfunny, "Ed" also has a dull plot (one could easily call that an understatement), and whether Jack "Deuce" Cooper is out on the baseball field with Ed, at home or on the road having problems with the chimp's behaviour, dating the Lydia character, etc., it's generally not entertaining at all. I should probably mention that the story sure is predictable as well, with no big surprises, and if the writers ever tried to be touching here, they also failed at that. All I could remember from what I saw of this movie back when I was ten years old was a baseball player saying Ed is Curious George, shaking his hand, and telling him he has read all his books, and the trouble the monkey causes as Jack's roommate making the struggling baseball player say, "I'm gonna spank that monkey!" Well, after watching what I saw all those years ago, along with the rest of the film, I'm going to remember a lot more, not that these memories will do me much good. If I hadn't been introduced to the film in my childhood, I doubt it would have really caught my attention when I found it in the bottom 100, and I wouldn't have ever seen it, but wouldn't have missed out on much had that been the case. Unlike so many other voters, I can't give "Ed" the lowest rating possible, and am not even 100% sure about my 2/10 rating, but see no really good reason why I should rate it any higher, since I agree with the vast majority that it's thoroughly unfunny and badly written. I may not have said much about this 1996 flop that others have already pointed out, but I agree with these criticisms, and would say there's absolutely nothing to make "Ed" worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chewy Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I personally thought it was one of the best movies I have seen in a while. I watched it recently on HBO, and I thought the plot was absolutely great. Whoever wrote the screenplay did an astounding job. Matt LeBlanc's acting was great in my opinion, and his chemistry with Ed was undeniably amazing. I couldn't even tell that Ed was a fake chimp because of the great editing and special effects in this movie. I am planning to watch this movie later while I enjoy a buttery bowl of Orville Redenbacher's popcorn. If you are reading this review, please do not listen to the other user reviews. The movie was great and a fun-filled family comedy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hands down the worst movie I've ever seen!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (mk3_@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this for my 12th birthday party because my mom wouldn't take us to anything rated PG-13 or higher. So I had to pick between Ed and Homeward Bound 2. I wasn't excited about either but I went with Ed because of the baseball angle. To this day, 14 years later everyone who was at that party, kids and adults, are united in agreement that it was the worst movie we've ever seen. I've tried to rewatch it a few times and show it to my fianc&eacute;' just to laugh at how bad it is but I can't even do that. We made it through 15 minutes and she couldn't take anymore. It's completely devoid of entertainment and all the other reviews have captured the reasons why. Every now and then I like to read the comments about it and chuckle because we still talk about how bad that movie was all these years later.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I want you to meet Mickey Mantle's monkey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Read my one line summary. Out loud, if it helps. More than once, if you need to. Do you honestly believe that it can be spoken, and that individual retaining just a smidgen of dignity, and continue to be respected? I wish I could claim that it is the only of its kind in this. Oh, how I would love to claim that this does not deserve its low rating... as I type this, it is #82 on the Bottom 100 on the site. This is irritating and intolerable from start to finish. No, I am not the intended viewer for this, but I maintain that this isn't likely to appeal to all that many. Simply put, unless you find chimps adorable and hilarious, there's nothing in this for you. It's well-trained, I'll give 'em that. I frankly wanted Ed to go nuts and kill everyone, which may be because the last 8 days, I've watched the Halloween films. If this is for children, then what's with the numerous crude jokes that are not appropriate for them? The material is atrocious, utterly devoid of creativity and the delivery is outrageously poor. If you laugh even once during this, it will probably be a reflex, or one of the kind that comes from a desperation that you can no longer contain, that you must *express*. The lead is annoying, and every "acting performance" is horrible. Jim Caviezel? Are you kidding me? Every character is one-note and stereotypical, and that girl is ridiculously precocious. The cartoon sound effects and "goofy music" try way too hard, and it winds up being embarrassing. Editing and cinematography are unimpressive. This mess manages to squeeze in every clich&eacute; in the book. I recommend this audience-insulting crap solely to those who have no taste, or those who *have to* see for themselves how awful it is. Your movie sucks, Matt. 1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I think the writers were usin' 'wacky tobacky'--that's the only thing that might explain this plot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even for a kids' movie, the premise to ED is incredibly lame. So lame that it boggles the mind to imagine that this film was made in the first place. I can only assume that the writers and execs at the studio were under the influence of some mind-altering drug while they were watching a re-run of a "Francis the Mule" film or else had loved ones kidnapped in order to force this film to be made. This is the only way you could understand this film. Even the worst of the most contrived Disney films of the 1960s and 70s look like "Gone With the Wind" compared to this! Matt LeBlanc stars as a guy who has a great pitching arm. However, when his game stinks, the manager punishes him by sending him to pick someone up at the bus stop. That 'someone' turns out to be a baseball playing chimp who is the team's new mascot. When I first saw this chimp, he really looked creepy--and I assume it was just a midget in an ape suit. It looked more realistic than chimps looked in films in 1940, but still looked bizarre and a bit scary! Well, only in a movie would it turn out that the chimp was a fantastic baseball player--with an arm like a rocket AND a thorough knowledge of how to play ball! How all the actors were able to participate in this farce of a film with straight faces is beyond me. Talk about an insane plot! Even small children would find this tough to swallow. However, given that he ultimately is SMARTER than LeBlanc isn't quite as hard to believe (at least in light of his role on "Friends"). Some of the low-points in this dreadful film include frequent fart jokes, snot jokes, Ed and LeBlanc both peeing together at the same toilet, belching, Ed driving a truck at what appears to be 400 mph, more fart jokes and Ed plying dress-up with grandma's clothes. At no point in the film is it clever or does it poke fun of itself (the only way this MIGHT have worked). Overall, a sorry mess of a film that is so inexplicably dumb that I can't believe it was made in the first place. Practically every clich&eacute; known to baseball is in this film and its only entertainment value is for people who want to laugh at the sheer inanity of the movie. Clearly, this film has earned its place on IMDb's Bottom 100 list!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It really is a secret stoner movie.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    westcor
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ed, what can you say about this movie that hasn't already been said? As the 3-bannanna reviewer stated, it contains all that is needed in a great movie. 1)Monkeys 2)Baseball 3)Someone from the show 'Friends.' If you pay to watch this movie you are a fool, luckily U-verse had it on for demand for free. Though on second thought, I remembered I did ask for my girlfriend to get it for me on Blu-ray if it ever came out; should a miracle like that ever happen. The reason people didn't find this movie funny, is because everyone thinks its a kid's movie. It's not. It's a movie for someone who just smoked a lot of bud. I laughed so hard at some points I was crying, and literally nothing would be happening except the Monkey farting or doing a flip while catching a ball. This movie would of been a complete disaster if they would have used a real monkey. It still is a disaster of sorts, but it is much funnier with a robotic monkey than the real thing. I have no idea how to even rate this movie, as it obviously is a horrible piece of cinema (OK that gives it too much credit, a horrible piece of film); but at the same time made me laugh more than any movie I can think of in recent history. I will meet in the middle and give it a 5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
