<filme>
 <id>
  1297
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110391
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Segredos do Cora&ccedil;&atilde;o
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Ex-football star Mike Gambril meets Terry McKay on a flight to Sydney, which is forced to land on a small atoll. Both engaged to others, they become romantic on board the ship sent to take ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Ex-football star Mike Gambril meets Terry McKay on a flight to Sydney, which is forced to land on a small atoll. Both engaged to others, they become romantic on board the ship sent to take the 'plane passengers to a larger island. They agree to meet in New York three months later to see if the attraction is real. One shows up, the other doesn't, but they run into each other afterwards.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   airplane
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   accident victim
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   aunt
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   accident
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Glenn Gordon Caron
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Mildred Cram
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Leo McCarey
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Warren Beatty
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Annette Bening
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Katharine Hepburn
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Weak Remake to Satisfy Warren Beatty's Ego
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1932 "Love Affair" is one of the most beautiful, charming and brokenhearted love stories of the cinema industry. Irene Dunne and Charles Boyer have the perfect chemistry and it is impossible not fall in love for her. The 1957 "An Affair to Remember" is a remake frame by frame of the original movie and also more famous. Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr also have perfect chemistry and had been my favorite romance after "Casablanca" until the day I saw the 1932 "Love Affair". I was curious to see the 1994 version of "Love Affair" and I found it a weak remake maybe to satisfy the ego of Warren Beatty. The introduction is awful with annoying music score and edition. Mike Gambril is a detestable character and I do not see any reason for Terry falling in love with him. It is only good to see Ms. Katharine Hepburn in her last feature. My vote is five. Title (Brazil): "Segredos do Cora&ccedil;&atilde;o" ("Secrets of the Heart")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's what true love is...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itazshi08
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have watched this movie several times and it amazes me every time. When I first watched it I didn't know it was a remake, but still I love this version more than the previous ones. The story revolves around two people (Warren and Annette) who crossed their paths while on a flight. they had emergency landing on an island where she meets his aunt (Katharine Hepburn). on a flight back, they have agreed to meet again after 3 months if they still like/love each other. This movie has the total charm. Warren and Annette played their roles with charms, I find them cute and fantastic. I love the scene with Katharine Hepburn, and I think the end scene of this version is more powerful compared in the other versions. The way Annette and Warren delivered their lines are more beautiful and realistic and somehow I think I'm seeing them real. Warren is cute, Annette is perfect, Katharine is indescribable. The background music has a great effect too, it leaves a beautiful feeling to the listener/viewer. You can't just forget it. Well, I don't to want to compare it more with the over versions. I go for this one solid, no matter what because I love watching them move! :) I gave it 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Third Time's "Almost" The Charm.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happipuppi13
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    People that know the 2 movies "An Affair To Remember" and the re-make before this one also called "Love Affair",pretty much know what the movie is about and what to expect. After viewing it all, I can honestly say that this re-make was not really necessary. I'm not saying it suffers the same fate of Striesand's remake of "A Star Is Born" (also a third go-round) but for all intentional purposes,it's just okay and a bit bland. I know Beatty is a good actor and so is Annette but there's not a whole lot of dramatic feeling in their parts for my taste. Even after her character is hurt and can't walk,you just don't feel that sense of urgency about these two. Which makes it very hard to care what happens to them. I was far more moved by Aunt Ginny's passing than anything else. Speaking of her : Like many have stated here though,Katharine Hepburn's brief appearance more than makes up for it. Her part really should have been written so she could at least have been in the film for an hour. I also wish she hadn't been made to use a certain 4 letter word also,totally unnecessary and cheap low brow humor. In all,it's okay to watch if you've nothing better in your collection or to rent, It is worth it for Hepburn,as is almost anything Hepburn ever made. Six stars,for simply a watchable enough film and of course,because it was Kate's last theatrical movie-screen appearance. She was always the bright spot in any film,good or bad. (END)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I like to see you move
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kaykim333
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    resent is most important. I agree with him 100%, but as everyone knows well, to know is different from to do. However I really want to enjoy my real life and share happiness with others. When I watched this movie, I was so happy and able to enjoy the present while I was watching it. Some people don't like romantic movies, they said the situations are ridiculous and acting is so exaggerated, but this movie is my cup of tea. I like a warm-hearted and make believe story about the power of love because in the real world there are a lot of sad things and scary news. I don't want to listen to these things any more. Even though movies are not real, I hope to feel the beauty of the nature and persons. This movie is about love story. Ex-football star Mike Gambril (Warren Beatty) meets Terry McKay (Annette Bening) on a flight, and then they are forced to land because of a weather condition. Both are engaged to others, but they fall in love each other. They promise that they will meet again in New York few months later. I don't want to spoil this movie, so you should watch this if you want to know the ending. This movie's setting is a beautiful island and New York. When they went to Mike's Aunt's house, the setting is very beautiful and refined. Even though it's just picture, I could feel that I am there. I can feel the wind and heavy rain in this movie. I can see the camera director's effort to take a photograph of the beauty of the nature. Especially I like the music and scenery most. This film's music is so beautiful and wonderful, for example "Love Affair Piano Solo" by Ennio Morricone, "I Will" by Beatles, "Chestnuts Roasting on an Open Fire" by Ray Charles. Even if you missed a chance to see this movie I strongly recommend to listen to this film's music . Most of all in the last scene while Mike is saying "If anything had to happen to one of us, why did it have to be you?", 'Love Affair Piano Solo' makes this scene the most beautiful and graceful. During watching this movie, actually I'm interested in the movie music and their dialogues. The lines from this movies are very simple, and poetic. The most famous line is "I like watching you move". In addition Terry's styling is the best!! I can't take away my eyes from her styling from the beginning to the end of this movie. Her white long dress and her beautiful scarf make this movie one of the great art pictures. One of the impressive things is that Warren Beatty and Annette Bening fell in love during a making this movie. Their feeling in this movie is not acting, but it's close to reality. I think this is the big reason why this movie could be so romantic. If you enjoy watching a romantic story, please watch this movie with a glass of wine on Friday night! It is the best choice for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still A Star Crossed Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anyone thinks that we've seen the last remake of Love Affair, think again. The Indian cinema has done a version of it a few years after this film came out. This story has a timeless appeal that Warren Beatty certainly recognized. Anyone who has seen the original Love Affair and the remake An Affair To Remember will know the plot of this film exactly. Warren Beatty and Annette Bening fill the shoes of previous lovers Charles Boyer and Irene Dunne and Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr. With very few deviations except those to update the story this film has the same plot. One of those deviations has our star crossed lovers Warren Beatty and Annette Bening meeting on a transoceanic flight to Sydney, Australia which is certainly a lot of time to get acquainted. They get even better acquainted when they are forced to land on a Pacific island where Beatty's grandmother Katharine Hepburn has a nice tropical place. The kind of setting where romance has to bloom. This was Katharine Hepburn's last big screen appearance, she did one more television film and then her Parkinson's Disease and other ailments that beset people of the age she lived to forced her retirement. I'll bet she never thought she would in 1939 wind up in a remake of a film doing a part Maria Ouspenskaya created. She does it grand style though and only Kate can make an old Anglo-Saxon expletive sound elegant. That Warren Beatty got nominated for a Razzie award for remaking Love Affair is a disgrace. This is old fashioned romantic entertainment, the kind that old Hollywood used to do. I think Beatty and everyone connected with this Love Affair should be proud. I notice that Leo McCarey who wrote and directed Love Affair and An Affair To Remember is prominently listed on the screen credits. He'd be proud of this remake himself, I'm sure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heartfelt and entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kmcresources
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've often heard how so many people, mostly women love the movie "An Affair To Remember," and yet, I never cared much for it. I like the actors, Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr, but the storyline and the idea of "an affair" didn't really appeal to me. I also didn't realize that it was a remake of "Love Affair" from 1939 starring Irene Dunne and Charles Boyer. I happened to see piece of it on a cruise ship and my husband and I recognized some of the dialog. And we both remember the reference to the movie in "Sleepless In Seattle." It was interesting to see this and I decided to borrow it from the library to watch and after watching it, I still didn't find "An Affair To Remember" very appealing. At the same time, I noticed the movie "Love Affair" with Warren Beatty and Annette Benning. I'm not really fans of either, but, for some reason, this movie caught my attention. It's possible it has appeal because here is an actor who was once known as a lifetime bachelor who has now married to an actress and raised four children and the chemistry with the woman he chose to spend his life with shows through. The music throughout the movie is beautiful and the main storyline follows its predecessor, but the dialog is fresh. I was glad to see that the "sensationalism" promoted by paparazzi is quelled by the quick wit of Mike Gambril paying a crew member to present a telegram to the photographer to send him on a wild chase preventing the "scandal" as in "An Affair To Remember." This movie gave me reason to like the story. I find that, even if I am not a fan of particular actors, I can enjoy a movie if they put their heart and souls into the project and not worry about impressing the viewers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This version of a movie previously filmed twice was quite charming for this first time Love Affair viewer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tavm
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Had my mom not rented this from Netflix, I probably wouldn't have bothered to see this third version of a romance previously filmed twice before by Leo McCarey. Real-life married couple Warren Beatty and Annette Bening play two people engaged to others (Kate Capshaw, Pierce Brosnan) who chance meet on a plane and then fall for each other on a cruise ship. At a pit stop, they visit Beatty's aunt (Katherine Hepburn in her last feature role) who provides some views about love. After that, they make a pact to meet at the Empire State Building after a few months and...well, if you've seen the other two (which I haven't) you know what happens. I wasn't sure what to think of this movie with many of the quick-cutting of some scenes and many of the somewhat benign nature of some of the dialogue at the beginning but by the time of Hepburn's appearance, I was charmed by the way Beatty and, especially, Bening interacted with the veteran 4-time Oscar winner especially with the way Ms. Hepburn used a certain word in asking about ducks. Also with her appearance as well as a later one with Ray Charles singing "The Christmas Song", I wondered about what great losses we've had the last five or so years. Many of the supporting cast like Garry Shandling and Harold Ramis (neither of whom I thought had any funny scenes) I recognized but I didn't realize Wendie Jo Sperber and Lisa Edelstein were here until I read the end credits. I did like also some of the musical selections like the "M'm! M'm! Good!" spot with Ed McMahon, the children's chorus of The Beatles' "I Will", and that duet with Louis Jordan and Louis Armstrong on "Life Is So Peculiar" that scored some of the cruise scenes. And the concluding scene was quite touching (if not tear-inducing) that I'm willing to give this version of Love Affair a pass. Bottom line, this was worth seeing for any romantics still out there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A scene which is worth a whole film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Haynoosh
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I want to watch a film in which Warren Beatty's name appears,I know that there must be a damn good reason that has made him contribute to this film. He doesn't have that many films,and there is hardly a film of his that doesn't have a strong statement to make. When I sat down to watch "Love Affair",I didn't know that it was a re-make of the 1939's "Love Affair" and 1957's "An Affair to Remember". I was so marveled with the boyish charm of Warren Beatty when he was trying to hook up the main female character of the film,his real life wife,Annette Bening as Terry McKay,and it was after Mike(Warren's character)and Terry's visit to his aunt,superbly portrayed by Katharine Hepburn,that I noticed the similarities. By the sheer appearance of Hepburn as Mike's aunt on the scene,even before she had noticed the arrival of her nephew,when she was chatting with the docks,she established her presence so rapidly and strongly that made me forget about the other characters. However strong was Hepburn's performance,how much it overshadowed the performance of Beatty and Bening,it was justified.One could sense their admiration towards her, not only as the characters of the film,but as co-workers as well. And that's exactly what gives truthfulness to the point of documentary,to this scene. When Beatty was listening and watching the two women perform the song ,it was obvious that it was not just Mike looking at his aunt,but also Warren Beatty,stoned in awe of the sensitivity and artistry of a Legend. The same goes for Annette Benning.In her conversations with the aunt, and while she was accompanying her by humming,while she was playing the piano,it was again Annette Bening dazzled by her aura. At that point, both us,the viewers,and Beatty and Bening became one,we all were viewers. They were all swans,both the couple dressed in white and in total peace and harmony with themselves and the nature,and the old and wise aunt,Katharine Hepburn,making her unforgettable performance as her swan song. If there is a reason for this film to exist, is that scene. The scenes following their arrival in New York do not have the saying and drive of the first half of the film. Even the scene with Ray Charles which is the living proof of the victory of love and dedication over any misfortune,is not able to prevent the spectator from feeling sorry for the lovers,instead of celebrating their re-union. The scene with the aunt was so honest, so profound,that I was expecting something new,something breathtaking as that scene itself.And I kept telling to myself that this is a Warren Beatty film,it is eventually going to take another turn, unravel another aspect of the story,it isn't going to end like that.But to my surprise it did. The "Love Affair" which began in the sky ended on a not strong enough land. But it made us the witnesses of one of cinema's most cherishable moments,the getting together of the guru and her apostles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Painting, Shawls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are multiple reasons to like this. I'll mention two. One comes from the fact that it is a remake. Such things have miraculous properties. Storytelling is all about choices, most invisible. Its the goal sometimes. But when you have a remake and you know the original, then all the scaffolding of the thing becomes visible and you can marvel or not at the changes that have been made. The choices. I do not know the 1939 version, but I do the 57 version with Cary Grant. Its not just mawkish and cheap, its offensive, even vile. The method of presentation depends not on the love, but on the helplessness of the pair. They are quite literally prostitutes, professional paid escorts. He is enchanted by her primarily because she didn't show at the rendezvous and since no one had ever turned him down before he fell in "love" hard, because of the chase. It hit all the negative buttons, even the racist ones. This redone in such a way that it avoids all those faults. It has almost precisely the same story, but instead of cheap sentimental exploitation, you get rich cinematic romance. You get love embodied in actors, three good ones. You get real love 혰 at least so far as movies have 혰 and not infatuation. You have lovers adjusting lives to fit, not tossing advantage in spite. For me it worked as a romantic movie. I know it failed to sell many tickets, and can only guess that it was too honest and true, with not enough sweeping violins. We don't like true love in movies. And that brings me to the other value, the fold with real life. Beatty really was the sort of character he played here, a serial screwer, a man engaged in the chase, someone not to be trusted but who clearly has an image-based artistic side. Benning's reputation was less public, but she was close to being the most desirable woman in Hollywood after "Grifters." They really did fall in love. At filming, she was already carrying their second child. The chemistry is real and conveyed effectively. I make a special study of films where the director is in love with the main actress. Its rare that such a man has such a love, and produces, writes and stars in such a profession of love. Life folded into film romance done competently and cinematically. Is there anything in film romance that matters more? The palette is rosey. Its lovely to watch. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Give this a chance...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MarieGabrielle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you know the story, and have seen the earlier versions, this is still worth a viewing. The current drama/romance genre is something I am not often fond of, yet this film had a resonance, especially for the holiday season. No, it is not the same as the Deborah Kerr, Cary Grant version, but that is a bit dated. There is a cameo scene with Katharine Hepburn, she as Beatty's great- aunt, he as someone at a crossroads in his life; wondering if there will be a turning point. Bening is a singer/actress, they agree to meet in NY, a year after if neither is attached to their current significant other. Beatty and Bening actually make a nice couple, for me to have enjoyed this film at Christmas, points to the fact that it is not another romantic comedy we can toss out ( a rare thing) probably because Beatty and Bening have a believable chemistry together. The final scene, sad as it is Christmas, and the children singing a version of the Beatles' "I will" is atmospheric. It was (for me anyway ) a more moving scene than the older version, perhaps because the children singing in the 1950's version- were singing a song from that 1950's time period.... Highly recommended. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Weak Remake to Satisfy Warren Beatty's Ego
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1932 "Love Affair" is one of the most beautiful, charming and brokenhearted love stories of the cinema industry. Irene Dunne and Charles Boyer have the perfect chemistry and it is impossible not fall in love for her. The 1957 "An Affair to Remember" is a remake frame by frame of the original movie and also more famous. Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr also have perfect chemistry and had been my favorite romance after "Casablanca" until the day I saw the 1932 "Love Affair". I was curious to see the 1994 version of "Love Affair" and I found it a weak remake maybe to satisfy the ego of Warren Beatty. The introduction is awful with annoying music score and edition. Mike Gambril is a detestable character and I do not see any reason for Terry falling in love with him. It is only good to see Ms. Katharine Hepburn in her last feature. My vote is five. Title (Brazil): "Segredos do Cora&ccedil;&atilde;o" ("Secrets of the Heart")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's what true love is...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itazshi08
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have watched this movie several times and it amazes me every time. When I first watched it I didn't know it was a remake, but still I love this version more than the previous ones. The story revolves around two people (Warren and Annette) who crossed their paths while on a flight. they had emergency landing on an island where she meets his aunt (Katharine Hepburn). on a flight back, they have agreed to meet again after 3 months if they still like/love each other. This movie has the total charm. Warren and Annette played their roles with charms, I find them cute and fantastic. I love the scene with Katharine Hepburn, and I think the end scene of this version is more powerful compared in the other versions. The way Annette and Warren delivered their lines are more beautiful and realistic and somehow I think I'm seeing them real. Warren is cute, Annette is perfect, Katharine is indescribable. The background music has a great effect too, it leaves a beautiful feeling to the listener/viewer. You can't just forget it. Well, I don't to want to compare it more with the over versions. I go for this one solid, no matter what because I love watching them move! :) I gave it 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Third Time's "Almost" The Charm.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happipuppi13
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    People that know the 2 movies "An Affair To Remember" and the re-make before this one also called "Love Affair",pretty much know what the movie is about and what to expect. After viewing it all, I can honestly say that this re-make was not really necessary. I'm not saying it suffers the same fate of Striesand's remake of "A Star Is Born" (also a third go-round) but for all intentional purposes,it's just okay and a bit bland. I know Beatty is a good actor and so is Annette but there's not a whole lot of dramatic feeling in their parts for my taste. Even after her character is hurt and can't walk,you just don't feel that sense of urgency about these two. Which makes it very hard to care what happens to them. I was far more moved by Aunt Ginny's passing than anything else. Speaking of her : Like many have stated here though,Katharine Hepburn's brief appearance more than makes up for it. Her part really should have been written so she could at least have been in the film for an hour. I also wish she hadn't been made to use a certain 4 letter word also,totally unnecessary and cheap low brow humor. In all,it's okay to watch if you've nothing better in your collection or to rent, It is worth it for Hepburn,as is almost anything Hepburn ever made. Six stars,for simply a watchable enough film and of course,because it was Kate's last theatrical movie-screen appearance. She was always the bright spot in any film,good or bad. (END)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I like to see you move
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kaykim333
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    resent is most important. I agree with him 100%, but as everyone knows well, to know is different from to do. However I really want to enjoy my real life and share happiness with others. When I watched this movie, I was so happy and able to enjoy the present while I was watching it. Some people don't like romantic movies, they said the situations are ridiculous and acting is so exaggerated, but this movie is my cup of tea. I like a warm-hearted and make believe story about the power of love because in the real world there are a lot of sad things and scary news. I don't want to listen to these things any more. Even though movies are not real, I hope to feel the beauty of the nature and persons. This movie is about love story. Ex-football star Mike Gambril (Warren Beatty) meets Terry McKay (Annette Bening) on a flight, and then they are forced to land because of a weather condition. Both are engaged to others, but they fall in love each other. They promise that they will meet again in New York few months later. I don't want to spoil this movie, so you should watch this if you want to know the ending. This movie's setting is a beautiful island and New York. When they went to Mike's Aunt's house, the setting is very beautiful and refined. Even though it's just picture, I could feel that I am there. I can feel the wind and heavy rain in this movie. I can see the camera director's effort to take a photograph of the beauty of the nature. Especially I like the music and scenery most. This film's music is so beautiful and wonderful, for example "Love Affair Piano Solo" by Ennio Morricone, "I Will" by Beatles, "Chestnuts Roasting on an Open Fire" by Ray Charles. Even if you missed a chance to see this movie I strongly recommend to listen to this film's music . Most of all in the last scene while Mike is saying "If anything had to happen to one of us, why did it have to be you?", 'Love Affair Piano Solo' makes this scene the most beautiful and graceful. During watching this movie, actually I'm interested in the movie music and their dialogues. The lines from this movies are very simple, and poetic. The most famous line is "I like watching you move". In addition Terry's styling is the best!! I can't take away my eyes from her styling from the beginning to the end of this movie. Her white long dress and her beautiful scarf make this movie one of the great art pictures. One of the impressive things is that Warren Beatty and Annette Bening fell in love during a making this movie. Their feeling in this movie is not acting, but it's close to reality. I think this is the big reason why this movie could be so romantic. If you enjoy watching a romantic story, please watch this movie with a glass of wine on Friday night! It is the best choice for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still A Star Crossed Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anyone thinks that we've seen the last remake of Love Affair, think again. The Indian cinema has done a version of it a few years after this film came out. This story has a timeless appeal that Warren Beatty certainly recognized. Anyone who has seen the original Love Affair and the remake An Affair To Remember will know the plot of this film exactly. Warren Beatty and Annette Bening fill the shoes of previous lovers Charles Boyer and Irene Dunne and Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr. With very few deviations except those to update the story this film has the same plot. One of those deviations has our star crossed lovers Warren Beatty and Annette Bening meeting on a transoceanic flight to Sydney, Australia which is certainly a lot of time to get acquainted. They get even better acquainted when they are forced to land on a Pacific island where Beatty's grandmother Katharine Hepburn has a nice tropical place. The kind of setting where romance has to bloom. This was Katharine Hepburn's last big screen appearance, she did one more television film and then her Parkinson's Disease and other ailments that beset people of the age she lived to forced her retirement. I'll bet she never thought she would in 1939 wind up in a remake of a film doing a part Maria Ouspenskaya created. She does it grand style though and only Kate can make an old Anglo-Saxon expletive sound elegant. That Warren Beatty got nominated for a Razzie award for remaking Love Affair is a disgrace. This is old fashioned romantic entertainment, the kind that old Hollywood used to do. I think Beatty and everyone connected with this Love Affair should be proud. I notice that Leo McCarey who wrote and directed Love Affair and An Affair To Remember is prominently listed on the screen credits. He'd be proud of this remake himself, I'm sure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heartfelt and entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kmcresources
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've often heard how so many people, mostly women love the movie "An Affair To Remember," and yet, I never cared much for it. I like the actors, Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr, but the storyline and the idea of "an affair" didn't really appeal to me. I also didn't realize that it was a remake of "Love Affair" from 1939 starring Irene Dunne and Charles Boyer. I happened to see piece of it on a cruise ship and my husband and I recognized some of the dialog. And we both remember the reference to the movie in "Sleepless In Seattle." It was interesting to see this and I decided to borrow it from the library to watch and after watching it, I still didn't find "An Affair To Remember" very appealing. At the same time, I noticed the movie "Love Affair" with Warren Beatty and Annette Benning. I'm not really fans of either, but, for some reason, this movie caught my attention. It's possible it has appeal because here is an actor who was once known as a lifetime bachelor who has now married to an actress and raised four children and the chemistry with the woman he chose to spend his life with shows through. The music throughout the movie is beautiful and the main storyline follows its predecessor, but the dialog is fresh. I was glad to see that the "sensationalism" promoted by paparazzi is quelled by the quick wit of Mike Gambril paying a crew member to present a telegram to the photographer to send him on a wild chase preventing the "scandal" as in "An Affair To Remember." This movie gave me reason to like the story. I find that, even if I am not a fan of particular actors, I can enjoy a movie if they put their heart and souls into the project and not worry about impressing the viewers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This version of a movie previously filmed twice was quite charming for this first time Love Affair viewer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tavm
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Had my mom not rented this from Netflix, I probably wouldn't have bothered to see this third version of a romance previously filmed twice before by Leo McCarey. Real-life married couple Warren Beatty and Annette Bening play two people engaged to others (Kate Capshaw, Pierce Brosnan) who chance meet on a plane and then fall for each other on a cruise ship. At a pit stop, they visit Beatty's aunt (Katherine Hepburn in her last feature role) who provides some views about love. After that, they make a pact to meet at the Empire State Building after a few months and...well, if you've seen the other two (which I haven't) you know what happens. I wasn't sure what to think of this movie with many of the quick-cutting of some scenes and many of the somewhat benign nature of some of the dialogue at the beginning but by the time of Hepburn's appearance, I was charmed by the way Beatty and, especially, Bening interacted with the veteran 4-time Oscar winner especially with the way Ms. Hepburn used a certain word in asking about ducks. Also with her appearance as well as a later one with Ray Charles singing "The Christmas Song", I wondered about what great losses we've had the last five or so years. Many of the supporting cast like Garry Shandling and Harold Ramis (neither of whom I thought had any funny scenes) I recognized but I didn't realize Wendie Jo Sperber and Lisa Edelstein were here until I read the end credits. I did like also some of the musical selections like the "M'm! M'm! Good!" spot with Ed McMahon, the children's chorus of The Beatles' "I Will", and that duet with Louis Jordan and Louis Armstrong on "Life Is So Peculiar" that scored some of the cruise scenes. And the concluding scene was quite touching (if not tear-inducing) that I'm willing to give this version of Love Affair a pass. Bottom line, this was worth seeing for any romantics still out there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A scene which is worth a whole film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Haynoosh
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I want to watch a film in which Warren Beatty's name appears,I know that there must be a damn good reason that has made him contribute to this film. He doesn't have that many films,and there is hardly a film of his that doesn't have a strong statement to make. When I sat down to watch "Love Affair",I didn't know that it was a re-make of the 1939's "Love Affair" and 1957's "An Affair to Remember". I was so marveled with the boyish charm of Warren Beatty when he was trying to hook up the main female character of the film,his real life wife,Annette Bening as Terry McKay,and it was after Mike(Warren's character)and Terry's visit to his aunt,superbly portrayed by Katharine Hepburn,that I noticed the similarities. By the sheer appearance of Hepburn as Mike's aunt on the scene,even before she had noticed the arrival of her nephew,when she was chatting with the docks,she established her presence so rapidly and strongly that made me forget about the other characters. However strong was Hepburn's performance,how much it overshadowed the performance of Beatty and Bening,it was justified.One could sense their admiration towards her, not only as the characters of the film,but as co-workers as well. And that's exactly what gives truthfulness to the point of documentary,to this scene. When Beatty was listening and watching the two women perform the song ,it was obvious that it was not just Mike looking at his aunt,but also Warren Beatty,stoned in awe of the sensitivity and artistry of a Legend. The same goes for Annette Benning.In her conversations with the aunt, and while she was accompanying her by humming,while she was playing the piano,it was again Annette Bening dazzled by her aura. At that point, both us,the viewers,and Beatty and Bening became one,we all were viewers. They were all swans,both the couple dressed in white and in total peace and harmony with themselves and the nature,and the old and wise aunt,Katharine Hepburn,making her unforgettable performance as her swan song. If there is a reason for this film to exist, is that scene. The scenes following their arrival in New York do not have the saying and drive of the first half of the film. Even the scene with Ray Charles which is the living proof of the victory of love and dedication over any misfortune,is not able to prevent the spectator from feeling sorry for the lovers,instead of celebrating their re-union. The scene with the aunt was so honest, so profound,that I was expecting something new,something breathtaking as that scene itself.And I kept telling to myself that this is a Warren Beatty film,it is eventually going to take another turn, unravel another aspect of the story,it isn't going to end like that.But to my surprise it did. The "Love Affair" which began in the sky ended on a not strong enough land. But it made us the witnesses of one of cinema's most cherishable moments,the getting together of the guru and her apostles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Painting, Shawls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are multiple reasons to like this. I'll mention two. One comes from the fact that it is a remake. Such things have miraculous properties. Storytelling is all about choices, most invisible. Its the goal sometimes. But when you have a remake and you know the original, then all the scaffolding of the thing becomes visible and you can marvel or not at the changes that have been made. The choices. I do not know the 1939 version, but I do the 57 version with Cary Grant. Its not just mawkish and cheap, its offensive, even vile. The method of presentation depends not on the love, but on the helplessness of the pair. They are quite literally prostitutes, professional paid escorts. He is enchanted by her primarily because she didn't show at the rendezvous and since no one had ever turned him down before he fell in "love" hard, because of the chase. It hit all the negative buttons, even the racist ones. This redone in such a way that it avoids all those faults. It has almost precisely the same story, but instead of cheap sentimental exploitation, you get rich cinematic romance. You get love embodied in actors, three good ones. You get real love 혰 at least so far as movies have 혰 and not infatuation. You have lovers adjusting lives to fit, not tossing advantage in spite. For me it worked as a romantic movie. I know it failed to sell many tickets, and can only guess that it was too honest and true, with not enough sweeping violins. We don't like true love in movies. And that brings me to the other value, the fold with real life. Beatty really was the sort of character he played here, a serial screwer, a man engaged in the chase, someone not to be trusted but who clearly has an image-based artistic side. Benning's reputation was less public, but she was close to being the most desirable woman in Hollywood after "Grifters." They really did fall in love. At filming, she was already carrying their second child. The chemistry is real and conveyed effectively. I make a special study of films where the director is in love with the main actress. Its rare that such a man has such a love, and produces, writes and stars in such a profession of love. Life folded into film romance done competently and cinematically. Is there anything in film romance that matters more? The palette is rosey. Its lovely to watch. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Give this a chance...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MarieGabrielle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you know the story, and have seen the earlier versions, this is still worth a viewing. The current drama/romance genre is something I am not often fond of, yet this film had a resonance, especially for the holiday season. No, it is not the same as the Deborah Kerr, Cary Grant version, but that is a bit dated. There is a cameo scene with Katharine Hepburn, she as Beatty's great- aunt, he as someone at a crossroads in his life; wondering if there will be a turning point. Bening is a singer/actress, they agree to meet in NY, a year after if neither is attached to their current significant other. Beatty and Bening actually make a nice couple, for me to have enjoyed this film at Christmas, points to the fact that it is not another romantic comedy we can toss out ( a rare thing) probably because Beatty and Bening have a believable chemistry together. The final scene, sad as it is Christmas, and the children singing a version of the Beatles' "I will" is atmospheric. It was (for me anyway ) a more moving scene than the older version, perhaps because the children singing in the 1950's version- were singing a song from that 1950's time period.... Highly recommended. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Weak Remake to Satisfy Warren Beatty's Ego
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1932 "Love Affair" is one of the most beautiful, charming and brokenhearted love stories of the cinema industry. Irene Dunne and Charles Boyer have the perfect chemistry and it is impossible not fall in love for her. The 1957 "An Affair to Remember" is a remake frame by frame of the original movie and also more famous. Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr also have perfect chemistry and had been my favorite romance after "Casablanca" until the day I saw the 1932 "Love Affair". I was curious to see the 1994 version of "Love Affair" and I found it a weak remake maybe to satisfy the ego of Warren Beatty. The introduction is awful with annoying music score and edition. Mike Gambril is a detestable character and I do not see any reason for Terry falling in love with him. It is only good to see Ms. Katharine Hepburn in her last feature. My vote is five. Title (Brazil): "Segredos do Cora&ccedil;&atilde;o" ("Secrets of the Heart")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's what true love is...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itazshi08
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have watched this movie several times and it amazes me every time. When I first watched it I didn't know it was a remake, but still I love this version more than the previous ones. The story revolves around two people (Warren and Annette) who crossed their paths while on a flight. they had emergency landing on an island where she meets his aunt (Katharine Hepburn). on a flight back, they have agreed to meet again after 3 months if they still like/love each other. This movie has the total charm. Warren and Annette played their roles with charms, I find them cute and fantastic. I love the scene with Katharine Hepburn, and I think the end scene of this version is more powerful compared in the other versions. The way Annette and Warren delivered their lines are more beautiful and realistic and somehow I think I'm seeing them real. Warren is cute, Annette is perfect, Katharine is indescribable. The background music has a great effect too, it leaves a beautiful feeling to the listener/viewer. You can't just forget it. Well, I don't to want to compare it more with the over versions. I go for this one solid, no matter what because I love watching them move! :) I gave it 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Third Time's "Almost" The Charm.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happipuppi13
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    People that know the 2 movies "An Affair To Remember" and the re-make before this one also called "Love Affair",pretty much know what the movie is about and what to expect. After viewing it all, I can honestly say that this re-make was not really necessary. I'm not saying it suffers the same fate of Striesand's remake of "A Star Is Born" (also a third go-round) but for all intentional purposes,it's just okay and a bit bland. I know Beatty is a good actor and so is Annette but there's not a whole lot of dramatic feeling in their parts for my taste. Even after her character is hurt and can't walk,you just don't feel that sense of urgency about these two. Which makes it very hard to care what happens to them. I was far more moved by Aunt Ginny's passing than anything else. Speaking of her : Like many have stated here though,Katharine Hepburn's brief appearance more than makes up for it. Her part really should have been written so she could at least have been in the film for an hour. I also wish she hadn't been made to use a certain 4 letter word also,totally unnecessary and cheap low brow humor. In all,it's okay to watch if you've nothing better in your collection or to rent, It is worth it for Hepburn,as is almost anything Hepburn ever made. Six stars,for simply a watchable enough film and of course,because it was Kate's last theatrical movie-screen appearance. She was always the bright spot in any film,good or bad. (END)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I like to see you move
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kaykim333
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    resent is most important. I agree with him 100%, but as everyone knows well, to know is different from to do. However I really want to enjoy my real life and share happiness with others. When I watched this movie, I was so happy and able to enjoy the present while I was watching it. Some people don't like romantic movies, they said the situations are ridiculous and acting is so exaggerated, but this movie is my cup of tea. I like a warm-hearted and make believe story about the power of love because in the real world there are a lot of sad things and scary news. I don't want to listen to these things any more. Even though movies are not real, I hope to feel the beauty of the nature and persons. This movie is about love story. Ex-football star Mike Gambril (Warren Beatty) meets Terry McKay (Annette Bening) on a flight, and then they are forced to land because of a weather condition. Both are engaged to others, but they fall in love each other. They promise that they will meet again in New York few months later. I don't want to spoil this movie, so you should watch this if you want to know the ending. This movie's setting is a beautiful island and New York. When they went to Mike's Aunt's house, the setting is very beautiful and refined. Even though it's just picture, I could feel that I am there. I can feel the wind and heavy rain in this movie. I can see the camera director's effort to take a photograph of the beauty of the nature. Especially I like the music and scenery most. This film's music is so beautiful and wonderful, for example "Love Affair Piano Solo" by Ennio Morricone, "I Will" by Beatles, "Chestnuts Roasting on an Open Fire" by Ray Charles. Even if you missed a chance to see this movie I strongly recommend to listen to this film's music . Most of all in the last scene while Mike is saying "If anything had to happen to one of us, why did it have to be you?", 'Love Affair Piano Solo' makes this scene the most beautiful and graceful. During watching this movie, actually I'm interested in the movie music and their dialogues. The lines from this movies are very simple, and poetic. The most famous line is "I like watching you move". In addition Terry's styling is the best!! I can't take away my eyes from her styling from the beginning to the end of this movie. Her white long dress and her beautiful scarf make this movie one of the great art pictures. One of the impressive things is that Warren Beatty and Annette Bening fell in love during a making this movie. Their feeling in this movie is not acting, but it's close to reality. I think this is the big reason why this movie could be so romantic. If you enjoy watching a romantic story, please watch this movie with a glass of wine on Friday night! It is the best choice for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still A Star Crossed Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anyone thinks that we've seen the last remake of Love Affair, think again. The Indian cinema has done a version of it a few years after this film came out. This story has a timeless appeal that Warren Beatty certainly recognized. Anyone who has seen the original Love Affair and the remake An Affair To Remember will know the plot of this film exactly. Warren Beatty and Annette Bening fill the shoes of previous lovers Charles Boyer and Irene Dunne and Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr. With very few deviations except those to update the story this film has the same plot. One of those deviations has our star crossed lovers Warren Beatty and Annette Bening meeting on a transoceanic flight to Sydney, Australia which is certainly a lot of time to get acquainted. They get even better acquainted when they are forced to land on a Pacific island where Beatty's grandmother Katharine Hepburn has a nice tropical place. The kind of setting where romance has to bloom. This was Katharine Hepburn's last big screen appearance, she did one more television film and then her Parkinson's Disease and other ailments that beset people of the age she lived to forced her retirement. I'll bet she never thought she would in 1939 wind up in a remake of a film doing a part Maria Ouspenskaya created. She does it grand style though and only Kate can make an old Anglo-Saxon expletive sound elegant. That Warren Beatty got nominated for a Razzie award for remaking Love Affair is a disgrace. This is old fashioned romantic entertainment, the kind that old Hollywood used to do. I think Beatty and everyone connected with this Love Affair should be proud. I notice that Leo McCarey who wrote and directed Love Affair and An Affair To Remember is prominently listed on the screen credits. He'd be proud of this remake himself, I'm sure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heartfelt and entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kmcresources
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've often heard how so many people, mostly women love the movie "An Affair To Remember," and yet, I never cared much for it. I like the actors, Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr, but the storyline and the idea of "an affair" didn't really appeal to me. I also didn't realize that it was a remake of "Love Affair" from 1939 starring Irene Dunne and Charles Boyer. I happened to see piece of it on a cruise ship and my husband and I recognized some of the dialog. And we both remember the reference to the movie in "Sleepless In Seattle." It was interesting to see this and I decided to borrow it from the library to watch and after watching it, I still didn't find "An Affair To Remember" very appealing. At the same time, I noticed the movie "Love Affair" with Warren Beatty and Annette Benning. I'm not really fans of either, but, for some reason, this movie caught my attention. It's possible it has appeal because here is an actor who was once known as a lifetime bachelor who has now married to an actress and raised four children and the chemistry with the woman he chose to spend his life with shows through. The music throughout the movie is beautiful and the main storyline follows its predecessor, but the dialog is fresh. I was glad to see that the "sensationalism" promoted by paparazzi is quelled by the quick wit of Mike Gambril paying a crew member to present a telegram to the photographer to send him on a wild chase preventing the "scandal" as in "An Affair To Remember." This movie gave me reason to like the story. I find that, even if I am not a fan of particular actors, I can enjoy a movie if they put their heart and souls into the project and not worry about impressing the viewers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This version of a movie previously filmed twice was quite charming for this first time Love Affair viewer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tavm
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Had my mom not rented this from Netflix, I probably wouldn't have bothered to see this third version of a romance previously filmed twice before by Leo McCarey. Real-life married couple Warren Beatty and Annette Bening play two people engaged to others (Kate Capshaw, Pierce Brosnan) who chance meet on a plane and then fall for each other on a cruise ship. At a pit stop, they visit Beatty's aunt (Katherine Hepburn in her last feature role) who provides some views about love. After that, they make a pact to meet at the Empire State Building after a few months and...well, if you've seen the other two (which I haven't) you know what happens. I wasn't sure what to think of this movie with many of the quick-cutting of some scenes and many of the somewhat benign nature of some of the dialogue at the beginning but by the time of Hepburn's appearance, I was charmed by the way Beatty and, especially, Bening interacted with the veteran 4-time Oscar winner especially with the way Ms. Hepburn used a certain word in asking about ducks. Also with her appearance as well as a later one with Ray Charles singing "The Christmas Song", I wondered about what great losses we've had the last five or so years. Many of the supporting cast like Garry Shandling and Harold Ramis (neither of whom I thought had any funny scenes) I recognized but I didn't realize Wendie Jo Sperber and Lisa Edelstein were here until I read the end credits. I did like also some of the musical selections like the "M'm! M'm! Good!" spot with Ed McMahon, the children's chorus of The Beatles' "I Will", and that duet with Louis Jordan and Louis Armstrong on "Life Is So Peculiar" that scored some of the cruise scenes. And the concluding scene was quite touching (if not tear-inducing) that I'm willing to give this version of Love Affair a pass. Bottom line, this was worth seeing for any romantics still out there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A scene which is worth a whole film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Haynoosh
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I want to watch a film in which Warren Beatty's name appears,I know that there must be a damn good reason that has made him contribute to this film. He doesn't have that many films,and there is hardly a film of his that doesn't have a strong statement to make. When I sat down to watch "Love Affair",I didn't know that it was a re-make of the 1939's "Love Affair" and 1957's "An Affair to Remember". I was so marveled with the boyish charm of Warren Beatty when he was trying to hook up the main female character of the film,his real life wife,Annette Bening as Terry McKay,and it was after Mike(Warren's character)and Terry's visit to his aunt,superbly portrayed by Katharine Hepburn,that I noticed the similarities. By the sheer appearance of Hepburn as Mike's aunt on the scene,even before she had noticed the arrival of her nephew,when she was chatting with the docks,she established her presence so rapidly and strongly that made me forget about the other characters. However strong was Hepburn's performance,how much it overshadowed the performance of Beatty and Bening,it was justified.One could sense their admiration towards her, not only as the characters of the film,but as co-workers as well. And that's exactly what gives truthfulness to the point of documentary,to this scene. When Beatty was listening and watching the two women perform the song ,it was obvious that it was not just Mike looking at his aunt,but also Warren Beatty,stoned in awe of the sensitivity and artistry of a Legend. The same goes for Annette Benning.In her conversations with the aunt, and while she was accompanying her by humming,while she was playing the piano,it was again Annette Bening dazzled by her aura. At that point, both us,the viewers,and Beatty and Bening became one,we all were viewers. They were all swans,both the couple dressed in white and in total peace and harmony with themselves and the nature,and the old and wise aunt,Katharine Hepburn,making her unforgettable performance as her swan song. If there is a reason for this film to exist, is that scene. The scenes following their arrival in New York do not have the saying and drive of the first half of the film. Even the scene with Ray Charles which is the living proof of the victory of love and dedication over any misfortune,is not able to prevent the spectator from feeling sorry for the lovers,instead of celebrating their re-union. The scene with the aunt was so honest, so profound,that I was expecting something new,something breathtaking as that scene itself.And I kept telling to myself that this is a Warren Beatty film,it is eventually going to take another turn, unravel another aspect of the story,it isn't going to end like that.But to my surprise it did. The "Love Affair" which began in the sky ended on a not strong enough land. But it made us the witnesses of one of cinema's most cherishable moments,the getting together of the guru and her apostles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Painting, Shawls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are multiple reasons to like this. I'll mention two. One comes from the fact that it is a remake. Such things have miraculous properties. Storytelling is all about choices, most invisible. Its the goal sometimes. But when you have a remake and you know the original, then all the scaffolding of the thing becomes visible and you can marvel or not at the changes that have been made. The choices. I do not know the 1939 version, but I do the 57 version with Cary Grant. Its not just mawkish and cheap, its offensive, even vile. The method of presentation depends not on the love, but on the helplessness of the pair. They are quite literally prostitutes, professional paid escorts. He is enchanted by her primarily because she didn't show at the rendezvous and since no one had ever turned him down before he fell in "love" hard, because of the chase. It hit all the negative buttons, even the racist ones. This redone in such a way that it avoids all those faults. It has almost precisely the same story, but instead of cheap sentimental exploitation, you get rich cinematic romance. You get love embodied in actors, three good ones. You get real love 혰 at least so far as movies have 혰 and not infatuation. You have lovers adjusting lives to fit, not tossing advantage in spite. For me it worked as a romantic movie. I know it failed to sell many tickets, and can only guess that it was too honest and true, with not enough sweeping violins. We don't like true love in movies. And that brings me to the other value, the fold with real life. Beatty really was the sort of character he played here, a serial screwer, a man engaged in the chase, someone not to be trusted but who clearly has an image-based artistic side. Benning's reputation was less public, but she was close to being the most desirable woman in Hollywood after "Grifters." They really did fall in love. At filming, she was already carrying their second child. The chemistry is real and conveyed effectively. I make a special study of films where the director is in love with the main actress. Its rare that such a man has such a love, and produces, writes and stars in such a profession of love. Life folded into film romance done competently and cinematically. Is there anything in film romance that matters more? The palette is rosey. Its lovely to watch. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Give this a chance...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MarieGabrielle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you know the story, and have seen the earlier versions, this is still worth a viewing. The current drama/romance genre is something I am not often fond of, yet this film had a resonance, especially for the holiday season. No, it is not the same as the Deborah Kerr, Cary Grant version, but that is a bit dated. There is a cameo scene with Katharine Hepburn, she as Beatty's great- aunt, he as someone at a crossroads in his life; wondering if there will be a turning point. Bening is a singer/actress, they agree to meet in NY, a year after if neither is attached to their current significant other. Beatty and Bening actually make a nice couple, for me to have enjoyed this film at Christmas, points to the fact that it is not another romantic comedy we can toss out ( a rare thing) probably because Beatty and Bening have a believable chemistry together. The final scene, sad as it is Christmas, and the children singing a version of the Beatles' "I will" is atmospheric. It was (for me anyway ) a more moving scene than the older version, perhaps because the children singing in the 1950's version- were singing a song from that 1950's time period.... Highly recommended. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Weak Remake to Satisfy Warren Beatty's Ego
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1932 "Love Affair" is one of the most beautiful, charming and brokenhearted love stories of the cinema industry. Irene Dunne and Charles Boyer have the perfect chemistry and it is impossible not fall in love for her. The 1957 "An Affair to Remember" is a remake frame by frame of the original movie and also more famous. Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr also have perfect chemistry and had been my favorite romance after "Casablanca" until the day I saw the 1932 "Love Affair". I was curious to see the 1994 version of "Love Affair" and I found it a weak remake maybe to satisfy the ego of Warren Beatty. The introduction is awful with annoying music score and edition. Mike Gambril is a detestable character and I do not see any reason for Terry falling in love with him. It is only good to see Ms. Katharine Hepburn in her last feature. My vote is five. Title (Brazil): "Segredos do Cora&ccedil;&atilde;o" ("Secrets of the Heart")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's what true love is...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itazshi08
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have watched this movie several times and it amazes me every time. When I first watched it I didn't know it was a remake, but still I love this version more than the previous ones. The story revolves around two people (Warren and Annette) who crossed their paths while on a flight. they had emergency landing on an island where she meets his aunt (Katharine Hepburn). on a flight back, they have agreed to meet again after 3 months if they still like/love each other. This movie has the total charm. Warren and Annette played their roles with charms, I find them cute and fantastic. I love the scene with Katharine Hepburn, and I think the end scene of this version is more powerful compared in the other versions. The way Annette and Warren delivered their lines are more beautiful and realistic and somehow I think I'm seeing them real. Warren is cute, Annette is perfect, Katharine is indescribable. The background music has a great effect too, it leaves a beautiful feeling to the listener/viewer. You can't just forget it. Well, I don't to want to compare it more with the over versions. I go for this one solid, no matter what because I love watching them move! :) I gave it 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Third Time's "Almost" The Charm.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happipuppi13
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    People that know the 2 movies "An Affair To Remember" and the re-make before this one also called "Love Affair",pretty much know what the movie is about and what to expect. After viewing it all, I can honestly say that this re-make was not really necessary. I'm not saying it suffers the same fate of Striesand's remake of "A Star Is Born" (also a third go-round) but for all intentional purposes,it's just okay and a bit bland. I know Beatty is a good actor and so is Annette but there's not a whole lot of dramatic feeling in their parts for my taste. Even after her character is hurt and can't walk,you just don't feel that sense of urgency about these two. Which makes it very hard to care what happens to them. I was far more moved by Aunt Ginny's passing than anything else. Speaking of her : Like many have stated here though,Katharine Hepburn's brief appearance more than makes up for it. Her part really should have been written so she could at least have been in the film for an hour. I also wish she hadn't been made to use a certain 4 letter word also,totally unnecessary and cheap low brow humor. In all,it's okay to watch if you've nothing better in your collection or to rent, It is worth it for Hepburn,as is almost anything Hepburn ever made. Six stars,for simply a watchable enough film and of course,because it was Kate's last theatrical movie-screen appearance. She was always the bright spot in any film,good or bad. (END)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I like to see you move
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kaykim333
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    resent is most important. I agree with him 100%, but as everyone knows well, to know is different from to do. However I really want to enjoy my real life and share happiness with others. When I watched this movie, I was so happy and able to enjoy the present while I was watching it. Some people don't like romantic movies, they said the situations are ridiculous and acting is so exaggerated, but this movie is my cup of tea. I like a warm-hearted and make believe story about the power of love because in the real world there are a lot of sad things and scary news. I don't want to listen to these things any more. Even though movies are not real, I hope to feel the beauty of the nature and persons. This movie is about love story. Ex-football star Mike Gambril (Warren Beatty) meets Terry McKay (Annette Bening) on a flight, and then they are forced to land because of a weather condition. Both are engaged to others, but they fall in love each other. They promise that they will meet again in New York few months later. I don't want to spoil this movie, so you should watch this if you want to know the ending. This movie's setting is a beautiful island and New York. When they went to Mike's Aunt's house, the setting is very beautiful and refined. Even though it's just picture, I could feel that I am there. I can feel the wind and heavy rain in this movie. I can see the camera director's effort to take a photograph of the beauty of the nature. Especially I like the music and scenery most. This film's music is so beautiful and wonderful, for example "Love Affair Piano Solo" by Ennio Morricone, "I Will" by Beatles, "Chestnuts Roasting on an Open Fire" by Ray Charles. Even if you missed a chance to see this movie I strongly recommend to listen to this film's music . Most of all in the last scene while Mike is saying "If anything had to happen to one of us, why did it have to be you?", 'Love Affair Piano Solo' makes this scene the most beautiful and graceful. During watching this movie, actually I'm interested in the movie music and their dialogues. The lines from this movies are very simple, and poetic. The most famous line is "I like watching you move". In addition Terry's styling is the best!! I can't take away my eyes from her styling from the beginning to the end of this movie. Her white long dress and her beautiful scarf make this movie one of the great art pictures. One of the impressive things is that Warren Beatty and Annette Bening fell in love during a making this movie. Their feeling in this movie is not acting, but it's close to reality. I think this is the big reason why this movie could be so romantic. If you enjoy watching a romantic story, please watch this movie with a glass of wine on Friday night! It is the best choice for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still A Star Crossed Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anyone thinks that we've seen the last remake of Love Affair, think again. The Indian cinema has done a version of it a few years after this film came out. This story has a timeless appeal that Warren Beatty certainly recognized. Anyone who has seen the original Love Affair and the remake An Affair To Remember will know the plot of this film exactly. Warren Beatty and Annette Bening fill the shoes of previous lovers Charles Boyer and Irene Dunne and Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr. With very few deviations except those to update the story this film has the same plot. One of those deviations has our star crossed lovers Warren Beatty and Annette Bening meeting on a transoceanic flight to Sydney, Australia which is certainly a lot of time to get acquainted. They get even better acquainted when they are forced to land on a Pacific island where Beatty's grandmother Katharine Hepburn has a nice tropical place. The kind of setting where romance has to bloom. This was Katharine Hepburn's last big screen appearance, she did one more television film and then her Parkinson's Disease and other ailments that beset people of the age she lived to forced her retirement. I'll bet she never thought she would in 1939 wind up in a remake of a film doing a part Maria Ouspenskaya created. She does it grand style though and only Kate can make an old Anglo-Saxon expletive sound elegant. That Warren Beatty got nominated for a Razzie award for remaking Love Affair is a disgrace. This is old fashioned romantic entertainment, the kind that old Hollywood used to do. I think Beatty and everyone connected with this Love Affair should be proud. I notice that Leo McCarey who wrote and directed Love Affair and An Affair To Remember is prominently listed on the screen credits. He'd be proud of this remake himself, I'm sure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heartfelt and entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kmcresources
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've often heard how so many people, mostly women love the movie "An Affair To Remember," and yet, I never cared much for it. I like the actors, Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr, but the storyline and the idea of "an affair" didn't really appeal to me. I also didn't realize that it was a remake of "Love Affair" from 1939 starring Irene Dunne and Charles Boyer. I happened to see piece of it on a cruise ship and my husband and I recognized some of the dialog. And we both remember the reference to the movie in "Sleepless In Seattle." It was interesting to see this and I decided to borrow it from the library to watch and after watching it, I still didn't find "An Affair To Remember" very appealing. At the same time, I noticed the movie "Love Affair" with Warren Beatty and Annette Benning. I'm not really fans of either, but, for some reason, this movie caught my attention. It's possible it has appeal because here is an actor who was once known as a lifetime bachelor who has now married to an actress and raised four children and the chemistry with the woman he chose to spend his life with shows through. The music throughout the movie is beautiful and the main storyline follows its predecessor, but the dialog is fresh. I was glad to see that the "sensationalism" promoted by paparazzi is quelled by the quick wit of Mike Gambril paying a crew member to present a telegram to the photographer to send him on a wild chase preventing the "scandal" as in "An Affair To Remember." This movie gave me reason to like the story. I find that, even if I am not a fan of particular actors, I can enjoy a movie if they put their heart and souls into the project and not worry about impressing the viewers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This version of a movie previously filmed twice was quite charming for this first time Love Affair viewer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tavm
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Had my mom not rented this from Netflix, I probably wouldn't have bothered to see this third version of a romance previously filmed twice before by Leo McCarey. Real-life married couple Warren Beatty and Annette Bening play two people engaged to others (Kate Capshaw, Pierce Brosnan) who chance meet on a plane and then fall for each other on a cruise ship. At a pit stop, they visit Beatty's aunt (Katherine Hepburn in her last feature role) who provides some views about love. After that, they make a pact to meet at the Empire State Building after a few months and...well, if you've seen the other two (which I haven't) you know what happens. I wasn't sure what to think of this movie with many of the quick-cutting of some scenes and many of the somewhat benign nature of some of the dialogue at the beginning but by the time of Hepburn's appearance, I was charmed by the way Beatty and, especially, Bening interacted with the veteran 4-time Oscar winner especially with the way Ms. Hepburn used a certain word in asking about ducks. Also with her appearance as well as a later one with Ray Charles singing "The Christmas Song", I wondered about what great losses we've had the last five or so years. Many of the supporting cast like Garry Shandling and Harold Ramis (neither of whom I thought had any funny scenes) I recognized but I didn't realize Wendie Jo Sperber and Lisa Edelstein were here until I read the end credits. I did like also some of the musical selections like the "M'm! M'm! Good!" spot with Ed McMahon, the children's chorus of The Beatles' "I Will", and that duet with Louis Jordan and Louis Armstrong on "Life Is So Peculiar" that scored some of the cruise scenes. And the concluding scene was quite touching (if not tear-inducing) that I'm willing to give this version of Love Affair a pass. Bottom line, this was worth seeing for any romantics still out there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A scene which is worth a whole film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Haynoosh
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I want to watch a film in which Warren Beatty's name appears,I know that there must be a damn good reason that has made him contribute to this film. He doesn't have that many films,and there is hardly a film of his that doesn't have a strong statement to make. When I sat down to watch "Love Affair",I didn't know that it was a re-make of the 1939's "Love Affair" and 1957's "An Affair to Remember". I was so marveled with the boyish charm of Warren Beatty when he was trying to hook up the main female character of the film,his real life wife,Annette Bening as Terry McKay,and it was after Mike(Warren's character)and Terry's visit to his aunt,superbly portrayed by Katharine Hepburn,that I noticed the similarities. By the sheer appearance of Hepburn as Mike's aunt on the scene,even before she had noticed the arrival of her nephew,when she was chatting with the docks,she established her presence so rapidly and strongly that made me forget about the other characters. However strong was Hepburn's performance,how much it overshadowed the performance of Beatty and Bening,it was justified.One could sense their admiration towards her, not only as the characters of the film,but as co-workers as well. And that's exactly what gives truthfulness to the point of documentary,to this scene. When Beatty was listening and watching the two women perform the song ,it was obvious that it was not just Mike looking at his aunt,but also Warren Beatty,stoned in awe of the sensitivity and artistry of a Legend. The same goes for Annette Benning.In her conversations with the aunt, and while she was accompanying her by humming,while she was playing the piano,it was again Annette Bening dazzled by her aura. At that point, both us,the viewers,and Beatty and Bening became one,we all were viewers. They were all swans,both the couple dressed in white and in total peace and harmony with themselves and the nature,and the old and wise aunt,Katharine Hepburn,making her unforgettable performance as her swan song. If there is a reason for this film to exist, is that scene. The scenes following their arrival in New York do not have the saying and drive of the first half of the film. Even the scene with Ray Charles which is the living proof of the victory of love and dedication over any misfortune,is not able to prevent the spectator from feeling sorry for the lovers,instead of celebrating their re-union. The scene with the aunt was so honest, so profound,that I was expecting something new,something breathtaking as that scene itself.And I kept telling to myself that this is a Warren Beatty film,it is eventually going to take another turn, unravel another aspect of the story,it isn't going to end like that.But to my surprise it did. The "Love Affair" which began in the sky ended on a not strong enough land. But it made us the witnesses of one of cinema's most cherishable moments,the getting together of the guru and her apostles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Painting, Shawls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are multiple reasons to like this. I'll mention two. One comes from the fact that it is a remake. Such things have miraculous properties. Storytelling is all about choices, most invisible. Its the goal sometimes. But when you have a remake and you know the original, then all the scaffolding of the thing becomes visible and you can marvel or not at the changes that have been made. The choices. I do not know the 1939 version, but I do the 57 version with Cary Grant. Its not just mawkish and cheap, its offensive, even vile. The method of presentation depends not on the love, but on the helplessness of the pair. They are quite literally prostitutes, professional paid escorts. He is enchanted by her primarily because she didn't show at the rendezvous and since no one had ever turned him down before he fell in "love" hard, because of the chase. It hit all the negative buttons, even the racist ones. This redone in such a way that it avoids all those faults. It has almost precisely the same story, but instead of cheap sentimental exploitation, you get rich cinematic romance. You get love embodied in actors, three good ones. You get real love 혰 at least so far as movies have 혰 and not infatuation. You have lovers adjusting lives to fit, not tossing advantage in spite. For me it worked as a romantic movie. I know it failed to sell many tickets, and can only guess that it was too honest and true, with not enough sweeping violins. We don't like true love in movies. And that brings me to the other value, the fold with real life. Beatty really was the sort of character he played here, a serial screwer, a man engaged in the chase, someone not to be trusted but who clearly has an image-based artistic side. Benning's reputation was less public, but she was close to being the most desirable woman in Hollywood after "Grifters." They really did fall in love. At filming, she was already carrying their second child. The chemistry is real and conveyed effectively. I make a special study of films where the director is in love with the main actress. Its rare that such a man has such a love, and produces, writes and stars in such a profession of love. Life folded into film romance done competently and cinematically. Is there anything in film romance that matters more? The palette is rosey. Its lovely to watch. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Give this a chance...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MarieGabrielle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you know the story, and have seen the earlier versions, this is still worth a viewing. The current drama/romance genre is something I am not often fond of, yet this film had a resonance, especially for the holiday season. No, it is not the same as the Deborah Kerr, Cary Grant version, but that is a bit dated. There is a cameo scene with Katharine Hepburn, she as Beatty's great- aunt, he as someone at a crossroads in his life; wondering if there will be a turning point. Bening is a singer/actress, they agree to meet in NY, a year after if neither is attached to their current significant other. Beatty and Bening actually make a nice couple, for me to have enjoyed this film at Christmas, points to the fact that it is not another romantic comedy we can toss out ( a rare thing) probably because Beatty and Bening have a believable chemistry together. The final scene, sad as it is Christmas, and the children singing a version of the Beatles' "I will" is atmospheric. It was (for me anyway ) a more moving scene than the older version, perhaps because the children singing in the 1950's version- were singing a song from that 1950's time period.... Highly recommended. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
