<filme>
 <id>
  130
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116745
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Kansas City
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Robert Altman's jazz-scored film explores themes of love, crime, race, and politics in 1930's Kansas City. When Blondie O'Hara's husband, a petty thief, is captured by Seldom Seen and held ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Robert Altman's jazz-scored film explores themes of love, crime, race, and politics in 1930's Kansas City. When Blondie O'Hara's husband, a petty thief, is captured by Seldom Seen and held at the Hey Hey Club, she lauches a desperate plan to release him. She kidnaps the wife of a powerful local politician in an attempt to blackmail him into using his connections to free Johnny. Despite this being election time, he risks exposure by putting the political machine into action to free Johnny and thereby save his wife. Mrs. Stilton, meanwhile, has befriended Blondie and is impressed by her love and devotion to Johnny, especially in contrast to her own loveless marriage.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Music
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   politician
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   election
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   1930s
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   kansas city
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   opium addict
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Robert Altman
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Robert Altman
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Frank Barhydt
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jennifer Jason Leigh
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Miranda Richardson
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Harry Belafonte
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Belafonte Fine, Music Even Better--But Central Miscasting Dooms It!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    museumofdave
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like the films of Orson Welles, Federico Fellini or Woody Allen, there's almost always a reason to watch, even if the completed whole doesn't quite add up to the sum of it's parts. Kansas City fits that bill for me. Altman weaves his usual rich tapestry of lives affected by history in a city alive with jazz and political chicanery, and Kansas City is worth watching for the unexpectedly mesmerizing performance by Harry Belafonte as "Seldom Seen," mobster boss. The jazz on display is equally dazzling, but just when your mind is settling into some rich, heady music, the film cuts back to the deadly, mannered, whiny performance turned in by Jennifer Jason Leigh; when most film fans recall the disaster that became Godfather III, the director's indulgence of the lackluster performance turned in by Sofia Coppola comes to mind; Leigh's performance similarly affects the tone of Kansas City, and since she is the protagonist, the film's interest flags with her director-free indulgence in some kind of method acting that fails to evoke much but self-indulgence. In short, Kansas City is well worth a look for superb mise-en-scene,for the music and atmosphere, but is deeply frustrating for it's central performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rich Textured Visuals
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lechuguilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A kidnapping and a robbery move the plot forward in a film that's less about plot than about cultural ambiance. "Kansas City" is mostly a cinematic expression of place and time. It's 1934, when gangsters and jazz ruled and Blacks and Whites went their separate ways. Visuals are very dark. And though the film is in color, tints are muted, which conveys a nostalgic, sentimental mood. The thin plot takes place largely at night. And the plot alternates with dark interior scenes at the Hey Hey Club, a risqu&eacute;, all-Black speakeasy where an all-Black band jives free-form jazz, and where illegal gambling fills the back rooms. None of the characters are sympathetic. But I don't think they're supposed to be. They're archetypes, models of desperate people in desperate times. A gun-wielding gangster's girl named Blondie (Jennifer Jason Leigh) wants to be like Jean Harlow. Mrs. Stilton (Miranda Richardson) is a wealthy, spaced-out politician's wife. Seldom Seen (based on a real-life person and played by Harry Belafonte) is the cigar smoking godfather who rules the dark, smoky Hey Hey Club with an iron fist and who likes to stand around giving lectures to people. The script's dialogue is mostly subtext, with message directed less at other characters than at viewers. And, as in other Altman films, then-current politics dance around the edges of the seedy story. The overall tone mixes depression with desperation. For me this is an easy film to judge. The characters and plot I cared for not at all. Jennifer Jason Leigh was painful to watch. And though the jazz is performed with great competence, its free-form, improvisational style is too contemporary to reflect the 1930s. On the other hand, Miranda Richardson gives a fine performance. Attention to detail in costumes, sets, props, and storefront exteriors make the film come alive with era realism. And lighting is absolutely terrific. If you go into this movie expecting a deep story and well-constructed plot, you'll be disappointed. Absorb the overall texture of the film's visuals. "Kansas City" is a terrific visual portrait of a specific place at a specific time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A depressing movie you should not watch when already depressed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here, Robert Altman attempts to do for Kansas City what William Kennedy did for Albany, New York. Sort of. Kennedy portrays the indefatigable Albany machine with a mix of cynicism, respect and love. In Ironweed we see more of the underbelly of the city, but even though a dark movie, there is a love for his O Albany. Altman's portrayal of Kansas City is dripping with cynicism, but lacks the love, and only offers the blackest of humor. What's worse, there are few likable characters. We spend most of the time watching two brainless women talking incoherently, one on drugs, the other with her teeth wired together. Yet Kansas City is still worth watching, if you are a serious film buff. Everyone, I assume, loves M*A*S*H (except, perhaps, for the Koreans, who do not have a sense of humor about their own country). Nashville and Gosford Park take a bit more savvy to appreciate, but if you understand them, you will know how to approach Kansas City. These Altman movies take an almost sociological-anthropological approach to their subjects, have strong portrayals of many characters, and more or less lack a plot or center, preferring a more naturalistic unfolding of events. Robert Altman is perhaps the greatest modern slice of life movie director. So don't focus so much on the story line as on the characters and their interactions. However, in Kansas City we are introduced to what we would expect to be more of an action movie, or at least a movie with a Hitchcock type plot. This is not what we get. And the first section consists of cutting back and forth among characters and scenes that do not bear much temporal relationship, which is confusing, and distracts from trying to focus on understanding the characters. Eventually, the movie assumes temporal normality, if not linearity. The music is absolutely outstanding. Much of it seems to accurately reproduce 1930s to early 1940s jazz, and seeing it performed in its natural setting of a nightclub gives you better insight into it than merely listening on a record, which gives it a more cerebral air. However, when truly great musicians like this were really cooking, I think the room would have been quieter, out of respect and interest; that's what I have read in some jazz musician memoirs. I was surprised by the atonality of some of the Count Basie riffs on the piano, not typical Basie style. Silver plated brass instruments would not have been common back then. And Charlie Parker never played a single note in the film, as he was pretty horrible when he was 14. There are no brave heroes in this movie. There was one clueless hero, the elections official, but he lasted for about 15 seconds, before being lines up against the wall and shot (although not realistic, perhaps key to the cinematic message). The musicians are the closest thing to nice guys in the movie, but they stay strictly in the barroom, holding aloof from corruption swirling around them, even while they see much of what is going on, as do most of the blacks. In short, Altman's Kansas City is as devoid of heroes as High Noon would be without Gary Cooper, or It's a Wonderful Life without Jimmy Stewart. Yeah, it's corrupt, but what are you going to do? Make the best of it by joining in, getting a piece of the action. (In reality, not everyone was corrupt, not even all Missouri politicians.) As to the portrayal of the Tom Pendergast political machine, I think Altman over does it. I sincerely doubt a political hack would pull out a gun in broad daylight in front of a polling place and shoot an elections official. Unnecessary and stupid, and sure to make the evening papers. The Pendergast machine was corrupt, but not stupid; the corruption focused on government contracts, from what I have read. The movie's strength is showing the different levels of society and how they interact, black working class, black mob, white political elite, white trash. Its other strength is reproducing the era in astonishingly rich detail. I love movies like this that get it right, and make you feel like you are being transported back in time. The acting is great, especially Harry Belafonte. Jennifer Jason Leigh gets on your nerves, big time, but does so convincingly. Spoiler alert: Near the end, Mrs. Stilton drops her medicine bottle on the ground. Your first thought is it was empty. Or she had decided to break her habit. But I suspect the real meaning, judging from her body language when she tosses the bottle down, is she was faking it, and wasn't so dependent on her "medicine." If you like this movie, try Ironweed, starring Jack Nicholson and Merle Streep. It's a better movie, but Kansas City has better jazz. The jazz, alone, is worth the price of admission.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vivid depiction of Kansas City, 1934
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tnrcooper
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having read all the reviews and seen the rating given this film by even more viewers, it would seem that many viewers are not au courant with the style of Jean Harlow and/or do not have the patience necessary to appreciate some films which do not move along at a quick clip. This would seem to be Altman's tribute to his hometown and to the period when he was a kid-he would have been 9 in 1934. Altman's take on the outre political corruption in Kansas City at that time would seem to be of a sort with the corruption facilitated by the Pendergras machine of the time. His depiction of black characters as autonomous, strong characters is refreshing. Harry Belafonte's mob boss Seldom Seen has to be one of the most ruthless characters seen on celluloid in recent years. Belafonte is at the top of his game, his smoky baritone all the more ominous for his low-key manner. Belafonte really deserved an Oscar nomination for his performance in this movie. One of the many aspects to recommend this film is the music that lit up Kansas City at that time-jazz. The music, featuring Lester Young, Coleman Hawkins, and even a very young Charlie Parker before he was a musician, is electric. The musicians-played by world-class musicians like Joshua Redman, David 'Fathead' Newman, and Christian McBride, electrify the scenes they are in, particularly in one duel which continues until daybreak. The musical scenes are truly magical and electric. We get a sense of the energy and vibrance in the Kansas City music scene at that time. Altman also tweaks notions of race by having white Johnny Flynn (an almost silent Dermot Mulroney) attempting to knock off a mob underling while wearing blackface. Altman considers race and is not afraid to depict and play around with it. The very fact that he is willing to consider its existence and status in society is interesting in itself. There are many black characters, many given great depth and range. Altman adds depth to our understanding of race and fleshes out depiction of people of color in ways that the vast majority of directors do not even acknowledge or consider. This makes the film valuable in and of itself. The film's plot revolves around the kidnapping of the Missouri governor's wife Caroline Stilson (Miranda Richardson) who is kidnapped to pressure the Governor to release Blondie's husband (Dermot Mulroney's Jonny Flynn) who has been caught after trying to rip off one of Seldom Seen's mob lieutenants. Blondie thinks that taking the governor's wife hostage will cause the governor to take the release of her husband more seriously. Some people don't like Jennifer Jason Leigh's performance in this movie, suggesting that it is difficult to understand her. I think that was intentional on her part-an effort to pay tribute to the work of Jean Harlow who was from Kansas City and who we see in a movie that Caroline and Blondie are watching. It's clear that Jean Harlow was attempting to depict a tougher veneer than she really had, as we see as Blondie's tough outer shell collapses as the movie progresses. I found it a very original, Oscar-worthy, performance. Miranda Richardson's depiction of a depressed, drug-addled, lonely political wife who ultimately turns out to know more than she lets on is very compelling. The chemistry between her and Leigh is electric and Richardson's role is very interesting. She delivers an excellent performance in an unusual role. Altman interweaves story lines-those of Seldom Seen and Jonny Flynn on the one hand, and Caroline Stilson and Blondie on the other-expertly-linking them effortlessly. This is one of Altman's greatest strengths-tying in disparate story lines and making connections where they might be less obvious to most filmmakers. Altman makes connections among figures where most directors wouldn't see them. I don't think this film is on the level of his tours de force in Gosford Park, Short Cuts, The Player, MASH, and Nashville, but Altman was always more about depicting a milieu and setting a scene and if his story did not have the pyrotechnics of some of many films in theaters at the time, he didn't care. This film smolders quietly, suggesting a city rotting from the inside out as evidenced by the political and criminal malfeasance which are so brazen in the picture. Altman tells rich, colorful stories and this one is no exception.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Altman With All That Jazz But It's A Little Bit Confusing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a new born to a new audience with excellent "The Player" and "Short Cuts" and slip down with the weird and unfunny "Pr&eacute;t-&agrave;-Porter", the master of the independent cinema Robert Altman gets back with a minor but interesting work in "Kansas City". Here, he reveals the dangerous Kansas City of the 1930's with their corrupt politicians, scary mobsters and people involved with all this world without noticing the danger right ahead. In the 1930's the young and beautiful Blondie (Jennifer Jason Leigh) kidnaps Carolyn (Miranda Richardson) the wife of a powerful politician (Michael Murphy) who can help her to save her boyfriend Johnny (Dermot Mulroney), a little burglar who stole an important big shot in the crime world, and now he's going to be killed by another powerful mob figure, the gangster Seldom Seen (Harry Belafonte). The frightened Carolyn is dragged away along with Blondie to several places in town, trying to get along with each other, which doesn't work quite well because of their different backgrounds. Blondie is addicted to the films of Jean Harlow and she keeps annoying her hostage all the way; while Carolyn is an addicted to opium that barely gets out of the house, suffering with her addiction. In the meantime the politician keeps dealing with the case, in a very discreet way to not ruin his future election that its getting ahead and because of his proximity with President Roosevelt. On the other part of town, Johnny has the chance to know more about what the real world of crime really is, listening to Seldom's menacing stories and to lots of jazz that is played in his captivity. Besides these two kidnaps there's a subplot concerning a girl who came to town to get an abortion and a political scandal involving a party which is buying votes to win the election using of deadly tactics. The same team of writers who signed "Short Cuts" tries to unite several characters that follow the same path in several situations having as link the jazz as musical background played in almost every scene. As I said, they tried to unite them but they end up confusing the public by dividing two situations, apparently disconnected, that will meet in the end, and until it get to the final result you keep wondering what's the reason for both kidnaps. When the two parts get together it all makes sense but before some answers appear many will have walked away of the movie because everything is slow, almost tedious. The perfect "Short Cuts" which tells the story of 23 characters crossing the way of each other in a chaotic Los Angeles, in a excellent tragicomedy of the real life, gets way better than "Kansas City" with their 6 main characters. On the other hand this confusion in dividing the film in two situations makes a intriguing film that makes the audience wants to know of what happens next. As favorable points, "Kansas City" has a great period reconstitution, the costumes of the 1930's, the old cars; the music (Altman worked the same musicians who appeared in his documentary "Jazz 34"); and a great performance by Harry Belafonte as the talking gangster who has an answer to everything. Michael Murphy surprises a lot in his short moments in which he appears; the other performances are not so interesting, sometimes they are very annoying, and that is the case of the main pair. Jennifer Jason Leigh's voice is tiring and very debauched for a dramatic film; Miranda Richardson has a very aloof character, a role that she would dominate better in the great "Falling Angels". Robert Altman made a good job despite not being too much impressive as his previous works. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh the pain, the pain. Is it over yet?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rodney_h
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm sorry but this movie was pitiful. I hated it. KC is S-L-O-W, B-O-R-I-N-G, crap. The dialog was laughable, trite and completely unbelievable. This is a bland thirty-minute short story stretched out to almost two painfully excruciating hours. The only good qualities in this waste of celluloid were 1. Great costumes and 2. Fabulous period cars. Where did they get all of those great old cars? CAUTION - This film is for jazz lovers only....and I hate jazz. How bad can it be? If YOU like this crap-fest, then help yourself to my DVD copy. I threw my disk in the trash. It'll be out at the county dump by now (where it belongs). 1 star out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lost somewhere between the 1930s and 1990s.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Altman's Kansas City is not a terrible movie by any stretch of the imagination and for any other director it would be a minor triumph. Yet, given the pedigree he has provided for himself, particularly with films such as MASH, McCabe & Mrs. Miller, Nashville and 3 Women on his resume, I hold his films to a higher order than most. Perhaps for that reason most of all, I was quite disappointed by this outcome. Jennifer Jason Leigh and Miranda Richardson star as small-time hoodlum and rich politician's wives, respectively, with Leigh taking Richardson hostage in hope that her husband will be released by the notorious gangster Seldom Seen. However, all this is simply a contrivance for what Altman is really after, which seems to me to be the context and feeling of the city of Kansas City in the 1930s when Jean Harlow movies played in the local cinemas and voting was a high-stakes gamble that if gone wrong had very serious consequences. In terms of the film itself, I would consider this film to suffer from the Hudsucker Proxy syndrome: it looks fantastic with the sets and costumes all perfectly realizing the era in which it attempts to capture. Yet, the story is almost thrown together with really not attempt to clarify or make known exactly what is happening. I understand this is Altman's style, particularly for this film, but in order to string the movie along and maintain audience interest, it certainly would have helped to include a more cohesive story line. Also, Jennifer Jason Leigh doesn't fit this part in my opinion, coming off more annoying and self-conscious than sympathetic and interestingly quirky. Her dialogue and delivery seem to come right out of the 1990s and have almost no place in the setting of the rest of the characters. I admire Altman as a director too much to call this film a disaster but it is by far the weakest of all his films I have seen and makes me question why he decided to make this film. Perhaps because he grew up in Kansas City in the 1930s or he felt interested in gangsters, jazz and the setting of a growing town prior to World War II. Whatever the reason, I was frequently out of touch with the story and can really give no compelling reason to seek it out as one of Altman's finer works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Celluloid Jazz
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "You know what I didn't do today? I didn't vote."  Carolyn Stilton I absolutely hated "Kansas City" upon first viewing. Its pace seemed strange, its flashbacks seemed oddly placed, its camera seemed to dwell on unimportant details and none of its characters seemed to exist to propel any clearly defined story forward. In other words, though I'd seen virtually every other Robert Altman film, "Kansas City" still left me in a state of bewilderment. But as is often the case with Altman, "Kansas City" began to make sense - in so far as Altman desires to make sense; his films seem to embrace a certain chaos - upon second viewing. Filled with loving shots of jazz musicians, the film is itself a jazzy tone poem, Altman coming at the audience from odd angles, asking us to pick up on his shifting rhythms of plot and character, themes of race, politics, violence and money. Consider the subtle juxtapositions Altman weaves into the film... A poor white man (Johnny O'Hara) paints his face black and robs a wealthy black man. Seeking assistance, the black man visits a powerful black crime boss called Seldom Seen. Seldom agrees to help, kidnaps Johnny and kills him. In contrast, Johnny's wife (Blondie O'Hara) kidnaps a wealthy white woman (Carolyn Stilton) while she applies a white beauty mask. Carolyn is married to Henry Stilton, a powerful politician. Blondie wants Henry to negotiate with the crime lord so that she may get her husband back. Blondie is eventually killed by Carolyn Stilton. While this drama is unfolding, other characters enter the mix. A young Charlie Parker, years away from musical fame, finds a pregnant black girl. He takes her to a maternity ward. Meanwhile, we learn that Blondie had her baby aborted because Johnny didn't want kids. Similarly, a poor black cab driver (who helped Johnny stage his robbery) is taken to a back alleyway and killed by Seldom and his gang. In contrast, Henry Stilton's goons kill a white man in broad daylight because he was hampering their efforts to falsify local election ballots. And so on and on it goes, Altman juxtaposing his jazz notes, "Kansas City" less a linear narrative than a series of contrasting sequences or oppositional musical riffs, some obvious, some subtle, but all revolving around class, race and gender. Blackface paint is mirrored to white beauty cream, black crime lords are mirrored to corrupt white politicians, political thugs are mirrored to violent gangsters, abortions are mirrored to pregnancies, loving marriages are mirrored to loveless couples, poverty is mirrored to power, underground gambling joints and brothels are mirrored to above ground poll booths and ballot stations. Blondie O'Hara, the young kidnapper, is herself contrasted with Carolyn Stilton, the woman she kidnaps. Blondie loves her husband and would do anything for him. Mrs Stilton, in contrast, is constantly doped up on opium and has long given up on her marriage. Furthermore, Blondie is constantly emulating Kansas City native Jean Harlow, an actress whom she idolises. This notion of "narrative emulation" is itself intended to mirror the "cutting contests" between the jazz musicians sprinkled throughout the film. Just as the musicians borrow from one another and weave each other's material into what they are improvising, Blondie borrows from the movies and weaves Harlow's tough girl phrases and expressions into her conversation. But Blondie's toughness is all a facade, a suit of armour used to compensate for her petite size and coarse environment. While Blondie gives up her child and is constantly subservient to her husband, it is Carolyn Stilton who possesses true strength. Despite her permanently doped up state, Carolyn constantly gives the impression that she knows more than she's letting on, always absorbing information and assessing her surroundings. Her final line, "I didn't vote", itself lets us know that she has long cut herself off from a venal world which she refuses to legitimize. And so with "Kansas City" - a film which ends with a crime lord counting money in the dark corners of a jazz club - Altman has abstracted the politics of power and persuasion, threat and privilege. Everything in the film hinges on social power, Altman drawing a clean line between those violent people who wield power and all those pathetic dreamers who try to grab it but never succeed in doing so for more than a fleeting moment. The political corruption of the city's democratic machine (the country was built on voting fraud and rigged elections; practises common even today), and the expanding influence of Hollywood (and the power of film to seduce and destroy people such as Blondie), is as important to Altman as the racial segregation that produces Kansas City's two worlds: the white world, dominated by the Stilton's, and the inverted black world of Seldom Seen, a vampiric world of music which seems to only come to life long after the surface world has gone to sleep. The film is also unique in the way it offers jazz music an unprecedented role within the diegetic world. This music is constantly "seeping into" he story, providing a kind of tapestry for the characters to perform against. The result is that the jazz music seems to become intertwined with the very social climate that influences it. Altman himself has said that it was his intention that jazz be the structure of the entire film. Whilst a typical song lasts 3 minutes, a jazz tune lasts as much as 17, the effect being that many of the film's scenes are elongated and purposefully stretched out. "Seldom Seen is like a brass instrument," Altman says, "when it's his turn to solo, he does long monologues and riffs. But the discussions of the two women are like reed instruments, saxophones having duets." 8/10 - Best appreciated as a kind of cinematic jazz, the plot lethargically frustrating as it intrigues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ....And All That Jazz
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Altman dishes up a terrific serving of jazz and Depression-era atmosphere in this crime thriller with film noir trappings. Jennifer Jason Leigh gives a fascinating and heartbreaking performance as Blondie, the pathetic Jean Harlow wannabe who kidnaps a senator's (Michael Murphy) wife (Miranda Richardson) in an attempt to force him into helping her husband, Johnny (Dermot Mulroney), who's himself been kidnapped by Seldom Seen (Harry Belafonte), a local gangster kingpin, after Johnny tried to pull a heist on one of Seldom's own. The dark plot works its way toward an inevitable and tragic ending, but as is true with many Altman films, what happens isn't as much fun as how it happens. Altman intersperses the film with segments of music being played in a hot jazz club, and the nearly constant soundtrack gives the whole movie the pulse and rhythm of the jazz numbers it's set to. I'm not so sure I liked the performance of Richardson. She plays a woman doped up on opiates, and while I don't know how someone would act in those circumstances, her performance felt cartoonish and exaggerated to me. But Leigh more than makes up for any weak performances, and she owns this film. Blondie is a born loser, a woman who's learned how to act tough from watching movies but who's not nearly tough enough to survive in the world around her. It's with a mixture of pity and relief that we see the film, and Blondie's fate, move toward its "They Shoot Horses, Don't They?" resolution. Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bonanza for jazz lovers - one of Mr Altman's more personal works
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ianlouisiana
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    God knows English politics is corrupt,but America seems to have raised duplicity to another level.Wheeling,dealing,threatening,bribing,snouts deep in the trough....I would have to be held at gunpoint before I'd vote for anybody.In the poor black Wards of Kansas City in the mid 1930s it doesn't matter who you vote for,your life is not going to get any better,the successful politico is just going to get richer. With a plot and characters remarkably similar to early Runyon,Mr Altman parallels the development of KC jazz with its turbulent social history. For lovers of Bennie Moten/Count Basie type music the movie is at least an aural treat;for the average moviegoer,"Kansas City" is very much a curate's egg. Unless you are at least familiar with Hawk,Pres,Bird and Jean Harlow your enjoyment of the movie may well be limited to the amount of admiration you have for Mr Altman's more personal work. With all due respect to the acting talent involved,no one apart from the much - maligned Miss J.J. Leigh has much to work with.As "Blondie" she has the only role that actually develops during the course of the film. In an era when movies were enormously influential her conscious morphing into a Jean Harlow persona is touching rather than laughable. With "Kansas City",Mr Altman continued to plough his lonely furrow.That it was not a great commercial success is hardly surprising,but admirers of maverick works will get pleasure from it.Jazz loving moviegoers,themselves to some degree mavericks,scouring the schedules in a usually vain attempt to satisfy both their Joneses,should seize the moment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Belafonte Fine, Music Even Better--But Central Miscasting Dooms It!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    museumofdave
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like the films of Orson Welles, Federico Fellini or Woody Allen, there's almost always a reason to watch, even if the completed whole doesn't quite add up to the sum of it's parts. Kansas City fits that bill for me. Altman weaves his usual rich tapestry of lives affected by history in a city alive with jazz and political chicanery, and Kansas City is worth watching for the unexpectedly mesmerizing performance by Harry Belafonte as "Seldom Seen," mobster boss. The jazz on display is equally dazzling, but just when your mind is settling into some rich, heady music, the film cuts back to the deadly, mannered, whiny performance turned in by Jennifer Jason Leigh; when most film fans recall the disaster that became Godfather III, the director's indulgence of the lackluster performance turned in by Sofia Coppola comes to mind; Leigh's performance similarly affects the tone of Kansas City, and since she is the protagonist, the film's interest flags with her director-free indulgence in some kind of method acting that fails to evoke much but self-indulgence. In short, Kansas City is well worth a look for superb mise-en-scene,for the music and atmosphere, but is deeply frustrating for it's central performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rich Textured Visuals
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lechuguilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A kidnapping and a robbery move the plot forward in a film that's less about plot than about cultural ambiance. "Kansas City" is mostly a cinematic expression of place and time. It's 1934, when gangsters and jazz ruled and Blacks and Whites went their separate ways. Visuals are very dark. And though the film is in color, tints are muted, which conveys a nostalgic, sentimental mood. The thin plot takes place largely at night. And the plot alternates with dark interior scenes at the Hey Hey Club, a risqu&eacute;, all-Black speakeasy where an all-Black band jives free-form jazz, and where illegal gambling fills the back rooms. None of the characters are sympathetic. But I don't think they're supposed to be. They're archetypes, models of desperate people in desperate times. A gun-wielding gangster's girl named Blondie (Jennifer Jason Leigh) wants to be like Jean Harlow. Mrs. Stilton (Miranda Richardson) is a wealthy, spaced-out politician's wife. Seldom Seen (based on a real-life person and played by Harry Belafonte) is the cigar smoking godfather who rules the dark, smoky Hey Hey Club with an iron fist and who likes to stand around giving lectures to people. The script's dialogue is mostly subtext, with message directed less at other characters than at viewers. And, as in other Altman films, then-current politics dance around the edges of the seedy story. The overall tone mixes depression with desperation. For me this is an easy film to judge. The characters and plot I cared for not at all. Jennifer Jason Leigh was painful to watch. And though the jazz is performed with great competence, its free-form, improvisational style is too contemporary to reflect the 1930s. On the other hand, Miranda Richardson gives a fine performance. Attention to detail in costumes, sets, props, and storefront exteriors make the film come alive with era realism. And lighting is absolutely terrific. If you go into this movie expecting a deep story and well-constructed plot, you'll be disappointed. Absorb the overall texture of the film's visuals. "Kansas City" is a terrific visual portrait of a specific place at a specific time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A depressing movie you should not watch when already depressed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here, Robert Altman attempts to do for Kansas City what William Kennedy did for Albany, New York. Sort of. Kennedy portrays the indefatigable Albany machine with a mix of cynicism, respect and love. In Ironweed we see more of the underbelly of the city, but even though a dark movie, there is a love for his O Albany. Altman's portrayal of Kansas City is dripping with cynicism, but lacks the love, and only offers the blackest of humor. What's worse, there are few likable characters. We spend most of the time watching two brainless women talking incoherently, one on drugs, the other with her teeth wired together. Yet Kansas City is still worth watching, if you are a serious film buff. Everyone, I assume, loves M*A*S*H (except, perhaps, for the Koreans, who do not have a sense of humor about their own country). Nashville and Gosford Park take a bit more savvy to appreciate, but if you understand them, you will know how to approach Kansas City. These Altman movies take an almost sociological-anthropological approach to their subjects, have strong portrayals of many characters, and more or less lack a plot or center, preferring a more naturalistic unfolding of events. Robert Altman is perhaps the greatest modern slice of life movie director. So don't focus so much on the story line as on the characters and their interactions. However, in Kansas City we are introduced to what we would expect to be more of an action movie, or at least a movie with a Hitchcock type plot. This is not what we get. And the first section consists of cutting back and forth among characters and scenes that do not bear much temporal relationship, which is confusing, and distracts from trying to focus on understanding the characters. Eventually, the movie assumes temporal normality, if not linearity. The music is absolutely outstanding. Much of it seems to accurately reproduce 1930s to early 1940s jazz, and seeing it performed in its natural setting of a nightclub gives you better insight into it than merely listening on a record, which gives it a more cerebral air. However, when truly great musicians like this were really cooking, I think the room would have been quieter, out of respect and interest; that's what I have read in some jazz musician memoirs. I was surprised by the atonality of some of the Count Basie riffs on the piano, not typical Basie style. Silver plated brass instruments would not have been common back then. And Charlie Parker never played a single note in the film, as he was pretty horrible when he was 14. There are no brave heroes in this movie. There was one clueless hero, the elections official, but he lasted for about 15 seconds, before being lines up against the wall and shot (although not realistic, perhaps key to the cinematic message). The musicians are the closest thing to nice guys in the movie, but they stay strictly in the barroom, holding aloof from corruption swirling around them, even while they see much of what is going on, as do most of the blacks. In short, Altman's Kansas City is as devoid of heroes as High Noon would be without Gary Cooper, or It's a Wonderful Life without Jimmy Stewart. Yeah, it's corrupt, but what are you going to do? Make the best of it by joining in, getting a piece of the action. (In reality, not everyone was corrupt, not even all Missouri politicians.) As to the portrayal of the Tom Pendergast political machine, I think Altman over does it. I sincerely doubt a political hack would pull out a gun in broad daylight in front of a polling place and shoot an elections official. Unnecessary and stupid, and sure to make the evening papers. The Pendergast machine was corrupt, but not stupid; the corruption focused on government contracts, from what I have read. The movie's strength is showing the different levels of society and how they interact, black working class, black mob, white political elite, white trash. Its other strength is reproducing the era in astonishingly rich detail. I love movies like this that get it right, and make you feel like you are being transported back in time. The acting is great, especially Harry Belafonte. Jennifer Jason Leigh gets on your nerves, big time, but does so convincingly. Spoiler alert: Near the end, Mrs. Stilton drops her medicine bottle on the ground. Your first thought is it was empty. Or she had decided to break her habit. But I suspect the real meaning, judging from her body language when she tosses the bottle down, is she was faking it, and wasn't so dependent on her "medicine." If you like this movie, try Ironweed, starring Jack Nicholson and Merle Streep. It's a better movie, but Kansas City has better jazz. The jazz, alone, is worth the price of admission.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vivid depiction of Kansas City, 1934
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tnrcooper
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having read all the reviews and seen the rating given this film by even more viewers, it would seem that many viewers are not au courant with the style of Jean Harlow and/or do not have the patience necessary to appreciate some films which do not move along at a quick clip. This would seem to be Altman's tribute to his hometown and to the period when he was a kid-he would have been 9 in 1934. Altman's take on the outre political corruption in Kansas City at that time would seem to be of a sort with the corruption facilitated by the Pendergras machine of the time. His depiction of black characters as autonomous, strong characters is refreshing. Harry Belafonte's mob boss Seldom Seen has to be one of the most ruthless characters seen on celluloid in recent years. Belafonte is at the top of his game, his smoky baritone all the more ominous for his low-key manner. Belafonte really deserved an Oscar nomination for his performance in this movie. One of the many aspects to recommend this film is the music that lit up Kansas City at that time-jazz. The music, featuring Lester Young, Coleman Hawkins, and even a very young Charlie Parker before he was a musician, is electric. The musicians-played by world-class musicians like Joshua Redman, David 'Fathead' Newman, and Christian McBride, electrify the scenes they are in, particularly in one duel which continues until daybreak. The musical scenes are truly magical and electric. We get a sense of the energy and vibrance in the Kansas City music scene at that time. Altman also tweaks notions of race by having white Johnny Flynn (an almost silent Dermot Mulroney) attempting to knock off a mob underling while wearing blackface. Altman considers race and is not afraid to depict and play around with it. The very fact that he is willing to consider its existence and status in society is interesting in itself. There are many black characters, many given great depth and range. Altman adds depth to our understanding of race and fleshes out depiction of people of color in ways that the vast majority of directors do not even acknowledge or consider. This makes the film valuable in and of itself. The film's plot revolves around the kidnapping of the Missouri governor's wife Caroline Stilson (Miranda Richardson) who is kidnapped to pressure the Governor to release Blondie's husband (Dermot Mulroney's Jonny Flynn) who has been caught after trying to rip off one of Seldom Seen's mob lieutenants. Blondie thinks that taking the governor's wife hostage will cause the governor to take the release of her husband more seriously. Some people don't like Jennifer Jason Leigh's performance in this movie, suggesting that it is difficult to understand her. I think that was intentional on her part-an effort to pay tribute to the work of Jean Harlow who was from Kansas City and who we see in a movie that Caroline and Blondie are watching. It's clear that Jean Harlow was attempting to depict a tougher veneer than she really had, as we see as Blondie's tough outer shell collapses as the movie progresses. I found it a very original, Oscar-worthy, performance. Miranda Richardson's depiction of a depressed, drug-addled, lonely political wife who ultimately turns out to know more than she lets on is very compelling. The chemistry between her and Leigh is electric and Richardson's role is very interesting. She delivers an excellent performance in an unusual role. Altman interweaves story lines-those of Seldom Seen and Jonny Flynn on the one hand, and Caroline Stilson and Blondie on the other-expertly-linking them effortlessly. This is one of Altman's greatest strengths-tying in disparate story lines and making connections where they might be less obvious to most filmmakers. Altman makes connections among figures where most directors wouldn't see them. I don't think this film is on the level of his tours de force in Gosford Park, Short Cuts, The Player, MASH, and Nashville, but Altman was always more about depicting a milieu and setting a scene and if his story did not have the pyrotechnics of some of many films in theaters at the time, he didn't care. This film smolders quietly, suggesting a city rotting from the inside out as evidenced by the political and criminal malfeasance which are so brazen in the picture. Altman tells rich, colorful stories and this one is no exception.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Altman With All That Jazz But It's A Little Bit Confusing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a new born to a new audience with excellent "The Player" and "Short Cuts" and slip down with the weird and unfunny "Pr&eacute;t-&agrave;-Porter", the master of the independent cinema Robert Altman gets back with a minor but interesting work in "Kansas City". Here, he reveals the dangerous Kansas City of the 1930's with their corrupt politicians, scary mobsters and people involved with all this world without noticing the danger right ahead. In the 1930's the young and beautiful Blondie (Jennifer Jason Leigh) kidnaps Carolyn (Miranda Richardson) the wife of a powerful politician (Michael Murphy) who can help her to save her boyfriend Johnny (Dermot Mulroney), a little burglar who stole an important big shot in the crime world, and now he's going to be killed by another powerful mob figure, the gangster Seldom Seen (Harry Belafonte). The frightened Carolyn is dragged away along with Blondie to several places in town, trying to get along with each other, which doesn't work quite well because of their different backgrounds. Blondie is addicted to the films of Jean Harlow and she keeps annoying her hostage all the way; while Carolyn is an addicted to opium that barely gets out of the house, suffering with her addiction. In the meantime the politician keeps dealing with the case, in a very discreet way to not ruin his future election that its getting ahead and because of his proximity with President Roosevelt. On the other part of town, Johnny has the chance to know more about what the real world of crime really is, listening to Seldom's menacing stories and to lots of jazz that is played in his captivity. Besides these two kidnaps there's a subplot concerning a girl who came to town to get an abortion and a political scandal involving a party which is buying votes to win the election using of deadly tactics. The same team of writers who signed "Short Cuts" tries to unite several characters that follow the same path in several situations having as link the jazz as musical background played in almost every scene. As I said, they tried to unite them but they end up confusing the public by dividing two situations, apparently disconnected, that will meet in the end, and until it get to the final result you keep wondering what's the reason for both kidnaps. When the two parts get together it all makes sense but before some answers appear many will have walked away of the movie because everything is slow, almost tedious. The perfect "Short Cuts" which tells the story of 23 characters crossing the way of each other in a chaotic Los Angeles, in a excellent tragicomedy of the real life, gets way better than "Kansas City" with their 6 main characters. On the other hand this confusion in dividing the film in two situations makes a intriguing film that makes the audience wants to know of what happens next. As favorable points, "Kansas City" has a great period reconstitution, the costumes of the 1930's, the old cars; the music (Altman worked the same musicians who appeared in his documentary "Jazz 34"); and a great performance by Harry Belafonte as the talking gangster who has an answer to everything. Michael Murphy surprises a lot in his short moments in which he appears; the other performances are not so interesting, sometimes they are very annoying, and that is the case of the main pair. Jennifer Jason Leigh's voice is tiring and very debauched for a dramatic film; Miranda Richardson has a very aloof character, a role that she would dominate better in the great "Falling Angels". Robert Altman made a good job despite not being too much impressive as his previous works. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh the pain, the pain. Is it over yet?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rodney_h
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm sorry but this movie was pitiful. I hated it. KC is S-L-O-W, B-O-R-I-N-G, crap. The dialog was laughable, trite and completely unbelievable. This is a bland thirty-minute short story stretched out to almost two painfully excruciating hours. The only good qualities in this waste of celluloid were 1. Great costumes and 2. Fabulous period cars. Where did they get all of those great old cars? CAUTION - This film is for jazz lovers only....and I hate jazz. How bad can it be? If YOU like this crap-fest, then help yourself to my DVD copy. I threw my disk in the trash. It'll be out at the county dump by now (where it belongs). 1 star out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lost somewhere between the 1930s and 1990s.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Altman's Kansas City is not a terrible movie by any stretch of the imagination and for any other director it would be a minor triumph. Yet, given the pedigree he has provided for himself, particularly with films such as MASH, McCabe & Mrs. Miller, Nashville and 3 Women on his resume, I hold his films to a higher order than most. Perhaps for that reason most of all, I was quite disappointed by this outcome. Jennifer Jason Leigh and Miranda Richardson star as small-time hoodlum and rich politician's wives, respectively, with Leigh taking Richardson hostage in hope that her husband will be released by the notorious gangster Seldom Seen. However, all this is simply a contrivance for what Altman is really after, which seems to me to be the context and feeling of the city of Kansas City in the 1930s when Jean Harlow movies played in the local cinemas and voting was a high-stakes gamble that if gone wrong had very serious consequences. In terms of the film itself, I would consider this film to suffer from the Hudsucker Proxy syndrome: it looks fantastic with the sets and costumes all perfectly realizing the era in which it attempts to capture. Yet, the story is almost thrown together with really not attempt to clarify or make known exactly what is happening. I understand this is Altman's style, particularly for this film, but in order to string the movie along and maintain audience interest, it certainly would have helped to include a more cohesive story line. Also, Jennifer Jason Leigh doesn't fit this part in my opinion, coming off more annoying and self-conscious than sympathetic and interestingly quirky. Her dialogue and delivery seem to come right out of the 1990s and have almost no place in the setting of the rest of the characters. I admire Altman as a director too much to call this film a disaster but it is by far the weakest of all his films I have seen and makes me question why he decided to make this film. Perhaps because he grew up in Kansas City in the 1930s or he felt interested in gangsters, jazz and the setting of a growing town prior to World War II. Whatever the reason, I was frequently out of touch with the story and can really give no compelling reason to seek it out as one of Altman's finer works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Celluloid Jazz
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "You know what I didn't do today? I didn't vote."  Carolyn Stilton I absolutely hated "Kansas City" upon first viewing. Its pace seemed strange, its flashbacks seemed oddly placed, its camera seemed to dwell on unimportant details and none of its characters seemed to exist to propel any clearly defined story forward. In other words, though I'd seen virtually every other Robert Altman film, "Kansas City" still left me in a state of bewilderment. But as is often the case with Altman, "Kansas City" began to make sense - in so far as Altman desires to make sense; his films seem to embrace a certain chaos - upon second viewing. Filled with loving shots of jazz musicians, the film is itself a jazzy tone poem, Altman coming at the audience from odd angles, asking us to pick up on his shifting rhythms of plot and character, themes of race, politics, violence and money. Consider the subtle juxtapositions Altman weaves into the film... A poor white man (Johnny O'Hara) paints his face black and robs a wealthy black man. Seeking assistance, the black man visits a powerful black crime boss called Seldom Seen. Seldom agrees to help, kidnaps Johnny and kills him. In contrast, Johnny's wife (Blondie O'Hara) kidnaps a wealthy white woman (Carolyn Stilton) while she applies a white beauty mask. Carolyn is married to Henry Stilton, a powerful politician. Blondie wants Henry to negotiate with the crime lord so that she may get her husband back. Blondie is eventually killed by Carolyn Stilton. While this drama is unfolding, other characters enter the mix. A young Charlie Parker, years away from musical fame, finds a pregnant black girl. He takes her to a maternity ward. Meanwhile, we learn that Blondie had her baby aborted because Johnny didn't want kids. Similarly, a poor black cab driver (who helped Johnny stage his robbery) is taken to a back alleyway and killed by Seldom and his gang. In contrast, Henry Stilton's goons kill a white man in broad daylight because he was hampering their efforts to falsify local election ballots. And so on and on it goes, Altman juxtaposing his jazz notes, "Kansas City" less a linear narrative than a series of contrasting sequences or oppositional musical riffs, some obvious, some subtle, but all revolving around class, race and gender. Blackface paint is mirrored to white beauty cream, black crime lords are mirrored to corrupt white politicians, political thugs are mirrored to violent gangsters, abortions are mirrored to pregnancies, loving marriages are mirrored to loveless couples, poverty is mirrored to power, underground gambling joints and brothels are mirrored to above ground poll booths and ballot stations. Blondie O'Hara, the young kidnapper, is herself contrasted with Carolyn Stilton, the woman she kidnaps. Blondie loves her husband and would do anything for him. Mrs Stilton, in contrast, is constantly doped up on opium and has long given up on her marriage. Furthermore, Blondie is constantly emulating Kansas City native Jean Harlow, an actress whom she idolises. This notion of "narrative emulation" is itself intended to mirror the "cutting contests" between the jazz musicians sprinkled throughout the film. Just as the musicians borrow from one another and weave each other's material into what they are improvising, Blondie borrows from the movies and weaves Harlow's tough girl phrases and expressions into her conversation. But Blondie's toughness is all a facade, a suit of armour used to compensate for her petite size and coarse environment. While Blondie gives up her child and is constantly subservient to her husband, it is Carolyn Stilton who possesses true strength. Despite her permanently doped up state, Carolyn constantly gives the impression that she knows more than she's letting on, always absorbing information and assessing her surroundings. Her final line, "I didn't vote", itself lets us know that she has long cut herself off from a venal world which she refuses to legitimize. And so with "Kansas City" - a film which ends with a crime lord counting money in the dark corners of a jazz club - Altman has abstracted the politics of power and persuasion, threat and privilege. Everything in the film hinges on social power, Altman drawing a clean line between those violent people who wield power and all those pathetic dreamers who try to grab it but never succeed in doing so for more than a fleeting moment. The political corruption of the city's democratic machine (the country was built on voting fraud and rigged elections; practises common even today), and the expanding influence of Hollywood (and the power of film to seduce and destroy people such as Blondie), is as important to Altman as the racial segregation that produces Kansas City's two worlds: the white world, dominated by the Stilton's, and the inverted black world of Seldom Seen, a vampiric world of music which seems to only come to life long after the surface world has gone to sleep. The film is also unique in the way it offers jazz music an unprecedented role within the diegetic world. This music is constantly "seeping into" he story, providing a kind of tapestry for the characters to perform against. The result is that the jazz music seems to become intertwined with the very social climate that influences it. Altman himself has said that it was his intention that jazz be the structure of the entire film. Whilst a typical song lasts 3 minutes, a jazz tune lasts as much as 17, the effect being that many of the film's scenes are elongated and purposefully stretched out. "Seldom Seen is like a brass instrument," Altman says, "when it's his turn to solo, he does long monologues and riffs. But the discussions of the two women are like reed instruments, saxophones having duets." 8/10 - Best appreciated as a kind of cinematic jazz, the plot lethargically frustrating as it intrigues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ....And All That Jazz
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Altman dishes up a terrific serving of jazz and Depression-era atmosphere in this crime thriller with film noir trappings. Jennifer Jason Leigh gives a fascinating and heartbreaking performance as Blondie, the pathetic Jean Harlow wannabe who kidnaps a senator's (Michael Murphy) wife (Miranda Richardson) in an attempt to force him into helping her husband, Johnny (Dermot Mulroney), who's himself been kidnapped by Seldom Seen (Harry Belafonte), a local gangster kingpin, after Johnny tried to pull a heist on one of Seldom's own. The dark plot works its way toward an inevitable and tragic ending, but as is true with many Altman films, what happens isn't as much fun as how it happens. Altman intersperses the film with segments of music being played in a hot jazz club, and the nearly constant soundtrack gives the whole movie the pulse and rhythm of the jazz numbers it's set to. I'm not so sure I liked the performance of Richardson. She plays a woman doped up on opiates, and while I don't know how someone would act in those circumstances, her performance felt cartoonish and exaggerated to me. But Leigh more than makes up for any weak performances, and she owns this film. Blondie is a born loser, a woman who's learned how to act tough from watching movies but who's not nearly tough enough to survive in the world around her. It's with a mixture of pity and relief that we see the film, and Blondie's fate, move toward its "They Shoot Horses, Don't They?" resolution. Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bonanza for jazz lovers - one of Mr Altman's more personal works
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ianlouisiana
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    God knows English politics is corrupt,but America seems to have raised duplicity to another level.Wheeling,dealing,threatening,bribing,snouts deep in the trough....I would have to be held at gunpoint before I'd vote for anybody.In the poor black Wards of Kansas City in the mid 1930s it doesn't matter who you vote for,your life is not going to get any better,the successful politico is just going to get richer. With a plot and characters remarkably similar to early Runyon,Mr Altman parallels the development of KC jazz with its turbulent social history. For lovers of Bennie Moten/Count Basie type music the movie is at least an aural treat;for the average moviegoer,"Kansas City" is very much a curate's egg. Unless you are at least familiar with Hawk,Pres,Bird and Jean Harlow your enjoyment of the movie may well be limited to the amount of admiration you have for Mr Altman's more personal work. With all due respect to the acting talent involved,no one apart from the much - maligned Miss J.J. Leigh has much to work with.As "Blondie" she has the only role that actually develops during the course of the film. In an era when movies were enormously influential her conscious morphing into a Jean Harlow persona is touching rather than laughable. With "Kansas City",Mr Altman continued to plough his lonely furrow.That it was not a great commercial success is hardly surprising,but admirers of maverick works will get pleasure from it.Jazz loving moviegoers,themselves to some degree mavericks,scouring the schedules in a usually vain attempt to satisfy both their Joneses,should seize the moment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Belafonte Fine, Music Even Better--But Central Miscasting Dooms It!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    museumofdave
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like the films of Orson Welles, Federico Fellini or Woody Allen, there's almost always a reason to watch, even if the completed whole doesn't quite add up to the sum of it's parts. Kansas City fits that bill for me. Altman weaves his usual rich tapestry of lives affected by history in a city alive with jazz and political chicanery, and Kansas City is worth watching for the unexpectedly mesmerizing performance by Harry Belafonte as "Seldom Seen," mobster boss. The jazz on display is equally dazzling, but just when your mind is settling into some rich, heady music, the film cuts back to the deadly, mannered, whiny performance turned in by Jennifer Jason Leigh; when most film fans recall the disaster that became Godfather III, the director's indulgence of the lackluster performance turned in by Sofia Coppola comes to mind; Leigh's performance similarly affects the tone of Kansas City, and since she is the protagonist, the film's interest flags with her director-free indulgence in some kind of method acting that fails to evoke much but self-indulgence. In short, Kansas City is well worth a look for superb mise-en-scene,for the music and atmosphere, but is deeply frustrating for it's central performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rich Textured Visuals
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lechuguilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A kidnapping and a robbery move the plot forward in a film that's less about plot than about cultural ambiance. "Kansas City" is mostly a cinematic expression of place and time. It's 1934, when gangsters and jazz ruled and Blacks and Whites went their separate ways. Visuals are very dark. And though the film is in color, tints are muted, which conveys a nostalgic, sentimental mood. The thin plot takes place largely at night. And the plot alternates with dark interior scenes at the Hey Hey Club, a risqu&eacute;, all-Black speakeasy where an all-Black band jives free-form jazz, and where illegal gambling fills the back rooms. None of the characters are sympathetic. But I don't think they're supposed to be. They're archetypes, models of desperate people in desperate times. A gun-wielding gangster's girl named Blondie (Jennifer Jason Leigh) wants to be like Jean Harlow. Mrs. Stilton (Miranda Richardson) is a wealthy, spaced-out politician's wife. Seldom Seen (based on a real-life person and played by Harry Belafonte) is the cigar smoking godfather who rules the dark, smoky Hey Hey Club with an iron fist and who likes to stand around giving lectures to people. The script's dialogue is mostly subtext, with message directed less at other characters than at viewers. And, as in other Altman films, then-current politics dance around the edges of the seedy story. The overall tone mixes depression with desperation. For me this is an easy film to judge. The characters and plot I cared for not at all. Jennifer Jason Leigh was painful to watch. And though the jazz is performed with great competence, its free-form, improvisational style is too contemporary to reflect the 1930s. On the other hand, Miranda Richardson gives a fine performance. Attention to detail in costumes, sets, props, and storefront exteriors make the film come alive with era realism. And lighting is absolutely terrific. If you go into this movie expecting a deep story and well-constructed plot, you'll be disappointed. Absorb the overall texture of the film's visuals. "Kansas City" is a terrific visual portrait of a specific place at a specific time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A depressing movie you should not watch when already depressed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here, Robert Altman attempts to do for Kansas City what William Kennedy did for Albany, New York. Sort of. Kennedy portrays the indefatigable Albany machine with a mix of cynicism, respect and love. In Ironweed we see more of the underbelly of the city, but even though a dark movie, there is a love for his O Albany. Altman's portrayal of Kansas City is dripping with cynicism, but lacks the love, and only offers the blackest of humor. What's worse, there are few likable characters. We spend most of the time watching two brainless women talking incoherently, one on drugs, the other with her teeth wired together. Yet Kansas City is still worth watching, if you are a serious film buff. Everyone, I assume, loves M*A*S*H (except, perhaps, for the Koreans, who do not have a sense of humor about their own country). Nashville and Gosford Park take a bit more savvy to appreciate, but if you understand them, you will know how to approach Kansas City. These Altman movies take an almost sociological-anthropological approach to their subjects, have strong portrayals of many characters, and more or less lack a plot or center, preferring a more naturalistic unfolding of events. Robert Altman is perhaps the greatest modern slice of life movie director. So don't focus so much on the story line as on the characters and their interactions. However, in Kansas City we are introduced to what we would expect to be more of an action movie, or at least a movie with a Hitchcock type plot. This is not what we get. And the first section consists of cutting back and forth among characters and scenes that do not bear much temporal relationship, which is confusing, and distracts from trying to focus on understanding the characters. Eventually, the movie assumes temporal normality, if not linearity. The music is absolutely outstanding. Much of it seems to accurately reproduce 1930s to early 1940s jazz, and seeing it performed in its natural setting of a nightclub gives you better insight into it than merely listening on a record, which gives it a more cerebral air. However, when truly great musicians like this were really cooking, I think the room would have been quieter, out of respect and interest; that's what I have read in some jazz musician memoirs. I was surprised by the atonality of some of the Count Basie riffs on the piano, not typical Basie style. Silver plated brass instruments would not have been common back then. And Charlie Parker never played a single note in the film, as he was pretty horrible when he was 14. There are no brave heroes in this movie. There was one clueless hero, the elections official, but he lasted for about 15 seconds, before being lines up against the wall and shot (although not realistic, perhaps key to the cinematic message). The musicians are the closest thing to nice guys in the movie, but they stay strictly in the barroom, holding aloof from corruption swirling around them, even while they see much of what is going on, as do most of the blacks. In short, Altman's Kansas City is as devoid of heroes as High Noon would be without Gary Cooper, or It's a Wonderful Life without Jimmy Stewart. Yeah, it's corrupt, but what are you going to do? Make the best of it by joining in, getting a piece of the action. (In reality, not everyone was corrupt, not even all Missouri politicians.) As to the portrayal of the Tom Pendergast political machine, I think Altman over does it. I sincerely doubt a political hack would pull out a gun in broad daylight in front of a polling place and shoot an elections official. Unnecessary and stupid, and sure to make the evening papers. The Pendergast machine was corrupt, but not stupid; the corruption focused on government contracts, from what I have read. The movie's strength is showing the different levels of society and how they interact, black working class, black mob, white political elite, white trash. Its other strength is reproducing the era in astonishingly rich detail. I love movies like this that get it right, and make you feel like you are being transported back in time. The acting is great, especially Harry Belafonte. Jennifer Jason Leigh gets on your nerves, big time, but does so convincingly. Spoiler alert: Near the end, Mrs. Stilton drops her medicine bottle on the ground. Your first thought is it was empty. Or she had decided to break her habit. But I suspect the real meaning, judging from her body language when she tosses the bottle down, is she was faking it, and wasn't so dependent on her "medicine." If you like this movie, try Ironweed, starring Jack Nicholson and Merle Streep. It's a better movie, but Kansas City has better jazz. The jazz, alone, is worth the price of admission.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vivid depiction of Kansas City, 1934
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tnrcooper
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having read all the reviews and seen the rating given this film by even more viewers, it would seem that many viewers are not au courant with the style of Jean Harlow and/or do not have the patience necessary to appreciate some films which do not move along at a quick clip. This would seem to be Altman's tribute to his hometown and to the period when he was a kid-he would have been 9 in 1934. Altman's take on the outre political corruption in Kansas City at that time would seem to be of a sort with the corruption facilitated by the Pendergras machine of the time. His depiction of black characters as autonomous, strong characters is refreshing. Harry Belafonte's mob boss Seldom Seen has to be one of the most ruthless characters seen on celluloid in recent years. Belafonte is at the top of his game, his smoky baritone all the more ominous for his low-key manner. Belafonte really deserved an Oscar nomination for his performance in this movie. One of the many aspects to recommend this film is the music that lit up Kansas City at that time-jazz. The music, featuring Lester Young, Coleman Hawkins, and even a very young Charlie Parker before he was a musician, is electric. The musicians-played by world-class musicians like Joshua Redman, David 'Fathead' Newman, and Christian McBride, electrify the scenes they are in, particularly in one duel which continues until daybreak. The musical scenes are truly magical and electric. We get a sense of the energy and vibrance in the Kansas City music scene at that time. Altman also tweaks notions of race by having white Johnny Flynn (an almost silent Dermot Mulroney) attempting to knock off a mob underling while wearing blackface. Altman considers race and is not afraid to depict and play around with it. The very fact that he is willing to consider its existence and status in society is interesting in itself. There are many black characters, many given great depth and range. Altman adds depth to our understanding of race and fleshes out depiction of people of color in ways that the vast majority of directors do not even acknowledge or consider. This makes the film valuable in and of itself. The film's plot revolves around the kidnapping of the Missouri governor's wife Caroline Stilson (Miranda Richardson) who is kidnapped to pressure the Governor to release Blondie's husband (Dermot Mulroney's Jonny Flynn) who has been caught after trying to rip off one of Seldom Seen's mob lieutenants. Blondie thinks that taking the governor's wife hostage will cause the governor to take the release of her husband more seriously. Some people don't like Jennifer Jason Leigh's performance in this movie, suggesting that it is difficult to understand her. I think that was intentional on her part-an effort to pay tribute to the work of Jean Harlow who was from Kansas City and who we see in a movie that Caroline and Blondie are watching. It's clear that Jean Harlow was attempting to depict a tougher veneer than she really had, as we see as Blondie's tough outer shell collapses as the movie progresses. I found it a very original, Oscar-worthy, performance. Miranda Richardson's depiction of a depressed, drug-addled, lonely political wife who ultimately turns out to know more than she lets on is very compelling. The chemistry between her and Leigh is electric and Richardson's role is very interesting. She delivers an excellent performance in an unusual role. Altman interweaves story lines-those of Seldom Seen and Jonny Flynn on the one hand, and Caroline Stilson and Blondie on the other-expertly-linking them effortlessly. This is one of Altman's greatest strengths-tying in disparate story lines and making connections where they might be less obvious to most filmmakers. Altman makes connections among figures where most directors wouldn't see them. I don't think this film is on the level of his tours de force in Gosford Park, Short Cuts, The Player, MASH, and Nashville, but Altman was always more about depicting a milieu and setting a scene and if his story did not have the pyrotechnics of some of many films in theaters at the time, he didn't care. This film smolders quietly, suggesting a city rotting from the inside out as evidenced by the political and criminal malfeasance which are so brazen in the picture. Altman tells rich, colorful stories and this one is no exception.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Altman With All That Jazz But It's A Little Bit Confusing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a new born to a new audience with excellent "The Player" and "Short Cuts" and slip down with the weird and unfunny "Pr&eacute;t-&agrave;-Porter", the master of the independent cinema Robert Altman gets back with a minor but interesting work in "Kansas City". Here, he reveals the dangerous Kansas City of the 1930's with their corrupt politicians, scary mobsters and people involved with all this world without noticing the danger right ahead. In the 1930's the young and beautiful Blondie (Jennifer Jason Leigh) kidnaps Carolyn (Miranda Richardson) the wife of a powerful politician (Michael Murphy) who can help her to save her boyfriend Johnny (Dermot Mulroney), a little burglar who stole an important big shot in the crime world, and now he's going to be killed by another powerful mob figure, the gangster Seldom Seen (Harry Belafonte). The frightened Carolyn is dragged away along with Blondie to several places in town, trying to get along with each other, which doesn't work quite well because of their different backgrounds. Blondie is addicted to the films of Jean Harlow and she keeps annoying her hostage all the way; while Carolyn is an addicted to opium that barely gets out of the house, suffering with her addiction. In the meantime the politician keeps dealing with the case, in a very discreet way to not ruin his future election that its getting ahead and because of his proximity with President Roosevelt. On the other part of town, Johnny has the chance to know more about what the real world of crime really is, listening to Seldom's menacing stories and to lots of jazz that is played in his captivity. Besides these two kidnaps there's a subplot concerning a girl who came to town to get an abortion and a political scandal involving a party which is buying votes to win the election using of deadly tactics. The same team of writers who signed "Short Cuts" tries to unite several characters that follow the same path in several situations having as link the jazz as musical background played in almost every scene. As I said, they tried to unite them but they end up confusing the public by dividing two situations, apparently disconnected, that will meet in the end, and until it get to the final result you keep wondering what's the reason for both kidnaps. When the two parts get together it all makes sense but before some answers appear many will have walked away of the movie because everything is slow, almost tedious. The perfect "Short Cuts" which tells the story of 23 characters crossing the way of each other in a chaotic Los Angeles, in a excellent tragicomedy of the real life, gets way better than "Kansas City" with their 6 main characters. On the other hand this confusion in dividing the film in two situations makes a intriguing film that makes the audience wants to know of what happens next. As favorable points, "Kansas City" has a great period reconstitution, the costumes of the 1930's, the old cars; the music (Altman worked the same musicians who appeared in his documentary "Jazz 34"); and a great performance by Harry Belafonte as the talking gangster who has an answer to everything. Michael Murphy surprises a lot in his short moments in which he appears; the other performances are not so interesting, sometimes they are very annoying, and that is the case of the main pair. Jennifer Jason Leigh's voice is tiring and very debauched for a dramatic film; Miranda Richardson has a very aloof character, a role that she would dominate better in the great "Falling Angels". Robert Altman made a good job despite not being too much impressive as his previous works. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh the pain, the pain. Is it over yet?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rodney_h
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm sorry but this movie was pitiful. I hated it. KC is S-L-O-W, B-O-R-I-N-G, crap. The dialog was laughable, trite and completely unbelievable. This is a bland thirty-minute short story stretched out to almost two painfully excruciating hours. The only good qualities in this waste of celluloid were 1. Great costumes and 2. Fabulous period cars. Where did they get all of those great old cars? CAUTION - This film is for jazz lovers only....and I hate jazz. How bad can it be? If YOU like this crap-fest, then help yourself to my DVD copy. I threw my disk in the trash. It'll be out at the county dump by now (where it belongs). 1 star out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lost somewhere between the 1930s and 1990s.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Altman's Kansas City is not a terrible movie by any stretch of the imagination and for any other director it would be a minor triumph. Yet, given the pedigree he has provided for himself, particularly with films such as MASH, McCabe & Mrs. Miller, Nashville and 3 Women on his resume, I hold his films to a higher order than most. Perhaps for that reason most of all, I was quite disappointed by this outcome. Jennifer Jason Leigh and Miranda Richardson star as small-time hoodlum and rich politician's wives, respectively, with Leigh taking Richardson hostage in hope that her husband will be released by the notorious gangster Seldom Seen. However, all this is simply a contrivance for what Altman is really after, which seems to me to be the context and feeling of the city of Kansas City in the 1930s when Jean Harlow movies played in the local cinemas and voting was a high-stakes gamble that if gone wrong had very serious consequences. In terms of the film itself, I would consider this film to suffer from the Hudsucker Proxy syndrome: it looks fantastic with the sets and costumes all perfectly realizing the era in which it attempts to capture. Yet, the story is almost thrown together with really not attempt to clarify or make known exactly what is happening. I understand this is Altman's style, particularly for this film, but in order to string the movie along and maintain audience interest, it certainly would have helped to include a more cohesive story line. Also, Jennifer Jason Leigh doesn't fit this part in my opinion, coming off more annoying and self-conscious than sympathetic and interestingly quirky. Her dialogue and delivery seem to come right out of the 1990s and have almost no place in the setting of the rest of the characters. I admire Altman as a director too much to call this film a disaster but it is by far the weakest of all his films I have seen and makes me question why he decided to make this film. Perhaps because he grew up in Kansas City in the 1930s or he felt interested in gangsters, jazz and the setting of a growing town prior to World War II. Whatever the reason, I was frequently out of touch with the story and can really give no compelling reason to seek it out as one of Altman's finer works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Celluloid Jazz
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "You know what I didn't do today? I didn't vote."  Carolyn Stilton I absolutely hated "Kansas City" upon first viewing. Its pace seemed strange, its flashbacks seemed oddly placed, its camera seemed to dwell on unimportant details and none of its characters seemed to exist to propel any clearly defined story forward. In other words, though I'd seen virtually every other Robert Altman film, "Kansas City" still left me in a state of bewilderment. But as is often the case with Altman, "Kansas City" began to make sense - in so far as Altman desires to make sense; his films seem to embrace a certain chaos - upon second viewing. Filled with loving shots of jazz musicians, the film is itself a jazzy tone poem, Altman coming at the audience from odd angles, asking us to pick up on his shifting rhythms of plot and character, themes of race, politics, violence and money. Consider the subtle juxtapositions Altman weaves into the film... A poor white man (Johnny O'Hara) paints his face black and robs a wealthy black man. Seeking assistance, the black man visits a powerful black crime boss called Seldom Seen. Seldom agrees to help, kidnaps Johnny and kills him. In contrast, Johnny's wife (Blondie O'Hara) kidnaps a wealthy white woman (Carolyn Stilton) while she applies a white beauty mask. Carolyn is married to Henry Stilton, a powerful politician. Blondie wants Henry to negotiate with the crime lord so that she may get her husband back. Blondie is eventually killed by Carolyn Stilton. While this drama is unfolding, other characters enter the mix. A young Charlie Parker, years away from musical fame, finds a pregnant black girl. He takes her to a maternity ward. Meanwhile, we learn that Blondie had her baby aborted because Johnny didn't want kids. Similarly, a poor black cab driver (who helped Johnny stage his robbery) is taken to a back alleyway and killed by Seldom and his gang. In contrast, Henry Stilton's goons kill a white man in broad daylight because he was hampering their efforts to falsify local election ballots. And so on and on it goes, Altman juxtaposing his jazz notes, "Kansas City" less a linear narrative than a series of contrasting sequences or oppositional musical riffs, some obvious, some subtle, but all revolving around class, race and gender. Blackface paint is mirrored to white beauty cream, black crime lords are mirrored to corrupt white politicians, political thugs are mirrored to violent gangsters, abortions are mirrored to pregnancies, loving marriages are mirrored to loveless couples, poverty is mirrored to power, underground gambling joints and brothels are mirrored to above ground poll booths and ballot stations. Blondie O'Hara, the young kidnapper, is herself contrasted with Carolyn Stilton, the woman she kidnaps. Blondie loves her husband and would do anything for him. Mrs Stilton, in contrast, is constantly doped up on opium and has long given up on her marriage. Furthermore, Blondie is constantly emulating Kansas City native Jean Harlow, an actress whom she idolises. This notion of "narrative emulation" is itself intended to mirror the "cutting contests" between the jazz musicians sprinkled throughout the film. Just as the musicians borrow from one another and weave each other's material into what they are improvising, Blondie borrows from the movies and weaves Harlow's tough girl phrases and expressions into her conversation. But Blondie's toughness is all a facade, a suit of armour used to compensate for her petite size and coarse environment. While Blondie gives up her child and is constantly subservient to her husband, it is Carolyn Stilton who possesses true strength. Despite her permanently doped up state, Carolyn constantly gives the impression that she knows more than she's letting on, always absorbing information and assessing her surroundings. Her final line, "I didn't vote", itself lets us know that she has long cut herself off from a venal world which she refuses to legitimize. And so with "Kansas City" - a film which ends with a crime lord counting money in the dark corners of a jazz club - Altman has abstracted the politics of power and persuasion, threat and privilege. Everything in the film hinges on social power, Altman drawing a clean line between those violent people who wield power and all those pathetic dreamers who try to grab it but never succeed in doing so for more than a fleeting moment. The political corruption of the city's democratic machine (the country was built on voting fraud and rigged elections; practises common even today), and the expanding influence of Hollywood (and the power of film to seduce and destroy people such as Blondie), is as important to Altman as the racial segregation that produces Kansas City's two worlds: the white world, dominated by the Stilton's, and the inverted black world of Seldom Seen, a vampiric world of music which seems to only come to life long after the surface world has gone to sleep. The film is also unique in the way it offers jazz music an unprecedented role within the diegetic world. This music is constantly "seeping into" he story, providing a kind of tapestry for the characters to perform against. The result is that the jazz music seems to become intertwined with the very social climate that influences it. Altman himself has said that it was his intention that jazz be the structure of the entire film. Whilst a typical song lasts 3 minutes, a jazz tune lasts as much as 17, the effect being that many of the film's scenes are elongated and purposefully stretched out. "Seldom Seen is like a brass instrument," Altman says, "when it's his turn to solo, he does long monologues and riffs. But the discussions of the two women are like reed instruments, saxophones having duets." 8/10 - Best appreciated as a kind of cinematic jazz, the plot lethargically frustrating as it intrigues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ....And All That Jazz
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Altman dishes up a terrific serving of jazz and Depression-era atmosphere in this crime thriller with film noir trappings. Jennifer Jason Leigh gives a fascinating and heartbreaking performance as Blondie, the pathetic Jean Harlow wannabe who kidnaps a senator's (Michael Murphy) wife (Miranda Richardson) in an attempt to force him into helping her husband, Johnny (Dermot Mulroney), who's himself been kidnapped by Seldom Seen (Harry Belafonte), a local gangster kingpin, after Johnny tried to pull a heist on one of Seldom's own. The dark plot works its way toward an inevitable and tragic ending, but as is true with many Altman films, what happens isn't as much fun as how it happens. Altman intersperses the film with segments of music being played in a hot jazz club, and the nearly constant soundtrack gives the whole movie the pulse and rhythm of the jazz numbers it's set to. I'm not so sure I liked the performance of Richardson. She plays a woman doped up on opiates, and while I don't know how someone would act in those circumstances, her performance felt cartoonish and exaggerated to me. But Leigh more than makes up for any weak performances, and she owns this film. Blondie is a born loser, a woman who's learned how to act tough from watching movies but who's not nearly tough enough to survive in the world around her. It's with a mixture of pity and relief that we see the film, and Blondie's fate, move toward its "They Shoot Horses, Don't They?" resolution. Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bonanza for jazz lovers - one of Mr Altman's more personal works
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ianlouisiana
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    God knows English politics is corrupt,but America seems to have raised duplicity to another level.Wheeling,dealing,threatening,bribing,snouts deep in the trough....I would have to be held at gunpoint before I'd vote for anybody.In the poor black Wards of Kansas City in the mid 1930s it doesn't matter who you vote for,your life is not going to get any better,the successful politico is just going to get richer. With a plot and characters remarkably similar to early Runyon,Mr Altman parallels the development of KC jazz with its turbulent social history. For lovers of Bennie Moten/Count Basie type music the movie is at least an aural treat;for the average moviegoer,"Kansas City" is very much a curate's egg. Unless you are at least familiar with Hawk,Pres,Bird and Jean Harlow your enjoyment of the movie may well be limited to the amount of admiration you have for Mr Altman's more personal work. With all due respect to the acting talent involved,no one apart from the much - maligned Miss J.J. Leigh has much to work with.As "Blondie" she has the only role that actually develops during the course of the film. In an era when movies were enormously influential her conscious morphing into a Jean Harlow persona is touching rather than laughable. With "Kansas City",Mr Altman continued to plough his lonely furrow.That it was not a great commercial success is hardly surprising,but admirers of maverick works will get pleasure from it.Jazz loving moviegoers,themselves to some degree mavericks,scouring the schedules in a usually vain attempt to satisfy both their Joneses,should seize the moment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Belafonte Fine, Music Even Better--But Central Miscasting Dooms It!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    museumofdave
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like the films of Orson Welles, Federico Fellini or Woody Allen, there's almost always a reason to watch, even if the completed whole doesn't quite add up to the sum of it's parts. Kansas City fits that bill for me. Altman weaves his usual rich tapestry of lives affected by history in a city alive with jazz and political chicanery, and Kansas City is worth watching for the unexpectedly mesmerizing performance by Harry Belafonte as "Seldom Seen," mobster boss. The jazz on display is equally dazzling, but just when your mind is settling into some rich, heady music, the film cuts back to the deadly, mannered, whiny performance turned in by Jennifer Jason Leigh; when most film fans recall the disaster that became Godfather III, the director's indulgence of the lackluster performance turned in by Sofia Coppola comes to mind; Leigh's performance similarly affects the tone of Kansas City, and since she is the protagonist, the film's interest flags with her director-free indulgence in some kind of method acting that fails to evoke much but self-indulgence. In short, Kansas City is well worth a look for superb mise-en-scene,for the music and atmosphere, but is deeply frustrating for it's central performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rich Textured Visuals
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lechuguilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A kidnapping and a robbery move the plot forward in a film that's less about plot than about cultural ambiance. "Kansas City" is mostly a cinematic expression of place and time. It's 1934, when gangsters and jazz ruled and Blacks and Whites went their separate ways. Visuals are very dark. And though the film is in color, tints are muted, which conveys a nostalgic, sentimental mood. The thin plot takes place largely at night. And the plot alternates with dark interior scenes at the Hey Hey Club, a risqu&eacute;, all-Black speakeasy where an all-Black band jives free-form jazz, and where illegal gambling fills the back rooms. None of the characters are sympathetic. But I don't think they're supposed to be. They're archetypes, models of desperate people in desperate times. A gun-wielding gangster's girl named Blondie (Jennifer Jason Leigh) wants to be like Jean Harlow. Mrs. Stilton (Miranda Richardson) is a wealthy, spaced-out politician's wife. Seldom Seen (based on a real-life person and played by Harry Belafonte) is the cigar smoking godfather who rules the dark, smoky Hey Hey Club with an iron fist and who likes to stand around giving lectures to people. The script's dialogue is mostly subtext, with message directed less at other characters than at viewers. And, as in other Altman films, then-current politics dance around the edges of the seedy story. The overall tone mixes depression with desperation. For me this is an easy film to judge. The characters and plot I cared for not at all. Jennifer Jason Leigh was painful to watch. And though the jazz is performed with great competence, its free-form, improvisational style is too contemporary to reflect the 1930s. On the other hand, Miranda Richardson gives a fine performance. Attention to detail in costumes, sets, props, and storefront exteriors make the film come alive with era realism. And lighting is absolutely terrific. If you go into this movie expecting a deep story and well-constructed plot, you'll be disappointed. Absorb the overall texture of the film's visuals. "Kansas City" is a terrific visual portrait of a specific place at a specific time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A depressing movie you should not watch when already depressed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here, Robert Altman attempts to do for Kansas City what William Kennedy did for Albany, New York. Sort of. Kennedy portrays the indefatigable Albany machine with a mix of cynicism, respect and love. In Ironweed we see more of the underbelly of the city, but even though a dark movie, there is a love for his O Albany. Altman's portrayal of Kansas City is dripping with cynicism, but lacks the love, and only offers the blackest of humor. What's worse, there are few likable characters. We spend most of the time watching two brainless women talking incoherently, one on drugs, the other with her teeth wired together. Yet Kansas City is still worth watching, if you are a serious film buff. Everyone, I assume, loves M*A*S*H (except, perhaps, for the Koreans, who do not have a sense of humor about their own country). Nashville and Gosford Park take a bit more savvy to appreciate, but if you understand them, you will know how to approach Kansas City. These Altman movies take an almost sociological-anthropological approach to their subjects, have strong portrayals of many characters, and more or less lack a plot or center, preferring a more naturalistic unfolding of events. Robert Altman is perhaps the greatest modern slice of life movie director. So don't focus so much on the story line as on the characters and their interactions. However, in Kansas City we are introduced to what we would expect to be more of an action movie, or at least a movie with a Hitchcock type plot. This is not what we get. And the first section consists of cutting back and forth among characters and scenes that do not bear much temporal relationship, which is confusing, and distracts from trying to focus on understanding the characters. Eventually, the movie assumes temporal normality, if not linearity. The music is absolutely outstanding. Much of it seems to accurately reproduce 1930s to early 1940s jazz, and seeing it performed in its natural setting of a nightclub gives you better insight into it than merely listening on a record, which gives it a more cerebral air. However, when truly great musicians like this were really cooking, I think the room would have been quieter, out of respect and interest; that's what I have read in some jazz musician memoirs. I was surprised by the atonality of some of the Count Basie riffs on the piano, not typical Basie style. Silver plated brass instruments would not have been common back then. And Charlie Parker never played a single note in the film, as he was pretty horrible when he was 14. There are no brave heroes in this movie. There was one clueless hero, the elections official, but he lasted for about 15 seconds, before being lines up against the wall and shot (although not realistic, perhaps key to the cinematic message). The musicians are the closest thing to nice guys in the movie, but they stay strictly in the barroom, holding aloof from corruption swirling around them, even while they see much of what is going on, as do most of the blacks. In short, Altman's Kansas City is as devoid of heroes as High Noon would be without Gary Cooper, or It's a Wonderful Life without Jimmy Stewart. Yeah, it's corrupt, but what are you going to do? Make the best of it by joining in, getting a piece of the action. (In reality, not everyone was corrupt, not even all Missouri politicians.) As to the portrayal of the Tom Pendergast political machine, I think Altman over does it. I sincerely doubt a political hack would pull out a gun in broad daylight in front of a polling place and shoot an elections official. Unnecessary and stupid, and sure to make the evening papers. The Pendergast machine was corrupt, but not stupid; the corruption focused on government contracts, from what I have read. The movie's strength is showing the different levels of society and how they interact, black working class, black mob, white political elite, white trash. Its other strength is reproducing the era in astonishingly rich detail. I love movies like this that get it right, and make you feel like you are being transported back in time. The acting is great, especially Harry Belafonte. Jennifer Jason Leigh gets on your nerves, big time, but does so convincingly. Spoiler alert: Near the end, Mrs. Stilton drops her medicine bottle on the ground. Your first thought is it was empty. Or she had decided to break her habit. But I suspect the real meaning, judging from her body language when she tosses the bottle down, is she was faking it, and wasn't so dependent on her "medicine." If you like this movie, try Ironweed, starring Jack Nicholson and Merle Streep. It's a better movie, but Kansas City has better jazz. The jazz, alone, is worth the price of admission.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vivid depiction of Kansas City, 1934
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tnrcooper
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having read all the reviews and seen the rating given this film by even more viewers, it would seem that many viewers are not au courant with the style of Jean Harlow and/or do not have the patience necessary to appreciate some films which do not move along at a quick clip. This would seem to be Altman's tribute to his hometown and to the period when he was a kid-he would have been 9 in 1934. Altman's take on the outre political corruption in Kansas City at that time would seem to be of a sort with the corruption facilitated by the Pendergras machine of the time. His depiction of black characters as autonomous, strong characters is refreshing. Harry Belafonte's mob boss Seldom Seen has to be one of the most ruthless characters seen on celluloid in recent years. Belafonte is at the top of his game, his smoky baritone all the more ominous for his low-key manner. Belafonte really deserved an Oscar nomination for his performance in this movie. One of the many aspects to recommend this film is the music that lit up Kansas City at that time-jazz. The music, featuring Lester Young, Coleman Hawkins, and even a very young Charlie Parker before he was a musician, is electric. The musicians-played by world-class musicians like Joshua Redman, David 'Fathead' Newman, and Christian McBride, electrify the scenes they are in, particularly in one duel which continues until daybreak. The musical scenes are truly magical and electric. We get a sense of the energy and vibrance in the Kansas City music scene at that time. Altman also tweaks notions of race by having white Johnny Flynn (an almost silent Dermot Mulroney) attempting to knock off a mob underling while wearing blackface. Altman considers race and is not afraid to depict and play around with it. The very fact that he is willing to consider its existence and status in society is interesting in itself. There are many black characters, many given great depth and range. Altman adds depth to our understanding of race and fleshes out depiction of people of color in ways that the vast majority of directors do not even acknowledge or consider. This makes the film valuable in and of itself. The film's plot revolves around the kidnapping of the Missouri governor's wife Caroline Stilson (Miranda Richardson) who is kidnapped to pressure the Governor to release Blondie's husband (Dermot Mulroney's Jonny Flynn) who has been caught after trying to rip off one of Seldom Seen's mob lieutenants. Blondie thinks that taking the governor's wife hostage will cause the governor to take the release of her husband more seriously. Some people don't like Jennifer Jason Leigh's performance in this movie, suggesting that it is difficult to understand her. I think that was intentional on her part-an effort to pay tribute to the work of Jean Harlow who was from Kansas City and who we see in a movie that Caroline and Blondie are watching. It's clear that Jean Harlow was attempting to depict a tougher veneer than she really had, as we see as Blondie's tough outer shell collapses as the movie progresses. I found it a very original, Oscar-worthy, performance. Miranda Richardson's depiction of a depressed, drug-addled, lonely political wife who ultimately turns out to know more than she lets on is very compelling. The chemistry between her and Leigh is electric and Richardson's role is very interesting. She delivers an excellent performance in an unusual role. Altman interweaves story lines-those of Seldom Seen and Jonny Flynn on the one hand, and Caroline Stilson and Blondie on the other-expertly-linking them effortlessly. This is one of Altman's greatest strengths-tying in disparate story lines and making connections where they might be less obvious to most filmmakers. Altman makes connections among figures where most directors wouldn't see them. I don't think this film is on the level of his tours de force in Gosford Park, Short Cuts, The Player, MASH, and Nashville, but Altman was always more about depicting a milieu and setting a scene and if his story did not have the pyrotechnics of some of many films in theaters at the time, he didn't care. This film smolders quietly, suggesting a city rotting from the inside out as evidenced by the political and criminal malfeasance which are so brazen in the picture. Altman tells rich, colorful stories and this one is no exception.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Altman With All That Jazz But It's A Little Bit Confusing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a new born to a new audience with excellent "The Player" and "Short Cuts" and slip down with the weird and unfunny "Pr&eacute;t-&agrave;-Porter", the master of the independent cinema Robert Altman gets back with a minor but interesting work in "Kansas City". Here, he reveals the dangerous Kansas City of the 1930's with their corrupt politicians, scary mobsters and people involved with all this world without noticing the danger right ahead. In the 1930's the young and beautiful Blondie (Jennifer Jason Leigh) kidnaps Carolyn (Miranda Richardson) the wife of a powerful politician (Michael Murphy) who can help her to save her boyfriend Johnny (Dermot Mulroney), a little burglar who stole an important big shot in the crime world, and now he's going to be killed by another powerful mob figure, the gangster Seldom Seen (Harry Belafonte). The frightened Carolyn is dragged away along with Blondie to several places in town, trying to get along with each other, which doesn't work quite well because of their different backgrounds. Blondie is addicted to the films of Jean Harlow and she keeps annoying her hostage all the way; while Carolyn is an addicted to opium that barely gets out of the house, suffering with her addiction. In the meantime the politician keeps dealing with the case, in a very discreet way to not ruin his future election that its getting ahead and because of his proximity with President Roosevelt. On the other part of town, Johnny has the chance to know more about what the real world of crime really is, listening to Seldom's menacing stories and to lots of jazz that is played in his captivity. Besides these two kidnaps there's a subplot concerning a girl who came to town to get an abortion and a political scandal involving a party which is buying votes to win the election using of deadly tactics. The same team of writers who signed "Short Cuts" tries to unite several characters that follow the same path in several situations having as link the jazz as musical background played in almost every scene. As I said, they tried to unite them but they end up confusing the public by dividing two situations, apparently disconnected, that will meet in the end, and until it get to the final result you keep wondering what's the reason for both kidnaps. When the two parts get together it all makes sense but before some answers appear many will have walked away of the movie because everything is slow, almost tedious. The perfect "Short Cuts" which tells the story of 23 characters crossing the way of each other in a chaotic Los Angeles, in a excellent tragicomedy of the real life, gets way better than "Kansas City" with their 6 main characters. On the other hand this confusion in dividing the film in two situations makes a intriguing film that makes the audience wants to know of what happens next. As favorable points, "Kansas City" has a great period reconstitution, the costumes of the 1930's, the old cars; the music (Altman worked the same musicians who appeared in his documentary "Jazz 34"); and a great performance by Harry Belafonte as the talking gangster who has an answer to everything. Michael Murphy surprises a lot in his short moments in which he appears; the other performances are not so interesting, sometimes they are very annoying, and that is the case of the main pair. Jennifer Jason Leigh's voice is tiring and very debauched for a dramatic film; Miranda Richardson has a very aloof character, a role that she would dominate better in the great "Falling Angels". Robert Altman made a good job despite not being too much impressive as his previous works. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh the pain, the pain. Is it over yet?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rodney_h
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm sorry but this movie was pitiful. I hated it. KC is S-L-O-W, B-O-R-I-N-G, crap. The dialog was laughable, trite and completely unbelievable. This is a bland thirty-minute short story stretched out to almost two painfully excruciating hours. The only good qualities in this waste of celluloid were 1. Great costumes and 2. Fabulous period cars. Where did they get all of those great old cars? CAUTION - This film is for jazz lovers only....and I hate jazz. How bad can it be? If YOU like this crap-fest, then help yourself to my DVD copy. I threw my disk in the trash. It'll be out at the county dump by now (where it belongs). 1 star out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lost somewhere between the 1930s and 1990s.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Altman's Kansas City is not a terrible movie by any stretch of the imagination and for any other director it would be a minor triumph. Yet, given the pedigree he has provided for himself, particularly with films such as MASH, McCabe & Mrs. Miller, Nashville and 3 Women on his resume, I hold his films to a higher order than most. Perhaps for that reason most of all, I was quite disappointed by this outcome. Jennifer Jason Leigh and Miranda Richardson star as small-time hoodlum and rich politician's wives, respectively, with Leigh taking Richardson hostage in hope that her husband will be released by the notorious gangster Seldom Seen. However, all this is simply a contrivance for what Altman is really after, which seems to me to be the context and feeling of the city of Kansas City in the 1930s when Jean Harlow movies played in the local cinemas and voting was a high-stakes gamble that if gone wrong had very serious consequences. In terms of the film itself, I would consider this film to suffer from the Hudsucker Proxy syndrome: it looks fantastic with the sets and costumes all perfectly realizing the era in which it attempts to capture. Yet, the story is almost thrown together with really not attempt to clarify or make known exactly what is happening. I understand this is Altman's style, particularly for this film, but in order to string the movie along and maintain audience interest, it certainly would have helped to include a more cohesive story line. Also, Jennifer Jason Leigh doesn't fit this part in my opinion, coming off more annoying and self-conscious than sympathetic and interestingly quirky. Her dialogue and delivery seem to come right out of the 1990s and have almost no place in the setting of the rest of the characters. I admire Altman as a director too much to call this film a disaster but it is by far the weakest of all his films I have seen and makes me question why he decided to make this film. Perhaps because he grew up in Kansas City in the 1930s or he felt interested in gangsters, jazz and the setting of a growing town prior to World War II. Whatever the reason, I was frequently out of touch with the story and can really give no compelling reason to seek it out as one of Altman's finer works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Celluloid Jazz
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "You know what I didn't do today? I didn't vote."  Carolyn Stilton I absolutely hated "Kansas City" upon first viewing. Its pace seemed strange, its flashbacks seemed oddly placed, its camera seemed to dwell on unimportant details and none of its characters seemed to exist to propel any clearly defined story forward. In other words, though I'd seen virtually every other Robert Altman film, "Kansas City" still left me in a state of bewilderment. But as is often the case with Altman, "Kansas City" began to make sense - in so far as Altman desires to make sense; his films seem to embrace a certain chaos - upon second viewing. Filled with loving shots of jazz musicians, the film is itself a jazzy tone poem, Altman coming at the audience from odd angles, asking us to pick up on his shifting rhythms of plot and character, themes of race, politics, violence and money. Consider the subtle juxtapositions Altman weaves into the film... A poor white man (Johnny O'Hara) paints his face black and robs a wealthy black man. Seeking assistance, the black man visits a powerful black crime boss called Seldom Seen. Seldom agrees to help, kidnaps Johnny and kills him. In contrast, Johnny's wife (Blondie O'Hara) kidnaps a wealthy white woman (Carolyn Stilton) while she applies a white beauty mask. Carolyn is married to Henry Stilton, a powerful politician. Blondie wants Henry to negotiate with the crime lord so that she may get her husband back. Blondie is eventually killed by Carolyn Stilton. While this drama is unfolding, other characters enter the mix. A young Charlie Parker, years away from musical fame, finds a pregnant black girl. He takes her to a maternity ward. Meanwhile, we learn that Blondie had her baby aborted because Johnny didn't want kids. Similarly, a poor black cab driver (who helped Johnny stage his robbery) is taken to a back alleyway and killed by Seldom and his gang. In contrast, Henry Stilton's goons kill a white man in broad daylight because he was hampering their efforts to falsify local election ballots. And so on and on it goes, Altman juxtaposing his jazz notes, "Kansas City" less a linear narrative than a series of contrasting sequences or oppositional musical riffs, some obvious, some subtle, but all revolving around class, race and gender. Blackface paint is mirrored to white beauty cream, black crime lords are mirrored to corrupt white politicians, political thugs are mirrored to violent gangsters, abortions are mirrored to pregnancies, loving marriages are mirrored to loveless couples, poverty is mirrored to power, underground gambling joints and brothels are mirrored to above ground poll booths and ballot stations. Blondie O'Hara, the young kidnapper, is herself contrasted with Carolyn Stilton, the woman she kidnaps. Blondie loves her husband and would do anything for him. Mrs Stilton, in contrast, is constantly doped up on opium and has long given up on her marriage. Furthermore, Blondie is constantly emulating Kansas City native Jean Harlow, an actress whom she idolises. This notion of "narrative emulation" is itself intended to mirror the "cutting contests" between the jazz musicians sprinkled throughout the film. Just as the musicians borrow from one another and weave each other's material into what they are improvising, Blondie borrows from the movies and weaves Harlow's tough girl phrases and expressions into her conversation. But Blondie's toughness is all a facade, a suit of armour used to compensate for her petite size and coarse environment. While Blondie gives up her child and is constantly subservient to her husband, it is Carolyn Stilton who possesses true strength. Despite her permanently doped up state, Carolyn constantly gives the impression that she knows more than she's letting on, always absorbing information and assessing her surroundings. Her final line, "I didn't vote", itself lets us know that she has long cut herself off from a venal world which she refuses to legitimize. And so with "Kansas City" - a film which ends with a crime lord counting money in the dark corners of a jazz club - Altman has abstracted the politics of power and persuasion, threat and privilege. Everything in the film hinges on social power, Altman drawing a clean line between those violent people who wield power and all those pathetic dreamers who try to grab it but never succeed in doing so for more than a fleeting moment. The political corruption of the city's democratic machine (the country was built on voting fraud and rigged elections; practises common even today), and the expanding influence of Hollywood (and the power of film to seduce and destroy people such as Blondie), is as important to Altman as the racial segregation that produces Kansas City's two worlds: the white world, dominated by the Stilton's, and the inverted black world of Seldom Seen, a vampiric world of music which seems to only come to life long after the surface world has gone to sleep. The film is also unique in the way it offers jazz music an unprecedented role within the diegetic world. This music is constantly "seeping into" he story, providing a kind of tapestry for the characters to perform against. The result is that the jazz music seems to become intertwined with the very social climate that influences it. Altman himself has said that it was his intention that jazz be the structure of the entire film. Whilst a typical song lasts 3 minutes, a jazz tune lasts as much as 17, the effect being that many of the film's scenes are elongated and purposefully stretched out. "Seldom Seen is like a brass instrument," Altman says, "when it's his turn to solo, he does long monologues and riffs. But the discussions of the two women are like reed instruments, saxophones having duets." 8/10 - Best appreciated as a kind of cinematic jazz, the plot lethargically frustrating as it intrigues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ....And All That Jazz
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Altman dishes up a terrific serving of jazz and Depression-era atmosphere in this crime thriller with film noir trappings. Jennifer Jason Leigh gives a fascinating and heartbreaking performance as Blondie, the pathetic Jean Harlow wannabe who kidnaps a senator's (Michael Murphy) wife (Miranda Richardson) in an attempt to force him into helping her husband, Johnny (Dermot Mulroney), who's himself been kidnapped by Seldom Seen (Harry Belafonte), a local gangster kingpin, after Johnny tried to pull a heist on one of Seldom's own. The dark plot works its way toward an inevitable and tragic ending, but as is true with many Altman films, what happens isn't as much fun as how it happens. Altman intersperses the film with segments of music being played in a hot jazz club, and the nearly constant soundtrack gives the whole movie the pulse and rhythm of the jazz numbers it's set to. I'm not so sure I liked the performance of Richardson. She plays a woman doped up on opiates, and while I don't know how someone would act in those circumstances, her performance felt cartoonish and exaggerated to me. But Leigh more than makes up for any weak performances, and she owns this film. Blondie is a born loser, a woman who's learned how to act tough from watching movies but who's not nearly tough enough to survive in the world around her. It's with a mixture of pity and relief that we see the film, and Blondie's fate, move toward its "They Shoot Horses, Don't They?" resolution. Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bonanza for jazz lovers - one of Mr Altman's more personal works
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ianlouisiana
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    God knows English politics is corrupt,but America seems to have raised duplicity to another level.Wheeling,dealing,threatening,bribing,snouts deep in the trough....I would have to be held at gunpoint before I'd vote for anybody.In the poor black Wards of Kansas City in the mid 1930s it doesn't matter who you vote for,your life is not going to get any better,the successful politico is just going to get richer. With a plot and characters remarkably similar to early Runyon,Mr Altman parallels the development of KC jazz with its turbulent social history. For lovers of Bennie Moten/Count Basie type music the movie is at least an aural treat;for the average moviegoer,"Kansas City" is very much a curate's egg. Unless you are at least familiar with Hawk,Pres,Bird and Jean Harlow your enjoyment of the movie may well be limited to the amount of admiration you have for Mr Altman's more personal work. With all due respect to the acting talent involved,no one apart from the much - maligned Miss J.J. Leigh has much to work with.As "Blondie" she has the only role that actually develops during the course of the film. In an era when movies were enormously influential her conscious morphing into a Jean Harlow persona is touching rather than laughable. With "Kansas City",Mr Altman continued to plough his lonely furrow.That it was not a great commercial success is hardly surprising,but admirers of maverick works will get pleasure from it.Jazz loving moviegoers,themselves to some degree mavericks,scouring the schedules in a usually vain attempt to satisfy both their Joneses,should seize the moment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Belafonte Fine, Music Even Better--But Central Miscasting Dooms It!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    museumofdave
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like the films of Orson Welles, Federico Fellini or Woody Allen, there's almost always a reason to watch, even if the completed whole doesn't quite add up to the sum of it's parts. Kansas City fits that bill for me. Altman weaves his usual rich tapestry of lives affected by history in a city alive with jazz and political chicanery, and Kansas City is worth watching for the unexpectedly mesmerizing performance by Harry Belafonte as "Seldom Seen," mobster boss. The jazz on display is equally dazzling, but just when your mind is settling into some rich, heady music, the film cuts back to the deadly, mannered, whiny performance turned in by Jennifer Jason Leigh; when most film fans recall the disaster that became Godfather III, the director's indulgence of the lackluster performance turned in by Sofia Coppola comes to mind; Leigh's performance similarly affects the tone of Kansas City, and since she is the protagonist, the film's interest flags with her director-free indulgence in some kind of method acting that fails to evoke much but self-indulgence. In short, Kansas City is well worth a look for superb mise-en-scene,for the music and atmosphere, but is deeply frustrating for it's central performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rich Textured Visuals
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lechuguilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A kidnapping and a robbery move the plot forward in a film that's less about plot than about cultural ambiance. "Kansas City" is mostly a cinematic expression of place and time. It's 1934, when gangsters and jazz ruled and Blacks and Whites went their separate ways. Visuals are very dark. And though the film is in color, tints are muted, which conveys a nostalgic, sentimental mood. The thin plot takes place largely at night. And the plot alternates with dark interior scenes at the Hey Hey Club, a risqu&eacute;, all-Black speakeasy where an all-Black band jives free-form jazz, and where illegal gambling fills the back rooms. None of the characters are sympathetic. But I don't think they're supposed to be. They're archetypes, models of desperate people in desperate times. A gun-wielding gangster's girl named Blondie (Jennifer Jason Leigh) wants to be like Jean Harlow. Mrs. Stilton (Miranda Richardson) is a wealthy, spaced-out politician's wife. Seldom Seen (based on a real-life person and played by Harry Belafonte) is the cigar smoking godfather who rules the dark, smoky Hey Hey Club with an iron fist and who likes to stand around giving lectures to people. The script's dialogue is mostly subtext, with message directed less at other characters than at viewers. And, as in other Altman films, then-current politics dance around the edges of the seedy story. The overall tone mixes depression with desperation. For me this is an easy film to judge. The characters and plot I cared for not at all. Jennifer Jason Leigh was painful to watch. And though the jazz is performed with great competence, its free-form, improvisational style is too contemporary to reflect the 1930s. On the other hand, Miranda Richardson gives a fine performance. Attention to detail in costumes, sets, props, and storefront exteriors make the film come alive with era realism. And lighting is absolutely terrific. If you go into this movie expecting a deep story and well-constructed plot, you'll be disappointed. Absorb the overall texture of the film's visuals. "Kansas City" is a terrific visual portrait of a specific place at a specific time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A depressing movie you should not watch when already depressed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here, Robert Altman attempts to do for Kansas City what William Kennedy did for Albany, New York. Sort of. Kennedy portrays the indefatigable Albany machine with a mix of cynicism, respect and love. In Ironweed we see more of the underbelly of the city, but even though a dark movie, there is a love for his O Albany. Altman's portrayal of Kansas City is dripping with cynicism, but lacks the love, and only offers the blackest of humor. What's worse, there are few likable characters. We spend most of the time watching two brainless women talking incoherently, one on drugs, the other with her teeth wired together. Yet Kansas City is still worth watching, if you are a serious film buff. Everyone, I assume, loves M*A*S*H (except, perhaps, for the Koreans, who do not have a sense of humor about their own country). Nashville and Gosford Park take a bit more savvy to appreciate, but if you understand them, you will know how to approach Kansas City. These Altman movies take an almost sociological-anthropological approach to their subjects, have strong portrayals of many characters, and more or less lack a plot or center, preferring a more naturalistic unfolding of events. Robert Altman is perhaps the greatest modern slice of life movie director. So don't focus so much on the story line as on the characters and their interactions. However, in Kansas City we are introduced to what we would expect to be more of an action movie, or at least a movie with a Hitchcock type plot. This is not what we get. And the first section consists of cutting back and forth among characters and scenes that do not bear much temporal relationship, which is confusing, and distracts from trying to focus on understanding the characters. Eventually, the movie assumes temporal normality, if not linearity. The music is absolutely outstanding. Much of it seems to accurately reproduce 1930s to early 1940s jazz, and seeing it performed in its natural setting of a nightclub gives you better insight into it than merely listening on a record, which gives it a more cerebral air. However, when truly great musicians like this were really cooking, I think the room would have been quieter, out of respect and interest; that's what I have read in some jazz musician memoirs. I was surprised by the atonality of some of the Count Basie riffs on the piano, not typical Basie style. Silver plated brass instruments would not have been common back then. And Charlie Parker never played a single note in the film, as he was pretty horrible when he was 14. There are no brave heroes in this movie. There was one clueless hero, the elections official, but he lasted for about 15 seconds, before being lines up against the wall and shot (although not realistic, perhaps key to the cinematic message). The musicians are the closest thing to nice guys in the movie, but they stay strictly in the barroom, holding aloof from corruption swirling around them, even while they see much of what is going on, as do most of the blacks. In short, Altman's Kansas City is as devoid of heroes as High Noon would be without Gary Cooper, or It's a Wonderful Life without Jimmy Stewart. Yeah, it's corrupt, but what are you going to do? Make the best of it by joining in, getting a piece of the action. (In reality, not everyone was corrupt, not even all Missouri politicians.) As to the portrayal of the Tom Pendergast political machine, I think Altman over does it. I sincerely doubt a political hack would pull out a gun in broad daylight in front of a polling place and shoot an elections official. Unnecessary and stupid, and sure to make the evening papers. The Pendergast machine was corrupt, but not stupid; the corruption focused on government contracts, from what I have read. The movie's strength is showing the different levels of society and how they interact, black working class, black mob, white political elite, white trash. Its other strength is reproducing the era in astonishingly rich detail. I love movies like this that get it right, and make you feel like you are being transported back in time. The acting is great, especially Harry Belafonte. Jennifer Jason Leigh gets on your nerves, big time, but does so convincingly. Spoiler alert: Near the end, Mrs. Stilton drops her medicine bottle on the ground. Your first thought is it was empty. Or she had decided to break her habit. But I suspect the real meaning, judging from her body language when she tosses the bottle down, is she was faking it, and wasn't so dependent on her "medicine." If you like this movie, try Ironweed, starring Jack Nicholson and Merle Streep. It's a better movie, but Kansas City has better jazz. The jazz, alone, is worth the price of admission.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vivid depiction of Kansas City, 1934
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tnrcooper
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having read all the reviews and seen the rating given this film by even more viewers, it would seem that many viewers are not au courant with the style of Jean Harlow and/or do not have the patience necessary to appreciate some films which do not move along at a quick clip. This would seem to be Altman's tribute to his hometown and to the period when he was a kid-he would have been 9 in 1934. Altman's take on the outre political corruption in Kansas City at that time would seem to be of a sort with the corruption facilitated by the Pendergras machine of the time. His depiction of black characters as autonomous, strong characters is refreshing. Harry Belafonte's mob boss Seldom Seen has to be one of the most ruthless characters seen on celluloid in recent years. Belafonte is at the top of his game, his smoky baritone all the more ominous for his low-key manner. Belafonte really deserved an Oscar nomination for his performance in this movie. One of the many aspects to recommend this film is the music that lit up Kansas City at that time-jazz. The music, featuring Lester Young, Coleman Hawkins, and even a very young Charlie Parker before he was a musician, is electric. The musicians-played by world-class musicians like Joshua Redman, David 'Fathead' Newman, and Christian McBride, electrify the scenes they are in, particularly in one duel which continues until daybreak. The musical scenes are truly magical and electric. We get a sense of the energy and vibrance in the Kansas City music scene at that time. Altman also tweaks notions of race by having white Johnny Flynn (an almost silent Dermot Mulroney) attempting to knock off a mob underling while wearing blackface. Altman considers race and is not afraid to depict and play around with it. The very fact that he is willing to consider its existence and status in society is interesting in itself. There are many black characters, many given great depth and range. Altman adds depth to our understanding of race and fleshes out depiction of people of color in ways that the vast majority of directors do not even acknowledge or consider. This makes the film valuable in and of itself. The film's plot revolves around the kidnapping of the Missouri governor's wife Caroline Stilson (Miranda Richardson) who is kidnapped to pressure the Governor to release Blondie's husband (Dermot Mulroney's Jonny Flynn) who has been caught after trying to rip off one of Seldom Seen's mob lieutenants. Blondie thinks that taking the governor's wife hostage will cause the governor to take the release of her husband more seriously. Some people don't like Jennifer Jason Leigh's performance in this movie, suggesting that it is difficult to understand her. I think that was intentional on her part-an effort to pay tribute to the work of Jean Harlow who was from Kansas City and who we see in a movie that Caroline and Blondie are watching. It's clear that Jean Harlow was attempting to depict a tougher veneer than she really had, as we see as Blondie's tough outer shell collapses as the movie progresses. I found it a very original, Oscar-worthy, performance. Miranda Richardson's depiction of a depressed, drug-addled, lonely political wife who ultimately turns out to know more than she lets on is very compelling. The chemistry between her and Leigh is electric and Richardson's role is very interesting. She delivers an excellent performance in an unusual role. Altman interweaves story lines-those of Seldom Seen and Jonny Flynn on the one hand, and Caroline Stilson and Blondie on the other-expertly-linking them effortlessly. This is one of Altman's greatest strengths-tying in disparate story lines and making connections where they might be less obvious to most filmmakers. Altman makes connections among figures where most directors wouldn't see them. I don't think this film is on the level of his tours de force in Gosford Park, Short Cuts, The Player, MASH, and Nashville, but Altman was always more about depicting a milieu and setting a scene and if his story did not have the pyrotechnics of some of many films in theaters at the time, he didn't care. This film smolders quietly, suggesting a city rotting from the inside out as evidenced by the political and criminal malfeasance which are so brazen in the picture. Altman tells rich, colorful stories and this one is no exception.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Altman With All That Jazz But It's A Little Bit Confusing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a new born to a new audience with excellent "The Player" and "Short Cuts" and slip down with the weird and unfunny "Pr&eacute;t-&agrave;-Porter", the master of the independent cinema Robert Altman gets back with a minor but interesting work in "Kansas City". Here, he reveals the dangerous Kansas City of the 1930's with their corrupt politicians, scary mobsters and people involved with all this world without noticing the danger right ahead. In the 1930's the young and beautiful Blondie (Jennifer Jason Leigh) kidnaps Carolyn (Miranda Richardson) the wife of a powerful politician (Michael Murphy) who can help her to save her boyfriend Johnny (Dermot Mulroney), a little burglar who stole an important big shot in the crime world, and now he's going to be killed by another powerful mob figure, the gangster Seldom Seen (Harry Belafonte). The frightened Carolyn is dragged away along with Blondie to several places in town, trying to get along with each other, which doesn't work quite well because of their different backgrounds. Blondie is addicted to the films of Jean Harlow and she keeps annoying her hostage all the way; while Carolyn is an addicted to opium that barely gets out of the house, suffering with her addiction. In the meantime the politician keeps dealing with the case, in a very discreet way to not ruin his future election that its getting ahead and because of his proximity with President Roosevelt. On the other part of town, Johnny has the chance to know more about what the real world of crime really is, listening to Seldom's menacing stories and to lots of jazz that is played in his captivity. Besides these two kidnaps there's a subplot concerning a girl who came to town to get an abortion and a political scandal involving a party which is buying votes to win the election using of deadly tactics. The same team of writers who signed "Short Cuts" tries to unite several characters that follow the same path in several situations having as link the jazz as musical background played in almost every scene. As I said, they tried to unite them but they end up confusing the public by dividing two situations, apparently disconnected, that will meet in the end, and until it get to the final result you keep wondering what's the reason for both kidnaps. When the two parts get together it all makes sense but before some answers appear many will have walked away of the movie because everything is slow, almost tedious. The perfect "Short Cuts" which tells the story of 23 characters crossing the way of each other in a chaotic Los Angeles, in a excellent tragicomedy of the real life, gets way better than "Kansas City" with their 6 main characters. On the other hand this confusion in dividing the film in two situations makes a intriguing film that makes the audience wants to know of what happens next. As favorable points, "Kansas City" has a great period reconstitution, the costumes of the 1930's, the old cars; the music (Altman worked the same musicians who appeared in his documentary "Jazz 34"); and a great performance by Harry Belafonte as the talking gangster who has an answer to everything. Michael Murphy surprises a lot in his short moments in which he appears; the other performances are not so interesting, sometimes they are very annoying, and that is the case of the main pair. Jennifer Jason Leigh's voice is tiring and very debauched for a dramatic film; Miranda Richardson has a very aloof character, a role that she would dominate better in the great "Falling Angels". Robert Altman made a good job despite not being too much impressive as his previous works. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh the pain, the pain. Is it over yet?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rodney_h
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm sorry but this movie was pitiful. I hated it. KC is S-L-O-W, B-O-R-I-N-G, crap. The dialog was laughable, trite and completely unbelievable. This is a bland thirty-minute short story stretched out to almost two painfully excruciating hours. The only good qualities in this waste of celluloid were 1. Great costumes and 2. Fabulous period cars. Where did they get all of those great old cars? CAUTION - This film is for jazz lovers only....and I hate jazz. How bad can it be? If YOU like this crap-fest, then help yourself to my DVD copy. I threw my disk in the trash. It'll be out at the county dump by now (where it belongs). 1 star out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lost somewhere between the 1930s and 1990s.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Altman's Kansas City is not a terrible movie by any stretch of the imagination and for any other director it would be a minor triumph. Yet, given the pedigree he has provided for himself, particularly with films such as MASH, McCabe & Mrs. Miller, Nashville and 3 Women on his resume, I hold his films to a higher order than most. Perhaps for that reason most of all, I was quite disappointed by this outcome. Jennifer Jason Leigh and Miranda Richardson star as small-time hoodlum and rich politician's wives, respectively, with Leigh taking Richardson hostage in hope that her husband will be released by the notorious gangster Seldom Seen. However, all this is simply a contrivance for what Altman is really after, which seems to me to be the context and feeling of the city of Kansas City in the 1930s when Jean Harlow movies played in the local cinemas and voting was a high-stakes gamble that if gone wrong had very serious consequences. In terms of the film itself, I would consider this film to suffer from the Hudsucker Proxy syndrome: it looks fantastic with the sets and costumes all perfectly realizing the era in which it attempts to capture. Yet, the story is almost thrown together with really not attempt to clarify or make known exactly what is happening. I understand this is Altman's style, particularly for this film, but in order to string the movie along and maintain audience interest, it certainly would have helped to include a more cohesive story line. Also, Jennifer Jason Leigh doesn't fit this part in my opinion, coming off more annoying and self-conscious than sympathetic and interestingly quirky. Her dialogue and delivery seem to come right out of the 1990s and have almost no place in the setting of the rest of the characters. I admire Altman as a director too much to call this film a disaster but it is by far the weakest of all his films I have seen and makes me question why he decided to make this film. Perhaps because he grew up in Kansas City in the 1930s or he felt interested in gangsters, jazz and the setting of a growing town prior to World War II. Whatever the reason, I was frequently out of touch with the story and can really give no compelling reason to seek it out as one of Altman's finer works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Celluloid Jazz
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "You know what I didn't do today? I didn't vote."  Carolyn Stilton I absolutely hated "Kansas City" upon first viewing. Its pace seemed strange, its flashbacks seemed oddly placed, its camera seemed to dwell on unimportant details and none of its characters seemed to exist to propel any clearly defined story forward. In other words, though I'd seen virtually every other Robert Altman film, "Kansas City" still left me in a state of bewilderment. But as is often the case with Altman, "Kansas City" began to make sense - in so far as Altman desires to make sense; his films seem to embrace a certain chaos - upon second viewing. Filled with loving shots of jazz musicians, the film is itself a jazzy tone poem, Altman coming at the audience from odd angles, asking us to pick up on his shifting rhythms of plot and character, themes of race, politics, violence and money. Consider the subtle juxtapositions Altman weaves into the film... A poor white man (Johnny O'Hara) paints his face black and robs a wealthy black man. Seeking assistance, the black man visits a powerful black crime boss called Seldom Seen. Seldom agrees to help, kidnaps Johnny and kills him. In contrast, Johnny's wife (Blondie O'Hara) kidnaps a wealthy white woman (Carolyn Stilton) while she applies a white beauty mask. Carolyn is married to Henry Stilton, a powerful politician. Blondie wants Henry to negotiate with the crime lord so that she may get her husband back. Blondie is eventually killed by Carolyn Stilton. While this drama is unfolding, other characters enter the mix. A young Charlie Parker, years away from musical fame, finds a pregnant black girl. He takes her to a maternity ward. Meanwhile, we learn that Blondie had her baby aborted because Johnny didn't want kids. Similarly, a poor black cab driver (who helped Johnny stage his robbery) is taken to a back alleyway and killed by Seldom and his gang. In contrast, Henry Stilton's goons kill a white man in broad daylight because he was hampering their efforts to falsify local election ballots. And so on and on it goes, Altman juxtaposing his jazz notes, "Kansas City" less a linear narrative than a series of contrasting sequences or oppositional musical riffs, some obvious, some subtle, but all revolving around class, race and gender. Blackface paint is mirrored to white beauty cream, black crime lords are mirrored to corrupt white politicians, political thugs are mirrored to violent gangsters, abortions are mirrored to pregnancies, loving marriages are mirrored to loveless couples, poverty is mirrored to power, underground gambling joints and brothels are mirrored to above ground poll booths and ballot stations. Blondie O'Hara, the young kidnapper, is herself contrasted with Carolyn Stilton, the woman she kidnaps. Blondie loves her husband and would do anything for him. Mrs Stilton, in contrast, is constantly doped up on opium and has long given up on her marriage. Furthermore, Blondie is constantly emulating Kansas City native Jean Harlow, an actress whom she idolises. This notion of "narrative emulation" is itself intended to mirror the "cutting contests" between the jazz musicians sprinkled throughout the film. Just as the musicians borrow from one another and weave each other's material into what they are improvising, Blondie borrows from the movies and weaves Harlow's tough girl phrases and expressions into her conversation. But Blondie's toughness is all a facade, a suit of armour used to compensate for her petite size and coarse environment. While Blondie gives up her child and is constantly subservient to her husband, it is Carolyn Stilton who possesses true strength. Despite her permanently doped up state, Carolyn constantly gives the impression that she knows more than she's letting on, always absorbing information and assessing her surroundings. Her final line, "I didn't vote", itself lets us know that she has long cut herself off from a venal world which she refuses to legitimize. And so with "Kansas City" - a film which ends with a crime lord counting money in the dark corners of a jazz club - Altman has abstracted the politics of power and persuasion, threat and privilege. Everything in the film hinges on social power, Altman drawing a clean line between those violent people who wield power and all those pathetic dreamers who try to grab it but never succeed in doing so for more than a fleeting moment. The political corruption of the city's democratic machine (the country was built on voting fraud and rigged elections; practises common even today), and the expanding influence of Hollywood (and the power of film to seduce and destroy people such as Blondie), is as important to Altman as the racial segregation that produces Kansas City's two worlds: the white world, dominated by the Stilton's, and the inverted black world of Seldom Seen, a vampiric world of music which seems to only come to life long after the surface world has gone to sleep. The film is also unique in the way it offers jazz music an unprecedented role within the diegetic world. This music is constantly "seeping into" he story, providing a kind of tapestry for the characters to perform against. The result is that the jazz music seems to become intertwined with the very social climate that influences it. Altman himself has said that it was his intention that jazz be the structure of the entire film. Whilst a typical song lasts 3 minutes, a jazz tune lasts as much as 17, the effect being that many of the film's scenes are elongated and purposefully stretched out. "Seldom Seen is like a brass instrument," Altman says, "when it's his turn to solo, he does long monologues and riffs. But the discussions of the two women are like reed instruments, saxophones having duets." 8/10 - Best appreciated as a kind of cinematic jazz, the plot lethargically frustrating as it intrigues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ....And All That Jazz
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Altman dishes up a terrific serving of jazz and Depression-era atmosphere in this crime thriller with film noir trappings. Jennifer Jason Leigh gives a fascinating and heartbreaking performance as Blondie, the pathetic Jean Harlow wannabe who kidnaps a senator's (Michael Murphy) wife (Miranda Richardson) in an attempt to force him into helping her husband, Johnny (Dermot Mulroney), who's himself been kidnapped by Seldom Seen (Harry Belafonte), a local gangster kingpin, after Johnny tried to pull a heist on one of Seldom's own. The dark plot works its way toward an inevitable and tragic ending, but as is true with many Altman films, what happens isn't as much fun as how it happens. Altman intersperses the film with segments of music being played in a hot jazz club, and the nearly constant soundtrack gives the whole movie the pulse and rhythm of the jazz numbers it's set to. I'm not so sure I liked the performance of Richardson. She plays a woman doped up on opiates, and while I don't know how someone would act in those circumstances, her performance felt cartoonish and exaggerated to me. But Leigh more than makes up for any weak performances, and she owns this film. Blondie is a born loser, a woman who's learned how to act tough from watching movies but who's not nearly tough enough to survive in the world around her. It's with a mixture of pity and relief that we see the film, and Blondie's fate, move toward its "They Shoot Horses, Don't They?" resolution. Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bonanza for jazz lovers - one of Mr Altman's more personal works
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ianlouisiana
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    God knows English politics is corrupt,but America seems to have raised duplicity to another level.Wheeling,dealing,threatening,bribing,snouts deep in the trough....I would have to be held at gunpoint before I'd vote for anybody.In the poor black Wards of Kansas City in the mid 1930s it doesn't matter who you vote for,your life is not going to get any better,the successful politico is just going to get richer. With a plot and characters remarkably similar to early Runyon,Mr Altman parallels the development of KC jazz with its turbulent social history. For lovers of Bennie Moten/Count Basie type music the movie is at least an aural treat;for the average moviegoer,"Kansas City" is very much a curate's egg. Unless you are at least familiar with Hawk,Pres,Bird and Jean Harlow your enjoyment of the movie may well be limited to the amount of admiration you have for Mr Altman's more personal work. With all due respect to the acting talent involved,no one apart from the much - maligned Miss J.J. Leigh has much to work with.As "Blondie" she has the only role that actually develops during the course of the film. In an era when movies were enormously influential her conscious morphing into a Jean Harlow persona is touching rather than laughable. With "Kansas City",Mr Altman continued to plough his lonely furrow.That it was not a great commercial success is hardly surprising,but admirers of maverick works will get pleasure from it.Jazz loving moviegoers,themselves to some degree mavericks,scouring the schedules in a usually vain attempt to satisfy both their Joneses,should seize the moment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
