<filme>
 <id>
  1303
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109890
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Fuga
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Doc McCoy is put in prison because his partners chickened out and flew off without him after exchanging a prisoner with a lot of money. Doc knows Jack Benyon, a rich "business"-man, is up ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Doc McCoy is put in prison because his partners chickened out and flew off without him after exchanging a prisoner with a lot of money. Doc knows Jack Benyon, a rich "business"-man, is up to something big, so he tells his wife (Carol McCoy) to tell him that he's for sale if Benyon can get him out of prison. Benyon pulls some strings and Doc McCoy is released again. Unfortunately he has to cooperate with the same person that got him to prison.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   money
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   adultery
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   police
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   shower
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   suicide by hanging
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Roger Donaldson
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Jim Thompson
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Walter Hill
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Alec Baldwin
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kim Basinger
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Michael Madsen
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Passable Action Fare...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the Jim Thompson novel of the same name, 'The Getaway' is A Passable Action Fare, that has some pumping action, a decent script & convincing performances as its aces. 'The Getaway' is the same old story of the good getting back at the bad. 'The Getaway' is passable entertainment. The script is decent, as it offers action & eroticism perfectly, although its clich&eacute;d to the core. Roger Donaldson's Direction is stylish. Cinematography is magnetized. Editing is sharp. Performance-Wise: Alec Bladwin is effortless in an action-oriented role. Kim Basinger looks stunning & adds tremendous style in the goings-on. James Woods is excellent, as always. Michael Madsen is evil personified. Jennifer Tilly is perfect. Philip Seymour Hoffman is efficient. On the whole, 'The Getaway' doesn't disappoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The plan is shut up......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Doc McCoy is put in prison because his partner flew off without him after exchanging a prisoner for a lot of money. Doc knows Jack Benyon, a rich man, is up to something big, so he tells his wife to tell him that he's for sale if Benyon can get him out of prison. Benyon pulls some strings and Doc McCoy is released again. Unfortunately he has to cooperate with the same person that got him to prison..... It's one of those films that never needed to be remade, but at the time, I'm guessing Basinger And Baldwin were the biggest couple in Hollywood, so why not do it again? The Marrying Man made a bundle, as did Love Affair. Oh hang on... But the point of the film is to entertain, and it does, as its one of the best looking action movies of 1994, and for once it treats the audience as an adult and is suitable as an action movie or couples, which is really rare. Baldwin is on the right side of tubby, but he over broods and it really gets to you after a while. Basinger does what. She normally does and smolders like a forties movie star. The rest of the cast are just there for the pay check. Woods does his bad guy who is a little prolific role, and is just there to ignite the passion between the two leads characters, and Madsen features in a really gloomy depressing subplot involving Jennifer Tilly, and its pretty bizarre. The action is good and its edited with a lot of respect, it just feels a little strange, despite the fact its enjoyable and fun, it feels too hasty and rushed. A lot more could have been done. But the one saving grace is at least they never remade it with Demi Moore and Ashton Kutcher.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dethroning the King of Cool?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomsview
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you remake one of Steve McQueen's best-known movies, comparisons are inevitable. Alec Baldwin is believable as the hardened criminal 'Doc' McCoy but where McQueen was able to suggest that there may be mitigating factors in the way his life turned out, Baldwin appears much harder, although he does show that there is at least honour among thieves. When all is said and done, this is a fairly straight remake, and the differences are all in the playing. Doc McCoy, facing a long prison sentence, sends his wife Carol, played by Kim Basinger, to ask for help from a corrupt businessman, Jack Benyon, played by James Woods. In return, Doc agrees to pull a robbery for Benyon. However the payment Benyon asks of Carol McCoy is beyond what Doc had in mind. She pays the price and Doc is released. Doc does the robbery but from this point on a series of double crosses sees Doc and Carol on the run  pursued by other criminals, the law and tensions between themselves. It all comes to a head with a shootout in a hotel in Texas. It is hard to believe that the McQueen version of "The Getaway" is over 40 years old, and that the King of Cool is now long gone. Of course, anyone familiar with the earlier version will know exactly what happens next although the sex scenes featuring Baldwin and Basinger register a few points higher on the Richter scale. In the end, the success or otherwise of this version comes down to nuance and shades of meaning  the way Shakespeare's plays are open to a new interpretation, giving them relevance for each generation. Not that the script for "The Getaway" has much to do with Shakespeare, nor likely to be required reading for high school students in the future, but it does provide a suitable vehicle for Baldwin and Basinger. Alec Baldwin will not replace the memory of Steve McQueen in this role, but Kim Basinger fares better when compared to Ali McGraw. Basinger projects a sultry presence; she is not a particularly animated actress, and the role of Carol McCoy seems tailor-made for her. It is only when she exchanges light dialogue with Richard Farnsworth's character near the end of the movie that you realise how heavy going the rest of the film is, exposing a fundamental problem  The McCoys are not fun people and it is hard for the audience to really like them. The subplot involving McCoy's ex-partner, Rudy, and his encounter with the veterinarian and his wife is just as nasty in this version with Michael Madsen creating a truly repellent character. Where this movie shines is in its production values and solid pacing; the action is exciting and the locations are interesting. Maybe thirty years from now, another group of filmmakers will feel the time is right for another interpretation of "The Getaway", but if they do, I think the King of Cool will still rule.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It sets the mark.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stanpol7
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Folks, why your reviews are so wordy and so empty the same time? This is the best motion picture I ever seen that shows that a real couple is all about. It just sets the mark. This film is about trust, love, devotion, honesty, tenderness, kindness, humanity after all. It shows good couple and bad couple, kind and evil. It is about forgiveness. It is about sharing. Yes, I didn't see the original. What for? I 've got the idea, I praise the play of Alec and Kim and the old guy. Why to judge between one good, kind story and another? This "good" is not good enough compared to the other? BS. This story sets the mark for a couple and the people, and the play is just superb. Final titles music is just superb as well. I wish I could have this kind of trust within my couple one day. If I ever do, I would be happy for the rest of my life. So, come on, folks, turn towards your good half of yourself, open you heart and say that this is a great movie to watch, to keep in your heart and to move on. If those two finally made it, maybe and I can make it one day. So... thank you, guys. 'Cause you just saved my heart again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Palatable...Not Preferable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A retread remake with very little original stuff. Especially the dialog and set pieces are nothing more than a carbon creation with no imagination. There is some style and the film is palatable if not preferable to the original 1972 Sam Peckinpah/Jim Thompson movie. The much talked about Peckinpah violent chops have become standard Hollywood fare and there is nothing new here or even an attempt to time-stamp the presentation. This xerox of a film does cut and paste some new sex scenes but so what. It is explicit and erotic, but, it is the grit and the guts that makes it mark on the crime thriller and the sex is best left for the more lurid of these types. Alec Baldwin is prettier than Steve McQueen and Kim Basinger is prettier than Ali MacGraw.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An 'A-List' cast in a bit of a 'B-List' movie I'm afraid (IMO) But hey, what do I know?...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well shot with some nice stunt work; sadly the script didn't live up to the mechanics of the filmmaking (more on that later). As far as performances go, well everyone did a pretty good job; Alec Baldwin was rough and tough as Carter 'Doc' McCoy and Kim Basinger did pretty well as Carol. Michael Madsen (with one of the great mullets) was pretty hateful as Rudy Travis and James Woods was masterful, as ever, as the evil Jack Benyon. Also worthy of note were; David Morse as Jim Deer Jackson, Jennifer Tilly as Fran Carvey, Richard Farnsworth as Slim and finally, sadly underused, Philip Seymour Hoffman as Frank Hansen (blink & you'll miss him). A film that tries to deal with some quite adult themes but in the end falls quite short of the mark. There is just too much going on, the main characters are not likable enough and there's just no charisma between them. When I find myself looking at my watch I know it's a very bad sign and my watch has seldom been looked at quite so much. On the plus side, I did like the performance of James Woods, he was particularly loathsome; the trouble is, there wasn't enough of him. A poor effort over all; an A-list cast but a bit of a B-list movie I'm afraid NOT RECOMMENDED. My score: 5.2/10 IMDb Score: 5.5/10 (based on 9,314 votes at the time of going to press). MetaScore: NO DATA: (Based on 0 critic reviews provided by Metacritic.com at the time of going to press). Rotten Tomatoes 'Tomatometer' Score: 33/100 (based on 21 reviews counted at the time of going to press). Rotten Tomatoes 'Audience' Score: 30/100 'Want to See' (based on 8,439 user ratings counted at the time of going to press). You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Alec Baldwin is about the worst possible choice for this sort of role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films like The Getaway are always fascinating to me on one level. That's because they demonstrate how important the most elemental and obvious choices in storytelling are and getting just one simple thing wrong can hamstring even the most talented filmmakers and performers. This movie is well written and nicely plotted. It has plenty of action and a couple of nice sex scenes. The cast is as good as you'll get for this sort of thing and the direction is unobjectionably competent. All of that goes almost entirely to waste, however, because the two main characters here are unsympathetic criminals whom the audience has no reason whatsoever to root for or care about what happens to them. Don't get me wrong. You can make a compelling and involving film about bad people. The star of every story doesn't have to be some selfless, noble champion of truth, justice and the American way. But if you're going to make a motion picture about a cold blooded villain, you've got to treat him as such and not try to pass him off as a hero. People like looking at sharks but they won't respond to you trying to pretend a great white shark is as cute and relatively harmless as a bottlenose dolphin. Carter "Doc" McCoy (Alec Baldwin) is a smart and stylish thief who can pretty much figure out how to get in anywhere to get anything. Teamed with his beautiful and devoted wife Carol (Kim Basinger), the two pass through a series of twists and turns until they end up on the run from a treacherous partner, some vengeance-seeking gunmen and the law enforcement. And let me stress again, all of that is well executed. Maybe The Getaway isn't a great action-adventure flick, but it's got all the right parts moving in all the right ways to be a very good one. None of it matters much because the movie never gives you a reason to really care if Doc and Carol live or die, succeed or fail, get caught and sent to prison or escape and live happily ever after. I don't think Doc does a single good or admirable thing until 90 minutes into the film. He's portrayed as a remorseless criminal who has not trouble at all assaulting an innocent cab driver or committing attempted murder by firing a shotgun at pursuing cops. The only good thing Carol does involved morally compromising herself to benefit Doc, which largely negates any credit she gets for being selfless. The Getaway rises and falls on one question. Why should the viewer cheer for Doc and Carol while booing their enemies? No explanation is ever provided, other than the charisma of its two stars. Well, Kim Basinger can project a fragile vulnerability like nobody's business but Carol is bound at the hip to Doc and for all of Alec Baldwin's dramatic and comedic abilities, he's never been a performer who radiated likability. At least not until he let himself get fat for TV. Now, I haven't seen the original and don't know how it handled the question of why people should care about these two characters. Maybe Steve McQueen could pull off what Baldwin couldn't or maybe the audience of the early 70s was more inclined to support unrepentant bad guys like Doc McCoy. This remake doesn't answer the question at all, let alone answer it badly. It would not be at all fair to call The Getaway a bad movie. It's never boring, the action scenes are pretty good and Basinger gets naked on more than one occasion, at least in the unrated version I saw. But I wouldn't have cared a whit if Doc and Carol had wound up dead in the desert instead of riding off into the sunset. I suppose someone else might like it much more than I, but I think the general reaction would be a shrug and the statement "Well, that was okay". In other words, if you've got nothing better to do, there are worse ways of wasting your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining Gangsters.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a pretty decent movie as these things go. Baldwin is Doc McCoy, newly released from prison in order to commit a high-end robbery. Faced with cheating partners, he and his wife, Basinger, make off with a gym bag full of large notes and are pursued throughout the Southwest to the Mexican border, where they finally take off on their own. There is some conflict internal to the family because Basinger had to allow the head of the parole board, also the manager of the robbery, access to her succulent body, and Baldwin resents this, sometimes violently, for the first two thirds of the movie. Lots of action, more explicit sex and brutality, and competent performances, yet something is missing. The chief subtrahend is originality. It's a remake of Sam Pekinpah's film of the same name, with Steve McQueen and Ali McGraw, from the 1960s. Pekinpah's production was edgier, with unexpected incidents, and used some magnificent locations in west Texas. And the production design and set dressing were superior. Even so quotidian a setting as a garbage dump outside of El Paso reeks with atmosphere in Pekinpah's film. Here, it's just a garbage dump. The same can be said of the interior -- and the exterior, for that matter -- of the seedy hotel in which the final shoot out takes place. But it isn't so much these details that detract from one's enjoyment of the film, it's the realization that it was done -- and done better -- almost thirty years earlier by a director in whose veins the balance between booze and talent was proportionate. How much in the way of credit should accrue to writers, directors, and producers who simply imitate a successful earlier movie in an attempt to cash in on its popularity and on the loosening of moral strictures in Hollywood? The remake is not quite shot-for-shot but almost, and much of the dialog is identical. Generally speaking, the performances here aren't bad, even though Baldwin is groomed on his release from the slams like a Hollywood star and lacks McQueen's jailhouse haircut. Kim Basinger does a bit better in the role of prisoner's wife than Ali McGraw did, for that matter. McGraw, unfortunately for her, cute as she was in her darkly furry way, always sounded as if she'd just graduated from Wellesley, which at one time she had. And the direction is competent without adding much to the goings on. Slow motion is used where Pekinpah had used it. And, if you want an instructive scene, watch the trio of bad guy Michael Madsen, Jennifer Tilly, and the DVM James Stevens when Madsen and Tilly become playful and start throwing take-out food at one another -- fried chicken and french fries. Madsen, without provocation, becomes angry and orders Tilly back into the front seat. In Pekinpah's movie the take out is barbecued ribs with sticky tomato sauce and they're tossed back and forth with abandon. The bad guy remains in the back seat and, pelted about the face with a couple of hefty ribs, grows visibly more irritated until he ends the game in an outburst of pique. Both the players and the car's interior are coated with Texas barbecue sauce. There's hardly any comparison in the effectiveness of the two, almost identical, incidents. Pekinpah's is superior. None of this should stand as a condemnation of the remake itself. If it stands alone, it's suspenseful and diverting. The world is largely divided into good guys and bad. That usually makes for easily digested entertainment and this movie delivers the goods.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why remake this film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    martinipromotion
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't get me wrong. I think that Alec Baldwin could have been great in this film, but the made the Doc character way too much of a wuss. Plus many of the scenes looked like an acting class that decided to use the scenes from the original as their scripted material. There was no tension and much of the subtext just disappeared. Still, there was good use of some character actors like Richard Farnsworth slotted into some of the smaller key roles and it was nice to pick up on some of the references to the original film. However, the overall viewing experience was far less fulfilling than the original, that kicked ass from start to finish. Also, do dog race tracks really hold huge amounts of money like that?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rare Chemistry Makes This Remake Work... Look At Michael Madson's Hair!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rpmmurphy
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Alec Baldwin and Kim Basinger were a married couple when they portrayed the married McCoys in this 1994 remake of the 1972. Their on-screen chemistry is incredible. Any time you get this kind of casting occurrence in a film, it is at least worth checking out. Here it really works. The thing that distinguishes this Jim Thompson story is the catch-22 Carol McCoy is faced with- and the percussive effect her necessary action has on the McCoy couple- while the tension is ratcheted up to 11- in their non-stop hour-and-a-half getaway throughout the Southwest. It is a juicy role for a married couple, and Baldwin & Basinger make the most of it. They both are in prime form here and very compelling to watch together. Besides the McCoys (and Richard Farnsworth), it is a B film. Michael Madson's hair is a real challenge to deal with. At least you can cut out of the Richard Marx end credit song. You have to live with Michael Madson's hair for the whole ride. IMDb rating should be around 7.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Passable Action Fare...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the Jim Thompson novel of the same name, 'The Getaway' is A Passable Action Fare, that has some pumping action, a decent script & convincing performances as its aces. 'The Getaway' is the same old story of the good getting back at the bad. 'The Getaway' is passable entertainment. The script is decent, as it offers action & eroticism perfectly, although its clich&eacute;d to the core. Roger Donaldson's Direction is stylish. Cinematography is magnetized. Editing is sharp. Performance-Wise: Alec Bladwin is effortless in an action-oriented role. Kim Basinger looks stunning & adds tremendous style in the goings-on. James Woods is excellent, as always. Michael Madsen is evil personified. Jennifer Tilly is perfect. Philip Seymour Hoffman is efficient. On the whole, 'The Getaway' doesn't disappoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The plan is shut up......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Doc McCoy is put in prison because his partner flew off without him after exchanging a prisoner for a lot of money. Doc knows Jack Benyon, a rich man, is up to something big, so he tells his wife to tell him that he's for sale if Benyon can get him out of prison. Benyon pulls some strings and Doc McCoy is released again. Unfortunately he has to cooperate with the same person that got him to prison..... It's one of those films that never needed to be remade, but at the time, I'm guessing Basinger And Baldwin were the biggest couple in Hollywood, so why not do it again? The Marrying Man made a bundle, as did Love Affair. Oh hang on... But the point of the film is to entertain, and it does, as its one of the best looking action movies of 1994, and for once it treats the audience as an adult and is suitable as an action movie or couples, which is really rare. Baldwin is on the right side of tubby, but he over broods and it really gets to you after a while. Basinger does what. She normally does and smolders like a forties movie star. The rest of the cast are just there for the pay check. Woods does his bad guy who is a little prolific role, and is just there to ignite the passion between the two leads characters, and Madsen features in a really gloomy depressing subplot involving Jennifer Tilly, and its pretty bizarre. The action is good and its edited with a lot of respect, it just feels a little strange, despite the fact its enjoyable and fun, it feels too hasty and rushed. A lot more could have been done. But the one saving grace is at least they never remade it with Demi Moore and Ashton Kutcher.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dethroning the King of Cool?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomsview
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you remake one of Steve McQueen's best-known movies, comparisons are inevitable. Alec Baldwin is believable as the hardened criminal 'Doc' McCoy but where McQueen was able to suggest that there may be mitigating factors in the way his life turned out, Baldwin appears much harder, although he does show that there is at least honour among thieves. When all is said and done, this is a fairly straight remake, and the differences are all in the playing. Doc McCoy, facing a long prison sentence, sends his wife Carol, played by Kim Basinger, to ask for help from a corrupt businessman, Jack Benyon, played by James Woods. In return, Doc agrees to pull a robbery for Benyon. However the payment Benyon asks of Carol McCoy is beyond what Doc had in mind. She pays the price and Doc is released. Doc does the robbery but from this point on a series of double crosses sees Doc and Carol on the run  pursued by other criminals, the law and tensions between themselves. It all comes to a head with a shootout in a hotel in Texas. It is hard to believe that the McQueen version of "The Getaway" is over 40 years old, and that the King of Cool is now long gone. Of course, anyone familiar with the earlier version will know exactly what happens next although the sex scenes featuring Baldwin and Basinger register a few points higher on the Richter scale. In the end, the success or otherwise of this version comes down to nuance and shades of meaning  the way Shakespeare's plays are open to a new interpretation, giving them relevance for each generation. Not that the script for "The Getaway" has much to do with Shakespeare, nor likely to be required reading for high school students in the future, but it does provide a suitable vehicle for Baldwin and Basinger. Alec Baldwin will not replace the memory of Steve McQueen in this role, but Kim Basinger fares better when compared to Ali McGraw. Basinger projects a sultry presence; she is not a particularly animated actress, and the role of Carol McCoy seems tailor-made for her. It is only when she exchanges light dialogue with Richard Farnsworth's character near the end of the movie that you realise how heavy going the rest of the film is, exposing a fundamental problem  The McCoys are not fun people and it is hard for the audience to really like them. The subplot involving McCoy's ex-partner, Rudy, and his encounter with the veterinarian and his wife is just as nasty in this version with Michael Madsen creating a truly repellent character. Where this movie shines is in its production values and solid pacing; the action is exciting and the locations are interesting. Maybe thirty years from now, another group of filmmakers will feel the time is right for another interpretation of "The Getaway", but if they do, I think the King of Cool will still rule.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It sets the mark.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stanpol7
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Folks, why your reviews are so wordy and so empty the same time? This is the best motion picture I ever seen that shows that a real couple is all about. It just sets the mark. This film is about trust, love, devotion, honesty, tenderness, kindness, humanity after all. It shows good couple and bad couple, kind and evil. It is about forgiveness. It is about sharing. Yes, I didn't see the original. What for? I 've got the idea, I praise the play of Alec and Kim and the old guy. Why to judge between one good, kind story and another? This "good" is not good enough compared to the other? BS. This story sets the mark for a couple and the people, and the play is just superb. Final titles music is just superb as well. I wish I could have this kind of trust within my couple one day. If I ever do, I would be happy for the rest of my life. So, come on, folks, turn towards your good half of yourself, open you heart and say that this is a great movie to watch, to keep in your heart and to move on. If those two finally made it, maybe and I can make it one day. So... thank you, guys. 'Cause you just saved my heart again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Palatable...Not Preferable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A retread remake with very little original stuff. Especially the dialog and set pieces are nothing more than a carbon creation with no imagination. There is some style and the film is palatable if not preferable to the original 1972 Sam Peckinpah/Jim Thompson movie. The much talked about Peckinpah violent chops have become standard Hollywood fare and there is nothing new here or even an attempt to time-stamp the presentation. This xerox of a film does cut and paste some new sex scenes but so what. It is explicit and erotic, but, it is the grit and the guts that makes it mark on the crime thriller and the sex is best left for the more lurid of these types. Alec Baldwin is prettier than Steve McQueen and Kim Basinger is prettier than Ali MacGraw.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An 'A-List' cast in a bit of a 'B-List' movie I'm afraid (IMO) But hey, what do I know?...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well shot with some nice stunt work; sadly the script didn't live up to the mechanics of the filmmaking (more on that later). As far as performances go, well everyone did a pretty good job; Alec Baldwin was rough and tough as Carter 'Doc' McCoy and Kim Basinger did pretty well as Carol. Michael Madsen (with one of the great mullets) was pretty hateful as Rudy Travis and James Woods was masterful, as ever, as the evil Jack Benyon. Also worthy of note were; David Morse as Jim Deer Jackson, Jennifer Tilly as Fran Carvey, Richard Farnsworth as Slim and finally, sadly underused, Philip Seymour Hoffman as Frank Hansen (blink & you'll miss him). A film that tries to deal with some quite adult themes but in the end falls quite short of the mark. There is just too much going on, the main characters are not likable enough and there's just no charisma between them. When I find myself looking at my watch I know it's a very bad sign and my watch has seldom been looked at quite so much. On the plus side, I did like the performance of James Woods, he was particularly loathsome; the trouble is, there wasn't enough of him. A poor effort over all; an A-list cast but a bit of a B-list movie I'm afraid NOT RECOMMENDED. My score: 5.2/10 IMDb Score: 5.5/10 (based on 9,314 votes at the time of going to press). MetaScore: NO DATA: (Based on 0 critic reviews provided by Metacritic.com at the time of going to press). Rotten Tomatoes 'Tomatometer' Score: 33/100 (based on 21 reviews counted at the time of going to press). Rotten Tomatoes 'Audience' Score: 30/100 'Want to See' (based on 8,439 user ratings counted at the time of going to press). You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Alec Baldwin is about the worst possible choice for this sort of role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films like The Getaway are always fascinating to me on one level. That's because they demonstrate how important the most elemental and obvious choices in storytelling are and getting just one simple thing wrong can hamstring even the most talented filmmakers and performers. This movie is well written and nicely plotted. It has plenty of action and a couple of nice sex scenes. The cast is as good as you'll get for this sort of thing and the direction is unobjectionably competent. All of that goes almost entirely to waste, however, because the two main characters here are unsympathetic criminals whom the audience has no reason whatsoever to root for or care about what happens to them. Don't get me wrong. You can make a compelling and involving film about bad people. The star of every story doesn't have to be some selfless, noble champion of truth, justice and the American way. But if you're going to make a motion picture about a cold blooded villain, you've got to treat him as such and not try to pass him off as a hero. People like looking at sharks but they won't respond to you trying to pretend a great white shark is as cute and relatively harmless as a bottlenose dolphin. Carter "Doc" McCoy (Alec Baldwin) is a smart and stylish thief who can pretty much figure out how to get in anywhere to get anything. Teamed with his beautiful and devoted wife Carol (Kim Basinger), the two pass through a series of twists and turns until they end up on the run from a treacherous partner, some vengeance-seeking gunmen and the law enforcement. And let me stress again, all of that is well executed. Maybe The Getaway isn't a great action-adventure flick, but it's got all the right parts moving in all the right ways to be a very good one. None of it matters much because the movie never gives you a reason to really care if Doc and Carol live or die, succeed or fail, get caught and sent to prison or escape and live happily ever after. I don't think Doc does a single good or admirable thing until 90 minutes into the film. He's portrayed as a remorseless criminal who has not trouble at all assaulting an innocent cab driver or committing attempted murder by firing a shotgun at pursuing cops. The only good thing Carol does involved morally compromising herself to benefit Doc, which largely negates any credit she gets for being selfless. The Getaway rises and falls on one question. Why should the viewer cheer for Doc and Carol while booing their enemies? No explanation is ever provided, other than the charisma of its two stars. Well, Kim Basinger can project a fragile vulnerability like nobody's business but Carol is bound at the hip to Doc and for all of Alec Baldwin's dramatic and comedic abilities, he's never been a performer who radiated likability. At least not until he let himself get fat for TV. Now, I haven't seen the original and don't know how it handled the question of why people should care about these two characters. Maybe Steve McQueen could pull off what Baldwin couldn't or maybe the audience of the early 70s was more inclined to support unrepentant bad guys like Doc McCoy. This remake doesn't answer the question at all, let alone answer it badly. It would not be at all fair to call The Getaway a bad movie. It's never boring, the action scenes are pretty good and Basinger gets naked on more than one occasion, at least in the unrated version I saw. But I wouldn't have cared a whit if Doc and Carol had wound up dead in the desert instead of riding off into the sunset. I suppose someone else might like it much more than I, but I think the general reaction would be a shrug and the statement "Well, that was okay". In other words, if you've got nothing better to do, there are worse ways of wasting your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining Gangsters.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a pretty decent movie as these things go. Baldwin is Doc McCoy, newly released from prison in order to commit a high-end robbery. Faced with cheating partners, he and his wife, Basinger, make off with a gym bag full of large notes and are pursued throughout the Southwest to the Mexican border, where they finally take off on their own. There is some conflict internal to the family because Basinger had to allow the head of the parole board, also the manager of the robbery, access to her succulent body, and Baldwin resents this, sometimes violently, for the first two thirds of the movie. Lots of action, more explicit sex and brutality, and competent performances, yet something is missing. The chief subtrahend is originality. It's a remake of Sam Pekinpah's film of the same name, with Steve McQueen and Ali McGraw, from the 1960s. Pekinpah's production was edgier, with unexpected incidents, and used some magnificent locations in west Texas. And the production design and set dressing were superior. Even so quotidian a setting as a garbage dump outside of El Paso reeks with atmosphere in Pekinpah's film. Here, it's just a garbage dump. The same can be said of the interior -- and the exterior, for that matter -- of the seedy hotel in which the final shoot out takes place. But it isn't so much these details that detract from one's enjoyment of the film, it's the realization that it was done -- and done better -- almost thirty years earlier by a director in whose veins the balance between booze and talent was proportionate. How much in the way of credit should accrue to writers, directors, and producers who simply imitate a successful earlier movie in an attempt to cash in on its popularity and on the loosening of moral strictures in Hollywood? The remake is not quite shot-for-shot but almost, and much of the dialog is identical. Generally speaking, the performances here aren't bad, even though Baldwin is groomed on his release from the slams like a Hollywood star and lacks McQueen's jailhouse haircut. Kim Basinger does a bit better in the role of prisoner's wife than Ali McGraw did, for that matter. McGraw, unfortunately for her, cute as she was in her darkly furry way, always sounded as if she'd just graduated from Wellesley, which at one time she had. And the direction is competent without adding much to the goings on. Slow motion is used where Pekinpah had used it. And, if you want an instructive scene, watch the trio of bad guy Michael Madsen, Jennifer Tilly, and the DVM James Stevens when Madsen and Tilly become playful and start throwing take-out food at one another -- fried chicken and french fries. Madsen, without provocation, becomes angry and orders Tilly back into the front seat. In Pekinpah's movie the take out is barbecued ribs with sticky tomato sauce and they're tossed back and forth with abandon. The bad guy remains in the back seat and, pelted about the face with a couple of hefty ribs, grows visibly more irritated until he ends the game in an outburst of pique. Both the players and the car's interior are coated with Texas barbecue sauce. There's hardly any comparison in the effectiveness of the two, almost identical, incidents. Pekinpah's is superior. None of this should stand as a condemnation of the remake itself. If it stands alone, it's suspenseful and diverting. The world is largely divided into good guys and bad. That usually makes for easily digested entertainment and this movie delivers the goods.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why remake this film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    martinipromotion
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't get me wrong. I think that Alec Baldwin could have been great in this film, but the made the Doc character way too much of a wuss. Plus many of the scenes looked like an acting class that decided to use the scenes from the original as their scripted material. There was no tension and much of the subtext just disappeared. Still, there was good use of some character actors like Richard Farnsworth slotted into some of the smaller key roles and it was nice to pick up on some of the references to the original film. However, the overall viewing experience was far less fulfilling than the original, that kicked ass from start to finish. Also, do dog race tracks really hold huge amounts of money like that?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rare Chemistry Makes This Remake Work... Look At Michael Madson's Hair!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rpmmurphy
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Alec Baldwin and Kim Basinger were a married couple when they portrayed the married McCoys in this 1994 remake of the 1972. Their on-screen chemistry is incredible. Any time you get this kind of casting occurrence in a film, it is at least worth checking out. Here it really works. The thing that distinguishes this Jim Thompson story is the catch-22 Carol McCoy is faced with- and the percussive effect her necessary action has on the McCoy couple- while the tension is ratcheted up to 11- in their non-stop hour-and-a-half getaway throughout the Southwest. It is a juicy role for a married couple, and Baldwin & Basinger make the most of it. They both are in prime form here and very compelling to watch together. Besides the McCoys (and Richard Farnsworth), it is a B film. Michael Madson's hair is a real challenge to deal with. At least you can cut out of the Richard Marx end credit song. You have to live with Michael Madson's hair for the whole ride. IMDb rating should be around 7.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Passable Action Fare...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the Jim Thompson novel of the same name, 'The Getaway' is A Passable Action Fare, that has some pumping action, a decent script & convincing performances as its aces. 'The Getaway' is the same old story of the good getting back at the bad. 'The Getaway' is passable entertainment. The script is decent, as it offers action & eroticism perfectly, although its clich&eacute;d to the core. Roger Donaldson's Direction is stylish. Cinematography is magnetized. Editing is sharp. Performance-Wise: Alec Bladwin is effortless in an action-oriented role. Kim Basinger looks stunning & adds tremendous style in the goings-on. James Woods is excellent, as always. Michael Madsen is evil personified. Jennifer Tilly is perfect. Philip Seymour Hoffman is efficient. On the whole, 'The Getaway' doesn't disappoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The plan is shut up......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Doc McCoy is put in prison because his partner flew off without him after exchanging a prisoner for a lot of money. Doc knows Jack Benyon, a rich man, is up to something big, so he tells his wife to tell him that he's for sale if Benyon can get him out of prison. Benyon pulls some strings and Doc McCoy is released again. Unfortunately he has to cooperate with the same person that got him to prison..... It's one of those films that never needed to be remade, but at the time, I'm guessing Basinger And Baldwin were the biggest couple in Hollywood, so why not do it again? The Marrying Man made a bundle, as did Love Affair. Oh hang on... But the point of the film is to entertain, and it does, as its one of the best looking action movies of 1994, and for once it treats the audience as an adult and is suitable as an action movie or couples, which is really rare. Baldwin is on the right side of tubby, but he over broods and it really gets to you after a while. Basinger does what. She normally does and smolders like a forties movie star. The rest of the cast are just there for the pay check. Woods does his bad guy who is a little prolific role, and is just there to ignite the passion between the two leads characters, and Madsen features in a really gloomy depressing subplot involving Jennifer Tilly, and its pretty bizarre. The action is good and its edited with a lot of respect, it just feels a little strange, despite the fact its enjoyable and fun, it feels too hasty and rushed. A lot more could have been done. But the one saving grace is at least they never remade it with Demi Moore and Ashton Kutcher.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dethroning the King of Cool?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomsview
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you remake one of Steve McQueen's best-known movies, comparisons are inevitable. Alec Baldwin is believable as the hardened criminal 'Doc' McCoy but where McQueen was able to suggest that there may be mitigating factors in the way his life turned out, Baldwin appears much harder, although he does show that there is at least honour among thieves. When all is said and done, this is a fairly straight remake, and the differences are all in the playing. Doc McCoy, facing a long prison sentence, sends his wife Carol, played by Kim Basinger, to ask for help from a corrupt businessman, Jack Benyon, played by James Woods. In return, Doc agrees to pull a robbery for Benyon. However the payment Benyon asks of Carol McCoy is beyond what Doc had in mind. She pays the price and Doc is released. Doc does the robbery but from this point on a series of double crosses sees Doc and Carol on the run  pursued by other criminals, the law and tensions between themselves. It all comes to a head with a shootout in a hotel in Texas. It is hard to believe that the McQueen version of "The Getaway" is over 40 years old, and that the King of Cool is now long gone. Of course, anyone familiar with the earlier version will know exactly what happens next although the sex scenes featuring Baldwin and Basinger register a few points higher on the Richter scale. In the end, the success or otherwise of this version comes down to nuance and shades of meaning  the way Shakespeare's plays are open to a new interpretation, giving them relevance for each generation. Not that the script for "The Getaway" has much to do with Shakespeare, nor likely to be required reading for high school students in the future, but it does provide a suitable vehicle for Baldwin and Basinger. Alec Baldwin will not replace the memory of Steve McQueen in this role, but Kim Basinger fares better when compared to Ali McGraw. Basinger projects a sultry presence; she is not a particularly animated actress, and the role of Carol McCoy seems tailor-made for her. It is only when she exchanges light dialogue with Richard Farnsworth's character near the end of the movie that you realise how heavy going the rest of the film is, exposing a fundamental problem  The McCoys are not fun people and it is hard for the audience to really like them. The subplot involving McCoy's ex-partner, Rudy, and his encounter with the veterinarian and his wife is just as nasty in this version with Michael Madsen creating a truly repellent character. Where this movie shines is in its production values and solid pacing; the action is exciting and the locations are interesting. Maybe thirty years from now, another group of filmmakers will feel the time is right for another interpretation of "The Getaway", but if they do, I think the King of Cool will still rule.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It sets the mark.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stanpol7
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Folks, why your reviews are so wordy and so empty the same time? This is the best motion picture I ever seen that shows that a real couple is all about. It just sets the mark. This film is about trust, love, devotion, honesty, tenderness, kindness, humanity after all. It shows good couple and bad couple, kind and evil. It is about forgiveness. It is about sharing. Yes, I didn't see the original. What for? I 've got the idea, I praise the play of Alec and Kim and the old guy. Why to judge between one good, kind story and another? This "good" is not good enough compared to the other? BS. This story sets the mark for a couple and the people, and the play is just superb. Final titles music is just superb as well. I wish I could have this kind of trust within my couple one day. If I ever do, I would be happy for the rest of my life. So, come on, folks, turn towards your good half of yourself, open you heart and say that this is a great movie to watch, to keep in your heart and to move on. If those two finally made it, maybe and I can make it one day. So... thank you, guys. 'Cause you just saved my heart again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Palatable...Not Preferable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A retread remake with very little original stuff. Especially the dialog and set pieces are nothing more than a carbon creation with no imagination. There is some style and the film is palatable if not preferable to the original 1972 Sam Peckinpah/Jim Thompson movie. The much talked about Peckinpah violent chops have become standard Hollywood fare and there is nothing new here or even an attempt to time-stamp the presentation. This xerox of a film does cut and paste some new sex scenes but so what. It is explicit and erotic, but, it is the grit and the guts that makes it mark on the crime thriller and the sex is best left for the more lurid of these types. Alec Baldwin is prettier than Steve McQueen and Kim Basinger is prettier than Ali MacGraw.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An 'A-List' cast in a bit of a 'B-List' movie I'm afraid (IMO) But hey, what do I know?...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well shot with some nice stunt work; sadly the script didn't live up to the mechanics of the filmmaking (more on that later). As far as performances go, well everyone did a pretty good job; Alec Baldwin was rough and tough as Carter 'Doc' McCoy and Kim Basinger did pretty well as Carol. Michael Madsen (with one of the great mullets) was pretty hateful as Rudy Travis and James Woods was masterful, as ever, as the evil Jack Benyon. Also worthy of note were; David Morse as Jim Deer Jackson, Jennifer Tilly as Fran Carvey, Richard Farnsworth as Slim and finally, sadly underused, Philip Seymour Hoffman as Frank Hansen (blink & you'll miss him). A film that tries to deal with some quite adult themes but in the end falls quite short of the mark. There is just too much going on, the main characters are not likable enough and there's just no charisma between them. When I find myself looking at my watch I know it's a very bad sign and my watch has seldom been looked at quite so much. On the plus side, I did like the performance of James Woods, he was particularly loathsome; the trouble is, there wasn't enough of him. A poor effort over all; an A-list cast but a bit of a B-list movie I'm afraid NOT RECOMMENDED. My score: 5.2/10 IMDb Score: 5.5/10 (based on 9,314 votes at the time of going to press). MetaScore: NO DATA: (Based on 0 critic reviews provided by Metacritic.com at the time of going to press). Rotten Tomatoes 'Tomatometer' Score: 33/100 (based on 21 reviews counted at the time of going to press). Rotten Tomatoes 'Audience' Score: 30/100 'Want to See' (based on 8,439 user ratings counted at the time of going to press). You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Alec Baldwin is about the worst possible choice for this sort of role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films like The Getaway are always fascinating to me on one level. That's because they demonstrate how important the most elemental and obvious choices in storytelling are and getting just one simple thing wrong can hamstring even the most talented filmmakers and performers. This movie is well written and nicely plotted. It has plenty of action and a couple of nice sex scenes. The cast is as good as you'll get for this sort of thing and the direction is unobjectionably competent. All of that goes almost entirely to waste, however, because the two main characters here are unsympathetic criminals whom the audience has no reason whatsoever to root for or care about what happens to them. Don't get me wrong. You can make a compelling and involving film about bad people. The star of every story doesn't have to be some selfless, noble champion of truth, justice and the American way. But if you're going to make a motion picture about a cold blooded villain, you've got to treat him as such and not try to pass him off as a hero. People like looking at sharks but they won't respond to you trying to pretend a great white shark is as cute and relatively harmless as a bottlenose dolphin. Carter "Doc" McCoy (Alec Baldwin) is a smart and stylish thief who can pretty much figure out how to get in anywhere to get anything. Teamed with his beautiful and devoted wife Carol (Kim Basinger), the two pass through a series of twists and turns until they end up on the run from a treacherous partner, some vengeance-seeking gunmen and the law enforcement. And let me stress again, all of that is well executed. Maybe The Getaway isn't a great action-adventure flick, but it's got all the right parts moving in all the right ways to be a very good one. None of it matters much because the movie never gives you a reason to really care if Doc and Carol live or die, succeed or fail, get caught and sent to prison or escape and live happily ever after. I don't think Doc does a single good or admirable thing until 90 minutes into the film. He's portrayed as a remorseless criminal who has not trouble at all assaulting an innocent cab driver or committing attempted murder by firing a shotgun at pursuing cops. The only good thing Carol does involved morally compromising herself to benefit Doc, which largely negates any credit she gets for being selfless. The Getaway rises and falls on one question. Why should the viewer cheer for Doc and Carol while booing their enemies? No explanation is ever provided, other than the charisma of its two stars. Well, Kim Basinger can project a fragile vulnerability like nobody's business but Carol is bound at the hip to Doc and for all of Alec Baldwin's dramatic and comedic abilities, he's never been a performer who radiated likability. At least not until he let himself get fat for TV. Now, I haven't seen the original and don't know how it handled the question of why people should care about these two characters. Maybe Steve McQueen could pull off what Baldwin couldn't or maybe the audience of the early 70s was more inclined to support unrepentant bad guys like Doc McCoy. This remake doesn't answer the question at all, let alone answer it badly. It would not be at all fair to call The Getaway a bad movie. It's never boring, the action scenes are pretty good and Basinger gets naked on more than one occasion, at least in the unrated version I saw. But I wouldn't have cared a whit if Doc and Carol had wound up dead in the desert instead of riding off into the sunset. I suppose someone else might like it much more than I, but I think the general reaction would be a shrug and the statement "Well, that was okay". In other words, if you've got nothing better to do, there are worse ways of wasting your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining Gangsters.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a pretty decent movie as these things go. Baldwin is Doc McCoy, newly released from prison in order to commit a high-end robbery. Faced with cheating partners, he and his wife, Basinger, make off with a gym bag full of large notes and are pursued throughout the Southwest to the Mexican border, where they finally take off on their own. There is some conflict internal to the family because Basinger had to allow the head of the parole board, also the manager of the robbery, access to her succulent body, and Baldwin resents this, sometimes violently, for the first two thirds of the movie. Lots of action, more explicit sex and brutality, and competent performances, yet something is missing. The chief subtrahend is originality. It's a remake of Sam Pekinpah's film of the same name, with Steve McQueen and Ali McGraw, from the 1960s. Pekinpah's production was edgier, with unexpected incidents, and used some magnificent locations in west Texas. And the production design and set dressing were superior. Even so quotidian a setting as a garbage dump outside of El Paso reeks with atmosphere in Pekinpah's film. Here, it's just a garbage dump. The same can be said of the interior -- and the exterior, for that matter -- of the seedy hotel in which the final shoot out takes place. But it isn't so much these details that detract from one's enjoyment of the film, it's the realization that it was done -- and done better -- almost thirty years earlier by a director in whose veins the balance between booze and talent was proportionate. How much in the way of credit should accrue to writers, directors, and producers who simply imitate a successful earlier movie in an attempt to cash in on its popularity and on the loosening of moral strictures in Hollywood? The remake is not quite shot-for-shot but almost, and much of the dialog is identical. Generally speaking, the performances here aren't bad, even though Baldwin is groomed on his release from the slams like a Hollywood star and lacks McQueen's jailhouse haircut. Kim Basinger does a bit better in the role of prisoner's wife than Ali McGraw did, for that matter. McGraw, unfortunately for her, cute as she was in her darkly furry way, always sounded as if she'd just graduated from Wellesley, which at one time she had. And the direction is competent without adding much to the goings on. Slow motion is used where Pekinpah had used it. And, if you want an instructive scene, watch the trio of bad guy Michael Madsen, Jennifer Tilly, and the DVM James Stevens when Madsen and Tilly become playful and start throwing take-out food at one another -- fried chicken and french fries. Madsen, without provocation, becomes angry and orders Tilly back into the front seat. In Pekinpah's movie the take out is barbecued ribs with sticky tomato sauce and they're tossed back and forth with abandon. The bad guy remains in the back seat and, pelted about the face with a couple of hefty ribs, grows visibly more irritated until he ends the game in an outburst of pique. Both the players and the car's interior are coated with Texas barbecue sauce. There's hardly any comparison in the effectiveness of the two, almost identical, incidents. Pekinpah's is superior. None of this should stand as a condemnation of the remake itself. If it stands alone, it's suspenseful and diverting. The world is largely divided into good guys and bad. That usually makes for easily digested entertainment and this movie delivers the goods.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why remake this film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    martinipromotion
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't get me wrong. I think that Alec Baldwin could have been great in this film, but the made the Doc character way too much of a wuss. Plus many of the scenes looked like an acting class that decided to use the scenes from the original as their scripted material. There was no tension and much of the subtext just disappeared. Still, there was good use of some character actors like Richard Farnsworth slotted into some of the smaller key roles and it was nice to pick up on some of the references to the original film. However, the overall viewing experience was far less fulfilling than the original, that kicked ass from start to finish. Also, do dog race tracks really hold huge amounts of money like that?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rare Chemistry Makes This Remake Work... Look At Michael Madson's Hair!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rpmmurphy
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Alec Baldwin and Kim Basinger were a married couple when they portrayed the married McCoys in this 1994 remake of the 1972. Their on-screen chemistry is incredible. Any time you get this kind of casting occurrence in a film, it is at least worth checking out. Here it really works. The thing that distinguishes this Jim Thompson story is the catch-22 Carol McCoy is faced with- and the percussive effect her necessary action has on the McCoy couple- while the tension is ratcheted up to 11- in their non-stop hour-and-a-half getaway throughout the Southwest. It is a juicy role for a married couple, and Baldwin & Basinger make the most of it. They both are in prime form here and very compelling to watch together. Besides the McCoys (and Richard Farnsworth), it is a B film. Michael Madson's hair is a real challenge to deal with. At least you can cut out of the Richard Marx end credit song. You have to live with Michael Madson's hair for the whole ride. IMDb rating should be around 7.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Passable Action Fare...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the Jim Thompson novel of the same name, 'The Getaway' is A Passable Action Fare, that has some pumping action, a decent script & convincing performances as its aces. 'The Getaway' is the same old story of the good getting back at the bad. 'The Getaway' is passable entertainment. The script is decent, as it offers action & eroticism perfectly, although its clich&eacute;d to the core. Roger Donaldson's Direction is stylish. Cinematography is magnetized. Editing is sharp. Performance-Wise: Alec Bladwin is effortless in an action-oriented role. Kim Basinger looks stunning & adds tremendous style in the goings-on. James Woods is excellent, as always. Michael Madsen is evil personified. Jennifer Tilly is perfect. Philip Seymour Hoffman is efficient. On the whole, 'The Getaway' doesn't disappoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The plan is shut up......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Doc McCoy is put in prison because his partner flew off without him after exchanging a prisoner for a lot of money. Doc knows Jack Benyon, a rich man, is up to something big, so he tells his wife to tell him that he's for sale if Benyon can get him out of prison. Benyon pulls some strings and Doc McCoy is released again. Unfortunately he has to cooperate with the same person that got him to prison..... It's one of those films that never needed to be remade, but at the time, I'm guessing Basinger And Baldwin were the biggest couple in Hollywood, so why not do it again? The Marrying Man made a bundle, as did Love Affair. Oh hang on... But the point of the film is to entertain, and it does, as its one of the best looking action movies of 1994, and for once it treats the audience as an adult and is suitable as an action movie or couples, which is really rare. Baldwin is on the right side of tubby, but he over broods and it really gets to you after a while. Basinger does what. She normally does and smolders like a forties movie star. The rest of the cast are just there for the pay check. Woods does his bad guy who is a little prolific role, and is just there to ignite the passion between the two leads characters, and Madsen features in a really gloomy depressing subplot involving Jennifer Tilly, and its pretty bizarre. The action is good and its edited with a lot of respect, it just feels a little strange, despite the fact its enjoyable and fun, it feels too hasty and rushed. A lot more could have been done. But the one saving grace is at least they never remade it with Demi Moore and Ashton Kutcher.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dethroning the King of Cool?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomsview
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you remake one of Steve McQueen's best-known movies, comparisons are inevitable. Alec Baldwin is believable as the hardened criminal 'Doc' McCoy but where McQueen was able to suggest that there may be mitigating factors in the way his life turned out, Baldwin appears much harder, although he does show that there is at least honour among thieves. When all is said and done, this is a fairly straight remake, and the differences are all in the playing. Doc McCoy, facing a long prison sentence, sends his wife Carol, played by Kim Basinger, to ask for help from a corrupt businessman, Jack Benyon, played by James Woods. In return, Doc agrees to pull a robbery for Benyon. However the payment Benyon asks of Carol McCoy is beyond what Doc had in mind. She pays the price and Doc is released. Doc does the robbery but from this point on a series of double crosses sees Doc and Carol on the run  pursued by other criminals, the law and tensions between themselves. It all comes to a head with a shootout in a hotel in Texas. It is hard to believe that the McQueen version of "The Getaway" is over 40 years old, and that the King of Cool is now long gone. Of course, anyone familiar with the earlier version will know exactly what happens next although the sex scenes featuring Baldwin and Basinger register a few points higher on the Richter scale. In the end, the success or otherwise of this version comes down to nuance and shades of meaning  the way Shakespeare's plays are open to a new interpretation, giving them relevance for each generation. Not that the script for "The Getaway" has much to do with Shakespeare, nor likely to be required reading for high school students in the future, but it does provide a suitable vehicle for Baldwin and Basinger. Alec Baldwin will not replace the memory of Steve McQueen in this role, but Kim Basinger fares better when compared to Ali McGraw. Basinger projects a sultry presence; she is not a particularly animated actress, and the role of Carol McCoy seems tailor-made for her. It is only when she exchanges light dialogue with Richard Farnsworth's character near the end of the movie that you realise how heavy going the rest of the film is, exposing a fundamental problem  The McCoys are not fun people and it is hard for the audience to really like them. The subplot involving McCoy's ex-partner, Rudy, and his encounter with the veterinarian and his wife is just as nasty in this version with Michael Madsen creating a truly repellent character. Where this movie shines is in its production values and solid pacing; the action is exciting and the locations are interesting. Maybe thirty years from now, another group of filmmakers will feel the time is right for another interpretation of "The Getaway", but if they do, I think the King of Cool will still rule.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It sets the mark.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stanpol7
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Folks, why your reviews are so wordy and so empty the same time? This is the best motion picture I ever seen that shows that a real couple is all about. It just sets the mark. This film is about trust, love, devotion, honesty, tenderness, kindness, humanity after all. It shows good couple and bad couple, kind and evil. It is about forgiveness. It is about sharing. Yes, I didn't see the original. What for? I 've got the idea, I praise the play of Alec and Kim and the old guy. Why to judge between one good, kind story and another? This "good" is not good enough compared to the other? BS. This story sets the mark for a couple and the people, and the play is just superb. Final titles music is just superb as well. I wish I could have this kind of trust within my couple one day. If I ever do, I would be happy for the rest of my life. So, come on, folks, turn towards your good half of yourself, open you heart and say that this is a great movie to watch, to keep in your heart and to move on. If those two finally made it, maybe and I can make it one day. So... thank you, guys. 'Cause you just saved my heart again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Palatable...Not Preferable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A retread remake with very little original stuff. Especially the dialog and set pieces are nothing more than a carbon creation with no imagination. There is some style and the film is palatable if not preferable to the original 1972 Sam Peckinpah/Jim Thompson movie. The much talked about Peckinpah violent chops have become standard Hollywood fare and there is nothing new here or even an attempt to time-stamp the presentation. This xerox of a film does cut and paste some new sex scenes but so what. It is explicit and erotic, but, it is the grit and the guts that makes it mark on the crime thriller and the sex is best left for the more lurid of these types. Alec Baldwin is prettier than Steve McQueen and Kim Basinger is prettier than Ali MacGraw.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An 'A-List' cast in a bit of a 'B-List' movie I'm afraid (IMO) But hey, what do I know?...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well shot with some nice stunt work; sadly the script didn't live up to the mechanics of the filmmaking (more on that later). As far as performances go, well everyone did a pretty good job; Alec Baldwin was rough and tough as Carter 'Doc' McCoy and Kim Basinger did pretty well as Carol. Michael Madsen (with one of the great mullets) was pretty hateful as Rudy Travis and James Woods was masterful, as ever, as the evil Jack Benyon. Also worthy of note were; David Morse as Jim Deer Jackson, Jennifer Tilly as Fran Carvey, Richard Farnsworth as Slim and finally, sadly underused, Philip Seymour Hoffman as Frank Hansen (blink & you'll miss him). A film that tries to deal with some quite adult themes but in the end falls quite short of the mark. There is just too much going on, the main characters are not likable enough and there's just no charisma between them. When I find myself looking at my watch I know it's a very bad sign and my watch has seldom been looked at quite so much. On the plus side, I did like the performance of James Woods, he was particularly loathsome; the trouble is, there wasn't enough of him. A poor effort over all; an A-list cast but a bit of a B-list movie I'm afraid NOT RECOMMENDED. My score: 5.2/10 IMDb Score: 5.5/10 (based on 9,314 votes at the time of going to press). MetaScore: NO DATA: (Based on 0 critic reviews provided by Metacritic.com at the time of going to press). Rotten Tomatoes 'Tomatometer' Score: 33/100 (based on 21 reviews counted at the time of going to press). Rotten Tomatoes 'Audience' Score: 30/100 'Want to See' (based on 8,439 user ratings counted at the time of going to press). You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Alec Baldwin is about the worst possible choice for this sort of role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films like The Getaway are always fascinating to me on one level. That's because they demonstrate how important the most elemental and obvious choices in storytelling are and getting just one simple thing wrong can hamstring even the most talented filmmakers and performers. This movie is well written and nicely plotted. It has plenty of action and a couple of nice sex scenes. The cast is as good as you'll get for this sort of thing and the direction is unobjectionably competent. All of that goes almost entirely to waste, however, because the two main characters here are unsympathetic criminals whom the audience has no reason whatsoever to root for or care about what happens to them. Don't get me wrong. You can make a compelling and involving film about bad people. The star of every story doesn't have to be some selfless, noble champion of truth, justice and the American way. But if you're going to make a motion picture about a cold blooded villain, you've got to treat him as such and not try to pass him off as a hero. People like looking at sharks but they won't respond to you trying to pretend a great white shark is as cute and relatively harmless as a bottlenose dolphin. Carter "Doc" McCoy (Alec Baldwin) is a smart and stylish thief who can pretty much figure out how to get in anywhere to get anything. Teamed with his beautiful and devoted wife Carol (Kim Basinger), the two pass through a series of twists and turns until they end up on the run from a treacherous partner, some vengeance-seeking gunmen and the law enforcement. And let me stress again, all of that is well executed. Maybe The Getaway isn't a great action-adventure flick, but it's got all the right parts moving in all the right ways to be a very good one. None of it matters much because the movie never gives you a reason to really care if Doc and Carol live or die, succeed or fail, get caught and sent to prison or escape and live happily ever after. I don't think Doc does a single good or admirable thing until 90 minutes into the film. He's portrayed as a remorseless criminal who has not trouble at all assaulting an innocent cab driver or committing attempted murder by firing a shotgun at pursuing cops. The only good thing Carol does involved morally compromising herself to benefit Doc, which largely negates any credit she gets for being selfless. The Getaway rises and falls on one question. Why should the viewer cheer for Doc and Carol while booing their enemies? No explanation is ever provided, other than the charisma of its two stars. Well, Kim Basinger can project a fragile vulnerability like nobody's business but Carol is bound at the hip to Doc and for all of Alec Baldwin's dramatic and comedic abilities, he's never been a performer who radiated likability. At least not until he let himself get fat for TV. Now, I haven't seen the original and don't know how it handled the question of why people should care about these two characters. Maybe Steve McQueen could pull off what Baldwin couldn't or maybe the audience of the early 70s was more inclined to support unrepentant bad guys like Doc McCoy. This remake doesn't answer the question at all, let alone answer it badly. It would not be at all fair to call The Getaway a bad movie. It's never boring, the action scenes are pretty good and Basinger gets naked on more than one occasion, at least in the unrated version I saw. But I wouldn't have cared a whit if Doc and Carol had wound up dead in the desert instead of riding off into the sunset. I suppose someone else might like it much more than I, but I think the general reaction would be a shrug and the statement "Well, that was okay". In other words, if you've got nothing better to do, there are worse ways of wasting your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining Gangsters.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a pretty decent movie as these things go. Baldwin is Doc McCoy, newly released from prison in order to commit a high-end robbery. Faced with cheating partners, he and his wife, Basinger, make off with a gym bag full of large notes and are pursued throughout the Southwest to the Mexican border, where they finally take off on their own. There is some conflict internal to the family because Basinger had to allow the head of the parole board, also the manager of the robbery, access to her succulent body, and Baldwin resents this, sometimes violently, for the first two thirds of the movie. Lots of action, more explicit sex and brutality, and competent performances, yet something is missing. The chief subtrahend is originality. It's a remake of Sam Pekinpah's film of the same name, with Steve McQueen and Ali McGraw, from the 1960s. Pekinpah's production was edgier, with unexpected incidents, and used some magnificent locations in west Texas. And the production design and set dressing were superior. Even so quotidian a setting as a garbage dump outside of El Paso reeks with atmosphere in Pekinpah's film. Here, it's just a garbage dump. The same can be said of the interior -- and the exterior, for that matter -- of the seedy hotel in which the final shoot out takes place. But it isn't so much these details that detract from one's enjoyment of the film, it's the realization that it was done -- and done better -- almost thirty years earlier by a director in whose veins the balance between booze and talent was proportionate. How much in the way of credit should accrue to writers, directors, and producers who simply imitate a successful earlier movie in an attempt to cash in on its popularity and on the loosening of moral strictures in Hollywood? The remake is not quite shot-for-shot but almost, and much of the dialog is identical. Generally speaking, the performances here aren't bad, even though Baldwin is groomed on his release from the slams like a Hollywood star and lacks McQueen's jailhouse haircut. Kim Basinger does a bit better in the role of prisoner's wife than Ali McGraw did, for that matter. McGraw, unfortunately for her, cute as she was in her darkly furry way, always sounded as if she'd just graduated from Wellesley, which at one time she had. And the direction is competent without adding much to the goings on. Slow motion is used where Pekinpah had used it. And, if you want an instructive scene, watch the trio of bad guy Michael Madsen, Jennifer Tilly, and the DVM James Stevens when Madsen and Tilly become playful and start throwing take-out food at one another -- fried chicken and french fries. Madsen, without provocation, becomes angry and orders Tilly back into the front seat. In Pekinpah's movie the take out is barbecued ribs with sticky tomato sauce and they're tossed back and forth with abandon. The bad guy remains in the back seat and, pelted about the face with a couple of hefty ribs, grows visibly more irritated until he ends the game in an outburst of pique. Both the players and the car's interior are coated with Texas barbecue sauce. There's hardly any comparison in the effectiveness of the two, almost identical, incidents. Pekinpah's is superior. None of this should stand as a condemnation of the remake itself. If it stands alone, it's suspenseful and diverting. The world is largely divided into good guys and bad. That usually makes for easily digested entertainment and this movie delivers the goods.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why remake this film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    martinipromotion
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't get me wrong. I think that Alec Baldwin could have been great in this film, but the made the Doc character way too much of a wuss. Plus many of the scenes looked like an acting class that decided to use the scenes from the original as their scripted material. There was no tension and much of the subtext just disappeared. Still, there was good use of some character actors like Richard Farnsworth slotted into some of the smaller key roles and it was nice to pick up on some of the references to the original film. However, the overall viewing experience was far less fulfilling than the original, that kicked ass from start to finish. Also, do dog race tracks really hold huge amounts of money like that?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rare Chemistry Makes This Remake Work... Look At Michael Madson's Hair!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rpmmurphy
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Alec Baldwin and Kim Basinger were a married couple when they portrayed the married McCoys in this 1994 remake of the 1972. Their on-screen chemistry is incredible. Any time you get this kind of casting occurrence in a film, it is at least worth checking out. Here it really works. The thing that distinguishes this Jim Thompson story is the catch-22 Carol McCoy is faced with- and the percussive effect her necessary action has on the McCoy couple- while the tension is ratcheted up to 11- in their non-stop hour-and-a-half getaway throughout the Southwest. It is a juicy role for a married couple, and Baldwin & Basinger make the most of it. They both are in prime form here and very compelling to watch together. Besides the McCoys (and Richard Farnsworth), it is a B film. Michael Madson's hair is a real challenge to deal with. At least you can cut out of the Richard Marx end credit song. You have to live with Michael Madson's hair for the whole ride. IMDb rating should be around 7.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Passable Action Fare...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the Jim Thompson novel of the same name, 'The Getaway' is A Passable Action Fare, that has some pumping action, a decent script & convincing performances as its aces. 'The Getaway' is the same old story of the good getting back at the bad. 'The Getaway' is passable entertainment. The script is decent, as it offers action & eroticism perfectly, although its clich&eacute;d to the core. Roger Donaldson's Direction is stylish. Cinematography is magnetized. Editing is sharp. Performance-Wise: Alec Bladwin is effortless in an action-oriented role. Kim Basinger looks stunning & adds tremendous style in the goings-on. James Woods is excellent, as always. Michael Madsen is evil personified. Jennifer Tilly is perfect. Philip Seymour Hoffman is efficient. On the whole, 'The Getaway' doesn't disappoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The plan is shut up......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Doc McCoy is put in prison because his partner flew off without him after exchanging a prisoner for a lot of money. Doc knows Jack Benyon, a rich man, is up to something big, so he tells his wife to tell him that he's for sale if Benyon can get him out of prison. Benyon pulls some strings and Doc McCoy is released again. Unfortunately he has to cooperate with the same person that got him to prison..... It's one of those films that never needed to be remade, but at the time, I'm guessing Basinger And Baldwin were the biggest couple in Hollywood, so why not do it again? The Marrying Man made a bundle, as did Love Affair. Oh hang on... But the point of the film is to entertain, and it does, as its one of the best looking action movies of 1994, and for once it treats the audience as an adult and is suitable as an action movie or couples, which is really rare. Baldwin is on the right side of tubby, but he over broods and it really gets to you after a while. Basinger does what. She normally does and smolders like a forties movie star. The rest of the cast are just there for the pay check. Woods does his bad guy who is a little prolific role, and is just there to ignite the passion between the two leads characters, and Madsen features in a really gloomy depressing subplot involving Jennifer Tilly, and its pretty bizarre. The action is good and its edited with a lot of respect, it just feels a little strange, despite the fact its enjoyable and fun, it feels too hasty and rushed. A lot more could have been done. But the one saving grace is at least they never remade it with Demi Moore and Ashton Kutcher.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dethroning the King of Cool?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomsview
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you remake one of Steve McQueen's best-known movies, comparisons are inevitable. Alec Baldwin is believable as the hardened criminal 'Doc' McCoy but where McQueen was able to suggest that there may be mitigating factors in the way his life turned out, Baldwin appears much harder, although he does show that there is at least honour among thieves. When all is said and done, this is a fairly straight remake, and the differences are all in the playing. Doc McCoy, facing a long prison sentence, sends his wife Carol, played by Kim Basinger, to ask for help from a corrupt businessman, Jack Benyon, played by James Woods. In return, Doc agrees to pull a robbery for Benyon. However the payment Benyon asks of Carol McCoy is beyond what Doc had in mind. She pays the price and Doc is released. Doc does the robbery but from this point on a series of double crosses sees Doc and Carol on the run  pursued by other criminals, the law and tensions between themselves. It all comes to a head with a shootout in a hotel in Texas. It is hard to believe that the McQueen version of "The Getaway" is over 40 years old, and that the King of Cool is now long gone. Of course, anyone familiar with the earlier version will know exactly what happens next although the sex scenes featuring Baldwin and Basinger register a few points higher on the Richter scale. In the end, the success or otherwise of this version comes down to nuance and shades of meaning  the way Shakespeare's plays are open to a new interpretation, giving them relevance for each generation. Not that the script for "The Getaway" has much to do with Shakespeare, nor likely to be required reading for high school students in the future, but it does provide a suitable vehicle for Baldwin and Basinger. Alec Baldwin will not replace the memory of Steve McQueen in this role, but Kim Basinger fares better when compared to Ali McGraw. Basinger projects a sultry presence; she is not a particularly animated actress, and the role of Carol McCoy seems tailor-made for her. It is only when she exchanges light dialogue with Richard Farnsworth's character near the end of the movie that you realise how heavy going the rest of the film is, exposing a fundamental problem  The McCoys are not fun people and it is hard for the audience to really like them. The subplot involving McCoy's ex-partner, Rudy, and his encounter with the veterinarian and his wife is just as nasty in this version with Michael Madsen creating a truly repellent character. Where this movie shines is in its production values and solid pacing; the action is exciting and the locations are interesting. Maybe thirty years from now, another group of filmmakers will feel the time is right for another interpretation of "The Getaway", but if they do, I think the King of Cool will still rule.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It sets the mark.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stanpol7
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Folks, why your reviews are so wordy and so empty the same time? This is the best motion picture I ever seen that shows that a real couple is all about. It just sets the mark. This film is about trust, love, devotion, honesty, tenderness, kindness, humanity after all. It shows good couple and bad couple, kind and evil. It is about forgiveness. It is about sharing. Yes, I didn't see the original. What for? I 've got the idea, I praise the play of Alec and Kim and the old guy. Why to judge between one good, kind story and another? This "good" is not good enough compared to the other? BS. This story sets the mark for a couple and the people, and the play is just superb. Final titles music is just superb as well. I wish I could have this kind of trust within my couple one day. If I ever do, I would be happy for the rest of my life. So, come on, folks, turn towards your good half of yourself, open you heart and say that this is a great movie to watch, to keep in your heart and to move on. If those two finally made it, maybe and I can make it one day. So... thank you, guys. 'Cause you just saved my heart again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Palatable...Not Preferable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A retread remake with very little original stuff. Especially the dialog and set pieces are nothing more than a carbon creation with no imagination. There is some style and the film is palatable if not preferable to the original 1972 Sam Peckinpah/Jim Thompson movie. The much talked about Peckinpah violent chops have become standard Hollywood fare and there is nothing new here or even an attempt to time-stamp the presentation. This xerox of a film does cut and paste some new sex scenes but so what. It is explicit and erotic, but, it is the grit and the guts that makes it mark on the crime thriller and the sex is best left for the more lurid of these types. Alec Baldwin is prettier than Steve McQueen and Kim Basinger is prettier than Ali MacGraw.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An 'A-List' cast in a bit of a 'B-List' movie I'm afraid (IMO) But hey, what do I know?...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well shot with some nice stunt work; sadly the script didn't live up to the mechanics of the filmmaking (more on that later). As far as performances go, well everyone did a pretty good job; Alec Baldwin was rough and tough as Carter 'Doc' McCoy and Kim Basinger did pretty well as Carol. Michael Madsen (with one of the great mullets) was pretty hateful as Rudy Travis and James Woods was masterful, as ever, as the evil Jack Benyon. Also worthy of note were; David Morse as Jim Deer Jackson, Jennifer Tilly as Fran Carvey, Richard Farnsworth as Slim and finally, sadly underused, Philip Seymour Hoffman as Frank Hansen (blink & you'll miss him). A film that tries to deal with some quite adult themes but in the end falls quite short of the mark. There is just too much going on, the main characters are not likable enough and there's just no charisma between them. When I find myself looking at my watch I know it's a very bad sign and my watch has seldom been looked at quite so much. On the plus side, I did like the performance of James Woods, he was particularly loathsome; the trouble is, there wasn't enough of him. A poor effort over all; an A-list cast but a bit of a B-list movie I'm afraid NOT RECOMMENDED. My score: 5.2/10 IMDb Score: 5.5/10 (based on 9,314 votes at the time of going to press). MetaScore: NO DATA: (Based on 0 critic reviews provided by Metacritic.com at the time of going to press). Rotten Tomatoes 'Tomatometer' Score: 33/100 (based on 21 reviews counted at the time of going to press). Rotten Tomatoes 'Audience' Score: 30/100 'Want to See' (based on 8,439 user ratings counted at the time of going to press). You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Alec Baldwin is about the worst possible choice for this sort of role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films like The Getaway are always fascinating to me on one level. That's because they demonstrate how important the most elemental and obvious choices in storytelling are and getting just one simple thing wrong can hamstring even the most talented filmmakers and performers. This movie is well written and nicely plotted. It has plenty of action and a couple of nice sex scenes. The cast is as good as you'll get for this sort of thing and the direction is unobjectionably competent. All of that goes almost entirely to waste, however, because the two main characters here are unsympathetic criminals whom the audience has no reason whatsoever to root for or care about what happens to them. Don't get me wrong. You can make a compelling and involving film about bad people. The star of every story doesn't have to be some selfless, noble champion of truth, justice and the American way. But if you're going to make a motion picture about a cold blooded villain, you've got to treat him as such and not try to pass him off as a hero. People like looking at sharks but they won't respond to you trying to pretend a great white shark is as cute and relatively harmless as a bottlenose dolphin. Carter "Doc" McCoy (Alec Baldwin) is a smart and stylish thief who can pretty much figure out how to get in anywhere to get anything. Teamed with his beautiful and devoted wife Carol (Kim Basinger), the two pass through a series of twists and turns until they end up on the run from a treacherous partner, some vengeance-seeking gunmen and the law enforcement. And let me stress again, all of that is well executed. Maybe The Getaway isn't a great action-adventure flick, but it's got all the right parts moving in all the right ways to be a very good one. None of it matters much because the movie never gives you a reason to really care if Doc and Carol live or die, succeed or fail, get caught and sent to prison or escape and live happily ever after. I don't think Doc does a single good or admirable thing until 90 minutes into the film. He's portrayed as a remorseless criminal who has not trouble at all assaulting an innocent cab driver or committing attempted murder by firing a shotgun at pursuing cops. The only good thing Carol does involved morally compromising herself to benefit Doc, which largely negates any credit she gets for being selfless. The Getaway rises and falls on one question. Why should the viewer cheer for Doc and Carol while booing their enemies? No explanation is ever provided, other than the charisma of its two stars. Well, Kim Basinger can project a fragile vulnerability like nobody's business but Carol is bound at the hip to Doc and for all of Alec Baldwin's dramatic and comedic abilities, he's never been a performer who radiated likability. At least not until he let himself get fat for TV. Now, I haven't seen the original and don't know how it handled the question of why people should care about these two characters. Maybe Steve McQueen could pull off what Baldwin couldn't or maybe the audience of the early 70s was more inclined to support unrepentant bad guys like Doc McCoy. This remake doesn't answer the question at all, let alone answer it badly. It would not be at all fair to call The Getaway a bad movie. It's never boring, the action scenes are pretty good and Basinger gets naked on more than one occasion, at least in the unrated version I saw. But I wouldn't have cared a whit if Doc and Carol had wound up dead in the desert instead of riding off into the sunset. I suppose someone else might like it much more than I, but I think the general reaction would be a shrug and the statement "Well, that was okay". In other words, if you've got nothing better to do, there are worse ways of wasting your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining Gangsters.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a pretty decent movie as these things go. Baldwin is Doc McCoy, newly released from prison in order to commit a high-end robbery. Faced with cheating partners, he and his wife, Basinger, make off with a gym bag full of large notes and are pursued throughout the Southwest to the Mexican border, where they finally take off on their own. There is some conflict internal to the family because Basinger had to allow the head of the parole board, also the manager of the robbery, access to her succulent body, and Baldwin resents this, sometimes violently, for the first two thirds of the movie. Lots of action, more explicit sex and brutality, and competent performances, yet something is missing. The chief subtrahend is originality. It's a remake of Sam Pekinpah's film of the same name, with Steve McQueen and Ali McGraw, from the 1960s. Pekinpah's production was edgier, with unexpected incidents, and used some magnificent locations in west Texas. And the production design and set dressing were superior. Even so quotidian a setting as a garbage dump outside of El Paso reeks with atmosphere in Pekinpah's film. Here, it's just a garbage dump. The same can be said of the interior -- and the exterior, for that matter -- of the seedy hotel in which the final shoot out takes place. But it isn't so much these details that detract from one's enjoyment of the film, it's the realization that it was done -- and done better -- almost thirty years earlier by a director in whose veins the balance between booze and talent was proportionate. How much in the way of credit should accrue to writers, directors, and producers who simply imitate a successful earlier movie in an attempt to cash in on its popularity and on the loosening of moral strictures in Hollywood? The remake is not quite shot-for-shot but almost, and much of the dialog is identical. Generally speaking, the performances here aren't bad, even though Baldwin is groomed on his release from the slams like a Hollywood star and lacks McQueen's jailhouse haircut. Kim Basinger does a bit better in the role of prisoner's wife than Ali McGraw did, for that matter. McGraw, unfortunately for her, cute as she was in her darkly furry way, always sounded as if she'd just graduated from Wellesley, which at one time she had. And the direction is competent without adding much to the goings on. Slow motion is used where Pekinpah had used it. And, if you want an instructive scene, watch the trio of bad guy Michael Madsen, Jennifer Tilly, and the DVM James Stevens when Madsen and Tilly become playful and start throwing take-out food at one another -- fried chicken and french fries. Madsen, without provocation, becomes angry and orders Tilly back into the front seat. In Pekinpah's movie the take out is barbecued ribs with sticky tomato sauce and they're tossed back and forth with abandon. The bad guy remains in the back seat and, pelted about the face with a couple of hefty ribs, grows visibly more irritated until he ends the game in an outburst of pique. Both the players and the car's interior are coated with Texas barbecue sauce. There's hardly any comparison in the effectiveness of the two, almost identical, incidents. Pekinpah's is superior. None of this should stand as a condemnation of the remake itself. If it stands alone, it's suspenseful and diverting. The world is largely divided into good guys and bad. That usually makes for easily digested entertainment and this movie delivers the goods.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why remake this film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    martinipromotion
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't get me wrong. I think that Alec Baldwin could have been great in this film, but the made the Doc character way too much of a wuss. Plus many of the scenes looked like an acting class that decided to use the scenes from the original as their scripted material. There was no tension and much of the subtext just disappeared. Still, there was good use of some character actors like Richard Farnsworth slotted into some of the smaller key roles and it was nice to pick up on some of the references to the original film. However, the overall viewing experience was far less fulfilling than the original, that kicked ass from start to finish. Also, do dog race tracks really hold huge amounts of money like that?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rare Chemistry Makes This Remake Work... Look At Michael Madson's Hair!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rpmmurphy
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Alec Baldwin and Kim Basinger were a married couple when they portrayed the married McCoys in this 1994 remake of the 1972. Their on-screen chemistry is incredible. Any time you get this kind of casting occurrence in a film, it is at least worth checking out. Here it really works. The thing that distinguishes this Jim Thompson story is the catch-22 Carol McCoy is faced with- and the percussive effect her necessary action has on the McCoy couple- while the tension is ratcheted up to 11- in their non-stop hour-and-a-half getaway throughout the Southwest. It is a juicy role for a married couple, and Baldwin & Basinger make the most of it. They both are in prime form here and very compelling to watch together. Besides the McCoys (and Richard Farnsworth), it is a B film. Michael Madson's hair is a real challenge to deal with. At least you can cut out of the Richard Marx end credit song. You have to live with Michael Madson's hair for the whole ride. IMDb rating should be around 7.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Passable Action Fare...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the Jim Thompson novel of the same name, 'The Getaway' is A Passable Action Fare, that has some pumping action, a decent script & convincing performances as its aces. 'The Getaway' is the same old story of the good getting back at the bad. 'The Getaway' is passable entertainment. The script is decent, as it offers action & eroticism perfectly, although its clich&eacute;d to the core. Roger Donaldson's Direction is stylish. Cinematography is magnetized. Editing is sharp. Performance-Wise: Alec Bladwin is effortless in an action-oriented role. Kim Basinger looks stunning & adds tremendous style in the goings-on. James Woods is excellent, as always. Michael Madsen is evil personified. Jennifer Tilly is perfect. Philip Seymour Hoffman is efficient. On the whole, 'The Getaway' doesn't disappoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The plan is shut up......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Doc McCoy is put in prison because his partner flew off without him after exchanging a prisoner for a lot of money. Doc knows Jack Benyon, a rich man, is up to something big, so he tells his wife to tell him that he's for sale if Benyon can get him out of prison. Benyon pulls some strings and Doc McCoy is released again. Unfortunately he has to cooperate with the same person that got him to prison..... It's one of those films that never needed to be remade, but at the time, I'm guessing Basinger And Baldwin were the biggest couple in Hollywood, so why not do it again? The Marrying Man made a bundle, as did Love Affair. Oh hang on... But the point of the film is to entertain, and it does, as its one of the best looking action movies of 1994, and for once it treats the audience as an adult and is suitable as an action movie or couples, which is really rare. Baldwin is on the right side of tubby, but he over broods and it really gets to you after a while. Basinger does what. She normally does and smolders like a forties movie star. The rest of the cast are just there for the pay check. Woods does his bad guy who is a little prolific role, and is just there to ignite the passion between the two leads characters, and Madsen features in a really gloomy depressing subplot involving Jennifer Tilly, and its pretty bizarre. The action is good and its edited with a lot of respect, it just feels a little strange, despite the fact its enjoyable and fun, it feels too hasty and rushed. A lot more could have been done. But the one saving grace is at least they never remade it with Demi Moore and Ashton Kutcher.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dethroning the King of Cool?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomsview
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you remake one of Steve McQueen's best-known movies, comparisons are inevitable. Alec Baldwin is believable as the hardened criminal 'Doc' McCoy but where McQueen was able to suggest that there may be mitigating factors in the way his life turned out, Baldwin appears much harder, although he does show that there is at least honour among thieves. When all is said and done, this is a fairly straight remake, and the differences are all in the playing. Doc McCoy, facing a long prison sentence, sends his wife Carol, played by Kim Basinger, to ask for help from a corrupt businessman, Jack Benyon, played by James Woods. In return, Doc agrees to pull a robbery for Benyon. However the payment Benyon asks of Carol McCoy is beyond what Doc had in mind. She pays the price and Doc is released. Doc does the robbery but from this point on a series of double crosses sees Doc and Carol on the run  pursued by other criminals, the law and tensions between themselves. It all comes to a head with a shootout in a hotel in Texas. It is hard to believe that the McQueen version of "The Getaway" is over 40 years old, and that the King of Cool is now long gone. Of course, anyone familiar with the earlier version will know exactly what happens next although the sex scenes featuring Baldwin and Basinger register a few points higher on the Richter scale. In the end, the success or otherwise of this version comes down to nuance and shades of meaning  the way Shakespeare's plays are open to a new interpretation, giving them relevance for each generation. Not that the script for "The Getaway" has much to do with Shakespeare, nor likely to be required reading for high school students in the future, but it does provide a suitable vehicle for Baldwin and Basinger. Alec Baldwin will not replace the memory of Steve McQueen in this role, but Kim Basinger fares better when compared to Ali McGraw. Basinger projects a sultry presence; she is not a particularly animated actress, and the role of Carol McCoy seems tailor-made for her. It is only when she exchanges light dialogue with Richard Farnsworth's character near the end of the movie that you realise how heavy going the rest of the film is, exposing a fundamental problem  The McCoys are not fun people and it is hard for the audience to really like them. The subplot involving McCoy's ex-partner, Rudy, and his encounter with the veterinarian and his wife is just as nasty in this version with Michael Madsen creating a truly repellent character. Where this movie shines is in its production values and solid pacing; the action is exciting and the locations are interesting. Maybe thirty years from now, another group of filmmakers will feel the time is right for another interpretation of "The Getaway", but if they do, I think the King of Cool will still rule.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It sets the mark.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stanpol7
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Folks, why your reviews are so wordy and so empty the same time? This is the best motion picture I ever seen that shows that a real couple is all about. It just sets the mark. This film is about trust, love, devotion, honesty, tenderness, kindness, humanity after all. It shows good couple and bad couple, kind and evil. It is about forgiveness. It is about sharing. Yes, I didn't see the original. What for? I 've got the idea, I praise the play of Alec and Kim and the old guy. Why to judge between one good, kind story and another? This "good" is not good enough compared to the other? BS. This story sets the mark for a couple and the people, and the play is just superb. Final titles music is just superb as well. I wish I could have this kind of trust within my couple one day. If I ever do, I would be happy for the rest of my life. So, come on, folks, turn towards your good half of yourself, open you heart and say that this is a great movie to watch, to keep in your heart and to move on. If those two finally made it, maybe and I can make it one day. So... thank you, guys. 'Cause you just saved my heart again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Palatable...Not Preferable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A retread remake with very little original stuff. Especially the dialog and set pieces are nothing more than a carbon creation with no imagination. There is some style and the film is palatable if not preferable to the original 1972 Sam Peckinpah/Jim Thompson movie. The much talked about Peckinpah violent chops have become standard Hollywood fare and there is nothing new here or even an attempt to time-stamp the presentation. This xerox of a film does cut and paste some new sex scenes but so what. It is explicit and erotic, but, it is the grit and the guts that makes it mark on the crime thriller and the sex is best left for the more lurid of these types. Alec Baldwin is prettier than Steve McQueen and Kim Basinger is prettier than Ali MacGraw.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An 'A-List' cast in a bit of a 'B-List' movie I'm afraid (IMO) But hey, what do I know?...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well shot with some nice stunt work; sadly the script didn't live up to the mechanics of the filmmaking (more on that later). As far as performances go, well everyone did a pretty good job; Alec Baldwin was rough and tough as Carter 'Doc' McCoy and Kim Basinger did pretty well as Carol. Michael Madsen (with one of the great mullets) was pretty hateful as Rudy Travis and James Woods was masterful, as ever, as the evil Jack Benyon. Also worthy of note were; David Morse as Jim Deer Jackson, Jennifer Tilly as Fran Carvey, Richard Farnsworth as Slim and finally, sadly underused, Philip Seymour Hoffman as Frank Hansen (blink & you'll miss him). A film that tries to deal with some quite adult themes but in the end falls quite short of the mark. There is just too much going on, the main characters are not likable enough and there's just no charisma between them. When I find myself looking at my watch I know it's a very bad sign and my watch has seldom been looked at quite so much. On the plus side, I did like the performance of James Woods, he was particularly loathsome; the trouble is, there wasn't enough of him. A poor effort over all; an A-list cast but a bit of a B-list movie I'm afraid NOT RECOMMENDED. My score: 5.2/10 IMDb Score: 5.5/10 (based on 9,314 votes at the time of going to press). MetaScore: NO DATA: (Based on 0 critic reviews provided by Metacritic.com at the time of going to press). Rotten Tomatoes 'Tomatometer' Score: 33/100 (based on 21 reviews counted at the time of going to press). Rotten Tomatoes 'Audience' Score: 30/100 'Want to See' (based on 8,439 user ratings counted at the time of going to press). You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Alec Baldwin is about the worst possible choice for this sort of role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films like The Getaway are always fascinating to me on one level. That's because they demonstrate how important the most elemental and obvious choices in storytelling are and getting just one simple thing wrong can hamstring even the most talented filmmakers and performers. This movie is well written and nicely plotted. It has plenty of action and a couple of nice sex scenes. The cast is as good as you'll get for this sort of thing and the direction is unobjectionably competent. All of that goes almost entirely to waste, however, because the two main characters here are unsympathetic criminals whom the audience has no reason whatsoever to root for or care about what happens to them. Don't get me wrong. You can make a compelling and involving film about bad people. The star of every story doesn't have to be some selfless, noble champion of truth, justice and the American way. But if you're going to make a motion picture about a cold blooded villain, you've got to treat him as such and not try to pass him off as a hero. People like looking at sharks but they won't respond to you trying to pretend a great white shark is as cute and relatively harmless as a bottlenose dolphin. Carter "Doc" McCoy (Alec Baldwin) is a smart and stylish thief who can pretty much figure out how to get in anywhere to get anything. Teamed with his beautiful and devoted wife Carol (Kim Basinger), the two pass through a series of twists and turns until they end up on the run from a treacherous partner, some vengeance-seeking gunmen and the law enforcement. And let me stress again, all of that is well executed. Maybe The Getaway isn't a great action-adventure flick, but it's got all the right parts moving in all the right ways to be a very good one. None of it matters much because the movie never gives you a reason to really care if Doc and Carol live or die, succeed or fail, get caught and sent to prison or escape and live happily ever after. I don't think Doc does a single good or admirable thing until 90 minutes into the film. He's portrayed as a remorseless criminal who has not trouble at all assaulting an innocent cab driver or committing attempted murder by firing a shotgun at pursuing cops. The only good thing Carol does involved morally compromising herself to benefit Doc, which largely negates any credit she gets for being selfless. The Getaway rises and falls on one question. Why should the viewer cheer for Doc and Carol while booing their enemies? No explanation is ever provided, other than the charisma of its two stars. Well, Kim Basinger can project a fragile vulnerability like nobody's business but Carol is bound at the hip to Doc and for all of Alec Baldwin's dramatic and comedic abilities, he's never been a performer who radiated likability. At least not until he let himself get fat for TV. Now, I haven't seen the original and don't know how it handled the question of why people should care about these two characters. Maybe Steve McQueen could pull off what Baldwin couldn't or maybe the audience of the early 70s was more inclined to support unrepentant bad guys like Doc McCoy. This remake doesn't answer the question at all, let alone answer it badly. It would not be at all fair to call The Getaway a bad movie. It's never boring, the action scenes are pretty good and Basinger gets naked on more than one occasion, at least in the unrated version I saw. But I wouldn't have cared a whit if Doc and Carol had wound up dead in the desert instead of riding off into the sunset. I suppose someone else might like it much more than I, but I think the general reaction would be a shrug and the statement "Well, that was okay". In other words, if you've got nothing better to do, there are worse ways of wasting your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining Gangsters.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a pretty decent movie as these things go. Baldwin is Doc McCoy, newly released from prison in order to commit a high-end robbery. Faced with cheating partners, he and his wife, Basinger, make off with a gym bag full of large notes and are pursued throughout the Southwest to the Mexican border, where they finally take off on their own. There is some conflict internal to the family because Basinger had to allow the head of the parole board, also the manager of the robbery, access to her succulent body, and Baldwin resents this, sometimes violently, for the first two thirds of the movie. Lots of action, more explicit sex and brutality, and competent performances, yet something is missing. The chief subtrahend is originality. It's a remake of Sam Pekinpah's film of the same name, with Steve McQueen and Ali McGraw, from the 1960s. Pekinpah's production was edgier, with unexpected incidents, and used some magnificent locations in west Texas. And the production design and set dressing were superior. Even so quotidian a setting as a garbage dump outside of El Paso reeks with atmosphere in Pekinpah's film. Here, it's just a garbage dump. The same can be said of the interior -- and the exterior, for that matter -- of the seedy hotel in which the final shoot out takes place. But it isn't so much these details that detract from one's enjoyment of the film, it's the realization that it was done -- and done better -- almost thirty years earlier by a director in whose veins the balance between booze and talent was proportionate. How much in the way of credit should accrue to writers, directors, and producers who simply imitate a successful earlier movie in an attempt to cash in on its popularity and on the loosening of moral strictures in Hollywood? The remake is not quite shot-for-shot but almost, and much of the dialog is identical. Generally speaking, the performances here aren't bad, even though Baldwin is groomed on his release from the slams like a Hollywood star and lacks McQueen's jailhouse haircut. Kim Basinger does a bit better in the role of prisoner's wife than Ali McGraw did, for that matter. McGraw, unfortunately for her, cute as she was in her darkly furry way, always sounded as if she'd just graduated from Wellesley, which at one time she had. And the direction is competent without adding much to the goings on. Slow motion is used where Pekinpah had used it. And, if you want an instructive scene, watch the trio of bad guy Michael Madsen, Jennifer Tilly, and the DVM James Stevens when Madsen and Tilly become playful and start throwing take-out food at one another -- fried chicken and french fries. Madsen, without provocation, becomes angry and orders Tilly back into the front seat. In Pekinpah's movie the take out is barbecued ribs with sticky tomato sauce and they're tossed back and forth with abandon. The bad guy remains in the back seat and, pelted about the face with a couple of hefty ribs, grows visibly more irritated until he ends the game in an outburst of pique. Both the players and the car's interior are coated with Texas barbecue sauce. There's hardly any comparison in the effectiveness of the two, almost identical, incidents. Pekinpah's is superior. None of this should stand as a condemnation of the remake itself. If it stands alone, it's suspenseful and diverting. The world is largely divided into good guys and bad. That usually makes for easily digested entertainment and this movie delivers the goods.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why remake this film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    martinipromotion
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't get me wrong. I think that Alec Baldwin could have been great in this film, but the made the Doc character way too much of a wuss. Plus many of the scenes looked like an acting class that decided to use the scenes from the original as their scripted material. There was no tension and much of the subtext just disappeared. Still, there was good use of some character actors like Richard Farnsworth slotted into some of the smaller key roles and it was nice to pick up on some of the references to the original film. However, the overall viewing experience was far less fulfilling than the original, that kicked ass from start to finish. Also, do dog race tracks really hold huge amounts of money like that?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rare Chemistry Makes This Remake Work... Look At Michael Madson's Hair!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rpmmurphy
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Alec Baldwin and Kim Basinger were a married couple when they portrayed the married McCoys in this 1994 remake of the 1972. Their on-screen chemistry is incredible. Any time you get this kind of casting occurrence in a film, it is at least worth checking out. Here it really works. The thing that distinguishes this Jim Thompson story is the catch-22 Carol McCoy is faced with- and the percussive effect her necessary action has on the McCoy couple- while the tension is ratcheted up to 11- in their non-stop hour-and-a-half getaway throughout the Southwest. It is a juicy role for a married couple, and Baldwin & Basinger make the most of it. They both are in prime form here and very compelling to watch together. Besides the McCoys (and Richard Farnsworth), it is a B film. Michael Madson's hair is a real challenge to deal with. At least you can cut out of the Richard Marx end credit song. You have to live with Michael Madson's hair for the whole ride. IMDb rating should be around 7.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
