<filme>
 <id>
  1313
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120782
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1998
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Crime em Palmetto
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A recently released ex-con gets involved in a fake kidnapping scheme that turns very real.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  After being released from prison on a bum charge, Harry Barber is out for some payback to regain the two years he has lost. He is hired by Mrs. Malroux to fake the kidnapping of her stepdaughter (the daughter of a dying millionaire). He discovers that he is being set up on multiple levels and will soon face a longer prison sentence if he does not prove the truth to the police.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Mystery
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   prison
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   fake kidnapping
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   scam
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   recovering alcoholic
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sculptor
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Volker Schl&ouml;ndorff
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   James Hadley Chase
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   E. Max Frye
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Woody Harrelson
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Elisabeth Shue
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Gina Gershon
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Under-rated Neo Noir
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sankhan99
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another underrated movie on IMDb like many other suspense/mystery thrillers. Seeing the rating on IMDb and then watching suspense/mystery thrillers made me feel that movies of mentioned genre are not rated well here. They are often underrated and because of that many suspense/mystery lovers might have missed quite brilliant movies. I rather put it in a way that Neo Noirs are actually not well rated here. Any suspense/mystery lover can easily like this movie. Movie has quite good twists and turns which are difficult to predict. Screenplay is written well but could be better. Woody has done great job but I feel Elizabeth was bit over acting. Direction is good. Overall movie has great neo noir feeling. I recommend this movie specially to neo noir lovers, they will not regret watch it. There are few others which I like to mention are well underrated like Wolfgang's Shattered, John Dhal's Kill me again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie is rated 6 out of 10?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oragex
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Seriously, those who rated this like some random stuff, are already medium to heavily hollyntoxicated. This is for the remaining ones who know what lively and charming acting is. This is the kind of entertainment movie I'm not sick to see. It's FRESH, teasing, simple and colored, something Hollywood guys forgot some time ago. Good actors but again not in the H. style (is that a style anyway?). Compared with Hollywood productions this movie is the same as going to a lively, friendly, full with warm locals bar, or going to some fancy club, full of models where nobody's talking with each other. Stop bashing, this is not perfect, but I prefer it to standard movies who are done by the book to the point the actors cannot express themselves any long.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sad day for James Hadley Chase
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pcsarkar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some highly talented authors have the misfortune of having their works being produced as trash in cinematic form. Like HP Lovecraft. James Hadley Chase was another one such unfortunate author. Being the owner of the biggest fan site of Chase on the Net, I eagerly picked up this movie recently, although having read its reviews, I was filled with trepidation. Without giving away the plot, some of my personal gripes are as follows: 1. Why the title change? "Just Another Sucker" is way more catchy and appropriate than the stupid "Palmetto" What the hell is Palmetto by the way? 2. Whats with the cockroaches throughout the movie? Palmetto bugs? What was the director thinking of? 3. While JHC developed the plot in his own awesome manner, the way the script-writer went about developing the script absolutely destroyed the suspense element. The motivation and desperation of the lead character in taking up such a dicey assignment went totally missing. The movie's mumbling, bumbling Harry Barber comes across as a parody of the novel's shrewd Harry Barber, who planned the kidnapping drama as meticulously as he could. 4. On second thoughts, most of the characters come across as parodies of their original selves, except perhaps, Nina (Gina Gershon). 5. Liquid Nitrogen being used to dissolve bodies to flush them down drains?? Hmmm... 6. Two Odettes? A big hmmmm.. I can go on and on.. but then, to hell with it. Its simply not worth the effort. Chase, 'ol friend, as a big fan of yours, I sympathize and even apologize for this fiasco of a movie. If I ever have enough money, I will make a film of one (or more) of your novels, and present it to the audience, the way you would have wanted it to be presented.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best James Hadley Chase adaptation.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviestar26
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just recently I came across the late author James Hadley Chase. I was surprised at the huge number of novels he had written over the 50s and 60s. A movie I had also watched a movie earlier which was giving reference to behind the inspiration used. I decided to dwell in to the writers works and discover what made him so popular. After reading one I could not give up. I was surprised by the themes and characters that were involved in the novels. Many times it felt like I was not reading a book, but watching a movie. Given the fact that his books were not long made it more easier to complete them. Many of Chase's novels have been adapted in to movies. The trend of Chase adaptations became a cult trend for french and Italian cinema. However here in the west it never took off. Novels like 'Miss Shunaway waves a wand', 'The set up' and 'Hit and run' were adapted for the big screen. Unfortunately they did not make bells ring at the box office. The novel 'Just another sucker' is made in to a movie and The theme became instantly familiar to me as the first few minutes begin to roll. The name of the novel has been changed to 'Palmetto' for the movie. As one watches on you realise the noir atmosphere is prevalent in almost every scene. An old novel's transition to modern day cinema makes an impressive outcome. Both Woody Harrelson and Elizabeth Shue were perfect choices for the casting. Their performances really make the movie for what it is. Volker Schlondorff makes a sincere attempt at presenting his perception of the novel. He has incorporated all his basic understanding of the theme and there is never a feeling that a foreign director made the movie. He has made many dull moments enhanced by capturing the character's expressions. There are a few scenes and moments that make the movie longer in duration but this does not put the viewer off. It was disappointing that the movie did not have huge box office status when it released. Since the theme of kidnapping was used, and one has to contend with releases like 'fargo' and 'The big lebowski', I would assume that this movie went unnoticed. I think that the reason behind its failure was directly due to the incorrect release date. Maybe a year early or late would have had some positive impact on the movie's success ratio. *********************SPOILERS AHEAD********************* Woody Harrelson plays Harry Barber who is released from prison after spending two years there for no reason. He considers going to Miami but his girlfriend (Gina Gershon) persuades him to not leave. At a bar he encounters a woman who who is the wife of a rich man by the name or Mr Malroux. She tempts him in to a fake kidnapping scheme where her step daughter (Chloe Sevigny) will be involved in. The ranson will be 500,000 dollars. All that Harry has to do is make a phone call and send the threatening letter demanding the ransom. Initially Harry does not approve but later he convinces himself. After meeting the step daughter the plan is put ahead. The girl stays away from home for a short time and her father delivers the money in a suitcase to the location mentioned. He is later shocked to discover that the girl has been killed and he has a body to dispose of that is not easy to do. The local authorities are on the case and 1 plus 1 does not seem to be adding to two for Harry. Plus what he received was not cash at all. The situation becomes more and more sinister and paranoia begins to take over him. To his surprise he later discovers that at every step of the way more and more clues will point towards him as the culprit behind Mr Malroux's daughters disappearance. He realises eventually that he was just used for the whole plan. Eventually he has to prove his innocence to the authorities. ************************END OF SPOILERS********************** I could not help getting a dejavu of 'Body Heat' while watching this movie. Many situations were reminiscent of the classic. The setting of Florida too was an indicator of this. The constant sweating faces and sexual intimidating scenes also were a giveaway. But the similarities end there. Movies like 'Derailed and 'Out of time' too had a similar concept. The director has incorporated many slow moving frames which highlight plot twists and key moments which are crucial. These are a highlight and really create the right tone at certain intervals. With a running time of 1 hour and 53 minutes the movie does tend to take long to get the plot to progress. Much of the first hour is spent behind planning the kidnapping. However the second hour's pace builds up. Much of that specific portion of the movie delivers plot twists after plot twists. These makes for a very intriguing experiences as the movie progresses. The usage of a background score is very minimum. But the sleazy sounds do appear regularly at important moments because you can't have a noir movie without them. This is one of Woody Harrelson's best performances. He has managed to blend many moods and shades in to one role. We can feel sympathy for his character as well as hating him. We can sense his paranoia and unsettling feeling while just watching him. There are certain moments where one would also laugh at him. He truly did play the man in despair from the heart. Elizabeth Shue would have given any actress from the 40s and 50s a run for their money as she played a femme fatale brilliantly. Her body language and acting were just on the mark. Overall this is the perfect treat for fans of noir. I would also recommend watching it with others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Chinatown" comes to Palmetto ..............
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In what seems to be an obvious reference to "Chinatown", the sexy would be kidnapper is named Mulroux, not Mulray, but Mulroux. Woody Harrelson is set up nicely to take the fall for a murder, hidden behind a fake kidnapping. Sexy women abound, and plot twists are nicely spaced along the way. Character development is acceptable, but not great, and believability at times is stretched. Nevertheless, "Palmetto" is a decent neo-noir that maintains interest throughout. My only letdown was an ending that seemed unsatisfying. Rather than compare this to blockbusters like "Body Heat" or "Chinatown", I would say it is more along the lines of "Red Rock West". - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good story, although the movie could have been better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Volker Schlondorff's "Palmetto" has a very interesting plot, although I think that the movie could be better. Woody Harrelson plays an ex-con who gets drawn into a supposedly fake kidnapping in Florida. The movie contains a series of plot twists (I won't name them, lest I spoil the whole thing), but nothing gratuitous. You have to realize that this is not a bad movie; it's just that Schlondorff could have done a better job with it (especially towards the end). Overall, I do recommend it. You'll probably like it. Also starring Elisabeth Shue, Gina Gershon, Michael Rapaport, Chloe Sevigny and Tom Wright. Schlondorff also directed "The Tin Drum" and "Strajk - Die Heldin von Danzig".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked a lot this modern film noir
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (butchfilms@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like this movie very much, each time I catch it by any chance on TV when I am making zapping I watch it again. I think that "Palmetto" deserves 7.5 stars, I was surprised to find out it has just 5.6 stars. I have always liked the work of Woody Harrelson, but in this movie he is great as the journalist Harry Barber. the supporting cast is very good too. The plot of the movie is about Harry Barber a journalist that is released from jail for being found innocent. After that he is going to have problems to find a job until a sexy woman proposes him to be involved in a false kidnapping for some easy money, because of this Harry is going to get in a lot of troubles. I recommend you to watch this movie, I found it very entertaining since the beginning until the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Very Underrated 'Neo Noir'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this is one of those modern-day film noirs (neo noir) that went under the radar. It is excellent, and few people know about it. It's a very underrated film. It had an interesting and unpredictable story with some very neat twists which a good noir might have. I'm not really sure I liked the very ending, but I sure enjoyed the rest of it. That entertainment included ogling a couple of sexy female leads, played by Elisabeth Shue and Chloe Sevigny and I loved the wonderful colors in this movie. Not only was the cinematography great, so was the soundtrack with some solid blues tracks. The guitar playing reminded me of the Ry Cooder's work in "Midnight Run." The movie was labeled by some national critics as a "poor man's 'Body Heat.'" Well, that's fine with me because I liked "Body Heat" a lot, too. If you liked that, you should like this movie, too. Yes, there are a few holes in the story but nothing that damaged the storyline to any degree. Woody Harrelson was good in the lead and Gina Gershon and Michael Rapaport provided solid performance in supporting roles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Okay Thriller With Tons of Sizzling Sex!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan1863Sickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Harrelson plays Harry Barber, a wise guy reporter who just did some jail time for a dirty deal that wasn't his fault. When he gets out of the slam, he just wants his life back. But bad breaks and shifty women soon send him right back into the seamy, sexy world of double deals and decadent rich folks, in a steamy Florida town called PALMETTO. The plot of this movie is okay, and the story moves along at a slow, but steady pace. But what really makes it work is the sexual subtext of a man fighting to maintain both his moral high ground and his sexual potency while surrounded by a trio of luscious, dangerous women. At first, Harry Barber's biggest problem is finding a job. When he gets out of jail, his loyal girl friend Nina (Gina Gershon) is waiting to meet him. Dark-eyed Nina is the ideal best pal -- friendly, loving, and supportive. Not only does she take Harry in, she's more than willing to pay for his expenses and keep him on as her "assistant" until he finds a job. The sizzling tension between them is that Nina wants a docile and submissive male concubine while Harry is too macho to accept the pleasures Nina can provide. He's clearly the kind of man who feels that it's emasculating for a woman to have too much money or power in a relationship. Still, Nina is so stunningly attractive and so clearly besotted with him that he almost unwillingly sinks into dependence. Watch the early morning scene where he makes coffee for Nina and tensely waits for her approval! It's pure Neanderthal male pride that drives Harry to accept a "dirty job" from blonde temptress Rhea Malroux. Elisabeth Shue has never, ever been more radiant than in this classic noir role of the black widow. The sex scenes are sizzling precisely because Rhea is using Harry and preparing to feed on him. Yet when her spoiled step daughter, Odette, appears, Harry is forced to pleasure not one but two of the most dangerous women in Palmetto! Frankly, the ending of this movie is not very satisfying -- Harry does not really triumph in the end, nor does he learn the value of Nina's loyalty and support. In the end it's more of a paranoid male fantasy than a real classic thriller, but still worth watching just for the sizzling sexual subtext between Harry and his three witches!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I have a genuine question - Please help me.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itsd-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie was fine, i agree with most of the other comments, a little slow, bad color, good plot, but worth watching. I just want to know, around 55 minutes into the movie, when Woody starts running on the beach away from the police, and he gets shot and falls on the sand then he gets up and starts running again. What is the significance on the lady in black holding a baby, just meters from the water edge. She does nothing and adds nothing to the movie. She then disappears behind some rocks, as Woody is running towards her. Please help....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Under-rated Neo Noir
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sankhan99
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another underrated movie on IMDb like many other suspense/mystery thrillers. Seeing the rating on IMDb and then watching suspense/mystery thrillers made me feel that movies of mentioned genre are not rated well here. They are often underrated and because of that many suspense/mystery lovers might have missed quite brilliant movies. I rather put it in a way that Neo Noirs are actually not well rated here. Any suspense/mystery lover can easily like this movie. Movie has quite good twists and turns which are difficult to predict. Screenplay is written well but could be better. Woody has done great job but I feel Elizabeth was bit over acting. Direction is good. Overall movie has great neo noir feeling. I recommend this movie specially to neo noir lovers, they will not regret watch it. There are few others which I like to mention are well underrated like Wolfgang's Shattered, John Dhal's Kill me again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie is rated 6 out of 10?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oragex
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Seriously, those who rated this like some random stuff, are already medium to heavily hollyntoxicated. This is for the remaining ones who know what lively and charming acting is. This is the kind of entertainment movie I'm not sick to see. It's FRESH, teasing, simple and colored, something Hollywood guys forgot some time ago. Good actors but again not in the H. style (is that a style anyway?). Compared with Hollywood productions this movie is the same as going to a lively, friendly, full with warm locals bar, or going to some fancy club, full of models where nobody's talking with each other. Stop bashing, this is not perfect, but I prefer it to standard movies who are done by the book to the point the actors cannot express themselves any long.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sad day for James Hadley Chase
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pcsarkar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some highly talented authors have the misfortune of having their works being produced as trash in cinematic form. Like HP Lovecraft. James Hadley Chase was another one such unfortunate author. Being the owner of the biggest fan site of Chase on the Net, I eagerly picked up this movie recently, although having read its reviews, I was filled with trepidation. Without giving away the plot, some of my personal gripes are as follows: 1. Why the title change? "Just Another Sucker" is way more catchy and appropriate than the stupid "Palmetto" What the hell is Palmetto by the way? 2. Whats with the cockroaches throughout the movie? Palmetto bugs? What was the director thinking of? 3. While JHC developed the plot in his own awesome manner, the way the script-writer went about developing the script absolutely destroyed the suspense element. The motivation and desperation of the lead character in taking up such a dicey assignment went totally missing. The movie's mumbling, bumbling Harry Barber comes across as a parody of the novel's shrewd Harry Barber, who planned the kidnapping drama as meticulously as he could. 4. On second thoughts, most of the characters come across as parodies of their original selves, except perhaps, Nina (Gina Gershon). 5. Liquid Nitrogen being used to dissolve bodies to flush them down drains?? Hmmm... 6. Two Odettes? A big hmmmm.. I can go on and on.. but then, to hell with it. Its simply not worth the effort. Chase, 'ol friend, as a big fan of yours, I sympathize and even apologize for this fiasco of a movie. If I ever have enough money, I will make a film of one (or more) of your novels, and present it to the audience, the way you would have wanted it to be presented.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best James Hadley Chase adaptation.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviestar26
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just recently I came across the late author James Hadley Chase. I was surprised at the huge number of novels he had written over the 50s and 60s. A movie I had also watched a movie earlier which was giving reference to behind the inspiration used. I decided to dwell in to the writers works and discover what made him so popular. After reading one I could not give up. I was surprised by the themes and characters that were involved in the novels. Many times it felt like I was not reading a book, but watching a movie. Given the fact that his books were not long made it more easier to complete them. Many of Chase's novels have been adapted in to movies. The trend of Chase adaptations became a cult trend for french and Italian cinema. However here in the west it never took off. Novels like 'Miss Shunaway waves a wand', 'The set up' and 'Hit and run' were adapted for the big screen. Unfortunately they did not make bells ring at the box office. The novel 'Just another sucker' is made in to a movie and The theme became instantly familiar to me as the first few minutes begin to roll. The name of the novel has been changed to 'Palmetto' for the movie. As one watches on you realise the noir atmosphere is prevalent in almost every scene. An old novel's transition to modern day cinema makes an impressive outcome. Both Woody Harrelson and Elizabeth Shue were perfect choices for the casting. Their performances really make the movie for what it is. Volker Schlondorff makes a sincere attempt at presenting his perception of the novel. He has incorporated all his basic understanding of the theme and there is never a feeling that a foreign director made the movie. He has made many dull moments enhanced by capturing the character's expressions. There are a few scenes and moments that make the movie longer in duration but this does not put the viewer off. It was disappointing that the movie did not have huge box office status when it released. Since the theme of kidnapping was used, and one has to contend with releases like 'fargo' and 'The big lebowski', I would assume that this movie went unnoticed. I think that the reason behind its failure was directly due to the incorrect release date. Maybe a year early or late would have had some positive impact on the movie's success ratio. *********************SPOILERS AHEAD********************* Woody Harrelson plays Harry Barber who is released from prison after spending two years there for no reason. He considers going to Miami but his girlfriend (Gina Gershon) persuades him to not leave. At a bar he encounters a woman who who is the wife of a rich man by the name or Mr Malroux. She tempts him in to a fake kidnapping scheme where her step daughter (Chloe Sevigny) will be involved in. The ranson will be 500,000 dollars. All that Harry has to do is make a phone call and send the threatening letter demanding the ransom. Initially Harry does not approve but later he convinces himself. After meeting the step daughter the plan is put ahead. The girl stays away from home for a short time and her father delivers the money in a suitcase to the location mentioned. He is later shocked to discover that the girl has been killed and he has a body to dispose of that is not easy to do. The local authorities are on the case and 1 plus 1 does not seem to be adding to two for Harry. Plus what he received was not cash at all. The situation becomes more and more sinister and paranoia begins to take over him. To his surprise he later discovers that at every step of the way more and more clues will point towards him as the culprit behind Mr Malroux's daughters disappearance. He realises eventually that he was just used for the whole plan. Eventually he has to prove his innocence to the authorities. ************************END OF SPOILERS********************** I could not help getting a dejavu of 'Body Heat' while watching this movie. Many situations were reminiscent of the classic. The setting of Florida too was an indicator of this. The constant sweating faces and sexual intimidating scenes also were a giveaway. But the similarities end there. Movies like 'Derailed and 'Out of time' too had a similar concept. The director has incorporated many slow moving frames which highlight plot twists and key moments which are crucial. These are a highlight and really create the right tone at certain intervals. With a running time of 1 hour and 53 minutes the movie does tend to take long to get the plot to progress. Much of the first hour is spent behind planning the kidnapping. However the second hour's pace builds up. Much of that specific portion of the movie delivers plot twists after plot twists. These makes for a very intriguing experiences as the movie progresses. The usage of a background score is very minimum. But the sleazy sounds do appear regularly at important moments because you can't have a noir movie without them. This is one of Woody Harrelson's best performances. He has managed to blend many moods and shades in to one role. We can feel sympathy for his character as well as hating him. We can sense his paranoia and unsettling feeling while just watching him. There are certain moments where one would also laugh at him. He truly did play the man in despair from the heart. Elizabeth Shue would have given any actress from the 40s and 50s a run for their money as she played a femme fatale brilliantly. Her body language and acting were just on the mark. Overall this is the perfect treat for fans of noir. I would also recommend watching it with others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Chinatown" comes to Palmetto ..............
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In what seems to be an obvious reference to "Chinatown", the sexy would be kidnapper is named Mulroux, not Mulray, but Mulroux. Woody Harrelson is set up nicely to take the fall for a murder, hidden behind a fake kidnapping. Sexy women abound, and plot twists are nicely spaced along the way. Character development is acceptable, but not great, and believability at times is stretched. Nevertheless, "Palmetto" is a decent neo-noir that maintains interest throughout. My only letdown was an ending that seemed unsatisfying. Rather than compare this to blockbusters like "Body Heat" or "Chinatown", I would say it is more along the lines of "Red Rock West". - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good story, although the movie could have been better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Volker Schlondorff's "Palmetto" has a very interesting plot, although I think that the movie could be better. Woody Harrelson plays an ex-con who gets drawn into a supposedly fake kidnapping in Florida. The movie contains a series of plot twists (I won't name them, lest I spoil the whole thing), but nothing gratuitous. You have to realize that this is not a bad movie; it's just that Schlondorff could have done a better job with it (especially towards the end). Overall, I do recommend it. You'll probably like it. Also starring Elisabeth Shue, Gina Gershon, Michael Rapaport, Chloe Sevigny and Tom Wright. Schlondorff also directed "The Tin Drum" and "Strajk - Die Heldin von Danzig".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked a lot this modern film noir
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (butchfilms@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like this movie very much, each time I catch it by any chance on TV when I am making zapping I watch it again. I think that "Palmetto" deserves 7.5 stars, I was surprised to find out it has just 5.6 stars. I have always liked the work of Woody Harrelson, but in this movie he is great as the journalist Harry Barber. the supporting cast is very good too. The plot of the movie is about Harry Barber a journalist that is released from jail for being found innocent. After that he is going to have problems to find a job until a sexy woman proposes him to be involved in a false kidnapping for some easy money, because of this Harry is going to get in a lot of troubles. I recommend you to watch this movie, I found it very entertaining since the beginning until the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Very Underrated 'Neo Noir'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this is one of those modern-day film noirs (neo noir) that went under the radar. It is excellent, and few people know about it. It's a very underrated film. It had an interesting and unpredictable story with some very neat twists which a good noir might have. I'm not really sure I liked the very ending, but I sure enjoyed the rest of it. That entertainment included ogling a couple of sexy female leads, played by Elisabeth Shue and Chloe Sevigny and I loved the wonderful colors in this movie. Not only was the cinematography great, so was the soundtrack with some solid blues tracks. The guitar playing reminded me of the Ry Cooder's work in "Midnight Run." The movie was labeled by some national critics as a "poor man's 'Body Heat.'" Well, that's fine with me because I liked "Body Heat" a lot, too. If you liked that, you should like this movie, too. Yes, there are a few holes in the story but nothing that damaged the storyline to any degree. Woody Harrelson was good in the lead and Gina Gershon and Michael Rapaport provided solid performance in supporting roles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Okay Thriller With Tons of Sizzling Sex!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan1863Sickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Harrelson plays Harry Barber, a wise guy reporter who just did some jail time for a dirty deal that wasn't his fault. When he gets out of the slam, he just wants his life back. But bad breaks and shifty women soon send him right back into the seamy, sexy world of double deals and decadent rich folks, in a steamy Florida town called PALMETTO. The plot of this movie is okay, and the story moves along at a slow, but steady pace. But what really makes it work is the sexual subtext of a man fighting to maintain both his moral high ground and his sexual potency while surrounded by a trio of luscious, dangerous women. At first, Harry Barber's biggest problem is finding a job. When he gets out of jail, his loyal girl friend Nina (Gina Gershon) is waiting to meet him. Dark-eyed Nina is the ideal best pal -- friendly, loving, and supportive. Not only does she take Harry in, she's more than willing to pay for his expenses and keep him on as her "assistant" until he finds a job. The sizzling tension between them is that Nina wants a docile and submissive male concubine while Harry is too macho to accept the pleasures Nina can provide. He's clearly the kind of man who feels that it's emasculating for a woman to have too much money or power in a relationship. Still, Nina is so stunningly attractive and so clearly besotted with him that he almost unwillingly sinks into dependence. Watch the early morning scene where he makes coffee for Nina and tensely waits for her approval! It's pure Neanderthal male pride that drives Harry to accept a "dirty job" from blonde temptress Rhea Malroux. Elisabeth Shue has never, ever been more radiant than in this classic noir role of the black widow. The sex scenes are sizzling precisely because Rhea is using Harry and preparing to feed on him. Yet when her spoiled step daughter, Odette, appears, Harry is forced to pleasure not one but two of the most dangerous women in Palmetto! Frankly, the ending of this movie is not very satisfying -- Harry does not really triumph in the end, nor does he learn the value of Nina's loyalty and support. In the end it's more of a paranoid male fantasy than a real classic thriller, but still worth watching just for the sizzling sexual subtext between Harry and his three witches!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I have a genuine question - Please help me.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itsd-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie was fine, i agree with most of the other comments, a little slow, bad color, good plot, but worth watching. I just want to know, around 55 minutes into the movie, when Woody starts running on the beach away from the police, and he gets shot and falls on the sand then he gets up and starts running again. What is the significance on the lady in black holding a baby, just meters from the water edge. She does nothing and adds nothing to the movie. She then disappears behind some rocks, as Woody is running towards her. Please help....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Under-rated Neo Noir
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sankhan99
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another underrated movie on IMDb like many other suspense/mystery thrillers. Seeing the rating on IMDb and then watching suspense/mystery thrillers made me feel that movies of mentioned genre are not rated well here. They are often underrated and because of that many suspense/mystery lovers might have missed quite brilliant movies. I rather put it in a way that Neo Noirs are actually not well rated here. Any suspense/mystery lover can easily like this movie. Movie has quite good twists and turns which are difficult to predict. Screenplay is written well but could be better. Woody has done great job but I feel Elizabeth was bit over acting. Direction is good. Overall movie has great neo noir feeling. I recommend this movie specially to neo noir lovers, they will not regret watch it. There are few others which I like to mention are well underrated like Wolfgang's Shattered, John Dhal's Kill me again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie is rated 6 out of 10?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oragex
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Seriously, those who rated this like some random stuff, are already medium to heavily hollyntoxicated. This is for the remaining ones who know what lively and charming acting is. This is the kind of entertainment movie I'm not sick to see. It's FRESH, teasing, simple and colored, something Hollywood guys forgot some time ago. Good actors but again not in the H. style (is that a style anyway?). Compared with Hollywood productions this movie is the same as going to a lively, friendly, full with warm locals bar, or going to some fancy club, full of models where nobody's talking with each other. Stop bashing, this is not perfect, but I prefer it to standard movies who are done by the book to the point the actors cannot express themselves any long.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sad day for James Hadley Chase
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pcsarkar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some highly talented authors have the misfortune of having their works being produced as trash in cinematic form. Like HP Lovecraft. James Hadley Chase was another one such unfortunate author. Being the owner of the biggest fan site of Chase on the Net, I eagerly picked up this movie recently, although having read its reviews, I was filled with trepidation. Without giving away the plot, some of my personal gripes are as follows: 1. Why the title change? "Just Another Sucker" is way more catchy and appropriate than the stupid "Palmetto" What the hell is Palmetto by the way? 2. Whats with the cockroaches throughout the movie? Palmetto bugs? What was the director thinking of? 3. While JHC developed the plot in his own awesome manner, the way the script-writer went about developing the script absolutely destroyed the suspense element. The motivation and desperation of the lead character in taking up such a dicey assignment went totally missing. The movie's mumbling, bumbling Harry Barber comes across as a parody of the novel's shrewd Harry Barber, who planned the kidnapping drama as meticulously as he could. 4. On second thoughts, most of the characters come across as parodies of their original selves, except perhaps, Nina (Gina Gershon). 5. Liquid Nitrogen being used to dissolve bodies to flush them down drains?? Hmmm... 6. Two Odettes? A big hmmmm.. I can go on and on.. but then, to hell with it. Its simply not worth the effort. Chase, 'ol friend, as a big fan of yours, I sympathize and even apologize for this fiasco of a movie. If I ever have enough money, I will make a film of one (or more) of your novels, and present it to the audience, the way you would have wanted it to be presented.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best James Hadley Chase adaptation.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviestar26
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just recently I came across the late author James Hadley Chase. I was surprised at the huge number of novels he had written over the 50s and 60s. A movie I had also watched a movie earlier which was giving reference to behind the inspiration used. I decided to dwell in to the writers works and discover what made him so popular. After reading one I could not give up. I was surprised by the themes and characters that were involved in the novels. Many times it felt like I was not reading a book, but watching a movie. Given the fact that his books were not long made it more easier to complete them. Many of Chase's novels have been adapted in to movies. The trend of Chase adaptations became a cult trend for french and Italian cinema. However here in the west it never took off. Novels like 'Miss Shunaway waves a wand', 'The set up' and 'Hit and run' were adapted for the big screen. Unfortunately they did not make bells ring at the box office. The novel 'Just another sucker' is made in to a movie and The theme became instantly familiar to me as the first few minutes begin to roll. The name of the novel has been changed to 'Palmetto' for the movie. As one watches on you realise the noir atmosphere is prevalent in almost every scene. An old novel's transition to modern day cinema makes an impressive outcome. Both Woody Harrelson and Elizabeth Shue were perfect choices for the casting. Their performances really make the movie for what it is. Volker Schlondorff makes a sincere attempt at presenting his perception of the novel. He has incorporated all his basic understanding of the theme and there is never a feeling that a foreign director made the movie. He has made many dull moments enhanced by capturing the character's expressions. There are a few scenes and moments that make the movie longer in duration but this does not put the viewer off. It was disappointing that the movie did not have huge box office status when it released. Since the theme of kidnapping was used, and one has to contend with releases like 'fargo' and 'The big lebowski', I would assume that this movie went unnoticed. I think that the reason behind its failure was directly due to the incorrect release date. Maybe a year early or late would have had some positive impact on the movie's success ratio. *********************SPOILERS AHEAD********************* Woody Harrelson plays Harry Barber who is released from prison after spending two years there for no reason. He considers going to Miami but his girlfriend (Gina Gershon) persuades him to not leave. At a bar he encounters a woman who who is the wife of a rich man by the name or Mr Malroux. She tempts him in to a fake kidnapping scheme where her step daughter (Chloe Sevigny) will be involved in. The ranson will be 500,000 dollars. All that Harry has to do is make a phone call and send the threatening letter demanding the ransom. Initially Harry does not approve but later he convinces himself. After meeting the step daughter the plan is put ahead. The girl stays away from home for a short time and her father delivers the money in a suitcase to the location mentioned. He is later shocked to discover that the girl has been killed and he has a body to dispose of that is not easy to do. The local authorities are on the case and 1 plus 1 does not seem to be adding to two for Harry. Plus what he received was not cash at all. The situation becomes more and more sinister and paranoia begins to take over him. To his surprise he later discovers that at every step of the way more and more clues will point towards him as the culprit behind Mr Malroux's daughters disappearance. He realises eventually that he was just used for the whole plan. Eventually he has to prove his innocence to the authorities. ************************END OF SPOILERS********************** I could not help getting a dejavu of 'Body Heat' while watching this movie. Many situations were reminiscent of the classic. The setting of Florida too was an indicator of this. The constant sweating faces and sexual intimidating scenes also were a giveaway. But the similarities end there. Movies like 'Derailed and 'Out of time' too had a similar concept. The director has incorporated many slow moving frames which highlight plot twists and key moments which are crucial. These are a highlight and really create the right tone at certain intervals. With a running time of 1 hour and 53 minutes the movie does tend to take long to get the plot to progress. Much of the first hour is spent behind planning the kidnapping. However the second hour's pace builds up. Much of that specific portion of the movie delivers plot twists after plot twists. These makes for a very intriguing experiences as the movie progresses. The usage of a background score is very minimum. But the sleazy sounds do appear regularly at important moments because you can't have a noir movie without them. This is one of Woody Harrelson's best performances. He has managed to blend many moods and shades in to one role. We can feel sympathy for his character as well as hating him. We can sense his paranoia and unsettling feeling while just watching him. There are certain moments where one would also laugh at him. He truly did play the man in despair from the heart. Elizabeth Shue would have given any actress from the 40s and 50s a run for their money as she played a femme fatale brilliantly. Her body language and acting were just on the mark. Overall this is the perfect treat for fans of noir. I would also recommend watching it with others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Chinatown" comes to Palmetto ..............
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In what seems to be an obvious reference to "Chinatown", the sexy would be kidnapper is named Mulroux, not Mulray, but Mulroux. Woody Harrelson is set up nicely to take the fall for a murder, hidden behind a fake kidnapping. Sexy women abound, and plot twists are nicely spaced along the way. Character development is acceptable, but not great, and believability at times is stretched. Nevertheless, "Palmetto" is a decent neo-noir that maintains interest throughout. My only letdown was an ending that seemed unsatisfying. Rather than compare this to blockbusters like "Body Heat" or "Chinatown", I would say it is more along the lines of "Red Rock West". - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good story, although the movie could have been better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Volker Schlondorff's "Palmetto" has a very interesting plot, although I think that the movie could be better. Woody Harrelson plays an ex-con who gets drawn into a supposedly fake kidnapping in Florida. The movie contains a series of plot twists (I won't name them, lest I spoil the whole thing), but nothing gratuitous. You have to realize that this is not a bad movie; it's just that Schlondorff could have done a better job with it (especially towards the end). Overall, I do recommend it. You'll probably like it. Also starring Elisabeth Shue, Gina Gershon, Michael Rapaport, Chloe Sevigny and Tom Wright. Schlondorff also directed "The Tin Drum" and "Strajk - Die Heldin von Danzig".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked a lot this modern film noir
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (butchfilms@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like this movie very much, each time I catch it by any chance on TV when I am making zapping I watch it again. I think that "Palmetto" deserves 7.5 stars, I was surprised to find out it has just 5.6 stars. I have always liked the work of Woody Harrelson, but in this movie he is great as the journalist Harry Barber. the supporting cast is very good too. The plot of the movie is about Harry Barber a journalist that is released from jail for being found innocent. After that he is going to have problems to find a job until a sexy woman proposes him to be involved in a false kidnapping for some easy money, because of this Harry is going to get in a lot of troubles. I recommend you to watch this movie, I found it very entertaining since the beginning until the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Very Underrated 'Neo Noir'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this is one of those modern-day film noirs (neo noir) that went under the radar. It is excellent, and few people know about it. It's a very underrated film. It had an interesting and unpredictable story with some very neat twists which a good noir might have. I'm not really sure I liked the very ending, but I sure enjoyed the rest of it. That entertainment included ogling a couple of sexy female leads, played by Elisabeth Shue and Chloe Sevigny and I loved the wonderful colors in this movie. Not only was the cinematography great, so was the soundtrack with some solid blues tracks. The guitar playing reminded me of the Ry Cooder's work in "Midnight Run." The movie was labeled by some national critics as a "poor man's 'Body Heat.'" Well, that's fine with me because I liked "Body Heat" a lot, too. If you liked that, you should like this movie, too. Yes, there are a few holes in the story but nothing that damaged the storyline to any degree. Woody Harrelson was good in the lead and Gina Gershon and Michael Rapaport provided solid performance in supporting roles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Okay Thriller With Tons of Sizzling Sex!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan1863Sickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Harrelson plays Harry Barber, a wise guy reporter who just did some jail time for a dirty deal that wasn't his fault. When he gets out of the slam, he just wants his life back. But bad breaks and shifty women soon send him right back into the seamy, sexy world of double deals and decadent rich folks, in a steamy Florida town called PALMETTO. The plot of this movie is okay, and the story moves along at a slow, but steady pace. But what really makes it work is the sexual subtext of a man fighting to maintain both his moral high ground and his sexual potency while surrounded by a trio of luscious, dangerous women. At first, Harry Barber's biggest problem is finding a job. When he gets out of jail, his loyal girl friend Nina (Gina Gershon) is waiting to meet him. Dark-eyed Nina is the ideal best pal -- friendly, loving, and supportive. Not only does she take Harry in, she's more than willing to pay for his expenses and keep him on as her "assistant" until he finds a job. The sizzling tension between them is that Nina wants a docile and submissive male concubine while Harry is too macho to accept the pleasures Nina can provide. He's clearly the kind of man who feels that it's emasculating for a woman to have too much money or power in a relationship. Still, Nina is so stunningly attractive and so clearly besotted with him that he almost unwillingly sinks into dependence. Watch the early morning scene where he makes coffee for Nina and tensely waits for her approval! It's pure Neanderthal male pride that drives Harry to accept a "dirty job" from blonde temptress Rhea Malroux. Elisabeth Shue has never, ever been more radiant than in this classic noir role of the black widow. The sex scenes are sizzling precisely because Rhea is using Harry and preparing to feed on him. Yet when her spoiled step daughter, Odette, appears, Harry is forced to pleasure not one but two of the most dangerous women in Palmetto! Frankly, the ending of this movie is not very satisfying -- Harry does not really triumph in the end, nor does he learn the value of Nina's loyalty and support. In the end it's more of a paranoid male fantasy than a real classic thriller, but still worth watching just for the sizzling sexual subtext between Harry and his three witches!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I have a genuine question - Please help me.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itsd-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie was fine, i agree with most of the other comments, a little slow, bad color, good plot, but worth watching. I just want to know, around 55 minutes into the movie, when Woody starts running on the beach away from the police, and he gets shot and falls on the sand then he gets up and starts running again. What is the significance on the lady in black holding a baby, just meters from the water edge. She does nothing and adds nothing to the movie. She then disappears behind some rocks, as Woody is running towards her. Please help....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Under-rated Neo Noir
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sankhan99
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another underrated movie on IMDb like many other suspense/mystery thrillers. Seeing the rating on IMDb and then watching suspense/mystery thrillers made me feel that movies of mentioned genre are not rated well here. They are often underrated and because of that many suspense/mystery lovers might have missed quite brilliant movies. I rather put it in a way that Neo Noirs are actually not well rated here. Any suspense/mystery lover can easily like this movie. Movie has quite good twists and turns which are difficult to predict. Screenplay is written well but could be better. Woody has done great job but I feel Elizabeth was bit over acting. Direction is good. Overall movie has great neo noir feeling. I recommend this movie specially to neo noir lovers, they will not regret watch it. There are few others which I like to mention are well underrated like Wolfgang's Shattered, John Dhal's Kill me again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie is rated 6 out of 10?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oragex
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Seriously, those who rated this like some random stuff, are already medium to heavily hollyntoxicated. This is for the remaining ones who know what lively and charming acting is. This is the kind of entertainment movie I'm not sick to see. It's FRESH, teasing, simple and colored, something Hollywood guys forgot some time ago. Good actors but again not in the H. style (is that a style anyway?). Compared with Hollywood productions this movie is the same as going to a lively, friendly, full with warm locals bar, or going to some fancy club, full of models where nobody's talking with each other. Stop bashing, this is not perfect, but I prefer it to standard movies who are done by the book to the point the actors cannot express themselves any long.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sad day for James Hadley Chase
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pcsarkar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some highly talented authors have the misfortune of having their works being produced as trash in cinematic form. Like HP Lovecraft. James Hadley Chase was another one such unfortunate author. Being the owner of the biggest fan site of Chase on the Net, I eagerly picked up this movie recently, although having read its reviews, I was filled with trepidation. Without giving away the plot, some of my personal gripes are as follows: 1. Why the title change? "Just Another Sucker" is way more catchy and appropriate than the stupid "Palmetto" What the hell is Palmetto by the way? 2. Whats with the cockroaches throughout the movie? Palmetto bugs? What was the director thinking of? 3. While JHC developed the plot in his own awesome manner, the way the script-writer went about developing the script absolutely destroyed the suspense element. The motivation and desperation of the lead character in taking up such a dicey assignment went totally missing. The movie's mumbling, bumbling Harry Barber comes across as a parody of the novel's shrewd Harry Barber, who planned the kidnapping drama as meticulously as he could. 4. On second thoughts, most of the characters come across as parodies of their original selves, except perhaps, Nina (Gina Gershon). 5. Liquid Nitrogen being used to dissolve bodies to flush them down drains?? Hmmm... 6. Two Odettes? A big hmmmm.. I can go on and on.. but then, to hell with it. Its simply not worth the effort. Chase, 'ol friend, as a big fan of yours, I sympathize and even apologize for this fiasco of a movie. If I ever have enough money, I will make a film of one (or more) of your novels, and present it to the audience, the way you would have wanted it to be presented.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best James Hadley Chase adaptation.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviestar26
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just recently I came across the late author James Hadley Chase. I was surprised at the huge number of novels he had written over the 50s and 60s. A movie I had also watched a movie earlier which was giving reference to behind the inspiration used. I decided to dwell in to the writers works and discover what made him so popular. After reading one I could not give up. I was surprised by the themes and characters that were involved in the novels. Many times it felt like I was not reading a book, but watching a movie. Given the fact that his books were not long made it more easier to complete them. Many of Chase's novels have been adapted in to movies. The trend of Chase adaptations became a cult trend for french and Italian cinema. However here in the west it never took off. Novels like 'Miss Shunaway waves a wand', 'The set up' and 'Hit and run' were adapted for the big screen. Unfortunately they did not make bells ring at the box office. The novel 'Just another sucker' is made in to a movie and The theme became instantly familiar to me as the first few minutes begin to roll. The name of the novel has been changed to 'Palmetto' for the movie. As one watches on you realise the noir atmosphere is prevalent in almost every scene. An old novel's transition to modern day cinema makes an impressive outcome. Both Woody Harrelson and Elizabeth Shue were perfect choices for the casting. Their performances really make the movie for what it is. Volker Schlondorff makes a sincere attempt at presenting his perception of the novel. He has incorporated all his basic understanding of the theme and there is never a feeling that a foreign director made the movie. He has made many dull moments enhanced by capturing the character's expressions. There are a few scenes and moments that make the movie longer in duration but this does not put the viewer off. It was disappointing that the movie did not have huge box office status when it released. Since the theme of kidnapping was used, and one has to contend with releases like 'fargo' and 'The big lebowski', I would assume that this movie went unnoticed. I think that the reason behind its failure was directly due to the incorrect release date. Maybe a year early or late would have had some positive impact on the movie's success ratio. *********************SPOILERS AHEAD********************* Woody Harrelson plays Harry Barber who is released from prison after spending two years there for no reason. He considers going to Miami but his girlfriend (Gina Gershon) persuades him to not leave. At a bar he encounters a woman who who is the wife of a rich man by the name or Mr Malroux. She tempts him in to a fake kidnapping scheme where her step daughter (Chloe Sevigny) will be involved in. The ranson will be 500,000 dollars. All that Harry has to do is make a phone call and send the threatening letter demanding the ransom. Initially Harry does not approve but later he convinces himself. After meeting the step daughter the plan is put ahead. The girl stays away from home for a short time and her father delivers the money in a suitcase to the location mentioned. He is later shocked to discover that the girl has been killed and he has a body to dispose of that is not easy to do. The local authorities are on the case and 1 plus 1 does not seem to be adding to two for Harry. Plus what he received was not cash at all. The situation becomes more and more sinister and paranoia begins to take over him. To his surprise he later discovers that at every step of the way more and more clues will point towards him as the culprit behind Mr Malroux's daughters disappearance. He realises eventually that he was just used for the whole plan. Eventually he has to prove his innocence to the authorities. ************************END OF SPOILERS********************** I could not help getting a dejavu of 'Body Heat' while watching this movie. Many situations were reminiscent of the classic. The setting of Florida too was an indicator of this. The constant sweating faces and sexual intimidating scenes also were a giveaway. But the similarities end there. Movies like 'Derailed and 'Out of time' too had a similar concept. The director has incorporated many slow moving frames which highlight plot twists and key moments which are crucial. These are a highlight and really create the right tone at certain intervals. With a running time of 1 hour and 53 minutes the movie does tend to take long to get the plot to progress. Much of the first hour is spent behind planning the kidnapping. However the second hour's pace builds up. Much of that specific portion of the movie delivers plot twists after plot twists. These makes for a very intriguing experiences as the movie progresses. The usage of a background score is very minimum. But the sleazy sounds do appear regularly at important moments because you can't have a noir movie without them. This is one of Woody Harrelson's best performances. He has managed to blend many moods and shades in to one role. We can feel sympathy for his character as well as hating him. We can sense his paranoia and unsettling feeling while just watching him. There are certain moments where one would also laugh at him. He truly did play the man in despair from the heart. Elizabeth Shue would have given any actress from the 40s and 50s a run for their money as she played a femme fatale brilliantly. Her body language and acting were just on the mark. Overall this is the perfect treat for fans of noir. I would also recommend watching it with others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Chinatown" comes to Palmetto ..............
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In what seems to be an obvious reference to "Chinatown", the sexy would be kidnapper is named Mulroux, not Mulray, but Mulroux. Woody Harrelson is set up nicely to take the fall for a murder, hidden behind a fake kidnapping. Sexy women abound, and plot twists are nicely spaced along the way. Character development is acceptable, but not great, and believability at times is stretched. Nevertheless, "Palmetto" is a decent neo-noir that maintains interest throughout. My only letdown was an ending that seemed unsatisfying. Rather than compare this to blockbusters like "Body Heat" or "Chinatown", I would say it is more along the lines of "Red Rock West". - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good story, although the movie could have been better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Volker Schlondorff's "Palmetto" has a very interesting plot, although I think that the movie could be better. Woody Harrelson plays an ex-con who gets drawn into a supposedly fake kidnapping in Florida. The movie contains a series of plot twists (I won't name them, lest I spoil the whole thing), but nothing gratuitous. You have to realize that this is not a bad movie; it's just that Schlondorff could have done a better job with it (especially towards the end). Overall, I do recommend it. You'll probably like it. Also starring Elisabeth Shue, Gina Gershon, Michael Rapaport, Chloe Sevigny and Tom Wright. Schlondorff also directed "The Tin Drum" and "Strajk - Die Heldin von Danzig".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked a lot this modern film noir
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (butchfilms@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like this movie very much, each time I catch it by any chance on TV when I am making zapping I watch it again. I think that "Palmetto" deserves 7.5 stars, I was surprised to find out it has just 5.6 stars. I have always liked the work of Woody Harrelson, but in this movie he is great as the journalist Harry Barber. the supporting cast is very good too. The plot of the movie is about Harry Barber a journalist that is released from jail for being found innocent. After that he is going to have problems to find a job until a sexy woman proposes him to be involved in a false kidnapping for some easy money, because of this Harry is going to get in a lot of troubles. I recommend you to watch this movie, I found it very entertaining since the beginning until the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Very Underrated 'Neo Noir'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this is one of those modern-day film noirs (neo noir) that went under the radar. It is excellent, and few people know about it. It's a very underrated film. It had an interesting and unpredictable story with some very neat twists which a good noir might have. I'm not really sure I liked the very ending, but I sure enjoyed the rest of it. That entertainment included ogling a couple of sexy female leads, played by Elisabeth Shue and Chloe Sevigny and I loved the wonderful colors in this movie. Not only was the cinematography great, so was the soundtrack with some solid blues tracks. The guitar playing reminded me of the Ry Cooder's work in "Midnight Run." The movie was labeled by some national critics as a "poor man's 'Body Heat.'" Well, that's fine with me because I liked "Body Heat" a lot, too. If you liked that, you should like this movie, too. Yes, there are a few holes in the story but nothing that damaged the storyline to any degree. Woody Harrelson was good in the lead and Gina Gershon and Michael Rapaport provided solid performance in supporting roles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Okay Thriller With Tons of Sizzling Sex!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan1863Sickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Harrelson plays Harry Barber, a wise guy reporter who just did some jail time for a dirty deal that wasn't his fault. When he gets out of the slam, he just wants his life back. But bad breaks and shifty women soon send him right back into the seamy, sexy world of double deals and decadent rich folks, in a steamy Florida town called PALMETTO. The plot of this movie is okay, and the story moves along at a slow, but steady pace. But what really makes it work is the sexual subtext of a man fighting to maintain both his moral high ground and his sexual potency while surrounded by a trio of luscious, dangerous women. At first, Harry Barber's biggest problem is finding a job. When he gets out of jail, his loyal girl friend Nina (Gina Gershon) is waiting to meet him. Dark-eyed Nina is the ideal best pal -- friendly, loving, and supportive. Not only does she take Harry in, she's more than willing to pay for his expenses and keep him on as her "assistant" until he finds a job. The sizzling tension between them is that Nina wants a docile and submissive male concubine while Harry is too macho to accept the pleasures Nina can provide. He's clearly the kind of man who feels that it's emasculating for a woman to have too much money or power in a relationship. Still, Nina is so stunningly attractive and so clearly besotted with him that he almost unwillingly sinks into dependence. Watch the early morning scene where he makes coffee for Nina and tensely waits for her approval! It's pure Neanderthal male pride that drives Harry to accept a "dirty job" from blonde temptress Rhea Malroux. Elisabeth Shue has never, ever been more radiant than in this classic noir role of the black widow. The sex scenes are sizzling precisely because Rhea is using Harry and preparing to feed on him. Yet when her spoiled step daughter, Odette, appears, Harry is forced to pleasure not one but two of the most dangerous women in Palmetto! Frankly, the ending of this movie is not very satisfying -- Harry does not really triumph in the end, nor does he learn the value of Nina's loyalty and support. In the end it's more of a paranoid male fantasy than a real classic thriller, but still worth watching just for the sizzling sexual subtext between Harry and his three witches!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I have a genuine question - Please help me.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itsd-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie was fine, i agree with most of the other comments, a little slow, bad color, good plot, but worth watching. I just want to know, around 55 minutes into the movie, when Woody starts running on the beach away from the police, and he gets shot and falls on the sand then he gets up and starts running again. What is the significance on the lady in black holding a baby, just meters from the water edge. She does nothing and adds nothing to the movie. She then disappears behind some rocks, as Woody is running towards her. Please help....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Under-rated Neo Noir
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sankhan99
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another underrated movie on IMDb like many other suspense/mystery thrillers. Seeing the rating on IMDb and then watching suspense/mystery thrillers made me feel that movies of mentioned genre are not rated well here. They are often underrated and because of that many suspense/mystery lovers might have missed quite brilliant movies. I rather put it in a way that Neo Noirs are actually not well rated here. Any suspense/mystery lover can easily like this movie. Movie has quite good twists and turns which are difficult to predict. Screenplay is written well but could be better. Woody has done great job but I feel Elizabeth was bit over acting. Direction is good. Overall movie has great neo noir feeling. I recommend this movie specially to neo noir lovers, they will not regret watch it. There are few others which I like to mention are well underrated like Wolfgang's Shattered, John Dhal's Kill me again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie is rated 6 out of 10?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oragex
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Seriously, those who rated this like some random stuff, are already medium to heavily hollyntoxicated. This is for the remaining ones who know what lively and charming acting is. This is the kind of entertainment movie I'm not sick to see. It's FRESH, teasing, simple and colored, something Hollywood guys forgot some time ago. Good actors but again not in the H. style (is that a style anyway?). Compared with Hollywood productions this movie is the same as going to a lively, friendly, full with warm locals bar, or going to some fancy club, full of models where nobody's talking with each other. Stop bashing, this is not perfect, but I prefer it to standard movies who are done by the book to the point the actors cannot express themselves any long.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sad day for James Hadley Chase
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pcsarkar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some highly talented authors have the misfortune of having their works being produced as trash in cinematic form. Like HP Lovecraft. James Hadley Chase was another one such unfortunate author. Being the owner of the biggest fan site of Chase on the Net, I eagerly picked up this movie recently, although having read its reviews, I was filled with trepidation. Without giving away the plot, some of my personal gripes are as follows: 1. Why the title change? "Just Another Sucker" is way more catchy and appropriate than the stupid "Palmetto" What the hell is Palmetto by the way? 2. Whats with the cockroaches throughout the movie? Palmetto bugs? What was the director thinking of? 3. While JHC developed the plot in his own awesome manner, the way the script-writer went about developing the script absolutely destroyed the suspense element. The motivation and desperation of the lead character in taking up such a dicey assignment went totally missing. The movie's mumbling, bumbling Harry Barber comes across as a parody of the novel's shrewd Harry Barber, who planned the kidnapping drama as meticulously as he could. 4. On second thoughts, most of the characters come across as parodies of their original selves, except perhaps, Nina (Gina Gershon). 5. Liquid Nitrogen being used to dissolve bodies to flush them down drains?? Hmmm... 6. Two Odettes? A big hmmmm.. I can go on and on.. but then, to hell with it. Its simply not worth the effort. Chase, 'ol friend, as a big fan of yours, I sympathize and even apologize for this fiasco of a movie. If I ever have enough money, I will make a film of one (or more) of your novels, and present it to the audience, the way you would have wanted it to be presented.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best James Hadley Chase adaptation.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviestar26
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just recently I came across the late author James Hadley Chase. I was surprised at the huge number of novels he had written over the 50s and 60s. A movie I had also watched a movie earlier which was giving reference to behind the inspiration used. I decided to dwell in to the writers works and discover what made him so popular. After reading one I could not give up. I was surprised by the themes and characters that were involved in the novels. Many times it felt like I was not reading a book, but watching a movie. Given the fact that his books were not long made it more easier to complete them. Many of Chase's novels have been adapted in to movies. The trend of Chase adaptations became a cult trend for french and Italian cinema. However here in the west it never took off. Novels like 'Miss Shunaway waves a wand', 'The set up' and 'Hit and run' were adapted for the big screen. Unfortunately they did not make bells ring at the box office. The novel 'Just another sucker' is made in to a movie and The theme became instantly familiar to me as the first few minutes begin to roll. The name of the novel has been changed to 'Palmetto' for the movie. As one watches on you realise the noir atmosphere is prevalent in almost every scene. An old novel's transition to modern day cinema makes an impressive outcome. Both Woody Harrelson and Elizabeth Shue were perfect choices for the casting. Their performances really make the movie for what it is. Volker Schlondorff makes a sincere attempt at presenting his perception of the novel. He has incorporated all his basic understanding of the theme and there is never a feeling that a foreign director made the movie. He has made many dull moments enhanced by capturing the character's expressions. There are a few scenes and moments that make the movie longer in duration but this does not put the viewer off. It was disappointing that the movie did not have huge box office status when it released. Since the theme of kidnapping was used, and one has to contend with releases like 'fargo' and 'The big lebowski', I would assume that this movie went unnoticed. I think that the reason behind its failure was directly due to the incorrect release date. Maybe a year early or late would have had some positive impact on the movie's success ratio. *********************SPOILERS AHEAD********************* Woody Harrelson plays Harry Barber who is released from prison after spending two years there for no reason. He considers going to Miami but his girlfriend (Gina Gershon) persuades him to not leave. At a bar he encounters a woman who who is the wife of a rich man by the name or Mr Malroux. She tempts him in to a fake kidnapping scheme where her step daughter (Chloe Sevigny) will be involved in. The ranson will be 500,000 dollars. All that Harry has to do is make a phone call and send the threatening letter demanding the ransom. Initially Harry does not approve but later he convinces himself. After meeting the step daughter the plan is put ahead. The girl stays away from home for a short time and her father delivers the money in a suitcase to the location mentioned. He is later shocked to discover that the girl has been killed and he has a body to dispose of that is not easy to do. The local authorities are on the case and 1 plus 1 does not seem to be adding to two for Harry. Plus what he received was not cash at all. The situation becomes more and more sinister and paranoia begins to take over him. To his surprise he later discovers that at every step of the way more and more clues will point towards him as the culprit behind Mr Malroux's daughters disappearance. He realises eventually that he was just used for the whole plan. Eventually he has to prove his innocence to the authorities. ************************END OF SPOILERS********************** I could not help getting a dejavu of 'Body Heat' while watching this movie. Many situations were reminiscent of the classic. The setting of Florida too was an indicator of this. The constant sweating faces and sexual intimidating scenes also were a giveaway. But the similarities end there. Movies like 'Derailed and 'Out of time' too had a similar concept. The director has incorporated many slow moving frames which highlight plot twists and key moments which are crucial. These are a highlight and really create the right tone at certain intervals. With a running time of 1 hour and 53 minutes the movie does tend to take long to get the plot to progress. Much of the first hour is spent behind planning the kidnapping. However the second hour's pace builds up. Much of that specific portion of the movie delivers plot twists after plot twists. These makes for a very intriguing experiences as the movie progresses. The usage of a background score is very minimum. But the sleazy sounds do appear regularly at important moments because you can't have a noir movie without them. This is one of Woody Harrelson's best performances. He has managed to blend many moods and shades in to one role. We can feel sympathy for his character as well as hating him. We can sense his paranoia and unsettling feeling while just watching him. There are certain moments where one would also laugh at him. He truly did play the man in despair from the heart. Elizabeth Shue would have given any actress from the 40s and 50s a run for their money as she played a femme fatale brilliantly. Her body language and acting were just on the mark. Overall this is the perfect treat for fans of noir. I would also recommend watching it with others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Chinatown" comes to Palmetto ..............
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In what seems to be an obvious reference to "Chinatown", the sexy would be kidnapper is named Mulroux, not Mulray, but Mulroux. Woody Harrelson is set up nicely to take the fall for a murder, hidden behind a fake kidnapping. Sexy women abound, and plot twists are nicely spaced along the way. Character development is acceptable, but not great, and believability at times is stretched. Nevertheless, "Palmetto" is a decent neo-noir that maintains interest throughout. My only letdown was an ending that seemed unsatisfying. Rather than compare this to blockbusters like "Body Heat" or "Chinatown", I would say it is more along the lines of "Red Rock West". - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good story, although the movie could have been better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Volker Schlondorff's "Palmetto" has a very interesting plot, although I think that the movie could be better. Woody Harrelson plays an ex-con who gets drawn into a supposedly fake kidnapping in Florida. The movie contains a series of plot twists (I won't name them, lest I spoil the whole thing), but nothing gratuitous. You have to realize that this is not a bad movie; it's just that Schlondorff could have done a better job with it (especially towards the end). Overall, I do recommend it. You'll probably like it. Also starring Elisabeth Shue, Gina Gershon, Michael Rapaport, Chloe Sevigny and Tom Wright. Schlondorff also directed "The Tin Drum" and "Strajk - Die Heldin von Danzig".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked a lot this modern film noir
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (butchfilms@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like this movie very much, each time I catch it by any chance on TV when I am making zapping I watch it again. I think that "Palmetto" deserves 7.5 stars, I was surprised to find out it has just 5.6 stars. I have always liked the work of Woody Harrelson, but in this movie he is great as the journalist Harry Barber. the supporting cast is very good too. The plot of the movie is about Harry Barber a journalist that is released from jail for being found innocent. After that he is going to have problems to find a job until a sexy woman proposes him to be involved in a false kidnapping for some easy money, because of this Harry is going to get in a lot of troubles. I recommend you to watch this movie, I found it very entertaining since the beginning until the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Very Underrated 'Neo Noir'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this is one of those modern-day film noirs (neo noir) that went under the radar. It is excellent, and few people know about it. It's a very underrated film. It had an interesting and unpredictable story with some very neat twists which a good noir might have. I'm not really sure I liked the very ending, but I sure enjoyed the rest of it. That entertainment included ogling a couple of sexy female leads, played by Elisabeth Shue and Chloe Sevigny and I loved the wonderful colors in this movie. Not only was the cinematography great, so was the soundtrack with some solid blues tracks. The guitar playing reminded me of the Ry Cooder's work in "Midnight Run." The movie was labeled by some national critics as a "poor man's 'Body Heat.'" Well, that's fine with me because I liked "Body Heat" a lot, too. If you liked that, you should like this movie, too. Yes, there are a few holes in the story but nothing that damaged the storyline to any degree. Woody Harrelson was good in the lead and Gina Gershon and Michael Rapaport provided solid performance in supporting roles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Okay Thriller With Tons of Sizzling Sex!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan1863Sickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Harrelson plays Harry Barber, a wise guy reporter who just did some jail time for a dirty deal that wasn't his fault. When he gets out of the slam, he just wants his life back. But bad breaks and shifty women soon send him right back into the seamy, sexy world of double deals and decadent rich folks, in a steamy Florida town called PALMETTO. The plot of this movie is okay, and the story moves along at a slow, but steady pace. But what really makes it work is the sexual subtext of a man fighting to maintain both his moral high ground and his sexual potency while surrounded by a trio of luscious, dangerous women. At first, Harry Barber's biggest problem is finding a job. When he gets out of jail, his loyal girl friend Nina (Gina Gershon) is waiting to meet him. Dark-eyed Nina is the ideal best pal -- friendly, loving, and supportive. Not only does she take Harry in, she's more than willing to pay for his expenses and keep him on as her "assistant" until he finds a job. The sizzling tension between them is that Nina wants a docile and submissive male concubine while Harry is too macho to accept the pleasures Nina can provide. He's clearly the kind of man who feels that it's emasculating for a woman to have too much money or power in a relationship. Still, Nina is so stunningly attractive and so clearly besotted with him that he almost unwillingly sinks into dependence. Watch the early morning scene where he makes coffee for Nina and tensely waits for her approval! It's pure Neanderthal male pride that drives Harry to accept a "dirty job" from blonde temptress Rhea Malroux. Elisabeth Shue has never, ever been more radiant than in this classic noir role of the black widow. The sex scenes are sizzling precisely because Rhea is using Harry and preparing to feed on him. Yet when her spoiled step daughter, Odette, appears, Harry is forced to pleasure not one but two of the most dangerous women in Palmetto! Frankly, the ending of this movie is not very satisfying -- Harry does not really triumph in the end, nor does he learn the value of Nina's loyalty and support. In the end it's more of a paranoid male fantasy than a real classic thriller, but still worth watching just for the sizzling sexual subtext between Harry and his three witches!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I have a genuine question - Please help me.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itsd-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie was fine, i agree with most of the other comments, a little slow, bad color, good plot, but worth watching. I just want to know, around 55 minutes into the movie, when Woody starts running on the beach away from the police, and he gets shot and falls on the sand then he gets up and starts running again. What is the significance on the lady in black holding a baby, just meters from the water edge. She does nothing and adds nothing to the movie. She then disappears behind some rocks, as Woody is running towards her. Please help....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
