<filme>
 <id>
  1318
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112646
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Catwalk
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A camera follows model Christy Turlington through the spring fashion shows in Milan, Paris, and New York one year in the early 1990s, probably 1992. She and others dash from one designer's ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A camera follows model Christy Turlington through the spring fashion shows in Milan, Paris, and New York one year in the early 1990s, probably 1992. She and others dash from one designer's unveilings to another. Extended footage looks at Versace and Armani in Milan, Galliano, Gaultier, and Langerfeld in Paris, and Isaac Mizrahi in New York. With Kate Moss, Naomi Campbell, and Turlington, we see the nature of friendships among models. With the engaging Mizrahi in particular, there's some exploration of the relationship between designer and models.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Documentary
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   fashion
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   one word title
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   paris france
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   new york city
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   independent film
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Robert Leacock
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores></escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Christy Turlington
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Azzedine Ala&iuml;a
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Giorgio Armani
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Documentary of a Lifetime!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    turlie
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Christy Turlington is the perfect person for documenting how the modeling and fashion industries collide. This film was a diamond in the rough. It not keeps true to the pure nature of the world of fashion and it's industry. It finally provides the respect needed for the modeling industry. This film follows the most highly respected models in the Fashion History. A 90+ minute chronicle of Christy Turlington's world wind life during collections in the fashion capitals. Moving from Milan to Paris and then ending in New York. The movie provides a realistic view of a model and the lives they lead. They are just like the rest of us. One exception - in the case of Christy, she is flawless by the centimeter. What I would like to see is Christy do a follow up documentary - since the filming of this movie in 1993 she has grown considerably in her career as well as her personal life. The documentary explains why Christy is one of the very few Supermodels still on top of an industry that is ever changing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
