<filme>
 <id>
  132
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0032138
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1939
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O M&aacute;gico de Oz
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Dorothy Gale is swept away to a magical land in a tornado and embarks on a quest to see the Wizard who can help her return home.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  In this charming film based on the popular L. Frank Baum stories, Dorothy and her dog Toto are caught in a tornado's path and somehow end up in the land of Oz. Here she meets some memorable friends and foes in her journey to meet the Wizard of Oz who everyone says can help her return home and possibly grant her new friends their goals of a brain, heart and courage.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   witch
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   dog
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   wizard
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   home
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   heart
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Victor Fleming
  </diretor>
  <diretor>
   George Cukor
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Noel Langley
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Florence Ryerson
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Judy Garland
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Frank Morgan
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ray Bolger
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Timeless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    meg_elizabeth
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "And you, and you, and you were there." All of Dorothy's friends look at her as if she was crazy, assuring her that her adventure was just a dream. Was it really just a dream? How could it be, when it seemed so real? In Viktor Fleming's, "The Wizard of Oz", dream is made into reality and reality into dream. "The Wizard of Oz" is a classical masterpiece in which breathtaking design, performance and a heart-warming storyline combine to create a movie in its very own category. In Kansas, a twister hits Dorothy's home and she is hit by a window, falling into her dreamland of Oz. We follow Dorothy (Judy Garland) on her quest for the Wizard of Oz, in the land of munchkins, evil and good witches, and many more interesting characters. The Scarecrow (Ray Bolger), Cowardly Lion (Bert Lahr), and Tin Man (Jack Haley) are just some of the friends, with their own problems, that she meets on her way. The story is all about "following the yellow brick road" as "we're off to see the wizard." The screenplay was adapted from Frank T. Baum's story chronicle, The Wizard of Oz. It was produced by Mervyn Leroy and acted out by a first class list of actors. Perhaps the most important factors of this movie are the Technicolor (this is the first movie in color), the songs (that you'll never forget and never get enough of), and the ubiquitous theme/moral of "there's no place like home." The plot is very easy to follow and straightforward. Despite the seemingly unrealistic storyline of wizards, a land of munchkins, flying monkeys, and bad witches flying on broomsticks, viewers can't help but fall into the fantasy of it all and imagine there really is such a place "somewhere over the rainbow." The characters are all believable and you seem able to relate to them and know at least one person in your life like them. People love the Scarecrow, Tin Man, and Cowardly Lion for their loyalty and personal quirks, and loathe the Wicked Witch of the West for being so sinfully evil. The dialogue is also very amusing, with a deeper meaning than most would conceive at first. There are many hidden messages of friendship, loyalty, and seeing what's right in front of you all along. The actors are very convincing as their characters, all seemingly to step right out from the original story. Judy Garland perhaps was the best choice for Dorothy because the viewer just can't help but fall in love and sympathize for her when they see those big brown eyes staring back at them from the screen. She has a raw performance in which you can feel each emotion through her expression. From the moment Dorothy opens her front door after landing in Oz and exclaims "Oh!" the screen is filled with bright and vibrant color, a sharp contrast from the dull black and white from a second before. The significance of this is not lost, as the use of color is artfully done throughout the movie. The Technicolor sets the film apart because it is the first picture to be in color. During the movie the ever present yellow brick road takes the viewer through a journey of colorful and unique places, like the charming Munchkin Land and eerily spooky Haunted Forest. This film is one that's timeless for a good reason. The acting is wonderful as is the set, themes, and dramatic aspects. The "Wizard of Oz" was one of a kind when it first came out and 75 years later it still touches people's hearts. The movie keeps the audience's interest and you walk away from it smiling. After watching the movie, it will give you a deeper respect for what you are and have. As Dorothy says, "There's no place like home," well, there's no movie like the Wizard of Oz.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A review of a movie everybody on the face of the earth saw
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maxfkeller
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the IMAX 3-D re-release 2 days ago and almost everyone at the theater was going to see this movie. I thought the 3D was very good and made me like the movie more. The film starts in black and... I don't need to talk about what happened in the movie, everybody saw it!!!!!! Being honest, I haven't seen the film in 5 years which made me forget a lot of parts of the film. Watching it, I felt like a little kid again. The choreography was good, the acting was very good, the cinematography was okay, the songs were very good. I just feel sad for forgetting the munchkins thanking Dorothy, the witch trying to get the slippers off of Dorothy, the "Lions and tigers and bears" scene, and the lion's if I were king of the forest song. I apologize to anybody reading this. Now you may disagree but The Wizard of Oz is a good film the family can watch during Taco Night. YAY!!!!!!!!! If you try, everyone eating will stop to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Wizard Of Oz 3-D IMAX 2013 - 4 Thumbs Up with Diamonds
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Russell Sanderlin (iMovieCritic@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone knows the story. Our thoughts on 3-D IMAX. Russell & Cissy, the Two Movie Critics rate movies based on Entertainment Value only. Follow and LIKE us at facebook.com/TwoMovieCritics A remake and remaster of the great classic movie in 3-D IMAX with stunning detail. It was an amazing transformation as Cissy and I were taken back in time before we both were born, August 15th, 1939 when The Wizard Of Oz opened at the Grauman's Chinese Theater. Immediately when the movie started and the title began in eye-popping 3-D fonts with the great sound track, Cissy and I got misty eyed. Now we were seeing this movie as it was meant to be seen and that we had only seen on T.V. sets all of our lives. Seeing it on the large IMAX screen, and in 3-D was an overwhelming experience. You see and hear things you missed all those years on TV. The detail of Glinda's ( The Good Witch's ) costume and many other costumes was amazing. The rust marks on the Tin Man's ( Jack Haley's ) body was very detailed, and later very shinny after their visit to Oz. We also heard several adults explaining to their children some of the story line before the movie started. A new generation was being introduced to the Wizard Of Oz just as if they were at the opening in 1939. I suggest all lovers of The Wizard Of Oz relive this classic again with their children, and grandchildren the way it was meant to be seen on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic movie that brings the imagination of childhood.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gokhan Erguven
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's probably a shame for me to have watched this movie too late, but since it's a classic, I don't feel bad about that. The setting, the costumes, the scene, the music, the effects are so beautiful that you can ignore the movie was shot in 1939. The movie is a classic and it has been referenced in so many movies and TV series that I watched so that it brought me to the point of I must watch it -- and it indeed was worth the watch. Judy Garland, Frank Morgan, Ray Bolger, Bert Lahr, Jack Haley, Billie Burke and all the other cast of the film are so great and talented that you'll be amazed by their performances. I also read a speculation that half the movie was shot colorless, and the other half with color on purpose, but there are other speculations that the movie was began to be shot in 1925 and done in 1939 because of the unavailable color film. Anyways, such a good film with a great imagination. Worth to watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent Work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    swpesto
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wizard of Oz with always be treasured throughout centuries. It is a piece of art. So magical. So beautiful. Judy Garland is so poised as Dorothy even at the young age of 16. The music and dancing are wonderful. Roy Bolger is awesome as "The Scarecrow". Such talent went into the casting of the film. Such special effects for a film almost putting it way before it's time. I feel some of these effects have been carried through with future films that have been made. Each film learns from the other. I will always love "The Wizard of Oz. Looking forward to the recent films that will continue the Oz series. I loved James Franco's portrayal in "Oz the Great and Powerful". Still nothing will come to the magic of the original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i have good review of dorothy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVIDMICHAEL HINES (2angelhines@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i am a film maker at LACC in los angeles californa and we all watch the movies in class and we saw this movie wizard of oz . she is a very good singer and actress .i love the way she does in the film . the most thing i seen was awesome that the tornado took her house up in the air once she woke up she saw the people she knows and she thought oh weired what is happening . as she looked down she jumped back and said omg she rush back to the bed . then she felt the house going back down like hell boom . once she came out she was in another world . she never gone before . as for toto very smart dog she was on her side . filmmaker student at lacc David B.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Follow The Yellow Brick Road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wizard Of Oz (TWOO) is probably one of the most famous Hollywood films of the late-1930s and, maybe, even the early-1940s. As I understand it, when TWOO was first released back in 1939 it really wasn't a colossal hit. It wasn't until the coming of TV when it was first aired in the 1950s that it attracted a humongous fan-base and from there it became one of the most popular films of all-time. Filmed at MGM Studios, TWOO was made at a time when MGM was, without question, the wealthiest, most impressive, and most successful Hollywood studio in the USA. Back in 1939 TWOO was made simply as a showpiece. This was MGM showing the world just how much power they wielded, that they could make an expensive film like this one and not care, one bit, whether it earned them a profit, or not. Little did the MGM big-wigs realize at the time that TWOO would go on to become one of the most beloved Fantasy/Adventure films of all time. So - "Tap your heels together 3 times and repeat after me - There's no place like home. There's no place like home."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Red Brick Road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kclov13
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies! I wore out the video tape a few times. I now own the DVD. Since I was little, I loved the movie. I was Dorothy for Halloween a couple years, I have the board game, and my first tattoo was inspired by this movie. The one thing that I have always questioned is where the Red Brick road goes. It would have been interesting to find out where it went. I hope that my future children will enjoy this movie as much as I did and still do. This movie has held up pretty good over the years, and I hope that it still does. I will continue to watch it and enjoy it as much as I did when I first saw it, (except now I probably know most of the lines to the movie).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll get you my little pretty, and your dog too."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are only two other Movies from Hollywood's Golden Age that have been as influential, deconstructed, analyzed, reconsidered, penetrating, viewed, and reviewed, noticed, and unforgotten as this one. King Kong (1933) and Citizen Kane (1941). Everyone who has seen Oz has an opinion and it is usually a strong one. It undeniably unmasks facades and oozes into the deeper parts of the consciousness worthy of the best Psychoanalysis. On the surface it lures one in with its sentimentality and charms with its catchy and heartfelt tunes. It bombards the senses, like a psychedelic, expanding consciousness through dripping Colors and the most imaginative of imagery. As the mind opens it is vulnerable to scary images as well as the sublime. Reality becomes a focused blur that is experienced profoundly and deeply. It is Art at its most cunningly persuasive. If you "pay no attention to the Man behind the curtain", you will find yourself in a land of Milk and Honey, but if you acknowledge reality for what it is and not what is hoped for, it might become a Truth that is as scary as a Flying Monkey. This Film is a Wonderful way to open the "doors of perception". That is the least and the best that the Movies can offer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lokethecheetah
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Often I am dubious about old movies, especially old sci-fi or "classic" movies. However, this movie was both enchanting and quite humorous for an oldie. The scenery was beautiful and so intricate. I was especially impressed by the lion's tail, flitting about in a life-like manner without the use of modern graphics or technology. The scenery impressed me because of all the time and effort that must have gone into creating it. Though much of the movie was spoiled for me through its fame, I was still amazed even with the scenes I knew were coming. The actors made the movie a delight to watch and the songs were humorous, and sometimes a bit stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Timeless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    meg_elizabeth
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "And you, and you, and you were there." All of Dorothy's friends look at her as if she was crazy, assuring her that her adventure was just a dream. Was it really just a dream? How could it be, when it seemed so real? In Viktor Fleming's, "The Wizard of Oz", dream is made into reality and reality into dream. "The Wizard of Oz" is a classical masterpiece in which breathtaking design, performance and a heart-warming storyline combine to create a movie in its very own category. In Kansas, a twister hits Dorothy's home and she is hit by a window, falling into her dreamland of Oz. We follow Dorothy (Judy Garland) on her quest for the Wizard of Oz, in the land of munchkins, evil and good witches, and many more interesting characters. The Scarecrow (Ray Bolger), Cowardly Lion (Bert Lahr), and Tin Man (Jack Haley) are just some of the friends, with their own problems, that she meets on her way. The story is all about "following the yellow brick road" as "we're off to see the wizard." The screenplay was adapted from Frank T. Baum's story chronicle, The Wizard of Oz. It was produced by Mervyn Leroy and acted out by a first class list of actors. Perhaps the most important factors of this movie are the Technicolor (this is the first movie in color), the songs (that you'll never forget and never get enough of), and the ubiquitous theme/moral of "there's no place like home." The plot is very easy to follow and straightforward. Despite the seemingly unrealistic storyline of wizards, a land of munchkins, flying monkeys, and bad witches flying on broomsticks, viewers can't help but fall into the fantasy of it all and imagine there really is such a place "somewhere over the rainbow." The characters are all believable and you seem able to relate to them and know at least one person in your life like them. People love the Scarecrow, Tin Man, and Cowardly Lion for their loyalty and personal quirks, and loathe the Wicked Witch of the West for being so sinfully evil. The dialogue is also very amusing, with a deeper meaning than most would conceive at first. There are many hidden messages of friendship, loyalty, and seeing what's right in front of you all along. The actors are very convincing as their characters, all seemingly to step right out from the original story. Judy Garland perhaps was the best choice for Dorothy because the viewer just can't help but fall in love and sympathize for her when they see those big brown eyes staring back at them from the screen. She has a raw performance in which you can feel each emotion through her expression. From the moment Dorothy opens her front door after landing in Oz and exclaims "Oh!" the screen is filled with bright and vibrant color, a sharp contrast from the dull black and white from a second before. The significance of this is not lost, as the use of color is artfully done throughout the movie. The Technicolor sets the film apart because it is the first picture to be in color. During the movie the ever present yellow brick road takes the viewer through a journey of colorful and unique places, like the charming Munchkin Land and eerily spooky Haunted Forest. This film is one that's timeless for a good reason. The acting is wonderful as is the set, themes, and dramatic aspects. The "Wizard of Oz" was one of a kind when it first came out and 75 years later it still touches people's hearts. The movie keeps the audience's interest and you walk away from it smiling. After watching the movie, it will give you a deeper respect for what you are and have. As Dorothy says, "There's no place like home," well, there's no movie like the Wizard of Oz.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A review of a movie everybody on the face of the earth saw
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maxfkeller
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the IMAX 3-D re-release 2 days ago and almost everyone at the theater was going to see this movie. I thought the 3D was very good and made me like the movie more. The film starts in black and... I don't need to talk about what happened in the movie, everybody saw it!!!!!! Being honest, I haven't seen the film in 5 years which made me forget a lot of parts of the film. Watching it, I felt like a little kid again. The choreography was good, the acting was very good, the cinematography was okay, the songs were very good. I just feel sad for forgetting the munchkins thanking Dorothy, the witch trying to get the slippers off of Dorothy, the "Lions and tigers and bears" scene, and the lion's if I were king of the forest song. I apologize to anybody reading this. Now you may disagree but The Wizard of Oz is a good film the family can watch during Taco Night. YAY!!!!!!!!! If you try, everyone eating will stop to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Wizard Of Oz 3-D IMAX 2013 - 4 Thumbs Up with Diamonds
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Russell Sanderlin (iMovieCritic@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone knows the story. Our thoughts on 3-D IMAX. Russell & Cissy, the Two Movie Critics rate movies based on Entertainment Value only. Follow and LIKE us at facebook.com/TwoMovieCritics A remake and remaster of the great classic movie in 3-D IMAX with stunning detail. It was an amazing transformation as Cissy and I were taken back in time before we both were born, August 15th, 1939 when The Wizard Of Oz opened at the Grauman's Chinese Theater. Immediately when the movie started and the title began in eye-popping 3-D fonts with the great sound track, Cissy and I got misty eyed. Now we were seeing this movie as it was meant to be seen and that we had only seen on T.V. sets all of our lives. Seeing it on the large IMAX screen, and in 3-D was an overwhelming experience. You see and hear things you missed all those years on TV. The detail of Glinda's ( The Good Witch's ) costume and many other costumes was amazing. The rust marks on the Tin Man's ( Jack Haley's ) body was very detailed, and later very shinny after their visit to Oz. We also heard several adults explaining to their children some of the story line before the movie started. A new generation was being introduced to the Wizard Of Oz just as if they were at the opening in 1939. I suggest all lovers of The Wizard Of Oz relive this classic again with their children, and grandchildren the way it was meant to be seen on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic movie that brings the imagination of childhood.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gokhan Erguven
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's probably a shame for me to have watched this movie too late, but since it's a classic, I don't feel bad about that. The setting, the costumes, the scene, the music, the effects are so beautiful that you can ignore the movie was shot in 1939. The movie is a classic and it has been referenced in so many movies and TV series that I watched so that it brought me to the point of I must watch it -- and it indeed was worth the watch. Judy Garland, Frank Morgan, Ray Bolger, Bert Lahr, Jack Haley, Billie Burke and all the other cast of the film are so great and talented that you'll be amazed by their performances. I also read a speculation that half the movie was shot colorless, and the other half with color on purpose, but there are other speculations that the movie was began to be shot in 1925 and done in 1939 because of the unavailable color film. Anyways, such a good film with a great imagination. Worth to watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent Work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    swpesto
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wizard of Oz with always be treasured throughout centuries. It is a piece of art. So magical. So beautiful. Judy Garland is so poised as Dorothy even at the young age of 16. The music and dancing are wonderful. Roy Bolger is awesome as "The Scarecrow". Such talent went into the casting of the film. Such special effects for a film almost putting it way before it's time. I feel some of these effects have been carried through with future films that have been made. Each film learns from the other. I will always love "The Wizard of Oz. Looking forward to the recent films that will continue the Oz series. I loved James Franco's portrayal in "Oz the Great and Powerful". Still nothing will come to the magic of the original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i have good review of dorothy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVIDMICHAEL HINES (2angelhines@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i am a film maker at LACC in los angeles californa and we all watch the movies in class and we saw this movie wizard of oz . she is a very good singer and actress .i love the way she does in the film . the most thing i seen was awesome that the tornado took her house up in the air once she woke up she saw the people she knows and she thought oh weired what is happening . as she looked down she jumped back and said omg she rush back to the bed . then she felt the house going back down like hell boom . once she came out she was in another world . she never gone before . as for toto very smart dog she was on her side . filmmaker student at lacc David B.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Follow The Yellow Brick Road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wizard Of Oz (TWOO) is probably one of the most famous Hollywood films of the late-1930s and, maybe, even the early-1940s. As I understand it, when TWOO was first released back in 1939 it really wasn't a colossal hit. It wasn't until the coming of TV when it was first aired in the 1950s that it attracted a humongous fan-base and from there it became one of the most popular films of all-time. Filmed at MGM Studios, TWOO was made at a time when MGM was, without question, the wealthiest, most impressive, and most successful Hollywood studio in the USA. Back in 1939 TWOO was made simply as a showpiece. This was MGM showing the world just how much power they wielded, that they could make an expensive film like this one and not care, one bit, whether it earned them a profit, or not. Little did the MGM big-wigs realize at the time that TWOO would go on to become one of the most beloved Fantasy/Adventure films of all time. So - "Tap your heels together 3 times and repeat after me - There's no place like home. There's no place like home."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Red Brick Road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kclov13
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies! I wore out the video tape a few times. I now own the DVD. Since I was little, I loved the movie. I was Dorothy for Halloween a couple years, I have the board game, and my first tattoo was inspired by this movie. The one thing that I have always questioned is where the Red Brick road goes. It would have been interesting to find out where it went. I hope that my future children will enjoy this movie as much as I did and still do. This movie has held up pretty good over the years, and I hope that it still does. I will continue to watch it and enjoy it as much as I did when I first saw it, (except now I probably know most of the lines to the movie).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll get you my little pretty, and your dog too."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are only two other Movies from Hollywood's Golden Age that have been as influential, deconstructed, analyzed, reconsidered, penetrating, viewed, and reviewed, noticed, and unforgotten as this one. King Kong (1933) and Citizen Kane (1941). Everyone who has seen Oz has an opinion and it is usually a strong one. It undeniably unmasks facades and oozes into the deeper parts of the consciousness worthy of the best Psychoanalysis. On the surface it lures one in with its sentimentality and charms with its catchy and heartfelt tunes. It bombards the senses, like a psychedelic, expanding consciousness through dripping Colors and the most imaginative of imagery. As the mind opens it is vulnerable to scary images as well as the sublime. Reality becomes a focused blur that is experienced profoundly and deeply. It is Art at its most cunningly persuasive. If you "pay no attention to the Man behind the curtain", you will find yourself in a land of Milk and Honey, but if you acknowledge reality for what it is and not what is hoped for, it might become a Truth that is as scary as a Flying Monkey. This Film is a Wonderful way to open the "doors of perception". That is the least and the best that the Movies can offer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lokethecheetah
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Often I am dubious about old movies, especially old sci-fi or "classic" movies. However, this movie was both enchanting and quite humorous for an oldie. The scenery was beautiful and so intricate. I was especially impressed by the lion's tail, flitting about in a life-like manner without the use of modern graphics or technology. The scenery impressed me because of all the time and effort that must have gone into creating it. Though much of the movie was spoiled for me through its fame, I was still amazed even with the scenes I knew were coming. The actors made the movie a delight to watch and the songs were humorous, and sometimes a bit stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Timeless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    meg_elizabeth
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "And you, and you, and you were there." All of Dorothy's friends look at her as if she was crazy, assuring her that her adventure was just a dream. Was it really just a dream? How could it be, when it seemed so real? In Viktor Fleming's, "The Wizard of Oz", dream is made into reality and reality into dream. "The Wizard of Oz" is a classical masterpiece in which breathtaking design, performance and a heart-warming storyline combine to create a movie in its very own category. In Kansas, a twister hits Dorothy's home and she is hit by a window, falling into her dreamland of Oz. We follow Dorothy (Judy Garland) on her quest for the Wizard of Oz, in the land of munchkins, evil and good witches, and many more interesting characters. The Scarecrow (Ray Bolger), Cowardly Lion (Bert Lahr), and Tin Man (Jack Haley) are just some of the friends, with their own problems, that she meets on her way. The story is all about "following the yellow brick road" as "we're off to see the wizard." The screenplay was adapted from Frank T. Baum's story chronicle, The Wizard of Oz. It was produced by Mervyn Leroy and acted out by a first class list of actors. Perhaps the most important factors of this movie are the Technicolor (this is the first movie in color), the songs (that you'll never forget and never get enough of), and the ubiquitous theme/moral of "there's no place like home." The plot is very easy to follow and straightforward. Despite the seemingly unrealistic storyline of wizards, a land of munchkins, flying monkeys, and bad witches flying on broomsticks, viewers can't help but fall into the fantasy of it all and imagine there really is such a place "somewhere over the rainbow." The characters are all believable and you seem able to relate to them and know at least one person in your life like them. People love the Scarecrow, Tin Man, and Cowardly Lion for their loyalty and personal quirks, and loathe the Wicked Witch of the West for being so sinfully evil. The dialogue is also very amusing, with a deeper meaning than most would conceive at first. There are many hidden messages of friendship, loyalty, and seeing what's right in front of you all along. The actors are very convincing as their characters, all seemingly to step right out from the original story. Judy Garland perhaps was the best choice for Dorothy because the viewer just can't help but fall in love and sympathize for her when they see those big brown eyes staring back at them from the screen. She has a raw performance in which you can feel each emotion through her expression. From the moment Dorothy opens her front door after landing in Oz and exclaims "Oh!" the screen is filled with bright and vibrant color, a sharp contrast from the dull black and white from a second before. The significance of this is not lost, as the use of color is artfully done throughout the movie. The Technicolor sets the film apart because it is the first picture to be in color. During the movie the ever present yellow brick road takes the viewer through a journey of colorful and unique places, like the charming Munchkin Land and eerily spooky Haunted Forest. This film is one that's timeless for a good reason. The acting is wonderful as is the set, themes, and dramatic aspects. The "Wizard of Oz" was one of a kind when it first came out and 75 years later it still touches people's hearts. The movie keeps the audience's interest and you walk away from it smiling. After watching the movie, it will give you a deeper respect for what you are and have. As Dorothy says, "There's no place like home," well, there's no movie like the Wizard of Oz.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A review of a movie everybody on the face of the earth saw
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maxfkeller
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the IMAX 3-D re-release 2 days ago and almost everyone at the theater was going to see this movie. I thought the 3D was very good and made me like the movie more. The film starts in black and... I don't need to talk about what happened in the movie, everybody saw it!!!!!! Being honest, I haven't seen the film in 5 years which made me forget a lot of parts of the film. Watching it, I felt like a little kid again. The choreography was good, the acting was very good, the cinematography was okay, the songs were very good. I just feel sad for forgetting the munchkins thanking Dorothy, the witch trying to get the slippers off of Dorothy, the "Lions and tigers and bears" scene, and the lion's if I were king of the forest song. I apologize to anybody reading this. Now you may disagree but The Wizard of Oz is a good film the family can watch during Taco Night. YAY!!!!!!!!! If you try, everyone eating will stop to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Wizard Of Oz 3-D IMAX 2013 - 4 Thumbs Up with Diamonds
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Russell Sanderlin (iMovieCritic@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone knows the story. Our thoughts on 3-D IMAX. Russell & Cissy, the Two Movie Critics rate movies based on Entertainment Value only. Follow and LIKE us at facebook.com/TwoMovieCritics A remake and remaster of the great classic movie in 3-D IMAX with stunning detail. It was an amazing transformation as Cissy and I were taken back in time before we both were born, August 15th, 1939 when The Wizard Of Oz opened at the Grauman's Chinese Theater. Immediately when the movie started and the title began in eye-popping 3-D fonts with the great sound track, Cissy and I got misty eyed. Now we were seeing this movie as it was meant to be seen and that we had only seen on T.V. sets all of our lives. Seeing it on the large IMAX screen, and in 3-D was an overwhelming experience. You see and hear things you missed all those years on TV. The detail of Glinda's ( The Good Witch's ) costume and many other costumes was amazing. The rust marks on the Tin Man's ( Jack Haley's ) body was very detailed, and later very shinny after their visit to Oz. We also heard several adults explaining to their children some of the story line before the movie started. A new generation was being introduced to the Wizard Of Oz just as if they were at the opening in 1939. I suggest all lovers of The Wizard Of Oz relive this classic again with their children, and grandchildren the way it was meant to be seen on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic movie that brings the imagination of childhood.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gokhan Erguven
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's probably a shame for me to have watched this movie too late, but since it's a classic, I don't feel bad about that. The setting, the costumes, the scene, the music, the effects are so beautiful that you can ignore the movie was shot in 1939. The movie is a classic and it has been referenced in so many movies and TV series that I watched so that it brought me to the point of I must watch it -- and it indeed was worth the watch. Judy Garland, Frank Morgan, Ray Bolger, Bert Lahr, Jack Haley, Billie Burke and all the other cast of the film are so great and talented that you'll be amazed by their performances. I also read a speculation that half the movie was shot colorless, and the other half with color on purpose, but there are other speculations that the movie was began to be shot in 1925 and done in 1939 because of the unavailable color film. Anyways, such a good film with a great imagination. Worth to watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent Work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    swpesto
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wizard of Oz with always be treasured throughout centuries. It is a piece of art. So magical. So beautiful. Judy Garland is so poised as Dorothy even at the young age of 16. The music and dancing are wonderful. Roy Bolger is awesome as "The Scarecrow". Such talent went into the casting of the film. Such special effects for a film almost putting it way before it's time. I feel some of these effects have been carried through with future films that have been made. Each film learns from the other. I will always love "The Wizard of Oz. Looking forward to the recent films that will continue the Oz series. I loved James Franco's portrayal in "Oz the Great and Powerful". Still nothing will come to the magic of the original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i have good review of dorothy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVIDMICHAEL HINES (2angelhines@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i am a film maker at LACC in los angeles californa and we all watch the movies in class and we saw this movie wizard of oz . she is a very good singer and actress .i love the way she does in the film . the most thing i seen was awesome that the tornado took her house up in the air once she woke up she saw the people she knows and she thought oh weired what is happening . as she looked down she jumped back and said omg she rush back to the bed . then she felt the house going back down like hell boom . once she came out she was in another world . she never gone before . as for toto very smart dog she was on her side . filmmaker student at lacc David B.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Follow The Yellow Brick Road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wizard Of Oz (TWOO) is probably one of the most famous Hollywood films of the late-1930s and, maybe, even the early-1940s. As I understand it, when TWOO was first released back in 1939 it really wasn't a colossal hit. It wasn't until the coming of TV when it was first aired in the 1950s that it attracted a humongous fan-base and from there it became one of the most popular films of all-time. Filmed at MGM Studios, TWOO was made at a time when MGM was, without question, the wealthiest, most impressive, and most successful Hollywood studio in the USA. Back in 1939 TWOO was made simply as a showpiece. This was MGM showing the world just how much power they wielded, that they could make an expensive film like this one and not care, one bit, whether it earned them a profit, or not. Little did the MGM big-wigs realize at the time that TWOO would go on to become one of the most beloved Fantasy/Adventure films of all time. So - "Tap your heels together 3 times and repeat after me - There's no place like home. There's no place like home."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Red Brick Road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kclov13
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies! I wore out the video tape a few times. I now own the DVD. Since I was little, I loved the movie. I was Dorothy for Halloween a couple years, I have the board game, and my first tattoo was inspired by this movie. The one thing that I have always questioned is where the Red Brick road goes. It would have been interesting to find out where it went. I hope that my future children will enjoy this movie as much as I did and still do. This movie has held up pretty good over the years, and I hope that it still does. I will continue to watch it and enjoy it as much as I did when I first saw it, (except now I probably know most of the lines to the movie).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll get you my little pretty, and your dog too."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are only two other Movies from Hollywood's Golden Age that have been as influential, deconstructed, analyzed, reconsidered, penetrating, viewed, and reviewed, noticed, and unforgotten as this one. King Kong (1933) and Citizen Kane (1941). Everyone who has seen Oz has an opinion and it is usually a strong one. It undeniably unmasks facades and oozes into the deeper parts of the consciousness worthy of the best Psychoanalysis. On the surface it lures one in with its sentimentality and charms with its catchy and heartfelt tunes. It bombards the senses, like a psychedelic, expanding consciousness through dripping Colors and the most imaginative of imagery. As the mind opens it is vulnerable to scary images as well as the sublime. Reality becomes a focused blur that is experienced profoundly and deeply. It is Art at its most cunningly persuasive. If you "pay no attention to the Man behind the curtain", you will find yourself in a land of Milk and Honey, but if you acknowledge reality for what it is and not what is hoped for, it might become a Truth that is as scary as a Flying Monkey. This Film is a Wonderful way to open the "doors of perception". That is the least and the best that the Movies can offer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lokethecheetah
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Often I am dubious about old movies, especially old sci-fi or "classic" movies. However, this movie was both enchanting and quite humorous for an oldie. The scenery was beautiful and so intricate. I was especially impressed by the lion's tail, flitting about in a life-like manner without the use of modern graphics or technology. The scenery impressed me because of all the time and effort that must have gone into creating it. Though much of the movie was spoiled for me through its fame, I was still amazed even with the scenes I knew were coming. The actors made the movie a delight to watch and the songs were humorous, and sometimes a bit stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Timeless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    meg_elizabeth
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "And you, and you, and you were there." All of Dorothy's friends look at her as if she was crazy, assuring her that her adventure was just a dream. Was it really just a dream? How could it be, when it seemed so real? In Viktor Fleming's, "The Wizard of Oz", dream is made into reality and reality into dream. "The Wizard of Oz" is a classical masterpiece in which breathtaking design, performance and a heart-warming storyline combine to create a movie in its very own category. In Kansas, a twister hits Dorothy's home and she is hit by a window, falling into her dreamland of Oz. We follow Dorothy (Judy Garland) on her quest for the Wizard of Oz, in the land of munchkins, evil and good witches, and many more interesting characters. The Scarecrow (Ray Bolger), Cowardly Lion (Bert Lahr), and Tin Man (Jack Haley) are just some of the friends, with their own problems, that she meets on her way. The story is all about "following the yellow brick road" as "we're off to see the wizard." The screenplay was adapted from Frank T. Baum's story chronicle, The Wizard of Oz. It was produced by Mervyn Leroy and acted out by a first class list of actors. Perhaps the most important factors of this movie are the Technicolor (this is the first movie in color), the songs (that you'll never forget and never get enough of), and the ubiquitous theme/moral of "there's no place like home." The plot is very easy to follow and straightforward. Despite the seemingly unrealistic storyline of wizards, a land of munchkins, flying monkeys, and bad witches flying on broomsticks, viewers can't help but fall into the fantasy of it all and imagine there really is such a place "somewhere over the rainbow." The characters are all believable and you seem able to relate to them and know at least one person in your life like them. People love the Scarecrow, Tin Man, and Cowardly Lion for their loyalty and personal quirks, and loathe the Wicked Witch of the West for being so sinfully evil. The dialogue is also very amusing, with a deeper meaning than most would conceive at first. There are many hidden messages of friendship, loyalty, and seeing what's right in front of you all along. The actors are very convincing as their characters, all seemingly to step right out from the original story. Judy Garland perhaps was the best choice for Dorothy because the viewer just can't help but fall in love and sympathize for her when they see those big brown eyes staring back at them from the screen. She has a raw performance in which you can feel each emotion through her expression. From the moment Dorothy opens her front door after landing in Oz and exclaims "Oh!" the screen is filled with bright and vibrant color, a sharp contrast from the dull black and white from a second before. The significance of this is not lost, as the use of color is artfully done throughout the movie. The Technicolor sets the film apart because it is the first picture to be in color. During the movie the ever present yellow brick road takes the viewer through a journey of colorful and unique places, like the charming Munchkin Land and eerily spooky Haunted Forest. This film is one that's timeless for a good reason. The acting is wonderful as is the set, themes, and dramatic aspects. The "Wizard of Oz" was one of a kind when it first came out and 75 years later it still touches people's hearts. The movie keeps the audience's interest and you walk away from it smiling. After watching the movie, it will give you a deeper respect for what you are and have. As Dorothy says, "There's no place like home," well, there's no movie like the Wizard of Oz.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A review of a movie everybody on the face of the earth saw
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maxfkeller
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the IMAX 3-D re-release 2 days ago and almost everyone at the theater was going to see this movie. I thought the 3D was very good and made me like the movie more. The film starts in black and... I don't need to talk about what happened in the movie, everybody saw it!!!!!! Being honest, I haven't seen the film in 5 years which made me forget a lot of parts of the film. Watching it, I felt like a little kid again. The choreography was good, the acting was very good, the cinematography was okay, the songs were very good. I just feel sad for forgetting the munchkins thanking Dorothy, the witch trying to get the slippers off of Dorothy, the "Lions and tigers and bears" scene, and the lion's if I were king of the forest song. I apologize to anybody reading this. Now you may disagree but The Wizard of Oz is a good film the family can watch during Taco Night. YAY!!!!!!!!! If you try, everyone eating will stop to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Wizard Of Oz 3-D IMAX 2013 - 4 Thumbs Up with Diamonds
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Russell Sanderlin (iMovieCritic@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone knows the story. Our thoughts on 3-D IMAX. Russell & Cissy, the Two Movie Critics rate movies based on Entertainment Value only. Follow and LIKE us at facebook.com/TwoMovieCritics A remake and remaster of the great classic movie in 3-D IMAX with stunning detail. It was an amazing transformation as Cissy and I were taken back in time before we both were born, August 15th, 1939 when The Wizard Of Oz opened at the Grauman's Chinese Theater. Immediately when the movie started and the title began in eye-popping 3-D fonts with the great sound track, Cissy and I got misty eyed. Now we were seeing this movie as it was meant to be seen and that we had only seen on T.V. sets all of our lives. Seeing it on the large IMAX screen, and in 3-D was an overwhelming experience. You see and hear things you missed all those years on TV. The detail of Glinda's ( The Good Witch's ) costume and many other costumes was amazing. The rust marks on the Tin Man's ( Jack Haley's ) body was very detailed, and later very shinny after their visit to Oz. We also heard several adults explaining to their children some of the story line before the movie started. A new generation was being introduced to the Wizard Of Oz just as if they were at the opening in 1939. I suggest all lovers of The Wizard Of Oz relive this classic again with their children, and grandchildren the way it was meant to be seen on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic movie that brings the imagination of childhood.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gokhan Erguven
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's probably a shame for me to have watched this movie too late, but since it's a classic, I don't feel bad about that. The setting, the costumes, the scene, the music, the effects are so beautiful that you can ignore the movie was shot in 1939. The movie is a classic and it has been referenced in so many movies and TV series that I watched so that it brought me to the point of I must watch it -- and it indeed was worth the watch. Judy Garland, Frank Morgan, Ray Bolger, Bert Lahr, Jack Haley, Billie Burke and all the other cast of the film are so great and talented that you'll be amazed by their performances. I also read a speculation that half the movie was shot colorless, and the other half with color on purpose, but there are other speculations that the movie was began to be shot in 1925 and done in 1939 because of the unavailable color film. Anyways, such a good film with a great imagination. Worth to watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent Work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    swpesto
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wizard of Oz with always be treasured throughout centuries. It is a piece of art. So magical. So beautiful. Judy Garland is so poised as Dorothy even at the young age of 16. The music and dancing are wonderful. Roy Bolger is awesome as "The Scarecrow". Such talent went into the casting of the film. Such special effects for a film almost putting it way before it's time. I feel some of these effects have been carried through with future films that have been made. Each film learns from the other. I will always love "The Wizard of Oz. Looking forward to the recent films that will continue the Oz series. I loved James Franco's portrayal in "Oz the Great and Powerful". Still nothing will come to the magic of the original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i have good review of dorothy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVIDMICHAEL HINES (2angelhines@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i am a film maker at LACC in los angeles californa and we all watch the movies in class and we saw this movie wizard of oz . she is a very good singer and actress .i love the way she does in the film . the most thing i seen was awesome that the tornado took her house up in the air once she woke up she saw the people she knows and she thought oh weired what is happening . as she looked down she jumped back and said omg she rush back to the bed . then she felt the house going back down like hell boom . once she came out she was in another world . she never gone before . as for toto very smart dog she was on her side . filmmaker student at lacc David B.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Follow The Yellow Brick Road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wizard Of Oz (TWOO) is probably one of the most famous Hollywood films of the late-1930s and, maybe, even the early-1940s. As I understand it, when TWOO was first released back in 1939 it really wasn't a colossal hit. It wasn't until the coming of TV when it was first aired in the 1950s that it attracted a humongous fan-base and from there it became one of the most popular films of all-time. Filmed at MGM Studios, TWOO was made at a time when MGM was, without question, the wealthiest, most impressive, and most successful Hollywood studio in the USA. Back in 1939 TWOO was made simply as a showpiece. This was MGM showing the world just how much power they wielded, that they could make an expensive film like this one and not care, one bit, whether it earned them a profit, or not. Little did the MGM big-wigs realize at the time that TWOO would go on to become one of the most beloved Fantasy/Adventure films of all time. So - "Tap your heels together 3 times and repeat after me - There's no place like home. There's no place like home."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Red Brick Road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kclov13
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies! I wore out the video tape a few times. I now own the DVD. Since I was little, I loved the movie. I was Dorothy for Halloween a couple years, I have the board game, and my first tattoo was inspired by this movie. The one thing that I have always questioned is where the Red Brick road goes. It would have been interesting to find out where it went. I hope that my future children will enjoy this movie as much as I did and still do. This movie has held up pretty good over the years, and I hope that it still does. I will continue to watch it and enjoy it as much as I did when I first saw it, (except now I probably know most of the lines to the movie).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll get you my little pretty, and your dog too."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are only two other Movies from Hollywood's Golden Age that have been as influential, deconstructed, analyzed, reconsidered, penetrating, viewed, and reviewed, noticed, and unforgotten as this one. King Kong (1933) and Citizen Kane (1941). Everyone who has seen Oz has an opinion and it is usually a strong one. It undeniably unmasks facades and oozes into the deeper parts of the consciousness worthy of the best Psychoanalysis. On the surface it lures one in with its sentimentality and charms with its catchy and heartfelt tunes. It bombards the senses, like a psychedelic, expanding consciousness through dripping Colors and the most imaginative of imagery. As the mind opens it is vulnerable to scary images as well as the sublime. Reality becomes a focused blur that is experienced profoundly and deeply. It is Art at its most cunningly persuasive. If you "pay no attention to the Man behind the curtain", you will find yourself in a land of Milk and Honey, but if you acknowledge reality for what it is and not what is hoped for, it might become a Truth that is as scary as a Flying Monkey. This Film is a Wonderful way to open the "doors of perception". That is the least and the best that the Movies can offer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lokethecheetah
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Often I am dubious about old movies, especially old sci-fi or "classic" movies. However, this movie was both enchanting and quite humorous for an oldie. The scenery was beautiful and so intricate. I was especially impressed by the lion's tail, flitting about in a life-like manner without the use of modern graphics or technology. The scenery impressed me because of all the time and effort that must have gone into creating it. Though much of the movie was spoiled for me through its fame, I was still amazed even with the scenes I knew were coming. The actors made the movie a delight to watch and the songs were humorous, and sometimes a bit stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Timeless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    meg_elizabeth
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "And you, and you, and you were there." All of Dorothy's friends look at her as if she was crazy, assuring her that her adventure was just a dream. Was it really just a dream? How could it be, when it seemed so real? In Viktor Fleming's, "The Wizard of Oz", dream is made into reality and reality into dream. "The Wizard of Oz" is a classical masterpiece in which breathtaking design, performance and a heart-warming storyline combine to create a movie in its very own category. In Kansas, a twister hits Dorothy's home and she is hit by a window, falling into her dreamland of Oz. We follow Dorothy (Judy Garland) on her quest for the Wizard of Oz, in the land of munchkins, evil and good witches, and many more interesting characters. The Scarecrow (Ray Bolger), Cowardly Lion (Bert Lahr), and Tin Man (Jack Haley) are just some of the friends, with their own problems, that she meets on her way. The story is all about "following the yellow brick road" as "we're off to see the wizard." The screenplay was adapted from Frank T. Baum's story chronicle, The Wizard of Oz. It was produced by Mervyn Leroy and acted out by a first class list of actors. Perhaps the most important factors of this movie are the Technicolor (this is the first movie in color), the songs (that you'll never forget and never get enough of), and the ubiquitous theme/moral of "there's no place like home." The plot is very easy to follow and straightforward. Despite the seemingly unrealistic storyline of wizards, a land of munchkins, flying monkeys, and bad witches flying on broomsticks, viewers can't help but fall into the fantasy of it all and imagine there really is such a place "somewhere over the rainbow." The characters are all believable and you seem able to relate to them and know at least one person in your life like them. People love the Scarecrow, Tin Man, and Cowardly Lion for their loyalty and personal quirks, and loathe the Wicked Witch of the West for being so sinfully evil. The dialogue is also very amusing, with a deeper meaning than most would conceive at first. There are many hidden messages of friendship, loyalty, and seeing what's right in front of you all along. The actors are very convincing as their characters, all seemingly to step right out from the original story. Judy Garland perhaps was the best choice for Dorothy because the viewer just can't help but fall in love and sympathize for her when they see those big brown eyes staring back at them from the screen. She has a raw performance in which you can feel each emotion through her expression. From the moment Dorothy opens her front door after landing in Oz and exclaims "Oh!" the screen is filled with bright and vibrant color, a sharp contrast from the dull black and white from a second before. The significance of this is not lost, as the use of color is artfully done throughout the movie. The Technicolor sets the film apart because it is the first picture to be in color. During the movie the ever present yellow brick road takes the viewer through a journey of colorful and unique places, like the charming Munchkin Land and eerily spooky Haunted Forest. This film is one that's timeless for a good reason. The acting is wonderful as is the set, themes, and dramatic aspects. The "Wizard of Oz" was one of a kind when it first came out and 75 years later it still touches people's hearts. The movie keeps the audience's interest and you walk away from it smiling. After watching the movie, it will give you a deeper respect for what you are and have. As Dorothy says, "There's no place like home," well, there's no movie like the Wizard of Oz.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A review of a movie everybody on the face of the earth saw
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maxfkeller
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the IMAX 3-D re-release 2 days ago and almost everyone at the theater was going to see this movie. I thought the 3D was very good and made me like the movie more. The film starts in black and... I don't need to talk about what happened in the movie, everybody saw it!!!!!! Being honest, I haven't seen the film in 5 years which made me forget a lot of parts of the film. Watching it, I felt like a little kid again. The choreography was good, the acting was very good, the cinematography was okay, the songs were very good. I just feel sad for forgetting the munchkins thanking Dorothy, the witch trying to get the slippers off of Dorothy, the "Lions and tigers and bears" scene, and the lion's if I were king of the forest song. I apologize to anybody reading this. Now you may disagree but The Wizard of Oz is a good film the family can watch during Taco Night. YAY!!!!!!!!! If you try, everyone eating will stop to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Wizard Of Oz 3-D IMAX 2013 - 4 Thumbs Up with Diamonds
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Russell Sanderlin (iMovieCritic@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone knows the story. Our thoughts on 3-D IMAX. Russell & Cissy, the Two Movie Critics rate movies based on Entertainment Value only. Follow and LIKE us at facebook.com/TwoMovieCritics A remake and remaster of the great classic movie in 3-D IMAX with stunning detail. It was an amazing transformation as Cissy and I were taken back in time before we both were born, August 15th, 1939 when The Wizard Of Oz opened at the Grauman's Chinese Theater. Immediately when the movie started and the title began in eye-popping 3-D fonts with the great sound track, Cissy and I got misty eyed. Now we were seeing this movie as it was meant to be seen and that we had only seen on T.V. sets all of our lives. Seeing it on the large IMAX screen, and in 3-D was an overwhelming experience. You see and hear things you missed all those years on TV. The detail of Glinda's ( The Good Witch's ) costume and many other costumes was amazing. The rust marks on the Tin Man's ( Jack Haley's ) body was very detailed, and later very shinny after their visit to Oz. We also heard several adults explaining to their children some of the story line before the movie started. A new generation was being introduced to the Wizard Of Oz just as if they were at the opening in 1939. I suggest all lovers of The Wizard Of Oz relive this classic again with their children, and grandchildren the way it was meant to be seen on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic movie that brings the imagination of childhood.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gokhan Erguven
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's probably a shame for me to have watched this movie too late, but since it's a classic, I don't feel bad about that. The setting, the costumes, the scene, the music, the effects are so beautiful that you can ignore the movie was shot in 1939. The movie is a classic and it has been referenced in so many movies and TV series that I watched so that it brought me to the point of I must watch it -- and it indeed was worth the watch. Judy Garland, Frank Morgan, Ray Bolger, Bert Lahr, Jack Haley, Billie Burke and all the other cast of the film are so great and talented that you'll be amazed by their performances. I also read a speculation that half the movie was shot colorless, and the other half with color on purpose, but there are other speculations that the movie was began to be shot in 1925 and done in 1939 because of the unavailable color film. Anyways, such a good film with a great imagination. Worth to watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent Work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    swpesto
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wizard of Oz with always be treasured throughout centuries. It is a piece of art. So magical. So beautiful. Judy Garland is so poised as Dorothy even at the young age of 16. The music and dancing are wonderful. Roy Bolger is awesome as "The Scarecrow". Such talent went into the casting of the film. Such special effects for a film almost putting it way before it's time. I feel some of these effects have been carried through with future films that have been made. Each film learns from the other. I will always love "The Wizard of Oz. Looking forward to the recent films that will continue the Oz series. I loved James Franco's portrayal in "Oz the Great and Powerful". Still nothing will come to the magic of the original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i have good review of dorothy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVIDMICHAEL HINES (2angelhines@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i am a film maker at LACC in los angeles californa and we all watch the movies in class and we saw this movie wizard of oz . she is a very good singer and actress .i love the way she does in the film . the most thing i seen was awesome that the tornado took her house up in the air once she woke up she saw the people she knows and she thought oh weired what is happening . as she looked down she jumped back and said omg she rush back to the bed . then she felt the house going back down like hell boom . once she came out she was in another world . she never gone before . as for toto very smart dog she was on her side . filmmaker student at lacc David B.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Follow The Yellow Brick Road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wizard Of Oz (TWOO) is probably one of the most famous Hollywood films of the late-1930s and, maybe, even the early-1940s. As I understand it, when TWOO was first released back in 1939 it really wasn't a colossal hit. It wasn't until the coming of TV when it was first aired in the 1950s that it attracted a humongous fan-base and from there it became one of the most popular films of all-time. Filmed at MGM Studios, TWOO was made at a time when MGM was, without question, the wealthiest, most impressive, and most successful Hollywood studio in the USA. Back in 1939 TWOO was made simply as a showpiece. This was MGM showing the world just how much power they wielded, that they could make an expensive film like this one and not care, one bit, whether it earned them a profit, or not. Little did the MGM big-wigs realize at the time that TWOO would go on to become one of the most beloved Fantasy/Adventure films of all time. So - "Tap your heels together 3 times and repeat after me - There's no place like home. There's no place like home."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Red Brick Road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kclov13
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies! I wore out the video tape a few times. I now own the DVD. Since I was little, I loved the movie. I was Dorothy for Halloween a couple years, I have the board game, and my first tattoo was inspired by this movie. The one thing that I have always questioned is where the Red Brick road goes. It would have been interesting to find out where it went. I hope that my future children will enjoy this movie as much as I did and still do. This movie has held up pretty good over the years, and I hope that it still does. I will continue to watch it and enjoy it as much as I did when I first saw it, (except now I probably know most of the lines to the movie).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll get you my little pretty, and your dog too."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are only two other Movies from Hollywood's Golden Age that have been as influential, deconstructed, analyzed, reconsidered, penetrating, viewed, and reviewed, noticed, and unforgotten as this one. King Kong (1933) and Citizen Kane (1941). Everyone who has seen Oz has an opinion and it is usually a strong one. It undeniably unmasks facades and oozes into the deeper parts of the consciousness worthy of the best Psychoanalysis. On the surface it lures one in with its sentimentality and charms with its catchy and heartfelt tunes. It bombards the senses, like a psychedelic, expanding consciousness through dripping Colors and the most imaginative of imagery. As the mind opens it is vulnerable to scary images as well as the sublime. Reality becomes a focused blur that is experienced profoundly and deeply. It is Art at its most cunningly persuasive. If you "pay no attention to the Man behind the curtain", you will find yourself in a land of Milk and Honey, but if you acknowledge reality for what it is and not what is hoped for, it might become a Truth that is as scary as a Flying Monkey. This Film is a Wonderful way to open the "doors of perception". That is the least and the best that the Movies can offer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lokethecheetah
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Often I am dubious about old movies, especially old sci-fi or "classic" movies. However, this movie was both enchanting and quite humorous for an oldie. The scenery was beautiful and so intricate. I was especially impressed by the lion's tail, flitting about in a life-like manner without the use of modern graphics or technology. The scenery impressed me because of all the time and effort that must have gone into creating it. Though much of the movie was spoiled for me through its fame, I was still amazed even with the scenes I knew were coming. The actors made the movie a delight to watch and the songs were humorous, and sometimes a bit stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Timeless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    meg_elizabeth
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "And you, and you, and you were there." All of Dorothy's friends look at her as if she was crazy, assuring her that her adventure was just a dream. Was it really just a dream? How could it be, when it seemed so real? In Viktor Fleming's, "The Wizard of Oz", dream is made into reality and reality into dream. "The Wizard of Oz" is a classical masterpiece in which breathtaking design, performance and a heart-warming storyline combine to create a movie in its very own category. In Kansas, a twister hits Dorothy's home and she is hit by a window, falling into her dreamland of Oz. We follow Dorothy (Judy Garland) on her quest for the Wizard of Oz, in the land of munchkins, evil and good witches, and many more interesting characters. The Scarecrow (Ray Bolger), Cowardly Lion (Bert Lahr), and Tin Man (Jack Haley) are just some of the friends, with their own problems, that she meets on her way. The story is all about "following the yellow brick road" as "we're off to see the wizard." The screenplay was adapted from Frank T. Baum's story chronicle, The Wizard of Oz. It was produced by Mervyn Leroy and acted out by a first class list of actors. Perhaps the most important factors of this movie are the Technicolor (this is the first movie in color), the songs (that you'll never forget and never get enough of), and the ubiquitous theme/moral of "there's no place like home." The plot is very easy to follow and straightforward. Despite the seemingly unrealistic storyline of wizards, a land of munchkins, flying monkeys, and bad witches flying on broomsticks, viewers can't help but fall into the fantasy of it all and imagine there really is such a place "somewhere over the rainbow." The characters are all believable and you seem able to relate to them and know at least one person in your life like them. People love the Scarecrow, Tin Man, and Cowardly Lion for their loyalty and personal quirks, and loathe the Wicked Witch of the West for being so sinfully evil. The dialogue is also very amusing, with a deeper meaning than most would conceive at first. There are many hidden messages of friendship, loyalty, and seeing what's right in front of you all along. The actors are very convincing as their characters, all seemingly to step right out from the original story. Judy Garland perhaps was the best choice for Dorothy because the viewer just can't help but fall in love and sympathize for her when they see those big brown eyes staring back at them from the screen. She has a raw performance in which you can feel each emotion through her expression. From the moment Dorothy opens her front door after landing in Oz and exclaims "Oh!" the screen is filled with bright and vibrant color, a sharp contrast from the dull black and white from a second before. The significance of this is not lost, as the use of color is artfully done throughout the movie. The Technicolor sets the film apart because it is the first picture to be in color. During the movie the ever present yellow brick road takes the viewer through a journey of colorful and unique places, like the charming Munchkin Land and eerily spooky Haunted Forest. This film is one that's timeless for a good reason. The acting is wonderful as is the set, themes, and dramatic aspects. The "Wizard of Oz" was one of a kind when it first came out and 75 years later it still touches people's hearts. The movie keeps the audience's interest and you walk away from it smiling. After watching the movie, it will give you a deeper respect for what you are and have. As Dorothy says, "There's no place like home," well, there's no movie like the Wizard of Oz.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A review of a movie everybody on the face of the earth saw
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maxfkeller
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the IMAX 3-D re-release 2 days ago and almost everyone at the theater was going to see this movie. I thought the 3D was very good and made me like the movie more. The film starts in black and... I don't need to talk about what happened in the movie, everybody saw it!!!!!! Being honest, I haven't seen the film in 5 years which made me forget a lot of parts of the film. Watching it, I felt like a little kid again. The choreography was good, the acting was very good, the cinematography was okay, the songs were very good. I just feel sad for forgetting the munchkins thanking Dorothy, the witch trying to get the slippers off of Dorothy, the "Lions and tigers and bears" scene, and the lion's if I were king of the forest song. I apologize to anybody reading this. Now you may disagree but The Wizard of Oz is a good film the family can watch during Taco Night. YAY!!!!!!!!! If you try, everyone eating will stop to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Wizard Of Oz 3-D IMAX 2013 - 4 Thumbs Up with Diamonds
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Russell Sanderlin (iMovieCritic@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone knows the story. Our thoughts on 3-D IMAX. Russell & Cissy, the Two Movie Critics rate movies based on Entertainment Value only. Follow and LIKE us at facebook.com/TwoMovieCritics A remake and remaster of the great classic movie in 3-D IMAX with stunning detail. It was an amazing transformation as Cissy and I were taken back in time before we both were born, August 15th, 1939 when The Wizard Of Oz opened at the Grauman's Chinese Theater. Immediately when the movie started and the title began in eye-popping 3-D fonts with the great sound track, Cissy and I got misty eyed. Now we were seeing this movie as it was meant to be seen and that we had only seen on T.V. sets all of our lives. Seeing it on the large IMAX screen, and in 3-D was an overwhelming experience. You see and hear things you missed all those years on TV. The detail of Glinda's ( The Good Witch's ) costume and many other costumes was amazing. The rust marks on the Tin Man's ( Jack Haley's ) body was very detailed, and later very shinny after their visit to Oz. We also heard several adults explaining to their children some of the story line before the movie started. A new generation was being introduced to the Wizard Of Oz just as if they were at the opening in 1939. I suggest all lovers of The Wizard Of Oz relive this classic again with their children, and grandchildren the way it was meant to be seen on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic movie that brings the imagination of childhood.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gokhan Erguven
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's probably a shame for me to have watched this movie too late, but since it's a classic, I don't feel bad about that. The setting, the costumes, the scene, the music, the effects are so beautiful that you can ignore the movie was shot in 1939. The movie is a classic and it has been referenced in so many movies and TV series that I watched so that it brought me to the point of I must watch it -- and it indeed was worth the watch. Judy Garland, Frank Morgan, Ray Bolger, Bert Lahr, Jack Haley, Billie Burke and all the other cast of the film are so great and talented that you'll be amazed by their performances. I also read a speculation that half the movie was shot colorless, and the other half with color on purpose, but there are other speculations that the movie was began to be shot in 1925 and done in 1939 because of the unavailable color film. Anyways, such a good film with a great imagination. Worth to watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent Work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    swpesto
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wizard of Oz with always be treasured throughout centuries. It is a piece of art. So magical. So beautiful. Judy Garland is so poised as Dorothy even at the young age of 16. The music and dancing are wonderful. Roy Bolger is awesome as "The Scarecrow". Such talent went into the casting of the film. Such special effects for a film almost putting it way before it's time. I feel some of these effects have been carried through with future films that have been made. Each film learns from the other. I will always love "The Wizard of Oz. Looking forward to the recent films that will continue the Oz series. I loved James Franco's portrayal in "Oz the Great and Powerful". Still nothing will come to the magic of the original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i have good review of dorothy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVIDMICHAEL HINES (2angelhines@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i am a film maker at LACC in los angeles californa and we all watch the movies in class and we saw this movie wizard of oz . she is a very good singer and actress .i love the way she does in the film . the most thing i seen was awesome that the tornado took her house up in the air once she woke up she saw the people she knows and she thought oh weired what is happening . as she looked down she jumped back and said omg she rush back to the bed . then she felt the house going back down like hell boom . once she came out she was in another world . she never gone before . as for toto very smart dog she was on her side . filmmaker student at lacc David B.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Follow The Yellow Brick Road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wizard Of Oz (TWOO) is probably one of the most famous Hollywood films of the late-1930s and, maybe, even the early-1940s. As I understand it, when TWOO was first released back in 1939 it really wasn't a colossal hit. It wasn't until the coming of TV when it was first aired in the 1950s that it attracted a humongous fan-base and from there it became one of the most popular films of all-time. Filmed at MGM Studios, TWOO was made at a time when MGM was, without question, the wealthiest, most impressive, and most successful Hollywood studio in the USA. Back in 1939 TWOO was made simply as a showpiece. This was MGM showing the world just how much power they wielded, that they could make an expensive film like this one and not care, one bit, whether it earned them a profit, or not. Little did the MGM big-wigs realize at the time that TWOO would go on to become one of the most beloved Fantasy/Adventure films of all time. So - "Tap your heels together 3 times and repeat after me - There's no place like home. There's no place like home."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Red Brick Road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kclov13
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies! I wore out the video tape a few times. I now own the DVD. Since I was little, I loved the movie. I was Dorothy for Halloween a couple years, I have the board game, and my first tattoo was inspired by this movie. The one thing that I have always questioned is where the Red Brick road goes. It would have been interesting to find out where it went. I hope that my future children will enjoy this movie as much as I did and still do. This movie has held up pretty good over the years, and I hope that it still does. I will continue to watch it and enjoy it as much as I did when I first saw it, (except now I probably know most of the lines to the movie).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll get you my little pretty, and your dog too."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are only two other Movies from Hollywood's Golden Age that have been as influential, deconstructed, analyzed, reconsidered, penetrating, viewed, and reviewed, noticed, and unforgotten as this one. King Kong (1933) and Citizen Kane (1941). Everyone who has seen Oz has an opinion and it is usually a strong one. It undeniably unmasks facades and oozes into the deeper parts of the consciousness worthy of the best Psychoanalysis. On the surface it lures one in with its sentimentality and charms with its catchy and heartfelt tunes. It bombards the senses, like a psychedelic, expanding consciousness through dripping Colors and the most imaginative of imagery. As the mind opens it is vulnerable to scary images as well as the sublime. Reality becomes a focused blur that is experienced profoundly and deeply. It is Art at its most cunningly persuasive. If you "pay no attention to the Man behind the curtain", you will find yourself in a land of Milk and Honey, but if you acknowledge reality for what it is and not what is hoped for, it might become a Truth that is as scary as a Flying Monkey. This Film is a Wonderful way to open the "doors of perception". That is the least and the best that the Movies can offer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lokethecheetah
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Often I am dubious about old movies, especially old sci-fi or "classic" movies. However, this movie was both enchanting and quite humorous for an oldie. The scenery was beautiful and so intricate. I was especially impressed by the lion's tail, flitting about in a life-like manner without the use of modern graphics or technology. The scenery impressed me because of all the time and effort that must have gone into creating it. Though much of the movie was spoiled for me through its fame, I was still amazed even with the scenes I knew were coming. The actors made the movie a delight to watch and the songs were humorous, and sometimes a bit stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Timeless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    meg_elizabeth
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "And you, and you, and you were there." All of Dorothy's friends look at her as if she was crazy, assuring her that her adventure was just a dream. Was it really just a dream? How could it be, when it seemed so real? In Viktor Fleming's, "The Wizard of Oz", dream is made into reality and reality into dream. "The Wizard of Oz" is a classical masterpiece in which breathtaking design, performance and a heart-warming storyline combine to create a movie in its very own category. In Kansas, a twister hits Dorothy's home and she is hit by a window, falling into her dreamland of Oz. We follow Dorothy (Judy Garland) on her quest for the Wizard of Oz, in the land of munchkins, evil and good witches, and many more interesting characters. The Scarecrow (Ray Bolger), Cowardly Lion (Bert Lahr), and Tin Man (Jack Haley) are just some of the friends, with their own problems, that she meets on her way. The story is all about "following the yellow brick road" as "we're off to see the wizard." The screenplay was adapted from Frank T. Baum's story chronicle, The Wizard of Oz. It was produced by Mervyn Leroy and acted out by a first class list of actors. Perhaps the most important factors of this movie are the Technicolor (this is the first movie in color), the songs (that you'll never forget and never get enough of), and the ubiquitous theme/moral of "there's no place like home." The plot is very easy to follow and straightforward. Despite the seemingly unrealistic storyline of wizards, a land of munchkins, flying monkeys, and bad witches flying on broomsticks, viewers can't help but fall into the fantasy of it all and imagine there really is such a place "somewhere over the rainbow." The characters are all believable and you seem able to relate to them and know at least one person in your life like them. People love the Scarecrow, Tin Man, and Cowardly Lion for their loyalty and personal quirks, and loathe the Wicked Witch of the West for being so sinfully evil. The dialogue is also very amusing, with a deeper meaning than most would conceive at first. There are many hidden messages of friendship, loyalty, and seeing what's right in front of you all along. The actors are very convincing as their characters, all seemingly to step right out from the original story. Judy Garland perhaps was the best choice for Dorothy because the viewer just can't help but fall in love and sympathize for her when they see those big brown eyes staring back at them from the screen. She has a raw performance in which you can feel each emotion through her expression. From the moment Dorothy opens her front door after landing in Oz and exclaims "Oh!" the screen is filled with bright and vibrant color, a sharp contrast from the dull black and white from a second before. The significance of this is not lost, as the use of color is artfully done throughout the movie. The Technicolor sets the film apart because it is the first picture to be in color. During the movie the ever present yellow brick road takes the viewer through a journey of colorful and unique places, like the charming Munchkin Land and eerily spooky Haunted Forest. This film is one that's timeless for a good reason. The acting is wonderful as is the set, themes, and dramatic aspects. The "Wizard of Oz" was one of a kind when it first came out and 75 years later it still touches people's hearts. The movie keeps the audience's interest and you walk away from it smiling. After watching the movie, it will give you a deeper respect for what you are and have. As Dorothy says, "There's no place like home," well, there's no movie like the Wizard of Oz.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A review of a movie everybody on the face of the earth saw
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maxfkeller
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the IMAX 3-D re-release 2 days ago and almost everyone at the theater was going to see this movie. I thought the 3D was very good and made me like the movie more. The film starts in black and... I don't need to talk about what happened in the movie, everybody saw it!!!!!! Being honest, I haven't seen the film in 5 years which made me forget a lot of parts of the film. Watching it, I felt like a little kid again. The choreography was good, the acting was very good, the cinematography was okay, the songs were very good. I just feel sad for forgetting the munchkins thanking Dorothy, the witch trying to get the slippers off of Dorothy, the "Lions and tigers and bears" scene, and the lion's if I were king of the forest song. I apologize to anybody reading this. Now you may disagree but The Wizard of Oz is a good film the family can watch during Taco Night. YAY!!!!!!!!! If you try, everyone eating will stop to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Wizard Of Oz 3-D IMAX 2013 - 4 Thumbs Up with Diamonds
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Russell Sanderlin (iMovieCritic@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone knows the story. Our thoughts on 3-D IMAX. Russell & Cissy, the Two Movie Critics rate movies based on Entertainment Value only. Follow and LIKE us at facebook.com/TwoMovieCritics A remake and remaster of the great classic movie in 3-D IMAX with stunning detail. It was an amazing transformation as Cissy and I were taken back in time before we both were born, August 15th, 1939 when The Wizard Of Oz opened at the Grauman's Chinese Theater. Immediately when the movie started and the title began in eye-popping 3-D fonts with the great sound track, Cissy and I got misty eyed. Now we were seeing this movie as it was meant to be seen and that we had only seen on T.V. sets all of our lives. Seeing it on the large IMAX screen, and in 3-D was an overwhelming experience. You see and hear things you missed all those years on TV. The detail of Glinda's ( The Good Witch's ) costume and many other costumes was amazing. The rust marks on the Tin Man's ( Jack Haley's ) body was very detailed, and later very shinny after their visit to Oz. We also heard several adults explaining to their children some of the story line before the movie started. A new generation was being introduced to the Wizard Of Oz just as if they were at the opening in 1939. I suggest all lovers of The Wizard Of Oz relive this classic again with their children, and grandchildren the way it was meant to be seen on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic movie that brings the imagination of childhood.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gokhan Erguven
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's probably a shame for me to have watched this movie too late, but since it's a classic, I don't feel bad about that. The setting, the costumes, the scene, the music, the effects are so beautiful that you can ignore the movie was shot in 1939. The movie is a classic and it has been referenced in so many movies and TV series that I watched so that it brought me to the point of I must watch it -- and it indeed was worth the watch. Judy Garland, Frank Morgan, Ray Bolger, Bert Lahr, Jack Haley, Billie Burke and all the other cast of the film are so great and talented that you'll be amazed by their performances. I also read a speculation that half the movie was shot colorless, and the other half with color on purpose, but there are other speculations that the movie was began to be shot in 1925 and done in 1939 because of the unavailable color film. Anyways, such a good film with a great imagination. Worth to watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent Work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    swpesto
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wizard of Oz with always be treasured throughout centuries. It is a piece of art. So magical. So beautiful. Judy Garland is so poised as Dorothy even at the young age of 16. The music and dancing are wonderful. Roy Bolger is awesome as "The Scarecrow". Such talent went into the casting of the film. Such special effects for a film almost putting it way before it's time. I feel some of these effects have been carried through with future films that have been made. Each film learns from the other. I will always love "The Wizard of Oz. Looking forward to the recent films that will continue the Oz series. I loved James Franco's portrayal in "Oz the Great and Powerful". Still nothing will come to the magic of the original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i have good review of dorothy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVIDMICHAEL HINES (2angelhines@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i am a film maker at LACC in los angeles californa and we all watch the movies in class and we saw this movie wizard of oz . she is a very good singer and actress .i love the way she does in the film . the most thing i seen was awesome that the tornado took her house up in the air once she woke up she saw the people she knows and she thought oh weired what is happening . as she looked down she jumped back and said omg she rush back to the bed . then she felt the house going back down like hell boom . once she came out she was in another world . she never gone before . as for toto very smart dog she was on her side . filmmaker student at lacc David B.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Follow The Yellow Brick Road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wizard Of Oz (TWOO) is probably one of the most famous Hollywood films of the late-1930s and, maybe, even the early-1940s. As I understand it, when TWOO was first released back in 1939 it really wasn't a colossal hit. It wasn't until the coming of TV when it was first aired in the 1950s that it attracted a humongous fan-base and from there it became one of the most popular films of all-time. Filmed at MGM Studios, TWOO was made at a time when MGM was, without question, the wealthiest, most impressive, and most successful Hollywood studio in the USA. Back in 1939 TWOO was made simply as a showpiece. This was MGM showing the world just how much power they wielded, that they could make an expensive film like this one and not care, one bit, whether it earned them a profit, or not. Little did the MGM big-wigs realize at the time that TWOO would go on to become one of the most beloved Fantasy/Adventure films of all time. So - "Tap your heels together 3 times and repeat after me - There's no place like home. There's no place like home."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Red Brick Road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kclov13
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies! I wore out the video tape a few times. I now own the DVD. Since I was little, I loved the movie. I was Dorothy for Halloween a couple years, I have the board game, and my first tattoo was inspired by this movie. The one thing that I have always questioned is where the Red Brick road goes. It would have been interesting to find out where it went. I hope that my future children will enjoy this movie as much as I did and still do. This movie has held up pretty good over the years, and I hope that it still does. I will continue to watch it and enjoy it as much as I did when I first saw it, (except now I probably know most of the lines to the movie).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll get you my little pretty, and your dog too."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are only two other Movies from Hollywood's Golden Age that have been as influential, deconstructed, analyzed, reconsidered, penetrating, viewed, and reviewed, noticed, and unforgotten as this one. King Kong (1933) and Citizen Kane (1941). Everyone who has seen Oz has an opinion and it is usually a strong one. It undeniably unmasks facades and oozes into the deeper parts of the consciousness worthy of the best Psychoanalysis. On the surface it lures one in with its sentimentality and charms with its catchy and heartfelt tunes. It bombards the senses, like a psychedelic, expanding consciousness through dripping Colors and the most imaginative of imagery. As the mind opens it is vulnerable to scary images as well as the sublime. Reality becomes a focused blur that is experienced profoundly and deeply. It is Art at its most cunningly persuasive. If you "pay no attention to the Man behind the curtain", you will find yourself in a land of Milk and Honey, but if you acknowledge reality for what it is and not what is hoped for, it might become a Truth that is as scary as a Flying Monkey. This Film is a Wonderful way to open the "doors of perception". That is the least and the best that the Movies can offer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lokethecheetah
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Often I am dubious about old movies, especially old sci-fi or "classic" movies. However, this movie was both enchanting and quite humorous for an oldie. The scenery was beautiful and so intricate. I was especially impressed by the lion's tail, flitting about in a life-like manner without the use of modern graphics or technology. The scenery impressed me because of all the time and effort that must have gone into creating it. Though much of the movie was spoiled for me through its fame, I was still amazed even with the scenes I knew were coming. The actors made the movie a delight to watch and the songs were humorous, and sometimes a bit stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Timeless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    meg_elizabeth
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "And you, and you, and you were there." All of Dorothy's friends look at her as if she was crazy, assuring her that her adventure was just a dream. Was it really just a dream? How could it be, when it seemed so real? In Viktor Fleming's, "The Wizard of Oz", dream is made into reality and reality into dream. "The Wizard of Oz" is a classical masterpiece in which breathtaking design, performance and a heart-warming storyline combine to create a movie in its very own category. In Kansas, a twister hits Dorothy's home and she is hit by a window, falling into her dreamland of Oz. We follow Dorothy (Judy Garland) on her quest for the Wizard of Oz, in the land of munchkins, evil and good witches, and many more interesting characters. The Scarecrow (Ray Bolger), Cowardly Lion (Bert Lahr), and Tin Man (Jack Haley) are just some of the friends, with their own problems, that she meets on her way. The story is all about "following the yellow brick road" as "we're off to see the wizard." The screenplay was adapted from Frank T. Baum's story chronicle, The Wizard of Oz. It was produced by Mervyn Leroy and acted out by a first class list of actors. Perhaps the most important factors of this movie are the Technicolor (this is the first movie in color), the songs (that you'll never forget and never get enough of), and the ubiquitous theme/moral of "there's no place like home." The plot is very easy to follow and straightforward. Despite the seemingly unrealistic storyline of wizards, a land of munchkins, flying monkeys, and bad witches flying on broomsticks, viewers can't help but fall into the fantasy of it all and imagine there really is such a place "somewhere over the rainbow." The characters are all believable and you seem able to relate to them and know at least one person in your life like them. People love the Scarecrow, Tin Man, and Cowardly Lion for their loyalty and personal quirks, and loathe the Wicked Witch of the West for being so sinfully evil. The dialogue is also very amusing, with a deeper meaning than most would conceive at first. There are many hidden messages of friendship, loyalty, and seeing what's right in front of you all along. The actors are very convincing as their characters, all seemingly to step right out from the original story. Judy Garland perhaps was the best choice for Dorothy because the viewer just can't help but fall in love and sympathize for her when they see those big brown eyes staring back at them from the screen. She has a raw performance in which you can feel each emotion through her expression. From the moment Dorothy opens her front door after landing in Oz and exclaims "Oh!" the screen is filled with bright and vibrant color, a sharp contrast from the dull black and white from a second before. The significance of this is not lost, as the use of color is artfully done throughout the movie. The Technicolor sets the film apart because it is the first picture to be in color. During the movie the ever present yellow brick road takes the viewer through a journey of colorful and unique places, like the charming Munchkin Land and eerily spooky Haunted Forest. This film is one that's timeless for a good reason. The acting is wonderful as is the set, themes, and dramatic aspects. The "Wizard of Oz" was one of a kind when it first came out and 75 years later it still touches people's hearts. The movie keeps the audience's interest and you walk away from it smiling. After watching the movie, it will give you a deeper respect for what you are and have. As Dorothy says, "There's no place like home," well, there's no movie like the Wizard of Oz.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A review of a movie everybody on the face of the earth saw
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maxfkeller
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the IMAX 3-D re-release 2 days ago and almost everyone at the theater was going to see this movie. I thought the 3D was very good and made me like the movie more. The film starts in black and... I don't need to talk about what happened in the movie, everybody saw it!!!!!! Being honest, I haven't seen the film in 5 years which made me forget a lot of parts of the film. Watching it, I felt like a little kid again. The choreography was good, the acting was very good, the cinematography was okay, the songs were very good. I just feel sad for forgetting the munchkins thanking Dorothy, the witch trying to get the slippers off of Dorothy, the "Lions and tigers and bears" scene, and the lion's if I were king of the forest song. I apologize to anybody reading this. Now you may disagree but The Wizard of Oz is a good film the family can watch during Taco Night. YAY!!!!!!!!! If you try, everyone eating will stop to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Wizard Of Oz 3-D IMAX 2013 - 4 Thumbs Up with Diamonds
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Russell Sanderlin (iMovieCritic@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone knows the story. Our thoughts on 3-D IMAX. Russell & Cissy, the Two Movie Critics rate movies based on Entertainment Value only. Follow and LIKE us at facebook.com/TwoMovieCritics A remake and remaster of the great classic movie in 3-D IMAX with stunning detail. It was an amazing transformation as Cissy and I were taken back in time before we both were born, August 15th, 1939 when The Wizard Of Oz opened at the Grauman's Chinese Theater. Immediately when the movie started and the title began in eye-popping 3-D fonts with the great sound track, Cissy and I got misty eyed. Now we were seeing this movie as it was meant to be seen and that we had only seen on T.V. sets all of our lives. Seeing it on the large IMAX screen, and in 3-D was an overwhelming experience. You see and hear things you missed all those years on TV. The detail of Glinda's ( The Good Witch's ) costume and many other costumes was amazing. The rust marks on the Tin Man's ( Jack Haley's ) body was very detailed, and later very shinny after their visit to Oz. We also heard several adults explaining to their children some of the story line before the movie started. A new generation was being introduced to the Wizard Of Oz just as if they were at the opening in 1939. I suggest all lovers of The Wizard Of Oz relive this classic again with their children, and grandchildren the way it was meant to be seen on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic movie that brings the imagination of childhood.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gokhan Erguven
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's probably a shame for me to have watched this movie too late, but since it's a classic, I don't feel bad about that. The setting, the costumes, the scene, the music, the effects are so beautiful that you can ignore the movie was shot in 1939. The movie is a classic and it has been referenced in so many movies and TV series that I watched so that it brought me to the point of I must watch it -- and it indeed was worth the watch. Judy Garland, Frank Morgan, Ray Bolger, Bert Lahr, Jack Haley, Billie Burke and all the other cast of the film are so great and talented that you'll be amazed by their performances. I also read a speculation that half the movie was shot colorless, and the other half with color on purpose, but there are other speculations that the movie was began to be shot in 1925 and done in 1939 because of the unavailable color film. Anyways, such a good film with a great imagination. Worth to watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent Work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    swpesto
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wizard of Oz with always be treasured throughout centuries. It is a piece of art. So magical. So beautiful. Judy Garland is so poised as Dorothy even at the young age of 16. The music and dancing are wonderful. Roy Bolger is awesome as "The Scarecrow". Such talent went into the casting of the film. Such special effects for a film almost putting it way before it's time. I feel some of these effects have been carried through with future films that have been made. Each film learns from the other. I will always love "The Wizard of Oz. Looking forward to the recent films that will continue the Oz series. I loved James Franco's portrayal in "Oz the Great and Powerful". Still nothing will come to the magic of the original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i have good review of dorothy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVIDMICHAEL HINES (2angelhines@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i am a film maker at LACC in los angeles californa and we all watch the movies in class and we saw this movie wizard of oz . she is a very good singer and actress .i love the way she does in the film . the most thing i seen was awesome that the tornado took her house up in the air once she woke up she saw the people she knows and she thought oh weired what is happening . as she looked down she jumped back and said omg she rush back to the bed . then she felt the house going back down like hell boom . once she came out she was in another world . she never gone before . as for toto very smart dog she was on her side . filmmaker student at lacc David B.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Follow The Yellow Brick Road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wizard Of Oz (TWOO) is probably one of the most famous Hollywood films of the late-1930s and, maybe, even the early-1940s. As I understand it, when TWOO was first released back in 1939 it really wasn't a colossal hit. It wasn't until the coming of TV when it was first aired in the 1950s that it attracted a humongous fan-base and from there it became one of the most popular films of all-time. Filmed at MGM Studios, TWOO was made at a time when MGM was, without question, the wealthiest, most impressive, and most successful Hollywood studio in the USA. Back in 1939 TWOO was made simply as a showpiece. This was MGM showing the world just how much power they wielded, that they could make an expensive film like this one and not care, one bit, whether it earned them a profit, or not. Little did the MGM big-wigs realize at the time that TWOO would go on to become one of the most beloved Fantasy/Adventure films of all time. So - "Tap your heels together 3 times and repeat after me - There's no place like home. There's no place like home."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Red Brick Road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kclov13
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies! I wore out the video tape a few times. I now own the DVD. Since I was little, I loved the movie. I was Dorothy for Halloween a couple years, I have the board game, and my first tattoo was inspired by this movie. The one thing that I have always questioned is where the Red Brick road goes. It would have been interesting to find out where it went. I hope that my future children will enjoy this movie as much as I did and still do. This movie has held up pretty good over the years, and I hope that it still does. I will continue to watch it and enjoy it as much as I did when I first saw it, (except now I probably know most of the lines to the movie).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll get you my little pretty, and your dog too."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are only two other Movies from Hollywood's Golden Age that have been as influential, deconstructed, analyzed, reconsidered, penetrating, viewed, and reviewed, noticed, and unforgotten as this one. King Kong (1933) and Citizen Kane (1941). Everyone who has seen Oz has an opinion and it is usually a strong one. It undeniably unmasks facades and oozes into the deeper parts of the consciousness worthy of the best Psychoanalysis. On the surface it lures one in with its sentimentality and charms with its catchy and heartfelt tunes. It bombards the senses, like a psychedelic, expanding consciousness through dripping Colors and the most imaginative of imagery. As the mind opens it is vulnerable to scary images as well as the sublime. Reality becomes a focused blur that is experienced profoundly and deeply. It is Art at its most cunningly persuasive. If you "pay no attention to the Man behind the curtain", you will find yourself in a land of Milk and Honey, but if you acknowledge reality for what it is and not what is hoped for, it might become a Truth that is as scary as a Flying Monkey. This Film is a Wonderful way to open the "doors of perception". That is the least and the best that the Movies can offer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lokethecheetah
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Often I am dubious about old movies, especially old sci-fi or "classic" movies. However, this movie was both enchanting and quite humorous for an oldie. The scenery was beautiful and so intricate. I was especially impressed by the lion's tail, flitting about in a life-like manner without the use of modern graphics or technology. The scenery impressed me because of all the time and effort that must have gone into creating it. Though much of the movie was spoiled for me through its fame, I was still amazed even with the scenes I knew were coming. The actors made the movie a delight to watch and the songs were humorous, and sometimes a bit stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Timeless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    meg_elizabeth
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "And you, and you, and you were there." All of Dorothy's friends look at her as if she was crazy, assuring her that her adventure was just a dream. Was it really just a dream? How could it be, when it seemed so real? In Viktor Fleming's, "The Wizard of Oz", dream is made into reality and reality into dream. "The Wizard of Oz" is a classical masterpiece in which breathtaking design, performance and a heart-warming storyline combine to create a movie in its very own category. In Kansas, a twister hits Dorothy's home and she is hit by a window, falling into her dreamland of Oz. We follow Dorothy (Judy Garland) on her quest for the Wizard of Oz, in the land of munchkins, evil and good witches, and many more interesting characters. The Scarecrow (Ray Bolger), Cowardly Lion (Bert Lahr), and Tin Man (Jack Haley) are just some of the friends, with their own problems, that she meets on her way. The story is all about "following the yellow brick road" as "we're off to see the wizard." The screenplay was adapted from Frank T. Baum's story chronicle, The Wizard of Oz. It was produced by Mervyn Leroy and acted out by a first class list of actors. Perhaps the most important factors of this movie are the Technicolor (this is the first movie in color), the songs (that you'll never forget and never get enough of), and the ubiquitous theme/moral of "there's no place like home." The plot is very easy to follow and straightforward. Despite the seemingly unrealistic storyline of wizards, a land of munchkins, flying monkeys, and bad witches flying on broomsticks, viewers can't help but fall into the fantasy of it all and imagine there really is such a place "somewhere over the rainbow." The characters are all believable and you seem able to relate to them and know at least one person in your life like them. People love the Scarecrow, Tin Man, and Cowardly Lion for their loyalty and personal quirks, and loathe the Wicked Witch of the West for being so sinfully evil. The dialogue is also very amusing, with a deeper meaning than most would conceive at first. There are many hidden messages of friendship, loyalty, and seeing what's right in front of you all along. The actors are very convincing as their characters, all seemingly to step right out from the original story. Judy Garland perhaps was the best choice for Dorothy because the viewer just can't help but fall in love and sympathize for her when they see those big brown eyes staring back at them from the screen. She has a raw performance in which you can feel each emotion through her expression. From the moment Dorothy opens her front door after landing in Oz and exclaims "Oh!" the screen is filled with bright and vibrant color, a sharp contrast from the dull black and white from a second before. The significance of this is not lost, as the use of color is artfully done throughout the movie. The Technicolor sets the film apart because it is the first picture to be in color. During the movie the ever present yellow brick road takes the viewer through a journey of colorful and unique places, like the charming Munchkin Land and eerily spooky Haunted Forest. This film is one that's timeless for a good reason. The acting is wonderful as is the set, themes, and dramatic aspects. The "Wizard of Oz" was one of a kind when it first came out and 75 years later it still touches people's hearts. The movie keeps the audience's interest and you walk away from it smiling. After watching the movie, it will give you a deeper respect for what you are and have. As Dorothy says, "There's no place like home," well, there's no movie like the Wizard of Oz.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A review of a movie everybody on the face of the earth saw
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maxfkeller
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the IMAX 3-D re-release 2 days ago and almost everyone at the theater was going to see this movie. I thought the 3D was very good and made me like the movie more. The film starts in black and... I don't need to talk about what happened in the movie, everybody saw it!!!!!! Being honest, I haven't seen the film in 5 years which made me forget a lot of parts of the film. Watching it, I felt like a little kid again. The choreography was good, the acting was very good, the cinematography was okay, the songs were very good. I just feel sad for forgetting the munchkins thanking Dorothy, the witch trying to get the slippers off of Dorothy, the "Lions and tigers and bears" scene, and the lion's if I were king of the forest song. I apologize to anybody reading this. Now you may disagree but The Wizard of Oz is a good film the family can watch during Taco Night. YAY!!!!!!!!! If you try, everyone eating will stop to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Wizard Of Oz 3-D IMAX 2013 - 4 Thumbs Up with Diamonds
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Russell Sanderlin (iMovieCritic@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone knows the story. Our thoughts on 3-D IMAX. Russell & Cissy, the Two Movie Critics rate movies based on Entertainment Value only. Follow and LIKE us at facebook.com/TwoMovieCritics A remake and remaster of the great classic movie in 3-D IMAX with stunning detail. It was an amazing transformation as Cissy and I were taken back in time before we both were born, August 15th, 1939 when The Wizard Of Oz opened at the Grauman's Chinese Theater. Immediately when the movie started and the title began in eye-popping 3-D fonts with the great sound track, Cissy and I got misty eyed. Now we were seeing this movie as it was meant to be seen and that we had only seen on T.V. sets all of our lives. Seeing it on the large IMAX screen, and in 3-D was an overwhelming experience. You see and hear things you missed all those years on TV. The detail of Glinda's ( The Good Witch's ) costume and many other costumes was amazing. The rust marks on the Tin Man's ( Jack Haley's ) body was very detailed, and later very shinny after their visit to Oz. We also heard several adults explaining to their children some of the story line before the movie started. A new generation was being introduced to the Wizard Of Oz just as if they were at the opening in 1939. I suggest all lovers of The Wizard Of Oz relive this classic again with their children, and grandchildren the way it was meant to be seen on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic movie that brings the imagination of childhood.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gokhan Erguven
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's probably a shame for me to have watched this movie too late, but since it's a classic, I don't feel bad about that. The setting, the costumes, the scene, the music, the effects are so beautiful that you can ignore the movie was shot in 1939. The movie is a classic and it has been referenced in so many movies and TV series that I watched so that it brought me to the point of I must watch it -- and it indeed was worth the watch. Judy Garland, Frank Morgan, Ray Bolger, Bert Lahr, Jack Haley, Billie Burke and all the other cast of the film are so great and talented that you'll be amazed by their performances. I also read a speculation that half the movie was shot colorless, and the other half with color on purpose, but there are other speculations that the movie was began to be shot in 1925 and done in 1939 because of the unavailable color film. Anyways, such a good film with a great imagination. Worth to watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent Work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    swpesto
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wizard of Oz with always be treasured throughout centuries. It is a piece of art. So magical. So beautiful. Judy Garland is so poised as Dorothy even at the young age of 16. The music and dancing are wonderful. Roy Bolger is awesome as "The Scarecrow". Such talent went into the casting of the film. Such special effects for a film almost putting it way before it's time. I feel some of these effects have been carried through with future films that have been made. Each film learns from the other. I will always love "The Wizard of Oz. Looking forward to the recent films that will continue the Oz series. I loved James Franco's portrayal in "Oz the Great and Powerful". Still nothing will come to the magic of the original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i have good review of dorothy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVIDMICHAEL HINES (2angelhines@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i am a film maker at LACC in los angeles californa and we all watch the movies in class and we saw this movie wizard of oz . she is a very good singer and actress .i love the way she does in the film . the most thing i seen was awesome that the tornado took her house up in the air once she woke up she saw the people she knows and she thought oh weired what is happening . as she looked down she jumped back and said omg she rush back to the bed . then she felt the house going back down like hell boom . once she came out she was in another world . she never gone before . as for toto very smart dog she was on her side . filmmaker student at lacc David B.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Follow The Yellow Brick Road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wizard Of Oz (TWOO) is probably one of the most famous Hollywood films of the late-1930s and, maybe, even the early-1940s. As I understand it, when TWOO was first released back in 1939 it really wasn't a colossal hit. It wasn't until the coming of TV when it was first aired in the 1950s that it attracted a humongous fan-base and from there it became one of the most popular films of all-time. Filmed at MGM Studios, TWOO was made at a time when MGM was, without question, the wealthiest, most impressive, and most successful Hollywood studio in the USA. Back in 1939 TWOO was made simply as a showpiece. This was MGM showing the world just how much power they wielded, that they could make an expensive film like this one and not care, one bit, whether it earned them a profit, or not. Little did the MGM big-wigs realize at the time that TWOO would go on to become one of the most beloved Fantasy/Adventure films of all time. So - "Tap your heels together 3 times and repeat after me - There's no place like home. There's no place like home."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Red Brick Road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kclov13
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies! I wore out the video tape a few times. I now own the DVD. Since I was little, I loved the movie. I was Dorothy for Halloween a couple years, I have the board game, and my first tattoo was inspired by this movie. The one thing that I have always questioned is where the Red Brick road goes. It would have been interesting to find out where it went. I hope that my future children will enjoy this movie as much as I did and still do. This movie has held up pretty good over the years, and I hope that it still does. I will continue to watch it and enjoy it as much as I did when I first saw it, (except now I probably know most of the lines to the movie).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll get you my little pretty, and your dog too."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are only two other Movies from Hollywood's Golden Age that have been as influential, deconstructed, analyzed, reconsidered, penetrating, viewed, and reviewed, noticed, and unforgotten as this one. King Kong (1933) and Citizen Kane (1941). Everyone who has seen Oz has an opinion and it is usually a strong one. It undeniably unmasks facades and oozes into the deeper parts of the consciousness worthy of the best Psychoanalysis. On the surface it lures one in with its sentimentality and charms with its catchy and heartfelt tunes. It bombards the senses, like a psychedelic, expanding consciousness through dripping Colors and the most imaginative of imagery. As the mind opens it is vulnerable to scary images as well as the sublime. Reality becomes a focused blur that is experienced profoundly and deeply. It is Art at its most cunningly persuasive. If you "pay no attention to the Man behind the curtain", you will find yourself in a land of Milk and Honey, but if you acknowledge reality for what it is and not what is hoped for, it might become a Truth that is as scary as a Flying Monkey. This Film is a Wonderful way to open the "doors of perception". That is the least and the best that the Movies can offer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lokethecheetah
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Often I am dubious about old movies, especially old sci-fi or "classic" movies. However, this movie was both enchanting and quite humorous for an oldie. The scenery was beautiful and so intricate. I was especially impressed by the lion's tail, flitting about in a life-like manner without the use of modern graphics or technology. The scenery impressed me because of all the time and effort that must have gone into creating it. Though much of the movie was spoiled for me through its fame, I was still amazed even with the scenes I knew were coming. The actors made the movie a delight to watch and the songs were humorous, and sometimes a bit stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Timeless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    meg_elizabeth
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "And you, and you, and you were there." All of Dorothy's friends look at her as if she was crazy, assuring her that her adventure was just a dream. Was it really just a dream? How could it be, when it seemed so real? In Viktor Fleming's, "The Wizard of Oz", dream is made into reality and reality into dream. "The Wizard of Oz" is a classical masterpiece in which breathtaking design, performance and a heart-warming storyline combine to create a movie in its very own category. In Kansas, a twister hits Dorothy's home and she is hit by a window, falling into her dreamland of Oz. We follow Dorothy (Judy Garland) on her quest for the Wizard of Oz, in the land of munchkins, evil and good witches, and many more interesting characters. The Scarecrow (Ray Bolger), Cowardly Lion (Bert Lahr), and Tin Man (Jack Haley) are just some of the friends, with their own problems, that she meets on her way. The story is all about "following the yellow brick road" as "we're off to see the wizard." The screenplay was adapted from Frank T. Baum's story chronicle, The Wizard of Oz. It was produced by Mervyn Leroy and acted out by a first class list of actors. Perhaps the most important factors of this movie are the Technicolor (this is the first movie in color), the songs (that you'll never forget and never get enough of), and the ubiquitous theme/moral of "there's no place like home." The plot is very easy to follow and straightforward. Despite the seemingly unrealistic storyline of wizards, a land of munchkins, flying monkeys, and bad witches flying on broomsticks, viewers can't help but fall into the fantasy of it all and imagine there really is such a place "somewhere over the rainbow." The characters are all believable and you seem able to relate to them and know at least one person in your life like them. People love the Scarecrow, Tin Man, and Cowardly Lion for their loyalty and personal quirks, and loathe the Wicked Witch of the West for being so sinfully evil. The dialogue is also very amusing, with a deeper meaning than most would conceive at first. There are many hidden messages of friendship, loyalty, and seeing what's right in front of you all along. The actors are very convincing as their characters, all seemingly to step right out from the original story. Judy Garland perhaps was the best choice for Dorothy because the viewer just can't help but fall in love and sympathize for her when they see those big brown eyes staring back at them from the screen. She has a raw performance in which you can feel each emotion through her expression. From the moment Dorothy opens her front door after landing in Oz and exclaims "Oh!" the screen is filled with bright and vibrant color, a sharp contrast from the dull black and white from a second before. The significance of this is not lost, as the use of color is artfully done throughout the movie. The Technicolor sets the film apart because it is the first picture to be in color. During the movie the ever present yellow brick road takes the viewer through a journey of colorful and unique places, like the charming Munchkin Land and eerily spooky Haunted Forest. This film is one that's timeless for a good reason. The acting is wonderful as is the set, themes, and dramatic aspects. The "Wizard of Oz" was one of a kind when it first came out and 75 years later it still touches people's hearts. The movie keeps the audience's interest and you walk away from it smiling. After watching the movie, it will give you a deeper respect for what you are and have. As Dorothy says, "There's no place like home," well, there's no movie like the Wizard of Oz.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A review of a movie everybody on the face of the earth saw
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maxfkeller
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the IMAX 3-D re-release 2 days ago and almost everyone at the theater was going to see this movie. I thought the 3D was very good and made me like the movie more. The film starts in black and... I don't need to talk about what happened in the movie, everybody saw it!!!!!! Being honest, I haven't seen the film in 5 years which made me forget a lot of parts of the film. Watching it, I felt like a little kid again. The choreography was good, the acting was very good, the cinematography was okay, the songs were very good. I just feel sad for forgetting the munchkins thanking Dorothy, the witch trying to get the slippers off of Dorothy, the "Lions and tigers and bears" scene, and the lion's if I were king of the forest song. I apologize to anybody reading this. Now you may disagree but The Wizard of Oz is a good film the family can watch during Taco Night. YAY!!!!!!!!! If you try, everyone eating will stop to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Wizard Of Oz 3-D IMAX 2013 - 4 Thumbs Up with Diamonds
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Russell Sanderlin (iMovieCritic@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone knows the story. Our thoughts on 3-D IMAX. Russell & Cissy, the Two Movie Critics rate movies based on Entertainment Value only. Follow and LIKE us at facebook.com/TwoMovieCritics A remake and remaster of the great classic movie in 3-D IMAX with stunning detail. It was an amazing transformation as Cissy and I were taken back in time before we both were born, August 15th, 1939 when The Wizard Of Oz opened at the Grauman's Chinese Theater. Immediately when the movie started and the title began in eye-popping 3-D fonts with the great sound track, Cissy and I got misty eyed. Now we were seeing this movie as it was meant to be seen and that we had only seen on T.V. sets all of our lives. Seeing it on the large IMAX screen, and in 3-D was an overwhelming experience. You see and hear things you missed all those years on TV. The detail of Glinda's ( The Good Witch's ) costume and many other costumes was amazing. The rust marks on the Tin Man's ( Jack Haley's ) body was very detailed, and later very shinny after their visit to Oz. We also heard several adults explaining to their children some of the story line before the movie started. A new generation was being introduced to the Wizard Of Oz just as if they were at the opening in 1939. I suggest all lovers of The Wizard Of Oz relive this classic again with their children, and grandchildren the way it was meant to be seen on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic movie that brings the imagination of childhood.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gokhan Erguven
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's probably a shame for me to have watched this movie too late, but since it's a classic, I don't feel bad about that. The setting, the costumes, the scene, the music, the effects are so beautiful that you can ignore the movie was shot in 1939. The movie is a classic and it has been referenced in so many movies and TV series that I watched so that it brought me to the point of I must watch it -- and it indeed was worth the watch. Judy Garland, Frank Morgan, Ray Bolger, Bert Lahr, Jack Haley, Billie Burke and all the other cast of the film are so great and talented that you'll be amazed by their performances. I also read a speculation that half the movie was shot colorless, and the other half with color on purpose, but there are other speculations that the movie was began to be shot in 1925 and done in 1939 because of the unavailable color film. Anyways, such a good film with a great imagination. Worth to watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent Work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    swpesto
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wizard of Oz with always be treasured throughout centuries. It is a piece of art. So magical. So beautiful. Judy Garland is so poised as Dorothy even at the young age of 16. The music and dancing are wonderful. Roy Bolger is awesome as "The Scarecrow". Such talent went into the casting of the film. Such special effects for a film almost putting it way before it's time. I feel some of these effects have been carried through with future films that have been made. Each film learns from the other. I will always love "The Wizard of Oz. Looking forward to the recent films that will continue the Oz series. I loved James Franco's portrayal in "Oz the Great and Powerful". Still nothing will come to the magic of the original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i have good review of dorothy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVIDMICHAEL HINES (2angelhines@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i am a film maker at LACC in los angeles californa and we all watch the movies in class and we saw this movie wizard of oz . she is a very good singer and actress .i love the way she does in the film . the most thing i seen was awesome that the tornado took her house up in the air once she woke up she saw the people she knows and she thought oh weired what is happening . as she looked down she jumped back and said omg she rush back to the bed . then she felt the house going back down like hell boom . once she came out she was in another world . she never gone before . as for toto very smart dog she was on her side . filmmaker student at lacc David B.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Follow The Yellow Brick Road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wizard Of Oz (TWOO) is probably one of the most famous Hollywood films of the late-1930s and, maybe, even the early-1940s. As I understand it, when TWOO was first released back in 1939 it really wasn't a colossal hit. It wasn't until the coming of TV when it was first aired in the 1950s that it attracted a humongous fan-base and from there it became one of the most popular films of all-time. Filmed at MGM Studios, TWOO was made at a time when MGM was, without question, the wealthiest, most impressive, and most successful Hollywood studio in the USA. Back in 1939 TWOO was made simply as a showpiece. This was MGM showing the world just how much power they wielded, that they could make an expensive film like this one and not care, one bit, whether it earned them a profit, or not. Little did the MGM big-wigs realize at the time that TWOO would go on to become one of the most beloved Fantasy/Adventure films of all time. So - "Tap your heels together 3 times and repeat after me - There's no place like home. There's no place like home."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Red Brick Road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kclov13
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies! I wore out the video tape a few times. I now own the DVD. Since I was little, I loved the movie. I was Dorothy for Halloween a couple years, I have the board game, and my first tattoo was inspired by this movie. The one thing that I have always questioned is where the Red Brick road goes. It would have been interesting to find out where it went. I hope that my future children will enjoy this movie as much as I did and still do. This movie has held up pretty good over the years, and I hope that it still does. I will continue to watch it and enjoy it as much as I did when I first saw it, (except now I probably know most of the lines to the movie).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll get you my little pretty, and your dog too."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are only two other Movies from Hollywood's Golden Age that have been as influential, deconstructed, analyzed, reconsidered, penetrating, viewed, and reviewed, noticed, and unforgotten as this one. King Kong (1933) and Citizen Kane (1941). Everyone who has seen Oz has an opinion and it is usually a strong one. It undeniably unmasks facades and oozes into the deeper parts of the consciousness worthy of the best Psychoanalysis. On the surface it lures one in with its sentimentality and charms with its catchy and heartfelt tunes. It bombards the senses, like a psychedelic, expanding consciousness through dripping Colors and the most imaginative of imagery. As the mind opens it is vulnerable to scary images as well as the sublime. Reality becomes a focused blur that is experienced profoundly and deeply. It is Art at its most cunningly persuasive. If you "pay no attention to the Man behind the curtain", you will find yourself in a land of Milk and Honey, but if you acknowledge reality for what it is and not what is hoped for, it might become a Truth that is as scary as a Flying Monkey. This Film is a Wonderful way to open the "doors of perception". That is the least and the best that the Movies can offer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lokethecheetah
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Often I am dubious about old movies, especially old sci-fi or "classic" movies. However, this movie was both enchanting and quite humorous for an oldie. The scenery was beautiful and so intricate. I was especially impressed by the lion's tail, flitting about in a life-like manner without the use of modern graphics or technology. The scenery impressed me because of all the time and effort that must have gone into creating it. Though much of the movie was spoiled for me through its fame, I was still amazed even with the scenes I knew were coming. The actors made the movie a delight to watch and the songs were humorous, and sometimes a bit stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
