<filme>
 <id>
  1320
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0113319
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Homage
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   witness
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   gardener
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   female nudity
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   fatal attraction
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   tragic event
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Ross Kagan Marks
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Mark Medoff
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Blythe Danner
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Frank Whaley
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Sheryl Lee
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who is responsible?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stephanie
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a disturbing movie that left my thoughts spinning through the credits, and far beyond. Documentary-interview style, it delves into a disturbed young man's life and his obsession with an actress and her mother. His desperate need for attention isolates him to the point of obsession. As he spins out of control, it asks important questions that I, for one, have never really pondered. Who is responsible when we live our lives oblivious to those around us? Who is responsible when we go another day without telling our loved ones that they matter, and we need them? And, more importantly, who is responsible when we let strangers' needs go unfulfilled? It's not too late to reach out and let someone know you love them.. Who really is to blame for the isolated, who never have the security of feeling loved and wanted - Are the resulting tailspins from our lack of action? Who can we blame for their final desperate actions? This is a serious, well acted film. Not particularly light entertainment, but extremely thought provoking - whether you are ready to ponder the disturbing conclusions... or not.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unibomber handyman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    batzi8m1
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/1999
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What do you get when a math genius psycho hangs out on a widow's ranch as a handyman just as the movie star daughter comes home to get away from being an image worship and just be a daughter? A chilling insightful movie about people either trying to find themselves or run away into fantasy. Fans of the latter will hate this movie, while those who like self examination and introspection might find it both rewarding and, at moments, amusing when the characters make a genuine offhand comment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
