<filme>
 <id>
  1333
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0111180
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Sibak
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Three young and good-looking brothers live with and support their parents in Manila; they dance at the male Club Exotica and work as "call boys." Joel has a wife and child; he and Dennis ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Three young and good-looking brothers live with and support their parents in Manila; they dance at the male Club Exotica and work as "call boys." Joel has a wife and child; he and Dennis are saving money to buy back lost family land. Sonny has dropped out of university and sees dancing as a way to make money for now. Joel has a regular boyfriend as well; Sonny spends time with Michelle, a transvestite; Dennis and his pals steal car radios. When their nanay takes in a homeless youth who is not what he appears to be, a chain of events is set in motion that brings tragedy. Is there any salvation in this late-night world of "macho dancing" and prostitution?
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   money
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   dancing
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   dance
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   university
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   transvestite
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Mel Chionglo
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Ricardo Lee
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Alex Del Rosario
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Gandong Cervantes
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Lawrence David
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A portrayal of family struggling in poverty, and has forced the 3 boys into prostitution particularly in the gay world.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jvn8080
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every bit of "Midnight Dancers" (Sibak) was fantastic !!! This is truly a work of Art. This could be one of the best Filipino films made ever. Very Phenomenal ! ! ! Mel Chionglo was outstanding in making this film, together with the entire cast and crew. From beginning to end, the film was captivating ! Every single one in the cast did his/her part so well ! Perla Bautista (Mila,the mother of the 3 brothers) being a veteran of Filipino movies was exceptionally excellent, just as in all her other films, and so is TV/Movie Commedienne Soxy Topacio (Dominic, the manager of the gay bar). There is only one single thing missing in the film- and that is A List of the entire cast and the Roles they portrayed. Example, who played the role of Dennis (Raffy)? I don't know if this is Alex Del Rosario or Gandong Cervantes, etc. I hope that list could be uploaded for others to know who portrayed who.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    More than merely a gay movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hunky Stud
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    All the three brothers work at the same gay bar. That is not so hard to believe. But all of them have homosexual lovers. one of the brother loves a transexual, one who is married with a kid also loves another man. That is very so unlikely by statistics. However, other than that slight problem, this movie is very touching. The homosexual element is not really the main focus.It depicts a general working class family's daily life. > There are not many movies that portray working families. So it is a movie well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
