<filme>
 <id>
  1336
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116756
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Kazaam
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  2.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Being a lone young boy in the 'hood" is dangerous and unpleasant. This is what Max experiences when he fools a gang of local toughs who cornered him at school. The gang finds out that the ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Being a lone young boy in the 'hood" is dangerous and unpleasant. This is what Max experiences when he fools a gang of local toughs who cornered him at school. The gang finds out that the key he gave them is of no value in committing a robbery, and they chase him through the streets of his neighborhood, bent on revenge. He tries to escape by slipping into the open door of an old warehouse, but they follow him there, too. While running from them through aisles filled with all kinds of stuff, he bumps into an old boom box. By doing that, he manages to release Kazaam, a genie who has been held captive for thousands of years. In order to stay free, Kazaam must give Max three wishes.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   key
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   chase
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   boom box
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   genie
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   warehouse
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Paul Michael Glaser
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Paul Michael Glaser
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Christian Ford
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Shaquille O'Neal
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Francis Capra
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ally Walker
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you watch this, expect a strong feeling of loss and regret
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brianmckann
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie deserves no rating, and it's not for the reasons you'd think. It is a complete failure, but mostly because it got past common sense, Hollywood budgets, and directing standards. All because I believe Shaq threw enormous piles of money at it, and no one wanted to tell him this was the worst possible movie idea. Also take note that Shaq raises his eyebrows every other word he speaks. Some moments are only mildly painful, while others are clench your teeth, eye-squinting travesties. Most notably, the rap battle between the boy and Shaq, where they repeat "We ain't men, we genie." * Scowling at a piece of toast. * A boom box that shoots a shower of sparks * A grown man showering in front of a child * A rapping genie, that despite boasting his lyrical skills, always starts every rhyme with "I am Kazaam" * More than an hour of your life wasted These are what you have to look forward to in watching this. I'm troubled that anyone thought this would make money, or legitimize Shaq's rapping career in the minds of children. If you have a choice between sitting in gridlock traffic for 9 hours, 10 straight hours of oral surgery or watching Kazaam, Kazaam wins by a slight margin. There's no more positive endorsement I can give.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is One Genie You Don't Want Three Wishes From
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony-rigoni
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We're all familiar with genies in Middle Eastern mythologies. They could be in lamps like Aladdin or in bottles like I Dream of Jeannie. But never, and I repeat never, have I heard of genies coming out of boom boxes! Shaq O'Neil maybe a famous basketball player, but he's such a crappy actor! There are a lot of issues that should have been easily fixed in the first place. First, the acting. Is it me or did everybody woke up in the middle of the afternoon and decided to say "Huh, whatever. Not my movie, I'm not going to act today." Second, the songs. And yes, Shaq O'Neil raps his brains out. But his rapping and the songs are so bland, I keep thinking that the songs were written by the same people who created Bebe's Kids and Tom and Jerry the Movie. Third, the humor. What is the intended age to make stupid jokes like that, ages Born-11 months?! This is probably the same age range intended for Babygeniuses and Titanic: The Legend Goes On! And now, here's my rap for this movie: This piece of crap is oh so bad, it makes me positively mad! It makes me shout and swear and scream, I'd throw this movie down a stream. It's Stupid and Crappy, Tacky and Sappy, Horrendous and Hideous Despicable and Tedious! Don't watch this movie, it'll get you rabies and the humor is intended for babies! Kazaam's a sham and Shaq O'Neil is full of ham! Kazaam is bad and this movie makes me really mad! And it stinks a lot like doggy poo, I might as well be playing Shaq Fu! (PS, that video game sucks too) Enough Said.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An example of why Shag should go back to basketball
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never heard of this film before, but after looking at the Nostalgia Critic review of this abomination, I did see this movie and I permanently despise it, but it's not the worst movie ever made. There are two enjoyable scenes in this movie which includes the bike race sequence and the flying french toasts. However, those two scenes didn't exactly make this film worth watching. The special effects are quite substandard, the script is too childish and very simple, and the story is pretty predictable. The acting is the worst aspect of this film, especially Shag's acting (even his rapping is much worse) and the child actor is so annoying it would make you want to slap him in the face. Overall, not the worst compared to Batman and Robin, Garbage Pail Kids, and Battlefield Earth, but still a horrible movie that needs to be avoided. Rating: 2/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The 90's were not funny, they were stupid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Twetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just started watching my way through IMBDs bottom 100 and this definitely belongs there, I'm pretty sure it deserves to be higher up than number 99 too. I've seen a video review of this so I kind of knew what to expect but it turned out to be so much worse. The other two films from the list that I've seen so far were immensely boring because nothing ever happened in them. This one at least had some action in it but every single thing that happened was just stupid. Now, I can enjoy stupid movies; films that are so bad they become funny, this one though was painfully unfunny. On top of that, the film is in the mid 90's and the film makers make that abundantly clear with the way people dress and above all the horrible hip hop music playing throughout the film. It reminds me of all the bad things about the 90's and none of the good ones. By far the worst thing though is Kazaam himself who, despite being thousands of years old is hip, but not in a good way, and goes around rhyming every sentence he utters like some kind of idiotic hip hop artist. That Shaq can't rap doesn't exactly make it any better. This whole thing feels like a bad 90's music video - starring an untalented rapper - drawn out to a full length feature.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect example of a movie that I loved as a child, hate as an adult...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, adolescent really(19). Like Howard the Duck, Kazaam was a movie I loved as a child but looking back on it I was shocked at how low my taste buds were as a kid. Granted, there are some funny moments specifically the ones with the flying toasts and the bicycle race. And it is not the worst movie of 1996, Ed and especially Bio Dome are worse. However, the special effects are really quite substandard, and the rest of the production values are of direct to video quality and shoddy ones at that. The story is predictable with only a few worthwhile scenes to favour, the sight gags suffer from poor comic timing and the script is childish and simplistic. The characters I really dislike here, the kid is annoying, the villain is one of the lamest I have seen in a long time while Shaquille O'Neal's Genie with his awful rapping(then again I dislike rap intensely, and that is the least problematic of his performance) grated on me fast. The acting doesn't fare much better either, while the direction is literally non-existent and the soundtrack is only tolerable if on mute. This is of course my opinion, disagree all you want, I guess I just didn't like it. 2/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Lamps Should Be Permanently Sealed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yankcrime15
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This isn't as much of a film as it is a giant promotional campaign by Touchstone Pictures to market the NBA's worst free thrower with his extraordinary height. Not only is this obviously forever trapped in a time capsule set to 1996, but everything in this film is done so bad that it's completely laughable. If I had a handful of cardboard cutouts, they would be far more dimensional than any of the people that acted in this film. It's obvious that Shaq not only fails at free throws, rapping and being a video game character, but his acting is absolutely dreadful. He's a "rapping" (actually a RHYMING) genie that moved into a boombox and is summoned when a boy named Max (played by a young Francis Capra) stumbles upon him after being chased by bullies. Throughout the movie, Shaq becomes a subject of slavery as Max owns him until his three wishes are granted. That's pretty much the whole plot, unless you're actually going to include a meaningless subplot about "finding the true father". It doesn't get any better from there. Shaq demonstrates his mad rapping skills by appearing at a night club where he becomes a selected guest. Guess how fast Theodor Geisel was spinning in his grave when he brought forth the detestable line of "Let's green egg and ham it!" Probably around the same speed that would also be brought forth by those two live action adaptations that shall not be named. Then there's some phenomenal acting. I'm talking about the magical french toast. That performance was far more convincing than anything you could expect Shaq to give us. Too bad this film killed its career. Speaking of career killers, ever noticed what happened to Paul Michael Glaser after he directed this film? It's a long story. Granted, it's not one of THE worst things I have ever seen, but it's very close. Kazaam is proof that pitching a non actor as a main character usually does not give satisfactory results. With all this time wasted in the production of this film, I bet Shaq could have gotten some more practice at free throws. The most shocking thing about this? Shaq actually got ANOTHER lead role a year later, but that's a whole different story subject.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why would someone make a film with Shaq as a Genie?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Criticman12
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boy, this is one of the worst films I've seen. No wonder it's on IMDb's Bottom 100 list. I'll start off with the good parts: It did have some funny moments like the scene with the flying french toasts and the scene where Max and Kazaam are having a bicycle race. The bad parts: Everything else in this movie was boring and bad. Shaq as a genie is just plain awful. Beside's he can't even rap. In one scene, he's singing, "Let's Green Eggs and Ham it". Seriously? That's kinda like a 5-year old doing a rap song. The other character's weren't even that good. Max is annoying. The villain is not even that evil. Literally. Also, wasn't this suppose to be a family film? In one scene, Max say's, "So after my 2 last wishes, I own you?", then Kazaam say's, "Technically". Is it me, or is this film about slavery? Overall, "Kazaam", is an awful movie that's not even worth watching. But compare it to, "Batman and Robin", "Son of the Mask", or "Battlefield Earth", it's not that bad. So if you're looking for a good movie with a Genie in it, watch the Disney movie, "Aladdin". That film has a Genie that can sing and make you laugh. He is also voiced by Robin Williams. A "GOOD" actor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All hail Shaq.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gabrielle Phillips
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie Kazaam featuring the multi-talented Shaquille O'Neal should be the standard which all movies are held to. Since originally viewing this wonderful work of cinema 15 years ago, I can say it has definitely held up to the test of time. I've yet to see a movie that even comes close to achieving the depth of character, raw emotion, and beauty that Kazaam portrays. Shaq is definitely a triple threat -- basketball, acting, and singing, what's next!? I can't wait to see more from this truly awe-inspiring man. This film has definitely slid under the radar of Hollywood critics, which I see as a blessing. I'd hate for this movie to get wildly popular and lose its innocence. Once I have children of my own, this will be one of the few movies I allow them to watch since it preaches such good morals & values. If you're debating whether to watch this film or not -- DO IT! Your life will never be the same in the best way possible.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you see this film..... You're as stupid as me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheNewCritic
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So I'm aware that this film was released a fair while ago, but I've only just seen it; and not out of free will. I can some up this film in 1 word.... Shaq, the only "actor" who is more robotic than the Terminator. And really thats all that needs to be said, it's a stupid stupid movie that barely makes any sense, it's so uninteresting that I could feel myself getting stupider as I watched. If you see a copy of this film DESTROY IT, and then maybe one day the world will be ridden of this raping of cinema known as Kazaam 1/10 (and the only reason it scored that high is that i'm not allowed to give it a zero)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    People who hate on this must just hate life :D
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Bywater
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quite simply I want to say that this shouldn't be in the bottom 100 movies as voted by the users of IMDb. It is a great heart warming movie, perfect for the whole family. There are many many many other movies out there so much worse than this movie. It made me laugh and that's exactly what a good comedy should do. This movie was hilarious! A rapping genie who knows kung fu and lives in a boom box played by none other than Shaquille O'Neal, what more could you want in a comedy?! I mean sure some of it was cringe worthy and it's not exactly Oscar material, but overall it was a great laugh. Anyone who wants to dis this movie needs to lighten up a little. Shaq has the greatest sense of humor!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you watch this, expect a strong feeling of loss and regret
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brianmckann
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie deserves no rating, and it's not for the reasons you'd think. It is a complete failure, but mostly because it got past common sense, Hollywood budgets, and directing standards. All because I believe Shaq threw enormous piles of money at it, and no one wanted to tell him this was the worst possible movie idea. Also take note that Shaq raises his eyebrows every other word he speaks. Some moments are only mildly painful, while others are clench your teeth, eye-squinting travesties. Most notably, the rap battle between the boy and Shaq, where they repeat "We ain't men, we genie." * Scowling at a piece of toast. * A boom box that shoots a shower of sparks * A grown man showering in front of a child * A rapping genie, that despite boasting his lyrical skills, always starts every rhyme with "I am Kazaam" * More than an hour of your life wasted These are what you have to look forward to in watching this. I'm troubled that anyone thought this would make money, or legitimize Shaq's rapping career in the minds of children. If you have a choice between sitting in gridlock traffic for 9 hours, 10 straight hours of oral surgery or watching Kazaam, Kazaam wins by a slight margin. There's no more positive endorsement I can give.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is One Genie You Don't Want Three Wishes From
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony-rigoni
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We're all familiar with genies in Middle Eastern mythologies. They could be in lamps like Aladdin or in bottles like I Dream of Jeannie. But never, and I repeat never, have I heard of genies coming out of boom boxes! Shaq O'Neil maybe a famous basketball player, but he's such a crappy actor! There are a lot of issues that should have been easily fixed in the first place. First, the acting. Is it me or did everybody woke up in the middle of the afternoon and decided to say "Huh, whatever. Not my movie, I'm not going to act today." Second, the songs. And yes, Shaq O'Neil raps his brains out. But his rapping and the songs are so bland, I keep thinking that the songs were written by the same people who created Bebe's Kids and Tom and Jerry the Movie. Third, the humor. What is the intended age to make stupid jokes like that, ages Born-11 months?! This is probably the same age range intended for Babygeniuses and Titanic: The Legend Goes On! And now, here's my rap for this movie: This piece of crap is oh so bad, it makes me positively mad! It makes me shout and swear and scream, I'd throw this movie down a stream. It's Stupid and Crappy, Tacky and Sappy, Horrendous and Hideous Despicable and Tedious! Don't watch this movie, it'll get you rabies and the humor is intended for babies! Kazaam's a sham and Shaq O'Neil is full of ham! Kazaam is bad and this movie makes me really mad! And it stinks a lot like doggy poo, I might as well be playing Shaq Fu! (PS, that video game sucks too) Enough Said.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An example of why Shag should go back to basketball
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never heard of this film before, but after looking at the Nostalgia Critic review of this abomination, I did see this movie and I permanently despise it, but it's not the worst movie ever made. There are two enjoyable scenes in this movie which includes the bike race sequence and the flying french toasts. However, those two scenes didn't exactly make this film worth watching. The special effects are quite substandard, the script is too childish and very simple, and the story is pretty predictable. The acting is the worst aspect of this film, especially Shag's acting (even his rapping is much worse) and the child actor is so annoying it would make you want to slap him in the face. Overall, not the worst compared to Batman and Robin, Garbage Pail Kids, and Battlefield Earth, but still a horrible movie that needs to be avoided. Rating: 2/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The 90's were not funny, they were stupid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Twetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just started watching my way through IMBDs bottom 100 and this definitely belongs there, I'm pretty sure it deserves to be higher up than number 99 too. I've seen a video review of this so I kind of knew what to expect but it turned out to be so much worse. The other two films from the list that I've seen so far were immensely boring because nothing ever happened in them. This one at least had some action in it but every single thing that happened was just stupid. Now, I can enjoy stupid movies; films that are so bad they become funny, this one though was painfully unfunny. On top of that, the film is in the mid 90's and the film makers make that abundantly clear with the way people dress and above all the horrible hip hop music playing throughout the film. It reminds me of all the bad things about the 90's and none of the good ones. By far the worst thing though is Kazaam himself who, despite being thousands of years old is hip, but not in a good way, and goes around rhyming every sentence he utters like some kind of idiotic hip hop artist. That Shaq can't rap doesn't exactly make it any better. This whole thing feels like a bad 90's music video - starring an untalented rapper - drawn out to a full length feature.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect example of a movie that I loved as a child, hate as an adult...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, adolescent really(19). Like Howard the Duck, Kazaam was a movie I loved as a child but looking back on it I was shocked at how low my taste buds were as a kid. Granted, there are some funny moments specifically the ones with the flying toasts and the bicycle race. And it is not the worst movie of 1996, Ed and especially Bio Dome are worse. However, the special effects are really quite substandard, and the rest of the production values are of direct to video quality and shoddy ones at that. The story is predictable with only a few worthwhile scenes to favour, the sight gags suffer from poor comic timing and the script is childish and simplistic. The characters I really dislike here, the kid is annoying, the villain is one of the lamest I have seen in a long time while Shaquille O'Neal's Genie with his awful rapping(then again I dislike rap intensely, and that is the least problematic of his performance) grated on me fast. The acting doesn't fare much better either, while the direction is literally non-existent and the soundtrack is only tolerable if on mute. This is of course my opinion, disagree all you want, I guess I just didn't like it. 2/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Lamps Should Be Permanently Sealed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yankcrime15
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This isn't as much of a film as it is a giant promotional campaign by Touchstone Pictures to market the NBA's worst free thrower with his extraordinary height. Not only is this obviously forever trapped in a time capsule set to 1996, but everything in this film is done so bad that it's completely laughable. If I had a handful of cardboard cutouts, they would be far more dimensional than any of the people that acted in this film. It's obvious that Shaq not only fails at free throws, rapping and being a video game character, but his acting is absolutely dreadful. He's a "rapping" (actually a RHYMING) genie that moved into a boombox and is summoned when a boy named Max (played by a young Francis Capra) stumbles upon him after being chased by bullies. Throughout the movie, Shaq becomes a subject of slavery as Max owns him until his three wishes are granted. That's pretty much the whole plot, unless you're actually going to include a meaningless subplot about "finding the true father". It doesn't get any better from there. Shaq demonstrates his mad rapping skills by appearing at a night club where he becomes a selected guest. Guess how fast Theodor Geisel was spinning in his grave when he brought forth the detestable line of "Let's green egg and ham it!" Probably around the same speed that would also be brought forth by those two live action adaptations that shall not be named. Then there's some phenomenal acting. I'm talking about the magical french toast. That performance was far more convincing than anything you could expect Shaq to give us. Too bad this film killed its career. Speaking of career killers, ever noticed what happened to Paul Michael Glaser after he directed this film? It's a long story. Granted, it's not one of THE worst things I have ever seen, but it's very close. Kazaam is proof that pitching a non actor as a main character usually does not give satisfactory results. With all this time wasted in the production of this film, I bet Shaq could have gotten some more practice at free throws. The most shocking thing about this? Shaq actually got ANOTHER lead role a year later, but that's a whole different story subject.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why would someone make a film with Shaq as a Genie?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Criticman12
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boy, this is one of the worst films I've seen. No wonder it's on IMDb's Bottom 100 list. I'll start off with the good parts: It did have some funny moments like the scene with the flying french toasts and the scene where Max and Kazaam are having a bicycle race. The bad parts: Everything else in this movie was boring and bad. Shaq as a genie is just plain awful. Beside's he can't even rap. In one scene, he's singing, "Let's Green Eggs and Ham it". Seriously? That's kinda like a 5-year old doing a rap song. The other character's weren't even that good. Max is annoying. The villain is not even that evil. Literally. Also, wasn't this suppose to be a family film? In one scene, Max say's, "So after my 2 last wishes, I own you?", then Kazaam say's, "Technically". Is it me, or is this film about slavery? Overall, "Kazaam", is an awful movie that's not even worth watching. But compare it to, "Batman and Robin", "Son of the Mask", or "Battlefield Earth", it's not that bad. So if you're looking for a good movie with a Genie in it, watch the Disney movie, "Aladdin". That film has a Genie that can sing and make you laugh. He is also voiced by Robin Williams. A "GOOD" actor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All hail Shaq.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gabrielle Phillips
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie Kazaam featuring the multi-talented Shaquille O'Neal should be the standard which all movies are held to. Since originally viewing this wonderful work of cinema 15 years ago, I can say it has definitely held up to the test of time. I've yet to see a movie that even comes close to achieving the depth of character, raw emotion, and beauty that Kazaam portrays. Shaq is definitely a triple threat -- basketball, acting, and singing, what's next!? I can't wait to see more from this truly awe-inspiring man. This film has definitely slid under the radar of Hollywood critics, which I see as a blessing. I'd hate for this movie to get wildly popular and lose its innocence. Once I have children of my own, this will be one of the few movies I allow them to watch since it preaches such good morals & values. If you're debating whether to watch this film or not -- DO IT! Your life will never be the same in the best way possible.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you see this film..... You're as stupid as me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheNewCritic
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So I'm aware that this film was released a fair while ago, but I've only just seen it; and not out of free will. I can some up this film in 1 word.... Shaq, the only "actor" who is more robotic than the Terminator. And really thats all that needs to be said, it's a stupid stupid movie that barely makes any sense, it's so uninteresting that I could feel myself getting stupider as I watched. If you see a copy of this film DESTROY IT, and then maybe one day the world will be ridden of this raping of cinema known as Kazaam 1/10 (and the only reason it scored that high is that i'm not allowed to give it a zero)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    People who hate on this must just hate life :D
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Bywater
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quite simply I want to say that this shouldn't be in the bottom 100 movies as voted by the users of IMDb. It is a great heart warming movie, perfect for the whole family. There are many many many other movies out there so much worse than this movie. It made me laugh and that's exactly what a good comedy should do. This movie was hilarious! A rapping genie who knows kung fu and lives in a boom box played by none other than Shaquille O'Neal, what more could you want in a comedy?! I mean sure some of it was cringe worthy and it's not exactly Oscar material, but overall it was a great laugh. Anyone who wants to dis this movie needs to lighten up a little. Shaq has the greatest sense of humor!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you watch this, expect a strong feeling of loss and regret
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brianmckann
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie deserves no rating, and it's not for the reasons you'd think. It is a complete failure, but mostly because it got past common sense, Hollywood budgets, and directing standards. All because I believe Shaq threw enormous piles of money at it, and no one wanted to tell him this was the worst possible movie idea. Also take note that Shaq raises his eyebrows every other word he speaks. Some moments are only mildly painful, while others are clench your teeth, eye-squinting travesties. Most notably, the rap battle between the boy and Shaq, where they repeat "We ain't men, we genie." * Scowling at a piece of toast. * A boom box that shoots a shower of sparks * A grown man showering in front of a child * A rapping genie, that despite boasting his lyrical skills, always starts every rhyme with "I am Kazaam" * More than an hour of your life wasted These are what you have to look forward to in watching this. I'm troubled that anyone thought this would make money, or legitimize Shaq's rapping career in the minds of children. If you have a choice between sitting in gridlock traffic for 9 hours, 10 straight hours of oral surgery or watching Kazaam, Kazaam wins by a slight margin. There's no more positive endorsement I can give.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is One Genie You Don't Want Three Wishes From
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony-rigoni
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We're all familiar with genies in Middle Eastern mythologies. They could be in lamps like Aladdin or in bottles like I Dream of Jeannie. But never, and I repeat never, have I heard of genies coming out of boom boxes! Shaq O'Neil maybe a famous basketball player, but he's such a crappy actor! There are a lot of issues that should have been easily fixed in the first place. First, the acting. Is it me or did everybody woke up in the middle of the afternoon and decided to say "Huh, whatever. Not my movie, I'm not going to act today." Second, the songs. And yes, Shaq O'Neil raps his brains out. But his rapping and the songs are so bland, I keep thinking that the songs were written by the same people who created Bebe's Kids and Tom and Jerry the Movie. Third, the humor. What is the intended age to make stupid jokes like that, ages Born-11 months?! This is probably the same age range intended for Babygeniuses and Titanic: The Legend Goes On! And now, here's my rap for this movie: This piece of crap is oh so bad, it makes me positively mad! It makes me shout and swear and scream, I'd throw this movie down a stream. It's Stupid and Crappy, Tacky and Sappy, Horrendous and Hideous Despicable and Tedious! Don't watch this movie, it'll get you rabies and the humor is intended for babies! Kazaam's a sham and Shaq O'Neil is full of ham! Kazaam is bad and this movie makes me really mad! And it stinks a lot like doggy poo, I might as well be playing Shaq Fu! (PS, that video game sucks too) Enough Said.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An example of why Shag should go back to basketball
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never heard of this film before, but after looking at the Nostalgia Critic review of this abomination, I did see this movie and I permanently despise it, but it's not the worst movie ever made. There are two enjoyable scenes in this movie which includes the bike race sequence and the flying french toasts. However, those two scenes didn't exactly make this film worth watching. The special effects are quite substandard, the script is too childish and very simple, and the story is pretty predictable. The acting is the worst aspect of this film, especially Shag's acting (even his rapping is much worse) and the child actor is so annoying it would make you want to slap him in the face. Overall, not the worst compared to Batman and Robin, Garbage Pail Kids, and Battlefield Earth, but still a horrible movie that needs to be avoided. Rating: 2/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The 90's were not funny, they were stupid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Twetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just started watching my way through IMBDs bottom 100 and this definitely belongs there, I'm pretty sure it deserves to be higher up than number 99 too. I've seen a video review of this so I kind of knew what to expect but it turned out to be so much worse. The other two films from the list that I've seen so far were immensely boring because nothing ever happened in them. This one at least had some action in it but every single thing that happened was just stupid. Now, I can enjoy stupid movies; films that are so bad they become funny, this one though was painfully unfunny. On top of that, the film is in the mid 90's and the film makers make that abundantly clear with the way people dress and above all the horrible hip hop music playing throughout the film. It reminds me of all the bad things about the 90's and none of the good ones. By far the worst thing though is Kazaam himself who, despite being thousands of years old is hip, but not in a good way, and goes around rhyming every sentence he utters like some kind of idiotic hip hop artist. That Shaq can't rap doesn't exactly make it any better. This whole thing feels like a bad 90's music video - starring an untalented rapper - drawn out to a full length feature.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect example of a movie that I loved as a child, hate as an adult...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, adolescent really(19). Like Howard the Duck, Kazaam was a movie I loved as a child but looking back on it I was shocked at how low my taste buds were as a kid. Granted, there are some funny moments specifically the ones with the flying toasts and the bicycle race. And it is not the worst movie of 1996, Ed and especially Bio Dome are worse. However, the special effects are really quite substandard, and the rest of the production values are of direct to video quality and shoddy ones at that. The story is predictable with only a few worthwhile scenes to favour, the sight gags suffer from poor comic timing and the script is childish and simplistic. The characters I really dislike here, the kid is annoying, the villain is one of the lamest I have seen in a long time while Shaquille O'Neal's Genie with his awful rapping(then again I dislike rap intensely, and that is the least problematic of his performance) grated on me fast. The acting doesn't fare much better either, while the direction is literally non-existent and the soundtrack is only tolerable if on mute. This is of course my opinion, disagree all you want, I guess I just didn't like it. 2/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Lamps Should Be Permanently Sealed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yankcrime15
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This isn't as much of a film as it is a giant promotional campaign by Touchstone Pictures to market the NBA's worst free thrower with his extraordinary height. Not only is this obviously forever trapped in a time capsule set to 1996, but everything in this film is done so bad that it's completely laughable. If I had a handful of cardboard cutouts, they would be far more dimensional than any of the people that acted in this film. It's obvious that Shaq not only fails at free throws, rapping and being a video game character, but his acting is absolutely dreadful. He's a "rapping" (actually a RHYMING) genie that moved into a boombox and is summoned when a boy named Max (played by a young Francis Capra) stumbles upon him after being chased by bullies. Throughout the movie, Shaq becomes a subject of slavery as Max owns him until his three wishes are granted. That's pretty much the whole plot, unless you're actually going to include a meaningless subplot about "finding the true father". It doesn't get any better from there. Shaq demonstrates his mad rapping skills by appearing at a night club where he becomes a selected guest. Guess how fast Theodor Geisel was spinning in his grave when he brought forth the detestable line of "Let's green egg and ham it!" Probably around the same speed that would also be brought forth by those two live action adaptations that shall not be named. Then there's some phenomenal acting. I'm talking about the magical french toast. That performance was far more convincing than anything you could expect Shaq to give us. Too bad this film killed its career. Speaking of career killers, ever noticed what happened to Paul Michael Glaser after he directed this film? It's a long story. Granted, it's not one of THE worst things I have ever seen, but it's very close. Kazaam is proof that pitching a non actor as a main character usually does not give satisfactory results. With all this time wasted in the production of this film, I bet Shaq could have gotten some more practice at free throws. The most shocking thing about this? Shaq actually got ANOTHER lead role a year later, but that's a whole different story subject.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why would someone make a film with Shaq as a Genie?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Criticman12
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boy, this is one of the worst films I've seen. No wonder it's on IMDb's Bottom 100 list. I'll start off with the good parts: It did have some funny moments like the scene with the flying french toasts and the scene where Max and Kazaam are having a bicycle race. The bad parts: Everything else in this movie was boring and bad. Shaq as a genie is just plain awful. Beside's he can't even rap. In one scene, he's singing, "Let's Green Eggs and Ham it". Seriously? That's kinda like a 5-year old doing a rap song. The other character's weren't even that good. Max is annoying. The villain is not even that evil. Literally. Also, wasn't this suppose to be a family film? In one scene, Max say's, "So after my 2 last wishes, I own you?", then Kazaam say's, "Technically". Is it me, or is this film about slavery? Overall, "Kazaam", is an awful movie that's not even worth watching. But compare it to, "Batman and Robin", "Son of the Mask", or "Battlefield Earth", it's not that bad. So if you're looking for a good movie with a Genie in it, watch the Disney movie, "Aladdin". That film has a Genie that can sing and make you laugh. He is also voiced by Robin Williams. A "GOOD" actor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All hail Shaq.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gabrielle Phillips
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie Kazaam featuring the multi-talented Shaquille O'Neal should be the standard which all movies are held to. Since originally viewing this wonderful work of cinema 15 years ago, I can say it has definitely held up to the test of time. I've yet to see a movie that even comes close to achieving the depth of character, raw emotion, and beauty that Kazaam portrays. Shaq is definitely a triple threat -- basketball, acting, and singing, what's next!? I can't wait to see more from this truly awe-inspiring man. This film has definitely slid under the radar of Hollywood critics, which I see as a blessing. I'd hate for this movie to get wildly popular and lose its innocence. Once I have children of my own, this will be one of the few movies I allow them to watch since it preaches such good morals & values. If you're debating whether to watch this film or not -- DO IT! Your life will never be the same in the best way possible.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you see this film..... You're as stupid as me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheNewCritic
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So I'm aware that this film was released a fair while ago, but I've only just seen it; and not out of free will. I can some up this film in 1 word.... Shaq, the only "actor" who is more robotic than the Terminator. And really thats all that needs to be said, it's a stupid stupid movie that barely makes any sense, it's so uninteresting that I could feel myself getting stupider as I watched. If you see a copy of this film DESTROY IT, and then maybe one day the world will be ridden of this raping of cinema known as Kazaam 1/10 (and the only reason it scored that high is that i'm not allowed to give it a zero)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    People who hate on this must just hate life :D
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Bywater
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quite simply I want to say that this shouldn't be in the bottom 100 movies as voted by the users of IMDb. It is a great heart warming movie, perfect for the whole family. There are many many many other movies out there so much worse than this movie. It made me laugh and that's exactly what a good comedy should do. This movie was hilarious! A rapping genie who knows kung fu and lives in a boom box played by none other than Shaquille O'Neal, what more could you want in a comedy?! I mean sure some of it was cringe worthy and it's not exactly Oscar material, but overall it was a great laugh. Anyone who wants to dis this movie needs to lighten up a little. Shaq has the greatest sense of humor!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you watch this, expect a strong feeling of loss and regret
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brianmckann
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie deserves no rating, and it's not for the reasons you'd think. It is a complete failure, but mostly because it got past common sense, Hollywood budgets, and directing standards. All because I believe Shaq threw enormous piles of money at it, and no one wanted to tell him this was the worst possible movie idea. Also take note that Shaq raises his eyebrows every other word he speaks. Some moments are only mildly painful, while others are clench your teeth, eye-squinting travesties. Most notably, the rap battle between the boy and Shaq, where they repeat "We ain't men, we genie." * Scowling at a piece of toast. * A boom box that shoots a shower of sparks * A grown man showering in front of a child * A rapping genie, that despite boasting his lyrical skills, always starts every rhyme with "I am Kazaam" * More than an hour of your life wasted These are what you have to look forward to in watching this. I'm troubled that anyone thought this would make money, or legitimize Shaq's rapping career in the minds of children. If you have a choice between sitting in gridlock traffic for 9 hours, 10 straight hours of oral surgery or watching Kazaam, Kazaam wins by a slight margin. There's no more positive endorsement I can give.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is One Genie You Don't Want Three Wishes From
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony-rigoni
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We're all familiar with genies in Middle Eastern mythologies. They could be in lamps like Aladdin or in bottles like I Dream of Jeannie. But never, and I repeat never, have I heard of genies coming out of boom boxes! Shaq O'Neil maybe a famous basketball player, but he's such a crappy actor! There are a lot of issues that should have been easily fixed in the first place. First, the acting. Is it me or did everybody woke up in the middle of the afternoon and decided to say "Huh, whatever. Not my movie, I'm not going to act today." Second, the songs. And yes, Shaq O'Neil raps his brains out. But his rapping and the songs are so bland, I keep thinking that the songs were written by the same people who created Bebe's Kids and Tom and Jerry the Movie. Third, the humor. What is the intended age to make stupid jokes like that, ages Born-11 months?! This is probably the same age range intended for Babygeniuses and Titanic: The Legend Goes On! And now, here's my rap for this movie: This piece of crap is oh so bad, it makes me positively mad! It makes me shout and swear and scream, I'd throw this movie down a stream. It's Stupid and Crappy, Tacky and Sappy, Horrendous and Hideous Despicable and Tedious! Don't watch this movie, it'll get you rabies and the humor is intended for babies! Kazaam's a sham and Shaq O'Neil is full of ham! Kazaam is bad and this movie makes me really mad! And it stinks a lot like doggy poo, I might as well be playing Shaq Fu! (PS, that video game sucks too) Enough Said.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An example of why Shag should go back to basketball
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never heard of this film before, but after looking at the Nostalgia Critic review of this abomination, I did see this movie and I permanently despise it, but it's not the worst movie ever made. There are two enjoyable scenes in this movie which includes the bike race sequence and the flying french toasts. However, those two scenes didn't exactly make this film worth watching. The special effects are quite substandard, the script is too childish and very simple, and the story is pretty predictable. The acting is the worst aspect of this film, especially Shag's acting (even his rapping is much worse) and the child actor is so annoying it would make you want to slap him in the face. Overall, not the worst compared to Batman and Robin, Garbage Pail Kids, and Battlefield Earth, but still a horrible movie that needs to be avoided. Rating: 2/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The 90's were not funny, they were stupid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Twetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just started watching my way through IMBDs bottom 100 and this definitely belongs there, I'm pretty sure it deserves to be higher up than number 99 too. I've seen a video review of this so I kind of knew what to expect but it turned out to be so much worse. The other two films from the list that I've seen so far were immensely boring because nothing ever happened in them. This one at least had some action in it but every single thing that happened was just stupid. Now, I can enjoy stupid movies; films that are so bad they become funny, this one though was painfully unfunny. On top of that, the film is in the mid 90's and the film makers make that abundantly clear with the way people dress and above all the horrible hip hop music playing throughout the film. It reminds me of all the bad things about the 90's and none of the good ones. By far the worst thing though is Kazaam himself who, despite being thousands of years old is hip, but not in a good way, and goes around rhyming every sentence he utters like some kind of idiotic hip hop artist. That Shaq can't rap doesn't exactly make it any better. This whole thing feels like a bad 90's music video - starring an untalented rapper - drawn out to a full length feature.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect example of a movie that I loved as a child, hate as an adult...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, adolescent really(19). Like Howard the Duck, Kazaam was a movie I loved as a child but looking back on it I was shocked at how low my taste buds were as a kid. Granted, there are some funny moments specifically the ones with the flying toasts and the bicycle race. And it is not the worst movie of 1996, Ed and especially Bio Dome are worse. However, the special effects are really quite substandard, and the rest of the production values are of direct to video quality and shoddy ones at that. The story is predictable with only a few worthwhile scenes to favour, the sight gags suffer from poor comic timing and the script is childish and simplistic. The characters I really dislike here, the kid is annoying, the villain is one of the lamest I have seen in a long time while Shaquille O'Neal's Genie with his awful rapping(then again I dislike rap intensely, and that is the least problematic of his performance) grated on me fast. The acting doesn't fare much better either, while the direction is literally non-existent and the soundtrack is only tolerable if on mute. This is of course my opinion, disagree all you want, I guess I just didn't like it. 2/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Lamps Should Be Permanently Sealed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yankcrime15
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This isn't as much of a film as it is a giant promotional campaign by Touchstone Pictures to market the NBA's worst free thrower with his extraordinary height. Not only is this obviously forever trapped in a time capsule set to 1996, but everything in this film is done so bad that it's completely laughable. If I had a handful of cardboard cutouts, they would be far more dimensional than any of the people that acted in this film. It's obvious that Shaq not only fails at free throws, rapping and being a video game character, but his acting is absolutely dreadful. He's a "rapping" (actually a RHYMING) genie that moved into a boombox and is summoned when a boy named Max (played by a young Francis Capra) stumbles upon him after being chased by bullies. Throughout the movie, Shaq becomes a subject of slavery as Max owns him until his three wishes are granted. That's pretty much the whole plot, unless you're actually going to include a meaningless subplot about "finding the true father". It doesn't get any better from there. Shaq demonstrates his mad rapping skills by appearing at a night club where he becomes a selected guest. Guess how fast Theodor Geisel was spinning in his grave when he brought forth the detestable line of "Let's green egg and ham it!" Probably around the same speed that would also be brought forth by those two live action adaptations that shall not be named. Then there's some phenomenal acting. I'm talking about the magical french toast. That performance was far more convincing than anything you could expect Shaq to give us. Too bad this film killed its career. Speaking of career killers, ever noticed what happened to Paul Michael Glaser after he directed this film? It's a long story. Granted, it's not one of THE worst things I have ever seen, but it's very close. Kazaam is proof that pitching a non actor as a main character usually does not give satisfactory results. With all this time wasted in the production of this film, I bet Shaq could have gotten some more practice at free throws. The most shocking thing about this? Shaq actually got ANOTHER lead role a year later, but that's a whole different story subject.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why would someone make a film with Shaq as a Genie?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Criticman12
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boy, this is one of the worst films I've seen. No wonder it's on IMDb's Bottom 100 list. I'll start off with the good parts: It did have some funny moments like the scene with the flying french toasts and the scene where Max and Kazaam are having a bicycle race. The bad parts: Everything else in this movie was boring and bad. Shaq as a genie is just plain awful. Beside's he can't even rap. In one scene, he's singing, "Let's Green Eggs and Ham it". Seriously? That's kinda like a 5-year old doing a rap song. The other character's weren't even that good. Max is annoying. The villain is not even that evil. Literally. Also, wasn't this suppose to be a family film? In one scene, Max say's, "So after my 2 last wishes, I own you?", then Kazaam say's, "Technically". Is it me, or is this film about slavery? Overall, "Kazaam", is an awful movie that's not even worth watching. But compare it to, "Batman and Robin", "Son of the Mask", or "Battlefield Earth", it's not that bad. So if you're looking for a good movie with a Genie in it, watch the Disney movie, "Aladdin". That film has a Genie that can sing and make you laugh. He is also voiced by Robin Williams. A "GOOD" actor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All hail Shaq.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gabrielle Phillips
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie Kazaam featuring the multi-talented Shaquille O'Neal should be the standard which all movies are held to. Since originally viewing this wonderful work of cinema 15 years ago, I can say it has definitely held up to the test of time. I've yet to see a movie that even comes close to achieving the depth of character, raw emotion, and beauty that Kazaam portrays. Shaq is definitely a triple threat -- basketball, acting, and singing, what's next!? I can't wait to see more from this truly awe-inspiring man. This film has definitely slid under the radar of Hollywood critics, which I see as a blessing. I'd hate for this movie to get wildly popular and lose its innocence. Once I have children of my own, this will be one of the few movies I allow them to watch since it preaches such good morals & values. If you're debating whether to watch this film or not -- DO IT! Your life will never be the same in the best way possible.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you see this film..... You're as stupid as me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheNewCritic
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So I'm aware that this film was released a fair while ago, but I've only just seen it; and not out of free will. I can some up this film in 1 word.... Shaq, the only "actor" who is more robotic than the Terminator. And really thats all that needs to be said, it's a stupid stupid movie that barely makes any sense, it's so uninteresting that I could feel myself getting stupider as I watched. If you see a copy of this film DESTROY IT, and then maybe one day the world will be ridden of this raping of cinema known as Kazaam 1/10 (and the only reason it scored that high is that i'm not allowed to give it a zero)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    People who hate on this must just hate life :D
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Bywater
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quite simply I want to say that this shouldn't be in the bottom 100 movies as voted by the users of IMDb. It is a great heart warming movie, perfect for the whole family. There are many many many other movies out there so much worse than this movie. It made me laugh and that's exactly what a good comedy should do. This movie was hilarious! A rapping genie who knows kung fu and lives in a boom box played by none other than Shaquille O'Neal, what more could you want in a comedy?! I mean sure some of it was cringe worthy and it's not exactly Oscar material, but overall it was a great laugh. Anyone who wants to dis this movie needs to lighten up a little. Shaq has the greatest sense of humor!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you watch this, expect a strong feeling of loss and regret
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brianmckann
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie deserves no rating, and it's not for the reasons you'd think. It is a complete failure, but mostly because it got past common sense, Hollywood budgets, and directing standards. All because I believe Shaq threw enormous piles of money at it, and no one wanted to tell him this was the worst possible movie idea. Also take note that Shaq raises his eyebrows every other word he speaks. Some moments are only mildly painful, while others are clench your teeth, eye-squinting travesties. Most notably, the rap battle between the boy and Shaq, where they repeat "We ain't men, we genie." * Scowling at a piece of toast. * A boom box that shoots a shower of sparks * A grown man showering in front of a child * A rapping genie, that despite boasting his lyrical skills, always starts every rhyme with "I am Kazaam" * More than an hour of your life wasted These are what you have to look forward to in watching this. I'm troubled that anyone thought this would make money, or legitimize Shaq's rapping career in the minds of children. If you have a choice between sitting in gridlock traffic for 9 hours, 10 straight hours of oral surgery or watching Kazaam, Kazaam wins by a slight margin. There's no more positive endorsement I can give.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is One Genie You Don't Want Three Wishes From
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony-rigoni
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We're all familiar with genies in Middle Eastern mythologies. They could be in lamps like Aladdin or in bottles like I Dream of Jeannie. But never, and I repeat never, have I heard of genies coming out of boom boxes! Shaq O'Neil maybe a famous basketball player, but he's such a crappy actor! There are a lot of issues that should have been easily fixed in the first place. First, the acting. Is it me or did everybody woke up in the middle of the afternoon and decided to say "Huh, whatever. Not my movie, I'm not going to act today." Second, the songs. And yes, Shaq O'Neil raps his brains out. But his rapping and the songs are so bland, I keep thinking that the songs were written by the same people who created Bebe's Kids and Tom and Jerry the Movie. Third, the humor. What is the intended age to make stupid jokes like that, ages Born-11 months?! This is probably the same age range intended for Babygeniuses and Titanic: The Legend Goes On! And now, here's my rap for this movie: This piece of crap is oh so bad, it makes me positively mad! It makes me shout and swear and scream, I'd throw this movie down a stream. It's Stupid and Crappy, Tacky and Sappy, Horrendous and Hideous Despicable and Tedious! Don't watch this movie, it'll get you rabies and the humor is intended for babies! Kazaam's a sham and Shaq O'Neil is full of ham! Kazaam is bad and this movie makes me really mad! And it stinks a lot like doggy poo, I might as well be playing Shaq Fu! (PS, that video game sucks too) Enough Said.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An example of why Shag should go back to basketball
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never heard of this film before, but after looking at the Nostalgia Critic review of this abomination, I did see this movie and I permanently despise it, but it's not the worst movie ever made. There are two enjoyable scenes in this movie which includes the bike race sequence and the flying french toasts. However, those two scenes didn't exactly make this film worth watching. The special effects are quite substandard, the script is too childish and very simple, and the story is pretty predictable. The acting is the worst aspect of this film, especially Shag's acting (even his rapping is much worse) and the child actor is so annoying it would make you want to slap him in the face. Overall, not the worst compared to Batman and Robin, Garbage Pail Kids, and Battlefield Earth, but still a horrible movie that needs to be avoided. Rating: 2/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The 90's were not funny, they were stupid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Twetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just started watching my way through IMBDs bottom 100 and this definitely belongs there, I'm pretty sure it deserves to be higher up than number 99 too. I've seen a video review of this so I kind of knew what to expect but it turned out to be so much worse. The other two films from the list that I've seen so far were immensely boring because nothing ever happened in them. This one at least had some action in it but every single thing that happened was just stupid. Now, I can enjoy stupid movies; films that are so bad they become funny, this one though was painfully unfunny. On top of that, the film is in the mid 90's and the film makers make that abundantly clear with the way people dress and above all the horrible hip hop music playing throughout the film. It reminds me of all the bad things about the 90's and none of the good ones. By far the worst thing though is Kazaam himself who, despite being thousands of years old is hip, but not in a good way, and goes around rhyming every sentence he utters like some kind of idiotic hip hop artist. That Shaq can't rap doesn't exactly make it any better. This whole thing feels like a bad 90's music video - starring an untalented rapper - drawn out to a full length feature.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect example of a movie that I loved as a child, hate as an adult...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, adolescent really(19). Like Howard the Duck, Kazaam was a movie I loved as a child but looking back on it I was shocked at how low my taste buds were as a kid. Granted, there are some funny moments specifically the ones with the flying toasts and the bicycle race. And it is not the worst movie of 1996, Ed and especially Bio Dome are worse. However, the special effects are really quite substandard, and the rest of the production values are of direct to video quality and shoddy ones at that. The story is predictable with only a few worthwhile scenes to favour, the sight gags suffer from poor comic timing and the script is childish and simplistic. The characters I really dislike here, the kid is annoying, the villain is one of the lamest I have seen in a long time while Shaquille O'Neal's Genie with his awful rapping(then again I dislike rap intensely, and that is the least problematic of his performance) grated on me fast. The acting doesn't fare much better either, while the direction is literally non-existent and the soundtrack is only tolerable if on mute. This is of course my opinion, disagree all you want, I guess I just didn't like it. 2/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Lamps Should Be Permanently Sealed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yankcrime15
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This isn't as much of a film as it is a giant promotional campaign by Touchstone Pictures to market the NBA's worst free thrower with his extraordinary height. Not only is this obviously forever trapped in a time capsule set to 1996, but everything in this film is done so bad that it's completely laughable. If I had a handful of cardboard cutouts, they would be far more dimensional than any of the people that acted in this film. It's obvious that Shaq not only fails at free throws, rapping and being a video game character, but his acting is absolutely dreadful. He's a "rapping" (actually a RHYMING) genie that moved into a boombox and is summoned when a boy named Max (played by a young Francis Capra) stumbles upon him after being chased by bullies. Throughout the movie, Shaq becomes a subject of slavery as Max owns him until his three wishes are granted. That's pretty much the whole plot, unless you're actually going to include a meaningless subplot about "finding the true father". It doesn't get any better from there. Shaq demonstrates his mad rapping skills by appearing at a night club where he becomes a selected guest. Guess how fast Theodor Geisel was spinning in his grave when he brought forth the detestable line of "Let's green egg and ham it!" Probably around the same speed that would also be brought forth by those two live action adaptations that shall not be named. Then there's some phenomenal acting. I'm talking about the magical french toast. That performance was far more convincing than anything you could expect Shaq to give us. Too bad this film killed its career. Speaking of career killers, ever noticed what happened to Paul Michael Glaser after he directed this film? It's a long story. Granted, it's not one of THE worst things I have ever seen, but it's very close. Kazaam is proof that pitching a non actor as a main character usually does not give satisfactory results. With all this time wasted in the production of this film, I bet Shaq could have gotten some more practice at free throws. The most shocking thing about this? Shaq actually got ANOTHER lead role a year later, but that's a whole different story subject.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why would someone make a film with Shaq as a Genie?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Criticman12
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boy, this is one of the worst films I've seen. No wonder it's on IMDb's Bottom 100 list. I'll start off with the good parts: It did have some funny moments like the scene with the flying french toasts and the scene where Max and Kazaam are having a bicycle race. The bad parts: Everything else in this movie was boring and bad. Shaq as a genie is just plain awful. Beside's he can't even rap. In one scene, he's singing, "Let's Green Eggs and Ham it". Seriously? That's kinda like a 5-year old doing a rap song. The other character's weren't even that good. Max is annoying. The villain is not even that evil. Literally. Also, wasn't this suppose to be a family film? In one scene, Max say's, "So after my 2 last wishes, I own you?", then Kazaam say's, "Technically". Is it me, or is this film about slavery? Overall, "Kazaam", is an awful movie that's not even worth watching. But compare it to, "Batman and Robin", "Son of the Mask", or "Battlefield Earth", it's not that bad. So if you're looking for a good movie with a Genie in it, watch the Disney movie, "Aladdin". That film has a Genie that can sing and make you laugh. He is also voiced by Robin Williams. A "GOOD" actor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All hail Shaq.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gabrielle Phillips
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie Kazaam featuring the multi-talented Shaquille O'Neal should be the standard which all movies are held to. Since originally viewing this wonderful work of cinema 15 years ago, I can say it has definitely held up to the test of time. I've yet to see a movie that even comes close to achieving the depth of character, raw emotion, and beauty that Kazaam portrays. Shaq is definitely a triple threat -- basketball, acting, and singing, what's next!? I can't wait to see more from this truly awe-inspiring man. This film has definitely slid under the radar of Hollywood critics, which I see as a blessing. I'd hate for this movie to get wildly popular and lose its innocence. Once I have children of my own, this will be one of the few movies I allow them to watch since it preaches such good morals & values. If you're debating whether to watch this film or not -- DO IT! Your life will never be the same in the best way possible.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you see this film..... You're as stupid as me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheNewCritic
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So I'm aware that this film was released a fair while ago, but I've only just seen it; and not out of free will. I can some up this film in 1 word.... Shaq, the only "actor" who is more robotic than the Terminator. And really thats all that needs to be said, it's a stupid stupid movie that barely makes any sense, it's so uninteresting that I could feel myself getting stupider as I watched. If you see a copy of this film DESTROY IT, and then maybe one day the world will be ridden of this raping of cinema known as Kazaam 1/10 (and the only reason it scored that high is that i'm not allowed to give it a zero)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    People who hate on this must just hate life :D
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Bywater
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quite simply I want to say that this shouldn't be in the bottom 100 movies as voted by the users of IMDb. It is a great heart warming movie, perfect for the whole family. There are many many many other movies out there so much worse than this movie. It made me laugh and that's exactly what a good comedy should do. This movie was hilarious! A rapping genie who knows kung fu and lives in a boom box played by none other than Shaquille O'Neal, what more could you want in a comedy?! I mean sure some of it was cringe worthy and it's not exactly Oscar material, but overall it was a great laugh. Anyone who wants to dis this movie needs to lighten up a little. Shaq has the greatest sense of humor!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you watch this, expect a strong feeling of loss and regret
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brianmckann
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie deserves no rating, and it's not for the reasons you'd think. It is a complete failure, but mostly because it got past common sense, Hollywood budgets, and directing standards. All because I believe Shaq threw enormous piles of money at it, and no one wanted to tell him this was the worst possible movie idea. Also take note that Shaq raises his eyebrows every other word he speaks. Some moments are only mildly painful, while others are clench your teeth, eye-squinting travesties. Most notably, the rap battle between the boy and Shaq, where they repeat "We ain't men, we genie." * Scowling at a piece of toast. * A boom box that shoots a shower of sparks * A grown man showering in front of a child * A rapping genie, that despite boasting his lyrical skills, always starts every rhyme with "I am Kazaam" * More than an hour of your life wasted These are what you have to look forward to in watching this. I'm troubled that anyone thought this would make money, or legitimize Shaq's rapping career in the minds of children. If you have a choice between sitting in gridlock traffic for 9 hours, 10 straight hours of oral surgery or watching Kazaam, Kazaam wins by a slight margin. There's no more positive endorsement I can give.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is One Genie You Don't Want Three Wishes From
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony-rigoni
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We're all familiar with genies in Middle Eastern mythologies. They could be in lamps like Aladdin or in bottles like I Dream of Jeannie. But never, and I repeat never, have I heard of genies coming out of boom boxes! Shaq O'Neil maybe a famous basketball player, but he's such a crappy actor! There are a lot of issues that should have been easily fixed in the first place. First, the acting. Is it me or did everybody woke up in the middle of the afternoon and decided to say "Huh, whatever. Not my movie, I'm not going to act today." Second, the songs. And yes, Shaq O'Neil raps his brains out. But his rapping and the songs are so bland, I keep thinking that the songs were written by the same people who created Bebe's Kids and Tom and Jerry the Movie. Third, the humor. What is the intended age to make stupid jokes like that, ages Born-11 months?! This is probably the same age range intended for Babygeniuses and Titanic: The Legend Goes On! And now, here's my rap for this movie: This piece of crap is oh so bad, it makes me positively mad! It makes me shout and swear and scream, I'd throw this movie down a stream. It's Stupid and Crappy, Tacky and Sappy, Horrendous and Hideous Despicable and Tedious! Don't watch this movie, it'll get you rabies and the humor is intended for babies! Kazaam's a sham and Shaq O'Neil is full of ham! Kazaam is bad and this movie makes me really mad! And it stinks a lot like doggy poo, I might as well be playing Shaq Fu! (PS, that video game sucks too) Enough Said.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An example of why Shag should go back to basketball
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never heard of this film before, but after looking at the Nostalgia Critic review of this abomination, I did see this movie and I permanently despise it, but it's not the worst movie ever made. There are two enjoyable scenes in this movie which includes the bike race sequence and the flying french toasts. However, those two scenes didn't exactly make this film worth watching. The special effects are quite substandard, the script is too childish and very simple, and the story is pretty predictable. The acting is the worst aspect of this film, especially Shag's acting (even his rapping is much worse) and the child actor is so annoying it would make you want to slap him in the face. Overall, not the worst compared to Batman and Robin, Garbage Pail Kids, and Battlefield Earth, but still a horrible movie that needs to be avoided. Rating: 2/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The 90's were not funny, they were stupid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Twetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just started watching my way through IMBDs bottom 100 and this definitely belongs there, I'm pretty sure it deserves to be higher up than number 99 too. I've seen a video review of this so I kind of knew what to expect but it turned out to be so much worse. The other two films from the list that I've seen so far were immensely boring because nothing ever happened in them. This one at least had some action in it but every single thing that happened was just stupid. Now, I can enjoy stupid movies; films that are so bad they become funny, this one though was painfully unfunny. On top of that, the film is in the mid 90's and the film makers make that abundantly clear with the way people dress and above all the horrible hip hop music playing throughout the film. It reminds me of all the bad things about the 90's and none of the good ones. By far the worst thing though is Kazaam himself who, despite being thousands of years old is hip, but not in a good way, and goes around rhyming every sentence he utters like some kind of idiotic hip hop artist. That Shaq can't rap doesn't exactly make it any better. This whole thing feels like a bad 90's music video - starring an untalented rapper - drawn out to a full length feature.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect example of a movie that I loved as a child, hate as an adult...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, adolescent really(19). Like Howard the Duck, Kazaam was a movie I loved as a child but looking back on it I was shocked at how low my taste buds were as a kid. Granted, there are some funny moments specifically the ones with the flying toasts and the bicycle race. And it is not the worst movie of 1996, Ed and especially Bio Dome are worse. However, the special effects are really quite substandard, and the rest of the production values are of direct to video quality and shoddy ones at that. The story is predictable with only a few worthwhile scenes to favour, the sight gags suffer from poor comic timing and the script is childish and simplistic. The characters I really dislike here, the kid is annoying, the villain is one of the lamest I have seen in a long time while Shaquille O'Neal's Genie with his awful rapping(then again I dislike rap intensely, and that is the least problematic of his performance) grated on me fast. The acting doesn't fare much better either, while the direction is literally non-existent and the soundtrack is only tolerable if on mute. This is of course my opinion, disagree all you want, I guess I just didn't like it. 2/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Lamps Should Be Permanently Sealed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yankcrime15
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This isn't as much of a film as it is a giant promotional campaign by Touchstone Pictures to market the NBA's worst free thrower with his extraordinary height. Not only is this obviously forever trapped in a time capsule set to 1996, but everything in this film is done so bad that it's completely laughable. If I had a handful of cardboard cutouts, they would be far more dimensional than any of the people that acted in this film. It's obvious that Shaq not only fails at free throws, rapping and being a video game character, but his acting is absolutely dreadful. He's a "rapping" (actually a RHYMING) genie that moved into a boombox and is summoned when a boy named Max (played by a young Francis Capra) stumbles upon him after being chased by bullies. Throughout the movie, Shaq becomes a subject of slavery as Max owns him until his three wishes are granted. That's pretty much the whole plot, unless you're actually going to include a meaningless subplot about "finding the true father". It doesn't get any better from there. Shaq demonstrates his mad rapping skills by appearing at a night club where he becomes a selected guest. Guess how fast Theodor Geisel was spinning in his grave when he brought forth the detestable line of "Let's green egg and ham it!" Probably around the same speed that would also be brought forth by those two live action adaptations that shall not be named. Then there's some phenomenal acting. I'm talking about the magical french toast. That performance was far more convincing than anything you could expect Shaq to give us. Too bad this film killed its career. Speaking of career killers, ever noticed what happened to Paul Michael Glaser after he directed this film? It's a long story. Granted, it's not one of THE worst things I have ever seen, but it's very close. Kazaam is proof that pitching a non actor as a main character usually does not give satisfactory results. With all this time wasted in the production of this film, I bet Shaq could have gotten some more practice at free throws. The most shocking thing about this? Shaq actually got ANOTHER lead role a year later, but that's a whole different story subject.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why would someone make a film with Shaq as a Genie?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Criticman12
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boy, this is one of the worst films I've seen. No wonder it's on IMDb's Bottom 100 list. I'll start off with the good parts: It did have some funny moments like the scene with the flying french toasts and the scene where Max and Kazaam are having a bicycle race. The bad parts: Everything else in this movie was boring and bad. Shaq as a genie is just plain awful. Beside's he can't even rap. In one scene, he's singing, "Let's Green Eggs and Ham it". Seriously? That's kinda like a 5-year old doing a rap song. The other character's weren't even that good. Max is annoying. The villain is not even that evil. Literally. Also, wasn't this suppose to be a family film? In one scene, Max say's, "So after my 2 last wishes, I own you?", then Kazaam say's, "Technically". Is it me, or is this film about slavery? Overall, "Kazaam", is an awful movie that's not even worth watching. But compare it to, "Batman and Robin", "Son of the Mask", or "Battlefield Earth", it's not that bad. So if you're looking for a good movie with a Genie in it, watch the Disney movie, "Aladdin". That film has a Genie that can sing and make you laugh. He is also voiced by Robin Williams. A "GOOD" actor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All hail Shaq.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gabrielle Phillips
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie Kazaam featuring the multi-talented Shaquille O'Neal should be the standard which all movies are held to. Since originally viewing this wonderful work of cinema 15 years ago, I can say it has definitely held up to the test of time. I've yet to see a movie that even comes close to achieving the depth of character, raw emotion, and beauty that Kazaam portrays. Shaq is definitely a triple threat -- basketball, acting, and singing, what's next!? I can't wait to see more from this truly awe-inspiring man. This film has definitely slid under the radar of Hollywood critics, which I see as a blessing. I'd hate for this movie to get wildly popular and lose its innocence. Once I have children of my own, this will be one of the few movies I allow them to watch since it preaches such good morals & values. If you're debating whether to watch this film or not -- DO IT! Your life will never be the same in the best way possible.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you see this film..... You're as stupid as me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheNewCritic
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So I'm aware that this film was released a fair while ago, but I've only just seen it; and not out of free will. I can some up this film in 1 word.... Shaq, the only "actor" who is more robotic than the Terminator. And really thats all that needs to be said, it's a stupid stupid movie that barely makes any sense, it's so uninteresting that I could feel myself getting stupider as I watched. If you see a copy of this film DESTROY IT, and then maybe one day the world will be ridden of this raping of cinema known as Kazaam 1/10 (and the only reason it scored that high is that i'm not allowed to give it a zero)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    People who hate on this must just hate life :D
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Bywater
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quite simply I want to say that this shouldn't be in the bottom 100 movies as voted by the users of IMDb. It is a great heart warming movie, perfect for the whole family. There are many many many other movies out there so much worse than this movie. It made me laugh and that's exactly what a good comedy should do. This movie was hilarious! A rapping genie who knows kung fu and lives in a boom box played by none other than Shaquille O'Neal, what more could you want in a comedy?! I mean sure some of it was cringe worthy and it's not exactly Oscar material, but overall it was a great laugh. Anyone who wants to dis this movie needs to lighten up a little. Shaq has the greatest sense of humor!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you watch this, expect a strong feeling of loss and regret
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brianmckann
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie deserves no rating, and it's not for the reasons you'd think. It is a complete failure, but mostly because it got past common sense, Hollywood budgets, and directing standards. All because I believe Shaq threw enormous piles of money at it, and no one wanted to tell him this was the worst possible movie idea. Also take note that Shaq raises his eyebrows every other word he speaks. Some moments are only mildly painful, while others are clench your teeth, eye-squinting travesties. Most notably, the rap battle between the boy and Shaq, where they repeat "We ain't men, we genie." * Scowling at a piece of toast. * A boom box that shoots a shower of sparks * A grown man showering in front of a child * A rapping genie, that despite boasting his lyrical skills, always starts every rhyme with "I am Kazaam" * More than an hour of your life wasted These are what you have to look forward to in watching this. I'm troubled that anyone thought this would make money, or legitimize Shaq's rapping career in the minds of children. If you have a choice between sitting in gridlock traffic for 9 hours, 10 straight hours of oral surgery or watching Kazaam, Kazaam wins by a slight margin. There's no more positive endorsement I can give.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is One Genie You Don't Want Three Wishes From
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony-rigoni
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We're all familiar with genies in Middle Eastern mythologies. They could be in lamps like Aladdin or in bottles like I Dream of Jeannie. But never, and I repeat never, have I heard of genies coming out of boom boxes! Shaq O'Neil maybe a famous basketball player, but he's such a crappy actor! There are a lot of issues that should have been easily fixed in the first place. First, the acting. Is it me or did everybody woke up in the middle of the afternoon and decided to say "Huh, whatever. Not my movie, I'm not going to act today." Second, the songs. And yes, Shaq O'Neil raps his brains out. But his rapping and the songs are so bland, I keep thinking that the songs were written by the same people who created Bebe's Kids and Tom and Jerry the Movie. Third, the humor. What is the intended age to make stupid jokes like that, ages Born-11 months?! This is probably the same age range intended for Babygeniuses and Titanic: The Legend Goes On! And now, here's my rap for this movie: This piece of crap is oh so bad, it makes me positively mad! It makes me shout and swear and scream, I'd throw this movie down a stream. It's Stupid and Crappy, Tacky and Sappy, Horrendous and Hideous Despicable and Tedious! Don't watch this movie, it'll get you rabies and the humor is intended for babies! Kazaam's a sham and Shaq O'Neil is full of ham! Kazaam is bad and this movie makes me really mad! And it stinks a lot like doggy poo, I might as well be playing Shaq Fu! (PS, that video game sucks too) Enough Said.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An example of why Shag should go back to basketball
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never heard of this film before, but after looking at the Nostalgia Critic review of this abomination, I did see this movie and I permanently despise it, but it's not the worst movie ever made. There are two enjoyable scenes in this movie which includes the bike race sequence and the flying french toasts. However, those two scenes didn't exactly make this film worth watching. The special effects are quite substandard, the script is too childish and very simple, and the story is pretty predictable. The acting is the worst aspect of this film, especially Shag's acting (even his rapping is much worse) and the child actor is so annoying it would make you want to slap him in the face. Overall, not the worst compared to Batman and Robin, Garbage Pail Kids, and Battlefield Earth, but still a horrible movie that needs to be avoided. Rating: 2/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The 90's were not funny, they were stupid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Twetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just started watching my way through IMBDs bottom 100 and this definitely belongs there, I'm pretty sure it deserves to be higher up than number 99 too. I've seen a video review of this so I kind of knew what to expect but it turned out to be so much worse. The other two films from the list that I've seen so far were immensely boring because nothing ever happened in them. This one at least had some action in it but every single thing that happened was just stupid. Now, I can enjoy stupid movies; films that are so bad they become funny, this one though was painfully unfunny. On top of that, the film is in the mid 90's and the film makers make that abundantly clear with the way people dress and above all the horrible hip hop music playing throughout the film. It reminds me of all the bad things about the 90's and none of the good ones. By far the worst thing though is Kazaam himself who, despite being thousands of years old is hip, but not in a good way, and goes around rhyming every sentence he utters like some kind of idiotic hip hop artist. That Shaq can't rap doesn't exactly make it any better. This whole thing feels like a bad 90's music video - starring an untalented rapper - drawn out to a full length feature.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect example of a movie that I loved as a child, hate as an adult...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, adolescent really(19). Like Howard the Duck, Kazaam was a movie I loved as a child but looking back on it I was shocked at how low my taste buds were as a kid. Granted, there are some funny moments specifically the ones with the flying toasts and the bicycle race. And it is not the worst movie of 1996, Ed and especially Bio Dome are worse. However, the special effects are really quite substandard, and the rest of the production values are of direct to video quality and shoddy ones at that. The story is predictable with only a few worthwhile scenes to favour, the sight gags suffer from poor comic timing and the script is childish and simplistic. The characters I really dislike here, the kid is annoying, the villain is one of the lamest I have seen in a long time while Shaquille O'Neal's Genie with his awful rapping(then again I dislike rap intensely, and that is the least problematic of his performance) grated on me fast. The acting doesn't fare much better either, while the direction is literally non-existent and the soundtrack is only tolerable if on mute. This is of course my opinion, disagree all you want, I guess I just didn't like it. 2/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Lamps Should Be Permanently Sealed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yankcrime15
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This isn't as much of a film as it is a giant promotional campaign by Touchstone Pictures to market the NBA's worst free thrower with his extraordinary height. Not only is this obviously forever trapped in a time capsule set to 1996, but everything in this film is done so bad that it's completely laughable. If I had a handful of cardboard cutouts, they would be far more dimensional than any of the people that acted in this film. It's obvious that Shaq not only fails at free throws, rapping and being a video game character, but his acting is absolutely dreadful. He's a "rapping" (actually a RHYMING) genie that moved into a boombox and is summoned when a boy named Max (played by a young Francis Capra) stumbles upon him after being chased by bullies. Throughout the movie, Shaq becomes a subject of slavery as Max owns him until his three wishes are granted. That's pretty much the whole plot, unless you're actually going to include a meaningless subplot about "finding the true father". It doesn't get any better from there. Shaq demonstrates his mad rapping skills by appearing at a night club where he becomes a selected guest. Guess how fast Theodor Geisel was spinning in his grave when he brought forth the detestable line of "Let's green egg and ham it!" Probably around the same speed that would also be brought forth by those two live action adaptations that shall not be named. Then there's some phenomenal acting. I'm talking about the magical french toast. That performance was far more convincing than anything you could expect Shaq to give us. Too bad this film killed its career. Speaking of career killers, ever noticed what happened to Paul Michael Glaser after he directed this film? It's a long story. Granted, it's not one of THE worst things I have ever seen, but it's very close. Kazaam is proof that pitching a non actor as a main character usually does not give satisfactory results. With all this time wasted in the production of this film, I bet Shaq could have gotten some more practice at free throws. The most shocking thing about this? Shaq actually got ANOTHER lead role a year later, but that's a whole different story subject.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why would someone make a film with Shaq as a Genie?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Criticman12
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boy, this is one of the worst films I've seen. No wonder it's on IMDb's Bottom 100 list. I'll start off with the good parts: It did have some funny moments like the scene with the flying french toasts and the scene where Max and Kazaam are having a bicycle race. The bad parts: Everything else in this movie was boring and bad. Shaq as a genie is just plain awful. Beside's he can't even rap. In one scene, he's singing, "Let's Green Eggs and Ham it". Seriously? That's kinda like a 5-year old doing a rap song. The other character's weren't even that good. Max is annoying. The villain is not even that evil. Literally. Also, wasn't this suppose to be a family film? In one scene, Max say's, "So after my 2 last wishes, I own you?", then Kazaam say's, "Technically". Is it me, or is this film about slavery? Overall, "Kazaam", is an awful movie that's not even worth watching. But compare it to, "Batman and Robin", "Son of the Mask", or "Battlefield Earth", it's not that bad. So if you're looking for a good movie with a Genie in it, watch the Disney movie, "Aladdin". That film has a Genie that can sing and make you laugh. He is also voiced by Robin Williams. A "GOOD" actor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All hail Shaq.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gabrielle Phillips
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie Kazaam featuring the multi-talented Shaquille O'Neal should be the standard which all movies are held to. Since originally viewing this wonderful work of cinema 15 years ago, I can say it has definitely held up to the test of time. I've yet to see a movie that even comes close to achieving the depth of character, raw emotion, and beauty that Kazaam portrays. Shaq is definitely a triple threat -- basketball, acting, and singing, what's next!? I can't wait to see more from this truly awe-inspiring man. This film has definitely slid under the radar of Hollywood critics, which I see as a blessing. I'd hate for this movie to get wildly popular and lose its innocence. Once I have children of my own, this will be one of the few movies I allow them to watch since it preaches such good morals & values. If you're debating whether to watch this film or not -- DO IT! Your life will never be the same in the best way possible.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you see this film..... You're as stupid as me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheNewCritic
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So I'm aware that this film was released a fair while ago, but I've only just seen it; and not out of free will. I can some up this film in 1 word.... Shaq, the only "actor" who is more robotic than the Terminator. And really thats all that needs to be said, it's a stupid stupid movie that barely makes any sense, it's so uninteresting that I could feel myself getting stupider as I watched. If you see a copy of this film DESTROY IT, and then maybe one day the world will be ridden of this raping of cinema known as Kazaam 1/10 (and the only reason it scored that high is that i'm not allowed to give it a zero)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    People who hate on this must just hate life :D
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Bywater
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quite simply I want to say that this shouldn't be in the bottom 100 movies as voted by the users of IMDb. It is a great heart warming movie, perfect for the whole family. There are many many many other movies out there so much worse than this movie. It made me laugh and that's exactly what a good comedy should do. This movie was hilarious! A rapping genie who knows kung fu and lives in a boom box played by none other than Shaquille O'Neal, what more could you want in a comedy?! I mean sure some of it was cringe worthy and it's not exactly Oscar material, but overall it was a great laugh. Anyone who wants to dis this movie needs to lighten up a little. Shaq has the greatest sense of humor!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you watch this, expect a strong feeling of loss and regret
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brianmckann
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie deserves no rating, and it's not for the reasons you'd think. It is a complete failure, but mostly because it got past common sense, Hollywood budgets, and directing standards. All because I believe Shaq threw enormous piles of money at it, and no one wanted to tell him this was the worst possible movie idea. Also take note that Shaq raises his eyebrows every other word he speaks. Some moments are only mildly painful, while others are clench your teeth, eye-squinting travesties. Most notably, the rap battle between the boy and Shaq, where they repeat "We ain't men, we genie." * Scowling at a piece of toast. * A boom box that shoots a shower of sparks * A grown man showering in front of a child * A rapping genie, that despite boasting his lyrical skills, always starts every rhyme with "I am Kazaam" * More than an hour of your life wasted These are what you have to look forward to in watching this. I'm troubled that anyone thought this would make money, or legitimize Shaq's rapping career in the minds of children. If you have a choice between sitting in gridlock traffic for 9 hours, 10 straight hours of oral surgery or watching Kazaam, Kazaam wins by a slight margin. There's no more positive endorsement I can give.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is One Genie You Don't Want Three Wishes From
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony-rigoni
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We're all familiar with genies in Middle Eastern mythologies. They could be in lamps like Aladdin or in bottles like I Dream of Jeannie. But never, and I repeat never, have I heard of genies coming out of boom boxes! Shaq O'Neil maybe a famous basketball player, but he's such a crappy actor! There are a lot of issues that should have been easily fixed in the first place. First, the acting. Is it me or did everybody woke up in the middle of the afternoon and decided to say "Huh, whatever. Not my movie, I'm not going to act today." Second, the songs. And yes, Shaq O'Neil raps his brains out. But his rapping and the songs are so bland, I keep thinking that the songs were written by the same people who created Bebe's Kids and Tom and Jerry the Movie. Third, the humor. What is the intended age to make stupid jokes like that, ages Born-11 months?! This is probably the same age range intended for Babygeniuses and Titanic: The Legend Goes On! And now, here's my rap for this movie: This piece of crap is oh so bad, it makes me positively mad! It makes me shout and swear and scream, I'd throw this movie down a stream. It's Stupid and Crappy, Tacky and Sappy, Horrendous and Hideous Despicable and Tedious! Don't watch this movie, it'll get you rabies and the humor is intended for babies! Kazaam's a sham and Shaq O'Neil is full of ham! Kazaam is bad and this movie makes me really mad! And it stinks a lot like doggy poo, I might as well be playing Shaq Fu! (PS, that video game sucks too) Enough Said.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An example of why Shag should go back to basketball
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never heard of this film before, but after looking at the Nostalgia Critic review of this abomination, I did see this movie and I permanently despise it, but it's not the worst movie ever made. There are two enjoyable scenes in this movie which includes the bike race sequence and the flying french toasts. However, those two scenes didn't exactly make this film worth watching. The special effects are quite substandard, the script is too childish and very simple, and the story is pretty predictable. The acting is the worst aspect of this film, especially Shag's acting (even his rapping is much worse) and the child actor is so annoying it would make you want to slap him in the face. Overall, not the worst compared to Batman and Robin, Garbage Pail Kids, and Battlefield Earth, but still a horrible movie that needs to be avoided. Rating: 2/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The 90's were not funny, they were stupid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Twetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just started watching my way through IMBDs bottom 100 and this definitely belongs there, I'm pretty sure it deserves to be higher up than number 99 too. I've seen a video review of this so I kind of knew what to expect but it turned out to be so much worse. The other two films from the list that I've seen so far were immensely boring because nothing ever happened in them. This one at least had some action in it but every single thing that happened was just stupid. Now, I can enjoy stupid movies; films that are so bad they become funny, this one though was painfully unfunny. On top of that, the film is in the mid 90's and the film makers make that abundantly clear with the way people dress and above all the horrible hip hop music playing throughout the film. It reminds me of all the bad things about the 90's and none of the good ones. By far the worst thing though is Kazaam himself who, despite being thousands of years old is hip, but not in a good way, and goes around rhyming every sentence he utters like some kind of idiotic hip hop artist. That Shaq can't rap doesn't exactly make it any better. This whole thing feels like a bad 90's music video - starring an untalented rapper - drawn out to a full length feature.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect example of a movie that I loved as a child, hate as an adult...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, adolescent really(19). Like Howard the Duck, Kazaam was a movie I loved as a child but looking back on it I was shocked at how low my taste buds were as a kid. Granted, there are some funny moments specifically the ones with the flying toasts and the bicycle race. And it is not the worst movie of 1996, Ed and especially Bio Dome are worse. However, the special effects are really quite substandard, and the rest of the production values are of direct to video quality and shoddy ones at that. The story is predictable with only a few worthwhile scenes to favour, the sight gags suffer from poor comic timing and the script is childish and simplistic. The characters I really dislike here, the kid is annoying, the villain is one of the lamest I have seen in a long time while Shaquille O'Neal's Genie with his awful rapping(then again I dislike rap intensely, and that is the least problematic of his performance) grated on me fast. The acting doesn't fare much better either, while the direction is literally non-existent and the soundtrack is only tolerable if on mute. This is of course my opinion, disagree all you want, I guess I just didn't like it. 2/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Lamps Should Be Permanently Sealed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yankcrime15
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This isn't as much of a film as it is a giant promotional campaign by Touchstone Pictures to market the NBA's worst free thrower with his extraordinary height. Not only is this obviously forever trapped in a time capsule set to 1996, but everything in this film is done so bad that it's completely laughable. If I had a handful of cardboard cutouts, they would be far more dimensional than any of the people that acted in this film. It's obvious that Shaq not only fails at free throws, rapping and being a video game character, but his acting is absolutely dreadful. He's a "rapping" (actually a RHYMING) genie that moved into a boombox and is summoned when a boy named Max (played by a young Francis Capra) stumbles upon him after being chased by bullies. Throughout the movie, Shaq becomes a subject of slavery as Max owns him until his three wishes are granted. That's pretty much the whole plot, unless you're actually going to include a meaningless subplot about "finding the true father". It doesn't get any better from there. Shaq demonstrates his mad rapping skills by appearing at a night club where he becomes a selected guest. Guess how fast Theodor Geisel was spinning in his grave when he brought forth the detestable line of "Let's green egg and ham it!" Probably around the same speed that would also be brought forth by those two live action adaptations that shall not be named. Then there's some phenomenal acting. I'm talking about the magical french toast. That performance was far more convincing than anything you could expect Shaq to give us. Too bad this film killed its career. Speaking of career killers, ever noticed what happened to Paul Michael Glaser after he directed this film? It's a long story. Granted, it's not one of THE worst things I have ever seen, but it's very close. Kazaam is proof that pitching a non actor as a main character usually does not give satisfactory results. With all this time wasted in the production of this film, I bet Shaq could have gotten some more practice at free throws. The most shocking thing about this? Shaq actually got ANOTHER lead role a year later, but that's a whole different story subject.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why would someone make a film with Shaq as a Genie?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Criticman12
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boy, this is one of the worst films I've seen. No wonder it's on IMDb's Bottom 100 list. I'll start off with the good parts: It did have some funny moments like the scene with the flying french toasts and the scene where Max and Kazaam are having a bicycle race. The bad parts: Everything else in this movie was boring and bad. Shaq as a genie is just plain awful. Beside's he can't even rap. In one scene, he's singing, "Let's Green Eggs and Ham it". Seriously? That's kinda like a 5-year old doing a rap song. The other character's weren't even that good. Max is annoying. The villain is not even that evil. Literally. Also, wasn't this suppose to be a family film? In one scene, Max say's, "So after my 2 last wishes, I own you?", then Kazaam say's, "Technically". Is it me, or is this film about slavery? Overall, "Kazaam", is an awful movie that's not even worth watching. But compare it to, "Batman and Robin", "Son of the Mask", or "Battlefield Earth", it's not that bad. So if you're looking for a good movie with a Genie in it, watch the Disney movie, "Aladdin". That film has a Genie that can sing and make you laugh. He is also voiced by Robin Williams. A "GOOD" actor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All hail Shaq.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gabrielle Phillips
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie Kazaam featuring the multi-talented Shaquille O'Neal should be the standard which all movies are held to. Since originally viewing this wonderful work of cinema 15 years ago, I can say it has definitely held up to the test of time. I've yet to see a movie that even comes close to achieving the depth of character, raw emotion, and beauty that Kazaam portrays. Shaq is definitely a triple threat -- basketball, acting, and singing, what's next!? I can't wait to see more from this truly awe-inspiring man. This film has definitely slid under the radar of Hollywood critics, which I see as a blessing. I'd hate for this movie to get wildly popular and lose its innocence. Once I have children of my own, this will be one of the few movies I allow them to watch since it preaches such good morals & values. If you're debating whether to watch this film or not -- DO IT! Your life will never be the same in the best way possible.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you see this film..... You're as stupid as me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheNewCritic
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So I'm aware that this film was released a fair while ago, but I've only just seen it; and not out of free will. I can some up this film in 1 word.... Shaq, the only "actor" who is more robotic than the Terminator. And really thats all that needs to be said, it's a stupid stupid movie that barely makes any sense, it's so uninteresting that I could feel myself getting stupider as I watched. If you see a copy of this film DESTROY IT, and then maybe one day the world will be ridden of this raping of cinema known as Kazaam 1/10 (and the only reason it scored that high is that i'm not allowed to give it a zero)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    People who hate on this must just hate life :D
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Bywater
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quite simply I want to say that this shouldn't be in the bottom 100 movies as voted by the users of IMDb. It is a great heart warming movie, perfect for the whole family. There are many many many other movies out there so much worse than this movie. It made me laugh and that's exactly what a good comedy should do. This movie was hilarious! A rapping genie who knows kung fu and lives in a boom box played by none other than Shaquille O'Neal, what more could you want in a comedy?! I mean sure some of it was cringe worthy and it's not exactly Oscar material, but overall it was a great laugh. Anyone who wants to dis this movie needs to lighten up a little. Shaq has the greatest sense of humor!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you watch this, expect a strong feeling of loss and regret
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brianmckann
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie deserves no rating, and it's not for the reasons you'd think. It is a complete failure, but mostly because it got past common sense, Hollywood budgets, and directing standards. All because I believe Shaq threw enormous piles of money at it, and no one wanted to tell him this was the worst possible movie idea. Also take note that Shaq raises his eyebrows every other word he speaks. Some moments are only mildly painful, while others are clench your teeth, eye-squinting travesties. Most notably, the rap battle between the boy and Shaq, where they repeat "We ain't men, we genie." * Scowling at a piece of toast. * A boom box that shoots a shower of sparks * A grown man showering in front of a child * A rapping genie, that despite boasting his lyrical skills, always starts every rhyme with "I am Kazaam" * More than an hour of your life wasted These are what you have to look forward to in watching this. I'm troubled that anyone thought this would make money, or legitimize Shaq's rapping career in the minds of children. If you have a choice between sitting in gridlock traffic for 9 hours, 10 straight hours of oral surgery or watching Kazaam, Kazaam wins by a slight margin. There's no more positive endorsement I can give.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is One Genie You Don't Want Three Wishes From
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony-rigoni
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We're all familiar with genies in Middle Eastern mythologies. They could be in lamps like Aladdin or in bottles like I Dream of Jeannie. But never, and I repeat never, have I heard of genies coming out of boom boxes! Shaq O'Neil maybe a famous basketball player, but he's such a crappy actor! There are a lot of issues that should have been easily fixed in the first place. First, the acting. Is it me or did everybody woke up in the middle of the afternoon and decided to say "Huh, whatever. Not my movie, I'm not going to act today." Second, the songs. And yes, Shaq O'Neil raps his brains out. But his rapping and the songs are so bland, I keep thinking that the songs were written by the same people who created Bebe's Kids and Tom and Jerry the Movie. Third, the humor. What is the intended age to make stupid jokes like that, ages Born-11 months?! This is probably the same age range intended for Babygeniuses and Titanic: The Legend Goes On! And now, here's my rap for this movie: This piece of crap is oh so bad, it makes me positively mad! It makes me shout and swear and scream, I'd throw this movie down a stream. It's Stupid and Crappy, Tacky and Sappy, Horrendous and Hideous Despicable and Tedious! Don't watch this movie, it'll get you rabies and the humor is intended for babies! Kazaam's a sham and Shaq O'Neil is full of ham! Kazaam is bad and this movie makes me really mad! And it stinks a lot like doggy poo, I might as well be playing Shaq Fu! (PS, that video game sucks too) Enough Said.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An example of why Shag should go back to basketball
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never heard of this film before, but after looking at the Nostalgia Critic review of this abomination, I did see this movie and I permanently despise it, but it's not the worst movie ever made. There are two enjoyable scenes in this movie which includes the bike race sequence and the flying french toasts. However, those two scenes didn't exactly make this film worth watching. The special effects are quite substandard, the script is too childish and very simple, and the story is pretty predictable. The acting is the worst aspect of this film, especially Shag's acting (even his rapping is much worse) and the child actor is so annoying it would make you want to slap him in the face. Overall, not the worst compared to Batman and Robin, Garbage Pail Kids, and Battlefield Earth, but still a horrible movie that needs to be avoided. Rating: 2/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The 90's were not funny, they were stupid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Twetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just started watching my way through IMBDs bottom 100 and this definitely belongs there, I'm pretty sure it deserves to be higher up than number 99 too. I've seen a video review of this so I kind of knew what to expect but it turned out to be so much worse. The other two films from the list that I've seen so far were immensely boring because nothing ever happened in them. This one at least had some action in it but every single thing that happened was just stupid. Now, I can enjoy stupid movies; films that are so bad they become funny, this one though was painfully unfunny. On top of that, the film is in the mid 90's and the film makers make that abundantly clear with the way people dress and above all the horrible hip hop music playing throughout the film. It reminds me of all the bad things about the 90's and none of the good ones. By far the worst thing though is Kazaam himself who, despite being thousands of years old is hip, but not in a good way, and goes around rhyming every sentence he utters like some kind of idiotic hip hop artist. That Shaq can't rap doesn't exactly make it any better. This whole thing feels like a bad 90's music video - starring an untalented rapper - drawn out to a full length feature.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect example of a movie that I loved as a child, hate as an adult...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, adolescent really(19). Like Howard the Duck, Kazaam was a movie I loved as a child but looking back on it I was shocked at how low my taste buds were as a kid. Granted, there are some funny moments specifically the ones with the flying toasts and the bicycle race. And it is not the worst movie of 1996, Ed and especially Bio Dome are worse. However, the special effects are really quite substandard, and the rest of the production values are of direct to video quality and shoddy ones at that. The story is predictable with only a few worthwhile scenes to favour, the sight gags suffer from poor comic timing and the script is childish and simplistic. The characters I really dislike here, the kid is annoying, the villain is one of the lamest I have seen in a long time while Shaquille O'Neal's Genie with his awful rapping(then again I dislike rap intensely, and that is the least problematic of his performance) grated on me fast. The acting doesn't fare much better either, while the direction is literally non-existent and the soundtrack is only tolerable if on mute. This is of course my opinion, disagree all you want, I guess I just didn't like it. 2/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Lamps Should Be Permanently Sealed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yankcrime15
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This isn't as much of a film as it is a giant promotional campaign by Touchstone Pictures to market the NBA's worst free thrower with his extraordinary height. Not only is this obviously forever trapped in a time capsule set to 1996, but everything in this film is done so bad that it's completely laughable. If I had a handful of cardboard cutouts, they would be far more dimensional than any of the people that acted in this film. It's obvious that Shaq not only fails at free throws, rapping and being a video game character, but his acting is absolutely dreadful. He's a "rapping" (actually a RHYMING) genie that moved into a boombox and is summoned when a boy named Max (played by a young Francis Capra) stumbles upon him after being chased by bullies. Throughout the movie, Shaq becomes a subject of slavery as Max owns him until his three wishes are granted. That's pretty much the whole plot, unless you're actually going to include a meaningless subplot about "finding the true father". It doesn't get any better from there. Shaq demonstrates his mad rapping skills by appearing at a night club where he becomes a selected guest. Guess how fast Theodor Geisel was spinning in his grave when he brought forth the detestable line of "Let's green egg and ham it!" Probably around the same speed that would also be brought forth by those two live action adaptations that shall not be named. Then there's some phenomenal acting. I'm talking about the magical french toast. That performance was far more convincing than anything you could expect Shaq to give us. Too bad this film killed its career. Speaking of career killers, ever noticed what happened to Paul Michael Glaser after he directed this film? It's a long story. Granted, it's not one of THE worst things I have ever seen, but it's very close. Kazaam is proof that pitching a non actor as a main character usually does not give satisfactory results. With all this time wasted in the production of this film, I bet Shaq could have gotten some more practice at free throws. The most shocking thing about this? Shaq actually got ANOTHER lead role a year later, but that's a whole different story subject.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why would someone make a film with Shaq as a Genie?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Criticman12
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boy, this is one of the worst films I've seen. No wonder it's on IMDb's Bottom 100 list. I'll start off with the good parts: It did have some funny moments like the scene with the flying french toasts and the scene where Max and Kazaam are having a bicycle race. The bad parts: Everything else in this movie was boring and bad. Shaq as a genie is just plain awful. Beside's he can't even rap. In one scene, he's singing, "Let's Green Eggs and Ham it". Seriously? That's kinda like a 5-year old doing a rap song. The other character's weren't even that good. Max is annoying. The villain is not even that evil. Literally. Also, wasn't this suppose to be a family film? In one scene, Max say's, "So after my 2 last wishes, I own you?", then Kazaam say's, "Technically". Is it me, or is this film about slavery? Overall, "Kazaam", is an awful movie that's not even worth watching. But compare it to, "Batman and Robin", "Son of the Mask", or "Battlefield Earth", it's not that bad. So if you're looking for a good movie with a Genie in it, watch the Disney movie, "Aladdin". That film has a Genie that can sing and make you laugh. He is also voiced by Robin Williams. A "GOOD" actor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All hail Shaq.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gabrielle Phillips
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie Kazaam featuring the multi-talented Shaquille O'Neal should be the standard which all movies are held to. Since originally viewing this wonderful work of cinema 15 years ago, I can say it has definitely held up to the test of time. I've yet to see a movie that even comes close to achieving the depth of character, raw emotion, and beauty that Kazaam portrays. Shaq is definitely a triple threat -- basketball, acting, and singing, what's next!? I can't wait to see more from this truly awe-inspiring man. This film has definitely slid under the radar of Hollywood critics, which I see as a blessing. I'd hate for this movie to get wildly popular and lose its innocence. Once I have children of my own, this will be one of the few movies I allow them to watch since it preaches such good morals & values. If you're debating whether to watch this film or not -- DO IT! Your life will never be the same in the best way possible.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you see this film..... You're as stupid as me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheNewCritic
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So I'm aware that this film was released a fair while ago, but I've only just seen it; and not out of free will. I can some up this film in 1 word.... Shaq, the only "actor" who is more robotic than the Terminator. And really thats all that needs to be said, it's a stupid stupid movie that barely makes any sense, it's so uninteresting that I could feel myself getting stupider as I watched. If you see a copy of this film DESTROY IT, and then maybe one day the world will be ridden of this raping of cinema known as Kazaam 1/10 (and the only reason it scored that high is that i'm not allowed to give it a zero)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    People who hate on this must just hate life :D
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Bywater
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quite simply I want to say that this shouldn't be in the bottom 100 movies as voted by the users of IMDb. It is a great heart warming movie, perfect for the whole family. There are many many many other movies out there so much worse than this movie. It made me laugh and that's exactly what a good comedy should do. This movie was hilarious! A rapping genie who knows kung fu and lives in a boom box played by none other than Shaquille O'Neal, what more could you want in a comedy?! I mean sure some of it was cringe worthy and it's not exactly Oscar material, but overall it was a great laugh. Anyone who wants to dis this movie needs to lighten up a little. Shaq has the greatest sense of humor!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
