<filme>
 <id>
  1340
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112746
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  The Crude Oasis
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Lonely Kansas housewife Karen Webb despondent about her love life, her husband Jim Webb coldness and philandering, has a strong urge to change her future. Karen discovers the truth about ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Lonely Kansas housewife Karen Webb despondent about her love life, her husband Jim Webb coldness and philandering, has a strong urge to change her future. Karen discovers the truth about Jim and sets out to commit suicide by carbon monoxide poisoning in her garage, but her three dollar daily allowance for gasoline runs out before she expires. During one of her gas station refills, she spots a different type who catches her fancy in Harley Underwood and sets her sights on him.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   kansas
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   gas station
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   garage
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   dancer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   cheating husband
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Alex Graves
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Alex Graves
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jennifer Taylor
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Aaron Shields
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Robert Peterson
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loose Plot Great Directing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kindras_flame
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this film really early in the morning randomly when I was ill, the eerie atmosphere of the movie instantly pulled me in and although the plot was loose and it was hard to follow the art direction and acting kept me hooked. The plot was a bit strange and when it finished I still wasn't sure what the plot was however the film was more about what wasn't being said rather than what was, creating a thick atmospheric intensity that some modern films find hard to capture. Although low budget and obviously unknown the film left me with a haunting feeling and Im glad I watched it. The direction was really interesting and the acting of Aaron Stiles was really intense, if you come across this film watch it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Haunting, odd
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paul2001sw-1 (paul2001sw@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 'Crude Oasis' is an odd, haunting film about a lonely woman living in one of America's oil states. Throughout, the movie continually hints that a thriller, maybe even supernatural in origin, is about to explode; but contents itself with hints and resolves its issues in an understated, believable way. Slightly stylised and highly atmospheric, the film proves that you don't need monsters and murderers to actually construct what is in places a seriously scary story; but it is a bit a slow in places. Not a great film, it's still an interesting one: it's strange that director Alex Graves has made no more movies, and has hereafter worked only on television series, albeit much better known than this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    my thinking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    furby-sweet
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie delivered some thought provoking messages to me. Foremost was "How to maintain a long term marriage relationship," Secondly, "That religion is, or should be, important for the human race," And last, but not least, "How can we prevent our environment from suffering the ravages of air and water pollution"? And, upon Mike&furby reflection, we think sometimes that a change of venue might help us change our otherwise dull and unhappy lives. Perhaps a visit to different places and people might encourage our thoughts and efforts toward the messages delivered by the movie. I have directed my personal dislike toward that husband who constantly treats Karen like a servant or baby toy. He apparently grows quickly tired and weary of her constant presence around him. It would appear that the marriage has long lost its magic for this man. I have assumed that this man has a greater IQ than his wife. If indeed he has the greater IQ then one wonders why he does not infuse the marriage with interesting and diversified moments of enjoyment and stimulating events. Surely his wife would respond in kind to such moments of tenderness, caring, and affection. Another actor named Harry has been alone for many years since his wife died of a psychotic disease. Apparently, Harry wants to live in the past recalling those moments he shared with his wife. He remembers she once asked him to accompany her to church, and the time she asked they should go out and enjoy the natural surroundings. He recalls however that he would always find an excuse not to be with her. Unfortunately, this caused the wife much anguish and rejection. In the end, the wife has lost her desire and love for Harry. The marriage had decayed to such an extent that the wife quickly succumbed to her psychotic condition and died. By God&iexcl;&brvbar;s hands, two unhappy and alone people from seeing each other in that unknown dream until hugging each other in a special place of natural wonders in this world. They only gained the temporary pleasure, so in the end, they are still separate. I think they should had known each other before their first time marriage,but most of important is they should love God in advance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quirky, involving movie ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dwpollar
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1st watched 10/8/1999 - 6 out of 10(Dir-Alex Graves): Quirky, involving movie that follows the life of an unhappy married woman without a child.The director only hints at where the story is going which is most of the fun with following this movie.Slow moving at first but the uncertainty keeps you interested.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
