<filme>
 <id>
  135
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0062622
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1968
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  2001 - Uma Odiss&eacute;ia no Espa&ccedil;o
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Humanity finds a mysterious, obviously artificial, object buried beneath the Lunar surface and, with the intelligent computer H.A.L. 9000, sets off on a quest.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  "2001" is a story of evolution. Sometime in the distant past, someone or something nudged evolution by placing a monolith on Earth (presumably elsewhere throughout the universe as well). Evolution then enabled humankind to reach the moon's surface, where yet another monolith is found, one that signals the monolith placers that humankind has evolved that far. Now a race begins between computers (HAL) and human (Bowman) to reach the monolith placers. The winner will achieve the next step in evolution, whatever that may be.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Mystery
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   monolith
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   computer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   evolution
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   moon
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   astronaut
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Stanley Kubrick
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Stanley Kubrick
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Arthur C. Clarke
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Keir Dullea
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Gary Lockwood
  </ator>
  <ator>
   William Sylvester
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cannot be described
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    krustykrabpizza
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    2001: A Space Odyssey is like music. How do you tell someone that you like this movie? It's difficult, but to put it plainly, you can't. You just watch it. Listen to it. I was confused as to why I loved this movie so much even directly after the end credits began to roll, the story was quite confusing and there was a 20-minute scene at the start where monkeys were just being observed in a voyeuristic manner. It sounds like I'm appealing to a "certain intelligence" and I really don't like that, but it truly is a marvel that transcends language and all logical constructs. Don't read the reviews for this movie if you haven't seen it, just watch it. It's an experience that can only be unraveled from a personal point of view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated waste of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eumarius_89
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my first review. I didn't like this movie and i am seriously mad that i spent almost three hours of my life watching this. Of course that there will be some people who don't agree with me. Why i hate it so much: -Very very very slow paced, made me fall asleep a few times -I didn't understand the plot, maybe because i haven't read the book, but a movie shouldn't be made just for the people who read the book -Boring -Very little action -Very little character development -NO ENTERTAINMENT The ending was very complex and very boring. Maybe this is not the most objective review but i hope it will be useful for some to avoid making the same mistake i did. I normally don't feel this mad after watching a bad movie but this is so overrated, i just want people to realize it's not worth watching. My vote 1/10, i feel sorry for wasting my time with this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film-Strange author
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jam77-549-49835
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the three greatest movies of all time,I know it's a a.c Clarke(and we all know what that guys about) But if you get past that it has to be said that the sheer originality and breathtaking cinematography is enough of a reason to love this movie but the story builds to an absolute blow ya head off jaw dropping finale. There are times when you will be confused but later (much later for me) all will become clear. If Sci-Fi is your thing then this is your movie if not then this is still your movie, if you're going to trust any review then let it be this one. Everyone should see this film at least once believe me you will not regret it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dazzling Masterpiece.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stanley Kubrick's visually dazzling, intellectually stimulating and ambitious film makes one of the best uses of the medium known as cinema ever made. Film begins when humans were still apes, and how, when one of them touches a huge, mysterious monolith, he is pushed forward in evolution, and uses an old bone as a tool(to smash and kill of course...) Thousands of years later, man is now on the moon, and another monolith is uncovered, inspiring a spaceship crew to investigate, causing the on board ship computer HAL9000 to malfunction(sensing the oncoming next evolution it cannot experience?) One astronaut enters the monolith, and he(and the viewer) see an astonishing, even overwhelming assault on the senses that leads to... Well, for those who haven't seen it, no spoilers, but just consider how a "star child" fits in at the end... A unique achievement in film history, not to be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chrisborg1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw 2001: A Space Odyssey and I was blown away by the effects, the characters, and story. Now, when you see this movie you may not get it at first (I did not) but you have to think about it. This movie's story telling method is very different compared to nowadays but, I guess that's what makes it special. And in my opinion this is Kubrick's best film (but all of them are great) I think that when someone sees this they may dismiss it and say "this movie is so slow" which yes it may be slow but Kubrick did it that way so you could marvel at the terrific detail of the sets and all the little details that make the future so amazing. An amazing movie and great visual effects too: 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need the right mind set
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Martin
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First let me introduce myself, I am a 21 year old boy from the UK. I have very mixed reviews about this film, and am sure I am not the only one. I do not believe this to be a marmite film as most of the reviews suggest. I can and do see this from the point of view of both parties, seeing it as a boring waste of time and seeing it as sci-fi/cinematic history. I do agree, the story line is very scarce. There isn't that much happens, and when it does it is over before you even realise its begun. There is a lot of slow, boring and un-necessarily long clips of pretty much nothing; ships/people floating around, someone running, a phone call, a conversation that offers very little to the plot. I am not a troglodyte as some of the lovers of this film may be starting to think. I understand why it is included and done the way it is, but that doesn't stop it from being incredibly boring. However, to see this from a positive point of view, one must remember that this was made in the mid-to-late 1960's. Meaning that everything done in this was done for real, rather than CGI as everything is now. For this reason I don't feel that it can be put in the same class as modern sci-fi films. I sadly have not read the book of this, I have just decided to watch the film because my friend likes to quote it to me and I wanted to see what she was going on about. This left me very skeptical when I started watching, especially as seemingly nothing was actually happening. You really do have to keep watching and thinking about what it is actually depicting. A large amount of the themes and science fiction ideas were depicted on screen for the first time in this film and is therefore giving a visual insight into what mankind has predicted the future will be like and it is remarkable how much they have actually gotten right for what we have already accomplished and what we are still working on. A lot of the ideas in this film are still being copied to this day, and has now actually got me questioning Ridley Scott's work. I am not saying that Scott has copied Kubrick, just that some of the praises Scott has received shouldn't really be given solely to him for his work in the sci-fi genre. Kubrick has managed to show to the world the realism of space. We all watch films these days and like to point out, "that couldn't happen", "that would never happen", etc. etc. That is the reason behind all the slow and uneventful scenes, it is being kept to a realistic standard of how it would actually have to happen and to show you how slow a long space trip like that would actually be. The shots of space exploration also show demonstrations of the physical properties of our universe and how things actually happen. So, to conclude. Although this may not be an exciting, eventful or thrilling film, it is certainly a feat of cinematography. It more depicts the realistic side of sci-fi rather than the laser guns and phasers of popular sci-fi shows. So if you are looking for a fast paced, action sci-fi, then this isn't for you. If you more enjoy the technological/engineering side of themes like this, then it is right up your street. Just bare this in mind, be in the right mind set when you sit down to watch it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You're Left Confused...but Satisfied
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Juan Mendoza
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is definitely a film that you come back to watch again for two reasons: 1) You're not immediately sure you understood what happened, and 2) You are left feeling mentally/philosophically engaged. To be straight, you should know going into this film that you should have an eye for subtleties and symbolism, and above all, an open mind. From the onset, you can tell that the director is not going to attempt to appeal to the audience with fast paced action, explosions, etc. but rather with direct mental stimulation. You watch this film with a similar manner to that of an obscure yet significant painting, because the themes that are presented to you feel epic, and they are left open for interpretation; the lack of dialogue in favor of eerie music helps. However, even through all of the confusion, and tense mood, you also know you are watching something beautiful. With a few minor exceptions, the screenplay feels like it is consistently appealing to the eye in a simple nature. And when it does change into more flashy and complex imagery, your eyes seem to welcome it. I wouldn't say it is in my personal favorite films, but either way I am still thinking about it weeks after having watched it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A picture of a soup can is not art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    royu2
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If art has to be explained, it's not art, if you have ask "er, is that art?", it's not art. Art speaks for itself, that's the whole point of art, it is a self-reviewing piece of work that needs no further investigation. Art and fashion are not the same thing, they are in fact polar opposites. Fashion is a popularly contest and it's existence forever lives on borrowed time and the approval of others. Art is fundamentally timeless. Fashion requires an accepting audience to exist, art does not. I know a lot of artists, half my family consider themselves "artists". What amazes me is that it seems the deeper into "art" they get the more the lines are blurred between art and fashion. Fashion is NOT art. 2001 A Space Odyssey is fashion, it does not stand on it's own two feet as art, because it isn't. It must be explained, which by default makes it not art, but fashion. A picture of a soup can being worth millions of dollars can only be explained through the prism of fashion. This movie really is as terrible and pointless as a picture of a soup can. The only people that think this is art are people who don't understand that art and fashion are two very different things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visually stunning.Kubrick's best work.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those films that make me wish I had been around to see it on the big screen.I envy those that got that opportunity,because as visually stunning as it is on the small screen,it had to be 100 times so in the theater.The orchestral arrangements during space sequences were the best possible soundtrack for what would be a silent visual in reality.The other visual effect,such as those inside the space craft look to be way ahead of their time.As for the story,it plays just like a thriller as we have a great man vs. machine angle.Of all the Stanley Kubrick films I have viewed to date.This visually stunning production is by far the best.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Unprecedented, Unique & Unparalleled Achievement In Motion Picture History.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An unprecedented, unique & unparalleled achievement in motion picture history, 2001: A Space Odyssey is a path-breaking cinema and a splendid work of art. Far ahead of its time and universally & unanimously hailed as one of the greatest & most influential films ever made, this film redefines its genre unlike anything before or after it, features some of the most iconic moments ever captured on film, and is an elegant mix of remarkable cinematography, pioneering visual & sound effects, scientific accuracy, epic score & a distinct style of narration. Not only is 2001: A Space Odyssey a visually spellbinding experience filmed with great artistry but also, in my opinion, Stanley Kubrick's magnum opus. 2001: A Space Odyssey deals with the elements of human evolution, technology, artificial intelligence & extra-terrestrial life. It is divided into 3 segments & an epilogue, each connected with an extra-terrestrial reference. The movie begins with the Dawn of Man segment set in prehistoric Africa, where a group of primitive apes discover a mysterious black monolith which eventually alters their course of evolution. The movie then takes a giant leap into the future, the year 2001, when another monolith is discovered on moon. The film then approaches its third segment where the main plot finally surfaces aboard a spaceship on its mission to Jupiter, which later culminates with an ambiguous ending that's debatable to this date. Stanley Kubrick is one of cinema's most influential & innovative directors, with a legacy that, arguably, has no equals. 2001: A Space Odyssey is Kubrick's first venture into the science fiction genre where he ended up crafting a cinematic jewel that's one of the first to take its genre seriously. Putting science in science-fiction, this masterpiece by Kubrick is as mysterious as the man himself and although all the usual Kubrick's trademarks exist in the film, the entire treatment is very different from other films of his or even others. The pace is intentionally slowed down, the narration is through visuals & music, the performances are honest, the exchange of dialogues is minimal and the plot is engaging & confusing at the same time but gets better, more transparent & satisfying on multiple viewings. Coming to technical aspects, this film is an incredible work of breathtaking art. The cinematography is a delight for everyone who appreciates great photography. The beautiful captures of landscapes and jaw-dropping exploration of the space (most notably The Moon) makes it one of the finest works that cinema has to offer. Editing is precisely done. Set pieces are wonderful to look at and the visual & sound effects are so groundbreaking & ahead of its time that many movies boasting CGI stuff today are still no match to it. Also, it is one of the most accurate depiction of space travel & the silence that fills the space scenes not only serves its purpose as accurate science, but also adds to the mood of the film. The fact that Kubrick shot the moon scenes with that level of detail & accuracy even before the Apollo landing never fails to impress. Even though 2001 is a visual ride of astonishing beauty, it isn't a movie that everyone is going to appreciate. It's a long technical film that runs at an unusually slow pace, is full of metaphysical complexities and is destined to polarize viewers. Even though some will find it incredibly boring & a strong test of their patience, there will be many who will end up being completely engulfed by its sheer beauty and an unusual blend of poetry & mystery in its bizarre plot. It has inspired almost every film of its genre since its release and will continue to do so for as long as cinema exists. Because after all, this is the film that started it all and deserves to be seen by everyone who appreciates great cinema, especially the fans of Kubrick & science-fiction genre. It's an amazing journey through space & time that raises pretty good questions about our very own existence, is full of philosophical & allegorical meanings, and concludes with an ending that is open for each viewer to interpret his/her way. Overall, what impressed me the most about this film is its impressive detailing in every frame, captivating photography, dazzling visuals & great characterization of the Discovery One spaceship's computer HAL 9000, where Kubrick examines the idea of machines turning against the very people they were meant to serve, decades before James Cameron came up with The Terminator or Wachowski Bros. crafted the next big sci-fi leap with The Matrix. Scoring full marks in all aspects of filmmaking and influencing not only cinema but science, culture & art as well, 2001: A Space Odyssey is a landmark moment in motion picture history that almost killed its genre for it set a standard so high that it hasn't been equaled or challenged ever since. Advancements in science & technology may have brought few films closer to it on a technical scale but overall, it remains a superior film & a pinnacle of science-fiction filmmaking and is possibly the best work from a legendary filmmaker who had made a career out of crafting one masterpiece after another. Highly recommended. Multiple viewings advised.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cannot be described
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    krustykrabpizza
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    2001: A Space Odyssey is like music. How do you tell someone that you like this movie? It's difficult, but to put it plainly, you can't. You just watch it. Listen to it. I was confused as to why I loved this movie so much even directly after the end credits began to roll, the story was quite confusing and there was a 20-minute scene at the start where monkeys were just being observed in a voyeuristic manner. It sounds like I'm appealing to a "certain intelligence" and I really don't like that, but it truly is a marvel that transcends language and all logical constructs. Don't read the reviews for this movie if you haven't seen it, just watch it. It's an experience that can only be unraveled from a personal point of view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated waste of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eumarius_89
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my first review. I didn't like this movie and i am seriously mad that i spent almost three hours of my life watching this. Of course that there will be some people who don't agree with me. Why i hate it so much: -Very very very slow paced, made me fall asleep a few times -I didn't understand the plot, maybe because i haven't read the book, but a movie shouldn't be made just for the people who read the book -Boring -Very little action -Very little character development -NO ENTERTAINMENT The ending was very complex and very boring. Maybe this is not the most objective review but i hope it will be useful for some to avoid making the same mistake i did. I normally don't feel this mad after watching a bad movie but this is so overrated, i just want people to realize it's not worth watching. My vote 1/10, i feel sorry for wasting my time with this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film-Strange author
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jam77-549-49835
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the three greatest movies of all time,I know it's a a.c Clarke(and we all know what that guys about) But if you get past that it has to be said that the sheer originality and breathtaking cinematography is enough of a reason to love this movie but the story builds to an absolute blow ya head off jaw dropping finale. There are times when you will be confused but later (much later for me) all will become clear. If Sci-Fi is your thing then this is your movie if not then this is still your movie, if you're going to trust any review then let it be this one. Everyone should see this film at least once believe me you will not regret it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dazzling Masterpiece.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stanley Kubrick's visually dazzling, intellectually stimulating and ambitious film makes one of the best uses of the medium known as cinema ever made. Film begins when humans were still apes, and how, when one of them touches a huge, mysterious monolith, he is pushed forward in evolution, and uses an old bone as a tool(to smash and kill of course...) Thousands of years later, man is now on the moon, and another monolith is uncovered, inspiring a spaceship crew to investigate, causing the on board ship computer HAL9000 to malfunction(sensing the oncoming next evolution it cannot experience?) One astronaut enters the monolith, and he(and the viewer) see an astonishing, even overwhelming assault on the senses that leads to... Well, for those who haven't seen it, no spoilers, but just consider how a "star child" fits in at the end... A unique achievement in film history, not to be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chrisborg1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw 2001: A Space Odyssey and I was blown away by the effects, the characters, and story. Now, when you see this movie you may not get it at first (I did not) but you have to think about it. This movie's story telling method is very different compared to nowadays but, I guess that's what makes it special. And in my opinion this is Kubrick's best film (but all of them are great) I think that when someone sees this they may dismiss it and say "this movie is so slow" which yes it may be slow but Kubrick did it that way so you could marvel at the terrific detail of the sets and all the little details that make the future so amazing. An amazing movie and great visual effects too: 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need the right mind set
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Martin
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First let me introduce myself, I am a 21 year old boy from the UK. I have very mixed reviews about this film, and am sure I am not the only one. I do not believe this to be a marmite film as most of the reviews suggest. I can and do see this from the point of view of both parties, seeing it as a boring waste of time and seeing it as sci-fi/cinematic history. I do agree, the story line is very scarce. There isn't that much happens, and when it does it is over before you even realise its begun. There is a lot of slow, boring and un-necessarily long clips of pretty much nothing; ships/people floating around, someone running, a phone call, a conversation that offers very little to the plot. I am not a troglodyte as some of the lovers of this film may be starting to think. I understand why it is included and done the way it is, but that doesn't stop it from being incredibly boring. However, to see this from a positive point of view, one must remember that this was made in the mid-to-late 1960's. Meaning that everything done in this was done for real, rather than CGI as everything is now. For this reason I don't feel that it can be put in the same class as modern sci-fi films. I sadly have not read the book of this, I have just decided to watch the film because my friend likes to quote it to me and I wanted to see what she was going on about. This left me very skeptical when I started watching, especially as seemingly nothing was actually happening. You really do have to keep watching and thinking about what it is actually depicting. A large amount of the themes and science fiction ideas were depicted on screen for the first time in this film and is therefore giving a visual insight into what mankind has predicted the future will be like and it is remarkable how much they have actually gotten right for what we have already accomplished and what we are still working on. A lot of the ideas in this film are still being copied to this day, and has now actually got me questioning Ridley Scott's work. I am not saying that Scott has copied Kubrick, just that some of the praises Scott has received shouldn't really be given solely to him for his work in the sci-fi genre. Kubrick has managed to show to the world the realism of space. We all watch films these days and like to point out, "that couldn't happen", "that would never happen", etc. etc. That is the reason behind all the slow and uneventful scenes, it is being kept to a realistic standard of how it would actually have to happen and to show you how slow a long space trip like that would actually be. The shots of space exploration also show demonstrations of the physical properties of our universe and how things actually happen. So, to conclude. Although this may not be an exciting, eventful or thrilling film, it is certainly a feat of cinematography. It more depicts the realistic side of sci-fi rather than the laser guns and phasers of popular sci-fi shows. So if you are looking for a fast paced, action sci-fi, then this isn't for you. If you more enjoy the technological/engineering side of themes like this, then it is right up your street. Just bare this in mind, be in the right mind set when you sit down to watch it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You're Left Confused...but Satisfied
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Juan Mendoza
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is definitely a film that you come back to watch again for two reasons: 1) You're not immediately sure you understood what happened, and 2) You are left feeling mentally/philosophically engaged. To be straight, you should know going into this film that you should have an eye for subtleties and symbolism, and above all, an open mind. From the onset, you can tell that the director is not going to attempt to appeal to the audience with fast paced action, explosions, etc. but rather with direct mental stimulation. You watch this film with a similar manner to that of an obscure yet significant painting, because the themes that are presented to you feel epic, and they are left open for interpretation; the lack of dialogue in favor of eerie music helps. However, even through all of the confusion, and tense mood, you also know you are watching something beautiful. With a few minor exceptions, the screenplay feels like it is consistently appealing to the eye in a simple nature. And when it does change into more flashy and complex imagery, your eyes seem to welcome it. I wouldn't say it is in my personal favorite films, but either way I am still thinking about it weeks after having watched it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A picture of a soup can is not art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    royu2
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If art has to be explained, it's not art, if you have ask "er, is that art?", it's not art. Art speaks for itself, that's the whole point of art, it is a self-reviewing piece of work that needs no further investigation. Art and fashion are not the same thing, they are in fact polar opposites. Fashion is a popularly contest and it's existence forever lives on borrowed time and the approval of others. Art is fundamentally timeless. Fashion requires an accepting audience to exist, art does not. I know a lot of artists, half my family consider themselves "artists". What amazes me is that it seems the deeper into "art" they get the more the lines are blurred between art and fashion. Fashion is NOT art. 2001 A Space Odyssey is fashion, it does not stand on it's own two feet as art, because it isn't. It must be explained, which by default makes it not art, but fashion. A picture of a soup can being worth millions of dollars can only be explained through the prism of fashion. This movie really is as terrible and pointless as a picture of a soup can. The only people that think this is art are people who don't understand that art and fashion are two very different things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visually stunning.Kubrick's best work.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those films that make me wish I had been around to see it on the big screen.I envy those that got that opportunity,because as visually stunning as it is on the small screen,it had to be 100 times so in the theater.The orchestral arrangements during space sequences were the best possible soundtrack for what would be a silent visual in reality.The other visual effect,such as those inside the space craft look to be way ahead of their time.As for the story,it plays just like a thriller as we have a great man vs. machine angle.Of all the Stanley Kubrick films I have viewed to date.This visually stunning production is by far the best.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Unprecedented, Unique & Unparalleled Achievement In Motion Picture History.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An unprecedented, unique & unparalleled achievement in motion picture history, 2001: A Space Odyssey is a path-breaking cinema and a splendid work of art. Far ahead of its time and universally & unanimously hailed as one of the greatest & most influential films ever made, this film redefines its genre unlike anything before or after it, features some of the most iconic moments ever captured on film, and is an elegant mix of remarkable cinematography, pioneering visual & sound effects, scientific accuracy, epic score & a distinct style of narration. Not only is 2001: A Space Odyssey a visually spellbinding experience filmed with great artistry but also, in my opinion, Stanley Kubrick's magnum opus. 2001: A Space Odyssey deals with the elements of human evolution, technology, artificial intelligence & extra-terrestrial life. It is divided into 3 segments & an epilogue, each connected with an extra-terrestrial reference. The movie begins with the Dawn of Man segment set in prehistoric Africa, where a group of primitive apes discover a mysterious black monolith which eventually alters their course of evolution. The movie then takes a giant leap into the future, the year 2001, when another monolith is discovered on moon. The film then approaches its third segment where the main plot finally surfaces aboard a spaceship on its mission to Jupiter, which later culminates with an ambiguous ending that's debatable to this date. Stanley Kubrick is one of cinema's most influential & innovative directors, with a legacy that, arguably, has no equals. 2001: A Space Odyssey is Kubrick's first venture into the science fiction genre where he ended up crafting a cinematic jewel that's one of the first to take its genre seriously. Putting science in science-fiction, this masterpiece by Kubrick is as mysterious as the man himself and although all the usual Kubrick's trademarks exist in the film, the entire treatment is very different from other films of his or even others. The pace is intentionally slowed down, the narration is through visuals & music, the performances are honest, the exchange of dialogues is minimal and the plot is engaging & confusing at the same time but gets better, more transparent & satisfying on multiple viewings. Coming to technical aspects, this film is an incredible work of breathtaking art. The cinematography is a delight for everyone who appreciates great photography. The beautiful captures of landscapes and jaw-dropping exploration of the space (most notably The Moon) makes it one of the finest works that cinema has to offer. Editing is precisely done. Set pieces are wonderful to look at and the visual & sound effects are so groundbreaking & ahead of its time that many movies boasting CGI stuff today are still no match to it. Also, it is one of the most accurate depiction of space travel & the silence that fills the space scenes not only serves its purpose as accurate science, but also adds to the mood of the film. The fact that Kubrick shot the moon scenes with that level of detail & accuracy even before the Apollo landing never fails to impress. Even though 2001 is a visual ride of astonishing beauty, it isn't a movie that everyone is going to appreciate. It's a long technical film that runs at an unusually slow pace, is full of metaphysical complexities and is destined to polarize viewers. Even though some will find it incredibly boring & a strong test of their patience, there will be many who will end up being completely engulfed by its sheer beauty and an unusual blend of poetry & mystery in its bizarre plot. It has inspired almost every film of its genre since its release and will continue to do so for as long as cinema exists. Because after all, this is the film that started it all and deserves to be seen by everyone who appreciates great cinema, especially the fans of Kubrick & science-fiction genre. It's an amazing journey through space & time that raises pretty good questions about our very own existence, is full of philosophical & allegorical meanings, and concludes with an ending that is open for each viewer to interpret his/her way. Overall, what impressed me the most about this film is its impressive detailing in every frame, captivating photography, dazzling visuals & great characterization of the Discovery One spaceship's computer HAL 9000, where Kubrick examines the idea of machines turning against the very people they were meant to serve, decades before James Cameron came up with The Terminator or Wachowski Bros. crafted the next big sci-fi leap with The Matrix. Scoring full marks in all aspects of filmmaking and influencing not only cinema but science, culture & art as well, 2001: A Space Odyssey is a landmark moment in motion picture history that almost killed its genre for it set a standard so high that it hasn't been equaled or challenged ever since. Advancements in science & technology may have brought few films closer to it on a technical scale but overall, it remains a superior film & a pinnacle of science-fiction filmmaking and is possibly the best work from a legendary filmmaker who had made a career out of crafting one masterpiece after another. Highly recommended. Multiple viewings advised.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cannot be described
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    krustykrabpizza
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    2001: A Space Odyssey is like music. How do you tell someone that you like this movie? It's difficult, but to put it plainly, you can't. You just watch it. Listen to it. I was confused as to why I loved this movie so much even directly after the end credits began to roll, the story was quite confusing and there was a 20-minute scene at the start where monkeys were just being observed in a voyeuristic manner. It sounds like I'm appealing to a "certain intelligence" and I really don't like that, but it truly is a marvel that transcends language and all logical constructs. Don't read the reviews for this movie if you haven't seen it, just watch it. It's an experience that can only be unraveled from a personal point of view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated waste of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eumarius_89
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my first review. I didn't like this movie and i am seriously mad that i spent almost three hours of my life watching this. Of course that there will be some people who don't agree with me. Why i hate it so much: -Very very very slow paced, made me fall asleep a few times -I didn't understand the plot, maybe because i haven't read the book, but a movie shouldn't be made just for the people who read the book -Boring -Very little action -Very little character development -NO ENTERTAINMENT The ending was very complex and very boring. Maybe this is not the most objective review but i hope it will be useful for some to avoid making the same mistake i did. I normally don't feel this mad after watching a bad movie but this is so overrated, i just want people to realize it's not worth watching. My vote 1/10, i feel sorry for wasting my time with this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film-Strange author
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jam77-549-49835
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the three greatest movies of all time,I know it's a a.c Clarke(and we all know what that guys about) But if you get past that it has to be said that the sheer originality and breathtaking cinematography is enough of a reason to love this movie but the story builds to an absolute blow ya head off jaw dropping finale. There are times when you will be confused but later (much later for me) all will become clear. If Sci-Fi is your thing then this is your movie if not then this is still your movie, if you're going to trust any review then let it be this one. Everyone should see this film at least once believe me you will not regret it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dazzling Masterpiece.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stanley Kubrick's visually dazzling, intellectually stimulating and ambitious film makes one of the best uses of the medium known as cinema ever made. Film begins when humans were still apes, and how, when one of them touches a huge, mysterious monolith, he is pushed forward in evolution, and uses an old bone as a tool(to smash and kill of course...) Thousands of years later, man is now on the moon, and another monolith is uncovered, inspiring a spaceship crew to investigate, causing the on board ship computer HAL9000 to malfunction(sensing the oncoming next evolution it cannot experience?) One astronaut enters the monolith, and he(and the viewer) see an astonishing, even overwhelming assault on the senses that leads to... Well, for those who haven't seen it, no spoilers, but just consider how a "star child" fits in at the end... A unique achievement in film history, not to be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chrisborg1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw 2001: A Space Odyssey and I was blown away by the effects, the characters, and story. Now, when you see this movie you may not get it at first (I did not) but you have to think about it. This movie's story telling method is very different compared to nowadays but, I guess that's what makes it special. And in my opinion this is Kubrick's best film (but all of them are great) I think that when someone sees this they may dismiss it and say "this movie is so slow" which yes it may be slow but Kubrick did it that way so you could marvel at the terrific detail of the sets and all the little details that make the future so amazing. An amazing movie and great visual effects too: 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need the right mind set
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Martin
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First let me introduce myself, I am a 21 year old boy from the UK. I have very mixed reviews about this film, and am sure I am not the only one. I do not believe this to be a marmite film as most of the reviews suggest. I can and do see this from the point of view of both parties, seeing it as a boring waste of time and seeing it as sci-fi/cinematic history. I do agree, the story line is very scarce. There isn't that much happens, and when it does it is over before you even realise its begun. There is a lot of slow, boring and un-necessarily long clips of pretty much nothing; ships/people floating around, someone running, a phone call, a conversation that offers very little to the plot. I am not a troglodyte as some of the lovers of this film may be starting to think. I understand why it is included and done the way it is, but that doesn't stop it from being incredibly boring. However, to see this from a positive point of view, one must remember that this was made in the mid-to-late 1960's. Meaning that everything done in this was done for real, rather than CGI as everything is now. For this reason I don't feel that it can be put in the same class as modern sci-fi films. I sadly have not read the book of this, I have just decided to watch the film because my friend likes to quote it to me and I wanted to see what she was going on about. This left me very skeptical when I started watching, especially as seemingly nothing was actually happening. You really do have to keep watching and thinking about what it is actually depicting. A large amount of the themes and science fiction ideas were depicted on screen for the first time in this film and is therefore giving a visual insight into what mankind has predicted the future will be like and it is remarkable how much they have actually gotten right for what we have already accomplished and what we are still working on. A lot of the ideas in this film are still being copied to this day, and has now actually got me questioning Ridley Scott's work. I am not saying that Scott has copied Kubrick, just that some of the praises Scott has received shouldn't really be given solely to him for his work in the sci-fi genre. Kubrick has managed to show to the world the realism of space. We all watch films these days and like to point out, "that couldn't happen", "that would never happen", etc. etc. That is the reason behind all the slow and uneventful scenes, it is being kept to a realistic standard of how it would actually have to happen and to show you how slow a long space trip like that would actually be. The shots of space exploration also show demonstrations of the physical properties of our universe and how things actually happen. So, to conclude. Although this may not be an exciting, eventful or thrilling film, it is certainly a feat of cinematography. It more depicts the realistic side of sci-fi rather than the laser guns and phasers of popular sci-fi shows. So if you are looking for a fast paced, action sci-fi, then this isn't for you. If you more enjoy the technological/engineering side of themes like this, then it is right up your street. Just bare this in mind, be in the right mind set when you sit down to watch it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You're Left Confused...but Satisfied
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Juan Mendoza
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is definitely a film that you come back to watch again for two reasons: 1) You're not immediately sure you understood what happened, and 2) You are left feeling mentally/philosophically engaged. To be straight, you should know going into this film that you should have an eye for subtleties and symbolism, and above all, an open mind. From the onset, you can tell that the director is not going to attempt to appeal to the audience with fast paced action, explosions, etc. but rather with direct mental stimulation. You watch this film with a similar manner to that of an obscure yet significant painting, because the themes that are presented to you feel epic, and they are left open for interpretation; the lack of dialogue in favor of eerie music helps. However, even through all of the confusion, and tense mood, you also know you are watching something beautiful. With a few minor exceptions, the screenplay feels like it is consistently appealing to the eye in a simple nature. And when it does change into more flashy and complex imagery, your eyes seem to welcome it. I wouldn't say it is in my personal favorite films, but either way I am still thinking about it weeks after having watched it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A picture of a soup can is not art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    royu2
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If art has to be explained, it's not art, if you have ask "er, is that art?", it's not art. Art speaks for itself, that's the whole point of art, it is a self-reviewing piece of work that needs no further investigation. Art and fashion are not the same thing, they are in fact polar opposites. Fashion is a popularly contest and it's existence forever lives on borrowed time and the approval of others. Art is fundamentally timeless. Fashion requires an accepting audience to exist, art does not. I know a lot of artists, half my family consider themselves "artists". What amazes me is that it seems the deeper into "art" they get the more the lines are blurred between art and fashion. Fashion is NOT art. 2001 A Space Odyssey is fashion, it does not stand on it's own two feet as art, because it isn't. It must be explained, which by default makes it not art, but fashion. A picture of a soup can being worth millions of dollars can only be explained through the prism of fashion. This movie really is as terrible and pointless as a picture of a soup can. The only people that think this is art are people who don't understand that art and fashion are two very different things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visually stunning.Kubrick's best work.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those films that make me wish I had been around to see it on the big screen.I envy those that got that opportunity,because as visually stunning as it is on the small screen,it had to be 100 times so in the theater.The orchestral arrangements during space sequences were the best possible soundtrack for what would be a silent visual in reality.The other visual effect,such as those inside the space craft look to be way ahead of their time.As for the story,it plays just like a thriller as we have a great man vs. machine angle.Of all the Stanley Kubrick films I have viewed to date.This visually stunning production is by far the best.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Unprecedented, Unique & Unparalleled Achievement In Motion Picture History.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An unprecedented, unique & unparalleled achievement in motion picture history, 2001: A Space Odyssey is a path-breaking cinema and a splendid work of art. Far ahead of its time and universally & unanimously hailed as one of the greatest & most influential films ever made, this film redefines its genre unlike anything before or after it, features some of the most iconic moments ever captured on film, and is an elegant mix of remarkable cinematography, pioneering visual & sound effects, scientific accuracy, epic score & a distinct style of narration. Not only is 2001: A Space Odyssey a visually spellbinding experience filmed with great artistry but also, in my opinion, Stanley Kubrick's magnum opus. 2001: A Space Odyssey deals with the elements of human evolution, technology, artificial intelligence & extra-terrestrial life. It is divided into 3 segments & an epilogue, each connected with an extra-terrestrial reference. The movie begins with the Dawn of Man segment set in prehistoric Africa, where a group of primitive apes discover a mysterious black monolith which eventually alters their course of evolution. The movie then takes a giant leap into the future, the year 2001, when another monolith is discovered on moon. The film then approaches its third segment where the main plot finally surfaces aboard a spaceship on its mission to Jupiter, which later culminates with an ambiguous ending that's debatable to this date. Stanley Kubrick is one of cinema's most influential & innovative directors, with a legacy that, arguably, has no equals. 2001: A Space Odyssey is Kubrick's first venture into the science fiction genre where he ended up crafting a cinematic jewel that's one of the first to take its genre seriously. Putting science in science-fiction, this masterpiece by Kubrick is as mysterious as the man himself and although all the usual Kubrick's trademarks exist in the film, the entire treatment is very different from other films of his or even others. The pace is intentionally slowed down, the narration is through visuals & music, the performances are honest, the exchange of dialogues is minimal and the plot is engaging & confusing at the same time but gets better, more transparent & satisfying on multiple viewings. Coming to technical aspects, this film is an incredible work of breathtaking art. The cinematography is a delight for everyone who appreciates great photography. The beautiful captures of landscapes and jaw-dropping exploration of the space (most notably The Moon) makes it one of the finest works that cinema has to offer. Editing is precisely done. Set pieces are wonderful to look at and the visual & sound effects are so groundbreaking & ahead of its time that many movies boasting CGI stuff today are still no match to it. Also, it is one of the most accurate depiction of space travel & the silence that fills the space scenes not only serves its purpose as accurate science, but also adds to the mood of the film. The fact that Kubrick shot the moon scenes with that level of detail & accuracy even before the Apollo landing never fails to impress. Even though 2001 is a visual ride of astonishing beauty, it isn't a movie that everyone is going to appreciate. It's a long technical film that runs at an unusually slow pace, is full of metaphysical complexities and is destined to polarize viewers. Even though some will find it incredibly boring & a strong test of their patience, there will be many who will end up being completely engulfed by its sheer beauty and an unusual blend of poetry & mystery in its bizarre plot. It has inspired almost every film of its genre since its release and will continue to do so for as long as cinema exists. Because after all, this is the film that started it all and deserves to be seen by everyone who appreciates great cinema, especially the fans of Kubrick & science-fiction genre. It's an amazing journey through space & time that raises pretty good questions about our very own existence, is full of philosophical & allegorical meanings, and concludes with an ending that is open for each viewer to interpret his/her way. Overall, what impressed me the most about this film is its impressive detailing in every frame, captivating photography, dazzling visuals & great characterization of the Discovery One spaceship's computer HAL 9000, where Kubrick examines the idea of machines turning against the very people they were meant to serve, decades before James Cameron came up with The Terminator or Wachowski Bros. crafted the next big sci-fi leap with The Matrix. Scoring full marks in all aspects of filmmaking and influencing not only cinema but science, culture & art as well, 2001: A Space Odyssey is a landmark moment in motion picture history that almost killed its genre for it set a standard so high that it hasn't been equaled or challenged ever since. Advancements in science & technology may have brought few films closer to it on a technical scale but overall, it remains a superior film & a pinnacle of science-fiction filmmaking and is possibly the best work from a legendary filmmaker who had made a career out of crafting one masterpiece after another. Highly recommended. Multiple viewings advised.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cannot be described
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    krustykrabpizza
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    2001: A Space Odyssey is like music. How do you tell someone that you like this movie? It's difficult, but to put it plainly, you can't. You just watch it. Listen to it. I was confused as to why I loved this movie so much even directly after the end credits began to roll, the story was quite confusing and there was a 20-minute scene at the start where monkeys were just being observed in a voyeuristic manner. It sounds like I'm appealing to a "certain intelligence" and I really don't like that, but it truly is a marvel that transcends language and all logical constructs. Don't read the reviews for this movie if you haven't seen it, just watch it. It's an experience that can only be unraveled from a personal point of view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated waste of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eumarius_89
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my first review. I didn't like this movie and i am seriously mad that i spent almost three hours of my life watching this. Of course that there will be some people who don't agree with me. Why i hate it so much: -Very very very slow paced, made me fall asleep a few times -I didn't understand the plot, maybe because i haven't read the book, but a movie shouldn't be made just for the people who read the book -Boring -Very little action -Very little character development -NO ENTERTAINMENT The ending was very complex and very boring. Maybe this is not the most objective review but i hope it will be useful for some to avoid making the same mistake i did. I normally don't feel this mad after watching a bad movie but this is so overrated, i just want people to realize it's not worth watching. My vote 1/10, i feel sorry for wasting my time with this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film-Strange author
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jam77-549-49835
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the three greatest movies of all time,I know it's a a.c Clarke(and we all know what that guys about) But if you get past that it has to be said that the sheer originality and breathtaking cinematography is enough of a reason to love this movie but the story builds to an absolute blow ya head off jaw dropping finale. There are times when you will be confused but later (much later for me) all will become clear. If Sci-Fi is your thing then this is your movie if not then this is still your movie, if you're going to trust any review then let it be this one. Everyone should see this film at least once believe me you will not regret it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dazzling Masterpiece.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stanley Kubrick's visually dazzling, intellectually stimulating and ambitious film makes one of the best uses of the medium known as cinema ever made. Film begins when humans were still apes, and how, when one of them touches a huge, mysterious monolith, he is pushed forward in evolution, and uses an old bone as a tool(to smash and kill of course...) Thousands of years later, man is now on the moon, and another monolith is uncovered, inspiring a spaceship crew to investigate, causing the on board ship computer HAL9000 to malfunction(sensing the oncoming next evolution it cannot experience?) One astronaut enters the monolith, and he(and the viewer) see an astonishing, even overwhelming assault on the senses that leads to... Well, for those who haven't seen it, no spoilers, but just consider how a "star child" fits in at the end... A unique achievement in film history, not to be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chrisborg1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw 2001: A Space Odyssey and I was blown away by the effects, the characters, and story. Now, when you see this movie you may not get it at first (I did not) but you have to think about it. This movie's story telling method is very different compared to nowadays but, I guess that's what makes it special. And in my opinion this is Kubrick's best film (but all of them are great) I think that when someone sees this they may dismiss it and say "this movie is so slow" which yes it may be slow but Kubrick did it that way so you could marvel at the terrific detail of the sets and all the little details that make the future so amazing. An amazing movie and great visual effects too: 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need the right mind set
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Martin
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First let me introduce myself, I am a 21 year old boy from the UK. I have very mixed reviews about this film, and am sure I am not the only one. I do not believe this to be a marmite film as most of the reviews suggest. I can and do see this from the point of view of both parties, seeing it as a boring waste of time and seeing it as sci-fi/cinematic history. I do agree, the story line is very scarce. There isn't that much happens, and when it does it is over before you even realise its begun. There is a lot of slow, boring and un-necessarily long clips of pretty much nothing; ships/people floating around, someone running, a phone call, a conversation that offers very little to the plot. I am not a troglodyte as some of the lovers of this film may be starting to think. I understand why it is included and done the way it is, but that doesn't stop it from being incredibly boring. However, to see this from a positive point of view, one must remember that this was made in the mid-to-late 1960's. Meaning that everything done in this was done for real, rather than CGI as everything is now. For this reason I don't feel that it can be put in the same class as modern sci-fi films. I sadly have not read the book of this, I have just decided to watch the film because my friend likes to quote it to me and I wanted to see what she was going on about. This left me very skeptical when I started watching, especially as seemingly nothing was actually happening. You really do have to keep watching and thinking about what it is actually depicting. A large amount of the themes and science fiction ideas were depicted on screen for the first time in this film and is therefore giving a visual insight into what mankind has predicted the future will be like and it is remarkable how much they have actually gotten right for what we have already accomplished and what we are still working on. A lot of the ideas in this film are still being copied to this day, and has now actually got me questioning Ridley Scott's work. I am not saying that Scott has copied Kubrick, just that some of the praises Scott has received shouldn't really be given solely to him for his work in the sci-fi genre. Kubrick has managed to show to the world the realism of space. We all watch films these days and like to point out, "that couldn't happen", "that would never happen", etc. etc. That is the reason behind all the slow and uneventful scenes, it is being kept to a realistic standard of how it would actually have to happen and to show you how slow a long space trip like that would actually be. The shots of space exploration also show demonstrations of the physical properties of our universe and how things actually happen. So, to conclude. Although this may not be an exciting, eventful or thrilling film, it is certainly a feat of cinematography. It more depicts the realistic side of sci-fi rather than the laser guns and phasers of popular sci-fi shows. So if you are looking for a fast paced, action sci-fi, then this isn't for you. If you more enjoy the technological/engineering side of themes like this, then it is right up your street. Just bare this in mind, be in the right mind set when you sit down to watch it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You're Left Confused...but Satisfied
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Juan Mendoza
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is definitely a film that you come back to watch again for two reasons: 1) You're not immediately sure you understood what happened, and 2) You are left feeling mentally/philosophically engaged. To be straight, you should know going into this film that you should have an eye for subtleties and symbolism, and above all, an open mind. From the onset, you can tell that the director is not going to attempt to appeal to the audience with fast paced action, explosions, etc. but rather with direct mental stimulation. You watch this film with a similar manner to that of an obscure yet significant painting, because the themes that are presented to you feel epic, and they are left open for interpretation; the lack of dialogue in favor of eerie music helps. However, even through all of the confusion, and tense mood, you also know you are watching something beautiful. With a few minor exceptions, the screenplay feels like it is consistently appealing to the eye in a simple nature. And when it does change into more flashy and complex imagery, your eyes seem to welcome it. I wouldn't say it is in my personal favorite films, but either way I am still thinking about it weeks after having watched it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A picture of a soup can is not art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    royu2
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If art has to be explained, it's not art, if you have ask "er, is that art?", it's not art. Art speaks for itself, that's the whole point of art, it is a self-reviewing piece of work that needs no further investigation. Art and fashion are not the same thing, they are in fact polar opposites. Fashion is a popularly contest and it's existence forever lives on borrowed time and the approval of others. Art is fundamentally timeless. Fashion requires an accepting audience to exist, art does not. I know a lot of artists, half my family consider themselves "artists". What amazes me is that it seems the deeper into "art" they get the more the lines are blurred between art and fashion. Fashion is NOT art. 2001 A Space Odyssey is fashion, it does not stand on it's own two feet as art, because it isn't. It must be explained, which by default makes it not art, but fashion. A picture of a soup can being worth millions of dollars can only be explained through the prism of fashion. This movie really is as terrible and pointless as a picture of a soup can. The only people that think this is art are people who don't understand that art and fashion are two very different things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visually stunning.Kubrick's best work.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those films that make me wish I had been around to see it on the big screen.I envy those that got that opportunity,because as visually stunning as it is on the small screen,it had to be 100 times so in the theater.The orchestral arrangements during space sequences were the best possible soundtrack for what would be a silent visual in reality.The other visual effect,such as those inside the space craft look to be way ahead of their time.As for the story,it plays just like a thriller as we have a great man vs. machine angle.Of all the Stanley Kubrick films I have viewed to date.This visually stunning production is by far the best.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Unprecedented, Unique & Unparalleled Achievement In Motion Picture History.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An unprecedented, unique & unparalleled achievement in motion picture history, 2001: A Space Odyssey is a path-breaking cinema and a splendid work of art. Far ahead of its time and universally & unanimously hailed as one of the greatest & most influential films ever made, this film redefines its genre unlike anything before or after it, features some of the most iconic moments ever captured on film, and is an elegant mix of remarkable cinematography, pioneering visual & sound effects, scientific accuracy, epic score & a distinct style of narration. Not only is 2001: A Space Odyssey a visually spellbinding experience filmed with great artistry but also, in my opinion, Stanley Kubrick's magnum opus. 2001: A Space Odyssey deals with the elements of human evolution, technology, artificial intelligence & extra-terrestrial life. It is divided into 3 segments & an epilogue, each connected with an extra-terrestrial reference. The movie begins with the Dawn of Man segment set in prehistoric Africa, where a group of primitive apes discover a mysterious black monolith which eventually alters their course of evolution. The movie then takes a giant leap into the future, the year 2001, when another monolith is discovered on moon. The film then approaches its third segment where the main plot finally surfaces aboard a spaceship on its mission to Jupiter, which later culminates with an ambiguous ending that's debatable to this date. Stanley Kubrick is one of cinema's most influential & innovative directors, with a legacy that, arguably, has no equals. 2001: A Space Odyssey is Kubrick's first venture into the science fiction genre where he ended up crafting a cinematic jewel that's one of the first to take its genre seriously. Putting science in science-fiction, this masterpiece by Kubrick is as mysterious as the man himself and although all the usual Kubrick's trademarks exist in the film, the entire treatment is very different from other films of his or even others. The pace is intentionally slowed down, the narration is through visuals & music, the performances are honest, the exchange of dialogues is minimal and the plot is engaging & confusing at the same time but gets better, more transparent & satisfying on multiple viewings. Coming to technical aspects, this film is an incredible work of breathtaking art. The cinematography is a delight for everyone who appreciates great photography. The beautiful captures of landscapes and jaw-dropping exploration of the space (most notably The Moon) makes it one of the finest works that cinema has to offer. Editing is precisely done. Set pieces are wonderful to look at and the visual & sound effects are so groundbreaking & ahead of its time that many movies boasting CGI stuff today are still no match to it. Also, it is one of the most accurate depiction of space travel & the silence that fills the space scenes not only serves its purpose as accurate science, but also adds to the mood of the film. The fact that Kubrick shot the moon scenes with that level of detail & accuracy even before the Apollo landing never fails to impress. Even though 2001 is a visual ride of astonishing beauty, it isn't a movie that everyone is going to appreciate. It's a long technical film that runs at an unusually slow pace, is full of metaphysical complexities and is destined to polarize viewers. Even though some will find it incredibly boring & a strong test of their patience, there will be many who will end up being completely engulfed by its sheer beauty and an unusual blend of poetry & mystery in its bizarre plot. It has inspired almost every film of its genre since its release and will continue to do so for as long as cinema exists. Because after all, this is the film that started it all and deserves to be seen by everyone who appreciates great cinema, especially the fans of Kubrick & science-fiction genre. It's an amazing journey through space & time that raises pretty good questions about our very own existence, is full of philosophical & allegorical meanings, and concludes with an ending that is open for each viewer to interpret his/her way. Overall, what impressed me the most about this film is its impressive detailing in every frame, captivating photography, dazzling visuals & great characterization of the Discovery One spaceship's computer HAL 9000, where Kubrick examines the idea of machines turning against the very people they were meant to serve, decades before James Cameron came up with The Terminator or Wachowski Bros. crafted the next big sci-fi leap with The Matrix. Scoring full marks in all aspects of filmmaking and influencing not only cinema but science, culture & art as well, 2001: A Space Odyssey is a landmark moment in motion picture history that almost killed its genre for it set a standard so high that it hasn't been equaled or challenged ever since. Advancements in science & technology may have brought few films closer to it on a technical scale but overall, it remains a superior film & a pinnacle of science-fiction filmmaking and is possibly the best work from a legendary filmmaker who had made a career out of crafting one masterpiece after another. Highly recommended. Multiple viewings advised.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cannot be described
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    krustykrabpizza
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    2001: A Space Odyssey is like music. How do you tell someone that you like this movie? It's difficult, but to put it plainly, you can't. You just watch it. Listen to it. I was confused as to why I loved this movie so much even directly after the end credits began to roll, the story was quite confusing and there was a 20-minute scene at the start where monkeys were just being observed in a voyeuristic manner. It sounds like I'm appealing to a "certain intelligence" and I really don't like that, but it truly is a marvel that transcends language and all logical constructs. Don't read the reviews for this movie if you haven't seen it, just watch it. It's an experience that can only be unraveled from a personal point of view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated waste of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eumarius_89
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my first review. I didn't like this movie and i am seriously mad that i spent almost three hours of my life watching this. Of course that there will be some people who don't agree with me. Why i hate it so much: -Very very very slow paced, made me fall asleep a few times -I didn't understand the plot, maybe because i haven't read the book, but a movie shouldn't be made just for the people who read the book -Boring -Very little action -Very little character development -NO ENTERTAINMENT The ending was very complex and very boring. Maybe this is not the most objective review but i hope it will be useful for some to avoid making the same mistake i did. I normally don't feel this mad after watching a bad movie but this is so overrated, i just want people to realize it's not worth watching. My vote 1/10, i feel sorry for wasting my time with this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film-Strange author
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jam77-549-49835
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the three greatest movies of all time,I know it's a a.c Clarke(and we all know what that guys about) But if you get past that it has to be said that the sheer originality and breathtaking cinematography is enough of a reason to love this movie but the story builds to an absolute blow ya head off jaw dropping finale. There are times when you will be confused but later (much later for me) all will become clear. If Sci-Fi is your thing then this is your movie if not then this is still your movie, if you're going to trust any review then let it be this one. Everyone should see this film at least once believe me you will not regret it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dazzling Masterpiece.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stanley Kubrick's visually dazzling, intellectually stimulating and ambitious film makes one of the best uses of the medium known as cinema ever made. Film begins when humans were still apes, and how, when one of them touches a huge, mysterious monolith, he is pushed forward in evolution, and uses an old bone as a tool(to smash and kill of course...) Thousands of years later, man is now on the moon, and another monolith is uncovered, inspiring a spaceship crew to investigate, causing the on board ship computer HAL9000 to malfunction(sensing the oncoming next evolution it cannot experience?) One astronaut enters the monolith, and he(and the viewer) see an astonishing, even overwhelming assault on the senses that leads to... Well, for those who haven't seen it, no spoilers, but just consider how a "star child" fits in at the end... A unique achievement in film history, not to be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chrisborg1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw 2001: A Space Odyssey and I was blown away by the effects, the characters, and story. Now, when you see this movie you may not get it at first (I did not) but you have to think about it. This movie's story telling method is very different compared to nowadays but, I guess that's what makes it special. And in my opinion this is Kubrick's best film (but all of them are great) I think that when someone sees this they may dismiss it and say "this movie is so slow" which yes it may be slow but Kubrick did it that way so you could marvel at the terrific detail of the sets and all the little details that make the future so amazing. An amazing movie and great visual effects too: 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need the right mind set
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Martin
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First let me introduce myself, I am a 21 year old boy from the UK. I have very mixed reviews about this film, and am sure I am not the only one. I do not believe this to be a marmite film as most of the reviews suggest. I can and do see this from the point of view of both parties, seeing it as a boring waste of time and seeing it as sci-fi/cinematic history. I do agree, the story line is very scarce. There isn't that much happens, and when it does it is over before you even realise its begun. There is a lot of slow, boring and un-necessarily long clips of pretty much nothing; ships/people floating around, someone running, a phone call, a conversation that offers very little to the plot. I am not a troglodyte as some of the lovers of this film may be starting to think. I understand why it is included and done the way it is, but that doesn't stop it from being incredibly boring. However, to see this from a positive point of view, one must remember that this was made in the mid-to-late 1960's. Meaning that everything done in this was done for real, rather than CGI as everything is now. For this reason I don't feel that it can be put in the same class as modern sci-fi films. I sadly have not read the book of this, I have just decided to watch the film because my friend likes to quote it to me and I wanted to see what she was going on about. This left me very skeptical when I started watching, especially as seemingly nothing was actually happening. You really do have to keep watching and thinking about what it is actually depicting. A large amount of the themes and science fiction ideas were depicted on screen for the first time in this film and is therefore giving a visual insight into what mankind has predicted the future will be like and it is remarkable how much they have actually gotten right for what we have already accomplished and what we are still working on. A lot of the ideas in this film are still being copied to this day, and has now actually got me questioning Ridley Scott's work. I am not saying that Scott has copied Kubrick, just that some of the praises Scott has received shouldn't really be given solely to him for his work in the sci-fi genre. Kubrick has managed to show to the world the realism of space. We all watch films these days and like to point out, "that couldn't happen", "that would never happen", etc. etc. That is the reason behind all the slow and uneventful scenes, it is being kept to a realistic standard of how it would actually have to happen and to show you how slow a long space trip like that would actually be. The shots of space exploration also show demonstrations of the physical properties of our universe and how things actually happen. So, to conclude. Although this may not be an exciting, eventful or thrilling film, it is certainly a feat of cinematography. It more depicts the realistic side of sci-fi rather than the laser guns and phasers of popular sci-fi shows. So if you are looking for a fast paced, action sci-fi, then this isn't for you. If you more enjoy the technological/engineering side of themes like this, then it is right up your street. Just bare this in mind, be in the right mind set when you sit down to watch it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You're Left Confused...but Satisfied
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Juan Mendoza
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is definitely a film that you come back to watch again for two reasons: 1) You're not immediately sure you understood what happened, and 2) You are left feeling mentally/philosophically engaged. To be straight, you should know going into this film that you should have an eye for subtleties and symbolism, and above all, an open mind. From the onset, you can tell that the director is not going to attempt to appeal to the audience with fast paced action, explosions, etc. but rather with direct mental stimulation. You watch this film with a similar manner to that of an obscure yet significant painting, because the themes that are presented to you feel epic, and they are left open for interpretation; the lack of dialogue in favor of eerie music helps. However, even through all of the confusion, and tense mood, you also know you are watching something beautiful. With a few minor exceptions, the screenplay feels like it is consistently appealing to the eye in a simple nature. And when it does change into more flashy and complex imagery, your eyes seem to welcome it. I wouldn't say it is in my personal favorite films, but either way I am still thinking about it weeks after having watched it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A picture of a soup can is not art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    royu2
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If art has to be explained, it's not art, if you have ask "er, is that art?", it's not art. Art speaks for itself, that's the whole point of art, it is a self-reviewing piece of work that needs no further investigation. Art and fashion are not the same thing, they are in fact polar opposites. Fashion is a popularly contest and it's existence forever lives on borrowed time and the approval of others. Art is fundamentally timeless. Fashion requires an accepting audience to exist, art does not. I know a lot of artists, half my family consider themselves "artists". What amazes me is that it seems the deeper into "art" they get the more the lines are blurred between art and fashion. Fashion is NOT art. 2001 A Space Odyssey is fashion, it does not stand on it's own two feet as art, because it isn't. It must be explained, which by default makes it not art, but fashion. A picture of a soup can being worth millions of dollars can only be explained through the prism of fashion. This movie really is as terrible and pointless as a picture of a soup can. The only people that think this is art are people who don't understand that art and fashion are two very different things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visually stunning.Kubrick's best work.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those films that make me wish I had been around to see it on the big screen.I envy those that got that opportunity,because as visually stunning as it is on the small screen,it had to be 100 times so in the theater.The orchestral arrangements during space sequences were the best possible soundtrack for what would be a silent visual in reality.The other visual effect,such as those inside the space craft look to be way ahead of their time.As for the story,it plays just like a thriller as we have a great man vs. machine angle.Of all the Stanley Kubrick films I have viewed to date.This visually stunning production is by far the best.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Unprecedented, Unique & Unparalleled Achievement In Motion Picture History.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An unprecedented, unique & unparalleled achievement in motion picture history, 2001: A Space Odyssey is a path-breaking cinema and a splendid work of art. Far ahead of its time and universally & unanimously hailed as one of the greatest & most influential films ever made, this film redefines its genre unlike anything before or after it, features some of the most iconic moments ever captured on film, and is an elegant mix of remarkable cinematography, pioneering visual & sound effects, scientific accuracy, epic score & a distinct style of narration. Not only is 2001: A Space Odyssey a visually spellbinding experience filmed with great artistry but also, in my opinion, Stanley Kubrick's magnum opus. 2001: A Space Odyssey deals with the elements of human evolution, technology, artificial intelligence & extra-terrestrial life. It is divided into 3 segments & an epilogue, each connected with an extra-terrestrial reference. The movie begins with the Dawn of Man segment set in prehistoric Africa, where a group of primitive apes discover a mysterious black monolith which eventually alters their course of evolution. The movie then takes a giant leap into the future, the year 2001, when another monolith is discovered on moon. The film then approaches its third segment where the main plot finally surfaces aboard a spaceship on its mission to Jupiter, which later culminates with an ambiguous ending that's debatable to this date. Stanley Kubrick is one of cinema's most influential & innovative directors, with a legacy that, arguably, has no equals. 2001: A Space Odyssey is Kubrick's first venture into the science fiction genre where he ended up crafting a cinematic jewel that's one of the first to take its genre seriously. Putting science in science-fiction, this masterpiece by Kubrick is as mysterious as the man himself and although all the usual Kubrick's trademarks exist in the film, the entire treatment is very different from other films of his or even others. The pace is intentionally slowed down, the narration is through visuals & music, the performances are honest, the exchange of dialogues is minimal and the plot is engaging & confusing at the same time but gets better, more transparent & satisfying on multiple viewings. Coming to technical aspects, this film is an incredible work of breathtaking art. The cinematography is a delight for everyone who appreciates great photography. The beautiful captures of landscapes and jaw-dropping exploration of the space (most notably The Moon) makes it one of the finest works that cinema has to offer. Editing is precisely done. Set pieces are wonderful to look at and the visual & sound effects are so groundbreaking & ahead of its time that many movies boasting CGI stuff today are still no match to it. Also, it is one of the most accurate depiction of space travel & the silence that fills the space scenes not only serves its purpose as accurate science, but also adds to the mood of the film. The fact that Kubrick shot the moon scenes with that level of detail & accuracy even before the Apollo landing never fails to impress. Even though 2001 is a visual ride of astonishing beauty, it isn't a movie that everyone is going to appreciate. It's a long technical film that runs at an unusually slow pace, is full of metaphysical complexities and is destined to polarize viewers. Even though some will find it incredibly boring & a strong test of their patience, there will be many who will end up being completely engulfed by its sheer beauty and an unusual blend of poetry & mystery in its bizarre plot. It has inspired almost every film of its genre since its release and will continue to do so for as long as cinema exists. Because after all, this is the film that started it all and deserves to be seen by everyone who appreciates great cinema, especially the fans of Kubrick & science-fiction genre. It's an amazing journey through space & time that raises pretty good questions about our very own existence, is full of philosophical & allegorical meanings, and concludes with an ending that is open for each viewer to interpret his/her way. Overall, what impressed me the most about this film is its impressive detailing in every frame, captivating photography, dazzling visuals & great characterization of the Discovery One spaceship's computer HAL 9000, where Kubrick examines the idea of machines turning against the very people they were meant to serve, decades before James Cameron came up with The Terminator or Wachowski Bros. crafted the next big sci-fi leap with The Matrix. Scoring full marks in all aspects of filmmaking and influencing not only cinema but science, culture & art as well, 2001: A Space Odyssey is a landmark moment in motion picture history that almost killed its genre for it set a standard so high that it hasn't been equaled or challenged ever since. Advancements in science & technology may have brought few films closer to it on a technical scale but overall, it remains a superior film & a pinnacle of science-fiction filmmaking and is possibly the best work from a legendary filmmaker who had made a career out of crafting one masterpiece after another. Highly recommended. Multiple viewings advised.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cannot be described
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    krustykrabpizza
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    2001: A Space Odyssey is like music. How do you tell someone that you like this movie? It's difficult, but to put it plainly, you can't. You just watch it. Listen to it. I was confused as to why I loved this movie so much even directly after the end credits began to roll, the story was quite confusing and there was a 20-minute scene at the start where monkeys were just being observed in a voyeuristic manner. It sounds like I'm appealing to a "certain intelligence" and I really don't like that, but it truly is a marvel that transcends language and all logical constructs. Don't read the reviews for this movie if you haven't seen it, just watch it. It's an experience that can only be unraveled from a personal point of view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated waste of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eumarius_89
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my first review. I didn't like this movie and i am seriously mad that i spent almost three hours of my life watching this. Of course that there will be some people who don't agree with me. Why i hate it so much: -Very very very slow paced, made me fall asleep a few times -I didn't understand the plot, maybe because i haven't read the book, but a movie shouldn't be made just for the people who read the book -Boring -Very little action -Very little character development -NO ENTERTAINMENT The ending was very complex and very boring. Maybe this is not the most objective review but i hope it will be useful for some to avoid making the same mistake i did. I normally don't feel this mad after watching a bad movie but this is so overrated, i just want people to realize it's not worth watching. My vote 1/10, i feel sorry for wasting my time with this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film-Strange author
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jam77-549-49835
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the three greatest movies of all time,I know it's a a.c Clarke(and we all know what that guys about) But if you get past that it has to be said that the sheer originality and breathtaking cinematography is enough of a reason to love this movie but the story builds to an absolute blow ya head off jaw dropping finale. There are times when you will be confused but later (much later for me) all will become clear. If Sci-Fi is your thing then this is your movie if not then this is still your movie, if you're going to trust any review then let it be this one. Everyone should see this film at least once believe me you will not regret it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dazzling Masterpiece.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stanley Kubrick's visually dazzling, intellectually stimulating and ambitious film makes one of the best uses of the medium known as cinema ever made. Film begins when humans were still apes, and how, when one of them touches a huge, mysterious monolith, he is pushed forward in evolution, and uses an old bone as a tool(to smash and kill of course...) Thousands of years later, man is now on the moon, and another monolith is uncovered, inspiring a spaceship crew to investigate, causing the on board ship computer HAL9000 to malfunction(sensing the oncoming next evolution it cannot experience?) One astronaut enters the monolith, and he(and the viewer) see an astonishing, even overwhelming assault on the senses that leads to... Well, for those who haven't seen it, no spoilers, but just consider how a "star child" fits in at the end... A unique achievement in film history, not to be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chrisborg1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw 2001: A Space Odyssey and I was blown away by the effects, the characters, and story. Now, when you see this movie you may not get it at first (I did not) but you have to think about it. This movie's story telling method is very different compared to nowadays but, I guess that's what makes it special. And in my opinion this is Kubrick's best film (but all of them are great) I think that when someone sees this they may dismiss it and say "this movie is so slow" which yes it may be slow but Kubrick did it that way so you could marvel at the terrific detail of the sets and all the little details that make the future so amazing. An amazing movie and great visual effects too: 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need the right mind set
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Martin
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First let me introduce myself, I am a 21 year old boy from the UK. I have very mixed reviews about this film, and am sure I am not the only one. I do not believe this to be a marmite film as most of the reviews suggest. I can and do see this from the point of view of both parties, seeing it as a boring waste of time and seeing it as sci-fi/cinematic history. I do agree, the story line is very scarce. There isn't that much happens, and when it does it is over before you even realise its begun. There is a lot of slow, boring and un-necessarily long clips of pretty much nothing; ships/people floating around, someone running, a phone call, a conversation that offers very little to the plot. I am not a troglodyte as some of the lovers of this film may be starting to think. I understand why it is included and done the way it is, but that doesn't stop it from being incredibly boring. However, to see this from a positive point of view, one must remember that this was made in the mid-to-late 1960's. Meaning that everything done in this was done for real, rather than CGI as everything is now. For this reason I don't feel that it can be put in the same class as modern sci-fi films. I sadly have not read the book of this, I have just decided to watch the film because my friend likes to quote it to me and I wanted to see what she was going on about. This left me very skeptical when I started watching, especially as seemingly nothing was actually happening. You really do have to keep watching and thinking about what it is actually depicting. A large amount of the themes and science fiction ideas were depicted on screen for the first time in this film and is therefore giving a visual insight into what mankind has predicted the future will be like and it is remarkable how much they have actually gotten right for what we have already accomplished and what we are still working on. A lot of the ideas in this film are still being copied to this day, and has now actually got me questioning Ridley Scott's work. I am not saying that Scott has copied Kubrick, just that some of the praises Scott has received shouldn't really be given solely to him for his work in the sci-fi genre. Kubrick has managed to show to the world the realism of space. We all watch films these days and like to point out, "that couldn't happen", "that would never happen", etc. etc. That is the reason behind all the slow and uneventful scenes, it is being kept to a realistic standard of how it would actually have to happen and to show you how slow a long space trip like that would actually be. The shots of space exploration also show demonstrations of the physical properties of our universe and how things actually happen. So, to conclude. Although this may not be an exciting, eventful or thrilling film, it is certainly a feat of cinematography. It more depicts the realistic side of sci-fi rather than the laser guns and phasers of popular sci-fi shows. So if you are looking for a fast paced, action sci-fi, then this isn't for you. If you more enjoy the technological/engineering side of themes like this, then it is right up your street. Just bare this in mind, be in the right mind set when you sit down to watch it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You're Left Confused...but Satisfied
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Juan Mendoza
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is definitely a film that you come back to watch again for two reasons: 1) You're not immediately sure you understood what happened, and 2) You are left feeling mentally/philosophically engaged. To be straight, you should know going into this film that you should have an eye for subtleties and symbolism, and above all, an open mind. From the onset, you can tell that the director is not going to attempt to appeal to the audience with fast paced action, explosions, etc. but rather with direct mental stimulation. You watch this film with a similar manner to that of an obscure yet significant painting, because the themes that are presented to you feel epic, and they are left open for interpretation; the lack of dialogue in favor of eerie music helps. However, even through all of the confusion, and tense mood, you also know you are watching something beautiful. With a few minor exceptions, the screenplay feels like it is consistently appealing to the eye in a simple nature. And when it does change into more flashy and complex imagery, your eyes seem to welcome it. I wouldn't say it is in my personal favorite films, but either way I am still thinking about it weeks after having watched it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A picture of a soup can is not art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    royu2
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If art has to be explained, it's not art, if you have ask "er, is that art?", it's not art. Art speaks for itself, that's the whole point of art, it is a self-reviewing piece of work that needs no further investigation. Art and fashion are not the same thing, they are in fact polar opposites. Fashion is a popularly contest and it's existence forever lives on borrowed time and the approval of others. Art is fundamentally timeless. Fashion requires an accepting audience to exist, art does not. I know a lot of artists, half my family consider themselves "artists". What amazes me is that it seems the deeper into "art" they get the more the lines are blurred between art and fashion. Fashion is NOT art. 2001 A Space Odyssey is fashion, it does not stand on it's own two feet as art, because it isn't. It must be explained, which by default makes it not art, but fashion. A picture of a soup can being worth millions of dollars can only be explained through the prism of fashion. This movie really is as terrible and pointless as a picture of a soup can. The only people that think this is art are people who don't understand that art and fashion are two very different things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visually stunning.Kubrick's best work.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those films that make me wish I had been around to see it on the big screen.I envy those that got that opportunity,because as visually stunning as it is on the small screen,it had to be 100 times so in the theater.The orchestral arrangements during space sequences were the best possible soundtrack for what would be a silent visual in reality.The other visual effect,such as those inside the space craft look to be way ahead of their time.As for the story,it plays just like a thriller as we have a great man vs. machine angle.Of all the Stanley Kubrick films I have viewed to date.This visually stunning production is by far the best.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Unprecedented, Unique & Unparalleled Achievement In Motion Picture History.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An unprecedented, unique & unparalleled achievement in motion picture history, 2001: A Space Odyssey is a path-breaking cinema and a splendid work of art. Far ahead of its time and universally & unanimously hailed as one of the greatest & most influential films ever made, this film redefines its genre unlike anything before or after it, features some of the most iconic moments ever captured on film, and is an elegant mix of remarkable cinematography, pioneering visual & sound effects, scientific accuracy, epic score & a distinct style of narration. Not only is 2001: A Space Odyssey a visually spellbinding experience filmed with great artistry but also, in my opinion, Stanley Kubrick's magnum opus. 2001: A Space Odyssey deals with the elements of human evolution, technology, artificial intelligence & extra-terrestrial life. It is divided into 3 segments & an epilogue, each connected with an extra-terrestrial reference. The movie begins with the Dawn of Man segment set in prehistoric Africa, where a group of primitive apes discover a mysterious black monolith which eventually alters their course of evolution. The movie then takes a giant leap into the future, the year 2001, when another monolith is discovered on moon. The film then approaches its third segment where the main plot finally surfaces aboard a spaceship on its mission to Jupiter, which later culminates with an ambiguous ending that's debatable to this date. Stanley Kubrick is one of cinema's most influential & innovative directors, with a legacy that, arguably, has no equals. 2001: A Space Odyssey is Kubrick's first venture into the science fiction genre where he ended up crafting a cinematic jewel that's one of the first to take its genre seriously. Putting science in science-fiction, this masterpiece by Kubrick is as mysterious as the man himself and although all the usual Kubrick's trademarks exist in the film, the entire treatment is very different from other films of his or even others. The pace is intentionally slowed down, the narration is through visuals & music, the performances are honest, the exchange of dialogues is minimal and the plot is engaging & confusing at the same time but gets better, more transparent & satisfying on multiple viewings. Coming to technical aspects, this film is an incredible work of breathtaking art. The cinematography is a delight for everyone who appreciates great photography. The beautiful captures of landscapes and jaw-dropping exploration of the space (most notably The Moon) makes it one of the finest works that cinema has to offer. Editing is precisely done. Set pieces are wonderful to look at and the visual & sound effects are so groundbreaking & ahead of its time that many movies boasting CGI stuff today are still no match to it. Also, it is one of the most accurate depiction of space travel & the silence that fills the space scenes not only serves its purpose as accurate science, but also adds to the mood of the film. The fact that Kubrick shot the moon scenes with that level of detail & accuracy even before the Apollo landing never fails to impress. Even though 2001 is a visual ride of astonishing beauty, it isn't a movie that everyone is going to appreciate. It's a long technical film that runs at an unusually slow pace, is full of metaphysical complexities and is destined to polarize viewers. Even though some will find it incredibly boring & a strong test of their patience, there will be many who will end up being completely engulfed by its sheer beauty and an unusual blend of poetry & mystery in its bizarre plot. It has inspired almost every film of its genre since its release and will continue to do so for as long as cinema exists. Because after all, this is the film that started it all and deserves to be seen by everyone who appreciates great cinema, especially the fans of Kubrick & science-fiction genre. It's an amazing journey through space & time that raises pretty good questions about our very own existence, is full of philosophical & allegorical meanings, and concludes with an ending that is open for each viewer to interpret his/her way. Overall, what impressed me the most about this film is its impressive detailing in every frame, captivating photography, dazzling visuals & great characterization of the Discovery One spaceship's computer HAL 9000, where Kubrick examines the idea of machines turning against the very people they were meant to serve, decades before James Cameron came up with The Terminator or Wachowski Bros. crafted the next big sci-fi leap with The Matrix. Scoring full marks in all aspects of filmmaking and influencing not only cinema but science, culture & art as well, 2001: A Space Odyssey is a landmark moment in motion picture history that almost killed its genre for it set a standard so high that it hasn't been equaled or challenged ever since. Advancements in science & technology may have brought few films closer to it on a technical scale but overall, it remains a superior film & a pinnacle of science-fiction filmmaking and is possibly the best work from a legendary filmmaker who had made a career out of crafting one masterpiece after another. Highly recommended. Multiple viewings advised.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cannot be described
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    krustykrabpizza
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    2001: A Space Odyssey is like music. How do you tell someone that you like this movie? It's difficult, but to put it plainly, you can't. You just watch it. Listen to it. I was confused as to why I loved this movie so much even directly after the end credits began to roll, the story was quite confusing and there was a 20-minute scene at the start where monkeys were just being observed in a voyeuristic manner. It sounds like I'm appealing to a "certain intelligence" and I really don't like that, but it truly is a marvel that transcends language and all logical constructs. Don't read the reviews for this movie if you haven't seen it, just watch it. It's an experience that can only be unraveled from a personal point of view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated waste of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eumarius_89
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my first review. I didn't like this movie and i am seriously mad that i spent almost three hours of my life watching this. Of course that there will be some people who don't agree with me. Why i hate it so much: -Very very very slow paced, made me fall asleep a few times -I didn't understand the plot, maybe because i haven't read the book, but a movie shouldn't be made just for the people who read the book -Boring -Very little action -Very little character development -NO ENTERTAINMENT The ending was very complex and very boring. Maybe this is not the most objective review but i hope it will be useful for some to avoid making the same mistake i did. I normally don't feel this mad after watching a bad movie but this is so overrated, i just want people to realize it's not worth watching. My vote 1/10, i feel sorry for wasting my time with this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film-Strange author
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jam77-549-49835
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the three greatest movies of all time,I know it's a a.c Clarke(and we all know what that guys about) But if you get past that it has to be said that the sheer originality and breathtaking cinematography is enough of a reason to love this movie but the story builds to an absolute blow ya head off jaw dropping finale. There are times when you will be confused but later (much later for me) all will become clear. If Sci-Fi is your thing then this is your movie if not then this is still your movie, if you're going to trust any review then let it be this one. Everyone should see this film at least once believe me you will not regret it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dazzling Masterpiece.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stanley Kubrick's visually dazzling, intellectually stimulating and ambitious film makes one of the best uses of the medium known as cinema ever made. Film begins when humans were still apes, and how, when one of them touches a huge, mysterious monolith, he is pushed forward in evolution, and uses an old bone as a tool(to smash and kill of course...) Thousands of years later, man is now on the moon, and another monolith is uncovered, inspiring a spaceship crew to investigate, causing the on board ship computer HAL9000 to malfunction(sensing the oncoming next evolution it cannot experience?) One astronaut enters the monolith, and he(and the viewer) see an astonishing, even overwhelming assault on the senses that leads to... Well, for those who haven't seen it, no spoilers, but just consider how a "star child" fits in at the end... A unique achievement in film history, not to be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chrisborg1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw 2001: A Space Odyssey and I was blown away by the effects, the characters, and story. Now, when you see this movie you may not get it at first (I did not) but you have to think about it. This movie's story telling method is very different compared to nowadays but, I guess that's what makes it special. And in my opinion this is Kubrick's best film (but all of them are great) I think that when someone sees this they may dismiss it and say "this movie is so slow" which yes it may be slow but Kubrick did it that way so you could marvel at the terrific detail of the sets and all the little details that make the future so amazing. An amazing movie and great visual effects too: 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need the right mind set
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Martin
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First let me introduce myself, I am a 21 year old boy from the UK. I have very mixed reviews about this film, and am sure I am not the only one. I do not believe this to be a marmite film as most of the reviews suggest. I can and do see this from the point of view of both parties, seeing it as a boring waste of time and seeing it as sci-fi/cinematic history. I do agree, the story line is very scarce. There isn't that much happens, and when it does it is over before you even realise its begun. There is a lot of slow, boring and un-necessarily long clips of pretty much nothing; ships/people floating around, someone running, a phone call, a conversation that offers very little to the plot. I am not a troglodyte as some of the lovers of this film may be starting to think. I understand why it is included and done the way it is, but that doesn't stop it from being incredibly boring. However, to see this from a positive point of view, one must remember that this was made in the mid-to-late 1960's. Meaning that everything done in this was done for real, rather than CGI as everything is now. For this reason I don't feel that it can be put in the same class as modern sci-fi films. I sadly have not read the book of this, I have just decided to watch the film because my friend likes to quote it to me and I wanted to see what she was going on about. This left me very skeptical when I started watching, especially as seemingly nothing was actually happening. You really do have to keep watching and thinking about what it is actually depicting. A large amount of the themes and science fiction ideas were depicted on screen for the first time in this film and is therefore giving a visual insight into what mankind has predicted the future will be like and it is remarkable how much they have actually gotten right for what we have already accomplished and what we are still working on. A lot of the ideas in this film are still being copied to this day, and has now actually got me questioning Ridley Scott's work. I am not saying that Scott has copied Kubrick, just that some of the praises Scott has received shouldn't really be given solely to him for his work in the sci-fi genre. Kubrick has managed to show to the world the realism of space. We all watch films these days and like to point out, "that couldn't happen", "that would never happen", etc. etc. That is the reason behind all the slow and uneventful scenes, it is being kept to a realistic standard of how it would actually have to happen and to show you how slow a long space trip like that would actually be. The shots of space exploration also show demonstrations of the physical properties of our universe and how things actually happen. So, to conclude. Although this may not be an exciting, eventful or thrilling film, it is certainly a feat of cinematography. It more depicts the realistic side of sci-fi rather than the laser guns and phasers of popular sci-fi shows. So if you are looking for a fast paced, action sci-fi, then this isn't for you. If you more enjoy the technological/engineering side of themes like this, then it is right up your street. Just bare this in mind, be in the right mind set when you sit down to watch it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You're Left Confused...but Satisfied
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Juan Mendoza
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is definitely a film that you come back to watch again for two reasons: 1) You're not immediately sure you understood what happened, and 2) You are left feeling mentally/philosophically engaged. To be straight, you should know going into this film that you should have an eye for subtleties and symbolism, and above all, an open mind. From the onset, you can tell that the director is not going to attempt to appeal to the audience with fast paced action, explosions, etc. but rather with direct mental stimulation. You watch this film with a similar manner to that of an obscure yet significant painting, because the themes that are presented to you feel epic, and they are left open for interpretation; the lack of dialogue in favor of eerie music helps. However, even through all of the confusion, and tense mood, you also know you are watching something beautiful. With a few minor exceptions, the screenplay feels like it is consistently appealing to the eye in a simple nature. And when it does change into more flashy and complex imagery, your eyes seem to welcome it. I wouldn't say it is in my personal favorite films, but either way I am still thinking about it weeks after having watched it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A picture of a soup can is not art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    royu2
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If art has to be explained, it's not art, if you have ask "er, is that art?", it's not art. Art speaks for itself, that's the whole point of art, it is a self-reviewing piece of work that needs no further investigation. Art and fashion are not the same thing, they are in fact polar opposites. Fashion is a popularly contest and it's existence forever lives on borrowed time and the approval of others. Art is fundamentally timeless. Fashion requires an accepting audience to exist, art does not. I know a lot of artists, half my family consider themselves "artists". What amazes me is that it seems the deeper into "art" they get the more the lines are blurred between art and fashion. Fashion is NOT art. 2001 A Space Odyssey is fashion, it does not stand on it's own two feet as art, because it isn't. It must be explained, which by default makes it not art, but fashion. A picture of a soup can being worth millions of dollars can only be explained through the prism of fashion. This movie really is as terrible and pointless as a picture of a soup can. The only people that think this is art are people who don't understand that art and fashion are two very different things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visually stunning.Kubrick's best work.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those films that make me wish I had been around to see it on the big screen.I envy those that got that opportunity,because as visually stunning as it is on the small screen,it had to be 100 times so in the theater.The orchestral arrangements during space sequences were the best possible soundtrack for what would be a silent visual in reality.The other visual effect,such as those inside the space craft look to be way ahead of their time.As for the story,it plays just like a thriller as we have a great man vs. machine angle.Of all the Stanley Kubrick films I have viewed to date.This visually stunning production is by far the best.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Unprecedented, Unique & Unparalleled Achievement In Motion Picture History.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An unprecedented, unique & unparalleled achievement in motion picture history, 2001: A Space Odyssey is a path-breaking cinema and a splendid work of art. Far ahead of its time and universally & unanimously hailed as one of the greatest & most influential films ever made, this film redefines its genre unlike anything before or after it, features some of the most iconic moments ever captured on film, and is an elegant mix of remarkable cinematography, pioneering visual & sound effects, scientific accuracy, epic score & a distinct style of narration. Not only is 2001: A Space Odyssey a visually spellbinding experience filmed with great artistry but also, in my opinion, Stanley Kubrick's magnum opus. 2001: A Space Odyssey deals with the elements of human evolution, technology, artificial intelligence & extra-terrestrial life. It is divided into 3 segments & an epilogue, each connected with an extra-terrestrial reference. The movie begins with the Dawn of Man segment set in prehistoric Africa, where a group of primitive apes discover a mysterious black monolith which eventually alters their course of evolution. The movie then takes a giant leap into the future, the year 2001, when another monolith is discovered on moon. The film then approaches its third segment where the main plot finally surfaces aboard a spaceship on its mission to Jupiter, which later culminates with an ambiguous ending that's debatable to this date. Stanley Kubrick is one of cinema's most influential & innovative directors, with a legacy that, arguably, has no equals. 2001: A Space Odyssey is Kubrick's first venture into the science fiction genre where he ended up crafting a cinematic jewel that's one of the first to take its genre seriously. Putting science in science-fiction, this masterpiece by Kubrick is as mysterious as the man himself and although all the usual Kubrick's trademarks exist in the film, the entire treatment is very different from other films of his or even others. The pace is intentionally slowed down, the narration is through visuals & music, the performances are honest, the exchange of dialogues is minimal and the plot is engaging & confusing at the same time but gets better, more transparent & satisfying on multiple viewings. Coming to technical aspects, this film is an incredible work of breathtaking art. The cinematography is a delight for everyone who appreciates great photography. The beautiful captures of landscapes and jaw-dropping exploration of the space (most notably The Moon) makes it one of the finest works that cinema has to offer. Editing is precisely done. Set pieces are wonderful to look at and the visual & sound effects are so groundbreaking & ahead of its time that many movies boasting CGI stuff today are still no match to it. Also, it is one of the most accurate depiction of space travel & the silence that fills the space scenes not only serves its purpose as accurate science, but also adds to the mood of the film. The fact that Kubrick shot the moon scenes with that level of detail & accuracy even before the Apollo landing never fails to impress. Even though 2001 is a visual ride of astonishing beauty, it isn't a movie that everyone is going to appreciate. It's a long technical film that runs at an unusually slow pace, is full of metaphysical complexities and is destined to polarize viewers. Even though some will find it incredibly boring & a strong test of their patience, there will be many who will end up being completely engulfed by its sheer beauty and an unusual blend of poetry & mystery in its bizarre plot. It has inspired almost every film of its genre since its release and will continue to do so for as long as cinema exists. Because after all, this is the film that started it all and deserves to be seen by everyone who appreciates great cinema, especially the fans of Kubrick & science-fiction genre. It's an amazing journey through space & time that raises pretty good questions about our very own existence, is full of philosophical & allegorical meanings, and concludes with an ending that is open for each viewer to interpret his/her way. Overall, what impressed me the most about this film is its impressive detailing in every frame, captivating photography, dazzling visuals & great characterization of the Discovery One spaceship's computer HAL 9000, where Kubrick examines the idea of machines turning against the very people they were meant to serve, decades before James Cameron came up with The Terminator or Wachowski Bros. crafted the next big sci-fi leap with The Matrix. Scoring full marks in all aspects of filmmaking and influencing not only cinema but science, culture & art as well, 2001: A Space Odyssey is a landmark moment in motion picture history that almost killed its genre for it set a standard so high that it hasn't been equaled or challenged ever since. Advancements in science & technology may have brought few films closer to it on a technical scale but overall, it remains a superior film & a pinnacle of science-fiction filmmaking and is possibly the best work from a legendary filmmaker who had made a career out of crafting one masterpiece after another. Highly recommended. Multiple viewings advised.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cannot be described
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    krustykrabpizza
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    2001: A Space Odyssey is like music. How do you tell someone that you like this movie? It's difficult, but to put it plainly, you can't. You just watch it. Listen to it. I was confused as to why I loved this movie so much even directly after the end credits began to roll, the story was quite confusing and there was a 20-minute scene at the start where monkeys were just being observed in a voyeuristic manner. It sounds like I'm appealing to a "certain intelligence" and I really don't like that, but it truly is a marvel that transcends language and all logical constructs. Don't read the reviews for this movie if you haven't seen it, just watch it. It's an experience that can only be unraveled from a personal point of view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated waste of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eumarius_89
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my first review. I didn't like this movie and i am seriously mad that i spent almost three hours of my life watching this. Of course that there will be some people who don't agree with me. Why i hate it so much: -Very very very slow paced, made me fall asleep a few times -I didn't understand the plot, maybe because i haven't read the book, but a movie shouldn't be made just for the people who read the book -Boring -Very little action -Very little character development -NO ENTERTAINMENT The ending was very complex and very boring. Maybe this is not the most objective review but i hope it will be useful for some to avoid making the same mistake i did. I normally don't feel this mad after watching a bad movie but this is so overrated, i just want people to realize it's not worth watching. My vote 1/10, i feel sorry for wasting my time with this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film-Strange author
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jam77-549-49835
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the three greatest movies of all time,I know it's a a.c Clarke(and we all know what that guys about) But if you get past that it has to be said that the sheer originality and breathtaking cinematography is enough of a reason to love this movie but the story builds to an absolute blow ya head off jaw dropping finale. There are times when you will be confused but later (much later for me) all will become clear. If Sci-Fi is your thing then this is your movie if not then this is still your movie, if you're going to trust any review then let it be this one. Everyone should see this film at least once believe me you will not regret it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dazzling Masterpiece.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stanley Kubrick's visually dazzling, intellectually stimulating and ambitious film makes one of the best uses of the medium known as cinema ever made. Film begins when humans were still apes, and how, when one of them touches a huge, mysterious monolith, he is pushed forward in evolution, and uses an old bone as a tool(to smash and kill of course...) Thousands of years later, man is now on the moon, and another monolith is uncovered, inspiring a spaceship crew to investigate, causing the on board ship computer HAL9000 to malfunction(sensing the oncoming next evolution it cannot experience?) One astronaut enters the monolith, and he(and the viewer) see an astonishing, even overwhelming assault on the senses that leads to... Well, for those who haven't seen it, no spoilers, but just consider how a "star child" fits in at the end... A unique achievement in film history, not to be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chrisborg1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw 2001: A Space Odyssey and I was blown away by the effects, the characters, and story. Now, when you see this movie you may not get it at first (I did not) but you have to think about it. This movie's story telling method is very different compared to nowadays but, I guess that's what makes it special. And in my opinion this is Kubrick's best film (but all of them are great) I think that when someone sees this they may dismiss it and say "this movie is so slow" which yes it may be slow but Kubrick did it that way so you could marvel at the terrific detail of the sets and all the little details that make the future so amazing. An amazing movie and great visual effects too: 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need the right mind set
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Martin
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First let me introduce myself, I am a 21 year old boy from the UK. I have very mixed reviews about this film, and am sure I am not the only one. I do not believe this to be a marmite film as most of the reviews suggest. I can and do see this from the point of view of both parties, seeing it as a boring waste of time and seeing it as sci-fi/cinematic history. I do agree, the story line is very scarce. There isn't that much happens, and when it does it is over before you even realise its begun. There is a lot of slow, boring and un-necessarily long clips of pretty much nothing; ships/people floating around, someone running, a phone call, a conversation that offers very little to the plot. I am not a troglodyte as some of the lovers of this film may be starting to think. I understand why it is included and done the way it is, but that doesn't stop it from being incredibly boring. However, to see this from a positive point of view, one must remember that this was made in the mid-to-late 1960's. Meaning that everything done in this was done for real, rather than CGI as everything is now. For this reason I don't feel that it can be put in the same class as modern sci-fi films. I sadly have not read the book of this, I have just decided to watch the film because my friend likes to quote it to me and I wanted to see what she was going on about. This left me very skeptical when I started watching, especially as seemingly nothing was actually happening. You really do have to keep watching and thinking about what it is actually depicting. A large amount of the themes and science fiction ideas were depicted on screen for the first time in this film and is therefore giving a visual insight into what mankind has predicted the future will be like and it is remarkable how much they have actually gotten right for what we have already accomplished and what we are still working on. A lot of the ideas in this film are still being copied to this day, and has now actually got me questioning Ridley Scott's work. I am not saying that Scott has copied Kubrick, just that some of the praises Scott has received shouldn't really be given solely to him for his work in the sci-fi genre. Kubrick has managed to show to the world the realism of space. We all watch films these days and like to point out, "that couldn't happen", "that would never happen", etc. etc. That is the reason behind all the slow and uneventful scenes, it is being kept to a realistic standard of how it would actually have to happen and to show you how slow a long space trip like that would actually be. The shots of space exploration also show demonstrations of the physical properties of our universe and how things actually happen. So, to conclude. Although this may not be an exciting, eventful or thrilling film, it is certainly a feat of cinematography. It more depicts the realistic side of sci-fi rather than the laser guns and phasers of popular sci-fi shows. So if you are looking for a fast paced, action sci-fi, then this isn't for you. If you more enjoy the technological/engineering side of themes like this, then it is right up your street. Just bare this in mind, be in the right mind set when you sit down to watch it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You're Left Confused...but Satisfied
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Juan Mendoza
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is definitely a film that you come back to watch again for two reasons: 1) You're not immediately sure you understood what happened, and 2) You are left feeling mentally/philosophically engaged. To be straight, you should know going into this film that you should have an eye for subtleties and symbolism, and above all, an open mind. From the onset, you can tell that the director is not going to attempt to appeal to the audience with fast paced action, explosions, etc. but rather with direct mental stimulation. You watch this film with a similar manner to that of an obscure yet significant painting, because the themes that are presented to you feel epic, and they are left open for interpretation; the lack of dialogue in favor of eerie music helps. However, even through all of the confusion, and tense mood, you also know you are watching something beautiful. With a few minor exceptions, the screenplay feels like it is consistently appealing to the eye in a simple nature. And when it does change into more flashy and complex imagery, your eyes seem to welcome it. I wouldn't say it is in my personal favorite films, but either way I am still thinking about it weeks after having watched it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A picture of a soup can is not art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    royu2
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If art has to be explained, it's not art, if you have ask "er, is that art?", it's not art. Art speaks for itself, that's the whole point of art, it is a self-reviewing piece of work that needs no further investigation. Art and fashion are not the same thing, they are in fact polar opposites. Fashion is a popularly contest and it's existence forever lives on borrowed time and the approval of others. Art is fundamentally timeless. Fashion requires an accepting audience to exist, art does not. I know a lot of artists, half my family consider themselves "artists". What amazes me is that it seems the deeper into "art" they get the more the lines are blurred between art and fashion. Fashion is NOT art. 2001 A Space Odyssey is fashion, it does not stand on it's own two feet as art, because it isn't. It must be explained, which by default makes it not art, but fashion. A picture of a soup can being worth millions of dollars can only be explained through the prism of fashion. This movie really is as terrible and pointless as a picture of a soup can. The only people that think this is art are people who don't understand that art and fashion are two very different things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visually stunning.Kubrick's best work.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those films that make me wish I had been around to see it on the big screen.I envy those that got that opportunity,because as visually stunning as it is on the small screen,it had to be 100 times so in the theater.The orchestral arrangements during space sequences were the best possible soundtrack for what would be a silent visual in reality.The other visual effect,such as those inside the space craft look to be way ahead of their time.As for the story,it plays just like a thriller as we have a great man vs. machine angle.Of all the Stanley Kubrick films I have viewed to date.This visually stunning production is by far the best.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Unprecedented, Unique & Unparalleled Achievement In Motion Picture History.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An unprecedented, unique & unparalleled achievement in motion picture history, 2001: A Space Odyssey is a path-breaking cinema and a splendid work of art. Far ahead of its time and universally & unanimously hailed as one of the greatest & most influential films ever made, this film redefines its genre unlike anything before or after it, features some of the most iconic moments ever captured on film, and is an elegant mix of remarkable cinematography, pioneering visual & sound effects, scientific accuracy, epic score & a distinct style of narration. Not only is 2001: A Space Odyssey a visually spellbinding experience filmed with great artistry but also, in my opinion, Stanley Kubrick's magnum opus. 2001: A Space Odyssey deals with the elements of human evolution, technology, artificial intelligence & extra-terrestrial life. It is divided into 3 segments & an epilogue, each connected with an extra-terrestrial reference. The movie begins with the Dawn of Man segment set in prehistoric Africa, where a group of primitive apes discover a mysterious black monolith which eventually alters their course of evolution. The movie then takes a giant leap into the future, the year 2001, when another monolith is discovered on moon. The film then approaches its third segment where the main plot finally surfaces aboard a spaceship on its mission to Jupiter, which later culminates with an ambiguous ending that's debatable to this date. Stanley Kubrick is one of cinema's most influential & innovative directors, with a legacy that, arguably, has no equals. 2001: A Space Odyssey is Kubrick's first venture into the science fiction genre where he ended up crafting a cinematic jewel that's one of the first to take its genre seriously. Putting science in science-fiction, this masterpiece by Kubrick is as mysterious as the man himself and although all the usual Kubrick's trademarks exist in the film, the entire treatment is very different from other films of his or even others. The pace is intentionally slowed down, the narration is through visuals & music, the performances are honest, the exchange of dialogues is minimal and the plot is engaging & confusing at the same time but gets better, more transparent & satisfying on multiple viewings. Coming to technical aspects, this film is an incredible work of breathtaking art. The cinematography is a delight for everyone who appreciates great photography. The beautiful captures of landscapes and jaw-dropping exploration of the space (most notably The Moon) makes it one of the finest works that cinema has to offer. Editing is precisely done. Set pieces are wonderful to look at and the visual & sound effects are so groundbreaking & ahead of its time that many movies boasting CGI stuff today are still no match to it. Also, it is one of the most accurate depiction of space travel & the silence that fills the space scenes not only serves its purpose as accurate science, but also adds to the mood of the film. The fact that Kubrick shot the moon scenes with that level of detail & accuracy even before the Apollo landing never fails to impress. Even though 2001 is a visual ride of astonishing beauty, it isn't a movie that everyone is going to appreciate. It's a long technical film that runs at an unusually slow pace, is full of metaphysical complexities and is destined to polarize viewers. Even though some will find it incredibly boring & a strong test of their patience, there will be many who will end up being completely engulfed by its sheer beauty and an unusual blend of poetry & mystery in its bizarre plot. It has inspired almost every film of its genre since its release and will continue to do so for as long as cinema exists. Because after all, this is the film that started it all and deserves to be seen by everyone who appreciates great cinema, especially the fans of Kubrick & science-fiction genre. It's an amazing journey through space & time that raises pretty good questions about our very own existence, is full of philosophical & allegorical meanings, and concludes with an ending that is open for each viewer to interpret his/her way. Overall, what impressed me the most about this film is its impressive detailing in every frame, captivating photography, dazzling visuals & great characterization of the Discovery One spaceship's computer HAL 9000, where Kubrick examines the idea of machines turning against the very people they were meant to serve, decades before James Cameron came up with The Terminator or Wachowski Bros. crafted the next big sci-fi leap with The Matrix. Scoring full marks in all aspects of filmmaking and influencing not only cinema but science, culture & art as well, 2001: A Space Odyssey is a landmark moment in motion picture history that almost killed its genre for it set a standard so high that it hasn't been equaled or challenged ever since. Advancements in science & technology may have brought few films closer to it on a technical scale but overall, it remains a superior film & a pinnacle of science-fiction filmmaking and is possibly the best work from a legendary filmmaker who had made a career out of crafting one masterpiece after another. Highly recommended. Multiple viewings advised.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cannot be described
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    krustykrabpizza
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    2001: A Space Odyssey is like music. How do you tell someone that you like this movie? It's difficult, but to put it plainly, you can't. You just watch it. Listen to it. I was confused as to why I loved this movie so much even directly after the end credits began to roll, the story was quite confusing and there was a 20-minute scene at the start where monkeys were just being observed in a voyeuristic manner. It sounds like I'm appealing to a "certain intelligence" and I really don't like that, but it truly is a marvel that transcends language and all logical constructs. Don't read the reviews for this movie if you haven't seen it, just watch it. It's an experience that can only be unraveled from a personal point of view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated waste of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eumarius_89
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my first review. I didn't like this movie and i am seriously mad that i spent almost three hours of my life watching this. Of course that there will be some people who don't agree with me. Why i hate it so much: -Very very very slow paced, made me fall asleep a few times -I didn't understand the plot, maybe because i haven't read the book, but a movie shouldn't be made just for the people who read the book -Boring -Very little action -Very little character development -NO ENTERTAINMENT The ending was very complex and very boring. Maybe this is not the most objective review but i hope it will be useful for some to avoid making the same mistake i did. I normally don't feel this mad after watching a bad movie but this is so overrated, i just want people to realize it's not worth watching. My vote 1/10, i feel sorry for wasting my time with this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film-Strange author
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jam77-549-49835
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the three greatest movies of all time,I know it's a a.c Clarke(and we all know what that guys about) But if you get past that it has to be said that the sheer originality and breathtaking cinematography is enough of a reason to love this movie but the story builds to an absolute blow ya head off jaw dropping finale. There are times when you will be confused but later (much later for me) all will become clear. If Sci-Fi is your thing then this is your movie if not then this is still your movie, if you're going to trust any review then let it be this one. Everyone should see this film at least once believe me you will not regret it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dazzling Masterpiece.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stanley Kubrick's visually dazzling, intellectually stimulating and ambitious film makes one of the best uses of the medium known as cinema ever made. Film begins when humans were still apes, and how, when one of them touches a huge, mysterious monolith, he is pushed forward in evolution, and uses an old bone as a tool(to smash and kill of course...) Thousands of years later, man is now on the moon, and another monolith is uncovered, inspiring a spaceship crew to investigate, causing the on board ship computer HAL9000 to malfunction(sensing the oncoming next evolution it cannot experience?) One astronaut enters the monolith, and he(and the viewer) see an astonishing, even overwhelming assault on the senses that leads to... Well, for those who haven't seen it, no spoilers, but just consider how a "star child" fits in at the end... A unique achievement in film history, not to be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chrisborg1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw 2001: A Space Odyssey and I was blown away by the effects, the characters, and story. Now, when you see this movie you may not get it at first (I did not) but you have to think about it. This movie's story telling method is very different compared to nowadays but, I guess that's what makes it special. And in my opinion this is Kubrick's best film (but all of them are great) I think that when someone sees this they may dismiss it and say "this movie is so slow" which yes it may be slow but Kubrick did it that way so you could marvel at the terrific detail of the sets and all the little details that make the future so amazing. An amazing movie and great visual effects too: 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need the right mind set
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Martin
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First let me introduce myself, I am a 21 year old boy from the UK. I have very mixed reviews about this film, and am sure I am not the only one. I do not believe this to be a marmite film as most of the reviews suggest. I can and do see this from the point of view of both parties, seeing it as a boring waste of time and seeing it as sci-fi/cinematic history. I do agree, the story line is very scarce. There isn't that much happens, and when it does it is over before you even realise its begun. There is a lot of slow, boring and un-necessarily long clips of pretty much nothing; ships/people floating around, someone running, a phone call, a conversation that offers very little to the plot. I am not a troglodyte as some of the lovers of this film may be starting to think. I understand why it is included and done the way it is, but that doesn't stop it from being incredibly boring. However, to see this from a positive point of view, one must remember that this was made in the mid-to-late 1960's. Meaning that everything done in this was done for real, rather than CGI as everything is now. For this reason I don't feel that it can be put in the same class as modern sci-fi films. I sadly have not read the book of this, I have just decided to watch the film because my friend likes to quote it to me and I wanted to see what she was going on about. This left me very skeptical when I started watching, especially as seemingly nothing was actually happening. You really do have to keep watching and thinking about what it is actually depicting. A large amount of the themes and science fiction ideas were depicted on screen for the first time in this film and is therefore giving a visual insight into what mankind has predicted the future will be like and it is remarkable how much they have actually gotten right for what we have already accomplished and what we are still working on. A lot of the ideas in this film are still being copied to this day, and has now actually got me questioning Ridley Scott's work. I am not saying that Scott has copied Kubrick, just that some of the praises Scott has received shouldn't really be given solely to him for his work in the sci-fi genre. Kubrick has managed to show to the world the realism of space. We all watch films these days and like to point out, "that couldn't happen", "that would never happen", etc. etc. That is the reason behind all the slow and uneventful scenes, it is being kept to a realistic standard of how it would actually have to happen and to show you how slow a long space trip like that would actually be. The shots of space exploration also show demonstrations of the physical properties of our universe and how things actually happen. So, to conclude. Although this may not be an exciting, eventful or thrilling film, it is certainly a feat of cinematography. It more depicts the realistic side of sci-fi rather than the laser guns and phasers of popular sci-fi shows. So if you are looking for a fast paced, action sci-fi, then this isn't for you. If you more enjoy the technological/engineering side of themes like this, then it is right up your street. Just bare this in mind, be in the right mind set when you sit down to watch it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You're Left Confused...but Satisfied
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Juan Mendoza
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is definitely a film that you come back to watch again for two reasons: 1) You're not immediately sure you understood what happened, and 2) You are left feeling mentally/philosophically engaged. To be straight, you should know going into this film that you should have an eye for subtleties and symbolism, and above all, an open mind. From the onset, you can tell that the director is not going to attempt to appeal to the audience with fast paced action, explosions, etc. but rather with direct mental stimulation. You watch this film with a similar manner to that of an obscure yet significant painting, because the themes that are presented to you feel epic, and they are left open for interpretation; the lack of dialogue in favor of eerie music helps. However, even through all of the confusion, and tense mood, you also know you are watching something beautiful. With a few minor exceptions, the screenplay feels like it is consistently appealing to the eye in a simple nature. And when it does change into more flashy and complex imagery, your eyes seem to welcome it. I wouldn't say it is in my personal favorite films, but either way I am still thinking about it weeks after having watched it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A picture of a soup can is not art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    royu2
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If art has to be explained, it's not art, if you have ask "er, is that art?", it's not art. Art speaks for itself, that's the whole point of art, it is a self-reviewing piece of work that needs no further investigation. Art and fashion are not the same thing, they are in fact polar opposites. Fashion is a popularly contest and it's existence forever lives on borrowed time and the approval of others. Art is fundamentally timeless. Fashion requires an accepting audience to exist, art does not. I know a lot of artists, half my family consider themselves "artists". What amazes me is that it seems the deeper into "art" they get the more the lines are blurred between art and fashion. Fashion is NOT art. 2001 A Space Odyssey is fashion, it does not stand on it's own two feet as art, because it isn't. It must be explained, which by default makes it not art, but fashion. A picture of a soup can being worth millions of dollars can only be explained through the prism of fashion. This movie really is as terrible and pointless as a picture of a soup can. The only people that think this is art are people who don't understand that art and fashion are two very different things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visually stunning.Kubrick's best work.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those films that make me wish I had been around to see it on the big screen.I envy those that got that opportunity,because as visually stunning as it is on the small screen,it had to be 100 times so in the theater.The orchestral arrangements during space sequences were the best possible soundtrack for what would be a silent visual in reality.The other visual effect,such as those inside the space craft look to be way ahead of their time.As for the story,it plays just like a thriller as we have a great man vs. machine angle.Of all the Stanley Kubrick films I have viewed to date.This visually stunning production is by far the best.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Unprecedented, Unique & Unparalleled Achievement In Motion Picture History.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An unprecedented, unique & unparalleled achievement in motion picture history, 2001: A Space Odyssey is a path-breaking cinema and a splendid work of art. Far ahead of its time and universally & unanimously hailed as one of the greatest & most influential films ever made, this film redefines its genre unlike anything before or after it, features some of the most iconic moments ever captured on film, and is an elegant mix of remarkable cinematography, pioneering visual & sound effects, scientific accuracy, epic score & a distinct style of narration. Not only is 2001: A Space Odyssey a visually spellbinding experience filmed with great artistry but also, in my opinion, Stanley Kubrick's magnum opus. 2001: A Space Odyssey deals with the elements of human evolution, technology, artificial intelligence & extra-terrestrial life. It is divided into 3 segments & an epilogue, each connected with an extra-terrestrial reference. The movie begins with the Dawn of Man segment set in prehistoric Africa, where a group of primitive apes discover a mysterious black monolith which eventually alters their course of evolution. The movie then takes a giant leap into the future, the year 2001, when another monolith is discovered on moon. The film then approaches its third segment where the main plot finally surfaces aboard a spaceship on its mission to Jupiter, which later culminates with an ambiguous ending that's debatable to this date. Stanley Kubrick is one of cinema's most influential & innovative directors, with a legacy that, arguably, has no equals. 2001: A Space Odyssey is Kubrick's first venture into the science fiction genre where he ended up crafting a cinematic jewel that's one of the first to take its genre seriously. Putting science in science-fiction, this masterpiece by Kubrick is as mysterious as the man himself and although all the usual Kubrick's trademarks exist in the film, the entire treatment is very different from other films of his or even others. The pace is intentionally slowed down, the narration is through visuals & music, the performances are honest, the exchange of dialogues is minimal and the plot is engaging & confusing at the same time but gets better, more transparent & satisfying on multiple viewings. Coming to technical aspects, this film is an incredible work of breathtaking art. The cinematography is a delight for everyone who appreciates great photography. The beautiful captures of landscapes and jaw-dropping exploration of the space (most notably The Moon) makes it one of the finest works that cinema has to offer. Editing is precisely done. Set pieces are wonderful to look at and the visual & sound effects are so groundbreaking & ahead of its time that many movies boasting CGI stuff today are still no match to it. Also, it is one of the most accurate depiction of space travel & the silence that fills the space scenes not only serves its purpose as accurate science, but also adds to the mood of the film. The fact that Kubrick shot the moon scenes with that level of detail & accuracy even before the Apollo landing never fails to impress. Even though 2001 is a visual ride of astonishing beauty, it isn't a movie that everyone is going to appreciate. It's a long technical film that runs at an unusually slow pace, is full of metaphysical complexities and is destined to polarize viewers. Even though some will find it incredibly boring & a strong test of their patience, there will be many who will end up being completely engulfed by its sheer beauty and an unusual blend of poetry & mystery in its bizarre plot. It has inspired almost every film of its genre since its release and will continue to do so for as long as cinema exists. Because after all, this is the film that started it all and deserves to be seen by everyone who appreciates great cinema, especially the fans of Kubrick & science-fiction genre. It's an amazing journey through space & time that raises pretty good questions about our very own existence, is full of philosophical & allegorical meanings, and concludes with an ending that is open for each viewer to interpret his/her way. Overall, what impressed me the most about this film is its impressive detailing in every frame, captivating photography, dazzling visuals & great characterization of the Discovery One spaceship's computer HAL 9000, where Kubrick examines the idea of machines turning against the very people they were meant to serve, decades before James Cameron came up with The Terminator or Wachowski Bros. crafted the next big sci-fi leap with The Matrix. Scoring full marks in all aspects of filmmaking and influencing not only cinema but science, culture & art as well, 2001: A Space Odyssey is a landmark moment in motion picture history that almost killed its genre for it set a standard so high that it hasn't been equaled or challenged ever since. Advancements in science & technology may have brought few films closer to it on a technical scale but overall, it remains a superior film & a pinnacle of science-fiction filmmaking and is possibly the best work from a legendary filmmaker who had made a career out of crafting one masterpiece after another. Highly recommended. Multiple viewings advised.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cannot be described
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    krustykrabpizza
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    2001: A Space Odyssey is like music. How do you tell someone that you like this movie? It's difficult, but to put it plainly, you can't. You just watch it. Listen to it. I was confused as to why I loved this movie so much even directly after the end credits began to roll, the story was quite confusing and there was a 20-minute scene at the start where monkeys were just being observed in a voyeuristic manner. It sounds like I'm appealing to a "certain intelligence" and I really don't like that, but it truly is a marvel that transcends language and all logical constructs. Don't read the reviews for this movie if you haven't seen it, just watch it. It's an experience that can only be unraveled from a personal point of view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated waste of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eumarius_89
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my first review. I didn't like this movie and i am seriously mad that i spent almost three hours of my life watching this. Of course that there will be some people who don't agree with me. Why i hate it so much: -Very very very slow paced, made me fall asleep a few times -I didn't understand the plot, maybe because i haven't read the book, but a movie shouldn't be made just for the people who read the book -Boring -Very little action -Very little character development -NO ENTERTAINMENT The ending was very complex and very boring. Maybe this is not the most objective review but i hope it will be useful for some to avoid making the same mistake i did. I normally don't feel this mad after watching a bad movie but this is so overrated, i just want people to realize it's not worth watching. My vote 1/10, i feel sorry for wasting my time with this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film-Strange author
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jam77-549-49835
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the three greatest movies of all time,I know it's a a.c Clarke(and we all know what that guys about) But if you get past that it has to be said that the sheer originality and breathtaking cinematography is enough of a reason to love this movie but the story builds to an absolute blow ya head off jaw dropping finale. There are times when you will be confused but later (much later for me) all will become clear. If Sci-Fi is your thing then this is your movie if not then this is still your movie, if you're going to trust any review then let it be this one. Everyone should see this film at least once believe me you will not regret it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dazzling Masterpiece.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stanley Kubrick's visually dazzling, intellectually stimulating and ambitious film makes one of the best uses of the medium known as cinema ever made. Film begins when humans were still apes, and how, when one of them touches a huge, mysterious monolith, he is pushed forward in evolution, and uses an old bone as a tool(to smash and kill of course...) Thousands of years later, man is now on the moon, and another monolith is uncovered, inspiring a spaceship crew to investigate, causing the on board ship computer HAL9000 to malfunction(sensing the oncoming next evolution it cannot experience?) One astronaut enters the monolith, and he(and the viewer) see an astonishing, even overwhelming assault on the senses that leads to... Well, for those who haven't seen it, no spoilers, but just consider how a "star child" fits in at the end... A unique achievement in film history, not to be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chrisborg1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw 2001: A Space Odyssey and I was blown away by the effects, the characters, and story. Now, when you see this movie you may not get it at first (I did not) but you have to think about it. This movie's story telling method is very different compared to nowadays but, I guess that's what makes it special. And in my opinion this is Kubrick's best film (but all of them are great) I think that when someone sees this they may dismiss it and say "this movie is so slow" which yes it may be slow but Kubrick did it that way so you could marvel at the terrific detail of the sets and all the little details that make the future so amazing. An amazing movie and great visual effects too: 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need the right mind set
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Martin
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First let me introduce myself, I am a 21 year old boy from the UK. I have very mixed reviews about this film, and am sure I am not the only one. I do not believe this to be a marmite film as most of the reviews suggest. I can and do see this from the point of view of both parties, seeing it as a boring waste of time and seeing it as sci-fi/cinematic history. I do agree, the story line is very scarce. There isn't that much happens, and when it does it is over before you even realise its begun. There is a lot of slow, boring and un-necessarily long clips of pretty much nothing; ships/people floating around, someone running, a phone call, a conversation that offers very little to the plot. I am not a troglodyte as some of the lovers of this film may be starting to think. I understand why it is included and done the way it is, but that doesn't stop it from being incredibly boring. However, to see this from a positive point of view, one must remember that this was made in the mid-to-late 1960's. Meaning that everything done in this was done for real, rather than CGI as everything is now. For this reason I don't feel that it can be put in the same class as modern sci-fi films. I sadly have not read the book of this, I have just decided to watch the film because my friend likes to quote it to me and I wanted to see what she was going on about. This left me very skeptical when I started watching, especially as seemingly nothing was actually happening. You really do have to keep watching and thinking about what it is actually depicting. A large amount of the themes and science fiction ideas were depicted on screen for the first time in this film and is therefore giving a visual insight into what mankind has predicted the future will be like and it is remarkable how much they have actually gotten right for what we have already accomplished and what we are still working on. A lot of the ideas in this film are still being copied to this day, and has now actually got me questioning Ridley Scott's work. I am not saying that Scott has copied Kubrick, just that some of the praises Scott has received shouldn't really be given solely to him for his work in the sci-fi genre. Kubrick has managed to show to the world the realism of space. We all watch films these days and like to point out, "that couldn't happen", "that would never happen", etc. etc. That is the reason behind all the slow and uneventful scenes, it is being kept to a realistic standard of how it would actually have to happen and to show you how slow a long space trip like that would actually be. The shots of space exploration also show demonstrations of the physical properties of our universe and how things actually happen. So, to conclude. Although this may not be an exciting, eventful or thrilling film, it is certainly a feat of cinematography. It more depicts the realistic side of sci-fi rather than the laser guns and phasers of popular sci-fi shows. So if you are looking for a fast paced, action sci-fi, then this isn't for you. If you more enjoy the technological/engineering side of themes like this, then it is right up your street. Just bare this in mind, be in the right mind set when you sit down to watch it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You're Left Confused...but Satisfied
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Juan Mendoza
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is definitely a film that you come back to watch again for two reasons: 1) You're not immediately sure you understood what happened, and 2) You are left feeling mentally/philosophically engaged. To be straight, you should know going into this film that you should have an eye for subtleties and symbolism, and above all, an open mind. From the onset, you can tell that the director is not going to attempt to appeal to the audience with fast paced action, explosions, etc. but rather with direct mental stimulation. You watch this film with a similar manner to that of an obscure yet significant painting, because the themes that are presented to you feel epic, and they are left open for interpretation; the lack of dialogue in favor of eerie music helps. However, even through all of the confusion, and tense mood, you also know you are watching something beautiful. With a few minor exceptions, the screenplay feels like it is consistently appealing to the eye in a simple nature. And when it does change into more flashy and complex imagery, your eyes seem to welcome it. I wouldn't say it is in my personal favorite films, but either way I am still thinking about it weeks after having watched it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A picture of a soup can is not art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    royu2
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If art has to be explained, it's not art, if you have ask "er, is that art?", it's not art. Art speaks for itself, that's the whole point of art, it is a self-reviewing piece of work that needs no further investigation. Art and fashion are not the same thing, they are in fact polar opposites. Fashion is a popularly contest and it's existence forever lives on borrowed time and the approval of others. Art is fundamentally timeless. Fashion requires an accepting audience to exist, art does not. I know a lot of artists, half my family consider themselves "artists". What amazes me is that it seems the deeper into "art" they get the more the lines are blurred between art and fashion. Fashion is NOT art. 2001 A Space Odyssey is fashion, it does not stand on it's own two feet as art, because it isn't. It must be explained, which by default makes it not art, but fashion. A picture of a soup can being worth millions of dollars can only be explained through the prism of fashion. This movie really is as terrible and pointless as a picture of a soup can. The only people that think this is art are people who don't understand that art and fashion are two very different things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visually stunning.Kubrick's best work.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those films that make me wish I had been around to see it on the big screen.I envy those that got that opportunity,because as visually stunning as it is on the small screen,it had to be 100 times so in the theater.The orchestral arrangements during space sequences were the best possible soundtrack for what would be a silent visual in reality.The other visual effect,such as those inside the space craft look to be way ahead of their time.As for the story,it plays just like a thriller as we have a great man vs. machine angle.Of all the Stanley Kubrick films I have viewed to date.This visually stunning production is by far the best.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Unprecedented, Unique & Unparalleled Achievement In Motion Picture History.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An unprecedented, unique & unparalleled achievement in motion picture history, 2001: A Space Odyssey is a path-breaking cinema and a splendid work of art. Far ahead of its time and universally & unanimously hailed as one of the greatest & most influential films ever made, this film redefines its genre unlike anything before or after it, features some of the most iconic moments ever captured on film, and is an elegant mix of remarkable cinematography, pioneering visual & sound effects, scientific accuracy, epic score & a distinct style of narration. Not only is 2001: A Space Odyssey a visually spellbinding experience filmed with great artistry but also, in my opinion, Stanley Kubrick's magnum opus. 2001: A Space Odyssey deals with the elements of human evolution, technology, artificial intelligence & extra-terrestrial life. It is divided into 3 segments & an epilogue, each connected with an extra-terrestrial reference. The movie begins with the Dawn of Man segment set in prehistoric Africa, where a group of primitive apes discover a mysterious black monolith which eventually alters their course of evolution. The movie then takes a giant leap into the future, the year 2001, when another monolith is discovered on moon. The film then approaches its third segment where the main plot finally surfaces aboard a spaceship on its mission to Jupiter, which later culminates with an ambiguous ending that's debatable to this date. Stanley Kubrick is one of cinema's most influential & innovative directors, with a legacy that, arguably, has no equals. 2001: A Space Odyssey is Kubrick's first venture into the science fiction genre where he ended up crafting a cinematic jewel that's one of the first to take its genre seriously. Putting science in science-fiction, this masterpiece by Kubrick is as mysterious as the man himself and although all the usual Kubrick's trademarks exist in the film, the entire treatment is very different from other films of his or even others. The pace is intentionally slowed down, the narration is through visuals & music, the performances are honest, the exchange of dialogues is minimal and the plot is engaging & confusing at the same time but gets better, more transparent & satisfying on multiple viewings. Coming to technical aspects, this film is an incredible work of breathtaking art. The cinematography is a delight for everyone who appreciates great photography. The beautiful captures of landscapes and jaw-dropping exploration of the space (most notably The Moon) makes it one of the finest works that cinema has to offer. Editing is precisely done. Set pieces are wonderful to look at and the visual & sound effects are so groundbreaking & ahead of its time that many movies boasting CGI stuff today are still no match to it. Also, it is one of the most accurate depiction of space travel & the silence that fills the space scenes not only serves its purpose as accurate science, but also adds to the mood of the film. The fact that Kubrick shot the moon scenes with that level of detail & accuracy even before the Apollo landing never fails to impress. Even though 2001 is a visual ride of astonishing beauty, it isn't a movie that everyone is going to appreciate. It's a long technical film that runs at an unusually slow pace, is full of metaphysical complexities and is destined to polarize viewers. Even though some will find it incredibly boring & a strong test of their patience, there will be many who will end up being completely engulfed by its sheer beauty and an unusual blend of poetry & mystery in its bizarre plot. It has inspired almost every film of its genre since its release and will continue to do so for as long as cinema exists. Because after all, this is the film that started it all and deserves to be seen by everyone who appreciates great cinema, especially the fans of Kubrick & science-fiction genre. It's an amazing journey through space & time that raises pretty good questions about our very own existence, is full of philosophical & allegorical meanings, and concludes with an ending that is open for each viewer to interpret his/her way. Overall, what impressed me the most about this film is its impressive detailing in every frame, captivating photography, dazzling visuals & great characterization of the Discovery One spaceship's computer HAL 9000, where Kubrick examines the idea of machines turning against the very people they were meant to serve, decades before James Cameron came up with The Terminator or Wachowski Bros. crafted the next big sci-fi leap with The Matrix. Scoring full marks in all aspects of filmmaking and influencing not only cinema but science, culture & art as well, 2001: A Space Odyssey is a landmark moment in motion picture history that almost killed its genre for it set a standard so high that it hasn't been equaled or challenged ever since. Advancements in science & technology may have brought few films closer to it on a technical scale but overall, it remains a superior film & a pinnacle of science-fiction filmmaking and is possibly the best work from a legendary filmmaker who had made a career out of crafting one masterpiece after another. Highly recommended. Multiple viewings advised.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
