<filme>
 <id>
  1365
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0107274
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Johnny cien pesos
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Johnny, the young student and his 4 friends, decide to rob a bank. They pretend they are customers, and suddenly they take out pistols and force the staff to give all the money to them. ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Johnny, the young student and his 4 friends, decide to rob a bank. They pretend they are customers, and suddenly they take out pistols and force the staff to give all the money to them. When they try to leave, the police appear. The media deal with this story immediately and broadcast everything ...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   police
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   pistol
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   student
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   vandalism
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   silent alarm
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Gustavo Graef Marino
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Gerardo C&aacute;ceres
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Gustavo Graef Marino
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Armando Araiza
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Patricia Rivera
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Willy Semler
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmm...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    r-albury
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a true story, this movie shows the story of Johnny, a Chilean high school student involved in the robbery of a small illegal bank being fronted by a video store. Johnny and the other men involved take the people in the store hostage and negotiate with the police for hours over their escape. The entire spectacle is broadcast over live TV with interviews with Johnny's ex-girlfriend and mother. This film gives an interesting take on the media's role and influence in high profile situations and shows the negative aspects of the media. This movie was strange at best, the cinematography was mediocre and the acting was stilted.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bizarre, frantic, strange.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Samuel-Maldonado
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Johnny one hundred pesos was an ambitious project, with an important message about a culture in a strained transition between a military dictatorship and democracy. Despite its strong intentions, however, the movie came together in such a way as to make it uncomfortable to watch altogether. It is heavy on the symbolism, which can be a good thing -- the media's involvement, the role of Chile's youth, and even the timing of the event is significant. And it does have a strong message behind it. But the movie starts to sacrifice plot for the sake of symbolism; a series of nonsensical events occur that don't make sense apart from the symbolic meaning behind them. Add to this the strange, generally unlikeable, almost painful-to-watch main character and the movie just was not salvageable in my opinion, even with its important message. Not an enjoyable experience overall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite a home run
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachel Henderson
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chile's very own Dog Day Afternoon brings to audiences the story of what should have been the perfect crime but turned out to be a fantastic failure that caused the criminals to find themselves at the center of one of the most media-covered crimes in the history of the country. Johnny Gael Garcia is a seventeen-year-old student in Chile who opts for the life of a criminal in what seems like some dire attempt to find a family and earn respect. As an action movie, the style is completely unique to that of Hollywood's, as is most of Latin American Cinema. However, in the same way it still has something unique to it that gives it an edge when compared to Hollywood action movies. Rather than quick camera cuts and high- action scenes, the story relies more on story than Hollywood. Hollywood can distract viewers from a lack of plot with impressive graphics and special effects while a lower-budget film such as this, is left with the story as the center of attention. Producers of Johnny cien pesos excellently developed Johnny's story by explaining his path to crime with extreme and impressive creativity. In the end, this movie holds its own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    spirals out of control
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Abby Sawyer
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This 1994 film is based on a true story and directed by Gustavo Graef-Marino. Johnny, a young Chilean student, becomes involved with a group of criminals who decide to rob a clandestine money exchange office that fronts as a video store in an apartment building in Santiago. They pretend that they are customers and suddenly whip out guns and demand the money. The police are alerted and they decide to take the employees as hostages. The whole ordeal spirals out of control when the media gets involved and what was supposed to be a minor crime becomes the center of attention while all of Chile watches it unfold on their TV screens. There is a real critique of the media and the role that they play in situations like this. The TV reporter is very persistent and will stop at nothing to get a story that will capture the interest of the viewers. He goes to interview people from Johnny's life and ends up pushing them past their breaking point just for ratings. Overall this movie is a bit strange at times, but it is definitely dramatic and contains an unexpected ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A good genre film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daniel-242
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2000
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can say one thing about this movie: it's full of energy. And maybe looks like just another action movie, but the story has many chilean themes, like the orphan boy, the faceless police and the power of the media in a society with no other connection with the people's life. Very interesting, very good acted.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Realistic depiction of poorer Chilean youth in the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElianaM
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2000
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film presents realistic details of the problems, temptations and other dilemmas faced by the lower middle class and poor youth in urban Santiago (Chile). Though not too different from the plight of poorer urban teenagers worldwide, this drama is nevertheless worthwhile for those particularly interested in Chile. It also features good action scenes, and strong acting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
