<filme>
 <id>
  1367
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109781
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Faust
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A very free adaptation of Marlowe's 'Doctor Faustus', Goethe's 'Faust' and various other treatments of the old legend of the man who sold his soul to the devil. Svankmajer's Faust is a ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A very free adaptation of Marlowe's 'Doctor Faustus', Goethe's 'Faust' and various other treatments of the old legend of the man who sold his soul to the devil. Svankmajer's Faust is a nondescript man who, after being lured by a strange map into a sinister puppet theatre, finds himself immersed in an indescribably weird version of the play, blending live actors, clay model animation and giant puppets.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Animation
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   clay
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   egg
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   surrealism
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   deal with the devil
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   chicken
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Jan Svankmajer
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Johann Wolfgang Goethe
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Christian Dietrich Grabbe
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Petr Cepek
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jan Kraus
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Vladim&iacute;r Kudla
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The most imaginative and unpredictable Faust adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There has been numerous stage and film adaptations of Goethe's tragedy Faust, where the eponymous hero sells his soul to the Devil in exchange for the Devil serving Faust during his time on the Earth, as long as upon death, Faust will serve him in return in Hell. F.W. Murnau's 1926's Faust is probably the most acclaimed film adaptation, whilst Istvan Szabo's 1981 masterpiece Mephisto transformed the setting of the play to WWII-era Germany. I would imagine that there has never been such an imaginative and unpredictable interpretation than animator Jan Svankmajer's 1994 effort. Combining live-action, stop motion animation, and puppetry, the Czech's various talents come together to make a surreal, and brilliant, piece of art. The film begins as Faust (Petr Capek) finds a map on a train that leads him to an abandoned theatre. When there, he accidentally creates a clay baby that develops quickly from a foetus into a fully formed baby. It quickly starts shifting its face into adults, as the Devil starts to attempt communication with Faust. He destroys the baby, and ends up unwillingly on a stage, in costume, accompanied by large wooden puppets who act as the supporting characters. The play and reality start to blend together, as even when our hero pops outside for a cigarette, the puppets follow dressed in human's clothes. The play/story goes on, as Faust plays with his new powers, and is frequently influenced by the Devil. It's quite hard to write a formal review about a film that had its impact on me a couple of hours after the credits have rolled, and some scenes where I genuinely did not know what was happening. It plays out like a sort of medieval Punch and Judy show, with some strangely creepy characters. It's undoubtedly quite childish and playful, but at the same time it is dark and complex, and more than anything else, frequently surreal. In my favourite scene, the Fool character who is reading Faust's textbook discovers that he can the Devil whenever he likes and dismiss him just as quickly. When dismissed, the Devil quickly legs it out the door, dressing himself up in an overcoat and hat and passing the smoking Faust in the street. As he is called back, he is forced to shed the clothes and rush back to the stage to make a explosive entrance. He goes back and forth for about 5 minutes. I couldn't help but laugh at the sheer absurdness of it all. While quite not as stunning as Alice (his Alice In Wonderland adaptation), Faust does constantly surprise, entertain, and bewilder. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost a masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rectangular_businessman
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Faust was the first Jan Svankmajer's movie I've seen and I've been literally stunned by his wicked and exotic interpretation of this classic plot. This is not a literal adaptation of the book written by Goethe, but a surreal combination of the different version of the original story (Like, for example, the play of Cristopher Marlowe) with stop-motion animation, live action performances and puppets. The result it's very interesting and well made, creating a unique and fascinating world. It's easy to see in what way filmmakers like Terry Gilliam, the brothers Quay were influenced by the astounding work of Jan Svankmajer: There is a great, dark atmosphere, filled with bizarre creatures and strange situations, like in the movies of those directors. If you love dark, surreal films, then you will like a lot this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Weird, Mysterious and Unforgettable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eumenides_0
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jan Svankmajer is becoming one of my favorite filmmakers. His Alice movie introduced me to a new world of cinematic animation and surrealism. And now Faust takes me further into that world. Again, he has chosen to adapt one of my favorite books, Christopher Marlowe's Doctor Faustus. This movie has less stop-motion animation than Alice, but it has more surreal imagery. Again Svankmajer shows a talent to create scenes full of dread, dark humor and mystery. Characters quote from the original play, sets change around instantly, opera invades the movie halfway in, men turn into puppets, plasticine creatures become human. This is just a sample of what anyone can find in the movie. And the art direction is great: the sets are grimy, dusty, decadent. It looks like it takes place in a very old world. Once again the filmmaker isn't concerned with realism. This is fiction, and he knows it. When puppets show up, he closes in on the hands moving them. Other times he shows an audience watching the play within the movie, and sometimes Faustus can't even distinguish which is which. This is a great surrealist movie, perhaps superior to Alice. Anyone who enjoys Marlowe's play or a good strange movie should get a kick out of this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Angels, Angles, Demons, and Demonstrations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Polaris_DiB
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like "Alice in Wonderland", the story of Faust has been almost infinitely adapted to various interpretations based on the nationalist and socialistic concerns of the time, making it perfect material for Svankmajer to play with. In terms of Svankmajer's other work, this fits more closely to his 1970 short "Don Sanche", but overall it's the most populated movie of his I've seen thus far. Most of his shorts are rather hermetic, with story lines as splintered as his characters: "Alice" is kept entirely in the young girl's head, "Lunacy" is trapped in an insane asylum, and his shorts are either devoid of people or the very few characters that are there react to their absence. Here, he tries a little bit to provide a world populated with extras and background, but it isn't long before he removes the action (once again) to an abandoned theatre wherein he can get his puppets and claymation to work. Instead of a straight-up adaptation, Svankmajer plays it loose and surreal, introducing multiple layers of narrative and letting them dance with each other. This approach to storytelling is matched by the mixed media he includes with life-sized puppets, stop-motion animation, claymation, and live action, sometimes at the same time, sometimes taking over each other, and sometimes giving the floor to another. It's interesting that the primary recognizable Faust narrative is contained in puppetry, meaning that even behind the metaphysical story of the fateful struggle over a man's soul are unnamed human hands authoring the tale. On one hand, an argument could be made that the story doesn't really even start until the second half of the movie, meaning it could have been cut to about 45 minutes in length; on the other hand, like any serious animator's work, it's really much more about movement, and it never really drags. Of all of Svankmajer's work, this is one that seems like previous knowledge of him would be helpful going into. A lot of the symbolism, such as all of the food that gets eaten, the disembodied leg, the clay baby, and the close-ups of mouths are all much more easy to understand as shorthand to his usual concerns; I feel like had I not recognized them as such, I could have gotten bogged down trying to figure it all out and the movie would have been a bit more confusing. Remember that this story begins with a cracked egg. There are, indeed, many amazing and memorable scenes. The scene in the dressing room where Faust converses to an always metamorphosing Mephistopheles is really where all of the imagery and themes come together in their smoothest and most actualized forms--AND it's enough to disturb for weeks. I especially like the little angels and demons coming out of the big angels and demons; that scene also reflects the "consuming" nature of a lot of the earlier imagery. Anyway, definitely for die-hard fans of Svankmajer, though others might be a little put off, if not by its imagery, then by its pacing. --PolarisDiB
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very different!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Siloty
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i watched this movie and it took quite a long time before i understood what was going on. this movie definitely is a very different movie and i only continued to watch for the experience of the movie. it is very creative though. like the use of claymation,stop-motion and life sized puppets for some of the characters. these creative ideas and the movie's massive "what the?" factor about it is probably why i gave it a 6 out of 10. i would recommend this movie more for the cultural experience of different movies but thats all i can really give it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the nightmare and ecstasy of selling your soul to you-know-who
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jan Svankmajer probably has visions and dreams that few of us would want to have, but luckily for us he's so creative and talented and all-that-and-a-bag-of-chips with a mound of clay and (in this case) marionettes that he can put them all on display on film. His version of Faust is sometimes confusing, bewildering, and, as I gathered from not reading the original play or (sadly) not yet seeing the Murnau silent feature, not altogether makes a lot of sense. This isn't to say the central premise is lost on me, which is of a man who conjures up the force that is Mephistopheles and sells his soul. This is of course shown at one pivotal moment in the film, but if you think you know what to expect from this outcome or how it's presented you might have to rethink things. If you've seen Svankmajer's other films, however, like Alice, then some of his approach shouldn't seem too far out... Actually, it is always very far out, but in an approachable manner, told often in a classical style of cinema that relies often on the unspoken. In this case it's not as non-dialog laden as Alice, as there are often scenes with the marionettes going on and on with their dialogs, and then with the man and the Satan figure him/itself (whether it's a man or an 'it' I can't say for sure, as Svankmajer makes it a being who materializes first as some skull, then into a near reflection of the man himself as some crazy theologian). What draws one in is the lack of abandon for narrative, and the chances he takes in making it self-conscious. It would be one thing to present the puppets themselves, but the editing is feverish; cuts go between the puppets, their movements, and then those of the puppeteer's hands. We never see their faces, but we always know someone is pulling the strings. This is key. But beyond simply that, it's just a pure pleasure to take in how the filmmaker mixes the elements, tricks it up on the audience (i.e. after the marionettes inside for so long, they bust out into the streets without puppeteer's hands), and with the stop motion, and the moments of Bunuelian surrealism with the man going between puppet form and reality, and then out in the middle of some field. I can hardly explain more, and it would be better, after all, if he was allowed to introduce himself. Staggering, near masterpiece work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How To Sell Your Sell To The Devil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joseph Sylvers
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jan Svankmajer(Alice/Conspirators Of Pleasure), who I've been watching a lot of, as of late, has a story that incorporates elements of the Faust play, book, and folk tales, in a unique stop animation/claymation/ and puppetry driven surrealist film. A man receives a map on a subway from a stranger follows it to strange theater, housing life size puppets manipulated by always out of sight puppeteers(only their hands are visible), where he sells his soul to Lucifer, making himself Lucifer's servant until death, and is unmade by his hubris. It's edited much better than Alice was, and is immediately rewarded for it, its much faster and has less boring bits. It's a lot funnier and more horrific, as well. A good addition for Svankmajor fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Surrealist film that doesn't suck!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rooprect
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Surrealism tends to fall in one of 2 categories: (1) Random, confounding, absurd images best enjoyed under the influence of psychomorphic drugs (2) Careful, structured, lucid themes augmented by unusual visuals, all of which is designed to raise our understanding beyond what is "real" Or, I could also say that Surrealism tends to fall in one of 2 categories: (1) Sucky movies (2) Awesome movies I'm happy to report that in both cases, this film is a #2. It can be compared with the masterpieces of Jean Cocteau (Orphee, Beauty & the Beast), or if you prefer the modern stuff it can be compared with Terry Gilliam's early work before he turned into a dope. Svankmajer has that same creative spirit, the same eye for the bizarre and yet the same intelligence in presentation that makes for great art. This isn't simply a masturbatory showcase of "how much weird & pointless stuff we can throw at you", the way many famous Surrealists operate. Rather, this roots itself with a solid, philosophical foundation & excellent dialogue and takes it to the next level with creative visuals. And Svankmajer has a fantastic sense of humour, too, so you never get the feeling that he's some pompous, pretentious jerk showing off what he can do with a camera. I'm rating this a 10/10, and you can see by my voting history that I don't give 10s casually. This is truly a fantastic work. An important note: You should really read Marlowe's "Dr. Faustus" before watching this movie. And be sure it's the MARLOWE version (1604), not the Goethe version (1806) titled "Faust". Yes, the title of this movie is misleading.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Czech masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    karl_consiglio
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A very artistically playfully free film with the use of stop motion which must take a hell of a lot of work. This film is full of alchemical humour with the use of marionettes and what not. This film gave me that nostalgia to visit Prague again. This film is not exactly scary but tremendously haunting and is bound to remain imprinted in your mind. It is so dreamlike that to some it can be pretty disturbing. I think that this film is bursting with magic. Svankmajer is profoundly imaginative and consistent in his creativity, his work is pretty astounding. Here he plays around with the myth of Dr Faustus with the use of very diabolical life size marionettes and demons from hell who offer our main Czech actor all that he could possibly want in return for his soul. This is shockingly unique stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A surreal, masterful blend of reality and stop-motion fantasy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yardfx
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The atmospheric trailer for this film made its viewing essential: Why were disembodied hands beating drums in the woods? Who is Mephistopheles? Why are life-size wooden puppets running through Prague without a puppeteer? Svankmajer's film uses a great range of archetypes in this film that appeal to our sense of symbolism. Many scenes in the film have the poetic resonance of dreams: a cryptic note hurriedly pressed into our hands by a stranger, a dimly lit vaudeville stage, dark, grimly portentous puppets at the threshold, magic, illusion, damnation. Using the Faust legend as a starting point, the film explores such themes as predestination, religion, fear, folly and conjures a mesmerising film that I will watch many times for its enchanting originality. A must-see for lovers of spectacle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The most imaginative and unpredictable Faust adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There has been numerous stage and film adaptations of Goethe's tragedy Faust, where the eponymous hero sells his soul to the Devil in exchange for the Devil serving Faust during his time on the Earth, as long as upon death, Faust will serve him in return in Hell. F.W. Murnau's 1926's Faust is probably the most acclaimed film adaptation, whilst Istvan Szabo's 1981 masterpiece Mephisto transformed the setting of the play to WWII-era Germany. I would imagine that there has never been such an imaginative and unpredictable interpretation than animator Jan Svankmajer's 1994 effort. Combining live-action, stop motion animation, and puppetry, the Czech's various talents come together to make a surreal, and brilliant, piece of art. The film begins as Faust (Petr Capek) finds a map on a train that leads him to an abandoned theatre. When there, he accidentally creates a clay baby that develops quickly from a foetus into a fully formed baby. It quickly starts shifting its face into adults, as the Devil starts to attempt communication with Faust. He destroys the baby, and ends up unwillingly on a stage, in costume, accompanied by large wooden puppets who act as the supporting characters. The play and reality start to blend together, as even when our hero pops outside for a cigarette, the puppets follow dressed in human's clothes. The play/story goes on, as Faust plays with his new powers, and is frequently influenced by the Devil. It's quite hard to write a formal review about a film that had its impact on me a couple of hours after the credits have rolled, and some scenes where I genuinely did not know what was happening. It plays out like a sort of medieval Punch and Judy show, with some strangely creepy characters. It's undoubtedly quite childish and playful, but at the same time it is dark and complex, and more than anything else, frequently surreal. In my favourite scene, the Fool character who is reading Faust's textbook discovers that he can the Devil whenever he likes and dismiss him just as quickly. When dismissed, the Devil quickly legs it out the door, dressing himself up in an overcoat and hat and passing the smoking Faust in the street. As he is called back, he is forced to shed the clothes and rush back to the stage to make a explosive entrance. He goes back and forth for about 5 minutes. I couldn't help but laugh at the sheer absurdness of it all. While quite not as stunning as Alice (his Alice In Wonderland adaptation), Faust does constantly surprise, entertain, and bewilder. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost a masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rectangular_businessman
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Faust was the first Jan Svankmajer's movie I've seen and I've been literally stunned by his wicked and exotic interpretation of this classic plot. This is not a literal adaptation of the book written by Goethe, but a surreal combination of the different version of the original story (Like, for example, the play of Cristopher Marlowe) with stop-motion animation, live action performances and puppets. The result it's very interesting and well made, creating a unique and fascinating world. It's easy to see in what way filmmakers like Terry Gilliam, the brothers Quay were influenced by the astounding work of Jan Svankmajer: There is a great, dark atmosphere, filled with bizarre creatures and strange situations, like in the movies of those directors. If you love dark, surreal films, then you will like a lot this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Weird, Mysterious and Unforgettable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eumenides_0
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jan Svankmajer is becoming one of my favorite filmmakers. His Alice movie introduced me to a new world of cinematic animation and surrealism. And now Faust takes me further into that world. Again, he has chosen to adapt one of my favorite books, Christopher Marlowe's Doctor Faustus. This movie has less stop-motion animation than Alice, but it has more surreal imagery. Again Svankmajer shows a talent to create scenes full of dread, dark humor and mystery. Characters quote from the original play, sets change around instantly, opera invades the movie halfway in, men turn into puppets, plasticine creatures become human. This is just a sample of what anyone can find in the movie. And the art direction is great: the sets are grimy, dusty, decadent. It looks like it takes place in a very old world. Once again the filmmaker isn't concerned with realism. This is fiction, and he knows it. When puppets show up, he closes in on the hands moving them. Other times he shows an audience watching the play within the movie, and sometimes Faustus can't even distinguish which is which. This is a great surrealist movie, perhaps superior to Alice. Anyone who enjoys Marlowe's play or a good strange movie should get a kick out of this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Angels, Angles, Demons, and Demonstrations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Polaris_DiB
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like "Alice in Wonderland", the story of Faust has been almost infinitely adapted to various interpretations based on the nationalist and socialistic concerns of the time, making it perfect material for Svankmajer to play with. In terms of Svankmajer's other work, this fits more closely to his 1970 short "Don Sanche", but overall it's the most populated movie of his I've seen thus far. Most of his shorts are rather hermetic, with story lines as splintered as his characters: "Alice" is kept entirely in the young girl's head, "Lunacy" is trapped in an insane asylum, and his shorts are either devoid of people or the very few characters that are there react to their absence. Here, he tries a little bit to provide a world populated with extras and background, but it isn't long before he removes the action (once again) to an abandoned theatre wherein he can get his puppets and claymation to work. Instead of a straight-up adaptation, Svankmajer plays it loose and surreal, introducing multiple layers of narrative and letting them dance with each other. This approach to storytelling is matched by the mixed media he includes with life-sized puppets, stop-motion animation, claymation, and live action, sometimes at the same time, sometimes taking over each other, and sometimes giving the floor to another. It's interesting that the primary recognizable Faust narrative is contained in puppetry, meaning that even behind the metaphysical story of the fateful struggle over a man's soul are unnamed human hands authoring the tale. On one hand, an argument could be made that the story doesn't really even start until the second half of the movie, meaning it could have been cut to about 45 minutes in length; on the other hand, like any serious animator's work, it's really much more about movement, and it never really drags. Of all of Svankmajer's work, this is one that seems like previous knowledge of him would be helpful going into. A lot of the symbolism, such as all of the food that gets eaten, the disembodied leg, the clay baby, and the close-ups of mouths are all much more easy to understand as shorthand to his usual concerns; I feel like had I not recognized them as such, I could have gotten bogged down trying to figure it all out and the movie would have been a bit more confusing. Remember that this story begins with a cracked egg. There are, indeed, many amazing and memorable scenes. The scene in the dressing room where Faust converses to an always metamorphosing Mephistopheles is really where all of the imagery and themes come together in their smoothest and most actualized forms--AND it's enough to disturb for weeks. I especially like the little angels and demons coming out of the big angels and demons; that scene also reflects the "consuming" nature of a lot of the earlier imagery. Anyway, definitely for die-hard fans of Svankmajer, though others might be a little put off, if not by its imagery, then by its pacing. --PolarisDiB
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very different!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Siloty
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i watched this movie and it took quite a long time before i understood what was going on. this movie definitely is a very different movie and i only continued to watch for the experience of the movie. it is very creative though. like the use of claymation,stop-motion and life sized puppets for some of the characters. these creative ideas and the movie's massive "what the?" factor about it is probably why i gave it a 6 out of 10. i would recommend this movie more for the cultural experience of different movies but thats all i can really give it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the nightmare and ecstasy of selling your soul to you-know-who
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jan Svankmajer probably has visions and dreams that few of us would want to have, but luckily for us he's so creative and talented and all-that-and-a-bag-of-chips with a mound of clay and (in this case) marionettes that he can put them all on display on film. His version of Faust is sometimes confusing, bewildering, and, as I gathered from not reading the original play or (sadly) not yet seeing the Murnau silent feature, not altogether makes a lot of sense. This isn't to say the central premise is lost on me, which is of a man who conjures up the force that is Mephistopheles and sells his soul. This is of course shown at one pivotal moment in the film, but if you think you know what to expect from this outcome or how it's presented you might have to rethink things. If you've seen Svankmajer's other films, however, like Alice, then some of his approach shouldn't seem too far out... Actually, it is always very far out, but in an approachable manner, told often in a classical style of cinema that relies often on the unspoken. In this case it's not as non-dialog laden as Alice, as there are often scenes with the marionettes going on and on with their dialogs, and then with the man and the Satan figure him/itself (whether it's a man or an 'it' I can't say for sure, as Svankmajer makes it a being who materializes first as some skull, then into a near reflection of the man himself as some crazy theologian). What draws one in is the lack of abandon for narrative, and the chances he takes in making it self-conscious. It would be one thing to present the puppets themselves, but the editing is feverish; cuts go between the puppets, their movements, and then those of the puppeteer's hands. We never see their faces, but we always know someone is pulling the strings. This is key. But beyond simply that, it's just a pure pleasure to take in how the filmmaker mixes the elements, tricks it up on the audience (i.e. after the marionettes inside for so long, they bust out into the streets without puppeteer's hands), and with the stop motion, and the moments of Bunuelian surrealism with the man going between puppet form and reality, and then out in the middle of some field. I can hardly explain more, and it would be better, after all, if he was allowed to introduce himself. Staggering, near masterpiece work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How To Sell Your Sell To The Devil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joseph Sylvers
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jan Svankmajer(Alice/Conspirators Of Pleasure), who I've been watching a lot of, as of late, has a story that incorporates elements of the Faust play, book, and folk tales, in a unique stop animation/claymation/ and puppetry driven surrealist film. A man receives a map on a subway from a stranger follows it to strange theater, housing life size puppets manipulated by always out of sight puppeteers(only their hands are visible), where he sells his soul to Lucifer, making himself Lucifer's servant until death, and is unmade by his hubris. It's edited much better than Alice was, and is immediately rewarded for it, its much faster and has less boring bits. It's a lot funnier and more horrific, as well. A good addition for Svankmajor fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Surrealist film that doesn't suck!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rooprect
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Surrealism tends to fall in one of 2 categories: (1) Random, confounding, absurd images best enjoyed under the influence of psychomorphic drugs (2) Careful, structured, lucid themes augmented by unusual visuals, all of which is designed to raise our understanding beyond what is "real" Or, I could also say that Surrealism tends to fall in one of 2 categories: (1) Sucky movies (2) Awesome movies I'm happy to report that in both cases, this film is a #2. It can be compared with the masterpieces of Jean Cocteau (Orphee, Beauty & the Beast), or if you prefer the modern stuff it can be compared with Terry Gilliam's early work before he turned into a dope. Svankmajer has that same creative spirit, the same eye for the bizarre and yet the same intelligence in presentation that makes for great art. This isn't simply a masturbatory showcase of "how much weird & pointless stuff we can throw at you", the way many famous Surrealists operate. Rather, this roots itself with a solid, philosophical foundation & excellent dialogue and takes it to the next level with creative visuals. And Svankmajer has a fantastic sense of humour, too, so you never get the feeling that he's some pompous, pretentious jerk showing off what he can do with a camera. I'm rating this a 10/10, and you can see by my voting history that I don't give 10s casually. This is truly a fantastic work. An important note: You should really read Marlowe's "Dr. Faustus" before watching this movie. And be sure it's the MARLOWE version (1604), not the Goethe version (1806) titled "Faust". Yes, the title of this movie is misleading.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Czech masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    karl_consiglio
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A very artistically playfully free film with the use of stop motion which must take a hell of a lot of work. This film is full of alchemical humour with the use of marionettes and what not. This film gave me that nostalgia to visit Prague again. This film is not exactly scary but tremendously haunting and is bound to remain imprinted in your mind. It is so dreamlike that to some it can be pretty disturbing. I think that this film is bursting with magic. Svankmajer is profoundly imaginative and consistent in his creativity, his work is pretty astounding. Here he plays around with the myth of Dr Faustus with the use of very diabolical life size marionettes and demons from hell who offer our main Czech actor all that he could possibly want in return for his soul. This is shockingly unique stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A surreal, masterful blend of reality and stop-motion fantasy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yardfx
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The atmospheric trailer for this film made its viewing essential: Why were disembodied hands beating drums in the woods? Who is Mephistopheles? Why are life-size wooden puppets running through Prague without a puppeteer? Svankmajer's film uses a great range of archetypes in this film that appeal to our sense of symbolism. Many scenes in the film have the poetic resonance of dreams: a cryptic note hurriedly pressed into our hands by a stranger, a dimly lit vaudeville stage, dark, grimly portentous puppets at the threshold, magic, illusion, damnation. Using the Faust legend as a starting point, the film explores such themes as predestination, religion, fear, folly and conjures a mesmerising film that I will watch many times for its enchanting originality. A must-see for lovers of spectacle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The most imaginative and unpredictable Faust adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There has been numerous stage and film adaptations of Goethe's tragedy Faust, where the eponymous hero sells his soul to the Devil in exchange for the Devil serving Faust during his time on the Earth, as long as upon death, Faust will serve him in return in Hell. F.W. Murnau's 1926's Faust is probably the most acclaimed film adaptation, whilst Istvan Szabo's 1981 masterpiece Mephisto transformed the setting of the play to WWII-era Germany. I would imagine that there has never been such an imaginative and unpredictable interpretation than animator Jan Svankmajer's 1994 effort. Combining live-action, stop motion animation, and puppetry, the Czech's various talents come together to make a surreal, and brilliant, piece of art. The film begins as Faust (Petr Capek) finds a map on a train that leads him to an abandoned theatre. When there, he accidentally creates a clay baby that develops quickly from a foetus into a fully formed baby. It quickly starts shifting its face into adults, as the Devil starts to attempt communication with Faust. He destroys the baby, and ends up unwillingly on a stage, in costume, accompanied by large wooden puppets who act as the supporting characters. The play and reality start to blend together, as even when our hero pops outside for a cigarette, the puppets follow dressed in human's clothes. The play/story goes on, as Faust plays with his new powers, and is frequently influenced by the Devil. It's quite hard to write a formal review about a film that had its impact on me a couple of hours after the credits have rolled, and some scenes where I genuinely did not know what was happening. It plays out like a sort of medieval Punch and Judy show, with some strangely creepy characters. It's undoubtedly quite childish and playful, but at the same time it is dark and complex, and more than anything else, frequently surreal. In my favourite scene, the Fool character who is reading Faust's textbook discovers that he can the Devil whenever he likes and dismiss him just as quickly. When dismissed, the Devil quickly legs it out the door, dressing himself up in an overcoat and hat and passing the smoking Faust in the street. As he is called back, he is forced to shed the clothes and rush back to the stage to make a explosive entrance. He goes back and forth for about 5 minutes. I couldn't help but laugh at the sheer absurdness of it all. While quite not as stunning as Alice (his Alice In Wonderland adaptation), Faust does constantly surprise, entertain, and bewilder. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost a masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rectangular_businessman
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Faust was the first Jan Svankmajer's movie I've seen and I've been literally stunned by his wicked and exotic interpretation of this classic plot. This is not a literal adaptation of the book written by Goethe, but a surreal combination of the different version of the original story (Like, for example, the play of Cristopher Marlowe) with stop-motion animation, live action performances and puppets. The result it's very interesting and well made, creating a unique and fascinating world. It's easy to see in what way filmmakers like Terry Gilliam, the brothers Quay were influenced by the astounding work of Jan Svankmajer: There is a great, dark atmosphere, filled with bizarre creatures and strange situations, like in the movies of those directors. If you love dark, surreal films, then you will like a lot this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Weird, Mysterious and Unforgettable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eumenides_0
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jan Svankmajer is becoming one of my favorite filmmakers. His Alice movie introduced me to a new world of cinematic animation and surrealism. And now Faust takes me further into that world. Again, he has chosen to adapt one of my favorite books, Christopher Marlowe's Doctor Faustus. This movie has less stop-motion animation than Alice, but it has more surreal imagery. Again Svankmajer shows a talent to create scenes full of dread, dark humor and mystery. Characters quote from the original play, sets change around instantly, opera invades the movie halfway in, men turn into puppets, plasticine creatures become human. This is just a sample of what anyone can find in the movie. And the art direction is great: the sets are grimy, dusty, decadent. It looks like it takes place in a very old world. Once again the filmmaker isn't concerned with realism. This is fiction, and he knows it. When puppets show up, he closes in on the hands moving them. Other times he shows an audience watching the play within the movie, and sometimes Faustus can't even distinguish which is which. This is a great surrealist movie, perhaps superior to Alice. Anyone who enjoys Marlowe's play or a good strange movie should get a kick out of this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Angels, Angles, Demons, and Demonstrations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Polaris_DiB
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like "Alice in Wonderland", the story of Faust has been almost infinitely adapted to various interpretations based on the nationalist and socialistic concerns of the time, making it perfect material for Svankmajer to play with. In terms of Svankmajer's other work, this fits more closely to his 1970 short "Don Sanche", but overall it's the most populated movie of his I've seen thus far. Most of his shorts are rather hermetic, with story lines as splintered as his characters: "Alice" is kept entirely in the young girl's head, "Lunacy" is trapped in an insane asylum, and his shorts are either devoid of people or the very few characters that are there react to their absence. Here, he tries a little bit to provide a world populated with extras and background, but it isn't long before he removes the action (once again) to an abandoned theatre wherein he can get his puppets and claymation to work. Instead of a straight-up adaptation, Svankmajer plays it loose and surreal, introducing multiple layers of narrative and letting them dance with each other. This approach to storytelling is matched by the mixed media he includes with life-sized puppets, stop-motion animation, claymation, and live action, sometimes at the same time, sometimes taking over each other, and sometimes giving the floor to another. It's interesting that the primary recognizable Faust narrative is contained in puppetry, meaning that even behind the metaphysical story of the fateful struggle over a man's soul are unnamed human hands authoring the tale. On one hand, an argument could be made that the story doesn't really even start until the second half of the movie, meaning it could have been cut to about 45 minutes in length; on the other hand, like any serious animator's work, it's really much more about movement, and it never really drags. Of all of Svankmajer's work, this is one that seems like previous knowledge of him would be helpful going into. A lot of the symbolism, such as all of the food that gets eaten, the disembodied leg, the clay baby, and the close-ups of mouths are all much more easy to understand as shorthand to his usual concerns; I feel like had I not recognized them as such, I could have gotten bogged down trying to figure it all out and the movie would have been a bit more confusing. Remember that this story begins with a cracked egg. There are, indeed, many amazing and memorable scenes. The scene in the dressing room where Faust converses to an always metamorphosing Mephistopheles is really where all of the imagery and themes come together in their smoothest and most actualized forms--AND it's enough to disturb for weeks. I especially like the little angels and demons coming out of the big angels and demons; that scene also reflects the "consuming" nature of a lot of the earlier imagery. Anyway, definitely for die-hard fans of Svankmajer, though others might be a little put off, if not by its imagery, then by its pacing. --PolarisDiB
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very different!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Siloty
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i watched this movie and it took quite a long time before i understood what was going on. this movie definitely is a very different movie and i only continued to watch for the experience of the movie. it is very creative though. like the use of claymation,stop-motion and life sized puppets for some of the characters. these creative ideas and the movie's massive "what the?" factor about it is probably why i gave it a 6 out of 10. i would recommend this movie more for the cultural experience of different movies but thats all i can really give it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the nightmare and ecstasy of selling your soul to you-know-who
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jan Svankmajer probably has visions and dreams that few of us would want to have, but luckily for us he's so creative and talented and all-that-and-a-bag-of-chips with a mound of clay and (in this case) marionettes that he can put them all on display on film. His version of Faust is sometimes confusing, bewildering, and, as I gathered from not reading the original play or (sadly) not yet seeing the Murnau silent feature, not altogether makes a lot of sense. This isn't to say the central premise is lost on me, which is of a man who conjures up the force that is Mephistopheles and sells his soul. This is of course shown at one pivotal moment in the film, but if you think you know what to expect from this outcome or how it's presented you might have to rethink things. If you've seen Svankmajer's other films, however, like Alice, then some of his approach shouldn't seem too far out... Actually, it is always very far out, but in an approachable manner, told often in a classical style of cinema that relies often on the unspoken. In this case it's not as non-dialog laden as Alice, as there are often scenes with the marionettes going on and on with their dialogs, and then with the man and the Satan figure him/itself (whether it's a man or an 'it' I can't say for sure, as Svankmajer makes it a being who materializes first as some skull, then into a near reflection of the man himself as some crazy theologian). What draws one in is the lack of abandon for narrative, and the chances he takes in making it self-conscious. It would be one thing to present the puppets themselves, but the editing is feverish; cuts go between the puppets, their movements, and then those of the puppeteer's hands. We never see their faces, but we always know someone is pulling the strings. This is key. But beyond simply that, it's just a pure pleasure to take in how the filmmaker mixes the elements, tricks it up on the audience (i.e. after the marionettes inside for so long, they bust out into the streets without puppeteer's hands), and with the stop motion, and the moments of Bunuelian surrealism with the man going between puppet form and reality, and then out in the middle of some field. I can hardly explain more, and it would be better, after all, if he was allowed to introduce himself. Staggering, near masterpiece work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How To Sell Your Sell To The Devil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joseph Sylvers
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jan Svankmajer(Alice/Conspirators Of Pleasure), who I've been watching a lot of, as of late, has a story that incorporates elements of the Faust play, book, and folk tales, in a unique stop animation/claymation/ and puppetry driven surrealist film. A man receives a map on a subway from a stranger follows it to strange theater, housing life size puppets manipulated by always out of sight puppeteers(only their hands are visible), where he sells his soul to Lucifer, making himself Lucifer's servant until death, and is unmade by his hubris. It's edited much better than Alice was, and is immediately rewarded for it, its much faster and has less boring bits. It's a lot funnier and more horrific, as well. A good addition for Svankmajor fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Surrealist film that doesn't suck!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rooprect
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Surrealism tends to fall in one of 2 categories: (1) Random, confounding, absurd images best enjoyed under the influence of psychomorphic drugs (2) Careful, structured, lucid themes augmented by unusual visuals, all of which is designed to raise our understanding beyond what is "real" Or, I could also say that Surrealism tends to fall in one of 2 categories: (1) Sucky movies (2) Awesome movies I'm happy to report that in both cases, this film is a #2. It can be compared with the masterpieces of Jean Cocteau (Orphee, Beauty & the Beast), or if you prefer the modern stuff it can be compared with Terry Gilliam's early work before he turned into a dope. Svankmajer has that same creative spirit, the same eye for the bizarre and yet the same intelligence in presentation that makes for great art. This isn't simply a masturbatory showcase of "how much weird & pointless stuff we can throw at you", the way many famous Surrealists operate. Rather, this roots itself with a solid, philosophical foundation & excellent dialogue and takes it to the next level with creative visuals. And Svankmajer has a fantastic sense of humour, too, so you never get the feeling that he's some pompous, pretentious jerk showing off what he can do with a camera. I'm rating this a 10/10, and you can see by my voting history that I don't give 10s casually. This is truly a fantastic work. An important note: You should really read Marlowe's "Dr. Faustus" before watching this movie. And be sure it's the MARLOWE version (1604), not the Goethe version (1806) titled "Faust". Yes, the title of this movie is misleading.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Czech masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    karl_consiglio
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A very artistically playfully free film with the use of stop motion which must take a hell of a lot of work. This film is full of alchemical humour with the use of marionettes and what not. This film gave me that nostalgia to visit Prague again. This film is not exactly scary but tremendously haunting and is bound to remain imprinted in your mind. It is so dreamlike that to some it can be pretty disturbing. I think that this film is bursting with magic. Svankmajer is profoundly imaginative and consistent in his creativity, his work is pretty astounding. Here he plays around with the myth of Dr Faustus with the use of very diabolical life size marionettes and demons from hell who offer our main Czech actor all that he could possibly want in return for his soul. This is shockingly unique stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A surreal, masterful blend of reality and stop-motion fantasy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yardfx
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The atmospheric trailer for this film made its viewing essential: Why were disembodied hands beating drums in the woods? Who is Mephistopheles? Why are life-size wooden puppets running through Prague without a puppeteer? Svankmajer's film uses a great range of archetypes in this film that appeal to our sense of symbolism. Many scenes in the film have the poetic resonance of dreams: a cryptic note hurriedly pressed into our hands by a stranger, a dimly lit vaudeville stage, dark, grimly portentous puppets at the threshold, magic, illusion, damnation. Using the Faust legend as a starting point, the film explores such themes as predestination, religion, fear, folly and conjures a mesmerising film that I will watch many times for its enchanting originality. A must-see for lovers of spectacle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
