<filme>
 <id>
  1372
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0111219
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Sleeping with Strangers
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Daniel is in danger of losing his inn after another more modern establishment opens next door and steals his guests. He goes to the bank for a loan, but they tell him to hope for a miracle.... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Daniel is in danger of losing his inn after another more modern establishment opens next door and steals his guests. He goes to the bank for a loan, but they tell him to hope for a miracle. Then a limo pulls up carrying the hottest rock star and biggest movie actress around. The two inns compete for these prestigious guests, Daniel trying to save his inn, the other man (Mark) trying to drive Daniel out of business for good (and steal his fiancee).
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   rock star
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   actress
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bank
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   loan
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hotel
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   William T. Bolson
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Joan Carr-Wiggin
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Adrienne Shelly
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kim Huffman
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Alastair Duncan
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bed and Breakfast Rock-n-Roll Treat!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (vonceia@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/1/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sleeping With Strangers is one of those cuddle up in bed with a big bowl of popcorn, kinda movies. It's not heavy on the brain and keeps the laughs coming. The film stars Adrienne Shelly as the looking for love in all the wrong places movie star, Jenny, Neil Duncan as super proper bed and breakfast owner, Daniel, Kim Huff as Teri, Daniel's fianc&eacute;e and secret sweetheart of Daniel's rival, Shawn Thompson as Mark, Daniel's somewhat more modern and rival B&B owner and Scott McNeil, as Todd Warren, The Rock Star. Guys beware; there are places in the movie where it gets a little heavy on the romance. What makes it a cool movie and keeps it from getting too sugary sweet has to be Scott McNeil's Todd Warren. Rock star Todd, pushes the movie right off the cliff. Todd is the essence of the hyperactive; garage band stoner dude-next-door-who got saved by Rock & Roll. His light bulb doesn't shine too bright, but he's got a good heart...somewhere under the hair and through the haze. It was almost scary to watch Scott McNeil channel David Lee Roth, but it was just the right touch. Eye candy for the ladies with a nice set of pipes to boot! Oh yes, most memorable songs, "How Does it Feel" and "Rip My Clothes Off Baby!" This film also had a bunch of Canadian in-jokes, like Daniel's B&B serving macaroni and cheese. There were paparazzi/tabloid jokes and real people vs. star jokes. At one point, one of the star struck characters talks about Jenny, the movie star to her daughter... from two feet away, much in the same manner, as you'd talk about a zoo exhibit. I liked this movie because it was not only fun, but also it ends well too. The characters are allowed to improve...even Todd. Enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eily (familiar@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I bought this movie because I like Adrienne Shelly and the synopsis looked interesting. The first time I watched it I was a bit disappointed. I watched it again a couple years later to see if I liked it well enough to keep it and decided I did. The story is pretty light, like the romantic comedies from the '40s and '50s where the leads would meet, dance with each other for two hours and be madly in love and want to get married. The rock star character is a little over the top, but Neil Duncan is quite charming as the down-on-his-luck innkeeper. If you like him, or if you like Adrienne Shelly, you should like this movie. And if you like the Chris Isaak Show, keep an eye out for Jed Rees. I would give it a 5 or 6 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbelievably Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gazza-30
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I work for a cable movie channel and it is my job to watch films and certify them. Luckily we get more good than bad but this really is the worst film I have ever seen. The acting is poor, the plot is shocking and the less said about the script, the better. I can't believe it got such a high score.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantastic Bedroom Farce Style Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    schatt (schatt@schatt.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2000
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I absolutely love this film. Honestly, this is probably my favorite film. The acting is touching, and the scenery is beautiful. Excellent humor, as well as timing, I really like everything about this film. All in all, I recommend this film to everyone who likes humorous films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
