<filme>
 <id>
  1386
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0105569
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1992
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Tetsuo II: Body Hammer
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Sequel to "Tetsuo" this time has the Iron Man transforming into cyberkinetic gun when a gang of vicious skinheads kidnap his son. When the skinheads capture him, they begin to experiment on... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Sequel to "Tetsuo" this time has the Iron Man transforming into cyberkinetic gun when a gang of vicious skinheads kidnap his son. When the skinheads capture him, they begin to experiment on him...speeding up the mutative process!
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Horror
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   sequel
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   kidnapping
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   experimental film
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   tokyo japan
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   violence
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Shin'ya Tsukamoto
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Shin'ya Tsukamoto
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Tomorowo Taguchi
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Shin'ya Tsukamoto
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Nobu Kanaoka
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Metal machine movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The original Tetsuo: the Iron Man was a pretty unforgettable film. Shot in intense black and white and very pure in its intentions, it was an avant-garde sci-fi horror movie. An immediate cult film. With the follow up, director Shin'ya Tsukamoto has made a film which is more a remake than a true sequel. In this one, he shoots in colour and tries to incorporate a story of sorts. Although, this is a relative statement, as this is still a very weird film and it hardly adheres to cinematic storytelling norms. In essence it is once again about a man turning into a cyborg. Like the first it's visually very striking indeed. It seems to have influenced an awful lot of industrial bands from the 90's, seeing as many of their videos mimic the imagery found in this one. It's soundtrack I guess adds to this seeing as it is full on rock a lot of the time. As a piece of visual art Tetsuo II is a success. However, I do not think it reaches the same level as the original movie, which for my money was such an original piece of work it is hard to outdo. I think the introduction of more story here is also to the film's detriment. The story gets in the way, something you could never accuse the original film of. Still, this remains a pretty intense experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could've used a heavy metal soundtrack lol.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    meteoraxv
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A very "industrial" film. Flesh and metal are one. Steel and concrete are everywhere. Not blood, but corrosion is being drawn. A lot of people say that this film had a higher budget that the first one (which I haven't seen yet). It didn't really feel that way to me. The movie looked very, very low quality and felt very "small". Could've used a heavy metal soundtrack lol. The plot was hard to follow. Whereas a lot of other films are very high on dialogue, this one didn't really had enough dialogue to really be able to follow the story. It was very loose. This movie is being tagged as sci-fi/drama/horror. Sci-fi and drama are about right, but if you're looking for a horror film, meh. Not really. I loved the shots of the skyscrapers. It really added to the industrial feel of this movie. It was alright. Nothing I would really re-watch. I'll check out the first one very soon. I heard there's a part 3 too, so that should be interesting! 6*
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arguably Better than the Original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheExpatriate700
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tetsuo II: Body Hammer is the second entry in the Tetsuo series and arguably an improvement over the first film. It has a more coherent plot, better special effects, and a better flow. Of the two, it was the more accessible film. Body Hammer follows the struggle of a seemingly meek man after his son is kidnapped by a ruthless gang / cult. The cult is run by a mad scientist who seeks to combine man and machine. When the father is subjected to one of these experiments, all hell breaks loose. Although surreal, Tetsuo II is a distinctly more conventional film than its predecessor, which came across as a grotesque student film. The sequel has a more typical sci-fi action plot even as it uses the bizarre animation and concepts that made the original a cult classic. This is actually a good thing, as it makes it easier to discern what the director is trying to get across. The film also benefits from improved special effects and costumes. While the original relied on rather clunky stop motion animation, the effects in Body Hammer are far more convincing. There are some issues with the film's plot, not the least of which being why the gang would grant super powers to someone whose son they had just kidnapped. Nevertheless, it is definitely a worthy follow-up to the original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    More story this time but it's still being an odd movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first movie, "Tetsuo", was mostly a visual experience, while this sequel is also attempting to throw in some more story this time. It makes this movie a bit less artistic and a bit more mainstream than its predecessor but only just a bit though. "Tetsuo II: Body Hammer" is for most part being still one psychedelic ride. There are lots of odd images and events, that just don't make sense in the real world but help to make this still a good and intriguing watch. The movie has a more of a manga vibe and feeling to it than anything else really. Fans of manga will therefore also most likely to appreciate this movie better than the average person. It's obvious that Shinya Tsukamoto has progressed more as a director when watching this movie and compare it to its predecessor. It's also obvious that they had far more money to spend this time, though its still being a low-budget production. This movie doesn't makes much sense as a sequel but then again, the movie just doesn't make much sense in general. It's for most part simply a movie you have to experience, though I admit that it all got a bit tiresome to watch after a while. It also seemed as if the film-makers stopped caring toward the end and dropped the story and all logic. This is when the movie becomes a quite distant and bland one, that only solely relies on its images to keep its viewers interested. This might had all worked for an hour long movie but this movie is about 30 minutes too long for that. This is the foremost reason why the first movie is still the better one, despite the fact that this movie makes more 'sense' and is also a better made one, with better production values and all. Pehaps only truly interesting to watch this movie as a live-action manga. 6/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better made than the first in someways, but worse in others.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Prolox
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After his son is abducted & maybe even killed by some strange men, a frustrated father finds himself morphing into a half man half metal being, full of gears, wires & cables etc. Determined to find his son, his wife is soon abducted & learns a terrifying secret about her husbands connection to the leader of the group. TETSUO 2 is the in colour sequel to the directors really weird, creepy nightmare caught on black & white film TETSUO. This time the director obviously had a bigger budget to play with & just like in the original, the film is filled with stop motion animation, half human half cyborg creatures & people morphing into monsters, it also has somewhat more of a plot which based on the almost no existent plot of the original, is just as wild, however just like the original, the film makes the mistake of overusing it's stop motion & weirdness. The acting is poor & the direction although slightly better than the first, is still pretty bad & the film has nothing to offer those looking for more meat on it's bones regarding a decent plot. The film lacks the weird nightmarish edge of it's predecessor, yet the effects work is just as good. All in all like it's predecessor from which it is connected to in no way other than the same people who made it, the title & the concept of a human slowly mutating into a machine, this is an over-hyped movie that in the end is unforgettable, but fails to satisfy. Hopefully it's in the works sequel TETSUO: THE BULLETMAN is better. **1/2 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's get MetalPhysical...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    poe426
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like Canadian filmmaker David Cronenberg (early on in his career, anyway) and America's own David Lynch, Shinya Tsukamoto has mined (and defined) his own particular brand of cinematic gold. When he's at his best (as he is here), Tsukamoto is a brilliant blacksmith, hammering out searing, steamy imagery with a pulsating potency. Human beings in his films are often hardened, mentally, physically and- most important of all- emotionally. They move through cold, unforgiving industrial landscapes (where buildings tower like sterile tombstones) that become surreal dreamscapes populated by living, breathing nightmares. THE BODY HAMMER offers some of Tsukamoto's most interesting: bodybuilding skinheads (denizens of the darkest depths of the society that spawns them) who literally harden themselves into (first flesh and blood, then) metal monsters bent on total destruction- their own as well as everyone else's. The idea of the rivet guns that cause them to rust out was a great touch- and the pulsing music is a hammer on an anvil. Check out THE BODY HAMMER- if you've got the wiring (guts).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A visually arresting retread/re-imagining of the ideas and themes established in Tetsuo: The Iron Man.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Graham Greene
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tetsuo II: Body Hammer is director Shinya Tsukamoto's sequel/re-make/companion piece to his cult, low-budget 1988 art-house shocker Tetsuo: The Iron Man; a striking piece of hyper-kinetic visual film-making, in which an anonymous Japanese business man finds his body inexplicably mutating into a mass of metal, wire and steal. This version of the story cleans up and clarifies some of the more indistinct and visually abstract points established in the original film, but also adds to it a greater psychological subtext and a broader dramatic scale. The film begins in a more recognisable world than Tsukamoto's original, with the use of colour (albeit, heavily tinted to shades of blue, amber and grey) creating a more recognisable Tokyo that will later be juxtaposed against the hellish underworld depicted in the second half of the story. There's also more believable characterisation, a loose plot and some vague explanations for what is actually happening. Some fans of the original film consider this to be Body Hammer's major failing; with the clarification and characterisation detracting from the weird "wow-factor" of the original Iron Man film; which, as a work of great science-fiction cinema, really existed in its own world devoid of conservative narrative and cinematic convention. I like to appreciate the film from another perspective, however; with Tsukamoto simply fleshing out the themes of the original film a little further, in the same way that a song-writer might often perform a number of different songs about the same subject, but most often, with a different style and arrangement. Tsukamoto has always been more of an artist than a traditional filmmaker, which is why you can see the same themes resurfacing again and again in a different context throughout his work. Tsukamoto's principal preoccupations as a filmmaker are often with alienation, claustrophobia, technology, and most importantly, the human body. Throughout his work, Tsukamoto has looked at the self-inflicted destruction of the body, via films such as Iron Man, Body Hammer and Tokyo Fist; through to the more traditional notions of natural decay and internal destruction with films like A Snake of June, Bullet Ballet and Vital. All of these characteristics are present here, with the film showing us how easily tragedy can strike (and go un-noticed) in a built up city, and how striving to become the ultimate human often involves a melding of man with machine (the natural with the synthetic). The great thing about Tsukamoto's work is that it can often be enjoyed on a number of levels, so, with Body Hammer, we have something that could be viewed as a straight science-fiction film with elements of cyber-punk derived body horror, or instead we could look at some of the deeper, metaphorical interpretations pertaining to the loss of a child, parenthood, childhood trauma, guilt, and perhaps even notions more unsavoury than that! Without wanting to give away too much, there's an element of the plot here that involves the central character's infant son being kidnapped. What follows is quite shocking and heavily symbolic, but I personally like to think that this moment is actually the real impetuous for Body Hammer's plot. So, we have the idea of a character spiralling into a pit of despair, consumed by guilt and losing his mind and the trust of his wife in light of this tragic chain of events! Now, I'm not pretending I know all the answers here, but I like to theorise. Someone else might view the film and take from it an entirely different interpretation but could still find it enjoyable and entertaining. The fact remains that despite the layers of personal interpretation the one thing that will always stand out - regardless of whether or not you liked the film - is the unbridled imagination and visual flair that Tsukamoto brings to the project as it's writer, director, editor, art director, cinematographer, designer and supporting actor. It certainly won't be to all tastes, as even committed admirers of the first Tetsuo film often write this one off as an interesting failure, but for me, this film offers an entirely new perspective on the territory of Iron Man and the usual preoccupations of Tsukamoto's later films, such as Tokyo Fist, A Snake of June and Vital. As Roger Ebert wrote in his review at the time, "Tetsuo II' doesn't rise (or stoop) to the level of conventional action or suspense; it's a design concept, a director's attempt to take some of the ideas in Blade Runner and some of the Arnold Schwarzenegger films and the Japanese animated films like Akira and extend them into grotesquery". It's perhaps not on a par with some of Tsukamoto's other works, chiefly Tetsuo, Tokyo Fist, Gemini and A Snake of June, but regardless, remains a unique viewing experience for those who are genuinely into through-provoking, visually arresting art-house shock cinema. On a final note, I would perhaps suggest starting here and then progressing onto the first Tetsuo film, as this one is a little less challenging and easier to get through and thus acts as a nice little gateway into this particular filmmaker's warped and wonderful world.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maxyg18
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is highly recommended for the fans of its predecessor, although it's not in black and white, doesn't have as good of a soundtrack or have as much surrealism as the first film, but it remains to be a bit more action-packed and (let's not forget) makes a bit more sense. This time, the salary man (the protagonist from the first film) lives a normal life with his family until one day his son gets kidnapped and the salary man is forced to be experimented on by a large a gang of skinheads which speeds up the mutating process of becoming a part-metal weapon and part-human being. It's not really a sequel but it surely is one of the greatest underrated films of-all-time and is about as good as the first film (TETSUO), if not, better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Body Hammer BLOWS
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nedwalton
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was reading in a Stuff Magazine about some of the goriest, bloodiest films that Asia had to offer and I immediately jumped to Netflix to quench my thirst. Boy what a mistake I made. This movie is one of the worst films I have seen. First and foremost no plot, what I expected to be the plot (see: "Revenge") turned into a series of events just happening in a effort to spend their special effects budget of $14.89 and waste studio time. They should have kept their money and not wasted their time nor yours. When a major plot twist occurs, Tetsuo II: Body Hammer is given a new identity and I wasn't buying it. A flashback is given that should answer our questions, but seemed to me like I turned on Showtime at 3:47 am and dropped ACID. The movie continues and spirals out of control with cheesy graphics and special (olympic) effects. Do I seem bitter about this film? Yes. Did I see Iron Man? No. Was there a plot? No. Was it so symbolic that I didn't understand? NO. Was there a Body Hammer? Beats the Hell out of ME. So take my advice and STAY away!!!!!! (I must admit though I have had so much fun writing this and laughing to myself about this film that if you want to laugh, WATCH IT!!!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tetsuo is back!! ....And I'm still not impressed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Coventry
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't really know why everybody hates this movie and calls it so poor compared to the almighty 1988 original. Is it because this sequel is more coherent and easier to understand, maybe? People tend to refer to a movie as a 'masterpiece' much quicker when they don't understand one iota of it, of course. As far as I'm concerned, "Tetsuo II" is more or less as powerful (or as weak, if you wish) as the original, naturally with some aspects that are worse but also some aspects that are better! The story is pretty much a reworking of the first, only it's more accessible and  on a personal matter  it gave me a lot less headaches (which I liked!). Once again, the story handles about a man who strangely and disturbingly fuses into a piece of metal equipment, yet now you know more about his background so you can sympathize with him at least a little. His painful transformation is mainly caused by rage (his son was kidnapped) and 'medical' experiments performed by a group of skinheads. "Tetsuo II" contains just as much weirdness and psychedelic imagery as the original, but I admit it all doesn't look so nightmarish here. Partly because it's in color and partly because the characters are given depth, this sequel feels less like a genuine cult gem.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Metal machine movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The original Tetsuo: the Iron Man was a pretty unforgettable film. Shot in intense black and white and very pure in its intentions, it was an avant-garde sci-fi horror movie. An immediate cult film. With the follow up, director Shin'ya Tsukamoto has made a film which is more a remake than a true sequel. In this one, he shoots in colour and tries to incorporate a story of sorts. Although, this is a relative statement, as this is still a very weird film and it hardly adheres to cinematic storytelling norms. In essence it is once again about a man turning into a cyborg. Like the first it's visually very striking indeed. It seems to have influenced an awful lot of industrial bands from the 90's, seeing as many of their videos mimic the imagery found in this one. It's soundtrack I guess adds to this seeing as it is full on rock a lot of the time. As a piece of visual art Tetsuo II is a success. However, I do not think it reaches the same level as the original movie, which for my money was such an original piece of work it is hard to outdo. I think the introduction of more story here is also to the film's detriment. The story gets in the way, something you could never accuse the original film of. Still, this remains a pretty intense experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could've used a heavy metal soundtrack lol.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    meteoraxv
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A very "industrial" film. Flesh and metal are one. Steel and concrete are everywhere. Not blood, but corrosion is being drawn. A lot of people say that this film had a higher budget that the first one (which I haven't seen yet). It didn't really feel that way to me. The movie looked very, very low quality and felt very "small". Could've used a heavy metal soundtrack lol. The plot was hard to follow. Whereas a lot of other films are very high on dialogue, this one didn't really had enough dialogue to really be able to follow the story. It was very loose. This movie is being tagged as sci-fi/drama/horror. Sci-fi and drama are about right, but if you're looking for a horror film, meh. Not really. I loved the shots of the skyscrapers. It really added to the industrial feel of this movie. It was alright. Nothing I would really re-watch. I'll check out the first one very soon. I heard there's a part 3 too, so that should be interesting! 6*
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arguably Better than the Original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheExpatriate700
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tetsuo II: Body Hammer is the second entry in the Tetsuo series and arguably an improvement over the first film. It has a more coherent plot, better special effects, and a better flow. Of the two, it was the more accessible film. Body Hammer follows the struggle of a seemingly meek man after his son is kidnapped by a ruthless gang / cult. The cult is run by a mad scientist who seeks to combine man and machine. When the father is subjected to one of these experiments, all hell breaks loose. Although surreal, Tetsuo II is a distinctly more conventional film than its predecessor, which came across as a grotesque student film. The sequel has a more typical sci-fi action plot even as it uses the bizarre animation and concepts that made the original a cult classic. This is actually a good thing, as it makes it easier to discern what the director is trying to get across. The film also benefits from improved special effects and costumes. While the original relied on rather clunky stop motion animation, the effects in Body Hammer are far more convincing. There are some issues with the film's plot, not the least of which being why the gang would grant super powers to someone whose son they had just kidnapped. Nevertheless, it is definitely a worthy follow-up to the original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    More story this time but it's still being an odd movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first movie, "Tetsuo", was mostly a visual experience, while this sequel is also attempting to throw in some more story this time. It makes this movie a bit less artistic and a bit more mainstream than its predecessor but only just a bit though. "Tetsuo II: Body Hammer" is for most part being still one psychedelic ride. There are lots of odd images and events, that just don't make sense in the real world but help to make this still a good and intriguing watch. The movie has a more of a manga vibe and feeling to it than anything else really. Fans of manga will therefore also most likely to appreciate this movie better than the average person. It's obvious that Shinya Tsukamoto has progressed more as a director when watching this movie and compare it to its predecessor. It's also obvious that they had far more money to spend this time, though its still being a low-budget production. This movie doesn't makes much sense as a sequel but then again, the movie just doesn't make much sense in general. It's for most part simply a movie you have to experience, though I admit that it all got a bit tiresome to watch after a while. It also seemed as if the film-makers stopped caring toward the end and dropped the story and all logic. This is when the movie becomes a quite distant and bland one, that only solely relies on its images to keep its viewers interested. This might had all worked for an hour long movie but this movie is about 30 minutes too long for that. This is the foremost reason why the first movie is still the better one, despite the fact that this movie makes more 'sense' and is also a better made one, with better production values and all. Pehaps only truly interesting to watch this movie as a live-action manga. 6/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better made than the first in someways, but worse in others.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Prolox
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After his son is abducted & maybe even killed by some strange men, a frustrated father finds himself morphing into a half man half metal being, full of gears, wires & cables etc. Determined to find his son, his wife is soon abducted & learns a terrifying secret about her husbands connection to the leader of the group. TETSUO 2 is the in colour sequel to the directors really weird, creepy nightmare caught on black & white film TETSUO. This time the director obviously had a bigger budget to play with & just like in the original, the film is filled with stop motion animation, half human half cyborg creatures & people morphing into monsters, it also has somewhat more of a plot which based on the almost no existent plot of the original, is just as wild, however just like the original, the film makes the mistake of overusing it's stop motion & weirdness. The acting is poor & the direction although slightly better than the first, is still pretty bad & the film has nothing to offer those looking for more meat on it's bones regarding a decent plot. The film lacks the weird nightmarish edge of it's predecessor, yet the effects work is just as good. All in all like it's predecessor from which it is connected to in no way other than the same people who made it, the title & the concept of a human slowly mutating into a machine, this is an over-hyped movie that in the end is unforgettable, but fails to satisfy. Hopefully it's in the works sequel TETSUO: THE BULLETMAN is better. **1/2 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's get MetalPhysical...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    poe426
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like Canadian filmmaker David Cronenberg (early on in his career, anyway) and America's own David Lynch, Shinya Tsukamoto has mined (and defined) his own particular brand of cinematic gold. When he's at his best (as he is here), Tsukamoto is a brilliant blacksmith, hammering out searing, steamy imagery with a pulsating potency. Human beings in his films are often hardened, mentally, physically and- most important of all- emotionally. They move through cold, unforgiving industrial landscapes (where buildings tower like sterile tombstones) that become surreal dreamscapes populated by living, breathing nightmares. THE BODY HAMMER offers some of Tsukamoto's most interesting: bodybuilding skinheads (denizens of the darkest depths of the society that spawns them) who literally harden themselves into (first flesh and blood, then) metal monsters bent on total destruction- their own as well as everyone else's. The idea of the rivet guns that cause them to rust out was a great touch- and the pulsing music is a hammer on an anvil. Check out THE BODY HAMMER- if you've got the wiring (guts).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A visually arresting retread/re-imagining of the ideas and themes established in Tetsuo: The Iron Man.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Graham Greene
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tetsuo II: Body Hammer is director Shinya Tsukamoto's sequel/re-make/companion piece to his cult, low-budget 1988 art-house shocker Tetsuo: The Iron Man; a striking piece of hyper-kinetic visual film-making, in which an anonymous Japanese business man finds his body inexplicably mutating into a mass of metal, wire and steal. This version of the story cleans up and clarifies some of the more indistinct and visually abstract points established in the original film, but also adds to it a greater psychological subtext and a broader dramatic scale. The film begins in a more recognisable world than Tsukamoto's original, with the use of colour (albeit, heavily tinted to shades of blue, amber and grey) creating a more recognisable Tokyo that will later be juxtaposed against the hellish underworld depicted in the second half of the story. There's also more believable characterisation, a loose plot and some vague explanations for what is actually happening. Some fans of the original film consider this to be Body Hammer's major failing; with the clarification and characterisation detracting from the weird "wow-factor" of the original Iron Man film; which, as a work of great science-fiction cinema, really existed in its own world devoid of conservative narrative and cinematic convention. I like to appreciate the film from another perspective, however; with Tsukamoto simply fleshing out the themes of the original film a little further, in the same way that a song-writer might often perform a number of different songs about the same subject, but most often, with a different style and arrangement. Tsukamoto has always been more of an artist than a traditional filmmaker, which is why you can see the same themes resurfacing again and again in a different context throughout his work. Tsukamoto's principal preoccupations as a filmmaker are often with alienation, claustrophobia, technology, and most importantly, the human body. Throughout his work, Tsukamoto has looked at the self-inflicted destruction of the body, via films such as Iron Man, Body Hammer and Tokyo Fist; through to the more traditional notions of natural decay and internal destruction with films like A Snake of June, Bullet Ballet and Vital. All of these characteristics are present here, with the film showing us how easily tragedy can strike (and go un-noticed) in a built up city, and how striving to become the ultimate human often involves a melding of man with machine (the natural with the synthetic). The great thing about Tsukamoto's work is that it can often be enjoyed on a number of levels, so, with Body Hammer, we have something that could be viewed as a straight science-fiction film with elements of cyber-punk derived body horror, or instead we could look at some of the deeper, metaphorical interpretations pertaining to the loss of a child, parenthood, childhood trauma, guilt, and perhaps even notions more unsavoury than that! Without wanting to give away too much, there's an element of the plot here that involves the central character's infant son being kidnapped. What follows is quite shocking and heavily symbolic, but I personally like to think that this moment is actually the real impetuous for Body Hammer's plot. So, we have the idea of a character spiralling into a pit of despair, consumed by guilt and losing his mind and the trust of his wife in light of this tragic chain of events! Now, I'm not pretending I know all the answers here, but I like to theorise. Someone else might view the film and take from it an entirely different interpretation but could still find it enjoyable and entertaining. The fact remains that despite the layers of personal interpretation the one thing that will always stand out - regardless of whether or not you liked the film - is the unbridled imagination and visual flair that Tsukamoto brings to the project as it's writer, director, editor, art director, cinematographer, designer and supporting actor. It certainly won't be to all tastes, as even committed admirers of the first Tetsuo film often write this one off as an interesting failure, but for me, this film offers an entirely new perspective on the territory of Iron Man and the usual preoccupations of Tsukamoto's later films, such as Tokyo Fist, A Snake of June and Vital. As Roger Ebert wrote in his review at the time, "Tetsuo II' doesn't rise (or stoop) to the level of conventional action or suspense; it's a design concept, a director's attempt to take some of the ideas in Blade Runner and some of the Arnold Schwarzenegger films and the Japanese animated films like Akira and extend them into grotesquery". It's perhaps not on a par with some of Tsukamoto's other works, chiefly Tetsuo, Tokyo Fist, Gemini and A Snake of June, but regardless, remains a unique viewing experience for those who are genuinely into through-provoking, visually arresting art-house shock cinema. On a final note, I would perhaps suggest starting here and then progressing onto the first Tetsuo film, as this one is a little less challenging and easier to get through and thus acts as a nice little gateway into this particular filmmaker's warped and wonderful world.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maxyg18
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is highly recommended for the fans of its predecessor, although it's not in black and white, doesn't have as good of a soundtrack or have as much surrealism as the first film, but it remains to be a bit more action-packed and (let's not forget) makes a bit more sense. This time, the salary man (the protagonist from the first film) lives a normal life with his family until one day his son gets kidnapped and the salary man is forced to be experimented on by a large a gang of skinheads which speeds up the mutating process of becoming a part-metal weapon and part-human being. It's not really a sequel but it surely is one of the greatest underrated films of-all-time and is about as good as the first film (TETSUO), if not, better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Body Hammer BLOWS
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nedwalton
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was reading in a Stuff Magazine about some of the goriest, bloodiest films that Asia had to offer and I immediately jumped to Netflix to quench my thirst. Boy what a mistake I made. This movie is one of the worst films I have seen. First and foremost no plot, what I expected to be the plot (see: "Revenge") turned into a series of events just happening in a effort to spend their special effects budget of $14.89 and waste studio time. They should have kept their money and not wasted their time nor yours. When a major plot twist occurs, Tetsuo II: Body Hammer is given a new identity and I wasn't buying it. A flashback is given that should answer our questions, but seemed to me like I turned on Showtime at 3:47 am and dropped ACID. The movie continues and spirals out of control with cheesy graphics and special (olympic) effects. Do I seem bitter about this film? Yes. Did I see Iron Man? No. Was there a plot? No. Was it so symbolic that I didn't understand? NO. Was there a Body Hammer? Beats the Hell out of ME. So take my advice and STAY away!!!!!! (I must admit though I have had so much fun writing this and laughing to myself about this film that if you want to laugh, WATCH IT!!!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tetsuo is back!! ....And I'm still not impressed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Coventry
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't really know why everybody hates this movie and calls it so poor compared to the almighty 1988 original. Is it because this sequel is more coherent and easier to understand, maybe? People tend to refer to a movie as a 'masterpiece' much quicker when they don't understand one iota of it, of course. As far as I'm concerned, "Tetsuo II" is more or less as powerful (or as weak, if you wish) as the original, naturally with some aspects that are worse but also some aspects that are better! The story is pretty much a reworking of the first, only it's more accessible and  on a personal matter  it gave me a lot less headaches (which I liked!). Once again, the story handles about a man who strangely and disturbingly fuses into a piece of metal equipment, yet now you know more about his background so you can sympathize with him at least a little. His painful transformation is mainly caused by rage (his son was kidnapped) and 'medical' experiments performed by a group of skinheads. "Tetsuo II" contains just as much weirdness and psychedelic imagery as the original, but I admit it all doesn't look so nightmarish here. Partly because it's in color and partly because the characters are given depth, this sequel feels less like a genuine cult gem.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Metal machine movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The original Tetsuo: the Iron Man was a pretty unforgettable film. Shot in intense black and white and very pure in its intentions, it was an avant-garde sci-fi horror movie. An immediate cult film. With the follow up, director Shin'ya Tsukamoto has made a film which is more a remake than a true sequel. In this one, he shoots in colour and tries to incorporate a story of sorts. Although, this is a relative statement, as this is still a very weird film and it hardly adheres to cinematic storytelling norms. In essence it is once again about a man turning into a cyborg. Like the first it's visually very striking indeed. It seems to have influenced an awful lot of industrial bands from the 90's, seeing as many of their videos mimic the imagery found in this one. It's soundtrack I guess adds to this seeing as it is full on rock a lot of the time. As a piece of visual art Tetsuo II is a success. However, I do not think it reaches the same level as the original movie, which for my money was such an original piece of work it is hard to outdo. I think the introduction of more story here is also to the film's detriment. The story gets in the way, something you could never accuse the original film of. Still, this remains a pretty intense experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could've used a heavy metal soundtrack lol.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    meteoraxv
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A very "industrial" film. Flesh and metal are one. Steel and concrete are everywhere. Not blood, but corrosion is being drawn. A lot of people say that this film had a higher budget that the first one (which I haven't seen yet). It didn't really feel that way to me. The movie looked very, very low quality and felt very "small". Could've used a heavy metal soundtrack lol. The plot was hard to follow. Whereas a lot of other films are very high on dialogue, this one didn't really had enough dialogue to really be able to follow the story. It was very loose. This movie is being tagged as sci-fi/drama/horror. Sci-fi and drama are about right, but if you're looking for a horror film, meh. Not really. I loved the shots of the skyscrapers. It really added to the industrial feel of this movie. It was alright. Nothing I would really re-watch. I'll check out the first one very soon. I heard there's a part 3 too, so that should be interesting! 6*
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arguably Better than the Original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheExpatriate700
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tetsuo II: Body Hammer is the second entry in the Tetsuo series and arguably an improvement over the first film. It has a more coherent plot, better special effects, and a better flow. Of the two, it was the more accessible film. Body Hammer follows the struggle of a seemingly meek man after his son is kidnapped by a ruthless gang / cult. The cult is run by a mad scientist who seeks to combine man and machine. When the father is subjected to one of these experiments, all hell breaks loose. Although surreal, Tetsuo II is a distinctly more conventional film than its predecessor, which came across as a grotesque student film. The sequel has a more typical sci-fi action plot even as it uses the bizarre animation and concepts that made the original a cult classic. This is actually a good thing, as it makes it easier to discern what the director is trying to get across. The film also benefits from improved special effects and costumes. While the original relied on rather clunky stop motion animation, the effects in Body Hammer are far more convincing. There are some issues with the film's plot, not the least of which being why the gang would grant super powers to someone whose son they had just kidnapped. Nevertheless, it is definitely a worthy follow-up to the original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    More story this time but it's still being an odd movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first movie, "Tetsuo", was mostly a visual experience, while this sequel is also attempting to throw in some more story this time. It makes this movie a bit less artistic and a bit more mainstream than its predecessor but only just a bit though. "Tetsuo II: Body Hammer" is for most part being still one psychedelic ride. There are lots of odd images and events, that just don't make sense in the real world but help to make this still a good and intriguing watch. The movie has a more of a manga vibe and feeling to it than anything else really. Fans of manga will therefore also most likely to appreciate this movie better than the average person. It's obvious that Shinya Tsukamoto has progressed more as a director when watching this movie and compare it to its predecessor. It's also obvious that they had far more money to spend this time, though its still being a low-budget production. This movie doesn't makes much sense as a sequel but then again, the movie just doesn't make much sense in general. It's for most part simply a movie you have to experience, though I admit that it all got a bit tiresome to watch after a while. It also seemed as if the film-makers stopped caring toward the end and dropped the story and all logic. This is when the movie becomes a quite distant and bland one, that only solely relies on its images to keep its viewers interested. This might had all worked for an hour long movie but this movie is about 30 minutes too long for that. This is the foremost reason why the first movie is still the better one, despite the fact that this movie makes more 'sense' and is also a better made one, with better production values and all. Pehaps only truly interesting to watch this movie as a live-action manga. 6/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better made than the first in someways, but worse in others.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Prolox
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After his son is abducted & maybe even killed by some strange men, a frustrated father finds himself morphing into a half man half metal being, full of gears, wires & cables etc. Determined to find his son, his wife is soon abducted & learns a terrifying secret about her husbands connection to the leader of the group. TETSUO 2 is the in colour sequel to the directors really weird, creepy nightmare caught on black & white film TETSUO. This time the director obviously had a bigger budget to play with & just like in the original, the film is filled with stop motion animation, half human half cyborg creatures & people morphing into monsters, it also has somewhat more of a plot which based on the almost no existent plot of the original, is just as wild, however just like the original, the film makes the mistake of overusing it's stop motion & weirdness. The acting is poor & the direction although slightly better than the first, is still pretty bad & the film has nothing to offer those looking for more meat on it's bones regarding a decent plot. The film lacks the weird nightmarish edge of it's predecessor, yet the effects work is just as good. All in all like it's predecessor from which it is connected to in no way other than the same people who made it, the title & the concept of a human slowly mutating into a machine, this is an over-hyped movie that in the end is unforgettable, but fails to satisfy. Hopefully it's in the works sequel TETSUO: THE BULLETMAN is better. **1/2 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's get MetalPhysical...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    poe426
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like Canadian filmmaker David Cronenberg (early on in his career, anyway) and America's own David Lynch, Shinya Tsukamoto has mined (and defined) his own particular brand of cinematic gold. When he's at his best (as he is here), Tsukamoto is a brilliant blacksmith, hammering out searing, steamy imagery with a pulsating potency. Human beings in his films are often hardened, mentally, physically and- most important of all- emotionally. They move through cold, unforgiving industrial landscapes (where buildings tower like sterile tombstones) that become surreal dreamscapes populated by living, breathing nightmares. THE BODY HAMMER offers some of Tsukamoto's most interesting: bodybuilding skinheads (denizens of the darkest depths of the society that spawns them) who literally harden themselves into (first flesh and blood, then) metal monsters bent on total destruction- their own as well as everyone else's. The idea of the rivet guns that cause them to rust out was a great touch- and the pulsing music is a hammer on an anvil. Check out THE BODY HAMMER- if you've got the wiring (guts).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A visually arresting retread/re-imagining of the ideas and themes established in Tetsuo: The Iron Man.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Graham Greene
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tetsuo II: Body Hammer is director Shinya Tsukamoto's sequel/re-make/companion piece to his cult, low-budget 1988 art-house shocker Tetsuo: The Iron Man; a striking piece of hyper-kinetic visual film-making, in which an anonymous Japanese business man finds his body inexplicably mutating into a mass of metal, wire and steal. This version of the story cleans up and clarifies some of the more indistinct and visually abstract points established in the original film, but also adds to it a greater psychological subtext and a broader dramatic scale. The film begins in a more recognisable world than Tsukamoto's original, with the use of colour (albeit, heavily tinted to shades of blue, amber and grey) creating a more recognisable Tokyo that will later be juxtaposed against the hellish underworld depicted in the second half of the story. There's also more believable characterisation, a loose plot and some vague explanations for what is actually happening. Some fans of the original film consider this to be Body Hammer's major failing; with the clarification and characterisation detracting from the weird "wow-factor" of the original Iron Man film; which, as a work of great science-fiction cinema, really existed in its own world devoid of conservative narrative and cinematic convention. I like to appreciate the film from another perspective, however; with Tsukamoto simply fleshing out the themes of the original film a little further, in the same way that a song-writer might often perform a number of different songs about the same subject, but most often, with a different style and arrangement. Tsukamoto has always been more of an artist than a traditional filmmaker, which is why you can see the same themes resurfacing again and again in a different context throughout his work. Tsukamoto's principal preoccupations as a filmmaker are often with alienation, claustrophobia, technology, and most importantly, the human body. Throughout his work, Tsukamoto has looked at the self-inflicted destruction of the body, via films such as Iron Man, Body Hammer and Tokyo Fist; through to the more traditional notions of natural decay and internal destruction with films like A Snake of June, Bullet Ballet and Vital. All of these characteristics are present here, with the film showing us how easily tragedy can strike (and go un-noticed) in a built up city, and how striving to become the ultimate human often involves a melding of man with machine (the natural with the synthetic). The great thing about Tsukamoto's work is that it can often be enjoyed on a number of levels, so, with Body Hammer, we have something that could be viewed as a straight science-fiction film with elements of cyber-punk derived body horror, or instead we could look at some of the deeper, metaphorical interpretations pertaining to the loss of a child, parenthood, childhood trauma, guilt, and perhaps even notions more unsavoury than that! Without wanting to give away too much, there's an element of the plot here that involves the central character's infant son being kidnapped. What follows is quite shocking and heavily symbolic, but I personally like to think that this moment is actually the real impetuous for Body Hammer's plot. So, we have the idea of a character spiralling into a pit of despair, consumed by guilt and losing his mind and the trust of his wife in light of this tragic chain of events! Now, I'm not pretending I know all the answers here, but I like to theorise. Someone else might view the film and take from it an entirely different interpretation but could still find it enjoyable and entertaining. The fact remains that despite the layers of personal interpretation the one thing that will always stand out - regardless of whether or not you liked the film - is the unbridled imagination and visual flair that Tsukamoto brings to the project as it's writer, director, editor, art director, cinematographer, designer and supporting actor. It certainly won't be to all tastes, as even committed admirers of the first Tetsuo film often write this one off as an interesting failure, but for me, this film offers an entirely new perspective on the territory of Iron Man and the usual preoccupations of Tsukamoto's later films, such as Tokyo Fist, A Snake of June and Vital. As Roger Ebert wrote in his review at the time, "Tetsuo II' doesn't rise (or stoop) to the level of conventional action or suspense; it's a design concept, a director's attempt to take some of the ideas in Blade Runner and some of the Arnold Schwarzenegger films and the Japanese animated films like Akira and extend them into grotesquery". It's perhaps not on a par with some of Tsukamoto's other works, chiefly Tetsuo, Tokyo Fist, Gemini and A Snake of June, but regardless, remains a unique viewing experience for those who are genuinely into through-provoking, visually arresting art-house shock cinema. On a final note, I would perhaps suggest starting here and then progressing onto the first Tetsuo film, as this one is a little less challenging and easier to get through and thus acts as a nice little gateway into this particular filmmaker's warped and wonderful world.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maxyg18
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is highly recommended for the fans of its predecessor, although it's not in black and white, doesn't have as good of a soundtrack or have as much surrealism as the first film, but it remains to be a bit more action-packed and (let's not forget) makes a bit more sense. This time, the salary man (the protagonist from the first film) lives a normal life with his family until one day his son gets kidnapped and the salary man is forced to be experimented on by a large a gang of skinheads which speeds up the mutating process of becoming a part-metal weapon and part-human being. It's not really a sequel but it surely is one of the greatest underrated films of-all-time and is about as good as the first film (TETSUO), if not, better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Body Hammer BLOWS
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nedwalton
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was reading in a Stuff Magazine about some of the goriest, bloodiest films that Asia had to offer and I immediately jumped to Netflix to quench my thirst. Boy what a mistake I made. This movie is one of the worst films I have seen. First and foremost no plot, what I expected to be the plot (see: "Revenge") turned into a series of events just happening in a effort to spend their special effects budget of $14.89 and waste studio time. They should have kept their money and not wasted their time nor yours. When a major plot twist occurs, Tetsuo II: Body Hammer is given a new identity and I wasn't buying it. A flashback is given that should answer our questions, but seemed to me like I turned on Showtime at 3:47 am and dropped ACID. The movie continues and spirals out of control with cheesy graphics and special (olympic) effects. Do I seem bitter about this film? Yes. Did I see Iron Man? No. Was there a plot? No. Was it so symbolic that I didn't understand? NO. Was there a Body Hammer? Beats the Hell out of ME. So take my advice and STAY away!!!!!! (I must admit though I have had so much fun writing this and laughing to myself about this film that if you want to laugh, WATCH IT!!!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tetsuo is back!! ....And I'm still not impressed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Coventry
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't really know why everybody hates this movie and calls it so poor compared to the almighty 1988 original. Is it because this sequel is more coherent and easier to understand, maybe? People tend to refer to a movie as a 'masterpiece' much quicker when they don't understand one iota of it, of course. As far as I'm concerned, "Tetsuo II" is more or less as powerful (or as weak, if you wish) as the original, naturally with some aspects that are worse but also some aspects that are better! The story is pretty much a reworking of the first, only it's more accessible and  on a personal matter  it gave me a lot less headaches (which I liked!). Once again, the story handles about a man who strangely and disturbingly fuses into a piece of metal equipment, yet now you know more about his background so you can sympathize with him at least a little. His painful transformation is mainly caused by rage (his son was kidnapped) and 'medical' experiments performed by a group of skinheads. "Tetsuo II" contains just as much weirdness and psychedelic imagery as the original, but I admit it all doesn't look so nightmarish here. Partly because it's in color and partly because the characters are given depth, this sequel feels less like a genuine cult gem.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
