<filme>
 <id>
  1387
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119098
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Fall
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Cab driver Michael and supermodel Sarah fall in love while her gorgeous husband Phillippe is in Madrid for two months.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Two people from completely different worlds meet by chance, thrown together as if by fate. Their attraction is immediately obvious and overwhelming. He is attracted to her beauty (she is a supermodel) and good humor; she is seduced by his charisma and honesty. With his gifts of poetry and tenderness, he opens her heart to the possibility of true love. But it takes a lot of courage to make a commitment. Is she truly in love with him? And even if she is, will she able to leave the cosmopolitan, superficial lifestyle to be with him?
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   supermodel
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   poetry
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   pegging
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sex
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   female nudity
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Eric Schaeffer
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Eric Schaeffer
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Eric Schaeffer
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Amanda De Cadenet
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Rudolf Martin
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I love it when I stumble on a movie like this.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julsberg1723
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved the film and was shocked and moved by the superb ending. It is the kind of ending that makes you sit up and listen deeply rather than drift. I replayed the ending several times to capture the beautiful symphony of words, so beautifully crafted that the intensity of Michael's love cannot be denied. I particularly enjoy a film that does NOT have your typical mainstream actors, rather those who we hardly know. These are not "beautiful" people, but beautifully ordinary and perfectly paired for a memorable love story. Watch and enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmmmm.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    me_the_student
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hmmmm.... So, u r here. I saw it when i was 16 and loved it and eroticism wasn't the only reason. Watched it again a while back. This is a type of movie which doesn't get balanced reviews, either v good ones or very bad ones.... because this is an extreme movie, in its own fashion.... A movie that has an essence to have cult following.... A movie that tries not to compromise artistic credibility in favour of a neat structured format and readily digestible endings.... It has passion, ebbs and flows, it waxes and wanes, its a singsong, and it leaves lose ends, coz life is that way too, always.... The movie uses juxtaposition, placing side by side, two so incredibly different people, and draws out something of a life force out of them....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fall mostly just failed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ally Mason
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I caught this movie late night on a Wednesday I knew I wasn't in store for the best made film of all time, never the less I watched it until the end. The voice-overs were the largest point of contention for me, especially when they contained what was herald as "Poetry". They did nothing to forward the plot and did not give intelligence and charisma to the character of Michael. The other issue I had was the mini-flash back flash forward effect used in certain scenes. I saw these scene stutters as more annoying than artistic. The character was Michael was the most unrelatable, unbelievable character. I think he was suppose to be this perfect man that ever girl secretly wishes she had. Instead he comes off as completely unrealistic. He does no wrong, he's sensitive and patient. He has secret money and is wise beyond his years. He knows exactly what Sara wants and everyone loves him. I don't understand,he gives up writing because he can't deal with the fame? He never thought of using a pseudonym? He just gave up instead. I don't think the writer had this in mind but he seems to hide from situations he can't control. Sara is more rounded but still her character has zero depth( at least she had flaws). My thoughts were she is using Michael to slum it for awhile until figures out what she wants and then to get back at her husband. She's 28 (as stated in the film) which is like 40 in model years yet that is never explored. I also felt like the majority of camera angles and lighting were more flattering to Michael and left Sara looking odd and just awful in some scenes. This movie seemed more like a ego-centric glamour piece to it's seemingly narcissistic writer- producer-actor, than a movie about love and relationships. I didn't care about Michael and Sara and I don't believe much time and effort was put in to achieve that goal. The only characters I wanted to know more about were the Lesbian Dinner friends, sadly they were under-developed. I was really young in the 90's of maybe this was what was called "artistic," I just hope that it wasn't
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantasy never looked this good...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Greatornot)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... but a bad film indeed. I have seen many of the reviews about this film and I agree with the fact that the protagonist was an insensitive clod with high school like pick up techniques that would not amount to much more than getting a date with a back up cheerleader. I believe that the movie was about a taxi driver, with literary skills writing a novel. In other words , this was all fantasy and eventually to be written into a 'bestseller'. There are clues through out this film when images appear and disappear and our protagonist is in a meditational state, at various points in the film. Hints of Michaels imagination were sprinkled through out this film, even at the very end, if you watch closely. That said, This was not a particularly good film. The acting was on the lame side, the story is one that was done many times before and a lot of silliness and unrealistic scenes, even if it was from the standpoint Michael was writing a novel. This was basically , a movie within a movie and I did not feel it worked. I also believe this film glorified cheaters, stalkers and yes even rapists. Michael writing a book or not was not likable and neither was super model Sarah Easton, the chain smoking, giddy, romantic and very married partner in lust. This movie tried to be different and yes even realistic, with the character flaws. It just was a lesson in futility to try and root for any of these people... Part of cabbie Michaels novel or not.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe someday I'll watch the entire movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis-38
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just caught the last 25 minutes of "Fall." It struck no dim memory, so I stayed with it. I found the leading man attractive enough and the leading lady suitably endowed to be a top model. The plot--cabbie and supermodel--well, in one way or another this is one of the world's oldest films clich&eacute;s, and my eyes rolled when I read the synopsis. He was supposed to be a poet, so that was the big diff between the hundred other similar tales of Ordinary Joe and the Glam Lady. (Let's go back to "Her Highness and the Bellboy" with Hedy Lamarr and Robert Walker!) As "Fall" plummeted to its conclusion I was struck by the standard twists,right up to the airport dash, the miraculous sighting as she enters alimo in full drag--did he read the Paris gossip columns to know whereto find her?--his despondent reactions. (Although the pillow-weeping was a bit much.) I was also struck at how, well...very gay he seems.Not that there's anything wrong with that! But given his normal-guy looks, I had to take a big suspension of disbelief. Maybe in her business she was always sleeping with gay-ish men? What alerted me that this was probably a VERY bad movie, and I'd missed the worst of it, was his letter to her, read over the action as she leaves and he follows. It was such drivel I could only assume she fled to Paris because she realized he was retarded! He was certainly no writer of merit. I was dismayed when the movie closed with a very long shot of what appeared to be the two principals walking in the park, sitting on a bench, chatting. If it was not a misty flashback moment,one assumes they reconciled in some fashion? Unless it was another shortish, swishy man and his towering blonde friend? (Sorry for that, but I am gay myself and there is shot of him walking away from the camera, wearing only jeans that had me screaming, "you go,girlfriend!) If "Fall" pops up again, I'll probably watch it from the beginning. Sometimes a bad movie can lift the spirits better than a masterpiece. I just hope there are not a lot of examples of our cabbie/poet's writing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantastic Sleeper
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robins88
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how I missed this movie in first release. Saw today as a FLIX freebie and by the end was absolutely stunned. I wept for sadness and for joy. I think this is one of the best sleeper films I have seen in quite some time: the cinematography, the quirky characters, the narration, the issues, the musical score all combine to create a world that pulls you in. How refreshing to see a man comfortable with two strong women friends. How awesome to see rarely filmed wonderful shots of New York. Although the sex scenes at first seem perhaps a bit boring, they also felt real. The protagonist's poetry invited reflection. The film's ending narration was brilliant. I definitely recommend that you see this film if you are at all interested in a meditation on life's choices and uncertainty and hope.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fall" for romance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    krp2003
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cried. And cried and cried. Some films simply remind you of relationships, others evoke emotional experiences (should you have any) for relationships gone south, some tease you with relationships that might have been. "Fall" incorporates all of these. First off, my primary recollection from the 3 or 4 times I've enjoyed watching "Fall" is the ending. Sarah is in Paris, exiting some chic place with Phillipe. Michael, who has flown to Paris in desperate need to re-connect with her, tracks her down (magically) and sees her exiting. He looks at her, she looks at him, she non-verbally gestures "no, don't connect with me any more"--- and he breaks down in sobs. As do I, even as I'm writing this. The longing for true love on his facethe yearning for a love than can never be fully returnedis one of the best, if not THE best, portrayal of unrequited love I have ever seen in any film. Bar none. Heart-breaking sobs. You, who berate this film for Eric Schaeffer's self-indulgence and egoism, must never have felt this type of unrequited love, and for you I feel sorry (or notI guess it's easier to be ignorant in love but wise in film criticism). For the rest of us, he struck a chord that is rarely approached in film. Forget the strap-on, dismiss the socioeconomic disconnect, don't fret over the boastfulnessthis film simply nailed that painful yearning for true love that some romantics still treasure. The dialog touches many of us as personally poignant but that "film" critics interpret as trite. I could wax eloquent about the cinematographyespecially one scene where Sarah is walking past a piece d'art depicting waves (get the metaphor, duh!) with an equivalently apt soundtrackbut the arrogant, non-romantic film critics would dismiss this as being self-indulgent. You know, sometimes we need self-indulgenceespecially when it comes to relationships! Give me those scenes that touch my heart, expand my senses, and evoke my passion. If you want to be really TOUCHED by a film, see Fall. You won't be disappointed (unless you've taken Film Criticism 101, in which case cynicism trumps romanticism).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The movie of my life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kalin_vasilev_usa
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have searched for this movies for years since I first saw it back in 1999. At that time I have fallen deeply in love with my high school sweet heart. This movie has materialized a lot of the emotions a person experiences when falling. I kept it dear to my heart because of the beautiful poetry and the way how a person can truly relate to it. After spending 10 years looking for this title I finally found it. This movie is for the person who has experienced at least once in their life the real love. Passionate, spontaneous, deep. The chemistry between Schafer and deCadenet is real, like a true story that is waiting to happen to anybody who is ready to accept it. The energy, the romance, the erotic feelings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is what happens when you have zero self-awareness and lack that little voice telling you, Don't EVER Commit This Schlock to Paper!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    imdbnyc
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If I could give this movie 0/10, I would. I'm fairly positive anyone giving this movie more than a 1/10 is either Eric Schaeffer or one of Eric's hundreds of email/IMDb accounts. He's the sort who would do something like that. He's oversensitive, frail, and a basket case. The movie FALLS under the category of so laughably and horrifically atrocious, that it makes for some of the best comedy I've ever seen (laughing at you, Eric, NOT with you). Do yourself a favor and get the back story on Eric Schaeffer the boy-man. Read his salon interview (where he nonchalantly tells the reporter that as a child he had sex with his cousin), and check out some of the stuff on gawker. It begins to explain his insecure psyche, his repressed and latent homosexuality, his sub-acute anger towards women (he tells a woman he wants to bash her skull in with a rock). In two of his movies now a supermodel just happens to find him unbearably cute and attractive (yeah?! Really, Eric? I mean. Really?) It says that the guy's self worth is so rock-bottom that he would need a really attractive woman to validate him. One theme in Eric's life -- fiction and actual -- is the ubiquitous insecurity about his looks (and by extension his masculinity and sexuality). He's constantly asking women if they find him attractive. Women he's just met on a first date. And he'll badger them with the question until he gets the answer he's looking for. The tragedy of it all is that the man is almost 50. These are the kind of issues you should have ironed out -- oh, I dunno -- at least by the end of your thirties. There is a time when I probably might have liked this movie: when I was 16 and didn't know jack about life. It's no coincidence that most of the IMDb viewers who rate this movie high are teenage girls (check out the stats). There are some nice American Indie movies from the 90's. Kevin Smith, Edward Burns, etc. But if Eric Schaeffer is in any way associated with that group, it's completely by accident. In short, this movie isn't about idealistic, old-school romance and tenderness. It's about a guy who believes women should woe, fight for, and court him (and it's **so** unfair that the world doesn't work that way for him). A guy who wishes society found him as attractive as a supermodel. A guy who thinks women will instantly find him attractive just because HE thinks he's a helluva nice guy (which is kind of questionable). A guy who fetishizes tortured agony in lieu of real intimacy. Watch FALL to figure out how NOT to live your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    NY Romance - Scenerio E - Fall Hard for two months.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lwagner71
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There seems to be a trend - those who stumbled upon this film late night on IFC or on Showtime, as I did, seem to enjoy the film more than those who responded after the movie's initial release. Also the age demographic, those in their mid 30's - 40's seemed to relate more to the film. I fall into that category. I love NY/NJ Indie films, they are gritty and diverse - creating that either a love hate relationship with their screenwriters/directors - think Kevin Smith or Ed Burns. With this move I now have that love relationship with Eric Schaeffer. Which I did not have after "If Lucy Fell" (I do have the soundtrack for that movie, if anyone would like a copy). What I enjoyed about this film - the sexual tension and chemistry of the two main characters, seeing it portrayed on film, (call me crazy but no one gets naked anymore, it is refreshing - seeing realistic down and dirty sex scenes), and the passion that fuels/drives the first few weeks of a new relationship. You felt the tension and the heat. The first half an hour of the film reeled me in. Overall, FALL is much better than many of the large budget studio films and a good portion the Indie films I have seen recently. I have grown weary of seeing the same recycled character actors and over publicized glamor stars. It was nice to see fresh faces. Dialogue was quick, and surprisingly well written, story was predictable but overall a good adult film that brought back memories and made me fall into my husbands arms last night remembering our first turmultuous months together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I love it when I stumble on a movie like this.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julsberg1723
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved the film and was shocked and moved by the superb ending. It is the kind of ending that makes you sit up and listen deeply rather than drift. I replayed the ending several times to capture the beautiful symphony of words, so beautifully crafted that the intensity of Michael's love cannot be denied. I particularly enjoy a film that does NOT have your typical mainstream actors, rather those who we hardly know. These are not "beautiful" people, but beautifully ordinary and perfectly paired for a memorable love story. Watch and enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmmmm.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    me_the_student
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hmmmm.... So, u r here. I saw it when i was 16 and loved it and eroticism wasn't the only reason. Watched it again a while back. This is a type of movie which doesn't get balanced reviews, either v good ones or very bad ones.... because this is an extreme movie, in its own fashion.... A movie that has an essence to have cult following.... A movie that tries not to compromise artistic credibility in favour of a neat structured format and readily digestible endings.... It has passion, ebbs and flows, it waxes and wanes, its a singsong, and it leaves lose ends, coz life is that way too, always.... The movie uses juxtaposition, placing side by side, two so incredibly different people, and draws out something of a life force out of them....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fall mostly just failed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ally Mason
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I caught this movie late night on a Wednesday I knew I wasn't in store for the best made film of all time, never the less I watched it until the end. The voice-overs were the largest point of contention for me, especially when they contained what was herald as "Poetry". They did nothing to forward the plot and did not give intelligence and charisma to the character of Michael. The other issue I had was the mini-flash back flash forward effect used in certain scenes. I saw these scene stutters as more annoying than artistic. The character was Michael was the most unrelatable, unbelievable character. I think he was suppose to be this perfect man that ever girl secretly wishes she had. Instead he comes off as completely unrealistic. He does no wrong, he's sensitive and patient. He has secret money and is wise beyond his years. He knows exactly what Sara wants and everyone loves him. I don't understand,he gives up writing because he can't deal with the fame? He never thought of using a pseudonym? He just gave up instead. I don't think the writer had this in mind but he seems to hide from situations he can't control. Sara is more rounded but still her character has zero depth( at least she had flaws). My thoughts were she is using Michael to slum it for awhile until figures out what she wants and then to get back at her husband. She's 28 (as stated in the film) which is like 40 in model years yet that is never explored. I also felt like the majority of camera angles and lighting were more flattering to Michael and left Sara looking odd and just awful in some scenes. This movie seemed more like a ego-centric glamour piece to it's seemingly narcissistic writer- producer-actor, than a movie about love and relationships. I didn't care about Michael and Sara and I don't believe much time and effort was put in to achieve that goal. The only characters I wanted to know more about were the Lesbian Dinner friends, sadly they were under-developed. I was really young in the 90's of maybe this was what was called "artistic," I just hope that it wasn't
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantasy never looked this good...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Greatornot)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... but a bad film indeed. I have seen many of the reviews about this film and I agree with the fact that the protagonist was an insensitive clod with high school like pick up techniques that would not amount to much more than getting a date with a back up cheerleader. I believe that the movie was about a taxi driver, with literary skills writing a novel. In other words , this was all fantasy and eventually to be written into a 'bestseller'. There are clues through out this film when images appear and disappear and our protagonist is in a meditational state, at various points in the film. Hints of Michaels imagination were sprinkled through out this film, even at the very end, if you watch closely. That said, This was not a particularly good film. The acting was on the lame side, the story is one that was done many times before and a lot of silliness and unrealistic scenes, even if it was from the standpoint Michael was writing a novel. This was basically , a movie within a movie and I did not feel it worked. I also believe this film glorified cheaters, stalkers and yes even rapists. Michael writing a book or not was not likable and neither was super model Sarah Easton, the chain smoking, giddy, romantic and very married partner in lust. This movie tried to be different and yes even realistic, with the character flaws. It just was a lesson in futility to try and root for any of these people... Part of cabbie Michaels novel or not.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe someday I'll watch the entire movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis-38
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just caught the last 25 minutes of "Fall." It struck no dim memory, so I stayed with it. I found the leading man attractive enough and the leading lady suitably endowed to be a top model. The plot--cabbie and supermodel--well, in one way or another this is one of the world's oldest films clich&eacute;s, and my eyes rolled when I read the synopsis. He was supposed to be a poet, so that was the big diff between the hundred other similar tales of Ordinary Joe and the Glam Lady. (Let's go back to "Her Highness and the Bellboy" with Hedy Lamarr and Robert Walker!) As "Fall" plummeted to its conclusion I was struck by the standard twists,right up to the airport dash, the miraculous sighting as she enters alimo in full drag--did he read the Paris gossip columns to know whereto find her?--his despondent reactions. (Although the pillow-weeping was a bit much.) I was also struck at how, well...very gay he seems.Not that there's anything wrong with that! But given his normal-guy looks, I had to take a big suspension of disbelief. Maybe in her business she was always sleeping with gay-ish men? What alerted me that this was probably a VERY bad movie, and I'd missed the worst of it, was his letter to her, read over the action as she leaves and he follows. It was such drivel I could only assume she fled to Paris because she realized he was retarded! He was certainly no writer of merit. I was dismayed when the movie closed with a very long shot of what appeared to be the two principals walking in the park, sitting on a bench, chatting. If it was not a misty flashback moment,one assumes they reconciled in some fashion? Unless it was another shortish, swishy man and his towering blonde friend? (Sorry for that, but I am gay myself and there is shot of him walking away from the camera, wearing only jeans that had me screaming, "you go,girlfriend!) If "Fall" pops up again, I'll probably watch it from the beginning. Sometimes a bad movie can lift the spirits better than a masterpiece. I just hope there are not a lot of examples of our cabbie/poet's writing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantastic Sleeper
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robins88
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how I missed this movie in first release. Saw today as a FLIX freebie and by the end was absolutely stunned. I wept for sadness and for joy. I think this is one of the best sleeper films I have seen in quite some time: the cinematography, the quirky characters, the narration, the issues, the musical score all combine to create a world that pulls you in. How refreshing to see a man comfortable with two strong women friends. How awesome to see rarely filmed wonderful shots of New York. Although the sex scenes at first seem perhaps a bit boring, they also felt real. The protagonist's poetry invited reflection. The film's ending narration was brilliant. I definitely recommend that you see this film if you are at all interested in a meditation on life's choices and uncertainty and hope.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fall" for romance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    krp2003
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cried. And cried and cried. Some films simply remind you of relationships, others evoke emotional experiences (should you have any) for relationships gone south, some tease you with relationships that might have been. "Fall" incorporates all of these. First off, my primary recollection from the 3 or 4 times I've enjoyed watching "Fall" is the ending. Sarah is in Paris, exiting some chic place with Phillipe. Michael, who has flown to Paris in desperate need to re-connect with her, tracks her down (magically) and sees her exiting. He looks at her, she looks at him, she non-verbally gestures "no, don't connect with me any more"--- and he breaks down in sobs. As do I, even as I'm writing this. The longing for true love on his facethe yearning for a love than can never be fully returnedis one of the best, if not THE best, portrayal of unrequited love I have ever seen in any film. Bar none. Heart-breaking sobs. You, who berate this film for Eric Schaeffer's self-indulgence and egoism, must never have felt this type of unrequited love, and for you I feel sorry (or notI guess it's easier to be ignorant in love but wise in film criticism). For the rest of us, he struck a chord that is rarely approached in film. Forget the strap-on, dismiss the socioeconomic disconnect, don't fret over the boastfulnessthis film simply nailed that painful yearning for true love that some romantics still treasure. The dialog touches many of us as personally poignant but that "film" critics interpret as trite. I could wax eloquent about the cinematographyespecially one scene where Sarah is walking past a piece d'art depicting waves (get the metaphor, duh!) with an equivalently apt soundtrackbut the arrogant, non-romantic film critics would dismiss this as being self-indulgent. You know, sometimes we need self-indulgenceespecially when it comes to relationships! Give me those scenes that touch my heart, expand my senses, and evoke my passion. If you want to be really TOUCHED by a film, see Fall. You won't be disappointed (unless you've taken Film Criticism 101, in which case cynicism trumps romanticism).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The movie of my life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kalin_vasilev_usa
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have searched for this movies for years since I first saw it back in 1999. At that time I have fallen deeply in love with my high school sweet heart. This movie has materialized a lot of the emotions a person experiences when falling. I kept it dear to my heart because of the beautiful poetry and the way how a person can truly relate to it. After spending 10 years looking for this title I finally found it. This movie is for the person who has experienced at least once in their life the real love. Passionate, spontaneous, deep. The chemistry between Schafer and deCadenet is real, like a true story that is waiting to happen to anybody who is ready to accept it. The energy, the romance, the erotic feelings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is what happens when you have zero self-awareness and lack that little voice telling you, Don't EVER Commit This Schlock to Paper!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    imdbnyc
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If I could give this movie 0/10, I would. I'm fairly positive anyone giving this movie more than a 1/10 is either Eric Schaeffer or one of Eric's hundreds of email/IMDb accounts. He's the sort who would do something like that. He's oversensitive, frail, and a basket case. The movie FALLS under the category of so laughably and horrifically atrocious, that it makes for some of the best comedy I've ever seen (laughing at you, Eric, NOT with you). Do yourself a favor and get the back story on Eric Schaeffer the boy-man. Read his salon interview (where he nonchalantly tells the reporter that as a child he had sex with his cousin), and check out some of the stuff on gawker. It begins to explain his insecure psyche, his repressed and latent homosexuality, his sub-acute anger towards women (he tells a woman he wants to bash her skull in with a rock). In two of his movies now a supermodel just happens to find him unbearably cute and attractive (yeah?! Really, Eric? I mean. Really?) It says that the guy's self worth is so rock-bottom that he would need a really attractive woman to validate him. One theme in Eric's life -- fiction and actual -- is the ubiquitous insecurity about his looks (and by extension his masculinity and sexuality). He's constantly asking women if they find him attractive. Women he's just met on a first date. And he'll badger them with the question until he gets the answer he's looking for. The tragedy of it all is that the man is almost 50. These are the kind of issues you should have ironed out -- oh, I dunno -- at least by the end of your thirties. There is a time when I probably might have liked this movie: when I was 16 and didn't know jack about life. It's no coincidence that most of the IMDb viewers who rate this movie high are teenage girls (check out the stats). There are some nice American Indie movies from the 90's. Kevin Smith, Edward Burns, etc. But if Eric Schaeffer is in any way associated with that group, it's completely by accident. In short, this movie isn't about idealistic, old-school romance and tenderness. It's about a guy who believes women should woe, fight for, and court him (and it's **so** unfair that the world doesn't work that way for him). A guy who wishes society found him as attractive as a supermodel. A guy who thinks women will instantly find him attractive just because HE thinks he's a helluva nice guy (which is kind of questionable). A guy who fetishizes tortured agony in lieu of real intimacy. Watch FALL to figure out how NOT to live your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    NY Romance - Scenerio E - Fall Hard for two months.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lwagner71
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There seems to be a trend - those who stumbled upon this film late night on IFC or on Showtime, as I did, seem to enjoy the film more than those who responded after the movie's initial release. Also the age demographic, those in their mid 30's - 40's seemed to relate more to the film. I fall into that category. I love NY/NJ Indie films, they are gritty and diverse - creating that either a love hate relationship with their screenwriters/directors - think Kevin Smith or Ed Burns. With this move I now have that love relationship with Eric Schaeffer. Which I did not have after "If Lucy Fell" (I do have the soundtrack for that movie, if anyone would like a copy). What I enjoyed about this film - the sexual tension and chemistry of the two main characters, seeing it portrayed on film, (call me crazy but no one gets naked anymore, it is refreshing - seeing realistic down and dirty sex scenes), and the passion that fuels/drives the first few weeks of a new relationship. You felt the tension and the heat. The first half an hour of the film reeled me in. Overall, FALL is much better than many of the large budget studio films and a good portion the Indie films I have seen recently. I have grown weary of seeing the same recycled character actors and over publicized glamor stars. It was nice to see fresh faces. Dialogue was quick, and surprisingly well written, story was predictable but overall a good adult film that brought back memories and made me fall into my husbands arms last night remembering our first turmultuous months together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I love it when I stumble on a movie like this.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julsberg1723
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved the film and was shocked and moved by the superb ending. It is the kind of ending that makes you sit up and listen deeply rather than drift. I replayed the ending several times to capture the beautiful symphony of words, so beautifully crafted that the intensity of Michael's love cannot be denied. I particularly enjoy a film that does NOT have your typical mainstream actors, rather those who we hardly know. These are not "beautiful" people, but beautifully ordinary and perfectly paired for a memorable love story. Watch and enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmmmm.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    me_the_student
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hmmmm.... So, u r here. I saw it when i was 16 and loved it and eroticism wasn't the only reason. Watched it again a while back. This is a type of movie which doesn't get balanced reviews, either v good ones or very bad ones.... because this is an extreme movie, in its own fashion.... A movie that has an essence to have cult following.... A movie that tries not to compromise artistic credibility in favour of a neat structured format and readily digestible endings.... It has passion, ebbs and flows, it waxes and wanes, its a singsong, and it leaves lose ends, coz life is that way too, always.... The movie uses juxtaposition, placing side by side, two so incredibly different people, and draws out something of a life force out of them....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fall mostly just failed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ally Mason
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I caught this movie late night on a Wednesday I knew I wasn't in store for the best made film of all time, never the less I watched it until the end. The voice-overs were the largest point of contention for me, especially when they contained what was herald as "Poetry". They did nothing to forward the plot and did not give intelligence and charisma to the character of Michael. The other issue I had was the mini-flash back flash forward effect used in certain scenes. I saw these scene stutters as more annoying than artistic. The character was Michael was the most unrelatable, unbelievable character. I think he was suppose to be this perfect man that ever girl secretly wishes she had. Instead he comes off as completely unrealistic. He does no wrong, he's sensitive and patient. He has secret money and is wise beyond his years. He knows exactly what Sara wants and everyone loves him. I don't understand,he gives up writing because he can't deal with the fame? He never thought of using a pseudonym? He just gave up instead. I don't think the writer had this in mind but he seems to hide from situations he can't control. Sara is more rounded but still her character has zero depth( at least she had flaws). My thoughts were she is using Michael to slum it for awhile until figures out what she wants and then to get back at her husband. She's 28 (as stated in the film) which is like 40 in model years yet that is never explored. I also felt like the majority of camera angles and lighting were more flattering to Michael and left Sara looking odd and just awful in some scenes. This movie seemed more like a ego-centric glamour piece to it's seemingly narcissistic writer- producer-actor, than a movie about love and relationships. I didn't care about Michael and Sara and I don't believe much time and effort was put in to achieve that goal. The only characters I wanted to know more about were the Lesbian Dinner friends, sadly they were under-developed. I was really young in the 90's of maybe this was what was called "artistic," I just hope that it wasn't
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantasy never looked this good...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Greatornot)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... but a bad film indeed. I have seen many of the reviews about this film and I agree with the fact that the protagonist was an insensitive clod with high school like pick up techniques that would not amount to much more than getting a date with a back up cheerleader. I believe that the movie was about a taxi driver, with literary skills writing a novel. In other words , this was all fantasy and eventually to be written into a 'bestseller'. There are clues through out this film when images appear and disappear and our protagonist is in a meditational state, at various points in the film. Hints of Michaels imagination were sprinkled through out this film, even at the very end, if you watch closely. That said, This was not a particularly good film. The acting was on the lame side, the story is one that was done many times before and a lot of silliness and unrealistic scenes, even if it was from the standpoint Michael was writing a novel. This was basically , a movie within a movie and I did not feel it worked. I also believe this film glorified cheaters, stalkers and yes even rapists. Michael writing a book or not was not likable and neither was super model Sarah Easton, the chain smoking, giddy, romantic and very married partner in lust. This movie tried to be different and yes even realistic, with the character flaws. It just was a lesson in futility to try and root for any of these people... Part of cabbie Michaels novel or not.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe someday I'll watch the entire movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis-38
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just caught the last 25 minutes of "Fall." It struck no dim memory, so I stayed with it. I found the leading man attractive enough and the leading lady suitably endowed to be a top model. The plot--cabbie and supermodel--well, in one way or another this is one of the world's oldest films clich&eacute;s, and my eyes rolled when I read the synopsis. He was supposed to be a poet, so that was the big diff between the hundred other similar tales of Ordinary Joe and the Glam Lady. (Let's go back to "Her Highness and the Bellboy" with Hedy Lamarr and Robert Walker!) As "Fall" plummeted to its conclusion I was struck by the standard twists,right up to the airport dash, the miraculous sighting as she enters alimo in full drag--did he read the Paris gossip columns to know whereto find her?--his despondent reactions. (Although the pillow-weeping was a bit much.) I was also struck at how, well...very gay he seems.Not that there's anything wrong with that! But given his normal-guy looks, I had to take a big suspension of disbelief. Maybe in her business she was always sleeping with gay-ish men? What alerted me that this was probably a VERY bad movie, and I'd missed the worst of it, was his letter to her, read over the action as she leaves and he follows. It was such drivel I could only assume she fled to Paris because she realized he was retarded! He was certainly no writer of merit. I was dismayed when the movie closed with a very long shot of what appeared to be the two principals walking in the park, sitting on a bench, chatting. If it was not a misty flashback moment,one assumes they reconciled in some fashion? Unless it was another shortish, swishy man and his towering blonde friend? (Sorry for that, but I am gay myself and there is shot of him walking away from the camera, wearing only jeans that had me screaming, "you go,girlfriend!) If "Fall" pops up again, I'll probably watch it from the beginning. Sometimes a bad movie can lift the spirits better than a masterpiece. I just hope there are not a lot of examples of our cabbie/poet's writing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantastic Sleeper
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robins88
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how I missed this movie in first release. Saw today as a FLIX freebie and by the end was absolutely stunned. I wept for sadness and for joy. I think this is one of the best sleeper films I have seen in quite some time: the cinematography, the quirky characters, the narration, the issues, the musical score all combine to create a world that pulls you in. How refreshing to see a man comfortable with two strong women friends. How awesome to see rarely filmed wonderful shots of New York. Although the sex scenes at first seem perhaps a bit boring, they also felt real. The protagonist's poetry invited reflection. The film's ending narration was brilliant. I definitely recommend that you see this film if you are at all interested in a meditation on life's choices and uncertainty and hope.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fall" for romance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    krp2003
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cried. And cried and cried. Some films simply remind you of relationships, others evoke emotional experiences (should you have any) for relationships gone south, some tease you with relationships that might have been. "Fall" incorporates all of these. First off, my primary recollection from the 3 or 4 times I've enjoyed watching "Fall" is the ending. Sarah is in Paris, exiting some chic place with Phillipe. Michael, who has flown to Paris in desperate need to re-connect with her, tracks her down (magically) and sees her exiting. He looks at her, she looks at him, she non-verbally gestures "no, don't connect with me any more"--- and he breaks down in sobs. As do I, even as I'm writing this. The longing for true love on his facethe yearning for a love than can never be fully returnedis one of the best, if not THE best, portrayal of unrequited love I have ever seen in any film. Bar none. Heart-breaking sobs. You, who berate this film for Eric Schaeffer's self-indulgence and egoism, must never have felt this type of unrequited love, and for you I feel sorry (or notI guess it's easier to be ignorant in love but wise in film criticism). For the rest of us, he struck a chord that is rarely approached in film. Forget the strap-on, dismiss the socioeconomic disconnect, don't fret over the boastfulnessthis film simply nailed that painful yearning for true love that some romantics still treasure. The dialog touches many of us as personally poignant but that "film" critics interpret as trite. I could wax eloquent about the cinematographyespecially one scene where Sarah is walking past a piece d'art depicting waves (get the metaphor, duh!) with an equivalently apt soundtrackbut the arrogant, non-romantic film critics would dismiss this as being self-indulgent. You know, sometimes we need self-indulgenceespecially when it comes to relationships! Give me those scenes that touch my heart, expand my senses, and evoke my passion. If you want to be really TOUCHED by a film, see Fall. You won't be disappointed (unless you've taken Film Criticism 101, in which case cynicism trumps romanticism).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The movie of my life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kalin_vasilev_usa
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have searched for this movies for years since I first saw it back in 1999. At that time I have fallen deeply in love with my high school sweet heart. This movie has materialized a lot of the emotions a person experiences when falling. I kept it dear to my heart because of the beautiful poetry and the way how a person can truly relate to it. After spending 10 years looking for this title I finally found it. This movie is for the person who has experienced at least once in their life the real love. Passionate, spontaneous, deep. The chemistry between Schafer and deCadenet is real, like a true story that is waiting to happen to anybody who is ready to accept it. The energy, the romance, the erotic feelings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is what happens when you have zero self-awareness and lack that little voice telling you, Don't EVER Commit This Schlock to Paper!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    imdbnyc
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If I could give this movie 0/10, I would. I'm fairly positive anyone giving this movie more than a 1/10 is either Eric Schaeffer or one of Eric's hundreds of email/IMDb accounts. He's the sort who would do something like that. He's oversensitive, frail, and a basket case. The movie FALLS under the category of so laughably and horrifically atrocious, that it makes for some of the best comedy I've ever seen (laughing at you, Eric, NOT with you). Do yourself a favor and get the back story on Eric Schaeffer the boy-man. Read his salon interview (where he nonchalantly tells the reporter that as a child he had sex with his cousin), and check out some of the stuff on gawker. It begins to explain his insecure psyche, his repressed and latent homosexuality, his sub-acute anger towards women (he tells a woman he wants to bash her skull in with a rock). In two of his movies now a supermodel just happens to find him unbearably cute and attractive (yeah?! Really, Eric? I mean. Really?) It says that the guy's self worth is so rock-bottom that he would need a really attractive woman to validate him. One theme in Eric's life -- fiction and actual -- is the ubiquitous insecurity about his looks (and by extension his masculinity and sexuality). He's constantly asking women if they find him attractive. Women he's just met on a first date. And he'll badger them with the question until he gets the answer he's looking for. The tragedy of it all is that the man is almost 50. These are the kind of issues you should have ironed out -- oh, I dunno -- at least by the end of your thirties. There is a time when I probably might have liked this movie: when I was 16 and didn't know jack about life. It's no coincidence that most of the IMDb viewers who rate this movie high are teenage girls (check out the stats). There are some nice American Indie movies from the 90's. Kevin Smith, Edward Burns, etc. But if Eric Schaeffer is in any way associated with that group, it's completely by accident. In short, this movie isn't about idealistic, old-school romance and tenderness. It's about a guy who believes women should woe, fight for, and court him (and it's **so** unfair that the world doesn't work that way for him). A guy who wishes society found him as attractive as a supermodel. A guy who thinks women will instantly find him attractive just because HE thinks he's a helluva nice guy (which is kind of questionable). A guy who fetishizes tortured agony in lieu of real intimacy. Watch FALL to figure out how NOT to live your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    NY Romance - Scenerio E - Fall Hard for two months.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lwagner71
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There seems to be a trend - those who stumbled upon this film late night on IFC or on Showtime, as I did, seem to enjoy the film more than those who responded after the movie's initial release. Also the age demographic, those in their mid 30's - 40's seemed to relate more to the film. I fall into that category. I love NY/NJ Indie films, they are gritty and diverse - creating that either a love hate relationship with their screenwriters/directors - think Kevin Smith or Ed Burns. With this move I now have that love relationship with Eric Schaeffer. Which I did not have after "If Lucy Fell" (I do have the soundtrack for that movie, if anyone would like a copy). What I enjoyed about this film - the sexual tension and chemistry of the two main characters, seeing it portrayed on film, (call me crazy but no one gets naked anymore, it is refreshing - seeing realistic down and dirty sex scenes), and the passion that fuels/drives the first few weeks of a new relationship. You felt the tension and the heat. The first half an hour of the film reeled me in. Overall, FALL is much better than many of the large budget studio films and a good portion the Indie films I have seen recently. I have grown weary of seeing the same recycled character actors and over publicized glamor stars. It was nice to see fresh faces. Dialogue was quick, and surprisingly well written, story was predictable but overall a good adult film that brought back memories and made me fall into my husbands arms last night remembering our first turmultuous months together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I love it when I stumble on a movie like this.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julsberg1723
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved the film and was shocked and moved by the superb ending. It is the kind of ending that makes you sit up and listen deeply rather than drift. I replayed the ending several times to capture the beautiful symphony of words, so beautifully crafted that the intensity of Michael's love cannot be denied. I particularly enjoy a film that does NOT have your typical mainstream actors, rather those who we hardly know. These are not "beautiful" people, but beautifully ordinary and perfectly paired for a memorable love story. Watch and enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmmmm.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    me_the_student
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hmmmm.... So, u r here. I saw it when i was 16 and loved it and eroticism wasn't the only reason. Watched it again a while back. This is a type of movie which doesn't get balanced reviews, either v good ones or very bad ones.... because this is an extreme movie, in its own fashion.... A movie that has an essence to have cult following.... A movie that tries not to compromise artistic credibility in favour of a neat structured format and readily digestible endings.... It has passion, ebbs and flows, it waxes and wanes, its a singsong, and it leaves lose ends, coz life is that way too, always.... The movie uses juxtaposition, placing side by side, two so incredibly different people, and draws out something of a life force out of them....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fall mostly just failed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ally Mason
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I caught this movie late night on a Wednesday I knew I wasn't in store for the best made film of all time, never the less I watched it until the end. The voice-overs were the largest point of contention for me, especially when they contained what was herald as "Poetry". They did nothing to forward the plot and did not give intelligence and charisma to the character of Michael. The other issue I had was the mini-flash back flash forward effect used in certain scenes. I saw these scene stutters as more annoying than artistic. The character was Michael was the most unrelatable, unbelievable character. I think he was suppose to be this perfect man that ever girl secretly wishes she had. Instead he comes off as completely unrealistic. He does no wrong, he's sensitive and patient. He has secret money and is wise beyond his years. He knows exactly what Sara wants and everyone loves him. I don't understand,he gives up writing because he can't deal with the fame? He never thought of using a pseudonym? He just gave up instead. I don't think the writer had this in mind but he seems to hide from situations he can't control. Sara is more rounded but still her character has zero depth( at least she had flaws). My thoughts were she is using Michael to slum it for awhile until figures out what she wants and then to get back at her husband. She's 28 (as stated in the film) which is like 40 in model years yet that is never explored. I also felt like the majority of camera angles and lighting were more flattering to Michael and left Sara looking odd and just awful in some scenes. This movie seemed more like a ego-centric glamour piece to it's seemingly narcissistic writer- producer-actor, than a movie about love and relationships. I didn't care about Michael and Sara and I don't believe much time and effort was put in to achieve that goal. The only characters I wanted to know more about were the Lesbian Dinner friends, sadly they were under-developed. I was really young in the 90's of maybe this was what was called "artistic," I just hope that it wasn't
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantasy never looked this good...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Greatornot)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... but a bad film indeed. I have seen many of the reviews about this film and I agree with the fact that the protagonist was an insensitive clod with high school like pick up techniques that would not amount to much more than getting a date with a back up cheerleader. I believe that the movie was about a taxi driver, with literary skills writing a novel. In other words , this was all fantasy and eventually to be written into a 'bestseller'. There are clues through out this film when images appear and disappear and our protagonist is in a meditational state, at various points in the film. Hints of Michaels imagination were sprinkled through out this film, even at the very end, if you watch closely. That said, This was not a particularly good film. The acting was on the lame side, the story is one that was done many times before and a lot of silliness and unrealistic scenes, even if it was from the standpoint Michael was writing a novel. This was basically , a movie within a movie and I did not feel it worked. I also believe this film glorified cheaters, stalkers and yes even rapists. Michael writing a book or not was not likable and neither was super model Sarah Easton, the chain smoking, giddy, romantic and very married partner in lust. This movie tried to be different and yes even realistic, with the character flaws. It just was a lesson in futility to try and root for any of these people... Part of cabbie Michaels novel or not.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe someday I'll watch the entire movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis-38
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just caught the last 25 minutes of "Fall." It struck no dim memory, so I stayed with it. I found the leading man attractive enough and the leading lady suitably endowed to be a top model. The plot--cabbie and supermodel--well, in one way or another this is one of the world's oldest films clich&eacute;s, and my eyes rolled when I read the synopsis. He was supposed to be a poet, so that was the big diff between the hundred other similar tales of Ordinary Joe and the Glam Lady. (Let's go back to "Her Highness and the Bellboy" with Hedy Lamarr and Robert Walker!) As "Fall" plummeted to its conclusion I was struck by the standard twists,right up to the airport dash, the miraculous sighting as she enters alimo in full drag--did he read the Paris gossip columns to know whereto find her?--his despondent reactions. (Although the pillow-weeping was a bit much.) I was also struck at how, well...very gay he seems.Not that there's anything wrong with that! But given his normal-guy looks, I had to take a big suspension of disbelief. Maybe in her business she was always sleeping with gay-ish men? What alerted me that this was probably a VERY bad movie, and I'd missed the worst of it, was his letter to her, read over the action as she leaves and he follows. It was such drivel I could only assume she fled to Paris because she realized he was retarded! He was certainly no writer of merit. I was dismayed when the movie closed with a very long shot of what appeared to be the two principals walking in the park, sitting on a bench, chatting. If it was not a misty flashback moment,one assumes they reconciled in some fashion? Unless it was another shortish, swishy man and his towering blonde friend? (Sorry for that, but I am gay myself and there is shot of him walking away from the camera, wearing only jeans that had me screaming, "you go,girlfriend!) If "Fall" pops up again, I'll probably watch it from the beginning. Sometimes a bad movie can lift the spirits better than a masterpiece. I just hope there are not a lot of examples of our cabbie/poet's writing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantastic Sleeper
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robins88
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how I missed this movie in first release. Saw today as a FLIX freebie and by the end was absolutely stunned. I wept for sadness and for joy. I think this is one of the best sleeper films I have seen in quite some time: the cinematography, the quirky characters, the narration, the issues, the musical score all combine to create a world that pulls you in. How refreshing to see a man comfortable with two strong women friends. How awesome to see rarely filmed wonderful shots of New York. Although the sex scenes at first seem perhaps a bit boring, they also felt real. The protagonist's poetry invited reflection. The film's ending narration was brilliant. I definitely recommend that you see this film if you are at all interested in a meditation on life's choices and uncertainty and hope.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fall" for romance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    krp2003
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cried. And cried and cried. Some films simply remind you of relationships, others evoke emotional experiences (should you have any) for relationships gone south, some tease you with relationships that might have been. "Fall" incorporates all of these. First off, my primary recollection from the 3 or 4 times I've enjoyed watching "Fall" is the ending. Sarah is in Paris, exiting some chic place with Phillipe. Michael, who has flown to Paris in desperate need to re-connect with her, tracks her down (magically) and sees her exiting. He looks at her, she looks at him, she non-verbally gestures "no, don't connect with me any more"--- and he breaks down in sobs. As do I, even as I'm writing this. The longing for true love on his facethe yearning for a love than can never be fully returnedis one of the best, if not THE best, portrayal of unrequited love I have ever seen in any film. Bar none. Heart-breaking sobs. You, who berate this film for Eric Schaeffer's self-indulgence and egoism, must never have felt this type of unrequited love, and for you I feel sorry (or notI guess it's easier to be ignorant in love but wise in film criticism). For the rest of us, he struck a chord that is rarely approached in film. Forget the strap-on, dismiss the socioeconomic disconnect, don't fret over the boastfulnessthis film simply nailed that painful yearning for true love that some romantics still treasure. The dialog touches many of us as personally poignant but that "film" critics interpret as trite. I could wax eloquent about the cinematographyespecially one scene where Sarah is walking past a piece d'art depicting waves (get the metaphor, duh!) with an equivalently apt soundtrackbut the arrogant, non-romantic film critics would dismiss this as being self-indulgent. You know, sometimes we need self-indulgenceespecially when it comes to relationships! Give me those scenes that touch my heart, expand my senses, and evoke my passion. If you want to be really TOUCHED by a film, see Fall. You won't be disappointed (unless you've taken Film Criticism 101, in which case cynicism trumps romanticism).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The movie of my life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kalin_vasilev_usa
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have searched for this movies for years since I first saw it back in 1999. At that time I have fallen deeply in love with my high school sweet heart. This movie has materialized a lot of the emotions a person experiences when falling. I kept it dear to my heart because of the beautiful poetry and the way how a person can truly relate to it. After spending 10 years looking for this title I finally found it. This movie is for the person who has experienced at least once in their life the real love. Passionate, spontaneous, deep. The chemistry between Schafer and deCadenet is real, like a true story that is waiting to happen to anybody who is ready to accept it. The energy, the romance, the erotic feelings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is what happens when you have zero self-awareness and lack that little voice telling you, Don't EVER Commit This Schlock to Paper!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    imdbnyc
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If I could give this movie 0/10, I would. I'm fairly positive anyone giving this movie more than a 1/10 is either Eric Schaeffer or one of Eric's hundreds of email/IMDb accounts. He's the sort who would do something like that. He's oversensitive, frail, and a basket case. The movie FALLS under the category of so laughably and horrifically atrocious, that it makes for some of the best comedy I've ever seen (laughing at you, Eric, NOT with you). Do yourself a favor and get the back story on Eric Schaeffer the boy-man. Read his salon interview (where he nonchalantly tells the reporter that as a child he had sex with his cousin), and check out some of the stuff on gawker. It begins to explain his insecure psyche, his repressed and latent homosexuality, his sub-acute anger towards women (he tells a woman he wants to bash her skull in with a rock). In two of his movies now a supermodel just happens to find him unbearably cute and attractive (yeah?! Really, Eric? I mean. Really?) It says that the guy's self worth is so rock-bottom that he would need a really attractive woman to validate him. One theme in Eric's life -- fiction and actual -- is the ubiquitous insecurity about his looks (and by extension his masculinity and sexuality). He's constantly asking women if they find him attractive. Women he's just met on a first date. And he'll badger them with the question until he gets the answer he's looking for. The tragedy of it all is that the man is almost 50. These are the kind of issues you should have ironed out -- oh, I dunno -- at least by the end of your thirties. There is a time when I probably might have liked this movie: when I was 16 and didn't know jack about life. It's no coincidence that most of the IMDb viewers who rate this movie high are teenage girls (check out the stats). There are some nice American Indie movies from the 90's. Kevin Smith, Edward Burns, etc. But if Eric Schaeffer is in any way associated with that group, it's completely by accident. In short, this movie isn't about idealistic, old-school romance and tenderness. It's about a guy who believes women should woe, fight for, and court him (and it's **so** unfair that the world doesn't work that way for him). A guy who wishes society found him as attractive as a supermodel. A guy who thinks women will instantly find him attractive just because HE thinks he's a helluva nice guy (which is kind of questionable). A guy who fetishizes tortured agony in lieu of real intimacy. Watch FALL to figure out how NOT to live your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    NY Romance - Scenerio E - Fall Hard for two months.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lwagner71
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There seems to be a trend - those who stumbled upon this film late night on IFC or on Showtime, as I did, seem to enjoy the film more than those who responded after the movie's initial release. Also the age demographic, those in their mid 30's - 40's seemed to relate more to the film. I fall into that category. I love NY/NJ Indie films, they are gritty and diverse - creating that either a love hate relationship with their screenwriters/directors - think Kevin Smith or Ed Burns. With this move I now have that love relationship with Eric Schaeffer. Which I did not have after "If Lucy Fell" (I do have the soundtrack for that movie, if anyone would like a copy). What I enjoyed about this film - the sexual tension and chemistry of the two main characters, seeing it portrayed on film, (call me crazy but no one gets naked anymore, it is refreshing - seeing realistic down and dirty sex scenes), and the passion that fuels/drives the first few weeks of a new relationship. You felt the tension and the heat. The first half an hour of the film reeled me in. Overall, FALL is much better than many of the large budget studio films and a good portion the Indie films I have seen recently. I have grown weary of seeing the same recycled character actors and over publicized glamor stars. It was nice to see fresh faces. Dialogue was quick, and surprisingly well written, story was predictable but overall a good adult film that brought back memories and made me fall into my husbands arms last night remembering our first turmultuous months together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I love it when I stumble on a movie like this.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julsberg1723
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved the film and was shocked and moved by the superb ending. It is the kind of ending that makes you sit up and listen deeply rather than drift. I replayed the ending several times to capture the beautiful symphony of words, so beautifully crafted that the intensity of Michael's love cannot be denied. I particularly enjoy a film that does NOT have your typical mainstream actors, rather those who we hardly know. These are not "beautiful" people, but beautifully ordinary and perfectly paired for a memorable love story. Watch and enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmmmm.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    me_the_student
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hmmmm.... So, u r here. I saw it when i was 16 and loved it and eroticism wasn't the only reason. Watched it again a while back. This is a type of movie which doesn't get balanced reviews, either v good ones or very bad ones.... because this is an extreme movie, in its own fashion.... A movie that has an essence to have cult following.... A movie that tries not to compromise artistic credibility in favour of a neat structured format and readily digestible endings.... It has passion, ebbs and flows, it waxes and wanes, its a singsong, and it leaves lose ends, coz life is that way too, always.... The movie uses juxtaposition, placing side by side, two so incredibly different people, and draws out something of a life force out of them....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fall mostly just failed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ally Mason
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I caught this movie late night on a Wednesday I knew I wasn't in store for the best made film of all time, never the less I watched it until the end. The voice-overs were the largest point of contention for me, especially when they contained what was herald as "Poetry". They did nothing to forward the plot and did not give intelligence and charisma to the character of Michael. The other issue I had was the mini-flash back flash forward effect used in certain scenes. I saw these scene stutters as more annoying than artistic. The character was Michael was the most unrelatable, unbelievable character. I think he was suppose to be this perfect man that ever girl secretly wishes she had. Instead he comes off as completely unrealistic. He does no wrong, he's sensitive and patient. He has secret money and is wise beyond his years. He knows exactly what Sara wants and everyone loves him. I don't understand,he gives up writing because he can't deal with the fame? He never thought of using a pseudonym? He just gave up instead. I don't think the writer had this in mind but he seems to hide from situations he can't control. Sara is more rounded but still her character has zero depth( at least she had flaws). My thoughts were she is using Michael to slum it for awhile until figures out what she wants and then to get back at her husband. She's 28 (as stated in the film) which is like 40 in model years yet that is never explored. I also felt like the majority of camera angles and lighting were more flattering to Michael and left Sara looking odd and just awful in some scenes. This movie seemed more like a ego-centric glamour piece to it's seemingly narcissistic writer- producer-actor, than a movie about love and relationships. I didn't care about Michael and Sara and I don't believe much time and effort was put in to achieve that goal. The only characters I wanted to know more about were the Lesbian Dinner friends, sadly they were under-developed. I was really young in the 90's of maybe this was what was called "artistic," I just hope that it wasn't
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantasy never looked this good...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Greatornot)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... but a bad film indeed. I have seen many of the reviews about this film and I agree with the fact that the protagonist was an insensitive clod with high school like pick up techniques that would not amount to much more than getting a date with a back up cheerleader. I believe that the movie was about a taxi driver, with literary skills writing a novel. In other words , this was all fantasy and eventually to be written into a 'bestseller'. There are clues through out this film when images appear and disappear and our protagonist is in a meditational state, at various points in the film. Hints of Michaels imagination were sprinkled through out this film, even at the very end, if you watch closely. That said, This was not a particularly good film. The acting was on the lame side, the story is one that was done many times before and a lot of silliness and unrealistic scenes, even if it was from the standpoint Michael was writing a novel. This was basically , a movie within a movie and I did not feel it worked. I also believe this film glorified cheaters, stalkers and yes even rapists. Michael writing a book or not was not likable and neither was super model Sarah Easton, the chain smoking, giddy, romantic and very married partner in lust. This movie tried to be different and yes even realistic, with the character flaws. It just was a lesson in futility to try and root for any of these people... Part of cabbie Michaels novel or not.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe someday I'll watch the entire movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis-38
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just caught the last 25 minutes of "Fall." It struck no dim memory, so I stayed with it. I found the leading man attractive enough and the leading lady suitably endowed to be a top model. The plot--cabbie and supermodel--well, in one way or another this is one of the world's oldest films clich&eacute;s, and my eyes rolled when I read the synopsis. He was supposed to be a poet, so that was the big diff between the hundred other similar tales of Ordinary Joe and the Glam Lady. (Let's go back to "Her Highness and the Bellboy" with Hedy Lamarr and Robert Walker!) As "Fall" plummeted to its conclusion I was struck by the standard twists,right up to the airport dash, the miraculous sighting as she enters alimo in full drag--did he read the Paris gossip columns to know whereto find her?--his despondent reactions. (Although the pillow-weeping was a bit much.) I was also struck at how, well...very gay he seems.Not that there's anything wrong with that! But given his normal-guy looks, I had to take a big suspension of disbelief. Maybe in her business she was always sleeping with gay-ish men? What alerted me that this was probably a VERY bad movie, and I'd missed the worst of it, was his letter to her, read over the action as she leaves and he follows. It was such drivel I could only assume she fled to Paris because she realized he was retarded! He was certainly no writer of merit. I was dismayed when the movie closed with a very long shot of what appeared to be the two principals walking in the park, sitting on a bench, chatting. If it was not a misty flashback moment,one assumes they reconciled in some fashion? Unless it was another shortish, swishy man and his towering blonde friend? (Sorry for that, but I am gay myself and there is shot of him walking away from the camera, wearing only jeans that had me screaming, "you go,girlfriend!) If "Fall" pops up again, I'll probably watch it from the beginning. Sometimes a bad movie can lift the spirits better than a masterpiece. I just hope there are not a lot of examples of our cabbie/poet's writing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantastic Sleeper
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robins88
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how I missed this movie in first release. Saw today as a FLIX freebie and by the end was absolutely stunned. I wept for sadness and for joy. I think this is one of the best sleeper films I have seen in quite some time: the cinematography, the quirky characters, the narration, the issues, the musical score all combine to create a world that pulls you in. How refreshing to see a man comfortable with two strong women friends. How awesome to see rarely filmed wonderful shots of New York. Although the sex scenes at first seem perhaps a bit boring, they also felt real. The protagonist's poetry invited reflection. The film's ending narration was brilliant. I definitely recommend that you see this film if you are at all interested in a meditation on life's choices and uncertainty and hope.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fall" for romance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    krp2003
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cried. And cried and cried. Some films simply remind you of relationships, others evoke emotional experiences (should you have any) for relationships gone south, some tease you with relationships that might have been. "Fall" incorporates all of these. First off, my primary recollection from the 3 or 4 times I've enjoyed watching "Fall" is the ending. Sarah is in Paris, exiting some chic place with Phillipe. Michael, who has flown to Paris in desperate need to re-connect with her, tracks her down (magically) and sees her exiting. He looks at her, she looks at him, she non-verbally gestures "no, don't connect with me any more"--- and he breaks down in sobs. As do I, even as I'm writing this. The longing for true love on his facethe yearning for a love than can never be fully returnedis one of the best, if not THE best, portrayal of unrequited love I have ever seen in any film. Bar none. Heart-breaking sobs. You, who berate this film for Eric Schaeffer's self-indulgence and egoism, must never have felt this type of unrequited love, and for you I feel sorry (or notI guess it's easier to be ignorant in love but wise in film criticism). For the rest of us, he struck a chord that is rarely approached in film. Forget the strap-on, dismiss the socioeconomic disconnect, don't fret over the boastfulnessthis film simply nailed that painful yearning for true love that some romantics still treasure. The dialog touches many of us as personally poignant but that "film" critics interpret as trite. I could wax eloquent about the cinematographyespecially one scene where Sarah is walking past a piece d'art depicting waves (get the metaphor, duh!) with an equivalently apt soundtrackbut the arrogant, non-romantic film critics would dismiss this as being self-indulgent. You know, sometimes we need self-indulgenceespecially when it comes to relationships! Give me those scenes that touch my heart, expand my senses, and evoke my passion. If you want to be really TOUCHED by a film, see Fall. You won't be disappointed (unless you've taken Film Criticism 101, in which case cynicism trumps romanticism).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The movie of my life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kalin_vasilev_usa
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have searched for this movies for years since I first saw it back in 1999. At that time I have fallen deeply in love with my high school sweet heart. This movie has materialized a lot of the emotions a person experiences when falling. I kept it dear to my heart because of the beautiful poetry and the way how a person can truly relate to it. After spending 10 years looking for this title I finally found it. This movie is for the person who has experienced at least once in their life the real love. Passionate, spontaneous, deep. The chemistry between Schafer and deCadenet is real, like a true story that is waiting to happen to anybody who is ready to accept it. The energy, the romance, the erotic feelings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is what happens when you have zero self-awareness and lack that little voice telling you, Don't EVER Commit This Schlock to Paper!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    imdbnyc
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If I could give this movie 0/10, I would. I'm fairly positive anyone giving this movie more than a 1/10 is either Eric Schaeffer or one of Eric's hundreds of email/IMDb accounts. He's the sort who would do something like that. He's oversensitive, frail, and a basket case. The movie FALLS under the category of so laughably and horrifically atrocious, that it makes for some of the best comedy I've ever seen (laughing at you, Eric, NOT with you). Do yourself a favor and get the back story on Eric Schaeffer the boy-man. Read his salon interview (where he nonchalantly tells the reporter that as a child he had sex with his cousin), and check out some of the stuff on gawker. It begins to explain his insecure psyche, his repressed and latent homosexuality, his sub-acute anger towards women (he tells a woman he wants to bash her skull in with a rock). In two of his movies now a supermodel just happens to find him unbearably cute and attractive (yeah?! Really, Eric? I mean. Really?) It says that the guy's self worth is so rock-bottom that he would need a really attractive woman to validate him. One theme in Eric's life -- fiction and actual -- is the ubiquitous insecurity about his looks (and by extension his masculinity and sexuality). He's constantly asking women if they find him attractive. Women he's just met on a first date. And he'll badger them with the question until he gets the answer he's looking for. The tragedy of it all is that the man is almost 50. These are the kind of issues you should have ironed out -- oh, I dunno -- at least by the end of your thirties. There is a time when I probably might have liked this movie: when I was 16 and didn't know jack about life. It's no coincidence that most of the IMDb viewers who rate this movie high are teenage girls (check out the stats). There are some nice American Indie movies from the 90's. Kevin Smith, Edward Burns, etc. But if Eric Schaeffer is in any way associated with that group, it's completely by accident. In short, this movie isn't about idealistic, old-school romance and tenderness. It's about a guy who believes women should woe, fight for, and court him (and it's **so** unfair that the world doesn't work that way for him). A guy who wishes society found him as attractive as a supermodel. A guy who thinks women will instantly find him attractive just because HE thinks he's a helluva nice guy (which is kind of questionable). A guy who fetishizes tortured agony in lieu of real intimacy. Watch FALL to figure out how NOT to live your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    NY Romance - Scenerio E - Fall Hard for two months.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lwagner71
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There seems to be a trend - those who stumbled upon this film late night on IFC or on Showtime, as I did, seem to enjoy the film more than those who responded after the movie's initial release. Also the age demographic, those in their mid 30's - 40's seemed to relate more to the film. I fall into that category. I love NY/NJ Indie films, they are gritty and diverse - creating that either a love hate relationship with their screenwriters/directors - think Kevin Smith or Ed Burns. With this move I now have that love relationship with Eric Schaeffer. Which I did not have after "If Lucy Fell" (I do have the soundtrack for that movie, if anyone would like a copy). What I enjoyed about this film - the sexual tension and chemistry of the two main characters, seeing it portrayed on film, (call me crazy but no one gets naked anymore, it is refreshing - seeing realistic down and dirty sex scenes), and the passion that fuels/drives the first few weeks of a new relationship. You felt the tension and the heat. The first half an hour of the film reeled me in. Overall, FALL is much better than many of the large budget studio films and a good portion the Indie films I have seen recently. I have grown weary of seeing the same recycled character actors and over publicized glamor stars. It was nice to see fresh faces. Dialogue was quick, and surprisingly well written, story was predictable but overall a good adult film that brought back memories and made me fall into my husbands arms last night remembering our first turmultuous months together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I love it when I stumble on a movie like this.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julsberg1723
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved the film and was shocked and moved by the superb ending. It is the kind of ending that makes you sit up and listen deeply rather than drift. I replayed the ending several times to capture the beautiful symphony of words, so beautifully crafted that the intensity of Michael's love cannot be denied. I particularly enjoy a film that does NOT have your typical mainstream actors, rather those who we hardly know. These are not "beautiful" people, but beautifully ordinary and perfectly paired for a memorable love story. Watch and enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmmmm.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    me_the_student
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hmmmm.... So, u r here. I saw it when i was 16 and loved it and eroticism wasn't the only reason. Watched it again a while back. This is a type of movie which doesn't get balanced reviews, either v good ones or very bad ones.... because this is an extreme movie, in its own fashion.... A movie that has an essence to have cult following.... A movie that tries not to compromise artistic credibility in favour of a neat structured format and readily digestible endings.... It has passion, ebbs and flows, it waxes and wanes, its a singsong, and it leaves lose ends, coz life is that way too, always.... The movie uses juxtaposition, placing side by side, two so incredibly different people, and draws out something of a life force out of them....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fall mostly just failed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ally Mason
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I caught this movie late night on a Wednesday I knew I wasn't in store for the best made film of all time, never the less I watched it until the end. The voice-overs were the largest point of contention for me, especially when they contained what was herald as "Poetry". They did nothing to forward the plot and did not give intelligence and charisma to the character of Michael. The other issue I had was the mini-flash back flash forward effect used in certain scenes. I saw these scene stutters as more annoying than artistic. The character was Michael was the most unrelatable, unbelievable character. I think he was suppose to be this perfect man that ever girl secretly wishes she had. Instead he comes off as completely unrealistic. He does no wrong, he's sensitive and patient. He has secret money and is wise beyond his years. He knows exactly what Sara wants and everyone loves him. I don't understand,he gives up writing because he can't deal with the fame? He never thought of using a pseudonym? He just gave up instead. I don't think the writer had this in mind but he seems to hide from situations he can't control. Sara is more rounded but still her character has zero depth( at least she had flaws). My thoughts were she is using Michael to slum it for awhile until figures out what she wants and then to get back at her husband. She's 28 (as stated in the film) which is like 40 in model years yet that is never explored. I also felt like the majority of camera angles and lighting were more flattering to Michael and left Sara looking odd and just awful in some scenes. This movie seemed more like a ego-centric glamour piece to it's seemingly narcissistic writer- producer-actor, than a movie about love and relationships. I didn't care about Michael and Sara and I don't believe much time and effort was put in to achieve that goal. The only characters I wanted to know more about were the Lesbian Dinner friends, sadly they were under-developed. I was really young in the 90's of maybe this was what was called "artistic," I just hope that it wasn't
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantasy never looked this good...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Greatornot)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... but a bad film indeed. I have seen many of the reviews about this film and I agree with the fact that the protagonist was an insensitive clod with high school like pick up techniques that would not amount to much more than getting a date with a back up cheerleader. I believe that the movie was about a taxi driver, with literary skills writing a novel. In other words , this was all fantasy and eventually to be written into a 'bestseller'. There are clues through out this film when images appear and disappear and our protagonist is in a meditational state, at various points in the film. Hints of Michaels imagination were sprinkled through out this film, even at the very end, if you watch closely. That said, This was not a particularly good film. The acting was on the lame side, the story is one that was done many times before and a lot of silliness and unrealistic scenes, even if it was from the standpoint Michael was writing a novel. This was basically , a movie within a movie and I did not feel it worked. I also believe this film glorified cheaters, stalkers and yes even rapists. Michael writing a book or not was not likable and neither was super model Sarah Easton, the chain smoking, giddy, romantic and very married partner in lust. This movie tried to be different and yes even realistic, with the character flaws. It just was a lesson in futility to try and root for any of these people... Part of cabbie Michaels novel or not.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe someday I'll watch the entire movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis-38
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just caught the last 25 minutes of "Fall." It struck no dim memory, so I stayed with it. I found the leading man attractive enough and the leading lady suitably endowed to be a top model. The plot--cabbie and supermodel--well, in one way or another this is one of the world's oldest films clich&eacute;s, and my eyes rolled when I read the synopsis. He was supposed to be a poet, so that was the big diff between the hundred other similar tales of Ordinary Joe and the Glam Lady. (Let's go back to "Her Highness and the Bellboy" with Hedy Lamarr and Robert Walker!) As "Fall" plummeted to its conclusion I was struck by the standard twists,right up to the airport dash, the miraculous sighting as she enters alimo in full drag--did he read the Paris gossip columns to know whereto find her?--his despondent reactions. (Although the pillow-weeping was a bit much.) I was also struck at how, well...very gay he seems.Not that there's anything wrong with that! But given his normal-guy looks, I had to take a big suspension of disbelief. Maybe in her business she was always sleeping with gay-ish men? What alerted me that this was probably a VERY bad movie, and I'd missed the worst of it, was his letter to her, read over the action as she leaves and he follows. It was such drivel I could only assume she fled to Paris because she realized he was retarded! He was certainly no writer of merit. I was dismayed when the movie closed with a very long shot of what appeared to be the two principals walking in the park, sitting on a bench, chatting. If it was not a misty flashback moment,one assumes they reconciled in some fashion? Unless it was another shortish, swishy man and his towering blonde friend? (Sorry for that, but I am gay myself and there is shot of him walking away from the camera, wearing only jeans that had me screaming, "you go,girlfriend!) If "Fall" pops up again, I'll probably watch it from the beginning. Sometimes a bad movie can lift the spirits better than a masterpiece. I just hope there are not a lot of examples of our cabbie/poet's writing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantastic Sleeper
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robins88
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how I missed this movie in first release. Saw today as a FLIX freebie and by the end was absolutely stunned. I wept for sadness and for joy. I think this is one of the best sleeper films I have seen in quite some time: the cinematography, the quirky characters, the narration, the issues, the musical score all combine to create a world that pulls you in. How refreshing to see a man comfortable with two strong women friends. How awesome to see rarely filmed wonderful shots of New York. Although the sex scenes at first seem perhaps a bit boring, they also felt real. The protagonist's poetry invited reflection. The film's ending narration was brilliant. I definitely recommend that you see this film if you are at all interested in a meditation on life's choices and uncertainty and hope.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fall" for romance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    krp2003
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cried. And cried and cried. Some films simply remind you of relationships, others evoke emotional experiences (should you have any) for relationships gone south, some tease you with relationships that might have been. "Fall" incorporates all of these. First off, my primary recollection from the 3 or 4 times I've enjoyed watching "Fall" is the ending. Sarah is in Paris, exiting some chic place with Phillipe. Michael, who has flown to Paris in desperate need to re-connect with her, tracks her down (magically) and sees her exiting. He looks at her, she looks at him, she non-verbally gestures "no, don't connect with me any more"--- and he breaks down in sobs. As do I, even as I'm writing this. The longing for true love on his facethe yearning for a love than can never be fully returnedis one of the best, if not THE best, portrayal of unrequited love I have ever seen in any film. Bar none. Heart-breaking sobs. You, who berate this film for Eric Schaeffer's self-indulgence and egoism, must never have felt this type of unrequited love, and for you I feel sorry (or notI guess it's easier to be ignorant in love but wise in film criticism). For the rest of us, he struck a chord that is rarely approached in film. Forget the strap-on, dismiss the socioeconomic disconnect, don't fret over the boastfulnessthis film simply nailed that painful yearning for true love that some romantics still treasure. The dialog touches many of us as personally poignant but that "film" critics interpret as trite. I could wax eloquent about the cinematographyespecially one scene where Sarah is walking past a piece d'art depicting waves (get the metaphor, duh!) with an equivalently apt soundtrackbut the arrogant, non-romantic film critics would dismiss this as being self-indulgent. You know, sometimes we need self-indulgenceespecially when it comes to relationships! Give me those scenes that touch my heart, expand my senses, and evoke my passion. If you want to be really TOUCHED by a film, see Fall. You won't be disappointed (unless you've taken Film Criticism 101, in which case cynicism trumps romanticism).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The movie of my life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kalin_vasilev_usa
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have searched for this movies for years since I first saw it back in 1999. At that time I have fallen deeply in love with my high school sweet heart. This movie has materialized a lot of the emotions a person experiences when falling. I kept it dear to my heart because of the beautiful poetry and the way how a person can truly relate to it. After spending 10 years looking for this title I finally found it. This movie is for the person who has experienced at least once in their life the real love. Passionate, spontaneous, deep. The chemistry between Schafer and deCadenet is real, like a true story that is waiting to happen to anybody who is ready to accept it. The energy, the romance, the erotic feelings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is what happens when you have zero self-awareness and lack that little voice telling you, Don't EVER Commit This Schlock to Paper!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    imdbnyc
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If I could give this movie 0/10, I would. I'm fairly positive anyone giving this movie more than a 1/10 is either Eric Schaeffer or one of Eric's hundreds of email/IMDb accounts. He's the sort who would do something like that. He's oversensitive, frail, and a basket case. The movie FALLS under the category of so laughably and horrifically atrocious, that it makes for some of the best comedy I've ever seen (laughing at you, Eric, NOT with you). Do yourself a favor and get the back story on Eric Schaeffer the boy-man. Read his salon interview (where he nonchalantly tells the reporter that as a child he had sex with his cousin), and check out some of the stuff on gawker. It begins to explain his insecure psyche, his repressed and latent homosexuality, his sub-acute anger towards women (he tells a woman he wants to bash her skull in with a rock). In two of his movies now a supermodel just happens to find him unbearably cute and attractive (yeah?! Really, Eric? I mean. Really?) It says that the guy's self worth is so rock-bottom that he would need a really attractive woman to validate him. One theme in Eric's life -- fiction and actual -- is the ubiquitous insecurity about his looks (and by extension his masculinity and sexuality). He's constantly asking women if they find him attractive. Women he's just met on a first date. And he'll badger them with the question until he gets the answer he's looking for. The tragedy of it all is that the man is almost 50. These are the kind of issues you should have ironed out -- oh, I dunno -- at least by the end of your thirties. There is a time when I probably might have liked this movie: when I was 16 and didn't know jack about life. It's no coincidence that most of the IMDb viewers who rate this movie high are teenage girls (check out the stats). There are some nice American Indie movies from the 90's. Kevin Smith, Edward Burns, etc. But if Eric Schaeffer is in any way associated with that group, it's completely by accident. In short, this movie isn't about idealistic, old-school romance and tenderness. It's about a guy who believes women should woe, fight for, and court him (and it's **so** unfair that the world doesn't work that way for him). A guy who wishes society found him as attractive as a supermodel. A guy who thinks women will instantly find him attractive just because HE thinks he's a helluva nice guy (which is kind of questionable). A guy who fetishizes tortured agony in lieu of real intimacy. Watch FALL to figure out how NOT to live your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    NY Romance - Scenerio E - Fall Hard for two months.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lwagner71
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There seems to be a trend - those who stumbled upon this film late night on IFC or on Showtime, as I did, seem to enjoy the film more than those who responded after the movie's initial release. Also the age demographic, those in their mid 30's - 40's seemed to relate more to the film. I fall into that category. I love NY/NJ Indie films, they are gritty and diverse - creating that either a love hate relationship with their screenwriters/directors - think Kevin Smith or Ed Burns. With this move I now have that love relationship with Eric Schaeffer. Which I did not have after "If Lucy Fell" (I do have the soundtrack for that movie, if anyone would like a copy). What I enjoyed about this film - the sexual tension and chemistry of the two main characters, seeing it portrayed on film, (call me crazy but no one gets naked anymore, it is refreshing - seeing realistic down and dirty sex scenes), and the passion that fuels/drives the first few weeks of a new relationship. You felt the tension and the heat. The first half an hour of the film reeled me in. Overall, FALL is much better than many of the large budget studio films and a good portion the Indie films I have seen recently. I have grown weary of seeing the same recycled character actors and over publicized glamor stars. It was nice to see fresh faces. Dialogue was quick, and surprisingly well written, story was predictable but overall a good adult film that brought back memories and made me fall into my husbands arms last night remembering our first turmultuous months together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I love it when I stumble on a movie like this.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julsberg1723
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved the film and was shocked and moved by the superb ending. It is the kind of ending that makes you sit up and listen deeply rather than drift. I replayed the ending several times to capture the beautiful symphony of words, so beautifully crafted that the intensity of Michael's love cannot be denied. I particularly enjoy a film that does NOT have your typical mainstream actors, rather those who we hardly know. These are not "beautiful" people, but beautifully ordinary and perfectly paired for a memorable love story. Watch and enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmmmm.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    me_the_student
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hmmmm.... So, u r here. I saw it when i was 16 and loved it and eroticism wasn't the only reason. Watched it again a while back. This is a type of movie which doesn't get balanced reviews, either v good ones or very bad ones.... because this is an extreme movie, in its own fashion.... A movie that has an essence to have cult following.... A movie that tries not to compromise artistic credibility in favour of a neat structured format and readily digestible endings.... It has passion, ebbs and flows, it waxes and wanes, its a singsong, and it leaves lose ends, coz life is that way too, always.... The movie uses juxtaposition, placing side by side, two so incredibly different people, and draws out something of a life force out of them....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fall mostly just failed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ally Mason
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I caught this movie late night on a Wednesday I knew I wasn't in store for the best made film of all time, never the less I watched it until the end. The voice-overs were the largest point of contention for me, especially when they contained what was herald as "Poetry". They did nothing to forward the plot and did not give intelligence and charisma to the character of Michael. The other issue I had was the mini-flash back flash forward effect used in certain scenes. I saw these scene stutters as more annoying than artistic. The character was Michael was the most unrelatable, unbelievable character. I think he was suppose to be this perfect man that ever girl secretly wishes she had. Instead he comes off as completely unrealistic. He does no wrong, he's sensitive and patient. He has secret money and is wise beyond his years. He knows exactly what Sara wants and everyone loves him. I don't understand,he gives up writing because he can't deal with the fame? He never thought of using a pseudonym? He just gave up instead. I don't think the writer had this in mind but he seems to hide from situations he can't control. Sara is more rounded but still her character has zero depth( at least she had flaws). My thoughts were she is using Michael to slum it for awhile until figures out what she wants and then to get back at her husband. She's 28 (as stated in the film) which is like 40 in model years yet that is never explored. I also felt like the majority of camera angles and lighting were more flattering to Michael and left Sara looking odd and just awful in some scenes. This movie seemed more like a ego-centric glamour piece to it's seemingly narcissistic writer- producer-actor, than a movie about love and relationships. I didn't care about Michael and Sara and I don't believe much time and effort was put in to achieve that goal. The only characters I wanted to know more about were the Lesbian Dinner friends, sadly they were under-developed. I was really young in the 90's of maybe this was what was called "artistic," I just hope that it wasn't
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantasy never looked this good...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Greatornot)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... but a bad film indeed. I have seen many of the reviews about this film and I agree with the fact that the protagonist was an insensitive clod with high school like pick up techniques that would not amount to much more than getting a date with a back up cheerleader. I believe that the movie was about a taxi driver, with literary skills writing a novel. In other words , this was all fantasy and eventually to be written into a 'bestseller'. There are clues through out this film when images appear and disappear and our protagonist is in a meditational state, at various points in the film. Hints of Michaels imagination were sprinkled through out this film, even at the very end, if you watch closely. That said, This was not a particularly good film. The acting was on the lame side, the story is one that was done many times before and a lot of silliness and unrealistic scenes, even if it was from the standpoint Michael was writing a novel. This was basically , a movie within a movie and I did not feel it worked. I also believe this film glorified cheaters, stalkers and yes even rapists. Michael writing a book or not was not likable and neither was super model Sarah Easton, the chain smoking, giddy, romantic and very married partner in lust. This movie tried to be different and yes even realistic, with the character flaws. It just was a lesson in futility to try and root for any of these people... Part of cabbie Michaels novel or not.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe someday I'll watch the entire movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis-38
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just caught the last 25 minutes of "Fall." It struck no dim memory, so I stayed with it. I found the leading man attractive enough and the leading lady suitably endowed to be a top model. The plot--cabbie and supermodel--well, in one way or another this is one of the world's oldest films clich&eacute;s, and my eyes rolled when I read the synopsis. He was supposed to be a poet, so that was the big diff between the hundred other similar tales of Ordinary Joe and the Glam Lady. (Let's go back to "Her Highness and the Bellboy" with Hedy Lamarr and Robert Walker!) As "Fall" plummeted to its conclusion I was struck by the standard twists,right up to the airport dash, the miraculous sighting as she enters alimo in full drag--did he read the Paris gossip columns to know whereto find her?--his despondent reactions. (Although the pillow-weeping was a bit much.) I was also struck at how, well...very gay he seems.Not that there's anything wrong with that! But given his normal-guy looks, I had to take a big suspension of disbelief. Maybe in her business she was always sleeping with gay-ish men? What alerted me that this was probably a VERY bad movie, and I'd missed the worst of it, was his letter to her, read over the action as she leaves and he follows. It was such drivel I could only assume she fled to Paris because she realized he was retarded! He was certainly no writer of merit. I was dismayed when the movie closed with a very long shot of what appeared to be the two principals walking in the park, sitting on a bench, chatting. If it was not a misty flashback moment,one assumes they reconciled in some fashion? Unless it was another shortish, swishy man and his towering blonde friend? (Sorry for that, but I am gay myself and there is shot of him walking away from the camera, wearing only jeans that had me screaming, "you go,girlfriend!) If "Fall" pops up again, I'll probably watch it from the beginning. Sometimes a bad movie can lift the spirits better than a masterpiece. I just hope there are not a lot of examples of our cabbie/poet's writing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantastic Sleeper
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robins88
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how I missed this movie in first release. Saw today as a FLIX freebie and by the end was absolutely stunned. I wept for sadness and for joy. I think this is one of the best sleeper films I have seen in quite some time: the cinematography, the quirky characters, the narration, the issues, the musical score all combine to create a world that pulls you in. How refreshing to see a man comfortable with two strong women friends. How awesome to see rarely filmed wonderful shots of New York. Although the sex scenes at first seem perhaps a bit boring, they also felt real. The protagonist's poetry invited reflection. The film's ending narration was brilliant. I definitely recommend that you see this film if you are at all interested in a meditation on life's choices and uncertainty and hope.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fall" for romance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    krp2003
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cried. And cried and cried. Some films simply remind you of relationships, others evoke emotional experiences (should you have any) for relationships gone south, some tease you with relationships that might have been. "Fall" incorporates all of these. First off, my primary recollection from the 3 or 4 times I've enjoyed watching "Fall" is the ending. Sarah is in Paris, exiting some chic place with Phillipe. Michael, who has flown to Paris in desperate need to re-connect with her, tracks her down (magically) and sees her exiting. He looks at her, she looks at him, she non-verbally gestures "no, don't connect with me any more"--- and he breaks down in sobs. As do I, even as I'm writing this. The longing for true love on his facethe yearning for a love than can never be fully returnedis one of the best, if not THE best, portrayal of unrequited love I have ever seen in any film. Bar none. Heart-breaking sobs. You, who berate this film for Eric Schaeffer's self-indulgence and egoism, must never have felt this type of unrequited love, and for you I feel sorry (or notI guess it's easier to be ignorant in love but wise in film criticism). For the rest of us, he struck a chord that is rarely approached in film. Forget the strap-on, dismiss the socioeconomic disconnect, don't fret over the boastfulnessthis film simply nailed that painful yearning for true love that some romantics still treasure. The dialog touches many of us as personally poignant but that "film" critics interpret as trite. I could wax eloquent about the cinematographyespecially one scene where Sarah is walking past a piece d'art depicting waves (get the metaphor, duh!) with an equivalently apt soundtrackbut the arrogant, non-romantic film critics would dismiss this as being self-indulgent. You know, sometimes we need self-indulgenceespecially when it comes to relationships! Give me those scenes that touch my heart, expand my senses, and evoke my passion. If you want to be really TOUCHED by a film, see Fall. You won't be disappointed (unless you've taken Film Criticism 101, in which case cynicism trumps romanticism).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The movie of my life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kalin_vasilev_usa
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have searched for this movies for years since I first saw it back in 1999. At that time I have fallen deeply in love with my high school sweet heart. This movie has materialized a lot of the emotions a person experiences when falling. I kept it dear to my heart because of the beautiful poetry and the way how a person can truly relate to it. After spending 10 years looking for this title I finally found it. This movie is for the person who has experienced at least once in their life the real love. Passionate, spontaneous, deep. The chemistry between Schafer and deCadenet is real, like a true story that is waiting to happen to anybody who is ready to accept it. The energy, the romance, the erotic feelings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is what happens when you have zero self-awareness and lack that little voice telling you, Don't EVER Commit This Schlock to Paper!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    imdbnyc
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If I could give this movie 0/10, I would. I'm fairly positive anyone giving this movie more than a 1/10 is either Eric Schaeffer or one of Eric's hundreds of email/IMDb accounts. He's the sort who would do something like that. He's oversensitive, frail, and a basket case. The movie FALLS under the category of so laughably and horrifically atrocious, that it makes for some of the best comedy I've ever seen (laughing at you, Eric, NOT with you). Do yourself a favor and get the back story on Eric Schaeffer the boy-man. Read his salon interview (where he nonchalantly tells the reporter that as a child he had sex with his cousin), and check out some of the stuff on gawker. It begins to explain his insecure psyche, his repressed and latent homosexuality, his sub-acute anger towards women (he tells a woman he wants to bash her skull in with a rock). In two of his movies now a supermodel just happens to find him unbearably cute and attractive (yeah?! Really, Eric? I mean. Really?) It says that the guy's self worth is so rock-bottom that he would need a really attractive woman to validate him. One theme in Eric's life -- fiction and actual -- is the ubiquitous insecurity about his looks (and by extension his masculinity and sexuality). He's constantly asking women if they find him attractive. Women he's just met on a first date. And he'll badger them with the question until he gets the answer he's looking for. The tragedy of it all is that the man is almost 50. These are the kind of issues you should have ironed out -- oh, I dunno -- at least by the end of your thirties. There is a time when I probably might have liked this movie: when I was 16 and didn't know jack about life. It's no coincidence that most of the IMDb viewers who rate this movie high are teenage girls (check out the stats). There are some nice American Indie movies from the 90's. Kevin Smith, Edward Burns, etc. But if Eric Schaeffer is in any way associated with that group, it's completely by accident. In short, this movie isn't about idealistic, old-school romance and tenderness. It's about a guy who believes women should woe, fight for, and court him (and it's **so** unfair that the world doesn't work that way for him). A guy who wishes society found him as attractive as a supermodel. A guy who thinks women will instantly find him attractive just because HE thinks he's a helluva nice guy (which is kind of questionable). A guy who fetishizes tortured agony in lieu of real intimacy. Watch FALL to figure out how NOT to live your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    NY Romance - Scenerio E - Fall Hard for two months.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lwagner71
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There seems to be a trend - those who stumbled upon this film late night on IFC or on Showtime, as I did, seem to enjoy the film more than those who responded after the movie's initial release. Also the age demographic, those in their mid 30's - 40's seemed to relate more to the film. I fall into that category. I love NY/NJ Indie films, they are gritty and diverse - creating that either a love hate relationship with their screenwriters/directors - think Kevin Smith or Ed Burns. With this move I now have that love relationship with Eric Schaeffer. Which I did not have after "If Lucy Fell" (I do have the soundtrack for that movie, if anyone would like a copy). What I enjoyed about this film - the sexual tension and chemistry of the two main characters, seeing it portrayed on film, (call me crazy but no one gets naked anymore, it is refreshing - seeing realistic down and dirty sex scenes), and the passion that fuels/drives the first few weeks of a new relationship. You felt the tension and the heat. The first half an hour of the film reeled me in. Overall, FALL is much better than many of the large budget studio films and a good portion the Indie films I have seen recently. I have grown weary of seeing the same recycled character actors and over publicized glamor stars. It was nice to see fresh faces. Dialogue was quick, and surprisingly well written, story was predictable but overall a good adult film that brought back memories and made me fall into my husbands arms last night remembering our first turmultuous months together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I love it when I stumble on a movie like this.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julsberg1723
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved the film and was shocked and moved by the superb ending. It is the kind of ending that makes you sit up and listen deeply rather than drift. I replayed the ending several times to capture the beautiful symphony of words, so beautifully crafted that the intensity of Michael's love cannot be denied. I particularly enjoy a film that does NOT have your typical mainstream actors, rather those who we hardly know. These are not "beautiful" people, but beautifully ordinary and perfectly paired for a memorable love story. Watch and enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmmmm.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    me_the_student
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hmmmm.... So, u r here. I saw it when i was 16 and loved it and eroticism wasn't the only reason. Watched it again a while back. This is a type of movie which doesn't get balanced reviews, either v good ones or very bad ones.... because this is an extreme movie, in its own fashion.... A movie that has an essence to have cult following.... A movie that tries not to compromise artistic credibility in favour of a neat structured format and readily digestible endings.... It has passion, ebbs and flows, it waxes and wanes, its a singsong, and it leaves lose ends, coz life is that way too, always.... The movie uses juxtaposition, placing side by side, two so incredibly different people, and draws out something of a life force out of them....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fall mostly just failed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ally Mason
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I caught this movie late night on a Wednesday I knew I wasn't in store for the best made film of all time, never the less I watched it until the end. The voice-overs were the largest point of contention for me, especially when they contained what was herald as "Poetry". They did nothing to forward the plot and did not give intelligence and charisma to the character of Michael. The other issue I had was the mini-flash back flash forward effect used in certain scenes. I saw these scene stutters as more annoying than artistic. The character was Michael was the most unrelatable, unbelievable character. I think he was suppose to be this perfect man that ever girl secretly wishes she had. Instead he comes off as completely unrealistic. He does no wrong, he's sensitive and patient. He has secret money and is wise beyond his years. He knows exactly what Sara wants and everyone loves him. I don't understand,he gives up writing because he can't deal with the fame? He never thought of using a pseudonym? He just gave up instead. I don't think the writer had this in mind but he seems to hide from situations he can't control. Sara is more rounded but still her character has zero depth( at least she had flaws). My thoughts were she is using Michael to slum it for awhile until figures out what she wants and then to get back at her husband. She's 28 (as stated in the film) which is like 40 in model years yet that is never explored. I also felt like the majority of camera angles and lighting were more flattering to Michael and left Sara looking odd and just awful in some scenes. This movie seemed more like a ego-centric glamour piece to it's seemingly narcissistic writer- producer-actor, than a movie about love and relationships. I didn't care about Michael and Sara and I don't believe much time and effort was put in to achieve that goal. The only characters I wanted to know more about were the Lesbian Dinner friends, sadly they were under-developed. I was really young in the 90's of maybe this was what was called "artistic," I just hope that it wasn't
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantasy never looked this good...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Greatornot)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... but a bad film indeed. I have seen many of the reviews about this film and I agree with the fact that the protagonist was an insensitive clod with high school like pick up techniques that would not amount to much more than getting a date with a back up cheerleader. I believe that the movie was about a taxi driver, with literary skills writing a novel. In other words , this was all fantasy and eventually to be written into a 'bestseller'. There are clues through out this film when images appear and disappear and our protagonist is in a meditational state, at various points in the film. Hints of Michaels imagination were sprinkled through out this film, even at the very end, if you watch closely. That said, This was not a particularly good film. The acting was on the lame side, the story is one that was done many times before and a lot of silliness and unrealistic scenes, even if it was from the standpoint Michael was writing a novel. This was basically , a movie within a movie and I did not feel it worked. I also believe this film glorified cheaters, stalkers and yes even rapists. Michael writing a book or not was not likable and neither was super model Sarah Easton, the chain smoking, giddy, romantic and very married partner in lust. This movie tried to be different and yes even realistic, with the character flaws. It just was a lesson in futility to try and root for any of these people... Part of cabbie Michaels novel or not.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe someday I'll watch the entire movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis-38
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just caught the last 25 minutes of "Fall." It struck no dim memory, so I stayed with it. I found the leading man attractive enough and the leading lady suitably endowed to be a top model. The plot--cabbie and supermodel--well, in one way or another this is one of the world's oldest films clich&eacute;s, and my eyes rolled when I read the synopsis. He was supposed to be a poet, so that was the big diff between the hundred other similar tales of Ordinary Joe and the Glam Lady. (Let's go back to "Her Highness and the Bellboy" with Hedy Lamarr and Robert Walker!) As "Fall" plummeted to its conclusion I was struck by the standard twists,right up to the airport dash, the miraculous sighting as she enters alimo in full drag--did he read the Paris gossip columns to know whereto find her?--his despondent reactions. (Although the pillow-weeping was a bit much.) I was also struck at how, well...very gay he seems.Not that there's anything wrong with that! But given his normal-guy looks, I had to take a big suspension of disbelief. Maybe in her business she was always sleeping with gay-ish men? What alerted me that this was probably a VERY bad movie, and I'd missed the worst of it, was his letter to her, read over the action as she leaves and he follows. It was such drivel I could only assume she fled to Paris because she realized he was retarded! He was certainly no writer of merit. I was dismayed when the movie closed with a very long shot of what appeared to be the two principals walking in the park, sitting on a bench, chatting. If it was not a misty flashback moment,one assumes they reconciled in some fashion? Unless it was another shortish, swishy man and his towering blonde friend? (Sorry for that, but I am gay myself and there is shot of him walking away from the camera, wearing only jeans that had me screaming, "you go,girlfriend!) If "Fall" pops up again, I'll probably watch it from the beginning. Sometimes a bad movie can lift the spirits better than a masterpiece. I just hope there are not a lot of examples of our cabbie/poet's writing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantastic Sleeper
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robins88
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how I missed this movie in first release. Saw today as a FLIX freebie and by the end was absolutely stunned. I wept for sadness and for joy. I think this is one of the best sleeper films I have seen in quite some time: the cinematography, the quirky characters, the narration, the issues, the musical score all combine to create a world that pulls you in. How refreshing to see a man comfortable with two strong women friends. How awesome to see rarely filmed wonderful shots of New York. Although the sex scenes at first seem perhaps a bit boring, they also felt real. The protagonist's poetry invited reflection. The film's ending narration was brilliant. I definitely recommend that you see this film if you are at all interested in a meditation on life's choices and uncertainty and hope.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fall" for romance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    krp2003
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cried. And cried and cried. Some films simply remind you of relationships, others evoke emotional experiences (should you have any) for relationships gone south, some tease you with relationships that might have been. "Fall" incorporates all of these. First off, my primary recollection from the 3 or 4 times I've enjoyed watching "Fall" is the ending. Sarah is in Paris, exiting some chic place with Phillipe. Michael, who has flown to Paris in desperate need to re-connect with her, tracks her down (magically) and sees her exiting. He looks at her, she looks at him, she non-verbally gestures "no, don't connect with me any more"--- and he breaks down in sobs. As do I, even as I'm writing this. The longing for true love on his facethe yearning for a love than can never be fully returnedis one of the best, if not THE best, portrayal of unrequited love I have ever seen in any film. Bar none. Heart-breaking sobs. You, who berate this film for Eric Schaeffer's self-indulgence and egoism, must never have felt this type of unrequited love, and for you I feel sorry (or notI guess it's easier to be ignorant in love but wise in film criticism). For the rest of us, he struck a chord that is rarely approached in film. Forget the strap-on, dismiss the socioeconomic disconnect, don't fret over the boastfulnessthis film simply nailed that painful yearning for true love that some romantics still treasure. The dialog touches many of us as personally poignant but that "film" critics interpret as trite. I could wax eloquent about the cinematographyespecially one scene where Sarah is walking past a piece d'art depicting waves (get the metaphor, duh!) with an equivalently apt soundtrackbut the arrogant, non-romantic film critics would dismiss this as being self-indulgent. You know, sometimes we need self-indulgenceespecially when it comes to relationships! Give me those scenes that touch my heart, expand my senses, and evoke my passion. If you want to be really TOUCHED by a film, see Fall. You won't be disappointed (unless you've taken Film Criticism 101, in which case cynicism trumps romanticism).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The movie of my life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kalin_vasilev_usa
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have searched for this movies for years since I first saw it back in 1999. At that time I have fallen deeply in love with my high school sweet heart. This movie has materialized a lot of the emotions a person experiences when falling. I kept it dear to my heart because of the beautiful poetry and the way how a person can truly relate to it. After spending 10 years looking for this title I finally found it. This movie is for the person who has experienced at least once in their life the real love. Passionate, spontaneous, deep. The chemistry between Schafer and deCadenet is real, like a true story that is waiting to happen to anybody who is ready to accept it. The energy, the romance, the erotic feelings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is what happens when you have zero self-awareness and lack that little voice telling you, Don't EVER Commit This Schlock to Paper!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    imdbnyc
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If I could give this movie 0/10, I would. I'm fairly positive anyone giving this movie more than a 1/10 is either Eric Schaeffer or one of Eric's hundreds of email/IMDb accounts. He's the sort who would do something like that. He's oversensitive, frail, and a basket case. The movie FALLS under the category of so laughably and horrifically atrocious, that it makes for some of the best comedy I've ever seen (laughing at you, Eric, NOT with you). Do yourself a favor and get the back story on Eric Schaeffer the boy-man. Read his salon interview (where he nonchalantly tells the reporter that as a child he had sex with his cousin), and check out some of the stuff on gawker. It begins to explain his insecure psyche, his repressed and latent homosexuality, his sub-acute anger towards women (he tells a woman he wants to bash her skull in with a rock). In two of his movies now a supermodel just happens to find him unbearably cute and attractive (yeah?! Really, Eric? I mean. Really?) It says that the guy's self worth is so rock-bottom that he would need a really attractive woman to validate him. One theme in Eric's life -- fiction and actual -- is the ubiquitous insecurity about his looks (and by extension his masculinity and sexuality). He's constantly asking women if they find him attractive. Women he's just met on a first date. And he'll badger them with the question until he gets the answer he's looking for. The tragedy of it all is that the man is almost 50. These are the kind of issues you should have ironed out -- oh, I dunno -- at least by the end of your thirties. There is a time when I probably might have liked this movie: when I was 16 and didn't know jack about life. It's no coincidence that most of the IMDb viewers who rate this movie high are teenage girls (check out the stats). There are some nice American Indie movies from the 90's. Kevin Smith, Edward Burns, etc. But if Eric Schaeffer is in any way associated with that group, it's completely by accident. In short, this movie isn't about idealistic, old-school romance and tenderness. It's about a guy who believes women should woe, fight for, and court him (and it's **so** unfair that the world doesn't work that way for him). A guy who wishes society found him as attractive as a supermodel. A guy who thinks women will instantly find him attractive just because HE thinks he's a helluva nice guy (which is kind of questionable). A guy who fetishizes tortured agony in lieu of real intimacy. Watch FALL to figure out how NOT to live your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    NY Romance - Scenerio E - Fall Hard for two months.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lwagner71
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There seems to be a trend - those who stumbled upon this film late night on IFC or on Showtime, as I did, seem to enjoy the film more than those who responded after the movie's initial release. Also the age demographic, those in their mid 30's - 40's seemed to relate more to the film. I fall into that category. I love NY/NJ Indie films, they are gritty and diverse - creating that either a love hate relationship with their screenwriters/directors - think Kevin Smith or Ed Burns. With this move I now have that love relationship with Eric Schaeffer. Which I did not have after "If Lucy Fell" (I do have the soundtrack for that movie, if anyone would like a copy). What I enjoyed about this film - the sexual tension and chemistry of the two main characters, seeing it portrayed on film, (call me crazy but no one gets naked anymore, it is refreshing - seeing realistic down and dirty sex scenes), and the passion that fuels/drives the first few weeks of a new relationship. You felt the tension and the heat. The first half an hour of the film reeled me in. Overall, FALL is much better than many of the large budget studio films and a good portion the Indie films I have seen recently. I have grown weary of seeing the same recycled character actors and over publicized glamor stars. It was nice to see fresh faces. Dialogue was quick, and surprisingly well written, story was predictable but overall a good adult film that brought back memories and made me fall into my husbands arms last night remembering our first turmultuous months together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
