<filme>
 <id>
  1392
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119557
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Segredos Imperdo&aacute;veis
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A drifter enters a small town looking for employment. While working at the local cattle ranch, he meets and falls in love with the beautiful Kitty and becomes involved in a deadly yet erotic love triangle.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  The daily life in a tiny Kansas town is indelibly changed when enigmatic drifter Clay Hewitt enters the landscape. Within a few hours of Clay's arrival, he punches out the local drunk, steals his gorgeous lady love, Kitty, and is hired by the local feed ranch's owner, boozy aging widow Delilah. Known for her appetite for younger men, Delilah eagerly takes him in, letting him use the carriage house on her estate. She of course has more in mind for Clay than merely room and board. Her completely withdrawn and utterly dominated young son, Flyboy, hasn't spoken a word to anyone other than his pet bull since his recent return from a mental hospital following eight years of incarceration. Clay slowly yanks the boy out of his shell, which unleashes a series of (occasionally brutal) turns of events.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   kansas
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   cattle ranch
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   incest
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   shower
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   nymphomania
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   John Patrick Kelley
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   John Patrick Kelley
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Kate Capshaw
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jeremy Davies
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Vince Vaughn
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too depressing for the likes of me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    celticwanderer
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I must confess the ONLY reason I bought this film was because I live in Sealy, TX, and some of the scenes were shot a few blocks from my house. Considering all the preparations made to the buildings in downtown Sealy for this film, I was disappointed to discover very little of the town was actually shown in the movie. It seems a lot of effort for so little, but I'm sure the city administration was happy just getting Sealy in the credits. As for the movie itself, really not my cup of tea. I don't like these kinds of films at all. But I will say I thought the acting was as good as it could be considering the script moved like a pregnant snail and the dialog was often very weak.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A family with shocking secrets.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Clay Hewitt(Vince Vaughn)is a drifter from Missouri stopping in 1960s Kansas in hope to earn some money. He only has seven bucks in his pocket. He meets some locals, including Joel(Daniel Meyer), Earl(Paul Rudd), Patsy(Jessica Capshaw) and Kitty(Ashley Judd). Earl suggests he look for employment at Delilah Ashford Potts'(Kate Capshaw) feed ranch. Delilah's reputation of sleeping with her hired hands is common place. She demeans her son 'Flyboy', who is traumatized from his father's death. Clay finally fits in with the other workers and of course is a sexual target of his boss lady. Before Clay talks Kitty into moving on to California; he discovers two big Potts family secrets. The strong sexuality earns THE LOCUSTS the R rating. I really like the diverse characters. The photography catches the moodiness of the story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth more than 2 stars on premium digital cable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ishpafaro
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An American movie without happy end. Kate Capshaw heads a cast of young actors. From the start she comes over disgusting. 2 hours later you'll love here. It is really a very dark family secret. Vince Vaughn, Jeremy Davies, Ashley Judd are some of the names in this well-done USA movie. Who gives this stares anyway? Movie made during the 1997s. TRY TO WATCH IT ! The rest of the cast is young and horny. It plays on a mid America cattle farm. A seasonal worker, who may or may not haved killed a girl in KC, Kansas City, Missourri, finds a job in the south. La Madame Capshaw says yes. She smokes a lot in the movie. and she has a most wonderful main house ans cattlle field. A lot of blood on t-shirts and skirts. It makes it more hot. WATCH THIS MOVIE ! In Europe they would possibly say that if Kate Capshaw wasn't married to Steven Spielberg, this movie would have been never made? But watch for yourself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    all560
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ever lie awake at night, watch something on some obscure cable channel, and end up wondering why you didn't drink yourself into a stupor several hours earlier? I just did. I'd probably feel better tomorrow, had I chosen the booze. THE LOCUSTS is a truly awful film. It's one of those that always makes me ask the questions "WHY was it done and WHERE did the money come from?" Forget the attempts, so en vogue today, of trying to date and sentimentalize a film by mindless overlays of classic music! Genuine inability is timeless. Here is the one good thing I can say about this film: Ms. Judd's make-up artist, Ben Nye, Jr, had the sense to leave her alone. She's radiant...from the safe distance she was photographed. But, everything else is likewise-photographed. I guess the photographer didn't feel comfortable any closer to the storyline. The acting is laughable, especially the three leads. The kid spends two hours trying to do a James Dean and succeeds only in setting back the cause of the speech-impaired a couple decades. He is in rarefied atmosphere here. Only Jennifer Jason Leigh in KANSAS CITY and Richard Gere in BREATHLESS have given comparable performances. Capshaw is, well, Capshaw. Vince who? Doesn't he do novelty records? But the plot takes the cake. To think that human beings would allow themselves to dwell in or near this attempt of some swaggering pump-up to inflict his "values" or "Code of the Cool" on a defenseless kid is ludicrous. The mindset of the executive(s) responsible for the allocation of funds and the filming itself, who must have found SOME potential in the story, is unfathomable. There is none. GIANT and DUEL IN THE SUN and LONG HOT SUMMER have been done before. With taste, opulence, style or length to cover gaps in meaning or worth. This film has none of any of that. Fortunately, the family off themselves at the end, preventing a sequel. I think I now understand why Orion bankrupted.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Locust or Praying mantis?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviemaster
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have to wonder if the cohesion that might have held this movie together is lying on the cutting room floor. There are so many subplots that are never properly developed and not tied up at the end. I stumbled into this movie thinking it was some Sci-Fi work (as described by the on screen analysis of "on demand.") I just wanted a movie to put me to sleep. This wasn't that movie. Locusts did not take over the planet. But I was immediately struck by the brooding nature of the direction and how it drew me into the movie. However, sometimes I felt like it was some mini-series I had missed the first episode of. Some of the performances were good, but the plot meandered along until it suddenly became hurried. In the last 10 minutes the "mother" tells of her rape by her father, her son drowns himself, somehow, in the gelding shed and the mother finally did the world a favor and shot herself. Fortunately our hero and heroine ride off into the sunset in their maroon pick up truck and we're marooned, wondering if this is a happy ending or not... that is if you can consider a man who raped and murdered a woman a "hero." In the end, it didn't put me to sleep, but made me wonder why I had stayed up so late.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Locusts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    arlenedayj
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Excellent! This movie was so good. The acting was absolutely amazing! Vince Vaughn is an amazing actor. More roles like this for Vince, no more crap like Wedding Crashers. Wonderfully acted movie.. Finally a movie that you have to watch and understand. Where have all the great acting movies gone.. More movies like this. The story was simply told. Vince Vaughn can certainly. I recommend this movie highly. The sound track set the tone for this movie and took you back to a simpler time, with more complex issues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    True drama...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    EighthSense
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...in the type and class of 'Cat on a hot tin roof' and 'Summer and smoke'. Jeremy Davies should have won an award for his very talented performance of a difficult role-he's this generation's Anthony Perkins. Vince Vaughn's performance was excellent and moving too, and a meaty role for him-a Marlon Brando-type role, to be sure! Dark, depressed, tragic movie,with an air of inevitability hanging over it, beautifully photographed, with a lovely sound track with several golden oldies. The soundtrack really set a tone and time for the movie, and was at the right volume, unlike so many current artless movies where blasting music or car engines obliterate the dialog. Too bad that the delay of Clay in running after Flyboy at the end of the movie, as Flyboy ran from his mother's bedroom, was not believable-it was obvious that Clay would have ran after his very distraught young friend right away.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A very nice debut with a good story and some fine acting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Philip Van der Veken
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Normally when I hear or read the title of a movie, I have some idea of what it could be like. That's not always correct, but most of the time it works - especially with famous movies of course. But when I read the title of this movie, I really didn't know what it would be about. Of course I didn't think that it would be a movie about the insect, but I just couldn't form a good idea about it. That's why I just gave it a try, not knowing what to expect, but hoping for the best. And I'm glad that I did, because this certainly was a nice movie. "The Locusts" is situated in the 1950's and shows how the arrival of Clay Hewitt changes life drastically in a small town. He's looking for a job and is hired by the local feed ranch's owner, an aging widow who likes to drink and seduce younger men. He quickly becomes her new lover, but also has an eye for her quiet son Flyboy. The boy hasn't spoken a word in years and is completely withdrawn since the death of his father. The only one who he talks to since his recent return from a mental hospital is his pet bull. But Clay wants to give it a try and gradually he manages to get the boy out of his isolation, much against the will of the boy's mother... Even though this is perhaps not the most original story ever, I must say that I had a good time watching this movie. The acting has a lot to do with that of course. Vince Vaughn is very enjoyable as Clay Hewitt and Kate Capshaw did a very fine job portraying Delilah, but in my opinion it is Jeremy Davies as Flyboy, who was the best this time. But overall this is a movie that portrayed its characters well and didn't drown in an overdose of plot twists. This is John Patrick Kelley's first and so far only film, but it certainly makes me look forward to new projects from this man. I give this movie a rating between 7/10 and 7.5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Smoke, smoke, smoke that cigarette
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lurch-17
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I got lung cancer from all the second-hand smoke. In nearly every scene, cigarettes play a prominent role. Either the director was a cigarette junkie, the cast were nicotine addicts, or tobacco companies funded the entire production. The plot was predictably hokey, the acting mediocre (with the exception of Flyman), and the directing lazy. It seemed to pause often to make some point but never delivered the point. Capshaw was especially disappointing. I managed to struggle through all 2+ hours waiting for something to reach out of this film. It never did. The high point was seeing Vince Vaughn take off his shirt - and I'm straight. Don't waste the time and money. It could drive you to lighting up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    **SPOILERS** Gripping movie!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tamila_gill
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are so many words that can be used to describe the emotions that I felt while watching this movie, and I'm not sure how to display them. But, I must preface my comments about this movie with the following: I am an unapologetic, unabashed fan of Vince Vaughn's acting, and I'm pretty sure that I always will be. I am, however, unbiased when it comes to a movie role, and can admit when I'm unimpressed with his work (his hosting of SNL back in 1998 quickly comes to mind). Having said this, here is a brief synopsis of what I received from this movie. My comments are based on the assumption that you have already watched this film. I felt that Vince Vaughn was amazingly convincing as Clay, a drifter on the run from his past. His portrayal of Clay Hewitt was nothing short of genius. I'll never understand how he successfully pulled off this role, because the script in itself left a lot to be desired, in my opinion. Somehow, Vaughn balanced a tough, gritty, emotionally unattached character with one that was gentle and loving at the same time. I was also surprised at how well the actors displayed various trust and emotional issues throughout the film. Flyboy (Jeremy Davies) gradually opens up to Clay, which allows him to gradually expose Flyboy to a whole new world little by little. Flyboy trusts Clay with everything, even to the point of eventually revealing the awful truth to him about "The Anniversary". Clay eventually feels comfortable (or desperate) enough to disclose information to Kitty (Ashley Judd) about tragic events that occurred in his recent past. He reveals that he has been lying to protect himself from his past, and hopes to move on and start over. The irony is that upon arrival to this rural Kansas town, Clay is unknowingly placed at the center of a family web of murder, suicide, lies and deceit. I also appreciate the dynamic between Clay and Kitty. He is emotionally detached from her throughout the entire film, and his emotional capacity is dominated by his concern for Flyboy. Kitty is spurned by Clay on every attempt at affection and communication with him. It turns out in the end that Kitty is all that Clay has emotionally and he instantly becomes desperate for her support; he literally needs her help to physically stand up in the end. I enjoyed how this played out. Flyboy's mother, Delilah, actually sets the whole stage for the tragedy that ends their branch on the family tree. In the last scene of the movie, it is obvious that she is plotting in her mind how everything will play out, and things turn out tragically according to her plan. Clay is the one person that Flyboy was correct in knowing that he could trust with his life. The fact that Flyboy died believing that Clay committed the ultimate betrayal is a devastating end that was admittedly almost too much for me to handle. This is especially considering that Clay's whole existence throughout the last 3/4 of the movie was centered around his interest and eventual love for Flyboy. One may think to himself that it's horrible for Clay to have entered Flyboy's life only for Flyboy to meet such a tragic demise. It may even appear indirectly that Clay is the reason for Flyboy's death. But I believe that had it not been for Clay, Flyboy may have lived longer, but remained miserable. He would never have known what it felt like to be loved by someone who truly considered Flyboy to be his best friend, or cared for by a woman that showed him genuine affection and considered time spent with him as "the best date she ever had"...to sum it up, had it not been for Clay entering his life, it's safe to assume that Flyboy would never have known what true love was. It's amazing to me that these actors (namely Vaughn and Davies) could work together in a way that allowed me to receive this much from this movie. I was truly touched by this film, and it has become one of my all time favorites.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too depressing for the likes of me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    celticwanderer
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I must confess the ONLY reason I bought this film was because I live in Sealy, TX, and some of the scenes were shot a few blocks from my house. Considering all the preparations made to the buildings in downtown Sealy for this film, I was disappointed to discover very little of the town was actually shown in the movie. It seems a lot of effort for so little, but I'm sure the city administration was happy just getting Sealy in the credits. As for the movie itself, really not my cup of tea. I don't like these kinds of films at all. But I will say I thought the acting was as good as it could be considering the script moved like a pregnant snail and the dialog was often very weak.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A family with shocking secrets.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Clay Hewitt(Vince Vaughn)is a drifter from Missouri stopping in 1960s Kansas in hope to earn some money. He only has seven bucks in his pocket. He meets some locals, including Joel(Daniel Meyer), Earl(Paul Rudd), Patsy(Jessica Capshaw) and Kitty(Ashley Judd). Earl suggests he look for employment at Delilah Ashford Potts'(Kate Capshaw) feed ranch. Delilah's reputation of sleeping with her hired hands is common place. She demeans her son 'Flyboy', who is traumatized from his father's death. Clay finally fits in with the other workers and of course is a sexual target of his boss lady. Before Clay talks Kitty into moving on to California; he discovers two big Potts family secrets. The strong sexuality earns THE LOCUSTS the R rating. I really like the diverse characters. The photography catches the moodiness of the story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth more than 2 stars on premium digital cable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ishpafaro
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An American movie without happy end. Kate Capshaw heads a cast of young actors. From the start she comes over disgusting. 2 hours later you'll love here. It is really a very dark family secret. Vince Vaughn, Jeremy Davies, Ashley Judd are some of the names in this well-done USA movie. Who gives this stares anyway? Movie made during the 1997s. TRY TO WATCH IT ! The rest of the cast is young and horny. It plays on a mid America cattle farm. A seasonal worker, who may or may not haved killed a girl in KC, Kansas City, Missourri, finds a job in the south. La Madame Capshaw says yes. She smokes a lot in the movie. and she has a most wonderful main house ans cattlle field. A lot of blood on t-shirts and skirts. It makes it more hot. WATCH THIS MOVIE ! In Europe they would possibly say that if Kate Capshaw wasn't married to Steven Spielberg, this movie would have been never made? But watch for yourself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    all560
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ever lie awake at night, watch something on some obscure cable channel, and end up wondering why you didn't drink yourself into a stupor several hours earlier? I just did. I'd probably feel better tomorrow, had I chosen the booze. THE LOCUSTS is a truly awful film. It's one of those that always makes me ask the questions "WHY was it done and WHERE did the money come from?" Forget the attempts, so en vogue today, of trying to date and sentimentalize a film by mindless overlays of classic music! Genuine inability is timeless. Here is the one good thing I can say about this film: Ms. Judd's make-up artist, Ben Nye, Jr, had the sense to leave her alone. She's radiant...from the safe distance she was photographed. But, everything else is likewise-photographed. I guess the photographer didn't feel comfortable any closer to the storyline. The acting is laughable, especially the three leads. The kid spends two hours trying to do a James Dean and succeeds only in setting back the cause of the speech-impaired a couple decades. He is in rarefied atmosphere here. Only Jennifer Jason Leigh in KANSAS CITY and Richard Gere in BREATHLESS have given comparable performances. Capshaw is, well, Capshaw. Vince who? Doesn't he do novelty records? But the plot takes the cake. To think that human beings would allow themselves to dwell in or near this attempt of some swaggering pump-up to inflict his "values" or "Code of the Cool" on a defenseless kid is ludicrous. The mindset of the executive(s) responsible for the allocation of funds and the filming itself, who must have found SOME potential in the story, is unfathomable. There is none. GIANT and DUEL IN THE SUN and LONG HOT SUMMER have been done before. With taste, opulence, style or length to cover gaps in meaning or worth. This film has none of any of that. Fortunately, the family off themselves at the end, preventing a sequel. I think I now understand why Orion bankrupted.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Locust or Praying mantis?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviemaster
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have to wonder if the cohesion that might have held this movie together is lying on the cutting room floor. There are so many subplots that are never properly developed and not tied up at the end. I stumbled into this movie thinking it was some Sci-Fi work (as described by the on screen analysis of "on demand.") I just wanted a movie to put me to sleep. This wasn't that movie. Locusts did not take over the planet. But I was immediately struck by the brooding nature of the direction and how it drew me into the movie. However, sometimes I felt like it was some mini-series I had missed the first episode of. Some of the performances were good, but the plot meandered along until it suddenly became hurried. In the last 10 minutes the "mother" tells of her rape by her father, her son drowns himself, somehow, in the gelding shed and the mother finally did the world a favor and shot herself. Fortunately our hero and heroine ride off into the sunset in their maroon pick up truck and we're marooned, wondering if this is a happy ending or not... that is if you can consider a man who raped and murdered a woman a "hero." In the end, it didn't put me to sleep, but made me wonder why I had stayed up so late.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Locusts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    arlenedayj
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Excellent! This movie was so good. The acting was absolutely amazing! Vince Vaughn is an amazing actor. More roles like this for Vince, no more crap like Wedding Crashers. Wonderfully acted movie.. Finally a movie that you have to watch and understand. Where have all the great acting movies gone.. More movies like this. The story was simply told. Vince Vaughn can certainly. I recommend this movie highly. The sound track set the tone for this movie and took you back to a simpler time, with more complex issues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    True drama...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    EighthSense
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...in the type and class of 'Cat on a hot tin roof' and 'Summer and smoke'. Jeremy Davies should have won an award for his very talented performance of a difficult role-he's this generation's Anthony Perkins. Vince Vaughn's performance was excellent and moving too, and a meaty role for him-a Marlon Brando-type role, to be sure! Dark, depressed, tragic movie,with an air of inevitability hanging over it, beautifully photographed, with a lovely sound track with several golden oldies. The soundtrack really set a tone and time for the movie, and was at the right volume, unlike so many current artless movies where blasting music or car engines obliterate the dialog. Too bad that the delay of Clay in running after Flyboy at the end of the movie, as Flyboy ran from his mother's bedroom, was not believable-it was obvious that Clay would have ran after his very distraught young friend right away.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A very nice debut with a good story and some fine acting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Philip Van der Veken
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Normally when I hear or read the title of a movie, I have some idea of what it could be like. That's not always correct, but most of the time it works - especially with famous movies of course. But when I read the title of this movie, I really didn't know what it would be about. Of course I didn't think that it would be a movie about the insect, but I just couldn't form a good idea about it. That's why I just gave it a try, not knowing what to expect, but hoping for the best. And I'm glad that I did, because this certainly was a nice movie. "The Locusts" is situated in the 1950's and shows how the arrival of Clay Hewitt changes life drastically in a small town. He's looking for a job and is hired by the local feed ranch's owner, an aging widow who likes to drink and seduce younger men. He quickly becomes her new lover, but also has an eye for her quiet son Flyboy. The boy hasn't spoken a word in years and is completely withdrawn since the death of his father. The only one who he talks to since his recent return from a mental hospital is his pet bull. But Clay wants to give it a try and gradually he manages to get the boy out of his isolation, much against the will of the boy's mother... Even though this is perhaps not the most original story ever, I must say that I had a good time watching this movie. The acting has a lot to do with that of course. Vince Vaughn is very enjoyable as Clay Hewitt and Kate Capshaw did a very fine job portraying Delilah, but in my opinion it is Jeremy Davies as Flyboy, who was the best this time. But overall this is a movie that portrayed its characters well and didn't drown in an overdose of plot twists. This is John Patrick Kelley's first and so far only film, but it certainly makes me look forward to new projects from this man. I give this movie a rating between 7/10 and 7.5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Smoke, smoke, smoke that cigarette
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lurch-17
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I got lung cancer from all the second-hand smoke. In nearly every scene, cigarettes play a prominent role. Either the director was a cigarette junkie, the cast were nicotine addicts, or tobacco companies funded the entire production. The plot was predictably hokey, the acting mediocre (with the exception of Flyman), and the directing lazy. It seemed to pause often to make some point but never delivered the point. Capshaw was especially disappointing. I managed to struggle through all 2+ hours waiting for something to reach out of this film. It never did. The high point was seeing Vince Vaughn take off his shirt - and I'm straight. Don't waste the time and money. It could drive you to lighting up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    **SPOILERS** Gripping movie!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tamila_gill
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are so many words that can be used to describe the emotions that I felt while watching this movie, and I'm not sure how to display them. But, I must preface my comments about this movie with the following: I am an unapologetic, unabashed fan of Vince Vaughn's acting, and I'm pretty sure that I always will be. I am, however, unbiased when it comes to a movie role, and can admit when I'm unimpressed with his work (his hosting of SNL back in 1998 quickly comes to mind). Having said this, here is a brief synopsis of what I received from this movie. My comments are based on the assumption that you have already watched this film. I felt that Vince Vaughn was amazingly convincing as Clay, a drifter on the run from his past. His portrayal of Clay Hewitt was nothing short of genius. I'll never understand how he successfully pulled off this role, because the script in itself left a lot to be desired, in my opinion. Somehow, Vaughn balanced a tough, gritty, emotionally unattached character with one that was gentle and loving at the same time. I was also surprised at how well the actors displayed various trust and emotional issues throughout the film. Flyboy (Jeremy Davies) gradually opens up to Clay, which allows him to gradually expose Flyboy to a whole new world little by little. Flyboy trusts Clay with everything, even to the point of eventually revealing the awful truth to him about "The Anniversary". Clay eventually feels comfortable (or desperate) enough to disclose information to Kitty (Ashley Judd) about tragic events that occurred in his recent past. He reveals that he has been lying to protect himself from his past, and hopes to move on and start over. The irony is that upon arrival to this rural Kansas town, Clay is unknowingly placed at the center of a family web of murder, suicide, lies and deceit. I also appreciate the dynamic between Clay and Kitty. He is emotionally detached from her throughout the entire film, and his emotional capacity is dominated by his concern for Flyboy. Kitty is spurned by Clay on every attempt at affection and communication with him. It turns out in the end that Kitty is all that Clay has emotionally and he instantly becomes desperate for her support; he literally needs her help to physically stand up in the end. I enjoyed how this played out. Flyboy's mother, Delilah, actually sets the whole stage for the tragedy that ends their branch on the family tree. In the last scene of the movie, it is obvious that she is plotting in her mind how everything will play out, and things turn out tragically according to her plan. Clay is the one person that Flyboy was correct in knowing that he could trust with his life. The fact that Flyboy died believing that Clay committed the ultimate betrayal is a devastating end that was admittedly almost too much for me to handle. This is especially considering that Clay's whole existence throughout the last 3/4 of the movie was centered around his interest and eventual love for Flyboy. One may think to himself that it's horrible for Clay to have entered Flyboy's life only for Flyboy to meet such a tragic demise. It may even appear indirectly that Clay is the reason for Flyboy's death. But I believe that had it not been for Clay, Flyboy may have lived longer, but remained miserable. He would never have known what it felt like to be loved by someone who truly considered Flyboy to be his best friend, or cared for by a woman that showed him genuine affection and considered time spent with him as "the best date she ever had"...to sum it up, had it not been for Clay entering his life, it's safe to assume that Flyboy would never have known what true love was. It's amazing to me that these actors (namely Vaughn and Davies) could work together in a way that allowed me to receive this much from this movie. I was truly touched by this film, and it has become one of my all time favorites.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too depressing for the likes of me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    celticwanderer
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I must confess the ONLY reason I bought this film was because I live in Sealy, TX, and some of the scenes were shot a few blocks from my house. Considering all the preparations made to the buildings in downtown Sealy for this film, I was disappointed to discover very little of the town was actually shown in the movie. It seems a lot of effort for so little, but I'm sure the city administration was happy just getting Sealy in the credits. As for the movie itself, really not my cup of tea. I don't like these kinds of films at all. But I will say I thought the acting was as good as it could be considering the script moved like a pregnant snail and the dialog was often very weak.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A family with shocking secrets.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Clay Hewitt(Vince Vaughn)is a drifter from Missouri stopping in 1960s Kansas in hope to earn some money. He only has seven bucks in his pocket. He meets some locals, including Joel(Daniel Meyer), Earl(Paul Rudd), Patsy(Jessica Capshaw) and Kitty(Ashley Judd). Earl suggests he look for employment at Delilah Ashford Potts'(Kate Capshaw) feed ranch. Delilah's reputation of sleeping with her hired hands is common place. She demeans her son 'Flyboy', who is traumatized from his father's death. Clay finally fits in with the other workers and of course is a sexual target of his boss lady. Before Clay talks Kitty into moving on to California; he discovers two big Potts family secrets. The strong sexuality earns THE LOCUSTS the R rating. I really like the diverse characters. The photography catches the moodiness of the story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth more than 2 stars on premium digital cable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ishpafaro
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An American movie without happy end. Kate Capshaw heads a cast of young actors. From the start she comes over disgusting. 2 hours later you'll love here. It is really a very dark family secret. Vince Vaughn, Jeremy Davies, Ashley Judd are some of the names in this well-done USA movie. Who gives this stares anyway? Movie made during the 1997s. TRY TO WATCH IT ! The rest of the cast is young and horny. It plays on a mid America cattle farm. A seasonal worker, who may or may not haved killed a girl in KC, Kansas City, Missourri, finds a job in the south. La Madame Capshaw says yes. She smokes a lot in the movie. and she has a most wonderful main house ans cattlle field. A lot of blood on t-shirts and skirts. It makes it more hot. WATCH THIS MOVIE ! In Europe they would possibly say that if Kate Capshaw wasn't married to Steven Spielberg, this movie would have been never made? But watch for yourself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    all560
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ever lie awake at night, watch something on some obscure cable channel, and end up wondering why you didn't drink yourself into a stupor several hours earlier? I just did. I'd probably feel better tomorrow, had I chosen the booze. THE LOCUSTS is a truly awful film. It's one of those that always makes me ask the questions "WHY was it done and WHERE did the money come from?" Forget the attempts, so en vogue today, of trying to date and sentimentalize a film by mindless overlays of classic music! Genuine inability is timeless. Here is the one good thing I can say about this film: Ms. Judd's make-up artist, Ben Nye, Jr, had the sense to leave her alone. She's radiant...from the safe distance she was photographed. But, everything else is likewise-photographed. I guess the photographer didn't feel comfortable any closer to the storyline. The acting is laughable, especially the three leads. The kid spends two hours trying to do a James Dean and succeeds only in setting back the cause of the speech-impaired a couple decades. He is in rarefied atmosphere here. Only Jennifer Jason Leigh in KANSAS CITY and Richard Gere in BREATHLESS have given comparable performances. Capshaw is, well, Capshaw. Vince who? Doesn't he do novelty records? But the plot takes the cake. To think that human beings would allow themselves to dwell in or near this attempt of some swaggering pump-up to inflict his "values" or "Code of the Cool" on a defenseless kid is ludicrous. The mindset of the executive(s) responsible for the allocation of funds and the filming itself, who must have found SOME potential in the story, is unfathomable. There is none. GIANT and DUEL IN THE SUN and LONG HOT SUMMER have been done before. With taste, opulence, style or length to cover gaps in meaning or worth. This film has none of any of that. Fortunately, the family off themselves at the end, preventing a sequel. I think I now understand why Orion bankrupted.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Locust or Praying mantis?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviemaster
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have to wonder if the cohesion that might have held this movie together is lying on the cutting room floor. There are so many subplots that are never properly developed and not tied up at the end. I stumbled into this movie thinking it was some Sci-Fi work (as described by the on screen analysis of "on demand.") I just wanted a movie to put me to sleep. This wasn't that movie. Locusts did not take over the planet. But I was immediately struck by the brooding nature of the direction and how it drew me into the movie. However, sometimes I felt like it was some mini-series I had missed the first episode of. Some of the performances were good, but the plot meandered along until it suddenly became hurried. In the last 10 minutes the "mother" tells of her rape by her father, her son drowns himself, somehow, in the gelding shed and the mother finally did the world a favor and shot herself. Fortunately our hero and heroine ride off into the sunset in their maroon pick up truck and we're marooned, wondering if this is a happy ending or not... that is if you can consider a man who raped and murdered a woman a "hero." In the end, it didn't put me to sleep, but made me wonder why I had stayed up so late.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Locusts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    arlenedayj
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Excellent! This movie was so good. The acting was absolutely amazing! Vince Vaughn is an amazing actor. More roles like this for Vince, no more crap like Wedding Crashers. Wonderfully acted movie.. Finally a movie that you have to watch and understand. Where have all the great acting movies gone.. More movies like this. The story was simply told. Vince Vaughn can certainly. I recommend this movie highly. The sound track set the tone for this movie and took you back to a simpler time, with more complex issues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    True drama...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    EighthSense
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...in the type and class of 'Cat on a hot tin roof' and 'Summer and smoke'. Jeremy Davies should have won an award for his very talented performance of a difficult role-he's this generation's Anthony Perkins. Vince Vaughn's performance was excellent and moving too, and a meaty role for him-a Marlon Brando-type role, to be sure! Dark, depressed, tragic movie,with an air of inevitability hanging over it, beautifully photographed, with a lovely sound track with several golden oldies. The soundtrack really set a tone and time for the movie, and was at the right volume, unlike so many current artless movies where blasting music or car engines obliterate the dialog. Too bad that the delay of Clay in running after Flyboy at the end of the movie, as Flyboy ran from his mother's bedroom, was not believable-it was obvious that Clay would have ran after his very distraught young friend right away.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A very nice debut with a good story and some fine acting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Philip Van der Veken
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Normally when I hear or read the title of a movie, I have some idea of what it could be like. That's not always correct, but most of the time it works - especially with famous movies of course. But when I read the title of this movie, I really didn't know what it would be about. Of course I didn't think that it would be a movie about the insect, but I just couldn't form a good idea about it. That's why I just gave it a try, not knowing what to expect, but hoping for the best. And I'm glad that I did, because this certainly was a nice movie. "The Locusts" is situated in the 1950's and shows how the arrival of Clay Hewitt changes life drastically in a small town. He's looking for a job and is hired by the local feed ranch's owner, an aging widow who likes to drink and seduce younger men. He quickly becomes her new lover, but also has an eye for her quiet son Flyboy. The boy hasn't spoken a word in years and is completely withdrawn since the death of his father. The only one who he talks to since his recent return from a mental hospital is his pet bull. But Clay wants to give it a try and gradually he manages to get the boy out of his isolation, much against the will of the boy's mother... Even though this is perhaps not the most original story ever, I must say that I had a good time watching this movie. The acting has a lot to do with that of course. Vince Vaughn is very enjoyable as Clay Hewitt and Kate Capshaw did a very fine job portraying Delilah, but in my opinion it is Jeremy Davies as Flyboy, who was the best this time. But overall this is a movie that portrayed its characters well and didn't drown in an overdose of plot twists. This is John Patrick Kelley's first and so far only film, but it certainly makes me look forward to new projects from this man. I give this movie a rating between 7/10 and 7.5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Smoke, smoke, smoke that cigarette
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lurch-17
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I got lung cancer from all the second-hand smoke. In nearly every scene, cigarettes play a prominent role. Either the director was a cigarette junkie, the cast were nicotine addicts, or tobacco companies funded the entire production. The plot was predictably hokey, the acting mediocre (with the exception of Flyman), and the directing lazy. It seemed to pause often to make some point but never delivered the point. Capshaw was especially disappointing. I managed to struggle through all 2+ hours waiting for something to reach out of this film. It never did. The high point was seeing Vince Vaughn take off his shirt - and I'm straight. Don't waste the time and money. It could drive you to lighting up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    **SPOILERS** Gripping movie!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tamila_gill
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are so many words that can be used to describe the emotions that I felt while watching this movie, and I'm not sure how to display them. But, I must preface my comments about this movie with the following: I am an unapologetic, unabashed fan of Vince Vaughn's acting, and I'm pretty sure that I always will be. I am, however, unbiased when it comes to a movie role, and can admit when I'm unimpressed with his work (his hosting of SNL back in 1998 quickly comes to mind). Having said this, here is a brief synopsis of what I received from this movie. My comments are based on the assumption that you have already watched this film. I felt that Vince Vaughn was amazingly convincing as Clay, a drifter on the run from his past. His portrayal of Clay Hewitt was nothing short of genius. I'll never understand how he successfully pulled off this role, because the script in itself left a lot to be desired, in my opinion. Somehow, Vaughn balanced a tough, gritty, emotionally unattached character with one that was gentle and loving at the same time. I was also surprised at how well the actors displayed various trust and emotional issues throughout the film. Flyboy (Jeremy Davies) gradually opens up to Clay, which allows him to gradually expose Flyboy to a whole new world little by little. Flyboy trusts Clay with everything, even to the point of eventually revealing the awful truth to him about "The Anniversary". Clay eventually feels comfortable (or desperate) enough to disclose information to Kitty (Ashley Judd) about tragic events that occurred in his recent past. He reveals that he has been lying to protect himself from his past, and hopes to move on and start over. The irony is that upon arrival to this rural Kansas town, Clay is unknowingly placed at the center of a family web of murder, suicide, lies and deceit. I also appreciate the dynamic between Clay and Kitty. He is emotionally detached from her throughout the entire film, and his emotional capacity is dominated by his concern for Flyboy. Kitty is spurned by Clay on every attempt at affection and communication with him. It turns out in the end that Kitty is all that Clay has emotionally and he instantly becomes desperate for her support; he literally needs her help to physically stand up in the end. I enjoyed how this played out. Flyboy's mother, Delilah, actually sets the whole stage for the tragedy that ends their branch on the family tree. In the last scene of the movie, it is obvious that she is plotting in her mind how everything will play out, and things turn out tragically according to her plan. Clay is the one person that Flyboy was correct in knowing that he could trust with his life. The fact that Flyboy died believing that Clay committed the ultimate betrayal is a devastating end that was admittedly almost too much for me to handle. This is especially considering that Clay's whole existence throughout the last 3/4 of the movie was centered around his interest and eventual love for Flyboy. One may think to himself that it's horrible for Clay to have entered Flyboy's life only for Flyboy to meet such a tragic demise. It may even appear indirectly that Clay is the reason for Flyboy's death. But I believe that had it not been for Clay, Flyboy may have lived longer, but remained miserable. He would never have known what it felt like to be loved by someone who truly considered Flyboy to be his best friend, or cared for by a woman that showed him genuine affection and considered time spent with him as "the best date she ever had"...to sum it up, had it not been for Clay entering his life, it's safe to assume that Flyboy would never have known what true love was. It's amazing to me that these actors (namely Vaughn and Davies) could work together in a way that allowed me to receive this much from this movie. I was truly touched by this film, and it has become one of my all time favorites.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
