<filme>
 <id>
  14
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110877
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Carteiro e o Poeta
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Simple Italian postman learns to love poetry while delivering mail to a famous poet; he uses this to woo local beauty Beatrice.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Pablo Neruda, the famous Chilean poet, is exiled to a small island for political reasons. On the island, the unemployed son of a poor fisherman is hired as an extra postman due to the huge increase in mail that this causes. Il Postino is to hand-deliver the celebrity's mail to him. Though poorly educated, the postman learns to love poetry and eventually befriends Neruda. Struggling to grow and express himself more fully, he suddenly falls in love and needs Neruda's help and guidance more than ever.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Biography
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   postman
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   poetry
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   island
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   poet
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   pablo neruda
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Michael Radford
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Antonio Sk&aacute;rmeta
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Furio Scarpelli
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Massimo Troisi
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Philippe Noiret
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Maria Grazia Cucinotta
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    United in Friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although "Il Postino" simply means "The Postman", and although the film was at one time screened as "The Postman" in Britain, it is now generally known in English by its&nbsp;Italian title to avoid confusion with Kevin Costner's post-apocalyptic epic from three years later. It is loosely based upon the novel&nbsp;"Ardiente paciencia"&nbsp;by&nbsp;the Chilean&nbsp;writer Antonio Sk&aacute;rmeta, although it transfers the action from Chile to Italy. It takes as its starting-point the fact that in the early 1950s the famous&nbsp;Chilean&nbsp;poet&nbsp;Pablo Neruda, in exile from his homeland for political reasons, spent some time on the island of Capri. The film, however, is not set on Capri but on an unnamed Italian island. A young fisherman named Mario Ruoppolo applies for a job as the island's postman. As he owns a bicycle and is one of the very few islanders who can read and write he is accepted and is told that he will only have one customer, Neruda himself, as because of the low levels of literacy on the island nobody else ever receives any mail. (Were standards of education really so low in fifties Italy?) Although Mario has never previously heard of Neruda, and certainly has never read any of his poems, a friendship gradually grows up between the two men. Although Mario has had little formal education he is clearly an intelligent and sensitive man, and Neruda reads him some of his poetry (in Italian translation), teaching him about literary concepts such as metaphors. With Neruda's help Mario&nbsp;woos the beautiful Beatrice, a village girl with whom he has&nbsp;fallen in love, stealing some of the older man's love poems and passing them off as his own in order to win her affections. My one criticism of the film would be that it is too sentimental about Communism, but that is perhaps only to be expected of a film from Italy, a country which at one time had the largest Communist Party in Western Europe. (In the seventies they used to win around a third of the popular vote, at a time when the British Communist Party generally consisted of three old men and a dog). Pablo Neruda is here portrayed as a kindly, idealistic gentleman, but in reality, during the forties and early fifties, he was a Communist hardliner who enthusiastically defended Stalin's dictatorship in the Soviet Union. After Khrushchev's 1956 "secret speech" he was to criticise the Stalinist cult of personality but this was due less to a change of heart than to a desire to align himself with the new official Soviet party line. He was also, at the time of his Italian exile, around twenty years younger than the character portrayed here by Philippe Noiret. Its politics aside, however, "Il Postino" is in many ways an excellent film. There is some attractive photography of the Italian coastal scenery and a great musical score by Luis Enr&iacute;quez Bacalov. What really makes the film stand out, however, are the two great performances from Noiret and from Massimo Troisi, who tragically died of a heart attack soon afterwards, as Mario. There is also a good performance from the lovely Maria Grazia Cucinotta as Beatrice. Troisi received a posthumous Oscar nomination for "Best Actor", but lost out to Nicholas Cage in "Leaving Las Vegas"; as I have never seen that film I am unable to comment on the justice of that decision. I felt, however, that it was unfortunate that there was no nomination for Noiret either as "Best Actor" or "Best Supporting Actor". Indeed, this is one of those films which make me feel that it should be possible to nominate two actors for a joint award, as Noiret and Troisi combine together so well that their joint contribution seems greater than the sum of its two parts. This is the story of a touching relationship between two men of different generations, of different nationalities, of different levels of education and of&nbsp;different outlooks on life who are nevertheless united in friendship. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The deliverance of one man of letters by another is a cinematic love letter to poetry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edantheman
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Chilean poet and communist agitator Pablo Neruda may never have set foot on the island of Salina in 1950, but writer-actor Mariamo Troisi's exploration of the idea is probably more interesting than any account of his actual exiles abroad. The eponymous postman of the film, Mario, has never taken to the patrilineal profession of fishing in his family. His widower father understands he never will and releases his seemingly simple son from his duties, to choose an occupation more suited to his abilities. In town, the communist postmaster needs a hand with the flurry of fan mail in the wake of Neruda and his wife's arrival. He greatly admires the Bolivarian bard and has his new postman run reconnaissance and procure signatures from him. Though their early exchanges may be of little significance, the two very different men of letters soon form a bond through a series of exchanges on poetry, love and politics. When Mario first meets barmaid Beatrice Russo over a game of table football, he instantly falls in love. He is inspired by his mentor to write her love poems, many of which he plagiarizes, and soon wins her heart. Michael Radford's surname may seem a little consonant-heavy for a production of this origin but the writer-director's English eye can only be clearly detected in the humour of the pacey, racy table football scene; which a native or continental director may have shot a little more seductively. It is really Troisi who leaves his indelible print on the film, which would be his last (dying tragically the day after production wrapped). The actor's physical frailty comes across as his character's mumbling humility. When beautiful Maria Grazia Cucinotta falls for his charms (or lack thereof), no one would seem more deserving a husband than he, and it is immensely gratifying to see his son Pablito stumble onto screen at the end. Phillipe Noiret also evokes much feeling in the last scene, imagining his friend's great yet fatal agitation for change, while walking their familiar beach. We get the feeling they may have liberated one another. 'Il Postino' is very much a film that flows like poetry. There is no solid structure as prescribed by the script doctors of the time. No stakes and little drama. When our lovable protagonist dies at the end, it is not played for tears of devastation. I felt quiet elation: he had finally found his voice and could speak up for his people at the rally. He asks Neruda earlier in the film a question regarding the writer's revolutionary ideals, "So what if we break off our chains? What do we do then?" He obviously has an answer to that question by the end, which is satisfaction enough. In another exchange, when Mario's plagiarism is discovered by Pablo, he counters "Poetry doesn't belong to those who write it; it belongs to those who need it." This strikes one as quite humorous in the context of the scene but when recalled or read alone it signifies the point at which Mario has cast the chains off his mind. Sadly the distributors do not live by this dictum, and intellectual copyright law prevails online and elsewhere. While it may be a fictional account, the film is very much a celebration of the actual effect Neruda's poetry had on many of the working people of the world. Not so much a tribute to him, but to the millions of postini worldwide who have been delivered and a rallying call for all those who have yet to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Massimo Troisi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    his performance is essence of this adorable film. his character is so careful created that its fragility, humor, innocence, light of details are magnificent. he don't play a role but he is "il postino" . and this fact transforms entire scene. the story of Neruda exile is only arena for emotions of a small man on an Italian isle. the beautiful Beatrice is brick for his delicate happiness. Neruda himself is not exactly a mentor but a gardener. and the music, the extraordinary music, it is the soul of entire poetry. because a poetry is this movie who has as roots poems. very delicate, nice, nostalgic, melancholic, subtle, intelligent, precise, it is wonderful homage to a way to discover life as fundamental miracle. to feel the nuances of love, friendship, to be humble, modest and daring in same time, to feel gratitude as form of respiration. beautiful and impressive. touching. and unique. story of a postman. legacy of Massimo Troisi.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Art and Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gradyharp
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just visited the opera version of this film IL POSTINO by Daniel Catan courtesy of PBS Great Performances it is rewarding to return to the original source to honor the nidus for the inspiration for the opera. Directed by Michael Radford the film relates the heartwarming story of Mario (Massimo Troisi), a gentle and simple postman who falls for the beautiful caf&eacute; waitress Beatrice (Maria Grazia Cucinotta) from his village, but is too shy to speak to her. He meets the famous Chilean poet Pablo Neruda (Phillipe Noiret), and, as their friendship develops, the postman's own inner poet awakens. Soon he is able to win the love of Beatrice and even stand up for and express his own beliefs. This is a simple story graced by sensitive performances: of not the actor Massimo Trosi died from heart failure on the last day of production of the film. It is possibly this knowledge of the loss of one of Italy's best comedic actors along with the clarity and transparency of the film's gentle message about love and art that has made it a cult film. At any rate this is a film that belongs in every movie lover's library. Grady Harp
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great cinematography, good acting by Trosi, but Neruda comes out the loser here.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    felixoteiza
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is actually an Italian fairy tale, one where Neruda is little more than a simple enabler for two lovebirds. The story of a humble, uneducated, man who conquers the heart of a girl with words borrowed, or stolen, from the great poet. Nothing wrong with that, except that this Master of Words proves at the end to be very flawed, unworthy of the worshiping he's the object of-but more of that later. Decent acting overall, breathtaking scenerythose postcard coastal natural settings are also common in Neruda's Chilebut the writing lets a lot to be desired, with too many schmaltzy scenes & dialogs and assorted clich&eacute; situations. Not surprise then that he plot loses its breath half way, when the lovebirds get married and Pablo returns to Chile. What is left then is the same thing we had at the beginning: the daily routines of a small fishing town in southern Italy. Will that be enough to carry the rest of the movie? Don't think so. This isn't Amacord or IVitelloni, as the whole plot was resting on the relationship Neruda--Mario and so when that comes to an end the movie is left gasping for air, begging for some emotional filling as a replacement. With the poet gone and the romance morphed into routine, all what's left for Mario are unfulfilled family obligations and a constant moping for the absent Master. There is an obvious plot discontinuity when both men separate, perhaps because this script was made sewing up two original stories, set in different places at different times. Sure enough, Neruda was in exile in Italy after having fled Chile in 1949, when the Chilean government started jailing Communists, despite them being part of the governing coalition (!) after being pressured by the Yankees, who had started their own witch hunt. (it's hard to believe, but the reason why communists were hunted down was because Chile's president was afraid of it being considered unfriendly by the U.S and risk losing trade, diplomatic and political benefits). Neruda escaped to Argentina & then to Italy, where he was well received thanks to the work made on Italian public opinion by fellow communist Alberto Moravia. On the other hand, the story of him befriending a postman and writing him poems dedicated to his love interest comes from Antonio Skarmeta's Ardiente Paciencia, set in Chile in the 60s, in the coastal town of Isla Negra, where Neruda had a cottage (which is now a museum). So, this is really a Chilean story transposed to Italy, which may explain the awkward plot situation produced when Neruda leaves. Now, Noiret may be a great actor but he makes a disfavor to Neruda with his work here, at least in 2 instances. First, when he's back in Chile he forgets about Mario and doesn't even answer his mail. The real Neruda would have never done that, because for him friendship and loyalty were two things intrinsically tied to class struggle and political commitment. For him all communists--and all members of the working class-were his brothers whatever may have been their countries of origin or their educational level, and all right wingers and rich people in general his enemies, as for him there was no middle ground at that. In real life he would have never acted like he does with Mario, just because he's a less educated man. At least he would have sent him a postcard. The 2nd thing is you would have never caught him in church, let alone crossing himself, as he was an atheist who had no use for religions or for any organized church and the only people in that realm for whom he ever came to feel any respect at all were the Quakers, just because they helped pay for travel tickets to Chile for thousands of Spaniards fleeing their civil war. It's obvious that both misrepresentations have been committed to keep the plot going, which I can understand, but the record must be set straight anyway. Anyway, IP can be very touching the first time you see it, but it goes losing its emotional punch with time, as there's no much left to get hold of after the thrill of the love story and that of the beautiful words wears off. But worse is the portrayal of Neruda as a snob; an hypocrite who'll be nice to the locals as long as he needs them but who'll forget them as soon as he's gone. I'm all for artistic licenses, but not when they make appear an authentic individual under such an unfavorable and false light. In all, to see maybe a couple of times. Anyway, if you want to see something closer to the real man, watch Skarmeta's Ardiente Paciencia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who Really Wrote the Score?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jacobsencurtis
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Il Postino" is one of my favorite movies. The acting is superb. Massimo Troisi gives a uniquely unforgettable performance, despite his suffering from a fatal illness during filming. Phillipe Noiret, as Pablo Neruda, the Chilean poet-in-exile who befriends Mario (Troisi), gives one of his most memorable performances. The location is enchanting. I love all things Italian. Even a bad movie set in Italy is better for it having been shot there. Some of my favorites are "Enchanted April," "Summertime," and "Roman Holiday." And I love the score, which, until tonight, I assumed was written by Luis Bacalov, who is credited in the movie. But I just watched a movie from 1940 called "Dispatch from Reuters," a bio-pic starring Edward G. Robinson, and darned if the main theme from "Il Postino" isn't straight out of "Dispatch from Reuters." By the way, the music for "Reuters" was composed by the great Max Steiner, who, to my knowledge, received no screen credit in "Il Postino." How is this possible? Has the copyright expired rendering the music part of the public domain?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mundane
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike B
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I found this rather superficial and mundane. It's about the friendship between a worker  a postman - and a poet  Pablo Neruda. The poet awakens the young man's sensibilities and gives him the courage to pursue the village beauty. This is a tiny village - so why he had not realized her beauty before, and more so, why she was not being pursued by an entire flock of young men raised a question mark. The characters are all stereo-typed  the shy postman, the over-wordy poet and the village beauty with her raspy aunt. Everything was a caricature and the film suffered from a lack of passion, intensityI couldn't buy into it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice try, but not quite what I expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only heard of this movie on the TV game show 'Who Wants to be a Millionaire?'. The question was which one of 4 mentioned actors starred in the films 'Nuovo Cinema Paradiso' and 'Il Postino'. I hadn't heard of 'Il Postino' before, but I knew that Philippe Noiret stars in 'Nuovo Cinema Paradiso', so I already knew the answer. The presenter recommended the person who wrongly answered the question to watch these 2 movies because something changes inside us once we get to see these 2 films. Then I did research on this motion-picture. It sounded promising, even more so by being foreign. I also got to know the sad story of Massimo Troisi, who played the title's postman (Pablo Neruda's postman). The man suffered from heart disease since a long time ago. He knew about his fragile heart condition and knew he needed treatment, but despite this he wanted to do the movie anyway. He even postponed heart surgery so that he could complete the film. That was a brave move. And he did manage to finish the movie just in time. Only 12 hours after completing the film he died of heart attack. You can say that he gave his life to make this film. Massimo Troisi is great as Mario Ruoppolo, the postman. But it's also sad to see him in this film because we are looking at a man who was dying while making it and that he died almost immediately after completing it. Phillipe Noiret is great as the chilean poet Pablo Neruda. While Pablo Neruda existed for real, his friendship with the postman didn't. But I don't know if a postman named Mario Ruoppolo existed in real life or not and if he was Pablo Neruda's postman or not. The film's got beautiful cinematography and soundtrack, which gives it more emotion and beauty. The plot is, in concept, good. But the movie itself lacks something (perhaps more emotion is one of those things it lacks) and is even a little too-slow paced. It's not a bad movie. It's interesting, moving, pretty to view... a good attempt, just not quite top material. It just isn't as great as it reputation suggests (with, of course, all due respect in memory of our friend Massimo Troisi).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engrossing character study about two men and their connections to two separate women, as well as the poetry that forms the core of their own friendship.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Radford's tender and rather sweet film, The Postman, is a really quite blinding tale of a man, without either much of a life or very many happenings in and around his existence, going out of his way so as to spawn some. The film is a ground zero character study working its way up, centring on one man and coming to gloriously flesh out his relationships with two people in the form of a mentor and a love interest using the item of poetry, and poets in particular, as a focal point or anchor around which to revolve the ever shifting lives of these half a dozen-or so people. The central character is a certain young man named Mario Ruoppolo, played by Italian actor Massimo Troisi whom died shortly after the film was completed and is one of only seven people to have won a Posthumous Academy Award for acting, which he won for his portrayal of a character named Mario. His life in the early part of the 20th Century on an island off the coast of Italy lies seemingly dormant; a living with his father, whom spends his days at sea fishing for a living, whilst inhabiting a scruffy and run down house on the cliff-side which cannot even produce water from a tap when desired, the situation; with a postcard from some brothers whom have arrived in America offering a brief insight into a supposedly better life. Determined to get on track, the softly spoken; delicate and slow moving Mario shifts off to a local post office so as to apply for the advertised job of delivering letters and mail, locally. On another tangent, that later will become intrinsically linked to that of Mario, a controversial poet from South American nation Chile of true to life existence named Pablo Neruda (Noiret) arrives in Italy having been exiled. His demeanour arrives by way of a newsreel sequence at a picture house, footage which the locals and us watch and listen to simultaneously establishing a set-persona of the man and his controversial, Communist infused existence of writing poetry crash-landing on this small Italian island, much to some of the locals' anger but to the glee of others. The early perceptions of the man are meant to be relatively concrete; he inhabits a beautifully placed but isolated red-washed villa on a separate cliff edge, before plodding Mario comes to form a bond with the poet upon delivering his many letters and from whence the film garners its catalyst so as to play out. The film comes to form a learning process for that of Mario, a deconstruction of an item or art-form that he'd almost certainly heard of in the past but very rarely thought about above a certain level. The same can be said for that of Chilian poet Neruda in regards to the fondness and acceptance the town come to have of him after he and his wife and their bond with a number of people come to forge, a relationship much richer than what he has experienced back home or, you feel, in most other places. Romance appears to want to bloom between Mario and local girl Beatrice (Cucinotta), the daughter of a traditional, hard-up Catholic woman whom owns a tavern within the vicinity; the spying of her playing a game of rather erotically charged flick-rod football in said tavern complete with thrusting of the mannequin players and hammering home of the goals more than enough to have Mario smitten from then on in. But the film is ultimately about the relationship or bond between two men going on around their separate relationships with Beatrice and Pablo's own female partner whom later becomes his wife. It would be untrue to say that the film at all feels less of an accomplishment when certain events transpire and the once central unification of Mario and Pablo is broken up; rather, the ties they have to one another during the film's early scenes are just more interesting, as is the chilling finale involving the two, than any sub-plot to do with either men and what happens between them and their women. Mario's attempts to court a young local girl and the noticeable placing of Pablo's own female partner predominantly off screen and away from the action for most of the time might render the relationship between Mario and Pablo one of a homo-erotic nature. Much later on, a Paris based interview with the poet some years later has Mario read on with keen interest as to whether he or anyone from the town are mentioned; the camera darting around from face to face of those reading with Mario in a kind of panic or nervous excitement or lusting requirement for purifying fulfilment in the form of notifying them, predominantly the notifying of Mario. The convenience in having come to have known a master of poetry of a romantic sort, somebody that feeds off of a belief that all women love romantic poetry and that it is the key to pertaining to a relationship, works very much in Mario's favour. His gradual learning of how to construct it, the encountering of terms and words such as what a metaphor is gradually come to form the nucleus of the first half of the film; a fitting sequence on a nearby beach sees Pablo gradually reveal himself as he readies to swim in a physical sense as Mario comes to reveal a spoken metaphor for the very first time as, on another occasion, he gradually forms an opinion of a short poem Pablo comes up with on the spot. The film's attention to finer things such as these, an including of sequences in which characters must first come to master the basics of an art or activity so as to garner entry onto another plateau so as to put what has been learnt into action, feels wonderfully prominent, resulting in Radford's film being thoroughly worthwhile.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    magnificent masterpiece of Michael with two marvelous metaphors --the poet(Pablo) and the postman(Mario)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    superdirector007
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    what a magnificent movie, legendary work by Michael Redford , everything about this movie is beautiful ,,winning Oscar does not come in easy way ,,be it budget,,cinematography covering island's natural beauty ,,specially sea settings ,humourous dialogs with utmost simplicity and realistic performances by actors ,everything is admirable. sometimes you do not plan to make a great movie with highly perfection attitude but movie becomes and gets applauded ,,same happened with this movie,what i believe what is metaphor Mario asks Pablo says-like sky is weeping what does it mean Mario says means to say sky is raining Mario's response it's complicated and Pablo's response that complication does not have to do anything with person's emotions very meaningful and soulful dialogs ,that is the reason movie does not become boring end of the movie is very surprising ,it keeps you involve in the movie movie was shot on the island near by Meditteranean sea and every time tides go and again come to touch coastal areas that resembles one excellent scene goes with the hope to come with another lovely scene filled with emotional and heart touching dialogs to touch your heart movie is pretty simple but can you predict what's gonna happen in next scene ,probably not ,it has certain surprising elements this movie is not a movie this is everlasting experience to live with and cherish it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    United in Friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although "Il Postino" simply means "The Postman", and although the film was at one time screened as "The Postman" in Britain, it is now generally known in English by its&nbsp;Italian title to avoid confusion with Kevin Costner's post-apocalyptic epic from three years later. It is loosely based upon the novel&nbsp;"Ardiente paciencia"&nbsp;by&nbsp;the Chilean&nbsp;writer Antonio Sk&aacute;rmeta, although it transfers the action from Chile to Italy. It takes as its starting-point the fact that in the early 1950s the famous&nbsp;Chilean&nbsp;poet&nbsp;Pablo Neruda, in exile from his homeland for political reasons, spent some time on the island of Capri. The film, however, is not set on Capri but on an unnamed Italian island. A young fisherman named Mario Ruoppolo applies for a job as the island's postman. As he owns a bicycle and is one of the very few islanders who can read and write he is accepted and is told that he will only have one customer, Neruda himself, as because of the low levels of literacy on the island nobody else ever receives any mail. (Were standards of education really so low in fifties Italy?) Although Mario has never previously heard of Neruda, and certainly has never read any of his poems, a friendship gradually grows up between the two men. Although Mario has had little formal education he is clearly an intelligent and sensitive man, and Neruda reads him some of his poetry (in Italian translation), teaching him about literary concepts such as metaphors. With Neruda's help Mario&nbsp;woos the beautiful Beatrice, a village girl with whom he has&nbsp;fallen in love, stealing some of the older man's love poems and passing them off as his own in order to win her affections. My one criticism of the film would be that it is too sentimental about Communism, but that is perhaps only to be expected of a film from Italy, a country which at one time had the largest Communist Party in Western Europe. (In the seventies they used to win around a third of the popular vote, at a time when the British Communist Party generally consisted of three old men and a dog). Pablo Neruda is here portrayed as a kindly, idealistic gentleman, but in reality, during the forties and early fifties, he was a Communist hardliner who enthusiastically defended Stalin's dictatorship in the Soviet Union. After Khrushchev's 1956 "secret speech" he was to criticise the Stalinist cult of personality but this was due less to a change of heart than to a desire to align himself with the new official Soviet party line. He was also, at the time of his Italian exile, around twenty years younger than the character portrayed here by Philippe Noiret. Its politics aside, however, "Il Postino" is in many ways an excellent film. There is some attractive photography of the Italian coastal scenery and a great musical score by Luis Enr&iacute;quez Bacalov. What really makes the film stand out, however, are the two great performances from Noiret and from Massimo Troisi, who tragically died of a heart attack soon afterwards, as Mario. There is also a good performance from the lovely Maria Grazia Cucinotta as Beatrice. Troisi received a posthumous Oscar nomination for "Best Actor", but lost out to Nicholas Cage in "Leaving Las Vegas"; as I have never seen that film I am unable to comment on the justice of that decision. I felt, however, that it was unfortunate that there was no nomination for Noiret either as "Best Actor" or "Best Supporting Actor". Indeed, this is one of those films which make me feel that it should be possible to nominate two actors for a joint award, as Noiret and Troisi combine together so well that their joint contribution seems greater than the sum of its two parts. This is the story of a touching relationship between two men of different generations, of different nationalities, of different levels of education and of&nbsp;different outlooks on life who are nevertheless united in friendship. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The deliverance of one man of letters by another is a cinematic love letter to poetry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edantheman
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Chilean poet and communist agitator Pablo Neruda may never have set foot on the island of Salina in 1950, but writer-actor Mariamo Troisi's exploration of the idea is probably more interesting than any account of his actual exiles abroad. The eponymous postman of the film, Mario, has never taken to the patrilineal profession of fishing in his family. His widower father understands he never will and releases his seemingly simple son from his duties, to choose an occupation more suited to his abilities. In town, the communist postmaster needs a hand with the flurry of fan mail in the wake of Neruda and his wife's arrival. He greatly admires the Bolivarian bard and has his new postman run reconnaissance and procure signatures from him. Though their early exchanges may be of little significance, the two very different men of letters soon form a bond through a series of exchanges on poetry, love and politics. When Mario first meets barmaid Beatrice Russo over a game of table football, he instantly falls in love. He is inspired by his mentor to write her love poems, many of which he plagiarizes, and soon wins her heart. Michael Radford's surname may seem a little consonant-heavy for a production of this origin but the writer-director's English eye can only be clearly detected in the humour of the pacey, racy table football scene; which a native or continental director may have shot a little more seductively. It is really Troisi who leaves his indelible print on the film, which would be his last (dying tragically the day after production wrapped). The actor's physical frailty comes across as his character's mumbling humility. When beautiful Maria Grazia Cucinotta falls for his charms (or lack thereof), no one would seem more deserving a husband than he, and it is immensely gratifying to see his son Pablito stumble onto screen at the end. Phillipe Noiret also evokes much feeling in the last scene, imagining his friend's great yet fatal agitation for change, while walking their familiar beach. We get the feeling they may have liberated one another. 'Il Postino' is very much a film that flows like poetry. There is no solid structure as prescribed by the script doctors of the time. No stakes and little drama. When our lovable protagonist dies at the end, it is not played for tears of devastation. I felt quiet elation: he had finally found his voice and could speak up for his people at the rally. He asks Neruda earlier in the film a question regarding the writer's revolutionary ideals, "So what if we break off our chains? What do we do then?" He obviously has an answer to that question by the end, which is satisfaction enough. In another exchange, when Mario's plagiarism is discovered by Pablo, he counters "Poetry doesn't belong to those who write it; it belongs to those who need it." This strikes one as quite humorous in the context of the scene but when recalled or read alone it signifies the point at which Mario has cast the chains off his mind. Sadly the distributors do not live by this dictum, and intellectual copyright law prevails online and elsewhere. While it may be a fictional account, the film is very much a celebration of the actual effect Neruda's poetry had on many of the working people of the world. Not so much a tribute to him, but to the millions of postini worldwide who have been delivered and a rallying call for all those who have yet to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Massimo Troisi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    his performance is essence of this adorable film. his character is so careful created that its fragility, humor, innocence, light of details are magnificent. he don't play a role but he is "il postino" . and this fact transforms entire scene. the story of Neruda exile is only arena for emotions of a small man on an Italian isle. the beautiful Beatrice is brick for his delicate happiness. Neruda himself is not exactly a mentor but a gardener. and the music, the extraordinary music, it is the soul of entire poetry. because a poetry is this movie who has as roots poems. very delicate, nice, nostalgic, melancholic, subtle, intelligent, precise, it is wonderful homage to a way to discover life as fundamental miracle. to feel the nuances of love, friendship, to be humble, modest and daring in same time, to feel gratitude as form of respiration. beautiful and impressive. touching. and unique. story of a postman. legacy of Massimo Troisi.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Art and Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gradyharp
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just visited the opera version of this film IL POSTINO by Daniel Catan courtesy of PBS Great Performances it is rewarding to return to the original source to honor the nidus for the inspiration for the opera. Directed by Michael Radford the film relates the heartwarming story of Mario (Massimo Troisi), a gentle and simple postman who falls for the beautiful caf&eacute; waitress Beatrice (Maria Grazia Cucinotta) from his village, but is too shy to speak to her. He meets the famous Chilean poet Pablo Neruda (Phillipe Noiret), and, as their friendship develops, the postman's own inner poet awakens. Soon he is able to win the love of Beatrice and even stand up for and express his own beliefs. This is a simple story graced by sensitive performances: of not the actor Massimo Trosi died from heart failure on the last day of production of the film. It is possibly this knowledge of the loss of one of Italy's best comedic actors along with the clarity and transparency of the film's gentle message about love and art that has made it a cult film. At any rate this is a film that belongs in every movie lover's library. Grady Harp
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great cinematography, good acting by Trosi, but Neruda comes out the loser here.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    felixoteiza
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is actually an Italian fairy tale, one where Neruda is little more than a simple enabler for two lovebirds. The story of a humble, uneducated, man who conquers the heart of a girl with words borrowed, or stolen, from the great poet. Nothing wrong with that, except that this Master of Words proves at the end to be very flawed, unworthy of the worshiping he's the object of-but more of that later. Decent acting overall, breathtaking scenerythose postcard coastal natural settings are also common in Neruda's Chilebut the writing lets a lot to be desired, with too many schmaltzy scenes & dialogs and assorted clich&eacute; situations. Not surprise then that he plot loses its breath half way, when the lovebirds get married and Pablo returns to Chile. What is left then is the same thing we had at the beginning: the daily routines of a small fishing town in southern Italy. Will that be enough to carry the rest of the movie? Don't think so. This isn't Amacord or IVitelloni, as the whole plot was resting on the relationship Neruda--Mario and so when that comes to an end the movie is left gasping for air, begging for some emotional filling as a replacement. With the poet gone and the romance morphed into routine, all what's left for Mario are unfulfilled family obligations and a constant moping for the absent Master. There is an obvious plot discontinuity when both men separate, perhaps because this script was made sewing up two original stories, set in different places at different times. Sure enough, Neruda was in exile in Italy after having fled Chile in 1949, when the Chilean government started jailing Communists, despite them being part of the governing coalition (!) after being pressured by the Yankees, who had started their own witch hunt. (it's hard to believe, but the reason why communists were hunted down was because Chile's president was afraid of it being considered unfriendly by the U.S and risk losing trade, diplomatic and political benefits). Neruda escaped to Argentina & then to Italy, where he was well received thanks to the work made on Italian public opinion by fellow communist Alberto Moravia. On the other hand, the story of him befriending a postman and writing him poems dedicated to his love interest comes from Antonio Skarmeta's Ardiente Paciencia, set in Chile in the 60s, in the coastal town of Isla Negra, where Neruda had a cottage (which is now a museum). So, this is really a Chilean story transposed to Italy, which may explain the awkward plot situation produced when Neruda leaves. Now, Noiret may be a great actor but he makes a disfavor to Neruda with his work here, at least in 2 instances. First, when he's back in Chile he forgets about Mario and doesn't even answer his mail. The real Neruda would have never done that, because for him friendship and loyalty were two things intrinsically tied to class struggle and political commitment. For him all communists--and all members of the working class-were his brothers whatever may have been their countries of origin or their educational level, and all right wingers and rich people in general his enemies, as for him there was no middle ground at that. In real life he would have never acted like he does with Mario, just because he's a less educated man. At least he would have sent him a postcard. The 2nd thing is you would have never caught him in church, let alone crossing himself, as he was an atheist who had no use for religions or for any organized church and the only people in that realm for whom he ever came to feel any respect at all were the Quakers, just because they helped pay for travel tickets to Chile for thousands of Spaniards fleeing their civil war. It's obvious that both misrepresentations have been committed to keep the plot going, which I can understand, but the record must be set straight anyway. Anyway, IP can be very touching the first time you see it, but it goes losing its emotional punch with time, as there's no much left to get hold of after the thrill of the love story and that of the beautiful words wears off. But worse is the portrayal of Neruda as a snob; an hypocrite who'll be nice to the locals as long as he needs them but who'll forget them as soon as he's gone. I'm all for artistic licenses, but not when they make appear an authentic individual under such an unfavorable and false light. In all, to see maybe a couple of times. Anyway, if you want to see something closer to the real man, watch Skarmeta's Ardiente Paciencia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who Really Wrote the Score?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jacobsencurtis
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Il Postino" is one of my favorite movies. The acting is superb. Massimo Troisi gives a uniquely unforgettable performance, despite his suffering from a fatal illness during filming. Phillipe Noiret, as Pablo Neruda, the Chilean poet-in-exile who befriends Mario (Troisi), gives one of his most memorable performances. The location is enchanting. I love all things Italian. Even a bad movie set in Italy is better for it having been shot there. Some of my favorites are "Enchanted April," "Summertime," and "Roman Holiday." And I love the score, which, until tonight, I assumed was written by Luis Bacalov, who is credited in the movie. But I just watched a movie from 1940 called "Dispatch from Reuters," a bio-pic starring Edward G. Robinson, and darned if the main theme from "Il Postino" isn't straight out of "Dispatch from Reuters." By the way, the music for "Reuters" was composed by the great Max Steiner, who, to my knowledge, received no screen credit in "Il Postino." How is this possible? Has the copyright expired rendering the music part of the public domain?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mundane
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike B
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I found this rather superficial and mundane. It's about the friendship between a worker  a postman - and a poet  Pablo Neruda. The poet awakens the young man's sensibilities and gives him the courage to pursue the village beauty. This is a tiny village - so why he had not realized her beauty before, and more so, why she was not being pursued by an entire flock of young men raised a question mark. The characters are all stereo-typed  the shy postman, the over-wordy poet and the village beauty with her raspy aunt. Everything was a caricature and the film suffered from a lack of passion, intensityI couldn't buy into it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice try, but not quite what I expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only heard of this movie on the TV game show 'Who Wants to be a Millionaire?'. The question was which one of 4 mentioned actors starred in the films 'Nuovo Cinema Paradiso' and 'Il Postino'. I hadn't heard of 'Il Postino' before, but I knew that Philippe Noiret stars in 'Nuovo Cinema Paradiso', so I already knew the answer. The presenter recommended the person who wrongly answered the question to watch these 2 movies because something changes inside us once we get to see these 2 films. Then I did research on this motion-picture. It sounded promising, even more so by being foreign. I also got to know the sad story of Massimo Troisi, who played the title's postman (Pablo Neruda's postman). The man suffered from heart disease since a long time ago. He knew about his fragile heart condition and knew he needed treatment, but despite this he wanted to do the movie anyway. He even postponed heart surgery so that he could complete the film. That was a brave move. And he did manage to finish the movie just in time. Only 12 hours after completing the film he died of heart attack. You can say that he gave his life to make this film. Massimo Troisi is great as Mario Ruoppolo, the postman. But it's also sad to see him in this film because we are looking at a man who was dying while making it and that he died almost immediately after completing it. Phillipe Noiret is great as the chilean poet Pablo Neruda. While Pablo Neruda existed for real, his friendship with the postman didn't. But I don't know if a postman named Mario Ruoppolo existed in real life or not and if he was Pablo Neruda's postman or not. The film's got beautiful cinematography and soundtrack, which gives it more emotion and beauty. The plot is, in concept, good. But the movie itself lacks something (perhaps more emotion is one of those things it lacks) and is even a little too-slow paced. It's not a bad movie. It's interesting, moving, pretty to view... a good attempt, just not quite top material. It just isn't as great as it reputation suggests (with, of course, all due respect in memory of our friend Massimo Troisi).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engrossing character study about two men and their connections to two separate women, as well as the poetry that forms the core of their own friendship.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Radford's tender and rather sweet film, The Postman, is a really quite blinding tale of a man, without either much of a life or very many happenings in and around his existence, going out of his way so as to spawn some. The film is a ground zero character study working its way up, centring on one man and coming to gloriously flesh out his relationships with two people in the form of a mentor and a love interest using the item of poetry, and poets in particular, as a focal point or anchor around which to revolve the ever shifting lives of these half a dozen-or so people. The central character is a certain young man named Mario Ruoppolo, played by Italian actor Massimo Troisi whom died shortly after the film was completed and is one of only seven people to have won a Posthumous Academy Award for acting, which he won for his portrayal of a character named Mario. His life in the early part of the 20th Century on an island off the coast of Italy lies seemingly dormant; a living with his father, whom spends his days at sea fishing for a living, whilst inhabiting a scruffy and run down house on the cliff-side which cannot even produce water from a tap when desired, the situation; with a postcard from some brothers whom have arrived in America offering a brief insight into a supposedly better life. Determined to get on track, the softly spoken; delicate and slow moving Mario shifts off to a local post office so as to apply for the advertised job of delivering letters and mail, locally. On another tangent, that later will become intrinsically linked to that of Mario, a controversial poet from South American nation Chile of true to life existence named Pablo Neruda (Noiret) arrives in Italy having been exiled. His demeanour arrives by way of a newsreel sequence at a picture house, footage which the locals and us watch and listen to simultaneously establishing a set-persona of the man and his controversial, Communist infused existence of writing poetry crash-landing on this small Italian island, much to some of the locals' anger but to the glee of others. The early perceptions of the man are meant to be relatively concrete; he inhabits a beautifully placed but isolated red-washed villa on a separate cliff edge, before plodding Mario comes to form a bond with the poet upon delivering his many letters and from whence the film garners its catalyst so as to play out. The film comes to form a learning process for that of Mario, a deconstruction of an item or art-form that he'd almost certainly heard of in the past but very rarely thought about above a certain level. The same can be said for that of Chilian poet Neruda in regards to the fondness and acceptance the town come to have of him after he and his wife and their bond with a number of people come to forge, a relationship much richer than what he has experienced back home or, you feel, in most other places. Romance appears to want to bloom between Mario and local girl Beatrice (Cucinotta), the daughter of a traditional, hard-up Catholic woman whom owns a tavern within the vicinity; the spying of her playing a game of rather erotically charged flick-rod football in said tavern complete with thrusting of the mannequin players and hammering home of the goals more than enough to have Mario smitten from then on in. But the film is ultimately about the relationship or bond between two men going on around their separate relationships with Beatrice and Pablo's own female partner whom later becomes his wife. It would be untrue to say that the film at all feels less of an accomplishment when certain events transpire and the once central unification of Mario and Pablo is broken up; rather, the ties they have to one another during the film's early scenes are just more interesting, as is the chilling finale involving the two, than any sub-plot to do with either men and what happens between them and their women. Mario's attempts to court a young local girl and the noticeable placing of Pablo's own female partner predominantly off screen and away from the action for most of the time might render the relationship between Mario and Pablo one of a homo-erotic nature. Much later on, a Paris based interview with the poet some years later has Mario read on with keen interest as to whether he or anyone from the town are mentioned; the camera darting around from face to face of those reading with Mario in a kind of panic or nervous excitement or lusting requirement for purifying fulfilment in the form of notifying them, predominantly the notifying of Mario. The convenience in having come to have known a master of poetry of a romantic sort, somebody that feeds off of a belief that all women love romantic poetry and that it is the key to pertaining to a relationship, works very much in Mario's favour. His gradual learning of how to construct it, the encountering of terms and words such as what a metaphor is gradually come to form the nucleus of the first half of the film; a fitting sequence on a nearby beach sees Pablo gradually reveal himself as he readies to swim in a physical sense as Mario comes to reveal a spoken metaphor for the very first time as, on another occasion, he gradually forms an opinion of a short poem Pablo comes up with on the spot. The film's attention to finer things such as these, an including of sequences in which characters must first come to master the basics of an art or activity so as to garner entry onto another plateau so as to put what has been learnt into action, feels wonderfully prominent, resulting in Radford's film being thoroughly worthwhile.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    magnificent masterpiece of Michael with two marvelous metaphors --the poet(Pablo) and the postman(Mario)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    superdirector007
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    what a magnificent movie, legendary work by Michael Redford , everything about this movie is beautiful ,,winning Oscar does not come in easy way ,,be it budget,,cinematography covering island's natural beauty ,,specially sea settings ,humourous dialogs with utmost simplicity and realistic performances by actors ,everything is admirable. sometimes you do not plan to make a great movie with highly perfection attitude but movie becomes and gets applauded ,,same happened with this movie,what i believe what is metaphor Mario asks Pablo says-like sky is weeping what does it mean Mario says means to say sky is raining Mario's response it's complicated and Pablo's response that complication does not have to do anything with person's emotions very meaningful and soulful dialogs ,that is the reason movie does not become boring end of the movie is very surprising ,it keeps you involve in the movie movie was shot on the island near by Meditteranean sea and every time tides go and again come to touch coastal areas that resembles one excellent scene goes with the hope to come with another lovely scene filled with emotional and heart touching dialogs to touch your heart movie is pretty simple but can you predict what's gonna happen in next scene ,probably not ,it has certain surprising elements this movie is not a movie this is everlasting experience to live with and cherish it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    United in Friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although "Il Postino" simply means "The Postman", and although the film was at one time screened as "The Postman" in Britain, it is now generally known in English by its&nbsp;Italian title to avoid confusion with Kevin Costner's post-apocalyptic epic from three years later. It is loosely based upon the novel&nbsp;"Ardiente paciencia"&nbsp;by&nbsp;the Chilean&nbsp;writer Antonio Sk&aacute;rmeta, although it transfers the action from Chile to Italy. It takes as its starting-point the fact that in the early 1950s the famous&nbsp;Chilean&nbsp;poet&nbsp;Pablo Neruda, in exile from his homeland for political reasons, spent some time on the island of Capri. The film, however, is not set on Capri but on an unnamed Italian island. A young fisherman named Mario Ruoppolo applies for a job as the island's postman. As he owns a bicycle and is one of the very few islanders who can read and write he is accepted and is told that he will only have one customer, Neruda himself, as because of the low levels of literacy on the island nobody else ever receives any mail. (Were standards of education really so low in fifties Italy?) Although Mario has never previously heard of Neruda, and certainly has never read any of his poems, a friendship gradually grows up between the two men. Although Mario has had little formal education he is clearly an intelligent and sensitive man, and Neruda reads him some of his poetry (in Italian translation), teaching him about literary concepts such as metaphors. With Neruda's help Mario&nbsp;woos the beautiful Beatrice, a village girl with whom he has&nbsp;fallen in love, stealing some of the older man's love poems and passing them off as his own in order to win her affections. My one criticism of the film would be that it is too sentimental about Communism, but that is perhaps only to be expected of a film from Italy, a country which at one time had the largest Communist Party in Western Europe. (In the seventies they used to win around a third of the popular vote, at a time when the British Communist Party generally consisted of three old men and a dog). Pablo Neruda is here portrayed as a kindly, idealistic gentleman, but in reality, during the forties and early fifties, he was a Communist hardliner who enthusiastically defended Stalin's dictatorship in the Soviet Union. After Khrushchev's 1956 "secret speech" he was to criticise the Stalinist cult of personality but this was due less to a change of heart than to a desire to align himself with the new official Soviet party line. He was also, at the time of his Italian exile, around twenty years younger than the character portrayed here by Philippe Noiret. Its politics aside, however, "Il Postino" is in many ways an excellent film. There is some attractive photography of the Italian coastal scenery and a great musical score by Luis Enr&iacute;quez Bacalov. What really makes the film stand out, however, are the two great performances from Noiret and from Massimo Troisi, who tragically died of a heart attack soon afterwards, as Mario. There is also a good performance from the lovely Maria Grazia Cucinotta as Beatrice. Troisi received a posthumous Oscar nomination for "Best Actor", but lost out to Nicholas Cage in "Leaving Las Vegas"; as I have never seen that film I am unable to comment on the justice of that decision. I felt, however, that it was unfortunate that there was no nomination for Noiret either as "Best Actor" or "Best Supporting Actor". Indeed, this is one of those films which make me feel that it should be possible to nominate two actors for a joint award, as Noiret and Troisi combine together so well that their joint contribution seems greater than the sum of its two parts. This is the story of a touching relationship between two men of different generations, of different nationalities, of different levels of education and of&nbsp;different outlooks on life who are nevertheless united in friendship. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The deliverance of one man of letters by another is a cinematic love letter to poetry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edantheman
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Chilean poet and communist agitator Pablo Neruda may never have set foot on the island of Salina in 1950, but writer-actor Mariamo Troisi's exploration of the idea is probably more interesting than any account of his actual exiles abroad. The eponymous postman of the film, Mario, has never taken to the patrilineal profession of fishing in his family. His widower father understands he never will and releases his seemingly simple son from his duties, to choose an occupation more suited to his abilities. In town, the communist postmaster needs a hand with the flurry of fan mail in the wake of Neruda and his wife's arrival. He greatly admires the Bolivarian bard and has his new postman run reconnaissance and procure signatures from him. Though their early exchanges may be of little significance, the two very different men of letters soon form a bond through a series of exchanges on poetry, love and politics. When Mario first meets barmaid Beatrice Russo over a game of table football, he instantly falls in love. He is inspired by his mentor to write her love poems, many of which he plagiarizes, and soon wins her heart. Michael Radford's surname may seem a little consonant-heavy for a production of this origin but the writer-director's English eye can only be clearly detected in the humour of the pacey, racy table football scene; which a native or continental director may have shot a little more seductively. It is really Troisi who leaves his indelible print on the film, which would be his last (dying tragically the day after production wrapped). The actor's physical frailty comes across as his character's mumbling humility. When beautiful Maria Grazia Cucinotta falls for his charms (or lack thereof), no one would seem more deserving a husband than he, and it is immensely gratifying to see his son Pablito stumble onto screen at the end. Phillipe Noiret also evokes much feeling in the last scene, imagining his friend's great yet fatal agitation for change, while walking their familiar beach. We get the feeling they may have liberated one another. 'Il Postino' is very much a film that flows like poetry. There is no solid structure as prescribed by the script doctors of the time. No stakes and little drama. When our lovable protagonist dies at the end, it is not played for tears of devastation. I felt quiet elation: he had finally found his voice and could speak up for his people at the rally. He asks Neruda earlier in the film a question regarding the writer's revolutionary ideals, "So what if we break off our chains? What do we do then?" He obviously has an answer to that question by the end, which is satisfaction enough. In another exchange, when Mario's plagiarism is discovered by Pablo, he counters "Poetry doesn't belong to those who write it; it belongs to those who need it." This strikes one as quite humorous in the context of the scene but when recalled or read alone it signifies the point at which Mario has cast the chains off his mind. Sadly the distributors do not live by this dictum, and intellectual copyright law prevails online and elsewhere. While it may be a fictional account, the film is very much a celebration of the actual effect Neruda's poetry had on many of the working people of the world. Not so much a tribute to him, but to the millions of postini worldwide who have been delivered and a rallying call for all those who have yet to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Massimo Troisi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    his performance is essence of this adorable film. his character is so careful created that its fragility, humor, innocence, light of details are magnificent. he don't play a role but he is "il postino" . and this fact transforms entire scene. the story of Neruda exile is only arena for emotions of a small man on an Italian isle. the beautiful Beatrice is brick for his delicate happiness. Neruda himself is not exactly a mentor but a gardener. and the music, the extraordinary music, it is the soul of entire poetry. because a poetry is this movie who has as roots poems. very delicate, nice, nostalgic, melancholic, subtle, intelligent, precise, it is wonderful homage to a way to discover life as fundamental miracle. to feel the nuances of love, friendship, to be humble, modest and daring in same time, to feel gratitude as form of respiration. beautiful and impressive. touching. and unique. story of a postman. legacy of Massimo Troisi.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Art and Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gradyharp
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just visited the opera version of this film IL POSTINO by Daniel Catan courtesy of PBS Great Performances it is rewarding to return to the original source to honor the nidus for the inspiration for the opera. Directed by Michael Radford the film relates the heartwarming story of Mario (Massimo Troisi), a gentle and simple postman who falls for the beautiful caf&eacute; waitress Beatrice (Maria Grazia Cucinotta) from his village, but is too shy to speak to her. He meets the famous Chilean poet Pablo Neruda (Phillipe Noiret), and, as their friendship develops, the postman's own inner poet awakens. Soon he is able to win the love of Beatrice and even stand up for and express his own beliefs. This is a simple story graced by sensitive performances: of not the actor Massimo Trosi died from heart failure on the last day of production of the film. It is possibly this knowledge of the loss of one of Italy's best comedic actors along with the clarity and transparency of the film's gentle message about love and art that has made it a cult film. At any rate this is a film that belongs in every movie lover's library. Grady Harp
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great cinematography, good acting by Trosi, but Neruda comes out the loser here.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    felixoteiza
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is actually an Italian fairy tale, one where Neruda is little more than a simple enabler for two lovebirds. The story of a humble, uneducated, man who conquers the heart of a girl with words borrowed, or stolen, from the great poet. Nothing wrong with that, except that this Master of Words proves at the end to be very flawed, unworthy of the worshiping he's the object of-but more of that later. Decent acting overall, breathtaking scenerythose postcard coastal natural settings are also common in Neruda's Chilebut the writing lets a lot to be desired, with too many schmaltzy scenes & dialogs and assorted clich&eacute; situations. Not surprise then that he plot loses its breath half way, when the lovebirds get married and Pablo returns to Chile. What is left then is the same thing we had at the beginning: the daily routines of a small fishing town in southern Italy. Will that be enough to carry the rest of the movie? Don't think so. This isn't Amacord or IVitelloni, as the whole plot was resting on the relationship Neruda--Mario and so when that comes to an end the movie is left gasping for air, begging for some emotional filling as a replacement. With the poet gone and the romance morphed into routine, all what's left for Mario are unfulfilled family obligations and a constant moping for the absent Master. There is an obvious plot discontinuity when both men separate, perhaps because this script was made sewing up two original stories, set in different places at different times. Sure enough, Neruda was in exile in Italy after having fled Chile in 1949, when the Chilean government started jailing Communists, despite them being part of the governing coalition (!) after being pressured by the Yankees, who had started their own witch hunt. (it's hard to believe, but the reason why communists were hunted down was because Chile's president was afraid of it being considered unfriendly by the U.S and risk losing trade, diplomatic and political benefits). Neruda escaped to Argentina & then to Italy, where he was well received thanks to the work made on Italian public opinion by fellow communist Alberto Moravia. On the other hand, the story of him befriending a postman and writing him poems dedicated to his love interest comes from Antonio Skarmeta's Ardiente Paciencia, set in Chile in the 60s, in the coastal town of Isla Negra, where Neruda had a cottage (which is now a museum). So, this is really a Chilean story transposed to Italy, which may explain the awkward plot situation produced when Neruda leaves. Now, Noiret may be a great actor but he makes a disfavor to Neruda with his work here, at least in 2 instances. First, when he's back in Chile he forgets about Mario and doesn't even answer his mail. The real Neruda would have never done that, because for him friendship and loyalty were two things intrinsically tied to class struggle and political commitment. For him all communists--and all members of the working class-were his brothers whatever may have been their countries of origin or their educational level, and all right wingers and rich people in general his enemies, as for him there was no middle ground at that. In real life he would have never acted like he does with Mario, just because he's a less educated man. At least he would have sent him a postcard. The 2nd thing is you would have never caught him in church, let alone crossing himself, as he was an atheist who had no use for religions or for any organized church and the only people in that realm for whom he ever came to feel any respect at all were the Quakers, just because they helped pay for travel tickets to Chile for thousands of Spaniards fleeing their civil war. It's obvious that both misrepresentations have been committed to keep the plot going, which I can understand, but the record must be set straight anyway. Anyway, IP can be very touching the first time you see it, but it goes losing its emotional punch with time, as there's no much left to get hold of after the thrill of the love story and that of the beautiful words wears off. But worse is the portrayal of Neruda as a snob; an hypocrite who'll be nice to the locals as long as he needs them but who'll forget them as soon as he's gone. I'm all for artistic licenses, but not when they make appear an authentic individual under such an unfavorable and false light. In all, to see maybe a couple of times. Anyway, if you want to see something closer to the real man, watch Skarmeta's Ardiente Paciencia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who Really Wrote the Score?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jacobsencurtis
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Il Postino" is one of my favorite movies. The acting is superb. Massimo Troisi gives a uniquely unforgettable performance, despite his suffering from a fatal illness during filming. Phillipe Noiret, as Pablo Neruda, the Chilean poet-in-exile who befriends Mario (Troisi), gives one of his most memorable performances. The location is enchanting. I love all things Italian. Even a bad movie set in Italy is better for it having been shot there. Some of my favorites are "Enchanted April," "Summertime," and "Roman Holiday." And I love the score, which, until tonight, I assumed was written by Luis Bacalov, who is credited in the movie. But I just watched a movie from 1940 called "Dispatch from Reuters," a bio-pic starring Edward G. Robinson, and darned if the main theme from "Il Postino" isn't straight out of "Dispatch from Reuters." By the way, the music for "Reuters" was composed by the great Max Steiner, who, to my knowledge, received no screen credit in "Il Postino." How is this possible? Has the copyright expired rendering the music part of the public domain?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mundane
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike B
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I found this rather superficial and mundane. It's about the friendship between a worker  a postman - and a poet  Pablo Neruda. The poet awakens the young man's sensibilities and gives him the courage to pursue the village beauty. This is a tiny village - so why he had not realized her beauty before, and more so, why she was not being pursued by an entire flock of young men raised a question mark. The characters are all stereo-typed  the shy postman, the over-wordy poet and the village beauty with her raspy aunt. Everything was a caricature and the film suffered from a lack of passion, intensityI couldn't buy into it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice try, but not quite what I expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only heard of this movie on the TV game show 'Who Wants to be a Millionaire?'. The question was which one of 4 mentioned actors starred in the films 'Nuovo Cinema Paradiso' and 'Il Postino'. I hadn't heard of 'Il Postino' before, but I knew that Philippe Noiret stars in 'Nuovo Cinema Paradiso', so I already knew the answer. The presenter recommended the person who wrongly answered the question to watch these 2 movies because something changes inside us once we get to see these 2 films. Then I did research on this motion-picture. It sounded promising, even more so by being foreign. I also got to know the sad story of Massimo Troisi, who played the title's postman (Pablo Neruda's postman). The man suffered from heart disease since a long time ago. He knew about his fragile heart condition and knew he needed treatment, but despite this he wanted to do the movie anyway. He even postponed heart surgery so that he could complete the film. That was a brave move. And he did manage to finish the movie just in time. Only 12 hours after completing the film he died of heart attack. You can say that he gave his life to make this film. Massimo Troisi is great as Mario Ruoppolo, the postman. But it's also sad to see him in this film because we are looking at a man who was dying while making it and that he died almost immediately after completing it. Phillipe Noiret is great as the chilean poet Pablo Neruda. While Pablo Neruda existed for real, his friendship with the postman didn't. But I don't know if a postman named Mario Ruoppolo existed in real life or not and if he was Pablo Neruda's postman or not. The film's got beautiful cinematography and soundtrack, which gives it more emotion and beauty. The plot is, in concept, good. But the movie itself lacks something (perhaps more emotion is one of those things it lacks) and is even a little too-slow paced. It's not a bad movie. It's interesting, moving, pretty to view... a good attempt, just not quite top material. It just isn't as great as it reputation suggests (with, of course, all due respect in memory of our friend Massimo Troisi).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engrossing character study about two men and their connections to two separate women, as well as the poetry that forms the core of their own friendship.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Radford's tender and rather sweet film, The Postman, is a really quite blinding tale of a man, without either much of a life or very many happenings in and around his existence, going out of his way so as to spawn some. The film is a ground zero character study working its way up, centring on one man and coming to gloriously flesh out his relationships with two people in the form of a mentor and a love interest using the item of poetry, and poets in particular, as a focal point or anchor around which to revolve the ever shifting lives of these half a dozen-or so people. The central character is a certain young man named Mario Ruoppolo, played by Italian actor Massimo Troisi whom died shortly after the film was completed and is one of only seven people to have won a Posthumous Academy Award for acting, which he won for his portrayal of a character named Mario. His life in the early part of the 20th Century on an island off the coast of Italy lies seemingly dormant; a living with his father, whom spends his days at sea fishing for a living, whilst inhabiting a scruffy and run down house on the cliff-side which cannot even produce water from a tap when desired, the situation; with a postcard from some brothers whom have arrived in America offering a brief insight into a supposedly better life. Determined to get on track, the softly spoken; delicate and slow moving Mario shifts off to a local post office so as to apply for the advertised job of delivering letters and mail, locally. On another tangent, that later will become intrinsically linked to that of Mario, a controversial poet from South American nation Chile of true to life existence named Pablo Neruda (Noiret) arrives in Italy having been exiled. His demeanour arrives by way of a newsreel sequence at a picture house, footage which the locals and us watch and listen to simultaneously establishing a set-persona of the man and his controversial, Communist infused existence of writing poetry crash-landing on this small Italian island, much to some of the locals' anger but to the glee of others. The early perceptions of the man are meant to be relatively concrete; he inhabits a beautifully placed but isolated red-washed villa on a separate cliff edge, before plodding Mario comes to form a bond with the poet upon delivering his many letters and from whence the film garners its catalyst so as to play out. The film comes to form a learning process for that of Mario, a deconstruction of an item or art-form that he'd almost certainly heard of in the past but very rarely thought about above a certain level. The same can be said for that of Chilian poet Neruda in regards to the fondness and acceptance the town come to have of him after he and his wife and their bond with a number of people come to forge, a relationship much richer than what he has experienced back home or, you feel, in most other places. Romance appears to want to bloom between Mario and local girl Beatrice (Cucinotta), the daughter of a traditional, hard-up Catholic woman whom owns a tavern within the vicinity; the spying of her playing a game of rather erotically charged flick-rod football in said tavern complete with thrusting of the mannequin players and hammering home of the goals more than enough to have Mario smitten from then on in. But the film is ultimately about the relationship or bond between two men going on around their separate relationships with Beatrice and Pablo's own female partner whom later becomes his wife. It would be untrue to say that the film at all feels less of an accomplishment when certain events transpire and the once central unification of Mario and Pablo is broken up; rather, the ties they have to one another during the film's early scenes are just more interesting, as is the chilling finale involving the two, than any sub-plot to do with either men and what happens between them and their women. Mario's attempts to court a young local girl and the noticeable placing of Pablo's own female partner predominantly off screen and away from the action for most of the time might render the relationship between Mario and Pablo one of a homo-erotic nature. Much later on, a Paris based interview with the poet some years later has Mario read on with keen interest as to whether he or anyone from the town are mentioned; the camera darting around from face to face of those reading with Mario in a kind of panic or nervous excitement or lusting requirement for purifying fulfilment in the form of notifying them, predominantly the notifying of Mario. The convenience in having come to have known a master of poetry of a romantic sort, somebody that feeds off of a belief that all women love romantic poetry and that it is the key to pertaining to a relationship, works very much in Mario's favour. His gradual learning of how to construct it, the encountering of terms and words such as what a metaphor is gradually come to form the nucleus of the first half of the film; a fitting sequence on a nearby beach sees Pablo gradually reveal himself as he readies to swim in a physical sense as Mario comes to reveal a spoken metaphor for the very first time as, on another occasion, he gradually forms an opinion of a short poem Pablo comes up with on the spot. The film's attention to finer things such as these, an including of sequences in which characters must first come to master the basics of an art or activity so as to garner entry onto another plateau so as to put what has been learnt into action, feels wonderfully prominent, resulting in Radford's film being thoroughly worthwhile.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    magnificent masterpiece of Michael with two marvelous metaphors --the poet(Pablo) and the postman(Mario)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    superdirector007
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    what a magnificent movie, legendary work by Michael Redford , everything about this movie is beautiful ,,winning Oscar does not come in easy way ,,be it budget,,cinematography covering island's natural beauty ,,specially sea settings ,humourous dialogs with utmost simplicity and realistic performances by actors ,everything is admirable. sometimes you do not plan to make a great movie with highly perfection attitude but movie becomes and gets applauded ,,same happened with this movie,what i believe what is metaphor Mario asks Pablo says-like sky is weeping what does it mean Mario says means to say sky is raining Mario's response it's complicated and Pablo's response that complication does not have to do anything with person's emotions very meaningful and soulful dialogs ,that is the reason movie does not become boring end of the movie is very surprising ,it keeps you involve in the movie movie was shot on the island near by Meditteranean sea and every time tides go and again come to touch coastal areas that resembles one excellent scene goes with the hope to come with another lovely scene filled with emotional and heart touching dialogs to touch your heart movie is pretty simple but can you predict what's gonna happen in next scene ,probably not ,it has certain surprising elements this movie is not a movie this is everlasting experience to live with and cherish it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    United in Friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although "Il Postino" simply means "The Postman", and although the film was at one time screened as "The Postman" in Britain, it is now generally known in English by its&nbsp;Italian title to avoid confusion with Kevin Costner's post-apocalyptic epic from three years later. It is loosely based upon the novel&nbsp;"Ardiente paciencia"&nbsp;by&nbsp;the Chilean&nbsp;writer Antonio Sk&aacute;rmeta, although it transfers the action from Chile to Italy. It takes as its starting-point the fact that in the early 1950s the famous&nbsp;Chilean&nbsp;poet&nbsp;Pablo Neruda, in exile from his homeland for political reasons, spent some time on the island of Capri. The film, however, is not set on Capri but on an unnamed Italian island. A young fisherman named Mario Ruoppolo applies for a job as the island's postman. As he owns a bicycle and is one of the very few islanders who can read and write he is accepted and is told that he will only have one customer, Neruda himself, as because of the low levels of literacy on the island nobody else ever receives any mail. (Were standards of education really so low in fifties Italy?) Although Mario has never previously heard of Neruda, and certainly has never read any of his poems, a friendship gradually grows up between the two men. Although Mario has had little formal education he is clearly an intelligent and sensitive man, and Neruda reads him some of his poetry (in Italian translation), teaching him about literary concepts such as metaphors. With Neruda's help Mario&nbsp;woos the beautiful Beatrice, a village girl with whom he has&nbsp;fallen in love, stealing some of the older man's love poems and passing them off as his own in order to win her affections. My one criticism of the film would be that it is too sentimental about Communism, but that is perhaps only to be expected of a film from Italy, a country which at one time had the largest Communist Party in Western Europe. (In the seventies they used to win around a third of the popular vote, at a time when the British Communist Party generally consisted of three old men and a dog). Pablo Neruda is here portrayed as a kindly, idealistic gentleman, but in reality, during the forties and early fifties, he was a Communist hardliner who enthusiastically defended Stalin's dictatorship in the Soviet Union. After Khrushchev's 1956 "secret speech" he was to criticise the Stalinist cult of personality but this was due less to a change of heart than to a desire to align himself with the new official Soviet party line. He was also, at the time of his Italian exile, around twenty years younger than the character portrayed here by Philippe Noiret. Its politics aside, however, "Il Postino" is in many ways an excellent film. There is some attractive photography of the Italian coastal scenery and a great musical score by Luis Enr&iacute;quez Bacalov. What really makes the film stand out, however, are the two great performances from Noiret and from Massimo Troisi, who tragically died of a heart attack soon afterwards, as Mario. There is also a good performance from the lovely Maria Grazia Cucinotta as Beatrice. Troisi received a posthumous Oscar nomination for "Best Actor", but lost out to Nicholas Cage in "Leaving Las Vegas"; as I have never seen that film I am unable to comment on the justice of that decision. I felt, however, that it was unfortunate that there was no nomination for Noiret either as "Best Actor" or "Best Supporting Actor". Indeed, this is one of those films which make me feel that it should be possible to nominate two actors for a joint award, as Noiret and Troisi combine together so well that their joint contribution seems greater than the sum of its two parts. This is the story of a touching relationship between two men of different generations, of different nationalities, of different levels of education and of&nbsp;different outlooks on life who are nevertheless united in friendship. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The deliverance of one man of letters by another is a cinematic love letter to poetry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edantheman
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Chilean poet and communist agitator Pablo Neruda may never have set foot on the island of Salina in 1950, but writer-actor Mariamo Troisi's exploration of the idea is probably more interesting than any account of his actual exiles abroad. The eponymous postman of the film, Mario, has never taken to the patrilineal profession of fishing in his family. His widower father understands he never will and releases his seemingly simple son from his duties, to choose an occupation more suited to his abilities. In town, the communist postmaster needs a hand with the flurry of fan mail in the wake of Neruda and his wife's arrival. He greatly admires the Bolivarian bard and has his new postman run reconnaissance and procure signatures from him. Though their early exchanges may be of little significance, the two very different men of letters soon form a bond through a series of exchanges on poetry, love and politics. When Mario first meets barmaid Beatrice Russo over a game of table football, he instantly falls in love. He is inspired by his mentor to write her love poems, many of which he plagiarizes, and soon wins her heart. Michael Radford's surname may seem a little consonant-heavy for a production of this origin but the writer-director's English eye can only be clearly detected in the humour of the pacey, racy table football scene; which a native or continental director may have shot a little more seductively. It is really Troisi who leaves his indelible print on the film, which would be his last (dying tragically the day after production wrapped). The actor's physical frailty comes across as his character's mumbling humility. When beautiful Maria Grazia Cucinotta falls for his charms (or lack thereof), no one would seem more deserving a husband than he, and it is immensely gratifying to see his son Pablito stumble onto screen at the end. Phillipe Noiret also evokes much feeling in the last scene, imagining his friend's great yet fatal agitation for change, while walking their familiar beach. We get the feeling they may have liberated one another. 'Il Postino' is very much a film that flows like poetry. There is no solid structure as prescribed by the script doctors of the time. No stakes and little drama. When our lovable protagonist dies at the end, it is not played for tears of devastation. I felt quiet elation: he had finally found his voice and could speak up for his people at the rally. He asks Neruda earlier in the film a question regarding the writer's revolutionary ideals, "So what if we break off our chains? What do we do then?" He obviously has an answer to that question by the end, which is satisfaction enough. In another exchange, when Mario's plagiarism is discovered by Pablo, he counters "Poetry doesn't belong to those who write it; it belongs to those who need it." This strikes one as quite humorous in the context of the scene but when recalled or read alone it signifies the point at which Mario has cast the chains off his mind. Sadly the distributors do not live by this dictum, and intellectual copyright law prevails online and elsewhere. While it may be a fictional account, the film is very much a celebration of the actual effect Neruda's poetry had on many of the working people of the world. Not so much a tribute to him, but to the millions of postini worldwide who have been delivered and a rallying call for all those who have yet to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Massimo Troisi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    his performance is essence of this adorable film. his character is so careful created that its fragility, humor, innocence, light of details are magnificent. he don't play a role but he is "il postino" . and this fact transforms entire scene. the story of Neruda exile is only arena for emotions of a small man on an Italian isle. the beautiful Beatrice is brick for his delicate happiness. Neruda himself is not exactly a mentor but a gardener. and the music, the extraordinary music, it is the soul of entire poetry. because a poetry is this movie who has as roots poems. very delicate, nice, nostalgic, melancholic, subtle, intelligent, precise, it is wonderful homage to a way to discover life as fundamental miracle. to feel the nuances of love, friendship, to be humble, modest and daring in same time, to feel gratitude as form of respiration. beautiful and impressive. touching. and unique. story of a postman. legacy of Massimo Troisi.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Art and Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gradyharp
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just visited the opera version of this film IL POSTINO by Daniel Catan courtesy of PBS Great Performances it is rewarding to return to the original source to honor the nidus for the inspiration for the opera. Directed by Michael Radford the film relates the heartwarming story of Mario (Massimo Troisi), a gentle and simple postman who falls for the beautiful caf&eacute; waitress Beatrice (Maria Grazia Cucinotta) from his village, but is too shy to speak to her. He meets the famous Chilean poet Pablo Neruda (Phillipe Noiret), and, as their friendship develops, the postman's own inner poet awakens. Soon he is able to win the love of Beatrice and even stand up for and express his own beliefs. This is a simple story graced by sensitive performances: of not the actor Massimo Trosi died from heart failure on the last day of production of the film. It is possibly this knowledge of the loss of one of Italy's best comedic actors along with the clarity and transparency of the film's gentle message about love and art that has made it a cult film. At any rate this is a film that belongs in every movie lover's library. Grady Harp
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great cinematography, good acting by Trosi, but Neruda comes out the loser here.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    felixoteiza
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is actually an Italian fairy tale, one where Neruda is little more than a simple enabler for two lovebirds. The story of a humble, uneducated, man who conquers the heart of a girl with words borrowed, or stolen, from the great poet. Nothing wrong with that, except that this Master of Words proves at the end to be very flawed, unworthy of the worshiping he's the object of-but more of that later. Decent acting overall, breathtaking scenerythose postcard coastal natural settings are also common in Neruda's Chilebut the writing lets a lot to be desired, with too many schmaltzy scenes & dialogs and assorted clich&eacute; situations. Not surprise then that he plot loses its breath half way, when the lovebirds get married and Pablo returns to Chile. What is left then is the same thing we had at the beginning: the daily routines of a small fishing town in southern Italy. Will that be enough to carry the rest of the movie? Don't think so. This isn't Amacord or IVitelloni, as the whole plot was resting on the relationship Neruda--Mario and so when that comes to an end the movie is left gasping for air, begging for some emotional filling as a replacement. With the poet gone and the romance morphed into routine, all what's left for Mario are unfulfilled family obligations and a constant moping for the absent Master. There is an obvious plot discontinuity when both men separate, perhaps because this script was made sewing up two original stories, set in different places at different times. Sure enough, Neruda was in exile in Italy after having fled Chile in 1949, when the Chilean government started jailing Communists, despite them being part of the governing coalition (!) after being pressured by the Yankees, who had started their own witch hunt. (it's hard to believe, but the reason why communists were hunted down was because Chile's president was afraid of it being considered unfriendly by the U.S and risk losing trade, diplomatic and political benefits). Neruda escaped to Argentina & then to Italy, where he was well received thanks to the work made on Italian public opinion by fellow communist Alberto Moravia. On the other hand, the story of him befriending a postman and writing him poems dedicated to his love interest comes from Antonio Skarmeta's Ardiente Paciencia, set in Chile in the 60s, in the coastal town of Isla Negra, where Neruda had a cottage (which is now a museum). So, this is really a Chilean story transposed to Italy, which may explain the awkward plot situation produced when Neruda leaves. Now, Noiret may be a great actor but he makes a disfavor to Neruda with his work here, at least in 2 instances. First, when he's back in Chile he forgets about Mario and doesn't even answer his mail. The real Neruda would have never done that, because for him friendship and loyalty were two things intrinsically tied to class struggle and political commitment. For him all communists--and all members of the working class-were his brothers whatever may have been their countries of origin or their educational level, and all right wingers and rich people in general his enemies, as for him there was no middle ground at that. In real life he would have never acted like he does with Mario, just because he's a less educated man. At least he would have sent him a postcard. The 2nd thing is you would have never caught him in church, let alone crossing himself, as he was an atheist who had no use for religions or for any organized church and the only people in that realm for whom he ever came to feel any respect at all were the Quakers, just because they helped pay for travel tickets to Chile for thousands of Spaniards fleeing their civil war. It's obvious that both misrepresentations have been committed to keep the plot going, which I can understand, but the record must be set straight anyway. Anyway, IP can be very touching the first time you see it, but it goes losing its emotional punch with time, as there's no much left to get hold of after the thrill of the love story and that of the beautiful words wears off. But worse is the portrayal of Neruda as a snob; an hypocrite who'll be nice to the locals as long as he needs them but who'll forget them as soon as he's gone. I'm all for artistic licenses, but not when they make appear an authentic individual under such an unfavorable and false light. In all, to see maybe a couple of times. Anyway, if you want to see something closer to the real man, watch Skarmeta's Ardiente Paciencia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who Really Wrote the Score?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jacobsencurtis
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Il Postino" is one of my favorite movies. The acting is superb. Massimo Troisi gives a uniquely unforgettable performance, despite his suffering from a fatal illness during filming. Phillipe Noiret, as Pablo Neruda, the Chilean poet-in-exile who befriends Mario (Troisi), gives one of his most memorable performances. The location is enchanting. I love all things Italian. Even a bad movie set in Italy is better for it having been shot there. Some of my favorites are "Enchanted April," "Summertime," and "Roman Holiday." And I love the score, which, until tonight, I assumed was written by Luis Bacalov, who is credited in the movie. But I just watched a movie from 1940 called "Dispatch from Reuters," a bio-pic starring Edward G. Robinson, and darned if the main theme from "Il Postino" isn't straight out of "Dispatch from Reuters." By the way, the music for "Reuters" was composed by the great Max Steiner, who, to my knowledge, received no screen credit in "Il Postino." How is this possible? Has the copyright expired rendering the music part of the public domain?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mundane
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike B
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I found this rather superficial and mundane. It's about the friendship between a worker  a postman - and a poet  Pablo Neruda. The poet awakens the young man's sensibilities and gives him the courage to pursue the village beauty. This is a tiny village - so why he had not realized her beauty before, and more so, why she was not being pursued by an entire flock of young men raised a question mark. The characters are all stereo-typed  the shy postman, the over-wordy poet and the village beauty with her raspy aunt. Everything was a caricature and the film suffered from a lack of passion, intensityI couldn't buy into it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice try, but not quite what I expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only heard of this movie on the TV game show 'Who Wants to be a Millionaire?'. The question was which one of 4 mentioned actors starred in the films 'Nuovo Cinema Paradiso' and 'Il Postino'. I hadn't heard of 'Il Postino' before, but I knew that Philippe Noiret stars in 'Nuovo Cinema Paradiso', so I already knew the answer. The presenter recommended the person who wrongly answered the question to watch these 2 movies because something changes inside us once we get to see these 2 films. Then I did research on this motion-picture. It sounded promising, even more so by being foreign. I also got to know the sad story of Massimo Troisi, who played the title's postman (Pablo Neruda's postman). The man suffered from heart disease since a long time ago. He knew about his fragile heart condition and knew he needed treatment, but despite this he wanted to do the movie anyway. He even postponed heart surgery so that he could complete the film. That was a brave move. And he did manage to finish the movie just in time. Only 12 hours after completing the film he died of heart attack. You can say that he gave his life to make this film. Massimo Troisi is great as Mario Ruoppolo, the postman. But it's also sad to see him in this film because we are looking at a man who was dying while making it and that he died almost immediately after completing it. Phillipe Noiret is great as the chilean poet Pablo Neruda. While Pablo Neruda existed for real, his friendship with the postman didn't. But I don't know if a postman named Mario Ruoppolo existed in real life or not and if he was Pablo Neruda's postman or not. The film's got beautiful cinematography and soundtrack, which gives it more emotion and beauty. The plot is, in concept, good. But the movie itself lacks something (perhaps more emotion is one of those things it lacks) and is even a little too-slow paced. It's not a bad movie. It's interesting, moving, pretty to view... a good attempt, just not quite top material. It just isn't as great as it reputation suggests (with, of course, all due respect in memory of our friend Massimo Troisi).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engrossing character study about two men and their connections to two separate women, as well as the poetry that forms the core of their own friendship.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Radford's tender and rather sweet film, The Postman, is a really quite blinding tale of a man, without either much of a life or very many happenings in and around his existence, going out of his way so as to spawn some. The film is a ground zero character study working its way up, centring on one man and coming to gloriously flesh out his relationships with two people in the form of a mentor and a love interest using the item of poetry, and poets in particular, as a focal point or anchor around which to revolve the ever shifting lives of these half a dozen-or so people. The central character is a certain young man named Mario Ruoppolo, played by Italian actor Massimo Troisi whom died shortly after the film was completed and is one of only seven people to have won a Posthumous Academy Award for acting, which he won for his portrayal of a character named Mario. His life in the early part of the 20th Century on an island off the coast of Italy lies seemingly dormant; a living with his father, whom spends his days at sea fishing for a living, whilst inhabiting a scruffy and run down house on the cliff-side which cannot even produce water from a tap when desired, the situation; with a postcard from some brothers whom have arrived in America offering a brief insight into a supposedly better life. Determined to get on track, the softly spoken; delicate and slow moving Mario shifts off to a local post office so as to apply for the advertised job of delivering letters and mail, locally. On another tangent, that later will become intrinsically linked to that of Mario, a controversial poet from South American nation Chile of true to life existence named Pablo Neruda (Noiret) arrives in Italy having been exiled. His demeanour arrives by way of a newsreel sequence at a picture house, footage which the locals and us watch and listen to simultaneously establishing a set-persona of the man and his controversial, Communist infused existence of writing poetry crash-landing on this small Italian island, much to some of the locals' anger but to the glee of others. The early perceptions of the man are meant to be relatively concrete; he inhabits a beautifully placed but isolated red-washed villa on a separate cliff edge, before plodding Mario comes to form a bond with the poet upon delivering his many letters and from whence the film garners its catalyst so as to play out. The film comes to form a learning process for that of Mario, a deconstruction of an item or art-form that he'd almost certainly heard of in the past but very rarely thought about above a certain level. The same can be said for that of Chilian poet Neruda in regards to the fondness and acceptance the town come to have of him after he and his wife and their bond with a number of people come to forge, a relationship much richer than what he has experienced back home or, you feel, in most other places. Romance appears to want to bloom between Mario and local girl Beatrice (Cucinotta), the daughter of a traditional, hard-up Catholic woman whom owns a tavern within the vicinity; the spying of her playing a game of rather erotically charged flick-rod football in said tavern complete with thrusting of the mannequin players and hammering home of the goals more than enough to have Mario smitten from then on in. But the film is ultimately about the relationship or bond between two men going on around their separate relationships with Beatrice and Pablo's own female partner whom later becomes his wife. It would be untrue to say that the film at all feels less of an accomplishment when certain events transpire and the once central unification of Mario and Pablo is broken up; rather, the ties they have to one another during the film's early scenes are just more interesting, as is the chilling finale involving the two, than any sub-plot to do with either men and what happens between them and their women. Mario's attempts to court a young local girl and the noticeable placing of Pablo's own female partner predominantly off screen and away from the action for most of the time might render the relationship between Mario and Pablo one of a homo-erotic nature. Much later on, a Paris based interview with the poet some years later has Mario read on with keen interest as to whether he or anyone from the town are mentioned; the camera darting around from face to face of those reading with Mario in a kind of panic or nervous excitement or lusting requirement for purifying fulfilment in the form of notifying them, predominantly the notifying of Mario. The convenience in having come to have known a master of poetry of a romantic sort, somebody that feeds off of a belief that all women love romantic poetry and that it is the key to pertaining to a relationship, works very much in Mario's favour. His gradual learning of how to construct it, the encountering of terms and words such as what a metaphor is gradually come to form the nucleus of the first half of the film; a fitting sequence on a nearby beach sees Pablo gradually reveal himself as he readies to swim in a physical sense as Mario comes to reveal a spoken metaphor for the very first time as, on another occasion, he gradually forms an opinion of a short poem Pablo comes up with on the spot. The film's attention to finer things such as these, an including of sequences in which characters must first come to master the basics of an art or activity so as to garner entry onto another plateau so as to put what has been learnt into action, feels wonderfully prominent, resulting in Radford's film being thoroughly worthwhile.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    magnificent masterpiece of Michael with two marvelous metaphors --the poet(Pablo) and the postman(Mario)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    superdirector007
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    what a magnificent movie, legendary work by Michael Redford , everything about this movie is beautiful ,,winning Oscar does not come in easy way ,,be it budget,,cinematography covering island's natural beauty ,,specially sea settings ,humourous dialogs with utmost simplicity and realistic performances by actors ,everything is admirable. sometimes you do not plan to make a great movie with highly perfection attitude but movie becomes and gets applauded ,,same happened with this movie,what i believe what is metaphor Mario asks Pablo says-like sky is weeping what does it mean Mario says means to say sky is raining Mario's response it's complicated and Pablo's response that complication does not have to do anything with person's emotions very meaningful and soulful dialogs ,that is the reason movie does not become boring end of the movie is very surprising ,it keeps you involve in the movie movie was shot on the island near by Meditteranean sea and every time tides go and again come to touch coastal areas that resembles one excellent scene goes with the hope to come with another lovely scene filled with emotional and heart touching dialogs to touch your heart movie is pretty simple but can you predict what's gonna happen in next scene ,probably not ,it has certain surprising elements this movie is not a movie this is everlasting experience to live with and cherish it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    United in Friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although "Il Postino" simply means "The Postman", and although the film was at one time screened as "The Postman" in Britain, it is now generally known in English by its&nbsp;Italian title to avoid confusion with Kevin Costner's post-apocalyptic epic from three years later. It is loosely based upon the novel&nbsp;"Ardiente paciencia"&nbsp;by&nbsp;the Chilean&nbsp;writer Antonio Sk&aacute;rmeta, although it transfers the action from Chile to Italy. It takes as its starting-point the fact that in the early 1950s the famous&nbsp;Chilean&nbsp;poet&nbsp;Pablo Neruda, in exile from his homeland for political reasons, spent some time on the island of Capri. The film, however, is not set on Capri but on an unnamed Italian island. A young fisherman named Mario Ruoppolo applies for a job as the island's postman. As he owns a bicycle and is one of the very few islanders who can read and write he is accepted and is told that he will only have one customer, Neruda himself, as because of the low levels of literacy on the island nobody else ever receives any mail. (Were standards of education really so low in fifties Italy?) Although Mario has never previously heard of Neruda, and certainly has never read any of his poems, a friendship gradually grows up between the two men. Although Mario has had little formal education he is clearly an intelligent and sensitive man, and Neruda reads him some of his poetry (in Italian translation), teaching him about literary concepts such as metaphors. With Neruda's help Mario&nbsp;woos the beautiful Beatrice, a village girl with whom he has&nbsp;fallen in love, stealing some of the older man's love poems and passing them off as his own in order to win her affections. My one criticism of the film would be that it is too sentimental about Communism, but that is perhaps only to be expected of a film from Italy, a country which at one time had the largest Communist Party in Western Europe. (In the seventies they used to win around a third of the popular vote, at a time when the British Communist Party generally consisted of three old men and a dog). Pablo Neruda is here portrayed as a kindly, idealistic gentleman, but in reality, during the forties and early fifties, he was a Communist hardliner who enthusiastically defended Stalin's dictatorship in the Soviet Union. After Khrushchev's 1956 "secret speech" he was to criticise the Stalinist cult of personality but this was due less to a change of heart than to a desire to align himself with the new official Soviet party line. He was also, at the time of his Italian exile, around twenty years younger than the character portrayed here by Philippe Noiret. Its politics aside, however, "Il Postino" is in many ways an excellent film. There is some attractive photography of the Italian coastal scenery and a great musical score by Luis Enr&iacute;quez Bacalov. What really makes the film stand out, however, are the two great performances from Noiret and from Massimo Troisi, who tragically died of a heart attack soon afterwards, as Mario. There is also a good performance from the lovely Maria Grazia Cucinotta as Beatrice. Troisi received a posthumous Oscar nomination for "Best Actor", but lost out to Nicholas Cage in "Leaving Las Vegas"; as I have never seen that film I am unable to comment on the justice of that decision. I felt, however, that it was unfortunate that there was no nomination for Noiret either as "Best Actor" or "Best Supporting Actor". Indeed, this is one of those films which make me feel that it should be possible to nominate two actors for a joint award, as Noiret and Troisi combine together so well that their joint contribution seems greater than the sum of its two parts. This is the story of a touching relationship between two men of different generations, of different nationalities, of different levels of education and of&nbsp;different outlooks on life who are nevertheless united in friendship. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The deliverance of one man of letters by another is a cinematic love letter to poetry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edantheman
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Chilean poet and communist agitator Pablo Neruda may never have set foot on the island of Salina in 1950, but writer-actor Mariamo Troisi's exploration of the idea is probably more interesting than any account of his actual exiles abroad. The eponymous postman of the film, Mario, has never taken to the patrilineal profession of fishing in his family. His widower father understands he never will and releases his seemingly simple son from his duties, to choose an occupation more suited to his abilities. In town, the communist postmaster needs a hand with the flurry of fan mail in the wake of Neruda and his wife's arrival. He greatly admires the Bolivarian bard and has his new postman run reconnaissance and procure signatures from him. Though their early exchanges may be of little significance, the two very different men of letters soon form a bond through a series of exchanges on poetry, love and politics. When Mario first meets barmaid Beatrice Russo over a game of table football, he instantly falls in love. He is inspired by his mentor to write her love poems, many of which he plagiarizes, and soon wins her heart. Michael Radford's surname may seem a little consonant-heavy for a production of this origin but the writer-director's English eye can only be clearly detected in the humour of the pacey, racy table football scene; which a native or continental director may have shot a little more seductively. It is really Troisi who leaves his indelible print on the film, which would be his last (dying tragically the day after production wrapped). The actor's physical frailty comes across as his character's mumbling humility. When beautiful Maria Grazia Cucinotta falls for his charms (or lack thereof), no one would seem more deserving a husband than he, and it is immensely gratifying to see his son Pablito stumble onto screen at the end. Phillipe Noiret also evokes much feeling in the last scene, imagining his friend's great yet fatal agitation for change, while walking their familiar beach. We get the feeling they may have liberated one another. 'Il Postino' is very much a film that flows like poetry. There is no solid structure as prescribed by the script doctors of the time. No stakes and little drama. When our lovable protagonist dies at the end, it is not played for tears of devastation. I felt quiet elation: he had finally found his voice and could speak up for his people at the rally. He asks Neruda earlier in the film a question regarding the writer's revolutionary ideals, "So what if we break off our chains? What do we do then?" He obviously has an answer to that question by the end, which is satisfaction enough. In another exchange, when Mario's plagiarism is discovered by Pablo, he counters "Poetry doesn't belong to those who write it; it belongs to those who need it." This strikes one as quite humorous in the context of the scene but when recalled or read alone it signifies the point at which Mario has cast the chains off his mind. Sadly the distributors do not live by this dictum, and intellectual copyright law prevails online and elsewhere. While it may be a fictional account, the film is very much a celebration of the actual effect Neruda's poetry had on many of the working people of the world. Not so much a tribute to him, but to the millions of postini worldwide who have been delivered and a rallying call for all those who have yet to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Massimo Troisi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    his performance is essence of this adorable film. his character is so careful created that its fragility, humor, innocence, light of details are magnificent. he don't play a role but he is "il postino" . and this fact transforms entire scene. the story of Neruda exile is only arena for emotions of a small man on an Italian isle. the beautiful Beatrice is brick for his delicate happiness. Neruda himself is not exactly a mentor but a gardener. and the music, the extraordinary music, it is the soul of entire poetry. because a poetry is this movie who has as roots poems. very delicate, nice, nostalgic, melancholic, subtle, intelligent, precise, it is wonderful homage to a way to discover life as fundamental miracle. to feel the nuances of love, friendship, to be humble, modest and daring in same time, to feel gratitude as form of respiration. beautiful and impressive. touching. and unique. story of a postman. legacy of Massimo Troisi.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Art and Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gradyharp
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just visited the opera version of this film IL POSTINO by Daniel Catan courtesy of PBS Great Performances it is rewarding to return to the original source to honor the nidus for the inspiration for the opera. Directed by Michael Radford the film relates the heartwarming story of Mario (Massimo Troisi), a gentle and simple postman who falls for the beautiful caf&eacute; waitress Beatrice (Maria Grazia Cucinotta) from his village, but is too shy to speak to her. He meets the famous Chilean poet Pablo Neruda (Phillipe Noiret), and, as their friendship develops, the postman's own inner poet awakens. Soon he is able to win the love of Beatrice and even stand up for and express his own beliefs. This is a simple story graced by sensitive performances: of not the actor Massimo Trosi died from heart failure on the last day of production of the film. It is possibly this knowledge of the loss of one of Italy's best comedic actors along with the clarity and transparency of the film's gentle message about love and art that has made it a cult film. At any rate this is a film that belongs in every movie lover's library. Grady Harp
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great cinematography, good acting by Trosi, but Neruda comes out the loser here.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    felixoteiza
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is actually an Italian fairy tale, one where Neruda is little more than a simple enabler for two lovebirds. The story of a humble, uneducated, man who conquers the heart of a girl with words borrowed, or stolen, from the great poet. Nothing wrong with that, except that this Master of Words proves at the end to be very flawed, unworthy of the worshiping he's the object of-but more of that later. Decent acting overall, breathtaking scenerythose postcard coastal natural settings are also common in Neruda's Chilebut the writing lets a lot to be desired, with too many schmaltzy scenes & dialogs and assorted clich&eacute; situations. Not surprise then that he plot loses its breath half way, when the lovebirds get married and Pablo returns to Chile. What is left then is the same thing we had at the beginning: the daily routines of a small fishing town in southern Italy. Will that be enough to carry the rest of the movie? Don't think so. This isn't Amacord or IVitelloni, as the whole plot was resting on the relationship Neruda--Mario and so when that comes to an end the movie is left gasping for air, begging for some emotional filling as a replacement. With the poet gone and the romance morphed into routine, all what's left for Mario are unfulfilled family obligations and a constant moping for the absent Master. There is an obvious plot discontinuity when both men separate, perhaps because this script was made sewing up two original stories, set in different places at different times. Sure enough, Neruda was in exile in Italy after having fled Chile in 1949, when the Chilean government started jailing Communists, despite them being part of the governing coalition (!) after being pressured by the Yankees, who had started their own witch hunt. (it's hard to believe, but the reason why communists were hunted down was because Chile's president was afraid of it being considered unfriendly by the U.S and risk losing trade, diplomatic and political benefits). Neruda escaped to Argentina & then to Italy, where he was well received thanks to the work made on Italian public opinion by fellow communist Alberto Moravia. On the other hand, the story of him befriending a postman and writing him poems dedicated to his love interest comes from Antonio Skarmeta's Ardiente Paciencia, set in Chile in the 60s, in the coastal town of Isla Negra, where Neruda had a cottage (which is now a museum). So, this is really a Chilean story transposed to Italy, which may explain the awkward plot situation produced when Neruda leaves. Now, Noiret may be a great actor but he makes a disfavor to Neruda with his work here, at least in 2 instances. First, when he's back in Chile he forgets about Mario and doesn't even answer his mail. The real Neruda would have never done that, because for him friendship and loyalty were two things intrinsically tied to class struggle and political commitment. For him all communists--and all members of the working class-were his brothers whatever may have been their countries of origin or their educational level, and all right wingers and rich people in general his enemies, as for him there was no middle ground at that. In real life he would have never acted like he does with Mario, just because he's a less educated man. At least he would have sent him a postcard. The 2nd thing is you would have never caught him in church, let alone crossing himself, as he was an atheist who had no use for religions or for any organized church and the only people in that realm for whom he ever came to feel any respect at all were the Quakers, just because they helped pay for travel tickets to Chile for thousands of Spaniards fleeing their civil war. It's obvious that both misrepresentations have been committed to keep the plot going, which I can understand, but the record must be set straight anyway. Anyway, IP can be very touching the first time you see it, but it goes losing its emotional punch with time, as there's no much left to get hold of after the thrill of the love story and that of the beautiful words wears off. But worse is the portrayal of Neruda as a snob; an hypocrite who'll be nice to the locals as long as he needs them but who'll forget them as soon as he's gone. I'm all for artistic licenses, but not when they make appear an authentic individual under such an unfavorable and false light. In all, to see maybe a couple of times. Anyway, if you want to see something closer to the real man, watch Skarmeta's Ardiente Paciencia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who Really Wrote the Score?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jacobsencurtis
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Il Postino" is one of my favorite movies. The acting is superb. Massimo Troisi gives a uniquely unforgettable performance, despite his suffering from a fatal illness during filming. Phillipe Noiret, as Pablo Neruda, the Chilean poet-in-exile who befriends Mario (Troisi), gives one of his most memorable performances. The location is enchanting. I love all things Italian. Even a bad movie set in Italy is better for it having been shot there. Some of my favorites are "Enchanted April," "Summertime," and "Roman Holiday." And I love the score, which, until tonight, I assumed was written by Luis Bacalov, who is credited in the movie. But I just watched a movie from 1940 called "Dispatch from Reuters," a bio-pic starring Edward G. Robinson, and darned if the main theme from "Il Postino" isn't straight out of "Dispatch from Reuters." By the way, the music for "Reuters" was composed by the great Max Steiner, who, to my knowledge, received no screen credit in "Il Postino." How is this possible? Has the copyright expired rendering the music part of the public domain?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mundane
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike B
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I found this rather superficial and mundane. It's about the friendship between a worker  a postman - and a poet  Pablo Neruda. The poet awakens the young man's sensibilities and gives him the courage to pursue the village beauty. This is a tiny village - so why he had not realized her beauty before, and more so, why she was not being pursued by an entire flock of young men raised a question mark. The characters are all stereo-typed  the shy postman, the over-wordy poet and the village beauty with her raspy aunt. Everything was a caricature and the film suffered from a lack of passion, intensityI couldn't buy into it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice try, but not quite what I expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only heard of this movie on the TV game show 'Who Wants to be a Millionaire?'. The question was which one of 4 mentioned actors starred in the films 'Nuovo Cinema Paradiso' and 'Il Postino'. I hadn't heard of 'Il Postino' before, but I knew that Philippe Noiret stars in 'Nuovo Cinema Paradiso', so I already knew the answer. The presenter recommended the person who wrongly answered the question to watch these 2 movies because something changes inside us once we get to see these 2 films. Then I did research on this motion-picture. It sounded promising, even more so by being foreign. I also got to know the sad story of Massimo Troisi, who played the title's postman (Pablo Neruda's postman). The man suffered from heart disease since a long time ago. He knew about his fragile heart condition and knew he needed treatment, but despite this he wanted to do the movie anyway. He even postponed heart surgery so that he could complete the film. That was a brave move. And he did manage to finish the movie just in time. Only 12 hours after completing the film he died of heart attack. You can say that he gave his life to make this film. Massimo Troisi is great as Mario Ruoppolo, the postman. But it's also sad to see him in this film because we are looking at a man who was dying while making it and that he died almost immediately after completing it. Phillipe Noiret is great as the chilean poet Pablo Neruda. While Pablo Neruda existed for real, his friendship with the postman didn't. But I don't know if a postman named Mario Ruoppolo existed in real life or not and if he was Pablo Neruda's postman or not. The film's got beautiful cinematography and soundtrack, which gives it more emotion and beauty. The plot is, in concept, good. But the movie itself lacks something (perhaps more emotion is one of those things it lacks) and is even a little too-slow paced. It's not a bad movie. It's interesting, moving, pretty to view... a good attempt, just not quite top material. It just isn't as great as it reputation suggests (with, of course, all due respect in memory of our friend Massimo Troisi).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engrossing character study about two men and their connections to two separate women, as well as the poetry that forms the core of their own friendship.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Radford's tender and rather sweet film, The Postman, is a really quite blinding tale of a man, without either much of a life or very many happenings in and around his existence, going out of his way so as to spawn some. The film is a ground zero character study working its way up, centring on one man and coming to gloriously flesh out his relationships with two people in the form of a mentor and a love interest using the item of poetry, and poets in particular, as a focal point or anchor around which to revolve the ever shifting lives of these half a dozen-or so people. The central character is a certain young man named Mario Ruoppolo, played by Italian actor Massimo Troisi whom died shortly after the film was completed and is one of only seven people to have won a Posthumous Academy Award for acting, which he won for his portrayal of a character named Mario. His life in the early part of the 20th Century on an island off the coast of Italy lies seemingly dormant; a living with his father, whom spends his days at sea fishing for a living, whilst inhabiting a scruffy and run down house on the cliff-side which cannot even produce water from a tap when desired, the situation; with a postcard from some brothers whom have arrived in America offering a brief insight into a supposedly better life. Determined to get on track, the softly spoken; delicate and slow moving Mario shifts off to a local post office so as to apply for the advertised job of delivering letters and mail, locally. On another tangent, that later will become intrinsically linked to that of Mario, a controversial poet from South American nation Chile of true to life existence named Pablo Neruda (Noiret) arrives in Italy having been exiled. His demeanour arrives by way of a newsreel sequence at a picture house, footage which the locals and us watch and listen to simultaneously establishing a set-persona of the man and his controversial, Communist infused existence of writing poetry crash-landing on this small Italian island, much to some of the locals' anger but to the glee of others. The early perceptions of the man are meant to be relatively concrete; he inhabits a beautifully placed but isolated red-washed villa on a separate cliff edge, before plodding Mario comes to form a bond with the poet upon delivering his many letters and from whence the film garners its catalyst so as to play out. The film comes to form a learning process for that of Mario, a deconstruction of an item or art-form that he'd almost certainly heard of in the past but very rarely thought about above a certain level. The same can be said for that of Chilian poet Neruda in regards to the fondness and acceptance the town come to have of him after he and his wife and their bond with a number of people come to forge, a relationship much richer than what he has experienced back home or, you feel, in most other places. Romance appears to want to bloom between Mario and local girl Beatrice (Cucinotta), the daughter of a traditional, hard-up Catholic woman whom owns a tavern within the vicinity; the spying of her playing a game of rather erotically charged flick-rod football in said tavern complete with thrusting of the mannequin players and hammering home of the goals more than enough to have Mario smitten from then on in. But the film is ultimately about the relationship or bond between two men going on around their separate relationships with Beatrice and Pablo's own female partner whom later becomes his wife. It would be untrue to say that the film at all feels less of an accomplishment when certain events transpire and the once central unification of Mario and Pablo is broken up; rather, the ties they have to one another during the film's early scenes are just more interesting, as is the chilling finale involving the two, than any sub-plot to do with either men and what happens between them and their women. Mario's attempts to court a young local girl and the noticeable placing of Pablo's own female partner predominantly off screen and away from the action for most of the time might render the relationship between Mario and Pablo one of a homo-erotic nature. Much later on, a Paris based interview with the poet some years later has Mario read on with keen interest as to whether he or anyone from the town are mentioned; the camera darting around from face to face of those reading with Mario in a kind of panic or nervous excitement or lusting requirement for purifying fulfilment in the form of notifying them, predominantly the notifying of Mario. The convenience in having come to have known a master of poetry of a romantic sort, somebody that feeds off of a belief that all women love romantic poetry and that it is the key to pertaining to a relationship, works very much in Mario's favour. His gradual learning of how to construct it, the encountering of terms and words such as what a metaphor is gradually come to form the nucleus of the first half of the film; a fitting sequence on a nearby beach sees Pablo gradually reveal himself as he readies to swim in a physical sense as Mario comes to reveal a spoken metaphor for the very first time as, on another occasion, he gradually forms an opinion of a short poem Pablo comes up with on the spot. The film's attention to finer things such as these, an including of sequences in which characters must first come to master the basics of an art or activity so as to garner entry onto another plateau so as to put what has been learnt into action, feels wonderfully prominent, resulting in Radford's film being thoroughly worthwhile.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    magnificent masterpiece of Michael with two marvelous metaphors --the poet(Pablo) and the postman(Mario)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    superdirector007
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    what a magnificent movie, legendary work by Michael Redford , everything about this movie is beautiful ,,winning Oscar does not come in easy way ,,be it budget,,cinematography covering island's natural beauty ,,specially sea settings ,humourous dialogs with utmost simplicity and realistic performances by actors ,everything is admirable. sometimes you do not plan to make a great movie with highly perfection attitude but movie becomes and gets applauded ,,same happened with this movie,what i believe what is metaphor Mario asks Pablo says-like sky is weeping what does it mean Mario says means to say sky is raining Mario's response it's complicated and Pablo's response that complication does not have to do anything with person's emotions very meaningful and soulful dialogs ,that is the reason movie does not become boring end of the movie is very surprising ,it keeps you involve in the movie movie was shot on the island near by Meditteranean sea and every time tides go and again come to touch coastal areas that resembles one excellent scene goes with the hope to come with another lovely scene filled with emotional and heart touching dialogs to touch your heart movie is pretty simple but can you predict what's gonna happen in next scene ,probably not ,it has certain surprising elements this movie is not a movie this is everlasting experience to live with and cherish it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    United in Friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although "Il Postino" simply means "The Postman", and although the film was at one time screened as "The Postman" in Britain, it is now generally known in English by its&nbsp;Italian title to avoid confusion with Kevin Costner's post-apocalyptic epic from three years later. It is loosely based upon the novel&nbsp;"Ardiente paciencia"&nbsp;by&nbsp;the Chilean&nbsp;writer Antonio Sk&aacute;rmeta, although it transfers the action from Chile to Italy. It takes as its starting-point the fact that in the early 1950s the famous&nbsp;Chilean&nbsp;poet&nbsp;Pablo Neruda, in exile from his homeland for political reasons, spent some time on the island of Capri. The film, however, is not set on Capri but on an unnamed Italian island. A young fisherman named Mario Ruoppolo applies for a job as the island's postman. As he owns a bicycle and is one of the very few islanders who can read and write he is accepted and is told that he will only have one customer, Neruda himself, as because of the low levels of literacy on the island nobody else ever receives any mail. (Were standards of education really so low in fifties Italy?) Although Mario has never previously heard of Neruda, and certainly has never read any of his poems, a friendship gradually grows up between the two men. Although Mario has had little formal education he is clearly an intelligent and sensitive man, and Neruda reads him some of his poetry (in Italian translation), teaching him about literary concepts such as metaphors. With Neruda's help Mario&nbsp;woos the beautiful Beatrice, a village girl with whom he has&nbsp;fallen in love, stealing some of the older man's love poems and passing them off as his own in order to win her affections. My one criticism of the film would be that it is too sentimental about Communism, but that is perhaps only to be expected of a film from Italy, a country which at one time had the largest Communist Party in Western Europe. (In the seventies they used to win around a third of the popular vote, at a time when the British Communist Party generally consisted of three old men and a dog). Pablo Neruda is here portrayed as a kindly, idealistic gentleman, but in reality, during the forties and early fifties, he was a Communist hardliner who enthusiastically defended Stalin's dictatorship in the Soviet Union. After Khrushchev's 1956 "secret speech" he was to criticise the Stalinist cult of personality but this was due less to a change of heart than to a desire to align himself with the new official Soviet party line. He was also, at the time of his Italian exile, around twenty years younger than the character portrayed here by Philippe Noiret. Its politics aside, however, "Il Postino" is in many ways an excellent film. There is some attractive photography of the Italian coastal scenery and a great musical score by Luis Enr&iacute;quez Bacalov. What really makes the film stand out, however, are the two great performances from Noiret and from Massimo Troisi, who tragically died of a heart attack soon afterwards, as Mario. There is also a good performance from the lovely Maria Grazia Cucinotta as Beatrice. Troisi received a posthumous Oscar nomination for "Best Actor", but lost out to Nicholas Cage in "Leaving Las Vegas"; as I have never seen that film I am unable to comment on the justice of that decision. I felt, however, that it was unfortunate that there was no nomination for Noiret either as "Best Actor" or "Best Supporting Actor". Indeed, this is one of those films which make me feel that it should be possible to nominate two actors for a joint award, as Noiret and Troisi combine together so well that their joint contribution seems greater than the sum of its two parts. This is the story of a touching relationship between two men of different generations, of different nationalities, of different levels of education and of&nbsp;different outlooks on life who are nevertheless united in friendship. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The deliverance of one man of letters by another is a cinematic love letter to poetry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edantheman
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Chilean poet and communist agitator Pablo Neruda may never have set foot on the island of Salina in 1950, but writer-actor Mariamo Troisi's exploration of the idea is probably more interesting than any account of his actual exiles abroad. The eponymous postman of the film, Mario, has never taken to the patrilineal profession of fishing in his family. His widower father understands he never will and releases his seemingly simple son from his duties, to choose an occupation more suited to his abilities. In town, the communist postmaster needs a hand with the flurry of fan mail in the wake of Neruda and his wife's arrival. He greatly admires the Bolivarian bard and has his new postman run reconnaissance and procure signatures from him. Though their early exchanges may be of little significance, the two very different men of letters soon form a bond through a series of exchanges on poetry, love and politics. When Mario first meets barmaid Beatrice Russo over a game of table football, he instantly falls in love. He is inspired by his mentor to write her love poems, many of which he plagiarizes, and soon wins her heart. Michael Radford's surname may seem a little consonant-heavy for a production of this origin but the writer-director's English eye can only be clearly detected in the humour of the pacey, racy table football scene; which a native or continental director may have shot a little more seductively. It is really Troisi who leaves his indelible print on the film, which would be his last (dying tragically the day after production wrapped). The actor's physical frailty comes across as his character's mumbling humility. When beautiful Maria Grazia Cucinotta falls for his charms (or lack thereof), no one would seem more deserving a husband than he, and it is immensely gratifying to see his son Pablito stumble onto screen at the end. Phillipe Noiret also evokes much feeling in the last scene, imagining his friend's great yet fatal agitation for change, while walking their familiar beach. We get the feeling they may have liberated one another. 'Il Postino' is very much a film that flows like poetry. There is no solid structure as prescribed by the script doctors of the time. No stakes and little drama. When our lovable protagonist dies at the end, it is not played for tears of devastation. I felt quiet elation: he had finally found his voice and could speak up for his people at the rally. He asks Neruda earlier in the film a question regarding the writer's revolutionary ideals, "So what if we break off our chains? What do we do then?" He obviously has an answer to that question by the end, which is satisfaction enough. In another exchange, when Mario's plagiarism is discovered by Pablo, he counters "Poetry doesn't belong to those who write it; it belongs to those who need it." This strikes one as quite humorous in the context of the scene but when recalled or read alone it signifies the point at which Mario has cast the chains off his mind. Sadly the distributors do not live by this dictum, and intellectual copyright law prevails online and elsewhere. While it may be a fictional account, the film is very much a celebration of the actual effect Neruda's poetry had on many of the working people of the world. Not so much a tribute to him, but to the millions of postini worldwide who have been delivered and a rallying call for all those who have yet to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Massimo Troisi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    his performance is essence of this adorable film. his character is so careful created that its fragility, humor, innocence, light of details are magnificent. he don't play a role but he is "il postino" . and this fact transforms entire scene. the story of Neruda exile is only arena for emotions of a small man on an Italian isle. the beautiful Beatrice is brick for his delicate happiness. Neruda himself is not exactly a mentor but a gardener. and the music, the extraordinary music, it is the soul of entire poetry. because a poetry is this movie who has as roots poems. very delicate, nice, nostalgic, melancholic, subtle, intelligent, precise, it is wonderful homage to a way to discover life as fundamental miracle. to feel the nuances of love, friendship, to be humble, modest and daring in same time, to feel gratitude as form of respiration. beautiful and impressive. touching. and unique. story of a postman. legacy of Massimo Troisi.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Art and Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gradyharp
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just visited the opera version of this film IL POSTINO by Daniel Catan courtesy of PBS Great Performances it is rewarding to return to the original source to honor the nidus for the inspiration for the opera. Directed by Michael Radford the film relates the heartwarming story of Mario (Massimo Troisi), a gentle and simple postman who falls for the beautiful caf&eacute; waitress Beatrice (Maria Grazia Cucinotta) from his village, but is too shy to speak to her. He meets the famous Chilean poet Pablo Neruda (Phillipe Noiret), and, as their friendship develops, the postman's own inner poet awakens. Soon he is able to win the love of Beatrice and even stand up for and express his own beliefs. This is a simple story graced by sensitive performances: of not the actor Massimo Trosi died from heart failure on the last day of production of the film. It is possibly this knowledge of the loss of one of Italy's best comedic actors along with the clarity and transparency of the film's gentle message about love and art that has made it a cult film. At any rate this is a film that belongs in every movie lover's library. Grady Harp
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great cinematography, good acting by Trosi, but Neruda comes out the loser here.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    felixoteiza
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is actually an Italian fairy tale, one where Neruda is little more than a simple enabler for two lovebirds. The story of a humble, uneducated, man who conquers the heart of a girl with words borrowed, or stolen, from the great poet. Nothing wrong with that, except that this Master of Words proves at the end to be very flawed, unworthy of the worshiping he's the object of-but more of that later. Decent acting overall, breathtaking scenerythose postcard coastal natural settings are also common in Neruda's Chilebut the writing lets a lot to be desired, with too many schmaltzy scenes & dialogs and assorted clich&eacute; situations. Not surprise then that he plot loses its breath half way, when the lovebirds get married and Pablo returns to Chile. What is left then is the same thing we had at the beginning: the daily routines of a small fishing town in southern Italy. Will that be enough to carry the rest of the movie? Don't think so. This isn't Amacord or IVitelloni, as the whole plot was resting on the relationship Neruda--Mario and so when that comes to an end the movie is left gasping for air, begging for some emotional filling as a replacement. With the poet gone and the romance morphed into routine, all what's left for Mario are unfulfilled family obligations and a constant moping for the absent Master. There is an obvious plot discontinuity when both men separate, perhaps because this script was made sewing up two original stories, set in different places at different times. Sure enough, Neruda was in exile in Italy after having fled Chile in 1949, when the Chilean government started jailing Communists, despite them being part of the governing coalition (!) after being pressured by the Yankees, who had started their own witch hunt. (it's hard to believe, but the reason why communists were hunted down was because Chile's president was afraid of it being considered unfriendly by the U.S and risk losing trade, diplomatic and political benefits). Neruda escaped to Argentina & then to Italy, where he was well received thanks to the work made on Italian public opinion by fellow communist Alberto Moravia. On the other hand, the story of him befriending a postman and writing him poems dedicated to his love interest comes from Antonio Skarmeta's Ardiente Paciencia, set in Chile in the 60s, in the coastal town of Isla Negra, where Neruda had a cottage (which is now a museum). So, this is really a Chilean story transposed to Italy, which may explain the awkward plot situation produced when Neruda leaves. Now, Noiret may be a great actor but he makes a disfavor to Neruda with his work here, at least in 2 instances. First, when he's back in Chile he forgets about Mario and doesn't even answer his mail. The real Neruda would have never done that, because for him friendship and loyalty were two things intrinsically tied to class struggle and political commitment. For him all communists--and all members of the working class-were his brothers whatever may have been their countries of origin or their educational level, and all right wingers and rich people in general his enemies, as for him there was no middle ground at that. In real life he would have never acted like he does with Mario, just because he's a less educated man. At least he would have sent him a postcard. The 2nd thing is you would have never caught him in church, let alone crossing himself, as he was an atheist who had no use for religions or for any organized church and the only people in that realm for whom he ever came to feel any respect at all were the Quakers, just because they helped pay for travel tickets to Chile for thousands of Spaniards fleeing their civil war. It's obvious that both misrepresentations have been committed to keep the plot going, which I can understand, but the record must be set straight anyway. Anyway, IP can be very touching the first time you see it, but it goes losing its emotional punch with time, as there's no much left to get hold of after the thrill of the love story and that of the beautiful words wears off. But worse is the portrayal of Neruda as a snob; an hypocrite who'll be nice to the locals as long as he needs them but who'll forget them as soon as he's gone. I'm all for artistic licenses, but not when they make appear an authentic individual under such an unfavorable and false light. In all, to see maybe a couple of times. Anyway, if you want to see something closer to the real man, watch Skarmeta's Ardiente Paciencia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who Really Wrote the Score?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jacobsencurtis
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Il Postino" is one of my favorite movies. The acting is superb. Massimo Troisi gives a uniquely unforgettable performance, despite his suffering from a fatal illness during filming. Phillipe Noiret, as Pablo Neruda, the Chilean poet-in-exile who befriends Mario (Troisi), gives one of his most memorable performances. The location is enchanting. I love all things Italian. Even a bad movie set in Italy is better for it having been shot there. Some of my favorites are "Enchanted April," "Summertime," and "Roman Holiday." And I love the score, which, until tonight, I assumed was written by Luis Bacalov, who is credited in the movie. But I just watched a movie from 1940 called "Dispatch from Reuters," a bio-pic starring Edward G. Robinson, and darned if the main theme from "Il Postino" isn't straight out of "Dispatch from Reuters." By the way, the music for "Reuters" was composed by the great Max Steiner, who, to my knowledge, received no screen credit in "Il Postino." How is this possible? Has the copyright expired rendering the music part of the public domain?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mundane
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike B
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I found this rather superficial and mundane. It's about the friendship between a worker  a postman - and a poet  Pablo Neruda. The poet awakens the young man's sensibilities and gives him the courage to pursue the village beauty. This is a tiny village - so why he had not realized her beauty before, and more so, why she was not being pursued by an entire flock of young men raised a question mark. The characters are all stereo-typed  the shy postman, the over-wordy poet and the village beauty with her raspy aunt. Everything was a caricature and the film suffered from a lack of passion, intensityI couldn't buy into it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice try, but not quite what I expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only heard of this movie on the TV game show 'Who Wants to be a Millionaire?'. The question was which one of 4 mentioned actors starred in the films 'Nuovo Cinema Paradiso' and 'Il Postino'. I hadn't heard of 'Il Postino' before, but I knew that Philippe Noiret stars in 'Nuovo Cinema Paradiso', so I already knew the answer. The presenter recommended the person who wrongly answered the question to watch these 2 movies because something changes inside us once we get to see these 2 films. Then I did research on this motion-picture. It sounded promising, even more so by being foreign. I also got to know the sad story of Massimo Troisi, who played the title's postman (Pablo Neruda's postman). The man suffered from heart disease since a long time ago. He knew about his fragile heart condition and knew he needed treatment, but despite this he wanted to do the movie anyway. He even postponed heart surgery so that he could complete the film. That was a brave move. And he did manage to finish the movie just in time. Only 12 hours after completing the film he died of heart attack. You can say that he gave his life to make this film. Massimo Troisi is great as Mario Ruoppolo, the postman. But it's also sad to see him in this film because we are looking at a man who was dying while making it and that he died almost immediately after completing it. Phillipe Noiret is great as the chilean poet Pablo Neruda. While Pablo Neruda existed for real, his friendship with the postman didn't. But I don't know if a postman named Mario Ruoppolo existed in real life or not and if he was Pablo Neruda's postman or not. The film's got beautiful cinematography and soundtrack, which gives it more emotion and beauty. The plot is, in concept, good. But the movie itself lacks something (perhaps more emotion is one of those things it lacks) and is even a little too-slow paced. It's not a bad movie. It's interesting, moving, pretty to view... a good attempt, just not quite top material. It just isn't as great as it reputation suggests (with, of course, all due respect in memory of our friend Massimo Troisi).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engrossing character study about two men and their connections to two separate women, as well as the poetry that forms the core of their own friendship.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Radford's tender and rather sweet film, The Postman, is a really quite blinding tale of a man, without either much of a life or very many happenings in and around his existence, going out of his way so as to spawn some. The film is a ground zero character study working its way up, centring on one man and coming to gloriously flesh out his relationships with two people in the form of a mentor and a love interest using the item of poetry, and poets in particular, as a focal point or anchor around which to revolve the ever shifting lives of these half a dozen-or so people. The central character is a certain young man named Mario Ruoppolo, played by Italian actor Massimo Troisi whom died shortly after the film was completed and is one of only seven people to have won a Posthumous Academy Award for acting, which he won for his portrayal of a character named Mario. His life in the early part of the 20th Century on an island off the coast of Italy lies seemingly dormant; a living with his father, whom spends his days at sea fishing for a living, whilst inhabiting a scruffy and run down house on the cliff-side which cannot even produce water from a tap when desired, the situation; with a postcard from some brothers whom have arrived in America offering a brief insight into a supposedly better life. Determined to get on track, the softly spoken; delicate and slow moving Mario shifts off to a local post office so as to apply for the advertised job of delivering letters and mail, locally. On another tangent, that later will become intrinsically linked to that of Mario, a controversial poet from South American nation Chile of true to life existence named Pablo Neruda (Noiret) arrives in Italy having been exiled. His demeanour arrives by way of a newsreel sequence at a picture house, footage which the locals and us watch and listen to simultaneously establishing a set-persona of the man and his controversial, Communist infused existence of writing poetry crash-landing on this small Italian island, much to some of the locals' anger but to the glee of others. The early perceptions of the man are meant to be relatively concrete; he inhabits a beautifully placed but isolated red-washed villa on a separate cliff edge, before plodding Mario comes to form a bond with the poet upon delivering his many letters and from whence the film garners its catalyst so as to play out. The film comes to form a learning process for that of Mario, a deconstruction of an item or art-form that he'd almost certainly heard of in the past but very rarely thought about above a certain level. The same can be said for that of Chilian poet Neruda in regards to the fondness and acceptance the town come to have of him after he and his wife and their bond with a number of people come to forge, a relationship much richer than what he has experienced back home or, you feel, in most other places. Romance appears to want to bloom between Mario and local girl Beatrice (Cucinotta), the daughter of a traditional, hard-up Catholic woman whom owns a tavern within the vicinity; the spying of her playing a game of rather erotically charged flick-rod football in said tavern complete with thrusting of the mannequin players and hammering home of the goals more than enough to have Mario smitten from then on in. But the film is ultimately about the relationship or bond between two men going on around their separate relationships with Beatrice and Pablo's own female partner whom later becomes his wife. It would be untrue to say that the film at all feels less of an accomplishment when certain events transpire and the once central unification of Mario and Pablo is broken up; rather, the ties they have to one another during the film's early scenes are just more interesting, as is the chilling finale involving the two, than any sub-plot to do with either men and what happens between them and their women. Mario's attempts to court a young local girl and the noticeable placing of Pablo's own female partner predominantly off screen and away from the action for most of the time might render the relationship between Mario and Pablo one of a homo-erotic nature. Much later on, a Paris based interview with the poet some years later has Mario read on with keen interest as to whether he or anyone from the town are mentioned; the camera darting around from face to face of those reading with Mario in a kind of panic or nervous excitement or lusting requirement for purifying fulfilment in the form of notifying them, predominantly the notifying of Mario. The convenience in having come to have known a master of poetry of a romantic sort, somebody that feeds off of a belief that all women love romantic poetry and that it is the key to pertaining to a relationship, works very much in Mario's favour. His gradual learning of how to construct it, the encountering of terms and words such as what a metaphor is gradually come to form the nucleus of the first half of the film; a fitting sequence on a nearby beach sees Pablo gradually reveal himself as he readies to swim in a physical sense as Mario comes to reveal a spoken metaphor for the very first time as, on another occasion, he gradually forms an opinion of a short poem Pablo comes up with on the spot. The film's attention to finer things such as these, an including of sequences in which characters must first come to master the basics of an art or activity so as to garner entry onto another plateau so as to put what has been learnt into action, feels wonderfully prominent, resulting in Radford's film being thoroughly worthwhile.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    magnificent masterpiece of Michael with two marvelous metaphors --the poet(Pablo) and the postman(Mario)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    superdirector007
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    what a magnificent movie, legendary work by Michael Redford , everything about this movie is beautiful ,,winning Oscar does not come in easy way ,,be it budget,,cinematography covering island's natural beauty ,,specially sea settings ,humourous dialogs with utmost simplicity and realistic performances by actors ,everything is admirable. sometimes you do not plan to make a great movie with highly perfection attitude but movie becomes and gets applauded ,,same happened with this movie,what i believe what is metaphor Mario asks Pablo says-like sky is weeping what does it mean Mario says means to say sky is raining Mario's response it's complicated and Pablo's response that complication does not have to do anything with person's emotions very meaningful and soulful dialogs ,that is the reason movie does not become boring end of the movie is very surprising ,it keeps you involve in the movie movie was shot on the island near by Meditteranean sea and every time tides go and again come to touch coastal areas that resembles one excellent scene goes with the hope to come with another lovely scene filled with emotional and heart touching dialogs to touch your heart movie is pretty simple but can you predict what's gonna happen in next scene ,probably not ,it has certain surprising elements this movie is not a movie this is everlasting experience to live with and cherish it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    United in Friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although "Il Postino" simply means "The Postman", and although the film was at one time screened as "The Postman" in Britain, it is now generally known in English by its&nbsp;Italian title to avoid confusion with Kevin Costner's post-apocalyptic epic from three years later. It is loosely based upon the novel&nbsp;"Ardiente paciencia"&nbsp;by&nbsp;the Chilean&nbsp;writer Antonio Sk&aacute;rmeta, although it transfers the action from Chile to Italy. It takes as its starting-point the fact that in the early 1950s the famous&nbsp;Chilean&nbsp;poet&nbsp;Pablo Neruda, in exile from his homeland for political reasons, spent some time on the island of Capri. The film, however, is not set on Capri but on an unnamed Italian island. A young fisherman named Mario Ruoppolo applies for a job as the island's postman. As he owns a bicycle and is one of the very few islanders who can read and write he is accepted and is told that he will only have one customer, Neruda himself, as because of the low levels of literacy on the island nobody else ever receives any mail. (Were standards of education really so low in fifties Italy?) Although Mario has never previously heard of Neruda, and certainly has never read any of his poems, a friendship gradually grows up between the two men. Although Mario has had little formal education he is clearly an intelligent and sensitive man, and Neruda reads him some of his poetry (in Italian translation), teaching him about literary concepts such as metaphors. With Neruda's help Mario&nbsp;woos the beautiful Beatrice, a village girl with whom he has&nbsp;fallen in love, stealing some of the older man's love poems and passing them off as his own in order to win her affections. My one criticism of the film would be that it is too sentimental about Communism, but that is perhaps only to be expected of a film from Italy, a country which at one time had the largest Communist Party in Western Europe. (In the seventies they used to win around a third of the popular vote, at a time when the British Communist Party generally consisted of three old men and a dog). Pablo Neruda is here portrayed as a kindly, idealistic gentleman, but in reality, during the forties and early fifties, he was a Communist hardliner who enthusiastically defended Stalin's dictatorship in the Soviet Union. After Khrushchev's 1956 "secret speech" he was to criticise the Stalinist cult of personality but this was due less to a change of heart than to a desire to align himself with the new official Soviet party line. He was also, at the time of his Italian exile, around twenty years younger than the character portrayed here by Philippe Noiret. Its politics aside, however, "Il Postino" is in many ways an excellent film. There is some attractive photography of the Italian coastal scenery and a great musical score by Luis Enr&iacute;quez Bacalov. What really makes the film stand out, however, are the two great performances from Noiret and from Massimo Troisi, who tragically died of a heart attack soon afterwards, as Mario. There is also a good performance from the lovely Maria Grazia Cucinotta as Beatrice. Troisi received a posthumous Oscar nomination for "Best Actor", but lost out to Nicholas Cage in "Leaving Las Vegas"; as I have never seen that film I am unable to comment on the justice of that decision. I felt, however, that it was unfortunate that there was no nomination for Noiret either as "Best Actor" or "Best Supporting Actor". Indeed, this is one of those films which make me feel that it should be possible to nominate two actors for a joint award, as Noiret and Troisi combine together so well that their joint contribution seems greater than the sum of its two parts. This is the story of a touching relationship between two men of different generations, of different nationalities, of different levels of education and of&nbsp;different outlooks on life who are nevertheless united in friendship. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The deliverance of one man of letters by another is a cinematic love letter to poetry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edantheman
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Chilean poet and communist agitator Pablo Neruda may never have set foot on the island of Salina in 1950, but writer-actor Mariamo Troisi's exploration of the idea is probably more interesting than any account of his actual exiles abroad. The eponymous postman of the film, Mario, has never taken to the patrilineal profession of fishing in his family. His widower father understands he never will and releases his seemingly simple son from his duties, to choose an occupation more suited to his abilities. In town, the communist postmaster needs a hand with the flurry of fan mail in the wake of Neruda and his wife's arrival. He greatly admires the Bolivarian bard and has his new postman run reconnaissance and procure signatures from him. Though their early exchanges may be of little significance, the two very different men of letters soon form a bond through a series of exchanges on poetry, love and politics. When Mario first meets barmaid Beatrice Russo over a game of table football, he instantly falls in love. He is inspired by his mentor to write her love poems, many of which he plagiarizes, and soon wins her heart. Michael Radford's surname may seem a little consonant-heavy for a production of this origin but the writer-director's English eye can only be clearly detected in the humour of the pacey, racy table football scene; which a native or continental director may have shot a little more seductively. It is really Troisi who leaves his indelible print on the film, which would be his last (dying tragically the day after production wrapped). The actor's physical frailty comes across as his character's mumbling humility. When beautiful Maria Grazia Cucinotta falls for his charms (or lack thereof), no one would seem more deserving a husband than he, and it is immensely gratifying to see his son Pablito stumble onto screen at the end. Phillipe Noiret also evokes much feeling in the last scene, imagining his friend's great yet fatal agitation for change, while walking their familiar beach. We get the feeling they may have liberated one another. 'Il Postino' is very much a film that flows like poetry. There is no solid structure as prescribed by the script doctors of the time. No stakes and little drama. When our lovable protagonist dies at the end, it is not played for tears of devastation. I felt quiet elation: he had finally found his voice and could speak up for his people at the rally. He asks Neruda earlier in the film a question regarding the writer's revolutionary ideals, "So what if we break off our chains? What do we do then?" He obviously has an answer to that question by the end, which is satisfaction enough. In another exchange, when Mario's plagiarism is discovered by Pablo, he counters "Poetry doesn't belong to those who write it; it belongs to those who need it." This strikes one as quite humorous in the context of the scene but when recalled or read alone it signifies the point at which Mario has cast the chains off his mind. Sadly the distributors do not live by this dictum, and intellectual copyright law prevails online and elsewhere. While it may be a fictional account, the film is very much a celebration of the actual effect Neruda's poetry had on many of the working people of the world. Not so much a tribute to him, but to the millions of postini worldwide who have been delivered and a rallying call for all those who have yet to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Massimo Troisi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    his performance is essence of this adorable film. his character is so careful created that its fragility, humor, innocence, light of details are magnificent. he don't play a role but he is "il postino" . and this fact transforms entire scene. the story of Neruda exile is only arena for emotions of a small man on an Italian isle. the beautiful Beatrice is brick for his delicate happiness. Neruda himself is not exactly a mentor but a gardener. and the music, the extraordinary music, it is the soul of entire poetry. because a poetry is this movie who has as roots poems. very delicate, nice, nostalgic, melancholic, subtle, intelligent, precise, it is wonderful homage to a way to discover life as fundamental miracle. to feel the nuances of love, friendship, to be humble, modest and daring in same time, to feel gratitude as form of respiration. beautiful and impressive. touching. and unique. story of a postman. legacy of Massimo Troisi.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Art and Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gradyharp
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just visited the opera version of this film IL POSTINO by Daniel Catan courtesy of PBS Great Performances it is rewarding to return to the original source to honor the nidus for the inspiration for the opera. Directed by Michael Radford the film relates the heartwarming story of Mario (Massimo Troisi), a gentle and simple postman who falls for the beautiful caf&eacute; waitress Beatrice (Maria Grazia Cucinotta) from his village, but is too shy to speak to her. He meets the famous Chilean poet Pablo Neruda (Phillipe Noiret), and, as their friendship develops, the postman's own inner poet awakens. Soon he is able to win the love of Beatrice and even stand up for and express his own beliefs. This is a simple story graced by sensitive performances: of not the actor Massimo Trosi died from heart failure on the last day of production of the film. It is possibly this knowledge of the loss of one of Italy's best comedic actors along with the clarity and transparency of the film's gentle message about love and art that has made it a cult film. At any rate this is a film that belongs in every movie lover's library. Grady Harp
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great cinematography, good acting by Trosi, but Neruda comes out the loser here.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    felixoteiza
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is actually an Italian fairy tale, one where Neruda is little more than a simple enabler for two lovebirds. The story of a humble, uneducated, man who conquers the heart of a girl with words borrowed, or stolen, from the great poet. Nothing wrong with that, except that this Master of Words proves at the end to be very flawed, unworthy of the worshiping he's the object of-but more of that later. Decent acting overall, breathtaking scenerythose postcard coastal natural settings are also common in Neruda's Chilebut the writing lets a lot to be desired, with too many schmaltzy scenes & dialogs and assorted clich&eacute; situations. Not surprise then that he plot loses its breath half way, when the lovebirds get married and Pablo returns to Chile. What is left then is the same thing we had at the beginning: the daily routines of a small fishing town in southern Italy. Will that be enough to carry the rest of the movie? Don't think so. This isn't Amacord or IVitelloni, as the whole plot was resting on the relationship Neruda--Mario and so when that comes to an end the movie is left gasping for air, begging for some emotional filling as a replacement. With the poet gone and the romance morphed into routine, all what's left for Mario are unfulfilled family obligations and a constant moping for the absent Master. There is an obvious plot discontinuity when both men separate, perhaps because this script was made sewing up two original stories, set in different places at different times. Sure enough, Neruda was in exile in Italy after having fled Chile in 1949, when the Chilean government started jailing Communists, despite them being part of the governing coalition (!) after being pressured by the Yankees, who had started their own witch hunt. (it's hard to believe, but the reason why communists were hunted down was because Chile's president was afraid of it being considered unfriendly by the U.S and risk losing trade, diplomatic and political benefits). Neruda escaped to Argentina & then to Italy, where he was well received thanks to the work made on Italian public opinion by fellow communist Alberto Moravia. On the other hand, the story of him befriending a postman and writing him poems dedicated to his love interest comes from Antonio Skarmeta's Ardiente Paciencia, set in Chile in the 60s, in the coastal town of Isla Negra, where Neruda had a cottage (which is now a museum). So, this is really a Chilean story transposed to Italy, which may explain the awkward plot situation produced when Neruda leaves. Now, Noiret may be a great actor but he makes a disfavor to Neruda with his work here, at least in 2 instances. First, when he's back in Chile he forgets about Mario and doesn't even answer his mail. The real Neruda would have never done that, because for him friendship and loyalty were two things intrinsically tied to class struggle and political commitment. For him all communists--and all members of the working class-were his brothers whatever may have been their countries of origin or their educational level, and all right wingers and rich people in general his enemies, as for him there was no middle ground at that. In real life he would have never acted like he does with Mario, just because he's a less educated man. At least he would have sent him a postcard. The 2nd thing is you would have never caught him in church, let alone crossing himself, as he was an atheist who had no use for religions or for any organized church and the only people in that realm for whom he ever came to feel any respect at all were the Quakers, just because they helped pay for travel tickets to Chile for thousands of Spaniards fleeing their civil war. It's obvious that both misrepresentations have been committed to keep the plot going, which I can understand, but the record must be set straight anyway. Anyway, IP can be very touching the first time you see it, but it goes losing its emotional punch with time, as there's no much left to get hold of after the thrill of the love story and that of the beautiful words wears off. But worse is the portrayal of Neruda as a snob; an hypocrite who'll be nice to the locals as long as he needs them but who'll forget them as soon as he's gone. I'm all for artistic licenses, but not when they make appear an authentic individual under such an unfavorable and false light. In all, to see maybe a couple of times. Anyway, if you want to see something closer to the real man, watch Skarmeta's Ardiente Paciencia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who Really Wrote the Score?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jacobsencurtis
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Il Postino" is one of my favorite movies. The acting is superb. Massimo Troisi gives a uniquely unforgettable performance, despite his suffering from a fatal illness during filming. Phillipe Noiret, as Pablo Neruda, the Chilean poet-in-exile who befriends Mario (Troisi), gives one of his most memorable performances. The location is enchanting. I love all things Italian. Even a bad movie set in Italy is better for it having been shot there. Some of my favorites are "Enchanted April," "Summertime," and "Roman Holiday." And I love the score, which, until tonight, I assumed was written by Luis Bacalov, who is credited in the movie. But I just watched a movie from 1940 called "Dispatch from Reuters," a bio-pic starring Edward G. Robinson, and darned if the main theme from "Il Postino" isn't straight out of "Dispatch from Reuters." By the way, the music for "Reuters" was composed by the great Max Steiner, who, to my knowledge, received no screen credit in "Il Postino." How is this possible? Has the copyright expired rendering the music part of the public domain?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mundane
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike B
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I found this rather superficial and mundane. It's about the friendship between a worker  a postman - and a poet  Pablo Neruda. The poet awakens the young man's sensibilities and gives him the courage to pursue the village beauty. This is a tiny village - so why he had not realized her beauty before, and more so, why she was not being pursued by an entire flock of young men raised a question mark. The characters are all stereo-typed  the shy postman, the over-wordy poet and the village beauty with her raspy aunt. Everything was a caricature and the film suffered from a lack of passion, intensityI couldn't buy into it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice try, but not quite what I expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only heard of this movie on the TV game show 'Who Wants to be a Millionaire?'. The question was which one of 4 mentioned actors starred in the films 'Nuovo Cinema Paradiso' and 'Il Postino'. I hadn't heard of 'Il Postino' before, but I knew that Philippe Noiret stars in 'Nuovo Cinema Paradiso', so I already knew the answer. The presenter recommended the person who wrongly answered the question to watch these 2 movies because something changes inside us once we get to see these 2 films. Then I did research on this motion-picture. It sounded promising, even more so by being foreign. I also got to know the sad story of Massimo Troisi, who played the title's postman (Pablo Neruda's postman). The man suffered from heart disease since a long time ago. He knew about his fragile heart condition and knew he needed treatment, but despite this he wanted to do the movie anyway. He even postponed heart surgery so that he could complete the film. That was a brave move. And he did manage to finish the movie just in time. Only 12 hours after completing the film he died of heart attack. You can say that he gave his life to make this film. Massimo Troisi is great as Mario Ruoppolo, the postman. But it's also sad to see him in this film because we are looking at a man who was dying while making it and that he died almost immediately after completing it. Phillipe Noiret is great as the chilean poet Pablo Neruda. While Pablo Neruda existed for real, his friendship with the postman didn't. But I don't know if a postman named Mario Ruoppolo existed in real life or not and if he was Pablo Neruda's postman or not. The film's got beautiful cinematography and soundtrack, which gives it more emotion and beauty. The plot is, in concept, good. But the movie itself lacks something (perhaps more emotion is one of those things it lacks) and is even a little too-slow paced. It's not a bad movie. It's interesting, moving, pretty to view... a good attempt, just not quite top material. It just isn't as great as it reputation suggests (with, of course, all due respect in memory of our friend Massimo Troisi).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engrossing character study about two men and their connections to two separate women, as well as the poetry that forms the core of their own friendship.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Radford's tender and rather sweet film, The Postman, is a really quite blinding tale of a man, without either much of a life or very many happenings in and around his existence, going out of his way so as to spawn some. The film is a ground zero character study working its way up, centring on one man and coming to gloriously flesh out his relationships with two people in the form of a mentor and a love interest using the item of poetry, and poets in particular, as a focal point or anchor around which to revolve the ever shifting lives of these half a dozen-or so people. The central character is a certain young man named Mario Ruoppolo, played by Italian actor Massimo Troisi whom died shortly after the film was completed and is one of only seven people to have won a Posthumous Academy Award for acting, which he won for his portrayal of a character named Mario. His life in the early part of the 20th Century on an island off the coast of Italy lies seemingly dormant; a living with his father, whom spends his days at sea fishing for a living, whilst inhabiting a scruffy and run down house on the cliff-side which cannot even produce water from a tap when desired, the situation; with a postcard from some brothers whom have arrived in America offering a brief insight into a supposedly better life. Determined to get on track, the softly spoken; delicate and slow moving Mario shifts off to a local post office so as to apply for the advertised job of delivering letters and mail, locally. On another tangent, that later will become intrinsically linked to that of Mario, a controversial poet from South American nation Chile of true to life existence named Pablo Neruda (Noiret) arrives in Italy having been exiled. His demeanour arrives by way of a newsreel sequence at a picture house, footage which the locals and us watch and listen to simultaneously establishing a set-persona of the man and his controversial, Communist infused existence of writing poetry crash-landing on this small Italian island, much to some of the locals' anger but to the glee of others. The early perceptions of the man are meant to be relatively concrete; he inhabits a beautifully placed but isolated red-washed villa on a separate cliff edge, before plodding Mario comes to form a bond with the poet upon delivering his many letters and from whence the film garners its catalyst so as to play out. The film comes to form a learning process for that of Mario, a deconstruction of an item or art-form that he'd almost certainly heard of in the past but very rarely thought about above a certain level. The same can be said for that of Chilian poet Neruda in regards to the fondness and acceptance the town come to have of him after he and his wife and their bond with a number of people come to forge, a relationship much richer than what he has experienced back home or, you feel, in most other places. Romance appears to want to bloom between Mario and local girl Beatrice (Cucinotta), the daughter of a traditional, hard-up Catholic woman whom owns a tavern within the vicinity; the spying of her playing a game of rather erotically charged flick-rod football in said tavern complete with thrusting of the mannequin players and hammering home of the goals more than enough to have Mario smitten from then on in. But the film is ultimately about the relationship or bond between two men going on around their separate relationships with Beatrice and Pablo's own female partner whom later becomes his wife. It would be untrue to say that the film at all feels less of an accomplishment when certain events transpire and the once central unification of Mario and Pablo is broken up; rather, the ties they have to one another during the film's early scenes are just more interesting, as is the chilling finale involving the two, than any sub-plot to do with either men and what happens between them and their women. Mario's attempts to court a young local girl and the noticeable placing of Pablo's own female partner predominantly off screen and away from the action for most of the time might render the relationship between Mario and Pablo one of a homo-erotic nature. Much later on, a Paris based interview with the poet some years later has Mario read on with keen interest as to whether he or anyone from the town are mentioned; the camera darting around from face to face of those reading with Mario in a kind of panic or nervous excitement or lusting requirement for purifying fulfilment in the form of notifying them, predominantly the notifying of Mario. The convenience in having come to have known a master of poetry of a romantic sort, somebody that feeds off of a belief that all women love romantic poetry and that it is the key to pertaining to a relationship, works very much in Mario's favour. His gradual learning of how to construct it, the encountering of terms and words such as what a metaphor is gradually come to form the nucleus of the first half of the film; a fitting sequence on a nearby beach sees Pablo gradually reveal himself as he readies to swim in a physical sense as Mario comes to reveal a spoken metaphor for the very first time as, on another occasion, he gradually forms an opinion of a short poem Pablo comes up with on the spot. The film's attention to finer things such as these, an including of sequences in which characters must first come to master the basics of an art or activity so as to garner entry onto another plateau so as to put what has been learnt into action, feels wonderfully prominent, resulting in Radford's film being thoroughly worthwhile.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    magnificent masterpiece of Michael with two marvelous metaphors --the poet(Pablo) and the postman(Mario)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    superdirector007
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    what a magnificent movie, legendary work by Michael Redford , everything about this movie is beautiful ,,winning Oscar does not come in easy way ,,be it budget,,cinematography covering island's natural beauty ,,specially sea settings ,humourous dialogs with utmost simplicity and realistic performances by actors ,everything is admirable. sometimes you do not plan to make a great movie with highly perfection attitude but movie becomes and gets applauded ,,same happened with this movie,what i believe what is metaphor Mario asks Pablo says-like sky is weeping what does it mean Mario says means to say sky is raining Mario's response it's complicated and Pablo's response that complication does not have to do anything with person's emotions very meaningful and soulful dialogs ,that is the reason movie does not become boring end of the movie is very surprising ,it keeps you involve in the movie movie was shot on the island near by Meditteranean sea and every time tides go and again come to touch coastal areas that resembles one excellent scene goes with the hope to come with another lovely scene filled with emotional and heart touching dialogs to touch your heart movie is pretty simple but can you predict what's gonna happen in next scene ,probably not ,it has certain surprising elements this movie is not a movie this is everlasting experience to live with and cherish it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    United in Friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although "Il Postino" simply means "The Postman", and although the film was at one time screened as "The Postman" in Britain, it is now generally known in English by its&nbsp;Italian title to avoid confusion with Kevin Costner's post-apocalyptic epic from three years later. It is loosely based upon the novel&nbsp;"Ardiente paciencia"&nbsp;by&nbsp;the Chilean&nbsp;writer Antonio Sk&aacute;rmeta, although it transfers the action from Chile to Italy. It takes as its starting-point the fact that in the early 1950s the famous&nbsp;Chilean&nbsp;poet&nbsp;Pablo Neruda, in exile from his homeland for political reasons, spent some time on the island of Capri. The film, however, is not set on Capri but on an unnamed Italian island. A young fisherman named Mario Ruoppolo applies for a job as the island's postman. As he owns a bicycle and is one of the very few islanders who can read and write he is accepted and is told that he will only have one customer, Neruda himself, as because of the low levels of literacy on the island nobody else ever receives any mail. (Were standards of education really so low in fifties Italy?) Although Mario has never previously heard of Neruda, and certainly has never read any of his poems, a friendship gradually grows up between the two men. Although Mario has had little formal education he is clearly an intelligent and sensitive man, and Neruda reads him some of his poetry (in Italian translation), teaching him about literary concepts such as metaphors. With Neruda's help Mario&nbsp;woos the beautiful Beatrice, a village girl with whom he has&nbsp;fallen in love, stealing some of the older man's love poems and passing them off as his own in order to win her affections. My one criticism of the film would be that it is too sentimental about Communism, but that is perhaps only to be expected of a film from Italy, a country which at one time had the largest Communist Party in Western Europe. (In the seventies they used to win around a third of the popular vote, at a time when the British Communist Party generally consisted of three old men and a dog). Pablo Neruda is here portrayed as a kindly, idealistic gentleman, but in reality, during the forties and early fifties, he was a Communist hardliner who enthusiastically defended Stalin's dictatorship in the Soviet Union. After Khrushchev's 1956 "secret speech" he was to criticise the Stalinist cult of personality but this was due less to a change of heart than to a desire to align himself with the new official Soviet party line. He was also, at the time of his Italian exile, around twenty years younger than the character portrayed here by Philippe Noiret. Its politics aside, however, "Il Postino" is in many ways an excellent film. There is some attractive photography of the Italian coastal scenery and a great musical score by Luis Enr&iacute;quez Bacalov. What really makes the film stand out, however, are the two great performances from Noiret and from Massimo Troisi, who tragically died of a heart attack soon afterwards, as Mario. There is also a good performance from the lovely Maria Grazia Cucinotta as Beatrice. Troisi received a posthumous Oscar nomination for "Best Actor", but lost out to Nicholas Cage in "Leaving Las Vegas"; as I have never seen that film I am unable to comment on the justice of that decision. I felt, however, that it was unfortunate that there was no nomination for Noiret either as "Best Actor" or "Best Supporting Actor". Indeed, this is one of those films which make me feel that it should be possible to nominate two actors for a joint award, as Noiret and Troisi combine together so well that their joint contribution seems greater than the sum of its two parts. This is the story of a touching relationship between two men of different generations, of different nationalities, of different levels of education and of&nbsp;different outlooks on life who are nevertheless united in friendship. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The deliverance of one man of letters by another is a cinematic love letter to poetry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edantheman
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Chilean poet and communist agitator Pablo Neruda may never have set foot on the island of Salina in 1950, but writer-actor Mariamo Troisi's exploration of the idea is probably more interesting than any account of his actual exiles abroad. The eponymous postman of the film, Mario, has never taken to the patrilineal profession of fishing in his family. His widower father understands he never will and releases his seemingly simple son from his duties, to choose an occupation more suited to his abilities. In town, the communist postmaster needs a hand with the flurry of fan mail in the wake of Neruda and his wife's arrival. He greatly admires the Bolivarian bard and has his new postman run reconnaissance and procure signatures from him. Though their early exchanges may be of little significance, the two very different men of letters soon form a bond through a series of exchanges on poetry, love and politics. When Mario first meets barmaid Beatrice Russo over a game of table football, he instantly falls in love. He is inspired by his mentor to write her love poems, many of which he plagiarizes, and soon wins her heart. Michael Radford's surname may seem a little consonant-heavy for a production of this origin but the writer-director's English eye can only be clearly detected in the humour of the pacey, racy table football scene; which a native or continental director may have shot a little more seductively. It is really Troisi who leaves his indelible print on the film, which would be his last (dying tragically the day after production wrapped). The actor's physical frailty comes across as his character's mumbling humility. When beautiful Maria Grazia Cucinotta falls for his charms (or lack thereof), no one would seem more deserving a husband than he, and it is immensely gratifying to see his son Pablito stumble onto screen at the end. Phillipe Noiret also evokes much feeling in the last scene, imagining his friend's great yet fatal agitation for change, while walking their familiar beach. We get the feeling they may have liberated one another. 'Il Postino' is very much a film that flows like poetry. There is no solid structure as prescribed by the script doctors of the time. No stakes and little drama. When our lovable protagonist dies at the end, it is not played for tears of devastation. I felt quiet elation: he had finally found his voice and could speak up for his people at the rally. He asks Neruda earlier in the film a question regarding the writer's revolutionary ideals, "So what if we break off our chains? What do we do then?" He obviously has an answer to that question by the end, which is satisfaction enough. In another exchange, when Mario's plagiarism is discovered by Pablo, he counters "Poetry doesn't belong to those who write it; it belongs to those who need it." This strikes one as quite humorous in the context of the scene but when recalled or read alone it signifies the point at which Mario has cast the chains off his mind. Sadly the distributors do not live by this dictum, and intellectual copyright law prevails online and elsewhere. While it may be a fictional account, the film is very much a celebration of the actual effect Neruda's poetry had on many of the working people of the world. Not so much a tribute to him, but to the millions of postini worldwide who have been delivered and a rallying call for all those who have yet to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Massimo Troisi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    his performance is essence of this adorable film. his character is so careful created that its fragility, humor, innocence, light of details are magnificent. he don't play a role but he is "il postino" . and this fact transforms entire scene. the story of Neruda exile is only arena for emotions of a small man on an Italian isle. the beautiful Beatrice is brick for his delicate happiness. Neruda himself is not exactly a mentor but a gardener. and the music, the extraordinary music, it is the soul of entire poetry. because a poetry is this movie who has as roots poems. very delicate, nice, nostalgic, melancholic, subtle, intelligent, precise, it is wonderful homage to a way to discover life as fundamental miracle. to feel the nuances of love, friendship, to be humble, modest and daring in same time, to feel gratitude as form of respiration. beautiful and impressive. touching. and unique. story of a postman. legacy of Massimo Troisi.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Art and Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gradyharp
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just visited the opera version of this film IL POSTINO by Daniel Catan courtesy of PBS Great Performances it is rewarding to return to the original source to honor the nidus for the inspiration for the opera. Directed by Michael Radford the film relates the heartwarming story of Mario (Massimo Troisi), a gentle and simple postman who falls for the beautiful caf&eacute; waitress Beatrice (Maria Grazia Cucinotta) from his village, but is too shy to speak to her. He meets the famous Chilean poet Pablo Neruda (Phillipe Noiret), and, as their friendship develops, the postman's own inner poet awakens. Soon he is able to win the love of Beatrice and even stand up for and express his own beliefs. This is a simple story graced by sensitive performances: of not the actor Massimo Trosi died from heart failure on the last day of production of the film. It is possibly this knowledge of the loss of one of Italy's best comedic actors along with the clarity and transparency of the film's gentle message about love and art that has made it a cult film. At any rate this is a film that belongs in every movie lover's library. Grady Harp
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great cinematography, good acting by Trosi, but Neruda comes out the loser here.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    felixoteiza
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is actually an Italian fairy tale, one where Neruda is little more than a simple enabler for two lovebirds. The story of a humble, uneducated, man who conquers the heart of a girl with words borrowed, or stolen, from the great poet. Nothing wrong with that, except that this Master of Words proves at the end to be very flawed, unworthy of the worshiping he's the object of-but more of that later. Decent acting overall, breathtaking scenerythose postcard coastal natural settings are also common in Neruda's Chilebut the writing lets a lot to be desired, with too many schmaltzy scenes & dialogs and assorted clich&eacute; situations. Not surprise then that he plot loses its breath half way, when the lovebirds get married and Pablo returns to Chile. What is left then is the same thing we had at the beginning: the daily routines of a small fishing town in southern Italy. Will that be enough to carry the rest of the movie? Don't think so. This isn't Amacord or IVitelloni, as the whole plot was resting on the relationship Neruda--Mario and so when that comes to an end the movie is left gasping for air, begging for some emotional filling as a replacement. With the poet gone and the romance morphed into routine, all what's left for Mario are unfulfilled family obligations and a constant moping for the absent Master. There is an obvious plot discontinuity when both men separate, perhaps because this script was made sewing up two original stories, set in different places at different times. Sure enough, Neruda was in exile in Italy after having fled Chile in 1949, when the Chilean government started jailing Communists, despite them being part of the governing coalition (!) after being pressured by the Yankees, who had started their own witch hunt. (it's hard to believe, but the reason why communists were hunted down was because Chile's president was afraid of it being considered unfriendly by the U.S and risk losing trade, diplomatic and political benefits). Neruda escaped to Argentina & then to Italy, where he was well received thanks to the work made on Italian public opinion by fellow communist Alberto Moravia. On the other hand, the story of him befriending a postman and writing him poems dedicated to his love interest comes from Antonio Skarmeta's Ardiente Paciencia, set in Chile in the 60s, in the coastal town of Isla Negra, where Neruda had a cottage (which is now a museum). So, this is really a Chilean story transposed to Italy, which may explain the awkward plot situation produced when Neruda leaves. Now, Noiret may be a great actor but he makes a disfavor to Neruda with his work here, at least in 2 instances. First, when he's back in Chile he forgets about Mario and doesn't even answer his mail. The real Neruda would have never done that, because for him friendship and loyalty were two things intrinsically tied to class struggle and political commitment. For him all communists--and all members of the working class-were his brothers whatever may have been their countries of origin or their educational level, and all right wingers and rich people in general his enemies, as for him there was no middle ground at that. In real life he would have never acted like he does with Mario, just because he's a less educated man. At least he would have sent him a postcard. The 2nd thing is you would have never caught him in church, let alone crossing himself, as he was an atheist who had no use for religions or for any organized church and the only people in that realm for whom he ever came to feel any respect at all were the Quakers, just because they helped pay for travel tickets to Chile for thousands of Spaniards fleeing their civil war. It's obvious that both misrepresentations have been committed to keep the plot going, which I can understand, but the record must be set straight anyway. Anyway, IP can be very touching the first time you see it, but it goes losing its emotional punch with time, as there's no much left to get hold of after the thrill of the love story and that of the beautiful words wears off. But worse is the portrayal of Neruda as a snob; an hypocrite who'll be nice to the locals as long as he needs them but who'll forget them as soon as he's gone. I'm all for artistic licenses, but not when they make appear an authentic individual under such an unfavorable and false light. In all, to see maybe a couple of times. Anyway, if you want to see something closer to the real man, watch Skarmeta's Ardiente Paciencia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who Really Wrote the Score?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jacobsencurtis
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Il Postino" is one of my favorite movies. The acting is superb. Massimo Troisi gives a uniquely unforgettable performance, despite his suffering from a fatal illness during filming. Phillipe Noiret, as Pablo Neruda, the Chilean poet-in-exile who befriends Mario (Troisi), gives one of his most memorable performances. The location is enchanting. I love all things Italian. Even a bad movie set in Italy is better for it having been shot there. Some of my favorites are "Enchanted April," "Summertime," and "Roman Holiday." And I love the score, which, until tonight, I assumed was written by Luis Bacalov, who is credited in the movie. But I just watched a movie from 1940 called "Dispatch from Reuters," a bio-pic starring Edward G. Robinson, and darned if the main theme from "Il Postino" isn't straight out of "Dispatch from Reuters." By the way, the music for "Reuters" was composed by the great Max Steiner, who, to my knowledge, received no screen credit in "Il Postino." How is this possible? Has the copyright expired rendering the music part of the public domain?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mundane
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike B
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I found this rather superficial and mundane. It's about the friendship between a worker  a postman - and a poet  Pablo Neruda. The poet awakens the young man's sensibilities and gives him the courage to pursue the village beauty. This is a tiny village - so why he had not realized her beauty before, and more so, why she was not being pursued by an entire flock of young men raised a question mark. The characters are all stereo-typed  the shy postman, the over-wordy poet and the village beauty with her raspy aunt. Everything was a caricature and the film suffered from a lack of passion, intensityI couldn't buy into it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice try, but not quite what I expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only heard of this movie on the TV game show 'Who Wants to be a Millionaire?'. The question was which one of 4 mentioned actors starred in the films 'Nuovo Cinema Paradiso' and 'Il Postino'. I hadn't heard of 'Il Postino' before, but I knew that Philippe Noiret stars in 'Nuovo Cinema Paradiso', so I already knew the answer. The presenter recommended the person who wrongly answered the question to watch these 2 movies because something changes inside us once we get to see these 2 films. Then I did research on this motion-picture. It sounded promising, even more so by being foreign. I also got to know the sad story of Massimo Troisi, who played the title's postman (Pablo Neruda's postman). The man suffered from heart disease since a long time ago. He knew about his fragile heart condition and knew he needed treatment, but despite this he wanted to do the movie anyway. He even postponed heart surgery so that he could complete the film. That was a brave move. And he did manage to finish the movie just in time. Only 12 hours after completing the film he died of heart attack. You can say that he gave his life to make this film. Massimo Troisi is great as Mario Ruoppolo, the postman. But it's also sad to see him in this film because we are looking at a man who was dying while making it and that he died almost immediately after completing it. Phillipe Noiret is great as the chilean poet Pablo Neruda. While Pablo Neruda existed for real, his friendship with the postman didn't. But I don't know if a postman named Mario Ruoppolo existed in real life or not and if he was Pablo Neruda's postman or not. The film's got beautiful cinematography and soundtrack, which gives it more emotion and beauty. The plot is, in concept, good. But the movie itself lacks something (perhaps more emotion is one of those things it lacks) and is even a little too-slow paced. It's not a bad movie. It's interesting, moving, pretty to view... a good attempt, just not quite top material. It just isn't as great as it reputation suggests (with, of course, all due respect in memory of our friend Massimo Troisi).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engrossing character study about two men and their connections to two separate women, as well as the poetry that forms the core of their own friendship.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Radford's tender and rather sweet film, The Postman, is a really quite blinding tale of a man, without either much of a life or very many happenings in and around his existence, going out of his way so as to spawn some. The film is a ground zero character study working its way up, centring on one man and coming to gloriously flesh out his relationships with two people in the form of a mentor and a love interest using the item of poetry, and poets in particular, as a focal point or anchor around which to revolve the ever shifting lives of these half a dozen-or so people. The central character is a certain young man named Mario Ruoppolo, played by Italian actor Massimo Troisi whom died shortly after the film was completed and is one of only seven people to have won a Posthumous Academy Award for acting, which he won for his portrayal of a character named Mario. His life in the early part of the 20th Century on an island off the coast of Italy lies seemingly dormant; a living with his father, whom spends his days at sea fishing for a living, whilst inhabiting a scruffy and run down house on the cliff-side which cannot even produce water from a tap when desired, the situation; with a postcard from some brothers whom have arrived in America offering a brief insight into a supposedly better life. Determined to get on track, the softly spoken; delicate and slow moving Mario shifts off to a local post office so as to apply for the advertised job of delivering letters and mail, locally. On another tangent, that later will become intrinsically linked to that of Mario, a controversial poet from South American nation Chile of true to life existence named Pablo Neruda (Noiret) arrives in Italy having been exiled. His demeanour arrives by way of a newsreel sequence at a picture house, footage which the locals and us watch and listen to simultaneously establishing a set-persona of the man and his controversial, Communist infused existence of writing poetry crash-landing on this small Italian island, much to some of the locals' anger but to the glee of others. The early perceptions of the man are meant to be relatively concrete; he inhabits a beautifully placed but isolated red-washed villa on a separate cliff edge, before plodding Mario comes to form a bond with the poet upon delivering his many letters and from whence the film garners its catalyst so as to play out. The film comes to form a learning process for that of Mario, a deconstruction of an item or art-form that he'd almost certainly heard of in the past but very rarely thought about above a certain level. The same can be said for that of Chilian poet Neruda in regards to the fondness and acceptance the town come to have of him after he and his wife and their bond with a number of people come to forge, a relationship much richer than what he has experienced back home or, you feel, in most other places. Romance appears to want to bloom between Mario and local girl Beatrice (Cucinotta), the daughter of a traditional, hard-up Catholic woman whom owns a tavern within the vicinity; the spying of her playing a game of rather erotically charged flick-rod football in said tavern complete with thrusting of the mannequin players and hammering home of the goals more than enough to have Mario smitten from then on in. But the film is ultimately about the relationship or bond between two men going on around their separate relationships with Beatrice and Pablo's own female partner whom later becomes his wife. It would be untrue to say that the film at all feels less of an accomplishment when certain events transpire and the once central unification of Mario and Pablo is broken up; rather, the ties they have to one another during the film's early scenes are just more interesting, as is the chilling finale involving the two, than any sub-plot to do with either men and what happens between them and their women. Mario's attempts to court a young local girl and the noticeable placing of Pablo's own female partner predominantly off screen and away from the action for most of the time might render the relationship between Mario and Pablo one of a homo-erotic nature. Much later on, a Paris based interview with the poet some years later has Mario read on with keen interest as to whether he or anyone from the town are mentioned; the camera darting around from face to face of those reading with Mario in a kind of panic or nervous excitement or lusting requirement for purifying fulfilment in the form of notifying them, predominantly the notifying of Mario. The convenience in having come to have known a master of poetry of a romantic sort, somebody that feeds off of a belief that all women love romantic poetry and that it is the key to pertaining to a relationship, works very much in Mario's favour. His gradual learning of how to construct it, the encountering of terms and words such as what a metaphor is gradually come to form the nucleus of the first half of the film; a fitting sequence on a nearby beach sees Pablo gradually reveal himself as he readies to swim in a physical sense as Mario comes to reveal a spoken metaphor for the very first time as, on another occasion, he gradually forms an opinion of a short poem Pablo comes up with on the spot. The film's attention to finer things such as these, an including of sequences in which characters must first come to master the basics of an art or activity so as to garner entry onto another plateau so as to put what has been learnt into action, feels wonderfully prominent, resulting in Radford's film being thoroughly worthwhile.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    magnificent masterpiece of Michael with two marvelous metaphors --the poet(Pablo) and the postman(Mario)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    superdirector007
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    what a magnificent movie, legendary work by Michael Redford , everything about this movie is beautiful ,,winning Oscar does not come in easy way ,,be it budget,,cinematography covering island's natural beauty ,,specially sea settings ,humourous dialogs with utmost simplicity and realistic performances by actors ,everything is admirable. sometimes you do not plan to make a great movie with highly perfection attitude but movie becomes and gets applauded ,,same happened with this movie,what i believe what is metaphor Mario asks Pablo says-like sky is weeping what does it mean Mario says means to say sky is raining Mario's response it's complicated and Pablo's response that complication does not have to do anything with person's emotions very meaningful and soulful dialogs ,that is the reason movie does not become boring end of the movie is very surprising ,it keeps you involve in the movie movie was shot on the island near by Meditteranean sea and every time tides go and again come to touch coastal areas that resembles one excellent scene goes with the hope to come with another lovely scene filled with emotional and heart touching dialogs to touch your heart movie is pretty simple but can you predict what's gonna happen in next scene ,probably not ,it has certain surprising elements this movie is not a movie this is everlasting experience to live with and cherish it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    United in Friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although "Il Postino" simply means "The Postman", and although the film was at one time screened as "The Postman" in Britain, it is now generally known in English by its&nbsp;Italian title to avoid confusion with Kevin Costner's post-apocalyptic epic from three years later. It is loosely based upon the novel&nbsp;"Ardiente paciencia"&nbsp;by&nbsp;the Chilean&nbsp;writer Antonio Sk&aacute;rmeta, although it transfers the action from Chile to Italy. It takes as its starting-point the fact that in the early 1950s the famous&nbsp;Chilean&nbsp;poet&nbsp;Pablo Neruda, in exile from his homeland for political reasons, spent some time on the island of Capri. The film, however, is not set on Capri but on an unnamed Italian island. A young fisherman named Mario Ruoppolo applies for a job as the island's postman. As he owns a bicycle and is one of the very few islanders who can read and write he is accepted and is told that he will only have one customer, Neruda himself, as because of the low levels of literacy on the island nobody else ever receives any mail. (Were standards of education really so low in fifties Italy?) Although Mario has never previously heard of Neruda, and certainly has never read any of his poems, a friendship gradually grows up between the two men. Although Mario has had little formal education he is clearly an intelligent and sensitive man, and Neruda reads him some of his poetry (in Italian translation), teaching him about literary concepts such as metaphors. With Neruda's help Mario&nbsp;woos the beautiful Beatrice, a village girl with whom he has&nbsp;fallen in love, stealing some of the older man's love poems and passing them off as his own in order to win her affections. My one criticism of the film would be that it is too sentimental about Communism, but that is perhaps only to be expected of a film from Italy, a country which at one time had the largest Communist Party in Western Europe. (In the seventies they used to win around a third of the popular vote, at a time when the British Communist Party generally consisted of three old men and a dog). Pablo Neruda is here portrayed as a kindly, idealistic gentleman, but in reality, during the forties and early fifties, he was a Communist hardliner who enthusiastically defended Stalin's dictatorship in the Soviet Union. After Khrushchev's 1956 "secret speech" he was to criticise the Stalinist cult of personality but this was due less to a change of heart than to a desire to align himself with the new official Soviet party line. He was also, at the time of his Italian exile, around twenty years younger than the character portrayed here by Philippe Noiret. Its politics aside, however, "Il Postino" is in many ways an excellent film. There is some attractive photography of the Italian coastal scenery and a great musical score by Luis Enr&iacute;quez Bacalov. What really makes the film stand out, however, are the two great performances from Noiret and from Massimo Troisi, who tragically died of a heart attack soon afterwards, as Mario. There is also a good performance from the lovely Maria Grazia Cucinotta as Beatrice. Troisi received a posthumous Oscar nomination for "Best Actor", but lost out to Nicholas Cage in "Leaving Las Vegas"; as I have never seen that film I am unable to comment on the justice of that decision. I felt, however, that it was unfortunate that there was no nomination for Noiret either as "Best Actor" or "Best Supporting Actor". Indeed, this is one of those films which make me feel that it should be possible to nominate two actors for a joint award, as Noiret and Troisi combine together so well that their joint contribution seems greater than the sum of its two parts. This is the story of a touching relationship between two men of different generations, of different nationalities, of different levels of education and of&nbsp;different outlooks on life who are nevertheless united in friendship. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The deliverance of one man of letters by another is a cinematic love letter to poetry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edantheman
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Chilean poet and communist agitator Pablo Neruda may never have set foot on the island of Salina in 1950, but writer-actor Mariamo Troisi's exploration of the idea is probably more interesting than any account of his actual exiles abroad. The eponymous postman of the film, Mario, has never taken to the patrilineal profession of fishing in his family. His widower father understands he never will and releases his seemingly simple son from his duties, to choose an occupation more suited to his abilities. In town, the communist postmaster needs a hand with the flurry of fan mail in the wake of Neruda and his wife's arrival. He greatly admires the Bolivarian bard and has his new postman run reconnaissance and procure signatures from him. Though their early exchanges may be of little significance, the two very different men of letters soon form a bond through a series of exchanges on poetry, love and politics. When Mario first meets barmaid Beatrice Russo over a game of table football, he instantly falls in love. He is inspired by his mentor to write her love poems, many of which he plagiarizes, and soon wins her heart. Michael Radford's surname may seem a little consonant-heavy for a production of this origin but the writer-director's English eye can only be clearly detected in the humour of the pacey, racy table football scene; which a native or continental director may have shot a little more seductively. It is really Troisi who leaves his indelible print on the film, which would be his last (dying tragically the day after production wrapped). The actor's physical frailty comes across as his character's mumbling humility. When beautiful Maria Grazia Cucinotta falls for his charms (or lack thereof), no one would seem more deserving a husband than he, and it is immensely gratifying to see his son Pablito stumble onto screen at the end. Phillipe Noiret also evokes much feeling in the last scene, imagining his friend's great yet fatal agitation for change, while walking their familiar beach. We get the feeling they may have liberated one another. 'Il Postino' is very much a film that flows like poetry. There is no solid structure as prescribed by the script doctors of the time. No stakes and little drama. When our lovable protagonist dies at the end, it is not played for tears of devastation. I felt quiet elation: he had finally found his voice and could speak up for his people at the rally. He asks Neruda earlier in the film a question regarding the writer's revolutionary ideals, "So what if we break off our chains? What do we do then?" He obviously has an answer to that question by the end, which is satisfaction enough. In another exchange, when Mario's plagiarism is discovered by Pablo, he counters "Poetry doesn't belong to those who write it; it belongs to those who need it." This strikes one as quite humorous in the context of the scene but when recalled or read alone it signifies the point at which Mario has cast the chains off his mind. Sadly the distributors do not live by this dictum, and intellectual copyright law prevails online and elsewhere. While it may be a fictional account, the film is very much a celebration of the actual effect Neruda's poetry had on many of the working people of the world. Not so much a tribute to him, but to the millions of postini worldwide who have been delivered and a rallying call for all those who have yet to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Massimo Troisi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    his performance is essence of this adorable film. his character is so careful created that its fragility, humor, innocence, light of details are magnificent. he don't play a role but he is "il postino" . and this fact transforms entire scene. the story of Neruda exile is only arena for emotions of a small man on an Italian isle. the beautiful Beatrice is brick for his delicate happiness. Neruda himself is not exactly a mentor but a gardener. and the music, the extraordinary music, it is the soul of entire poetry. because a poetry is this movie who has as roots poems. very delicate, nice, nostalgic, melancholic, subtle, intelligent, precise, it is wonderful homage to a way to discover life as fundamental miracle. to feel the nuances of love, friendship, to be humble, modest and daring in same time, to feel gratitude as form of respiration. beautiful and impressive. touching. and unique. story of a postman. legacy of Massimo Troisi.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Art and Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gradyharp
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just visited the opera version of this film IL POSTINO by Daniel Catan courtesy of PBS Great Performances it is rewarding to return to the original source to honor the nidus for the inspiration for the opera. Directed by Michael Radford the film relates the heartwarming story of Mario (Massimo Troisi), a gentle and simple postman who falls for the beautiful caf&eacute; waitress Beatrice (Maria Grazia Cucinotta) from his village, but is too shy to speak to her. He meets the famous Chilean poet Pablo Neruda (Phillipe Noiret), and, as their friendship develops, the postman's own inner poet awakens. Soon he is able to win the love of Beatrice and even stand up for and express his own beliefs. This is a simple story graced by sensitive performances: of not the actor Massimo Trosi died from heart failure on the last day of production of the film. It is possibly this knowledge of the loss of one of Italy's best comedic actors along with the clarity and transparency of the film's gentle message about love and art that has made it a cult film. At any rate this is a film that belongs in every movie lover's library. Grady Harp
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great cinematography, good acting by Trosi, but Neruda comes out the loser here.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    felixoteiza
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is actually an Italian fairy tale, one where Neruda is little more than a simple enabler for two lovebirds. The story of a humble, uneducated, man who conquers the heart of a girl with words borrowed, or stolen, from the great poet. Nothing wrong with that, except that this Master of Words proves at the end to be very flawed, unworthy of the worshiping he's the object of-but more of that later. Decent acting overall, breathtaking scenerythose postcard coastal natural settings are also common in Neruda's Chilebut the writing lets a lot to be desired, with too many schmaltzy scenes & dialogs and assorted clich&eacute; situations. Not surprise then that he plot loses its breath half way, when the lovebirds get married and Pablo returns to Chile. What is left then is the same thing we had at the beginning: the daily routines of a small fishing town in southern Italy. Will that be enough to carry the rest of the movie? Don't think so. This isn't Amacord or IVitelloni, as the whole plot was resting on the relationship Neruda--Mario and so when that comes to an end the movie is left gasping for air, begging for some emotional filling as a replacement. With the poet gone and the romance morphed into routine, all what's left for Mario are unfulfilled family obligations and a constant moping for the absent Master. There is an obvious plot discontinuity when both men separate, perhaps because this script was made sewing up two original stories, set in different places at different times. Sure enough, Neruda was in exile in Italy after having fled Chile in 1949, when the Chilean government started jailing Communists, despite them being part of the governing coalition (!) after being pressured by the Yankees, who had started their own witch hunt. (it's hard to believe, but the reason why communists were hunted down was because Chile's president was afraid of it being considered unfriendly by the U.S and risk losing trade, diplomatic and political benefits). Neruda escaped to Argentina & then to Italy, where he was well received thanks to the work made on Italian public opinion by fellow communist Alberto Moravia. On the other hand, the story of him befriending a postman and writing him poems dedicated to his love interest comes from Antonio Skarmeta's Ardiente Paciencia, set in Chile in the 60s, in the coastal town of Isla Negra, where Neruda had a cottage (which is now a museum). So, this is really a Chilean story transposed to Italy, which may explain the awkward plot situation produced when Neruda leaves. Now, Noiret may be a great actor but he makes a disfavor to Neruda with his work here, at least in 2 instances. First, when he's back in Chile he forgets about Mario and doesn't even answer his mail. The real Neruda would have never done that, because for him friendship and loyalty were two things intrinsically tied to class struggle and political commitment. For him all communists--and all members of the working class-were his brothers whatever may have been their countries of origin or their educational level, and all right wingers and rich people in general his enemies, as for him there was no middle ground at that. In real life he would have never acted like he does with Mario, just because he's a less educated man. At least he would have sent him a postcard. The 2nd thing is you would have never caught him in church, let alone crossing himself, as he was an atheist who had no use for religions or for any organized church and the only people in that realm for whom he ever came to feel any respect at all were the Quakers, just because they helped pay for travel tickets to Chile for thousands of Spaniards fleeing their civil war. It's obvious that both misrepresentations have been committed to keep the plot going, which I can understand, but the record must be set straight anyway. Anyway, IP can be very touching the first time you see it, but it goes losing its emotional punch with time, as there's no much left to get hold of after the thrill of the love story and that of the beautiful words wears off. But worse is the portrayal of Neruda as a snob; an hypocrite who'll be nice to the locals as long as he needs them but who'll forget them as soon as he's gone. I'm all for artistic licenses, but not when they make appear an authentic individual under such an unfavorable and false light. In all, to see maybe a couple of times. Anyway, if you want to see something closer to the real man, watch Skarmeta's Ardiente Paciencia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who Really Wrote the Score?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jacobsencurtis
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Il Postino" is one of my favorite movies. The acting is superb. Massimo Troisi gives a uniquely unforgettable performance, despite his suffering from a fatal illness during filming. Phillipe Noiret, as Pablo Neruda, the Chilean poet-in-exile who befriends Mario (Troisi), gives one of his most memorable performances. The location is enchanting. I love all things Italian. Even a bad movie set in Italy is better for it having been shot there. Some of my favorites are "Enchanted April," "Summertime," and "Roman Holiday." And I love the score, which, until tonight, I assumed was written by Luis Bacalov, who is credited in the movie. But I just watched a movie from 1940 called "Dispatch from Reuters," a bio-pic starring Edward G. Robinson, and darned if the main theme from "Il Postino" isn't straight out of "Dispatch from Reuters." By the way, the music for "Reuters" was composed by the great Max Steiner, who, to my knowledge, received no screen credit in "Il Postino." How is this possible? Has the copyright expired rendering the music part of the public domain?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mundane
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike B
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I found this rather superficial and mundane. It's about the friendship between a worker  a postman - and a poet  Pablo Neruda. The poet awakens the young man's sensibilities and gives him the courage to pursue the village beauty. This is a tiny village - so why he had not realized her beauty before, and more so, why she was not being pursued by an entire flock of young men raised a question mark. The characters are all stereo-typed  the shy postman, the over-wordy poet and the village beauty with her raspy aunt. Everything was a caricature and the film suffered from a lack of passion, intensityI couldn't buy into it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice try, but not quite what I expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only heard of this movie on the TV game show 'Who Wants to be a Millionaire?'. The question was which one of 4 mentioned actors starred in the films 'Nuovo Cinema Paradiso' and 'Il Postino'. I hadn't heard of 'Il Postino' before, but I knew that Philippe Noiret stars in 'Nuovo Cinema Paradiso', so I already knew the answer. The presenter recommended the person who wrongly answered the question to watch these 2 movies because something changes inside us once we get to see these 2 films. Then I did research on this motion-picture. It sounded promising, even more so by being foreign. I also got to know the sad story of Massimo Troisi, who played the title's postman (Pablo Neruda's postman). The man suffered from heart disease since a long time ago. He knew about his fragile heart condition and knew he needed treatment, but despite this he wanted to do the movie anyway. He even postponed heart surgery so that he could complete the film. That was a brave move. And he did manage to finish the movie just in time. Only 12 hours after completing the film he died of heart attack. You can say that he gave his life to make this film. Massimo Troisi is great as Mario Ruoppolo, the postman. But it's also sad to see him in this film because we are looking at a man who was dying while making it and that he died almost immediately after completing it. Phillipe Noiret is great as the chilean poet Pablo Neruda. While Pablo Neruda existed for real, his friendship with the postman didn't. But I don't know if a postman named Mario Ruoppolo existed in real life or not and if he was Pablo Neruda's postman or not. The film's got beautiful cinematography and soundtrack, which gives it more emotion and beauty. The plot is, in concept, good. But the movie itself lacks something (perhaps more emotion is one of those things it lacks) and is even a little too-slow paced. It's not a bad movie. It's interesting, moving, pretty to view... a good attempt, just not quite top material. It just isn't as great as it reputation suggests (with, of course, all due respect in memory of our friend Massimo Troisi).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engrossing character study about two men and their connections to two separate women, as well as the poetry that forms the core of their own friendship.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Radford's tender and rather sweet film, The Postman, is a really quite blinding tale of a man, without either much of a life or very many happenings in and around his existence, going out of his way so as to spawn some. The film is a ground zero character study working its way up, centring on one man and coming to gloriously flesh out his relationships with two people in the form of a mentor and a love interest using the item of poetry, and poets in particular, as a focal point or anchor around which to revolve the ever shifting lives of these half a dozen-or so people. The central character is a certain young man named Mario Ruoppolo, played by Italian actor Massimo Troisi whom died shortly after the film was completed and is one of only seven people to have won a Posthumous Academy Award for acting, which he won for his portrayal of a character named Mario. His life in the early part of the 20th Century on an island off the coast of Italy lies seemingly dormant; a living with his father, whom spends his days at sea fishing for a living, whilst inhabiting a scruffy and run down house on the cliff-side which cannot even produce water from a tap when desired, the situation; with a postcard from some brothers whom have arrived in America offering a brief insight into a supposedly better life. Determined to get on track, the softly spoken; delicate and slow moving Mario shifts off to a local post office so as to apply for the advertised job of delivering letters and mail, locally. On another tangent, that later will become intrinsically linked to that of Mario, a controversial poet from South American nation Chile of true to life existence named Pablo Neruda (Noiret) arrives in Italy having been exiled. His demeanour arrives by way of a newsreel sequence at a picture house, footage which the locals and us watch and listen to simultaneously establishing a set-persona of the man and his controversial, Communist infused existence of writing poetry crash-landing on this small Italian island, much to some of the locals' anger but to the glee of others. The early perceptions of the man are meant to be relatively concrete; he inhabits a beautifully placed but isolated red-washed villa on a separate cliff edge, before plodding Mario comes to form a bond with the poet upon delivering his many letters and from whence the film garners its catalyst so as to play out. The film comes to form a learning process for that of Mario, a deconstruction of an item or art-form that he'd almost certainly heard of in the past but very rarely thought about above a certain level. The same can be said for that of Chilian poet Neruda in regards to the fondness and acceptance the town come to have of him after he and his wife and their bond with a number of people come to forge, a relationship much richer than what he has experienced back home or, you feel, in most other places. Romance appears to want to bloom between Mario and local girl Beatrice (Cucinotta), the daughter of a traditional, hard-up Catholic woman whom owns a tavern within the vicinity; the spying of her playing a game of rather erotically charged flick-rod football in said tavern complete with thrusting of the mannequin players and hammering home of the goals more than enough to have Mario smitten from then on in. But the film is ultimately about the relationship or bond between two men going on around their separate relationships with Beatrice and Pablo's own female partner whom later becomes his wife. It would be untrue to say that the film at all feels less of an accomplishment when certain events transpire and the once central unification of Mario and Pablo is broken up; rather, the ties they have to one another during the film's early scenes are just more interesting, as is the chilling finale involving the two, than any sub-plot to do with either men and what happens between them and their women. Mario's attempts to court a young local girl and the noticeable placing of Pablo's own female partner predominantly off screen and away from the action for most of the time might render the relationship between Mario and Pablo one of a homo-erotic nature. Much later on, a Paris based interview with the poet some years later has Mario read on with keen interest as to whether he or anyone from the town are mentioned; the camera darting around from face to face of those reading with Mario in a kind of panic or nervous excitement or lusting requirement for purifying fulfilment in the form of notifying them, predominantly the notifying of Mario. The convenience in having come to have known a master of poetry of a romantic sort, somebody that feeds off of a belief that all women love romantic poetry and that it is the key to pertaining to a relationship, works very much in Mario's favour. His gradual learning of how to construct it, the encountering of terms and words such as what a metaphor is gradually come to form the nucleus of the first half of the film; a fitting sequence on a nearby beach sees Pablo gradually reveal himself as he readies to swim in a physical sense as Mario comes to reveal a spoken metaphor for the very first time as, on another occasion, he gradually forms an opinion of a short poem Pablo comes up with on the spot. The film's attention to finer things such as these, an including of sequences in which characters must first come to master the basics of an art or activity so as to garner entry onto another plateau so as to put what has been learnt into action, feels wonderfully prominent, resulting in Radford's film being thoroughly worthwhile.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    magnificent masterpiece of Michael with two marvelous metaphors --the poet(Pablo) and the postman(Mario)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    superdirector007
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    what a magnificent movie, legendary work by Michael Redford , everything about this movie is beautiful ,,winning Oscar does not come in easy way ,,be it budget,,cinematography covering island's natural beauty ,,specially sea settings ,humourous dialogs with utmost simplicity and realistic performances by actors ,everything is admirable. sometimes you do not plan to make a great movie with highly perfection attitude but movie becomes and gets applauded ,,same happened with this movie,what i believe what is metaphor Mario asks Pablo says-like sky is weeping what does it mean Mario says means to say sky is raining Mario's response it's complicated and Pablo's response that complication does not have to do anything with person's emotions very meaningful and soulful dialogs ,that is the reason movie does not become boring end of the movie is very surprising ,it keeps you involve in the movie movie was shot on the island near by Meditteranean sea and every time tides go and again come to touch coastal areas that resembles one excellent scene goes with the hope to come with another lovely scene filled with emotional and heart touching dialogs to touch your heart movie is pretty simple but can you predict what's gonna happen in next scene ,probably not ,it has certain surprising elements this movie is not a movie this is everlasting experience to live with and cherish it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    United in Friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although "Il Postino" simply means "The Postman", and although the film was at one time screened as "The Postman" in Britain, it is now generally known in English by its&nbsp;Italian title to avoid confusion with Kevin Costner's post-apocalyptic epic from three years later. It is loosely based upon the novel&nbsp;"Ardiente paciencia"&nbsp;by&nbsp;the Chilean&nbsp;writer Antonio Sk&aacute;rmeta, although it transfers the action from Chile to Italy. It takes as its starting-point the fact that in the early 1950s the famous&nbsp;Chilean&nbsp;poet&nbsp;Pablo Neruda, in exile from his homeland for political reasons, spent some time on the island of Capri. The film, however, is not set on Capri but on an unnamed Italian island. A young fisherman named Mario Ruoppolo applies for a job as the island's postman. As he owns a bicycle and is one of the very few islanders who can read and write he is accepted and is told that he will only have one customer, Neruda himself, as because of the low levels of literacy on the island nobody else ever receives any mail. (Were standards of education really so low in fifties Italy?) Although Mario has never previously heard of Neruda, and certainly has never read any of his poems, a friendship gradually grows up between the two men. Although Mario has had little formal education he is clearly an intelligent and sensitive man, and Neruda reads him some of his poetry (in Italian translation), teaching him about literary concepts such as metaphors. With Neruda's help Mario&nbsp;woos the beautiful Beatrice, a village girl with whom he has&nbsp;fallen in love, stealing some of the older man's love poems and passing them off as his own in order to win her affections. My one criticism of the film would be that it is too sentimental about Communism, but that is perhaps only to be expected of a film from Italy, a country which at one time had the largest Communist Party in Western Europe. (In the seventies they used to win around a third of the popular vote, at a time when the British Communist Party generally consisted of three old men and a dog). Pablo Neruda is here portrayed as a kindly, idealistic gentleman, but in reality, during the forties and early fifties, he was a Communist hardliner who enthusiastically defended Stalin's dictatorship in the Soviet Union. After Khrushchev's 1956 "secret speech" he was to criticise the Stalinist cult of personality but this was due less to a change of heart than to a desire to align himself with the new official Soviet party line. He was also, at the time of his Italian exile, around twenty years younger than the character portrayed here by Philippe Noiret. Its politics aside, however, "Il Postino" is in many ways an excellent film. There is some attractive photography of the Italian coastal scenery and a great musical score by Luis Enr&iacute;quez Bacalov. What really makes the film stand out, however, are the two great performances from Noiret and from Massimo Troisi, who tragically died of a heart attack soon afterwards, as Mario. There is also a good performance from the lovely Maria Grazia Cucinotta as Beatrice. Troisi received a posthumous Oscar nomination for "Best Actor", but lost out to Nicholas Cage in "Leaving Las Vegas"; as I have never seen that film I am unable to comment on the justice of that decision. I felt, however, that it was unfortunate that there was no nomination for Noiret either as "Best Actor" or "Best Supporting Actor". Indeed, this is one of those films which make me feel that it should be possible to nominate two actors for a joint award, as Noiret and Troisi combine together so well that their joint contribution seems greater than the sum of its two parts. This is the story of a touching relationship between two men of different generations, of different nationalities, of different levels of education and of&nbsp;different outlooks on life who are nevertheless united in friendship. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The deliverance of one man of letters by another is a cinematic love letter to poetry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edantheman
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Chilean poet and communist agitator Pablo Neruda may never have set foot on the island of Salina in 1950, but writer-actor Mariamo Troisi's exploration of the idea is probably more interesting than any account of his actual exiles abroad. The eponymous postman of the film, Mario, has never taken to the patrilineal profession of fishing in his family. His widower father understands he never will and releases his seemingly simple son from his duties, to choose an occupation more suited to his abilities. In town, the communist postmaster needs a hand with the flurry of fan mail in the wake of Neruda and his wife's arrival. He greatly admires the Bolivarian bard and has his new postman run reconnaissance and procure signatures from him. Though their early exchanges may be of little significance, the two very different men of letters soon form a bond through a series of exchanges on poetry, love and politics. When Mario first meets barmaid Beatrice Russo over a game of table football, he instantly falls in love. He is inspired by his mentor to write her love poems, many of which he plagiarizes, and soon wins her heart. Michael Radford's surname may seem a little consonant-heavy for a production of this origin but the writer-director's English eye can only be clearly detected in the humour of the pacey, racy table football scene; which a native or continental director may have shot a little more seductively. It is really Troisi who leaves his indelible print on the film, which would be his last (dying tragically the day after production wrapped). The actor's physical frailty comes across as his character's mumbling humility. When beautiful Maria Grazia Cucinotta falls for his charms (or lack thereof), no one would seem more deserving a husband than he, and it is immensely gratifying to see his son Pablito stumble onto screen at the end. Phillipe Noiret also evokes much feeling in the last scene, imagining his friend's great yet fatal agitation for change, while walking their familiar beach. We get the feeling they may have liberated one another. 'Il Postino' is very much a film that flows like poetry. There is no solid structure as prescribed by the script doctors of the time. No stakes and little drama. When our lovable protagonist dies at the end, it is not played for tears of devastation. I felt quiet elation: he had finally found his voice and could speak up for his people at the rally. He asks Neruda earlier in the film a question regarding the writer's revolutionary ideals, "So what if we break off our chains? What do we do then?" He obviously has an answer to that question by the end, which is satisfaction enough. In another exchange, when Mario's plagiarism is discovered by Pablo, he counters "Poetry doesn't belong to those who write it; it belongs to those who need it." This strikes one as quite humorous in the context of the scene but when recalled or read alone it signifies the point at which Mario has cast the chains off his mind. Sadly the distributors do not live by this dictum, and intellectual copyright law prevails online and elsewhere. While it may be a fictional account, the film is very much a celebration of the actual effect Neruda's poetry had on many of the working people of the world. Not so much a tribute to him, but to the millions of postini worldwide who have been delivered and a rallying call for all those who have yet to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Massimo Troisi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    his performance is essence of this adorable film. his character is so careful created that its fragility, humor, innocence, light of details are magnificent. he don't play a role but he is "il postino" . and this fact transforms entire scene. the story of Neruda exile is only arena for emotions of a small man on an Italian isle. the beautiful Beatrice is brick for his delicate happiness. Neruda himself is not exactly a mentor but a gardener. and the music, the extraordinary music, it is the soul of entire poetry. because a poetry is this movie who has as roots poems. very delicate, nice, nostalgic, melancholic, subtle, intelligent, precise, it is wonderful homage to a way to discover life as fundamental miracle. to feel the nuances of love, friendship, to be humble, modest and daring in same time, to feel gratitude as form of respiration. beautiful and impressive. touching. and unique. story of a postman. legacy of Massimo Troisi.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Art and Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gradyharp
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just visited the opera version of this film IL POSTINO by Daniel Catan courtesy of PBS Great Performances it is rewarding to return to the original source to honor the nidus for the inspiration for the opera. Directed by Michael Radford the film relates the heartwarming story of Mario (Massimo Troisi), a gentle and simple postman who falls for the beautiful caf&eacute; waitress Beatrice (Maria Grazia Cucinotta) from his village, but is too shy to speak to her. He meets the famous Chilean poet Pablo Neruda (Phillipe Noiret), and, as their friendship develops, the postman's own inner poet awakens. Soon he is able to win the love of Beatrice and even stand up for and express his own beliefs. This is a simple story graced by sensitive performances: of not the actor Massimo Trosi died from heart failure on the last day of production of the film. It is possibly this knowledge of the loss of one of Italy's best comedic actors along with the clarity and transparency of the film's gentle message about love and art that has made it a cult film. At any rate this is a film that belongs in every movie lover's library. Grady Harp
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great cinematography, good acting by Trosi, but Neruda comes out the loser here.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    felixoteiza
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is actually an Italian fairy tale, one where Neruda is little more than a simple enabler for two lovebirds. The story of a humble, uneducated, man who conquers the heart of a girl with words borrowed, or stolen, from the great poet. Nothing wrong with that, except that this Master of Words proves at the end to be very flawed, unworthy of the worshiping he's the object of-but more of that later. Decent acting overall, breathtaking scenerythose postcard coastal natural settings are also common in Neruda's Chilebut the writing lets a lot to be desired, with too many schmaltzy scenes & dialogs and assorted clich&eacute; situations. Not surprise then that he plot loses its breath half way, when the lovebirds get married and Pablo returns to Chile. What is left then is the same thing we had at the beginning: the daily routines of a small fishing town in southern Italy. Will that be enough to carry the rest of the movie? Don't think so. This isn't Amacord or IVitelloni, as the whole plot was resting on the relationship Neruda--Mario and so when that comes to an end the movie is left gasping for air, begging for some emotional filling as a replacement. With the poet gone and the romance morphed into routine, all what's left for Mario are unfulfilled family obligations and a constant moping for the absent Master. There is an obvious plot discontinuity when both men separate, perhaps because this script was made sewing up two original stories, set in different places at different times. Sure enough, Neruda was in exile in Italy after having fled Chile in 1949, when the Chilean government started jailing Communists, despite them being part of the governing coalition (!) after being pressured by the Yankees, who had started their own witch hunt. (it's hard to believe, but the reason why communists were hunted down was because Chile's president was afraid of it being considered unfriendly by the U.S and risk losing trade, diplomatic and political benefits). Neruda escaped to Argentina & then to Italy, where he was well received thanks to the work made on Italian public opinion by fellow communist Alberto Moravia. On the other hand, the story of him befriending a postman and writing him poems dedicated to his love interest comes from Antonio Skarmeta's Ardiente Paciencia, set in Chile in the 60s, in the coastal town of Isla Negra, where Neruda had a cottage (which is now a museum). So, this is really a Chilean story transposed to Italy, which may explain the awkward plot situation produced when Neruda leaves. Now, Noiret may be a great actor but he makes a disfavor to Neruda with his work here, at least in 2 instances. First, when he's back in Chile he forgets about Mario and doesn't even answer his mail. The real Neruda would have never done that, because for him friendship and loyalty were two things intrinsically tied to class struggle and political commitment. For him all communists--and all members of the working class-were his brothers whatever may have been their countries of origin or their educational level, and all right wingers and rich people in general his enemies, as for him there was no middle ground at that. In real life he would have never acted like he does with Mario, just because he's a less educated man. At least he would have sent him a postcard. The 2nd thing is you would have never caught him in church, let alone crossing himself, as he was an atheist who had no use for religions or for any organized church and the only people in that realm for whom he ever came to feel any respect at all were the Quakers, just because they helped pay for travel tickets to Chile for thousands of Spaniards fleeing their civil war. It's obvious that both misrepresentations have been committed to keep the plot going, which I can understand, but the record must be set straight anyway. Anyway, IP can be very touching the first time you see it, but it goes losing its emotional punch with time, as there's no much left to get hold of after the thrill of the love story and that of the beautiful words wears off. But worse is the portrayal of Neruda as a snob; an hypocrite who'll be nice to the locals as long as he needs them but who'll forget them as soon as he's gone. I'm all for artistic licenses, but not when they make appear an authentic individual under such an unfavorable and false light. In all, to see maybe a couple of times. Anyway, if you want to see something closer to the real man, watch Skarmeta's Ardiente Paciencia.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who Really Wrote the Score?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jacobsencurtis
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Il Postino" is one of my favorite movies. The acting is superb. Massimo Troisi gives a uniquely unforgettable performance, despite his suffering from a fatal illness during filming. Phillipe Noiret, as Pablo Neruda, the Chilean poet-in-exile who befriends Mario (Troisi), gives one of his most memorable performances. The location is enchanting. I love all things Italian. Even a bad movie set in Italy is better for it having been shot there. Some of my favorites are "Enchanted April," "Summertime," and "Roman Holiday." And I love the score, which, until tonight, I assumed was written by Luis Bacalov, who is credited in the movie. But I just watched a movie from 1940 called "Dispatch from Reuters," a bio-pic starring Edward G. Robinson, and darned if the main theme from "Il Postino" isn't straight out of "Dispatch from Reuters." By the way, the music for "Reuters" was composed by the great Max Steiner, who, to my knowledge, received no screen credit in "Il Postino." How is this possible? Has the copyright expired rendering the music part of the public domain?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mundane
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike B
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I found this rather superficial and mundane. It's about the friendship between a worker  a postman - and a poet  Pablo Neruda. The poet awakens the young man's sensibilities and gives him the courage to pursue the village beauty. This is a tiny village - so why he had not realized her beauty before, and more so, why she was not being pursued by an entire flock of young men raised a question mark. The characters are all stereo-typed  the shy postman, the over-wordy poet and the village beauty with her raspy aunt. Everything was a caricature and the film suffered from a lack of passion, intensityI couldn't buy into it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice try, but not quite what I expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only heard of this movie on the TV game show 'Who Wants to be a Millionaire?'. The question was which one of 4 mentioned actors starred in the films 'Nuovo Cinema Paradiso' and 'Il Postino'. I hadn't heard of 'Il Postino' before, but I knew that Philippe Noiret stars in 'Nuovo Cinema Paradiso', so I already knew the answer. The presenter recommended the person who wrongly answered the question to watch these 2 movies because something changes inside us once we get to see these 2 films. Then I did research on this motion-picture. It sounded promising, even more so by being foreign. I also got to know the sad story of Massimo Troisi, who played the title's postman (Pablo Neruda's postman). The man suffered from heart disease since a long time ago. He knew about his fragile heart condition and knew he needed treatment, but despite this he wanted to do the movie anyway. He even postponed heart surgery so that he could complete the film. That was a brave move. And he did manage to finish the movie just in time. Only 12 hours after completing the film he died of heart attack. You can say that he gave his life to make this film. Massimo Troisi is great as Mario Ruoppolo, the postman. But it's also sad to see him in this film because we are looking at a man who was dying while making it and that he died almost immediately after completing it. Phillipe Noiret is great as the chilean poet Pablo Neruda. While Pablo Neruda existed for real, his friendship with the postman didn't. But I don't know if a postman named Mario Ruoppolo existed in real life or not and if he was Pablo Neruda's postman or not. The film's got beautiful cinematography and soundtrack, which gives it more emotion and beauty. The plot is, in concept, good. But the movie itself lacks something (perhaps more emotion is one of those things it lacks) and is even a little too-slow paced. It's not a bad movie. It's interesting, moving, pretty to view... a good attempt, just not quite top material. It just isn't as great as it reputation suggests (with, of course, all due respect in memory of our friend Massimo Troisi).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engrossing character study about two men and their connections to two separate women, as well as the poetry that forms the core of their own friendship.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Radford's tender and rather sweet film, The Postman, is a really quite blinding tale of a man, without either much of a life or very many happenings in and around his existence, going out of his way so as to spawn some. The film is a ground zero character study working its way up, centring on one man and coming to gloriously flesh out his relationships with two people in the form of a mentor and a love interest using the item of poetry, and poets in particular, as a focal point or anchor around which to revolve the ever shifting lives of these half a dozen-or so people. The central character is a certain young man named Mario Ruoppolo, played by Italian actor Massimo Troisi whom died shortly after the film was completed and is one of only seven people to have won a Posthumous Academy Award for acting, which he won for his portrayal of a character named Mario. His life in the early part of the 20th Century on an island off the coast of Italy lies seemingly dormant; a living with his father, whom spends his days at sea fishing for a living, whilst inhabiting a scruffy and run down house on the cliff-side which cannot even produce water from a tap when desired, the situation; with a postcard from some brothers whom have arrived in America offering a brief insight into a supposedly better life. Determined to get on track, the softly spoken; delicate and slow moving Mario shifts off to a local post office so as to apply for the advertised job of delivering letters and mail, locally. On another tangent, that later will become intrinsically linked to that of Mario, a controversial poet from South American nation Chile of true to life existence named Pablo Neruda (Noiret) arrives in Italy having been exiled. His demeanour arrives by way of a newsreel sequence at a picture house, footage which the locals and us watch and listen to simultaneously establishing a set-persona of the man and his controversial, Communist infused existence of writing poetry crash-landing on this small Italian island, much to some of the locals' anger but to the glee of others. The early perceptions of the man are meant to be relatively concrete; he inhabits a beautifully placed but isolated red-washed villa on a separate cliff edge, before plodding Mario comes to form a bond with the poet upon delivering his many letters and from whence the film garners its catalyst so as to play out. The film comes to form a learning process for that of Mario, a deconstruction of an item or art-form that he'd almost certainly heard of in the past but very rarely thought about above a certain level. The same can be said for that of Chilian poet Neruda in regards to the fondness and acceptance the town come to have of him after he and his wife and their bond with a number of people come to forge, a relationship much richer than what he has experienced back home or, you feel, in most other places. Romance appears to want to bloom between Mario and local girl Beatrice (Cucinotta), the daughter of a traditional, hard-up Catholic woman whom owns a tavern within the vicinity; the spying of her playing a game of rather erotically charged flick-rod football in said tavern complete with thrusting of the mannequin players and hammering home of the goals more than enough to have Mario smitten from then on in. But the film is ultimately about the relationship or bond between two men going on around their separate relationships with Beatrice and Pablo's own female partner whom later becomes his wife. It would be untrue to say that the film at all feels less of an accomplishment when certain events transpire and the once central unification of Mario and Pablo is broken up; rather, the ties they have to one another during the film's early scenes are just more interesting, as is the chilling finale involving the two, than any sub-plot to do with either men and what happens between them and their women. Mario's attempts to court a young local girl and the noticeable placing of Pablo's own female partner predominantly off screen and away from the action for most of the time might render the relationship between Mario and Pablo one of a homo-erotic nature. Much later on, a Paris based interview with the poet some years later has Mario read on with keen interest as to whether he or anyone from the town are mentioned; the camera darting around from face to face of those reading with Mario in a kind of panic or nervous excitement or lusting requirement for purifying fulfilment in the form of notifying them, predominantly the notifying of Mario. The convenience in having come to have known a master of poetry of a romantic sort, somebody that feeds off of a belief that all women love romantic poetry and that it is the key to pertaining to a relationship, works very much in Mario's favour. His gradual learning of how to construct it, the encountering of terms and words such as what a metaphor is gradually come to form the nucleus of the first half of the film; a fitting sequence on a nearby beach sees Pablo gradually reveal himself as he readies to swim in a physical sense as Mario comes to reveal a spoken metaphor for the very first time as, on another occasion, he gradually forms an opinion of a short poem Pablo comes up with on the spot. The film's attention to finer things such as these, an including of sequences in which characters must first come to master the basics of an art or activity so as to garner entry onto another plateau so as to put what has been learnt into action, feels wonderfully prominent, resulting in Radford's film being thoroughly worthwhile.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    magnificent masterpiece of Michael with two marvelous metaphors --the poet(Pablo) and the postman(Mario)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    superdirector007
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    what a magnificent movie, legendary work by Michael Redford , everything about this movie is beautiful ,,winning Oscar does not come in easy way ,,be it budget,,cinematography covering island's natural beauty ,,specially sea settings ,humourous dialogs with utmost simplicity and realistic performances by actors ,everything is admirable. sometimes you do not plan to make a great movie with highly perfection attitude but movie becomes and gets applauded ,,same happened with this movie,what i believe what is metaphor Mario asks Pablo says-like sky is weeping what does it mean Mario says means to say sky is raining Mario's response it's complicated and Pablo's response that complication does not have to do anything with person's emotions very meaningful and soulful dialogs ,that is the reason movie does not become boring end of the movie is very surprising ,it keeps you involve in the movie movie was shot on the island near by Meditteranean sea and every time tides go and again come to touch coastal areas that resembles one excellent scene goes with the hope to come with another lovely scene filled with emotional and heart touching dialogs to touch your heart movie is pretty simple but can you predict what's gonna happen in next scene ,probably not ,it has certain surprising elements this movie is not a movie this is everlasting experience to live with and cherish it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
