<filme>
 <id>
  140
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0107131
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1993
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Incr&iacute;vel Jornada
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Three pets escape from a California ranch to find their owners in San Francisco.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Three pets (Chance, a young dog unfamiliar with the world; Shadow, an aging, wise dog; and Sassy, a snobby cat) are left behind when their family goes on vacation. Unsure of what happened, the animals set out on a quest to find their family. This journey across America is very dangerous and the animals risk never seeing their masters again. The group of pets travel across forested mountains and areas of wide-open countryside, while their family searches for them in the same areas.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   cat
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   dog
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   journey
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   quest
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   golden retriever
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Duwayne Dunham
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Sheila Burnford
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Caroline Thompson
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Michael J. Fox
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Sally Field
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Don Alder
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wonderful movie for all generations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jeandewey
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this movie when my children were young in the early 80's. Now 30 years later I am enjoying it again with my granddaughter. For a two year old she sits spellbound through it from beginning to end. She is always concerned when Shadow falls from the railroad tracks in to the mud and cant get out and encourages him to keep trying. My favorite scene is the suspense building as you wait for the animals to come in to view in the end and return to their owners. Waiting for Shadow to make his appearance always has the tears running down my cheeks. I know he is going to make it but it is still an emotional scene as he gains speed running to his owner. I had to order this movie to add to my granddaughters collection.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad at all, it's a great classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On a social networking site, a friend posted a screen cap of a movie with edited captions on it. The movie was of some dogs talking to each other. I looked it up and discovered this movie. I got it and watched it. My younger sister came in halfway and she is very sensitive to movies that are even a little bit scary. To give an example, she cried at the end of Open Season because she didn't think Boog would make it back home and was upset about it. So with that in mind, I watched the movie for the first time. And so I didn't have the nostalgia feeling as many did. But I still enjoyed it and could tell that it could produce that feeling for those growing up. I really liked the plot, the simplicity of the animals speaking (no moving animated mouths or anything) and the music helped to fit in with the theme. I rate this 8/10 for a brilliant movie that deserves a higher rating on IMDb than a 6.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Good, But It's Also A Little Bland.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a little kid, I absolutely adored this movie. As someone older, I am sorry, but I really didn't think that much of it. Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey is a good movie, but unfortunately it is also a little bland. What I mean is while I thought that this was a good movie, it did not think that it was a great movie, I found it a little forced and bland. But what I can say is that this movie is not totally and completely repulsive, it just didn't really do anything for me. A few positive things I can say are that the acting in this movie was good, the live-action actors did a very good job with the parts that they were given. Another thing good about this movie is the scenery and the cinematography, the scenery (especially in the wilderness) was beautiful to look at. But on the whole, while this movie is not a masterpiece of filming, I can say that I still liked it as a whole. I'll give this movie a rating of seven stars out of ten. The seven means that while this movie is far from perfect, it still is enjoyable and watchable, as well as entertaining. The biggest problem with the movie is the animals. I'm sorry if this offends anybody, but I just didn't really care for them. I understand that they were talking by telepathy, but still, that didn't suit them at all. Talking animals don't really go well in live-action movies, in cartoons, yes, in live action movies, no, just no. Another problem with the movie is the fact that it is really different from the original story. There are quite a few differences between the book and this movie. I would go on and name them, but I won't because it would take to much time to name all of them. But anyway, despite these flaws, this movie is still enjoyable to watch and be entertained. Go ahead and watch this movie if you haven't seen it yet, because who knows, you might love it. Just because I didn't really care for it that much, doesn't mean anything. You might end up loving it a whole lot! Well all in all, this movie is far from being perfect but it is even farther from being horrible. So while this movie is not one of the greatest movies ever made, I still find it to be entertaining and likable in a few ways. Well go ahead and watch this, because you will probably like it. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Artless !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Omkar Joshi
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It took me to the times when I had pets and they actually formed an integral part of my life ! The best part of the movie is it's majestic panorama - pine forests, clear streams,undisturbed stretches of open fields and grandeur of the mountains - I haven't searched about where this film was shot but will find it soon. An old craving to make a vagabond amidst nature popped up again ! Having experienced the psyche of cats and dogs closely, I enjoyed the depiction.Though cats are not as emotional as Sassy,it feels good to see it that way.Chance is a typical pup which appeals directly due to it's raw innocence.Shadow,on the contrary,adds much of the emotional flavor the movie has. All in all,the movie is a win.Only one sad thing struck my mind - I doubt if the future generations will ever experience an idyllic,artless childhood amidst a calm nature !!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fine animal movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bts1984
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a remake of the 1963 oldie 'The Incredibly Journey'. Surprisingly the plot is almost identical. The biggest difference is that this version is more movie-like and has far more humor. Another big difference is that the animals talk here, which is good because they only talk by telepathy. If they talked and moved their lips like people or like animals do in cartoons, it would be phony and ridiculous. I hate it when they do that. The older version resembles a documentary, humor is not a priority and the animals don't talk. That's just the way they are: simply animals and not human-like. More than a remake, this more recent version is a more likable and amusing film although clearly based on the old one. For those who are fond of good animal movies, I dare to say that this is an instant classic. It's very hard to find an animal film of good taste like this nowadays. This charming motion picture is heartwarming, touching, fun and contains lots of adventure, enjoyable characters and a classic soundtrack. The Sierra mountains are astonishing, being the result rich and wonderful landscapes, so beautiful that it's like a dream. As for the pets (3 great animal actors voiced by human actors who do a pretty good vocal job), Sassy and Chance are a comic relief. Shadow is wise and caring. Shadow possesses all the qualities a Golden Retriever is supposed to have, which makes him a favorite (and besides, I adore Golden Retrievers). The human characters, more precisely the family, are likable characters too and well performed by the actors. This film was followed by a sequel which is okay but lacks what makes the first one such an appreciated classic. Title in Portugal: 'Regresso a Casa'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very nice scenery and an exciting adventure, but the characters and humour generally aren't so impressive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing most of this family adventure movie as a kid. It was released early in 1993, and I think I saw it on video later that year. Towards the end, I came across a scene which I found too overwhelmingly sad, and I guess I didn't watch what little was left of the film, though I did watch the sequel, "Homeward Bound II: Lost in San Francisco", from beginning to end shortly after it was released on video in 1996. I believe it's been nearly seventeen years since I watched any of "Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey", but after all these years, I still remember it. After renting it this month, I can say I've finally seen it all. While it's not what I would call a bad movie, I was definitely not as impressed as many others clearly have been. Chance is a na&iuml;ve young Bulldog who was once stuck at the pound, a place he hated, but is now owned by a boy named Jamie Seaver. He lives with two other domestic animals: Shadow, a wise old Golden Retriever owned by Jamie's stepbrother, Peter Burnford; and Sassy, an arrogant Himalayan cat owned by Peter's sister, Hope. After Laura Burnford and Bob Seaver get married, meaning that the two families are now one, they go on a trip to San Francisco and the pets are left at a friend's ranch. Chance, Shadow, and Sassy do not understand what has just happened, and don't realize that their owners will come back, so they think they've been abandoned! Shadow decides to leave the ranch and set out to find the family, and Sassy and Chance soon follow! The three of them find themselves on a journey through the wilderness, facing the dangers of this terrain! Chance's lack of experience definitely won't help him on this adventure. The silly things Chance does and the rivalry between Chance and Sassy are meant to be comical, which they sometimes are, but not usually. Chance's antics can also get tiring after a short while. I didn't care much for these two characters, and don't think Michael J. Fox and Sally Field did a very good job providing their respective voices. Don Ameche as Shadow might be the only decent voice-over of the three, and this character is the most likable of the leads. After I started watching "Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey" this month, I soon realized how boring I found the film, and that didn't change until I got to the part where the journey begins. There's lots of beautiful scenery through the mountainous wilderness and the adventure of the three domestic animals is often exciting. Shadow's wisdom can be another intriguing aspect of the film, and some scenes are fairly touching, such as the Golden Retriever saving a little girl lost in the forest. However, there's still more weak humour during the adventure, and the scenes with the humans looking for the animals are certainly not as interesting as the ones showing the pets on their journey. None of the human characters really stand out. With a spoiler warning, I will tell you which part made me really sad all those years ago, and the ending that follows. If you haven't seen the film, you might not want to read on, but if you have, then maybe you've already guessed. It's the part where the three pets are almost home, but Shadow falls into a pit and injures his leg, and it appears he can't get out! When I watched "Homeward Bound II: Lost in San Francisco", I knew the aging dog obviously got out of the pit somehow, since he's in that sequel. After over a decade and a half, I finally found out that "Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey" doesn't show how Shadow gets out, but at the end, we see the three animals returning to their owners, even though it takes the Golden Retriever longer to show up than it does for the other two. Anyway, overall, this particular animal movie is hit-and-miss, with an exciting adventure and cute animal stars, but also with several significant shortcomings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Animal adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a story of two dogs and a cat looking for their way back home.Old and wise Golden Retriever Shadow, young American Bulldog Chance and Himalayan cat Sassy flee from the ranch and go into the wilderness to be reunited with their family.Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey (1993) is a family adventure directed by Duwayne Dunham.It's a remake of a 1963 film.This movie got a sequel three years later.Michael J. Fox is the perfect man to do the voice-over for Chance.Fox has some youthful energy he brings to the role.Sally Field does great voice work as Sassy.Don Ameche is fantastic as Shadow.This was this veteran actor's second last movie.Also the visible actors are great.Kim Greist plays Laura Burnford-Seaver.Robert Hays is Bob Seaver.Benji Thall plays Peter Burnford.Veronica Lauren is Hope Burnford.Kevin Chevalia is Jamie Seaver.Jean Smart portrays Kate.It's quite amazing to watch these pets trying to survive in the wilderness.We see Sassy taken by the river and she seems like a goner.The bear scene is exiting and funny.Chance has no chance with that big, hungry bear.And his meeting with the porcupine looks painful.This is some great fun for the whole family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Three animals go on a journey to make their way back home.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anna N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my favorite family movies. Loved it when I was little and it still holds up with me now that I'm older. I still laugh at all the same old jokes and might even shed a tear a times. I never have much cared for animals talking, or at least UN-animated ones but this one I'll stand up for. It's a pretty old movie but it will always hold a place in my heart. There aren't any other live animal movies that I can think of at the moment that I even could compare with, let alone like as much as this one. I might be giving too much praise to this movie but I don't think show. I really holds that great message that" Home is where the heart is." Or at least that's the message I gained from it. Definitely recommended for a good old family movie night.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A really nice family movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tamimarie228
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a really nice and sweet movie that the entire family can enjoy. It's about two dogs and a cat who are taken away to live with someone else for a little while but the animals don't understand and they escape and go to find the family on their own. The cat is named Sassy and she lives up to her name. Chance is the younger dog who knows a lot about life on the inside of the pound. Shadow is the older and wiser dog who senses things. Put those three together on an adventure and it makes for a happy and fun filled time. There are no special effects of the mouths moving so it isn't cheesy at all. It's the best talking animal movie that I've seen so far. It's a really good movie for families.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and beautifully filmed movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I loved Bruce Broughton's music score, very lyrical, and this alone added to the film's charm. The best aspect of the movie were the three animals, superlatively voiced by Michael J.Fox, Sally Field and the late Don Ameche. Whereas Fox has the funniest lines, Ameche plays a rather brooding otherwise engaging character(the voice of reason), and Field adds wit into a character that is always seen telling Chance off. The humans weren't as engaging, and sometimes the film dragged, but that is my only complaint. This is one beautiful-looking film, with beautiful close up shots of Canada, I believe. Although the film itself is quite long, there is never a seriously dull moment, and this is advantaged by the voice work and a well-written script. All in all, a charming and perhaps underrated film, with a 9/10 from me. Bethany Cox.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wonderful movie for all generations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jeandewey
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this movie when my children were young in the early 80's. Now 30 years later I am enjoying it again with my granddaughter. For a two year old she sits spellbound through it from beginning to end. She is always concerned when Shadow falls from the railroad tracks in to the mud and cant get out and encourages him to keep trying. My favorite scene is the suspense building as you wait for the animals to come in to view in the end and return to their owners. Waiting for Shadow to make his appearance always has the tears running down my cheeks. I know he is going to make it but it is still an emotional scene as he gains speed running to his owner. I had to order this movie to add to my granddaughters collection.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad at all, it's a great classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On a social networking site, a friend posted a screen cap of a movie with edited captions on it. The movie was of some dogs talking to each other. I looked it up and discovered this movie. I got it and watched it. My younger sister came in halfway and she is very sensitive to movies that are even a little bit scary. To give an example, she cried at the end of Open Season because she didn't think Boog would make it back home and was upset about it. So with that in mind, I watched the movie for the first time. And so I didn't have the nostalgia feeling as many did. But I still enjoyed it and could tell that it could produce that feeling for those growing up. I really liked the plot, the simplicity of the animals speaking (no moving animated mouths or anything) and the music helped to fit in with the theme. I rate this 8/10 for a brilliant movie that deserves a higher rating on IMDb than a 6.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Good, But It's Also A Little Bland.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a little kid, I absolutely adored this movie. As someone older, I am sorry, but I really didn't think that much of it. Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey is a good movie, but unfortunately it is also a little bland. What I mean is while I thought that this was a good movie, it did not think that it was a great movie, I found it a little forced and bland. But what I can say is that this movie is not totally and completely repulsive, it just didn't really do anything for me. A few positive things I can say are that the acting in this movie was good, the live-action actors did a very good job with the parts that they were given. Another thing good about this movie is the scenery and the cinematography, the scenery (especially in the wilderness) was beautiful to look at. But on the whole, while this movie is not a masterpiece of filming, I can say that I still liked it as a whole. I'll give this movie a rating of seven stars out of ten. The seven means that while this movie is far from perfect, it still is enjoyable and watchable, as well as entertaining. The biggest problem with the movie is the animals. I'm sorry if this offends anybody, but I just didn't really care for them. I understand that they were talking by telepathy, but still, that didn't suit them at all. Talking animals don't really go well in live-action movies, in cartoons, yes, in live action movies, no, just no. Another problem with the movie is the fact that it is really different from the original story. There are quite a few differences between the book and this movie. I would go on and name them, but I won't because it would take to much time to name all of them. But anyway, despite these flaws, this movie is still enjoyable to watch and be entertained. Go ahead and watch this movie if you haven't seen it yet, because who knows, you might love it. Just because I didn't really care for it that much, doesn't mean anything. You might end up loving it a whole lot! Well all in all, this movie is far from being perfect but it is even farther from being horrible. So while this movie is not one of the greatest movies ever made, I still find it to be entertaining and likable in a few ways. Well go ahead and watch this, because you will probably like it. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Artless !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Omkar Joshi
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It took me to the times when I had pets and they actually formed an integral part of my life ! The best part of the movie is it's majestic panorama - pine forests, clear streams,undisturbed stretches of open fields and grandeur of the mountains - I haven't searched about where this film was shot but will find it soon. An old craving to make a vagabond amidst nature popped up again ! Having experienced the psyche of cats and dogs closely, I enjoyed the depiction.Though cats are not as emotional as Sassy,it feels good to see it that way.Chance is a typical pup which appeals directly due to it's raw innocence.Shadow,on the contrary,adds much of the emotional flavor the movie has. All in all,the movie is a win.Only one sad thing struck my mind - I doubt if the future generations will ever experience an idyllic,artless childhood amidst a calm nature !!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fine animal movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bts1984
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a remake of the 1963 oldie 'The Incredibly Journey'. Surprisingly the plot is almost identical. The biggest difference is that this version is more movie-like and has far more humor. Another big difference is that the animals talk here, which is good because they only talk by telepathy. If they talked and moved their lips like people or like animals do in cartoons, it would be phony and ridiculous. I hate it when they do that. The older version resembles a documentary, humor is not a priority and the animals don't talk. That's just the way they are: simply animals and not human-like. More than a remake, this more recent version is a more likable and amusing film although clearly based on the old one. For those who are fond of good animal movies, I dare to say that this is an instant classic. It's very hard to find an animal film of good taste like this nowadays. This charming motion picture is heartwarming, touching, fun and contains lots of adventure, enjoyable characters and a classic soundtrack. The Sierra mountains are astonishing, being the result rich and wonderful landscapes, so beautiful that it's like a dream. As for the pets (3 great animal actors voiced by human actors who do a pretty good vocal job), Sassy and Chance are a comic relief. Shadow is wise and caring. Shadow possesses all the qualities a Golden Retriever is supposed to have, which makes him a favorite (and besides, I adore Golden Retrievers). The human characters, more precisely the family, are likable characters too and well performed by the actors. This film was followed by a sequel which is okay but lacks what makes the first one such an appreciated classic. Title in Portugal: 'Regresso a Casa'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very nice scenery and an exciting adventure, but the characters and humour generally aren't so impressive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing most of this family adventure movie as a kid. It was released early in 1993, and I think I saw it on video later that year. Towards the end, I came across a scene which I found too overwhelmingly sad, and I guess I didn't watch what little was left of the film, though I did watch the sequel, "Homeward Bound II: Lost in San Francisco", from beginning to end shortly after it was released on video in 1996. I believe it's been nearly seventeen years since I watched any of "Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey", but after all these years, I still remember it. After renting it this month, I can say I've finally seen it all. While it's not what I would call a bad movie, I was definitely not as impressed as many others clearly have been. Chance is a na&iuml;ve young Bulldog who was once stuck at the pound, a place he hated, but is now owned by a boy named Jamie Seaver. He lives with two other domestic animals: Shadow, a wise old Golden Retriever owned by Jamie's stepbrother, Peter Burnford; and Sassy, an arrogant Himalayan cat owned by Peter's sister, Hope. After Laura Burnford and Bob Seaver get married, meaning that the two families are now one, they go on a trip to San Francisco and the pets are left at a friend's ranch. Chance, Shadow, and Sassy do not understand what has just happened, and don't realize that their owners will come back, so they think they've been abandoned! Shadow decides to leave the ranch and set out to find the family, and Sassy and Chance soon follow! The three of them find themselves on a journey through the wilderness, facing the dangers of this terrain! Chance's lack of experience definitely won't help him on this adventure. The silly things Chance does and the rivalry between Chance and Sassy are meant to be comical, which they sometimes are, but not usually. Chance's antics can also get tiring after a short while. I didn't care much for these two characters, and don't think Michael J. Fox and Sally Field did a very good job providing their respective voices. Don Ameche as Shadow might be the only decent voice-over of the three, and this character is the most likable of the leads. After I started watching "Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey" this month, I soon realized how boring I found the film, and that didn't change until I got to the part where the journey begins. There's lots of beautiful scenery through the mountainous wilderness and the adventure of the three domestic animals is often exciting. Shadow's wisdom can be another intriguing aspect of the film, and some scenes are fairly touching, such as the Golden Retriever saving a little girl lost in the forest. However, there's still more weak humour during the adventure, and the scenes with the humans looking for the animals are certainly not as interesting as the ones showing the pets on their journey. None of the human characters really stand out. With a spoiler warning, I will tell you which part made me really sad all those years ago, and the ending that follows. If you haven't seen the film, you might not want to read on, but if you have, then maybe you've already guessed. It's the part where the three pets are almost home, but Shadow falls into a pit and injures his leg, and it appears he can't get out! When I watched "Homeward Bound II: Lost in San Francisco", I knew the aging dog obviously got out of the pit somehow, since he's in that sequel. After over a decade and a half, I finally found out that "Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey" doesn't show how Shadow gets out, but at the end, we see the three animals returning to their owners, even though it takes the Golden Retriever longer to show up than it does for the other two. Anyway, overall, this particular animal movie is hit-and-miss, with an exciting adventure and cute animal stars, but also with several significant shortcomings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Animal adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a story of two dogs and a cat looking for their way back home.Old and wise Golden Retriever Shadow, young American Bulldog Chance and Himalayan cat Sassy flee from the ranch and go into the wilderness to be reunited with their family.Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey (1993) is a family adventure directed by Duwayne Dunham.It's a remake of a 1963 film.This movie got a sequel three years later.Michael J. Fox is the perfect man to do the voice-over for Chance.Fox has some youthful energy he brings to the role.Sally Field does great voice work as Sassy.Don Ameche is fantastic as Shadow.This was this veteran actor's second last movie.Also the visible actors are great.Kim Greist plays Laura Burnford-Seaver.Robert Hays is Bob Seaver.Benji Thall plays Peter Burnford.Veronica Lauren is Hope Burnford.Kevin Chevalia is Jamie Seaver.Jean Smart portrays Kate.It's quite amazing to watch these pets trying to survive in the wilderness.We see Sassy taken by the river and she seems like a goner.The bear scene is exiting and funny.Chance has no chance with that big, hungry bear.And his meeting with the porcupine looks painful.This is some great fun for the whole family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Three animals go on a journey to make their way back home.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anna N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my favorite family movies. Loved it when I was little and it still holds up with me now that I'm older. I still laugh at all the same old jokes and might even shed a tear a times. I never have much cared for animals talking, or at least UN-animated ones but this one I'll stand up for. It's a pretty old movie but it will always hold a place in my heart. There aren't any other live animal movies that I can think of at the moment that I even could compare with, let alone like as much as this one. I might be giving too much praise to this movie but I don't think show. I really holds that great message that" Home is where the heart is." Or at least that's the message I gained from it. Definitely recommended for a good old family movie night.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A really nice family movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tamimarie228
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a really nice and sweet movie that the entire family can enjoy. It's about two dogs and a cat who are taken away to live with someone else for a little while but the animals don't understand and they escape and go to find the family on their own. The cat is named Sassy and she lives up to her name. Chance is the younger dog who knows a lot about life on the inside of the pound. Shadow is the older and wiser dog who senses things. Put those three together on an adventure and it makes for a happy and fun filled time. There are no special effects of the mouths moving so it isn't cheesy at all. It's the best talking animal movie that I've seen so far. It's a really good movie for families.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and beautifully filmed movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I loved Bruce Broughton's music score, very lyrical, and this alone added to the film's charm. The best aspect of the movie were the three animals, superlatively voiced by Michael J.Fox, Sally Field and the late Don Ameche. Whereas Fox has the funniest lines, Ameche plays a rather brooding otherwise engaging character(the voice of reason), and Field adds wit into a character that is always seen telling Chance off. The humans weren't as engaging, and sometimes the film dragged, but that is my only complaint. This is one beautiful-looking film, with beautiful close up shots of Canada, I believe. Although the film itself is quite long, there is never a seriously dull moment, and this is advantaged by the voice work and a well-written script. All in all, a charming and perhaps underrated film, with a 9/10 from me. Bethany Cox.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wonderful movie for all generations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jeandewey
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this movie when my children were young in the early 80's. Now 30 years later I am enjoying it again with my granddaughter. For a two year old she sits spellbound through it from beginning to end. She is always concerned when Shadow falls from the railroad tracks in to the mud and cant get out and encourages him to keep trying. My favorite scene is the suspense building as you wait for the animals to come in to view in the end and return to their owners. Waiting for Shadow to make his appearance always has the tears running down my cheeks. I know he is going to make it but it is still an emotional scene as he gains speed running to his owner. I had to order this movie to add to my granddaughters collection.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad at all, it's a great classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On a social networking site, a friend posted a screen cap of a movie with edited captions on it. The movie was of some dogs talking to each other. I looked it up and discovered this movie. I got it and watched it. My younger sister came in halfway and she is very sensitive to movies that are even a little bit scary. To give an example, she cried at the end of Open Season because she didn't think Boog would make it back home and was upset about it. So with that in mind, I watched the movie for the first time. And so I didn't have the nostalgia feeling as many did. But I still enjoyed it and could tell that it could produce that feeling for those growing up. I really liked the plot, the simplicity of the animals speaking (no moving animated mouths or anything) and the music helped to fit in with the theme. I rate this 8/10 for a brilliant movie that deserves a higher rating on IMDb than a 6.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Good, But It's Also A Little Bland.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a little kid, I absolutely adored this movie. As someone older, I am sorry, but I really didn't think that much of it. Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey is a good movie, but unfortunately it is also a little bland. What I mean is while I thought that this was a good movie, it did not think that it was a great movie, I found it a little forced and bland. But what I can say is that this movie is not totally and completely repulsive, it just didn't really do anything for me. A few positive things I can say are that the acting in this movie was good, the live-action actors did a very good job with the parts that they were given. Another thing good about this movie is the scenery and the cinematography, the scenery (especially in the wilderness) was beautiful to look at. But on the whole, while this movie is not a masterpiece of filming, I can say that I still liked it as a whole. I'll give this movie a rating of seven stars out of ten. The seven means that while this movie is far from perfect, it still is enjoyable and watchable, as well as entertaining. The biggest problem with the movie is the animals. I'm sorry if this offends anybody, but I just didn't really care for them. I understand that they were talking by telepathy, but still, that didn't suit them at all. Talking animals don't really go well in live-action movies, in cartoons, yes, in live action movies, no, just no. Another problem with the movie is the fact that it is really different from the original story. There are quite a few differences between the book and this movie. I would go on and name them, but I won't because it would take to much time to name all of them. But anyway, despite these flaws, this movie is still enjoyable to watch and be entertained. Go ahead and watch this movie if you haven't seen it yet, because who knows, you might love it. Just because I didn't really care for it that much, doesn't mean anything. You might end up loving it a whole lot! Well all in all, this movie is far from being perfect but it is even farther from being horrible. So while this movie is not one of the greatest movies ever made, I still find it to be entertaining and likable in a few ways. Well go ahead and watch this, because you will probably like it. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Artless !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Omkar Joshi
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It took me to the times when I had pets and they actually formed an integral part of my life ! The best part of the movie is it's majestic panorama - pine forests, clear streams,undisturbed stretches of open fields and grandeur of the mountains - I haven't searched about where this film was shot but will find it soon. An old craving to make a vagabond amidst nature popped up again ! Having experienced the psyche of cats and dogs closely, I enjoyed the depiction.Though cats are not as emotional as Sassy,it feels good to see it that way.Chance is a typical pup which appeals directly due to it's raw innocence.Shadow,on the contrary,adds much of the emotional flavor the movie has. All in all,the movie is a win.Only one sad thing struck my mind - I doubt if the future generations will ever experience an idyllic,artless childhood amidst a calm nature !!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fine animal movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bts1984
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a remake of the 1963 oldie 'The Incredibly Journey'. Surprisingly the plot is almost identical. The biggest difference is that this version is more movie-like and has far more humor. Another big difference is that the animals talk here, which is good because they only talk by telepathy. If they talked and moved their lips like people or like animals do in cartoons, it would be phony and ridiculous. I hate it when they do that. The older version resembles a documentary, humor is not a priority and the animals don't talk. That's just the way they are: simply animals and not human-like. More than a remake, this more recent version is a more likable and amusing film although clearly based on the old one. For those who are fond of good animal movies, I dare to say that this is an instant classic. It's very hard to find an animal film of good taste like this nowadays. This charming motion picture is heartwarming, touching, fun and contains lots of adventure, enjoyable characters and a classic soundtrack. The Sierra mountains are astonishing, being the result rich and wonderful landscapes, so beautiful that it's like a dream. As for the pets (3 great animal actors voiced by human actors who do a pretty good vocal job), Sassy and Chance are a comic relief. Shadow is wise and caring. Shadow possesses all the qualities a Golden Retriever is supposed to have, which makes him a favorite (and besides, I adore Golden Retrievers). The human characters, more precisely the family, are likable characters too and well performed by the actors. This film was followed by a sequel which is okay but lacks what makes the first one such an appreciated classic. Title in Portugal: 'Regresso a Casa'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very nice scenery and an exciting adventure, but the characters and humour generally aren't so impressive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing most of this family adventure movie as a kid. It was released early in 1993, and I think I saw it on video later that year. Towards the end, I came across a scene which I found too overwhelmingly sad, and I guess I didn't watch what little was left of the film, though I did watch the sequel, "Homeward Bound II: Lost in San Francisco", from beginning to end shortly after it was released on video in 1996. I believe it's been nearly seventeen years since I watched any of "Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey", but after all these years, I still remember it. After renting it this month, I can say I've finally seen it all. While it's not what I would call a bad movie, I was definitely not as impressed as many others clearly have been. Chance is a na&iuml;ve young Bulldog who was once stuck at the pound, a place he hated, but is now owned by a boy named Jamie Seaver. He lives with two other domestic animals: Shadow, a wise old Golden Retriever owned by Jamie's stepbrother, Peter Burnford; and Sassy, an arrogant Himalayan cat owned by Peter's sister, Hope. After Laura Burnford and Bob Seaver get married, meaning that the two families are now one, they go on a trip to San Francisco and the pets are left at a friend's ranch. Chance, Shadow, and Sassy do not understand what has just happened, and don't realize that their owners will come back, so they think they've been abandoned! Shadow decides to leave the ranch and set out to find the family, and Sassy and Chance soon follow! The three of them find themselves on a journey through the wilderness, facing the dangers of this terrain! Chance's lack of experience definitely won't help him on this adventure. The silly things Chance does and the rivalry between Chance and Sassy are meant to be comical, which they sometimes are, but not usually. Chance's antics can also get tiring after a short while. I didn't care much for these two characters, and don't think Michael J. Fox and Sally Field did a very good job providing their respective voices. Don Ameche as Shadow might be the only decent voice-over of the three, and this character is the most likable of the leads. After I started watching "Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey" this month, I soon realized how boring I found the film, and that didn't change until I got to the part where the journey begins. There's lots of beautiful scenery through the mountainous wilderness and the adventure of the three domestic animals is often exciting. Shadow's wisdom can be another intriguing aspect of the film, and some scenes are fairly touching, such as the Golden Retriever saving a little girl lost in the forest. However, there's still more weak humour during the adventure, and the scenes with the humans looking for the animals are certainly not as interesting as the ones showing the pets on their journey. None of the human characters really stand out. With a spoiler warning, I will tell you which part made me really sad all those years ago, and the ending that follows. If you haven't seen the film, you might not want to read on, but if you have, then maybe you've already guessed. It's the part where the three pets are almost home, but Shadow falls into a pit and injures his leg, and it appears he can't get out! When I watched "Homeward Bound II: Lost in San Francisco", I knew the aging dog obviously got out of the pit somehow, since he's in that sequel. After over a decade and a half, I finally found out that "Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey" doesn't show how Shadow gets out, but at the end, we see the three animals returning to their owners, even though it takes the Golden Retriever longer to show up than it does for the other two. Anyway, overall, this particular animal movie is hit-and-miss, with an exciting adventure and cute animal stars, but also with several significant shortcomings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Animal adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a story of two dogs and a cat looking for their way back home.Old and wise Golden Retriever Shadow, young American Bulldog Chance and Himalayan cat Sassy flee from the ranch and go into the wilderness to be reunited with their family.Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey (1993) is a family adventure directed by Duwayne Dunham.It's a remake of a 1963 film.This movie got a sequel three years later.Michael J. Fox is the perfect man to do the voice-over for Chance.Fox has some youthful energy he brings to the role.Sally Field does great voice work as Sassy.Don Ameche is fantastic as Shadow.This was this veteran actor's second last movie.Also the visible actors are great.Kim Greist plays Laura Burnford-Seaver.Robert Hays is Bob Seaver.Benji Thall plays Peter Burnford.Veronica Lauren is Hope Burnford.Kevin Chevalia is Jamie Seaver.Jean Smart portrays Kate.It's quite amazing to watch these pets trying to survive in the wilderness.We see Sassy taken by the river and she seems like a goner.The bear scene is exiting and funny.Chance has no chance with that big, hungry bear.And his meeting with the porcupine looks painful.This is some great fun for the whole family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Three animals go on a journey to make their way back home.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anna N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my favorite family movies. Loved it when I was little and it still holds up with me now that I'm older. I still laugh at all the same old jokes and might even shed a tear a times. I never have much cared for animals talking, or at least UN-animated ones but this one I'll stand up for. It's a pretty old movie but it will always hold a place in my heart. There aren't any other live animal movies that I can think of at the moment that I even could compare with, let alone like as much as this one. I might be giving too much praise to this movie but I don't think show. I really holds that great message that" Home is where the heart is." Or at least that's the message I gained from it. Definitely recommended for a good old family movie night.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A really nice family movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tamimarie228
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a really nice and sweet movie that the entire family can enjoy. It's about two dogs and a cat who are taken away to live with someone else for a little while but the animals don't understand and they escape and go to find the family on their own. The cat is named Sassy and she lives up to her name. Chance is the younger dog who knows a lot about life on the inside of the pound. Shadow is the older and wiser dog who senses things. Put those three together on an adventure and it makes for a happy and fun filled time. There are no special effects of the mouths moving so it isn't cheesy at all. It's the best talking animal movie that I've seen so far. It's a really good movie for families.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and beautifully filmed movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I loved Bruce Broughton's music score, very lyrical, and this alone added to the film's charm. The best aspect of the movie were the three animals, superlatively voiced by Michael J.Fox, Sally Field and the late Don Ameche. Whereas Fox has the funniest lines, Ameche plays a rather brooding otherwise engaging character(the voice of reason), and Field adds wit into a character that is always seen telling Chance off. The humans weren't as engaging, and sometimes the film dragged, but that is my only complaint. This is one beautiful-looking film, with beautiful close up shots of Canada, I believe. Although the film itself is quite long, there is never a seriously dull moment, and this is advantaged by the voice work and a well-written script. All in all, a charming and perhaps underrated film, with a 9/10 from me. Bethany Cox.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wonderful movie for all generations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jeandewey
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this movie when my children were young in the early 80's. Now 30 years later I am enjoying it again with my granddaughter. For a two year old she sits spellbound through it from beginning to end. She is always concerned when Shadow falls from the railroad tracks in to the mud and cant get out and encourages him to keep trying. My favorite scene is the suspense building as you wait for the animals to come in to view in the end and return to their owners. Waiting for Shadow to make his appearance always has the tears running down my cheeks. I know he is going to make it but it is still an emotional scene as he gains speed running to his owner. I had to order this movie to add to my granddaughters collection.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad at all, it's a great classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On a social networking site, a friend posted a screen cap of a movie with edited captions on it. The movie was of some dogs talking to each other. I looked it up and discovered this movie. I got it and watched it. My younger sister came in halfway and she is very sensitive to movies that are even a little bit scary. To give an example, she cried at the end of Open Season because she didn't think Boog would make it back home and was upset about it. So with that in mind, I watched the movie for the first time. And so I didn't have the nostalgia feeling as many did. But I still enjoyed it and could tell that it could produce that feeling for those growing up. I really liked the plot, the simplicity of the animals speaking (no moving animated mouths or anything) and the music helped to fit in with the theme. I rate this 8/10 for a brilliant movie that deserves a higher rating on IMDb than a 6.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Good, But It's Also A Little Bland.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a little kid, I absolutely adored this movie. As someone older, I am sorry, but I really didn't think that much of it. Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey is a good movie, but unfortunately it is also a little bland. What I mean is while I thought that this was a good movie, it did not think that it was a great movie, I found it a little forced and bland. But what I can say is that this movie is not totally and completely repulsive, it just didn't really do anything for me. A few positive things I can say are that the acting in this movie was good, the live-action actors did a very good job with the parts that they were given. Another thing good about this movie is the scenery and the cinematography, the scenery (especially in the wilderness) was beautiful to look at. But on the whole, while this movie is not a masterpiece of filming, I can say that I still liked it as a whole. I'll give this movie a rating of seven stars out of ten. The seven means that while this movie is far from perfect, it still is enjoyable and watchable, as well as entertaining. The biggest problem with the movie is the animals. I'm sorry if this offends anybody, but I just didn't really care for them. I understand that they were talking by telepathy, but still, that didn't suit them at all. Talking animals don't really go well in live-action movies, in cartoons, yes, in live action movies, no, just no. Another problem with the movie is the fact that it is really different from the original story. There are quite a few differences between the book and this movie. I would go on and name them, but I won't because it would take to much time to name all of them. But anyway, despite these flaws, this movie is still enjoyable to watch and be entertained. Go ahead and watch this movie if you haven't seen it yet, because who knows, you might love it. Just because I didn't really care for it that much, doesn't mean anything. You might end up loving it a whole lot! Well all in all, this movie is far from being perfect but it is even farther from being horrible. So while this movie is not one of the greatest movies ever made, I still find it to be entertaining and likable in a few ways. Well go ahead and watch this, because you will probably like it. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Artless !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Omkar Joshi
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It took me to the times when I had pets and they actually formed an integral part of my life ! The best part of the movie is it's majestic panorama - pine forests, clear streams,undisturbed stretches of open fields and grandeur of the mountains - I haven't searched about where this film was shot but will find it soon. An old craving to make a vagabond amidst nature popped up again ! Having experienced the psyche of cats and dogs closely, I enjoyed the depiction.Though cats are not as emotional as Sassy,it feels good to see it that way.Chance is a typical pup which appeals directly due to it's raw innocence.Shadow,on the contrary,adds much of the emotional flavor the movie has. All in all,the movie is a win.Only one sad thing struck my mind - I doubt if the future generations will ever experience an idyllic,artless childhood amidst a calm nature !!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fine animal movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bts1984
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a remake of the 1963 oldie 'The Incredibly Journey'. Surprisingly the plot is almost identical. The biggest difference is that this version is more movie-like and has far more humor. Another big difference is that the animals talk here, which is good because they only talk by telepathy. If they talked and moved their lips like people or like animals do in cartoons, it would be phony and ridiculous. I hate it when they do that. The older version resembles a documentary, humor is not a priority and the animals don't talk. That's just the way they are: simply animals and not human-like. More than a remake, this more recent version is a more likable and amusing film although clearly based on the old one. For those who are fond of good animal movies, I dare to say that this is an instant classic. It's very hard to find an animal film of good taste like this nowadays. This charming motion picture is heartwarming, touching, fun and contains lots of adventure, enjoyable characters and a classic soundtrack. The Sierra mountains are astonishing, being the result rich and wonderful landscapes, so beautiful that it's like a dream. As for the pets (3 great animal actors voiced by human actors who do a pretty good vocal job), Sassy and Chance are a comic relief. Shadow is wise and caring. Shadow possesses all the qualities a Golden Retriever is supposed to have, which makes him a favorite (and besides, I adore Golden Retrievers). The human characters, more precisely the family, are likable characters too and well performed by the actors. This film was followed by a sequel which is okay but lacks what makes the first one such an appreciated classic. Title in Portugal: 'Regresso a Casa'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very nice scenery and an exciting adventure, but the characters and humour generally aren't so impressive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing most of this family adventure movie as a kid. It was released early in 1993, and I think I saw it on video later that year. Towards the end, I came across a scene which I found too overwhelmingly sad, and I guess I didn't watch what little was left of the film, though I did watch the sequel, "Homeward Bound II: Lost in San Francisco", from beginning to end shortly after it was released on video in 1996. I believe it's been nearly seventeen years since I watched any of "Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey", but after all these years, I still remember it. After renting it this month, I can say I've finally seen it all. While it's not what I would call a bad movie, I was definitely not as impressed as many others clearly have been. Chance is a na&iuml;ve young Bulldog who was once stuck at the pound, a place he hated, but is now owned by a boy named Jamie Seaver. He lives with two other domestic animals: Shadow, a wise old Golden Retriever owned by Jamie's stepbrother, Peter Burnford; and Sassy, an arrogant Himalayan cat owned by Peter's sister, Hope. After Laura Burnford and Bob Seaver get married, meaning that the two families are now one, they go on a trip to San Francisco and the pets are left at a friend's ranch. Chance, Shadow, and Sassy do not understand what has just happened, and don't realize that their owners will come back, so they think they've been abandoned! Shadow decides to leave the ranch and set out to find the family, and Sassy and Chance soon follow! The three of them find themselves on a journey through the wilderness, facing the dangers of this terrain! Chance's lack of experience definitely won't help him on this adventure. The silly things Chance does and the rivalry between Chance and Sassy are meant to be comical, which they sometimes are, but not usually. Chance's antics can also get tiring after a short while. I didn't care much for these two characters, and don't think Michael J. Fox and Sally Field did a very good job providing their respective voices. Don Ameche as Shadow might be the only decent voice-over of the three, and this character is the most likable of the leads. After I started watching "Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey" this month, I soon realized how boring I found the film, and that didn't change until I got to the part where the journey begins. There's lots of beautiful scenery through the mountainous wilderness and the adventure of the three domestic animals is often exciting. Shadow's wisdom can be another intriguing aspect of the film, and some scenes are fairly touching, such as the Golden Retriever saving a little girl lost in the forest. However, there's still more weak humour during the adventure, and the scenes with the humans looking for the animals are certainly not as interesting as the ones showing the pets on their journey. None of the human characters really stand out. With a spoiler warning, I will tell you which part made me really sad all those years ago, and the ending that follows. If you haven't seen the film, you might not want to read on, but if you have, then maybe you've already guessed. It's the part where the three pets are almost home, but Shadow falls into a pit and injures his leg, and it appears he can't get out! When I watched "Homeward Bound II: Lost in San Francisco", I knew the aging dog obviously got out of the pit somehow, since he's in that sequel. After over a decade and a half, I finally found out that "Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey" doesn't show how Shadow gets out, but at the end, we see the three animals returning to their owners, even though it takes the Golden Retriever longer to show up than it does for the other two. Anyway, overall, this particular animal movie is hit-and-miss, with an exciting adventure and cute animal stars, but also with several significant shortcomings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Animal adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a story of two dogs and a cat looking for their way back home.Old and wise Golden Retriever Shadow, young American Bulldog Chance and Himalayan cat Sassy flee from the ranch and go into the wilderness to be reunited with their family.Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey (1993) is a family adventure directed by Duwayne Dunham.It's a remake of a 1963 film.This movie got a sequel three years later.Michael J. Fox is the perfect man to do the voice-over for Chance.Fox has some youthful energy he brings to the role.Sally Field does great voice work as Sassy.Don Ameche is fantastic as Shadow.This was this veteran actor's second last movie.Also the visible actors are great.Kim Greist plays Laura Burnford-Seaver.Robert Hays is Bob Seaver.Benji Thall plays Peter Burnford.Veronica Lauren is Hope Burnford.Kevin Chevalia is Jamie Seaver.Jean Smart portrays Kate.It's quite amazing to watch these pets trying to survive in the wilderness.We see Sassy taken by the river and she seems like a goner.The bear scene is exiting and funny.Chance has no chance with that big, hungry bear.And his meeting with the porcupine looks painful.This is some great fun for the whole family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Three animals go on a journey to make their way back home.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anna N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my favorite family movies. Loved it when I was little and it still holds up with me now that I'm older. I still laugh at all the same old jokes and might even shed a tear a times. I never have much cared for animals talking, or at least UN-animated ones but this one I'll stand up for. It's a pretty old movie but it will always hold a place in my heart. There aren't any other live animal movies that I can think of at the moment that I even could compare with, let alone like as much as this one. I might be giving too much praise to this movie but I don't think show. I really holds that great message that" Home is where the heart is." Or at least that's the message I gained from it. Definitely recommended for a good old family movie night.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A really nice family movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tamimarie228
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a really nice and sweet movie that the entire family can enjoy. It's about two dogs and a cat who are taken away to live with someone else for a little while but the animals don't understand and they escape and go to find the family on their own. The cat is named Sassy and she lives up to her name. Chance is the younger dog who knows a lot about life on the inside of the pound. Shadow is the older and wiser dog who senses things. Put those three together on an adventure and it makes for a happy and fun filled time. There are no special effects of the mouths moving so it isn't cheesy at all. It's the best talking animal movie that I've seen so far. It's a really good movie for families.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and beautifully filmed movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I loved Bruce Broughton's music score, very lyrical, and this alone added to the film's charm. The best aspect of the movie were the three animals, superlatively voiced by Michael J.Fox, Sally Field and the late Don Ameche. Whereas Fox has the funniest lines, Ameche plays a rather brooding otherwise engaging character(the voice of reason), and Field adds wit into a character that is always seen telling Chance off. The humans weren't as engaging, and sometimes the film dragged, but that is my only complaint. This is one beautiful-looking film, with beautiful close up shots of Canada, I believe. Although the film itself is quite long, there is never a seriously dull moment, and this is advantaged by the voice work and a well-written script. All in all, a charming and perhaps underrated film, with a 9/10 from me. Bethany Cox.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wonderful movie for all generations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jeandewey
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this movie when my children were young in the early 80's. Now 30 years later I am enjoying it again with my granddaughter. For a two year old she sits spellbound through it from beginning to end. She is always concerned when Shadow falls from the railroad tracks in to the mud and cant get out and encourages him to keep trying. My favorite scene is the suspense building as you wait for the animals to come in to view in the end and return to their owners. Waiting for Shadow to make his appearance always has the tears running down my cheeks. I know he is going to make it but it is still an emotional scene as he gains speed running to his owner. I had to order this movie to add to my granddaughters collection.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad at all, it's a great classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On a social networking site, a friend posted a screen cap of a movie with edited captions on it. The movie was of some dogs talking to each other. I looked it up and discovered this movie. I got it and watched it. My younger sister came in halfway and she is very sensitive to movies that are even a little bit scary. To give an example, she cried at the end of Open Season because she didn't think Boog would make it back home and was upset about it. So with that in mind, I watched the movie for the first time. And so I didn't have the nostalgia feeling as many did. But I still enjoyed it and could tell that it could produce that feeling for those growing up. I really liked the plot, the simplicity of the animals speaking (no moving animated mouths or anything) and the music helped to fit in with the theme. I rate this 8/10 for a brilliant movie that deserves a higher rating on IMDb than a 6.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Good, But It's Also A Little Bland.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a little kid, I absolutely adored this movie. As someone older, I am sorry, but I really didn't think that much of it. Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey is a good movie, but unfortunately it is also a little bland. What I mean is while I thought that this was a good movie, it did not think that it was a great movie, I found it a little forced and bland. But what I can say is that this movie is not totally and completely repulsive, it just didn't really do anything for me. A few positive things I can say are that the acting in this movie was good, the live-action actors did a very good job with the parts that they were given. Another thing good about this movie is the scenery and the cinematography, the scenery (especially in the wilderness) was beautiful to look at. But on the whole, while this movie is not a masterpiece of filming, I can say that I still liked it as a whole. I'll give this movie a rating of seven stars out of ten. The seven means that while this movie is far from perfect, it still is enjoyable and watchable, as well as entertaining. The biggest problem with the movie is the animals. I'm sorry if this offends anybody, but I just didn't really care for them. I understand that they were talking by telepathy, but still, that didn't suit them at all. Talking animals don't really go well in live-action movies, in cartoons, yes, in live action movies, no, just no. Another problem with the movie is the fact that it is really different from the original story. There are quite a few differences between the book and this movie. I would go on and name them, but I won't because it would take to much time to name all of them. But anyway, despite these flaws, this movie is still enjoyable to watch and be entertained. Go ahead and watch this movie if you haven't seen it yet, because who knows, you might love it. Just because I didn't really care for it that much, doesn't mean anything. You might end up loving it a whole lot! Well all in all, this movie is far from being perfect but it is even farther from being horrible. So while this movie is not one of the greatest movies ever made, I still find it to be entertaining and likable in a few ways. Well go ahead and watch this, because you will probably like it. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Artless !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Omkar Joshi
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It took me to the times when I had pets and they actually formed an integral part of my life ! The best part of the movie is it's majestic panorama - pine forests, clear streams,undisturbed stretches of open fields and grandeur of the mountains - I haven't searched about where this film was shot but will find it soon. An old craving to make a vagabond amidst nature popped up again ! Having experienced the psyche of cats and dogs closely, I enjoyed the depiction.Though cats are not as emotional as Sassy,it feels good to see it that way.Chance is a typical pup which appeals directly due to it's raw innocence.Shadow,on the contrary,adds much of the emotional flavor the movie has. All in all,the movie is a win.Only one sad thing struck my mind - I doubt if the future generations will ever experience an idyllic,artless childhood amidst a calm nature !!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fine animal movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bts1984
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a remake of the 1963 oldie 'The Incredibly Journey'. Surprisingly the plot is almost identical. The biggest difference is that this version is more movie-like and has far more humor. Another big difference is that the animals talk here, which is good because they only talk by telepathy. If they talked and moved their lips like people or like animals do in cartoons, it would be phony and ridiculous. I hate it when they do that. The older version resembles a documentary, humor is not a priority and the animals don't talk. That's just the way they are: simply animals and not human-like. More than a remake, this more recent version is a more likable and amusing film although clearly based on the old one. For those who are fond of good animal movies, I dare to say that this is an instant classic. It's very hard to find an animal film of good taste like this nowadays. This charming motion picture is heartwarming, touching, fun and contains lots of adventure, enjoyable characters and a classic soundtrack. The Sierra mountains are astonishing, being the result rich and wonderful landscapes, so beautiful that it's like a dream. As for the pets (3 great animal actors voiced by human actors who do a pretty good vocal job), Sassy and Chance are a comic relief. Shadow is wise and caring. Shadow possesses all the qualities a Golden Retriever is supposed to have, which makes him a favorite (and besides, I adore Golden Retrievers). The human characters, more precisely the family, are likable characters too and well performed by the actors. This film was followed by a sequel which is okay but lacks what makes the first one such an appreciated classic. Title in Portugal: 'Regresso a Casa'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very nice scenery and an exciting adventure, but the characters and humour generally aren't so impressive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing most of this family adventure movie as a kid. It was released early in 1993, and I think I saw it on video later that year. Towards the end, I came across a scene which I found too overwhelmingly sad, and I guess I didn't watch what little was left of the film, though I did watch the sequel, "Homeward Bound II: Lost in San Francisco", from beginning to end shortly after it was released on video in 1996. I believe it's been nearly seventeen years since I watched any of "Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey", but after all these years, I still remember it. After renting it this month, I can say I've finally seen it all. While it's not what I would call a bad movie, I was definitely not as impressed as many others clearly have been. Chance is a na&iuml;ve young Bulldog who was once stuck at the pound, a place he hated, but is now owned by a boy named Jamie Seaver. He lives with two other domestic animals: Shadow, a wise old Golden Retriever owned by Jamie's stepbrother, Peter Burnford; and Sassy, an arrogant Himalayan cat owned by Peter's sister, Hope. After Laura Burnford and Bob Seaver get married, meaning that the two families are now one, they go on a trip to San Francisco and the pets are left at a friend's ranch. Chance, Shadow, and Sassy do not understand what has just happened, and don't realize that their owners will come back, so they think they've been abandoned! Shadow decides to leave the ranch and set out to find the family, and Sassy and Chance soon follow! The three of them find themselves on a journey through the wilderness, facing the dangers of this terrain! Chance's lack of experience definitely won't help him on this adventure. The silly things Chance does and the rivalry between Chance and Sassy are meant to be comical, which they sometimes are, but not usually. Chance's antics can also get tiring after a short while. I didn't care much for these two characters, and don't think Michael J. Fox and Sally Field did a very good job providing their respective voices. Don Ameche as Shadow might be the only decent voice-over of the three, and this character is the most likable of the leads. After I started watching "Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey" this month, I soon realized how boring I found the film, and that didn't change until I got to the part where the journey begins. There's lots of beautiful scenery through the mountainous wilderness and the adventure of the three domestic animals is often exciting. Shadow's wisdom can be another intriguing aspect of the film, and some scenes are fairly touching, such as the Golden Retriever saving a little girl lost in the forest. However, there's still more weak humour during the adventure, and the scenes with the humans looking for the animals are certainly not as interesting as the ones showing the pets on their journey. None of the human characters really stand out. With a spoiler warning, I will tell you which part made me really sad all those years ago, and the ending that follows. If you haven't seen the film, you might not want to read on, but if you have, then maybe you've already guessed. It's the part where the three pets are almost home, but Shadow falls into a pit and injures his leg, and it appears he can't get out! When I watched "Homeward Bound II: Lost in San Francisco", I knew the aging dog obviously got out of the pit somehow, since he's in that sequel. After over a decade and a half, I finally found out that "Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey" doesn't show how Shadow gets out, but at the end, we see the three animals returning to their owners, even though it takes the Golden Retriever longer to show up than it does for the other two. Anyway, overall, this particular animal movie is hit-and-miss, with an exciting adventure and cute animal stars, but also with several significant shortcomings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Animal adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a story of two dogs and a cat looking for their way back home.Old and wise Golden Retriever Shadow, young American Bulldog Chance and Himalayan cat Sassy flee from the ranch and go into the wilderness to be reunited with their family.Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey (1993) is a family adventure directed by Duwayne Dunham.It's a remake of a 1963 film.This movie got a sequel three years later.Michael J. Fox is the perfect man to do the voice-over for Chance.Fox has some youthful energy he brings to the role.Sally Field does great voice work as Sassy.Don Ameche is fantastic as Shadow.This was this veteran actor's second last movie.Also the visible actors are great.Kim Greist plays Laura Burnford-Seaver.Robert Hays is Bob Seaver.Benji Thall plays Peter Burnford.Veronica Lauren is Hope Burnford.Kevin Chevalia is Jamie Seaver.Jean Smart portrays Kate.It's quite amazing to watch these pets trying to survive in the wilderness.We see Sassy taken by the river and she seems like a goner.The bear scene is exiting and funny.Chance has no chance with that big, hungry bear.And his meeting with the porcupine looks painful.This is some great fun for the whole family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Three animals go on a journey to make their way back home.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anna N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my favorite family movies. Loved it when I was little and it still holds up with me now that I'm older. I still laugh at all the same old jokes and might even shed a tear a times. I never have much cared for animals talking, or at least UN-animated ones but this one I'll stand up for. It's a pretty old movie but it will always hold a place in my heart. There aren't any other live animal movies that I can think of at the moment that I even could compare with, let alone like as much as this one. I might be giving too much praise to this movie but I don't think show. I really holds that great message that" Home is where the heart is." Or at least that's the message I gained from it. Definitely recommended for a good old family movie night.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A really nice family movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tamimarie228
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a really nice and sweet movie that the entire family can enjoy. It's about two dogs and a cat who are taken away to live with someone else for a little while but the animals don't understand and they escape and go to find the family on their own. The cat is named Sassy and she lives up to her name. Chance is the younger dog who knows a lot about life on the inside of the pound. Shadow is the older and wiser dog who senses things. Put those three together on an adventure and it makes for a happy and fun filled time. There are no special effects of the mouths moving so it isn't cheesy at all. It's the best talking animal movie that I've seen so far. It's a really good movie for families.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and beautifully filmed movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I loved Bruce Broughton's music score, very lyrical, and this alone added to the film's charm. The best aspect of the movie were the three animals, superlatively voiced by Michael J.Fox, Sally Field and the late Don Ameche. Whereas Fox has the funniest lines, Ameche plays a rather brooding otherwise engaging character(the voice of reason), and Field adds wit into a character that is always seen telling Chance off. The humans weren't as engaging, and sometimes the film dragged, but that is my only complaint. This is one beautiful-looking film, with beautiful close up shots of Canada, I believe. Although the film itself is quite long, there is never a seriously dull moment, and this is advantaged by the voice work and a well-written script. All in all, a charming and perhaps underrated film, with a 9/10 from me. Bethany Cox.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wonderful movie for all generations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jeandewey
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this movie when my children were young in the early 80's. Now 30 years later I am enjoying it again with my granddaughter. For a two year old she sits spellbound through it from beginning to end. She is always concerned when Shadow falls from the railroad tracks in to the mud and cant get out and encourages him to keep trying. My favorite scene is the suspense building as you wait for the animals to come in to view in the end and return to their owners. Waiting for Shadow to make his appearance always has the tears running down my cheeks. I know he is going to make it but it is still an emotional scene as he gains speed running to his owner. I had to order this movie to add to my granddaughters collection.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad at all, it's a great classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On a social networking site, a friend posted a screen cap of a movie with edited captions on it. The movie was of some dogs talking to each other. I looked it up and discovered this movie. I got it and watched it. My younger sister came in halfway and she is very sensitive to movies that are even a little bit scary. To give an example, she cried at the end of Open Season because she didn't think Boog would make it back home and was upset about it. So with that in mind, I watched the movie for the first time. And so I didn't have the nostalgia feeling as many did. But I still enjoyed it and could tell that it could produce that feeling for those growing up. I really liked the plot, the simplicity of the animals speaking (no moving animated mouths or anything) and the music helped to fit in with the theme. I rate this 8/10 for a brilliant movie that deserves a higher rating on IMDb than a 6.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Good, But It's Also A Little Bland.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a little kid, I absolutely adored this movie. As someone older, I am sorry, but I really didn't think that much of it. Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey is a good movie, but unfortunately it is also a little bland. What I mean is while I thought that this was a good movie, it did not think that it was a great movie, I found it a little forced and bland. But what I can say is that this movie is not totally and completely repulsive, it just didn't really do anything for me. A few positive things I can say are that the acting in this movie was good, the live-action actors did a very good job with the parts that they were given. Another thing good about this movie is the scenery and the cinematography, the scenery (especially in the wilderness) was beautiful to look at. But on the whole, while this movie is not a masterpiece of filming, I can say that I still liked it as a whole. I'll give this movie a rating of seven stars out of ten. The seven means that while this movie is far from perfect, it still is enjoyable and watchable, as well as entertaining. The biggest problem with the movie is the animals. I'm sorry if this offends anybody, but I just didn't really care for them. I understand that they were talking by telepathy, but still, that didn't suit them at all. Talking animals don't really go well in live-action movies, in cartoons, yes, in live action movies, no, just no. Another problem with the movie is the fact that it is really different from the original story. There are quite a few differences between the book and this movie. I would go on and name them, but I won't because it would take to much time to name all of them. But anyway, despite these flaws, this movie is still enjoyable to watch and be entertained. Go ahead and watch this movie if you haven't seen it yet, because who knows, you might love it. Just because I didn't really care for it that much, doesn't mean anything. You might end up loving it a whole lot! Well all in all, this movie is far from being perfect but it is even farther from being horrible. So while this movie is not one of the greatest movies ever made, I still find it to be entertaining and likable in a few ways. Well go ahead and watch this, because you will probably like it. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Artless !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Omkar Joshi
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It took me to the times when I had pets and they actually formed an integral part of my life ! The best part of the movie is it's majestic panorama - pine forests, clear streams,undisturbed stretches of open fields and grandeur of the mountains - I haven't searched about where this film was shot but will find it soon. An old craving to make a vagabond amidst nature popped up again ! Having experienced the psyche of cats and dogs closely, I enjoyed the depiction.Though cats are not as emotional as Sassy,it feels good to see it that way.Chance is a typical pup which appeals directly due to it's raw innocence.Shadow,on the contrary,adds much of the emotional flavor the movie has. All in all,the movie is a win.Only one sad thing struck my mind - I doubt if the future generations will ever experience an idyllic,artless childhood amidst a calm nature !!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fine animal movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bts1984
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a remake of the 1963 oldie 'The Incredibly Journey'. Surprisingly the plot is almost identical. The biggest difference is that this version is more movie-like and has far more humor. Another big difference is that the animals talk here, which is good because they only talk by telepathy. If they talked and moved their lips like people or like animals do in cartoons, it would be phony and ridiculous. I hate it when they do that. The older version resembles a documentary, humor is not a priority and the animals don't talk. That's just the way they are: simply animals and not human-like. More than a remake, this more recent version is a more likable and amusing film although clearly based on the old one. For those who are fond of good animal movies, I dare to say that this is an instant classic. It's very hard to find an animal film of good taste like this nowadays. This charming motion picture is heartwarming, touching, fun and contains lots of adventure, enjoyable characters and a classic soundtrack. The Sierra mountains are astonishing, being the result rich and wonderful landscapes, so beautiful that it's like a dream. As for the pets (3 great animal actors voiced by human actors who do a pretty good vocal job), Sassy and Chance are a comic relief. Shadow is wise and caring. Shadow possesses all the qualities a Golden Retriever is supposed to have, which makes him a favorite (and besides, I adore Golden Retrievers). The human characters, more precisely the family, are likable characters too and well performed by the actors. This film was followed by a sequel which is okay but lacks what makes the first one such an appreciated classic. Title in Portugal: 'Regresso a Casa'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very nice scenery and an exciting adventure, but the characters and humour generally aren't so impressive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing most of this family adventure movie as a kid. It was released early in 1993, and I think I saw it on video later that year. Towards the end, I came across a scene which I found too overwhelmingly sad, and I guess I didn't watch what little was left of the film, though I did watch the sequel, "Homeward Bound II: Lost in San Francisco", from beginning to end shortly after it was released on video in 1996. I believe it's been nearly seventeen years since I watched any of "Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey", but after all these years, I still remember it. After renting it this month, I can say I've finally seen it all. While it's not what I would call a bad movie, I was definitely not as impressed as many others clearly have been. Chance is a na&iuml;ve young Bulldog who was once stuck at the pound, a place he hated, but is now owned by a boy named Jamie Seaver. He lives with two other domestic animals: Shadow, a wise old Golden Retriever owned by Jamie's stepbrother, Peter Burnford; and Sassy, an arrogant Himalayan cat owned by Peter's sister, Hope. After Laura Burnford and Bob Seaver get married, meaning that the two families are now one, they go on a trip to San Francisco and the pets are left at a friend's ranch. Chance, Shadow, and Sassy do not understand what has just happened, and don't realize that their owners will come back, so they think they've been abandoned! Shadow decides to leave the ranch and set out to find the family, and Sassy and Chance soon follow! The three of them find themselves on a journey through the wilderness, facing the dangers of this terrain! Chance's lack of experience definitely won't help him on this adventure. The silly things Chance does and the rivalry between Chance and Sassy are meant to be comical, which they sometimes are, but not usually. Chance's antics can also get tiring after a short while. I didn't care much for these two characters, and don't think Michael J. Fox and Sally Field did a very good job providing their respective voices. Don Ameche as Shadow might be the only decent voice-over of the three, and this character is the most likable of the leads. After I started watching "Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey" this month, I soon realized how boring I found the film, and that didn't change until I got to the part where the journey begins. There's lots of beautiful scenery through the mountainous wilderness and the adventure of the three domestic animals is often exciting. Shadow's wisdom can be another intriguing aspect of the film, and some scenes are fairly touching, such as the Golden Retriever saving a little girl lost in the forest. However, there's still more weak humour during the adventure, and the scenes with the humans looking for the animals are certainly not as interesting as the ones showing the pets on their journey. None of the human characters really stand out. With a spoiler warning, I will tell you which part made me really sad all those years ago, and the ending that follows. If you haven't seen the film, you might not want to read on, but if you have, then maybe you've already guessed. It's the part where the three pets are almost home, but Shadow falls into a pit and injures his leg, and it appears he can't get out! When I watched "Homeward Bound II: Lost in San Francisco", I knew the aging dog obviously got out of the pit somehow, since he's in that sequel. After over a decade and a half, I finally found out that "Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey" doesn't show how Shadow gets out, but at the end, we see the three animals returning to their owners, even though it takes the Golden Retriever longer to show up than it does for the other two. Anyway, overall, this particular animal movie is hit-and-miss, with an exciting adventure and cute animal stars, but also with several significant shortcomings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Animal adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a story of two dogs and a cat looking for their way back home.Old and wise Golden Retriever Shadow, young American Bulldog Chance and Himalayan cat Sassy flee from the ranch and go into the wilderness to be reunited with their family.Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey (1993) is a family adventure directed by Duwayne Dunham.It's a remake of a 1963 film.This movie got a sequel three years later.Michael J. Fox is the perfect man to do the voice-over for Chance.Fox has some youthful energy he brings to the role.Sally Field does great voice work as Sassy.Don Ameche is fantastic as Shadow.This was this veteran actor's second last movie.Also the visible actors are great.Kim Greist plays Laura Burnford-Seaver.Robert Hays is Bob Seaver.Benji Thall plays Peter Burnford.Veronica Lauren is Hope Burnford.Kevin Chevalia is Jamie Seaver.Jean Smart portrays Kate.It's quite amazing to watch these pets trying to survive in the wilderness.We see Sassy taken by the river and she seems like a goner.The bear scene is exiting and funny.Chance has no chance with that big, hungry bear.And his meeting with the porcupine looks painful.This is some great fun for the whole family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Three animals go on a journey to make their way back home.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anna N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my favorite family movies. Loved it when I was little and it still holds up with me now that I'm older. I still laugh at all the same old jokes and might even shed a tear a times. I never have much cared for animals talking, or at least UN-animated ones but this one I'll stand up for. It's a pretty old movie but it will always hold a place in my heart. There aren't any other live animal movies that I can think of at the moment that I even could compare with, let alone like as much as this one. I might be giving too much praise to this movie but I don't think show. I really holds that great message that" Home is where the heart is." Or at least that's the message I gained from it. Definitely recommended for a good old family movie night.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A really nice family movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tamimarie228
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a really nice and sweet movie that the entire family can enjoy. It's about two dogs and a cat who are taken away to live with someone else for a little while but the animals don't understand and they escape and go to find the family on their own. The cat is named Sassy and she lives up to her name. Chance is the younger dog who knows a lot about life on the inside of the pound. Shadow is the older and wiser dog who senses things. Put those three together on an adventure and it makes for a happy and fun filled time. There are no special effects of the mouths moving so it isn't cheesy at all. It's the best talking animal movie that I've seen so far. It's a really good movie for families.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and beautifully filmed movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I loved Bruce Broughton's music score, very lyrical, and this alone added to the film's charm. The best aspect of the movie were the three animals, superlatively voiced by Michael J.Fox, Sally Field and the late Don Ameche. Whereas Fox has the funniest lines, Ameche plays a rather brooding otherwise engaging character(the voice of reason), and Field adds wit into a character that is always seen telling Chance off. The humans weren't as engaging, and sometimes the film dragged, but that is my only complaint. This is one beautiful-looking film, with beautiful close up shots of Canada, I believe. Although the film itself is quite long, there is never a seriously dull moment, and this is advantaged by the voice work and a well-written script. All in all, a charming and perhaps underrated film, with a 9/10 from me. Bethany Cox.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wonderful movie for all generations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jeandewey
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this movie when my children were young in the early 80's. Now 30 years later I am enjoying it again with my granddaughter. For a two year old she sits spellbound through it from beginning to end. She is always concerned when Shadow falls from the railroad tracks in to the mud and cant get out and encourages him to keep trying. My favorite scene is the suspense building as you wait for the animals to come in to view in the end and return to their owners. Waiting for Shadow to make his appearance always has the tears running down my cheeks. I know he is going to make it but it is still an emotional scene as he gains speed running to his owner. I had to order this movie to add to my granddaughters collection.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad at all, it's a great classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On a social networking site, a friend posted a screen cap of a movie with edited captions on it. The movie was of some dogs talking to each other. I looked it up and discovered this movie. I got it and watched it. My younger sister came in halfway and she is very sensitive to movies that are even a little bit scary. To give an example, she cried at the end of Open Season because she didn't think Boog would make it back home and was upset about it. So with that in mind, I watched the movie for the first time. And so I didn't have the nostalgia feeling as many did. But I still enjoyed it and could tell that it could produce that feeling for those growing up. I really liked the plot, the simplicity of the animals speaking (no moving animated mouths or anything) and the music helped to fit in with the theme. I rate this 8/10 for a brilliant movie that deserves a higher rating on IMDb than a 6.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Good, But It's Also A Little Bland.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a little kid, I absolutely adored this movie. As someone older, I am sorry, but I really didn't think that much of it. Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey is a good movie, but unfortunately it is also a little bland. What I mean is while I thought that this was a good movie, it did not think that it was a great movie, I found it a little forced and bland. But what I can say is that this movie is not totally and completely repulsive, it just didn't really do anything for me. A few positive things I can say are that the acting in this movie was good, the live-action actors did a very good job with the parts that they were given. Another thing good about this movie is the scenery and the cinematography, the scenery (especially in the wilderness) was beautiful to look at. But on the whole, while this movie is not a masterpiece of filming, I can say that I still liked it as a whole. I'll give this movie a rating of seven stars out of ten. The seven means that while this movie is far from perfect, it still is enjoyable and watchable, as well as entertaining. The biggest problem with the movie is the animals. I'm sorry if this offends anybody, but I just didn't really care for them. I understand that they were talking by telepathy, but still, that didn't suit them at all. Talking animals don't really go well in live-action movies, in cartoons, yes, in live action movies, no, just no. Another problem with the movie is the fact that it is really different from the original story. There are quite a few differences between the book and this movie. I would go on and name them, but I won't because it would take to much time to name all of them. But anyway, despite these flaws, this movie is still enjoyable to watch and be entertained. Go ahead and watch this movie if you haven't seen it yet, because who knows, you might love it. Just because I didn't really care for it that much, doesn't mean anything. You might end up loving it a whole lot! Well all in all, this movie is far from being perfect but it is even farther from being horrible. So while this movie is not one of the greatest movies ever made, I still find it to be entertaining and likable in a few ways. Well go ahead and watch this, because you will probably like it. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Artless !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Omkar Joshi
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It took me to the times when I had pets and they actually formed an integral part of my life ! The best part of the movie is it's majestic panorama - pine forests, clear streams,undisturbed stretches of open fields and grandeur of the mountains - I haven't searched about where this film was shot but will find it soon. An old craving to make a vagabond amidst nature popped up again ! Having experienced the psyche of cats and dogs closely, I enjoyed the depiction.Though cats are not as emotional as Sassy,it feels good to see it that way.Chance is a typical pup which appeals directly due to it's raw innocence.Shadow,on the contrary,adds much of the emotional flavor the movie has. All in all,the movie is a win.Only one sad thing struck my mind - I doubt if the future generations will ever experience an idyllic,artless childhood amidst a calm nature !!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fine animal movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bts1984
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a remake of the 1963 oldie 'The Incredibly Journey'. Surprisingly the plot is almost identical. The biggest difference is that this version is more movie-like and has far more humor. Another big difference is that the animals talk here, which is good because they only talk by telepathy. If they talked and moved their lips like people or like animals do in cartoons, it would be phony and ridiculous. I hate it when they do that. The older version resembles a documentary, humor is not a priority and the animals don't talk. That's just the way they are: simply animals and not human-like. More than a remake, this more recent version is a more likable and amusing film although clearly based on the old one. For those who are fond of good animal movies, I dare to say that this is an instant classic. It's very hard to find an animal film of good taste like this nowadays. This charming motion picture is heartwarming, touching, fun and contains lots of adventure, enjoyable characters and a classic soundtrack. The Sierra mountains are astonishing, being the result rich and wonderful landscapes, so beautiful that it's like a dream. As for the pets (3 great animal actors voiced by human actors who do a pretty good vocal job), Sassy and Chance are a comic relief. Shadow is wise and caring. Shadow possesses all the qualities a Golden Retriever is supposed to have, which makes him a favorite (and besides, I adore Golden Retrievers). The human characters, more precisely the family, are likable characters too and well performed by the actors. This film was followed by a sequel which is okay but lacks what makes the first one such an appreciated classic. Title in Portugal: 'Regresso a Casa'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very nice scenery and an exciting adventure, but the characters and humour generally aren't so impressive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing most of this family adventure movie as a kid. It was released early in 1993, and I think I saw it on video later that year. Towards the end, I came across a scene which I found too overwhelmingly sad, and I guess I didn't watch what little was left of the film, though I did watch the sequel, "Homeward Bound II: Lost in San Francisco", from beginning to end shortly after it was released on video in 1996. I believe it's been nearly seventeen years since I watched any of "Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey", but after all these years, I still remember it. After renting it this month, I can say I've finally seen it all. While it's not what I would call a bad movie, I was definitely not as impressed as many others clearly have been. Chance is a na&iuml;ve young Bulldog who was once stuck at the pound, a place he hated, but is now owned by a boy named Jamie Seaver. He lives with two other domestic animals: Shadow, a wise old Golden Retriever owned by Jamie's stepbrother, Peter Burnford; and Sassy, an arrogant Himalayan cat owned by Peter's sister, Hope. After Laura Burnford and Bob Seaver get married, meaning that the two families are now one, they go on a trip to San Francisco and the pets are left at a friend's ranch. Chance, Shadow, and Sassy do not understand what has just happened, and don't realize that their owners will come back, so they think they've been abandoned! Shadow decides to leave the ranch and set out to find the family, and Sassy and Chance soon follow! The three of them find themselves on a journey through the wilderness, facing the dangers of this terrain! Chance's lack of experience definitely won't help him on this adventure. The silly things Chance does and the rivalry between Chance and Sassy are meant to be comical, which they sometimes are, but not usually. Chance's antics can also get tiring after a short while. I didn't care much for these two characters, and don't think Michael J. Fox and Sally Field did a very good job providing their respective voices. Don Ameche as Shadow might be the only decent voice-over of the three, and this character is the most likable of the leads. After I started watching "Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey" this month, I soon realized how boring I found the film, and that didn't change until I got to the part where the journey begins. There's lots of beautiful scenery through the mountainous wilderness and the adventure of the three domestic animals is often exciting. Shadow's wisdom can be another intriguing aspect of the film, and some scenes are fairly touching, such as the Golden Retriever saving a little girl lost in the forest. However, there's still more weak humour during the adventure, and the scenes with the humans looking for the animals are certainly not as interesting as the ones showing the pets on their journey. None of the human characters really stand out. With a spoiler warning, I will tell you which part made me really sad all those years ago, and the ending that follows. If you haven't seen the film, you might not want to read on, but if you have, then maybe you've already guessed. It's the part where the three pets are almost home, but Shadow falls into a pit and injures his leg, and it appears he can't get out! When I watched "Homeward Bound II: Lost in San Francisco", I knew the aging dog obviously got out of the pit somehow, since he's in that sequel. After over a decade and a half, I finally found out that "Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey" doesn't show how Shadow gets out, but at the end, we see the three animals returning to their owners, even though it takes the Golden Retriever longer to show up than it does for the other two. Anyway, overall, this particular animal movie is hit-and-miss, with an exciting adventure and cute animal stars, but also with several significant shortcomings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Animal adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a story of two dogs and a cat looking for their way back home.Old and wise Golden Retriever Shadow, young American Bulldog Chance and Himalayan cat Sassy flee from the ranch and go into the wilderness to be reunited with their family.Homeward Bound: The Incredible Journey (1993) is a family adventure directed by Duwayne Dunham.It's a remake of a 1963 film.This movie got a sequel three years later.Michael J. Fox is the perfect man to do the voice-over for Chance.Fox has some youthful energy he brings to the role.Sally Field does great voice work as Sassy.Don Ameche is fantastic as Shadow.This was this veteran actor's second last movie.Also the visible actors are great.Kim Greist plays Laura Burnford-Seaver.Robert Hays is Bob Seaver.Benji Thall plays Peter Burnford.Veronica Lauren is Hope Burnford.Kevin Chevalia is Jamie Seaver.Jean Smart portrays Kate.It's quite amazing to watch these pets trying to survive in the wilderness.We see Sassy taken by the river and she seems like a goner.The bear scene is exiting and funny.Chance has no chance with that big, hungry bear.And his meeting with the porcupine looks painful.This is some great fun for the whole family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Three animals go on a journey to make their way back home.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anna N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my favorite family movies. Loved it when I was little and it still holds up with me now that I'm older. I still laugh at all the same old jokes and might even shed a tear a times. I never have much cared for animals talking, or at least UN-animated ones but this one I'll stand up for. It's a pretty old movie but it will always hold a place in my heart. There aren't any other live animal movies that I can think of at the moment that I even could compare with, let alone like as much as this one. I might be giving too much praise to this movie but I don't think show. I really holds that great message that" Home is where the heart is." Or at least that's the message I gained from it. Definitely recommended for a good old family movie night.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A really nice family movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tamimarie228
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a really nice and sweet movie that the entire family can enjoy. It's about two dogs and a cat who are taken away to live with someone else for a little while but the animals don't understand and they escape and go to find the family on their own. The cat is named Sassy and she lives up to her name. Chance is the younger dog who knows a lot about life on the inside of the pound. Shadow is the older and wiser dog who senses things. Put those three together on an adventure and it makes for a happy and fun filled time. There are no special effects of the mouths moving so it isn't cheesy at all. It's the best talking animal movie that I've seen so far. It's a really good movie for families.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and beautifully filmed movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I loved Bruce Broughton's music score, very lyrical, and this alone added to the film's charm. The best aspect of the movie were the three animals, superlatively voiced by Michael J.Fox, Sally Field and the late Don Ameche. Whereas Fox has the funniest lines, Ameche plays a rather brooding otherwise engaging character(the voice of reason), and Field adds wit into a character that is always seen telling Chance off. The humans weren't as engaging, and sometimes the film dragged, but that is my only complaint. This is one beautiful-looking film, with beautiful close up shots of Canada, I believe. Although the film itself is quite long, there is never a seriously dull moment, and this is advantaged by the voice work and a well-written script. All in all, a charming and perhaps underrated film, with a 9/10 from me. Bethany Cox.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
