<filme>
 <id>
  141
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0046672
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1954
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  20.000 L&eacute;guas Submarinas
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A ship sent to investigate a wave of mysterious sinkings encounters the advanced submarine, the Nautilus, commanded by Captain Nemo.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  The oceans during the late 1860-92s are no longer safe; many ships have been lost. Sailors have returned to port with stories of a vicious narwhal (a giant whale with a long horn) which sinks their ships. A naturalist, Professor (Pierre) Aronnax, his assistant, Conseil, and a professional whaler, Ned Land, join an US expedition which attempts to unravel the mystery.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   ocean
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   captain
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   professor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   whale
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   submarine
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Richard Fleischer
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Earl Felton
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Kirk Douglas
  </ator>
  <ator>
   James Mason
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Paul Lukas
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Fifties Sci-Fi Movie That Has Stood the Test of Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jules Verne's novel "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is set aboard an ocean-going submarine, something which did not exist when he wrote it in 1870, so it can be regarded as an early example of science fiction. (Verne had a record of making predictions which later came true; he also, for example, foresaw a journey from the Earth to the Moon). This film can be seen as an early example of the genre now called steampunk, that sub-genre of science-fiction which delights in 19th century technology, real or invented. The story tells of the adventures of Captain Nemo, the commander and designer of the submarine "Nautilus". Nemo's name, derived from the Latin for "no man", is an appropriate one, because he is a strange, mysterious figure. He is a brilliant inventor and engineer, but serves no government and no country, preferring to sail the seas with a crew who owe loyalty only to him. He is, at one and the same time, a humanitarian and a misanthropist, hating tyranny but regarding most men as unworthy of freedom. He claims to hate war, but his greatest passion is a desire for revenge on an unnamed "hated nation" whose government were responsible for the deaths of his wife and son and for his own imprisonment in a penal colony. The other main characters in the film are Professor Pierre Aronnax, a French scientist, his assistant Conseil and a sailor named Ned Land. These three are the only survivors of a shipwreck and have been reluctantly rescued by&nbsp;Nemo who sank their vessel after it fired on the "Nautilus", believing it to be a&nbsp;sea monster. Much of the dramatic tension in the film arises from the contrasting personalities of Nemo and his captives. Aronnax, a gentlemanly intellectual, initially believes Nemo to be mad, but later comes to sympathise, at least partially, with his world-view. The cocky and more plebeian Land distrusts both Aronnax and Nemo and spends most of his time formulating plans of escape. "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is therefore unusually character-driven for a science fiction film, so it is hardly surprising that four major stars, James Mason, Kirk Douglas, Paul Lukas&nbsp;and&nbsp;Peter Lorre were cast in the leading roles. (Interestingly, none of these men were of the same nationality as their characters. The Englishman Mason plays Nemo, whom Verne originally envisaged as Polish but later described as Indian. The American&nbsp;Douglas plays Land, who was originally Canadian. The Frenchmen Aronnax and Conseil are played by Lukas and Lorre, both Hungarian by birth). All four are good, but Mason is especially good as the tormented Nemo, a man who appears to be at war with the rest of humanity but who is really at war with himself, torn between his desire for revenge and his better nature which tells him that revenge is a futile pursuit. The film was directed by Richard Fleischer, a versatile director who seemed able to work in virtually any genre, including film noir ("The Armoured Car Robbery"), true crime ("Ten Rillington Place", "The Girl in the Red Velvet Swing"), the historical epic ("The Vikings"), and sword- and-sorcery fantasy ("Conan the Destroyer", "Red Sonja"). He also made a number of science-fiction films, including this one, "Fantastic Voyage" (which also involves a submarine) and "Soylent Green". Fifties sci-fi has&nbsp;a rather unenviable reputation; many films in the genre from this decade were made on a low budget, with clich&eacute;d scripts and low-quality special effects; some examples, such as the notorious "Plan 9 from Outer Space" are frequently to be found on lists of the "worst films ever made". There were, however, some very good science fiction&nbsp;films from the period,&nbsp;such as&nbsp;"Forbidden Planet", with a plot based on Shakespeare's "The Tempest", or the 1953 version of "The War of the Worlds", and "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is another in the same category. Not only does it have a humane and intelligent script and some first-rate acting performances, the special effects- so often sci-fi's Achilles heel- are actually rather good, especially during the scene where the&nbsp;"Nautilus"&nbsp; is attacked by&nbsp;a giant squid. The vessel itself looks realistic enough to be convincing, while different enough from a modern submarine to make us realised that we are watching a Victorian fantasy. This is one science fiction film that has stood the test of time. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You'll pray for a torpedo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If I were on this voyage I'd jump overboard. Harpooner Kirk Douglas, professor Paul Lukas and his apprentice Peter Lorre are taken on board the Nautilus, a submarine helmed by James Mason's Captain Nemo, after he destroys their ship. Then nothing of interest happens for an hour. Then we hit the island of cannibals and an attack by a giant squid... Nope, still not interesting. There's some fun to be had courtesy of Douglas's likable performance, but other than that there's little to recommend this flat adventure, which could do with being a good deal shorter and wastes Peter Lorre in a thankless role. In the plus column, it's better than 'Mysterious Island'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    best Disney movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bailey-86
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    my favorite Disney movie. Love it and i wish that Disney would make more Disney movies like 20,000 Leagues Under the Sea. Great movie what I love about the movie is that it's live action and animation that Walt Disney was the producer of the movie. I still watch the movie even though I am in my 20's. Great and Clean Disney movie. Love the cast including Peter Lorree, James Mason, Kirk Douglas, and Paul Lukas. Best Disney movie and appropriate for all ages and family. The movie is one of my favorite Disney movies ever made. I love it that Richard Fleschier who directed Dr. Doolittle did the perfect job directing the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic among classic adventure tales
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By 1954, Disney already had a name for itself with producing quality entertainment. So it shouldn't shock many (now) that Walt Disney decided to take on this project and adapt Jules Verne's story to the big screen. But here's the game changer, the cast has big name actors, the special effects are fantastic, the props are spectacular and the screenplay was well revised. The story takes place in the late 1800's where a Professor Aronnax (Paul Lukas) and his assistant Conseil (Peter Lorre) are put their knowledge and well being to the test when they are given the opportunity of a life time. Recently, there have been sightings of a "sea monster" attacking vessels out on the open sea. The offer, is to sail with the US navy to track down the monster and destroy it. At first the professor and his assistant were curious, but soon audiences will watch them grow and understand that the answers they were hoping for, were not even close to what they thought they could be. Aboard this ship is Ned Land (Kirk Douglas), a master harpooner who seems to have an attitude with authority but in the most lighthearted and high-spirited way. But another character that is one of the most intriguing and hard to figure out characters is Captain Nemo, brilliantly played by James Mason. The way Mason portrays his character makes it so hard to read. Mason acts with a controlled yet ferocious hatred, but it never seems like that. In fact, he may seem a little mad (crazy), but he will always use a sophisticated vocabulary. Also, for 1954 the special effects and props were so convincing. Wait until you see that giant squid! Absolutely phenomenal! And because the film is in wide screen, it looks even better. The sets either on the ships, in the water beside the choral reefs or on an island looks great. The music provided by Paul L. Smith was much welcomed too. Since Smith has worked with Disney before on various other projects like Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937), his score emits all the right feelings for each scene. The reason why I titled this as the classic among classic adventure tales because that's what it is. This is the purest of the pure in what this genre is. Setting out on a journey with no idea of what the end result may be is exactly what an adventure is. I mean, what else could you ask for? Sailing out to sea to find a monster sounds exciting and scary at the same time, plus you have cannons, island natives, underwater treasure and so on. There's just so many things to explore! Because of the top-notch acting, amazing set pieces, adventurous music and spectacular special effects, this is by far Disney's most famous live-action piece from the 1950s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Wonder of 1954
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Whitney
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this film is best appreciated when watched empowered with an education of film history, taking into consideration the technological challenges which were overcome to make it all happen successfully, appreciating the risks it entailed for the Disney Studios, and imagining how it felt for audiences who experienced it for the first time as what was truly an unprecedented under-water cinematic feat. It was the most expensive film ever made up to that time, and if you look closely you can tell that no expense was spared. Nevertheless, in our modern era of Hollywood indulgence and computer generated graphics, 20,000 Leagues under the Sea inevitably ends up feeling slightly dated & hokey at times. The movie boasts many timeless strengths though, among them being interesting characters, excellent performances, and some great intellectual dialogue/debate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Come aboard the Naultius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before there was Bio Shock. Before Steampunk became cool. There was this movie. The year is 1868, a number of sea monsters attacks in the Pacific, has cause fear among sailors. Professor Pierre M. Arrnoax (Paul Lakas) and his assistant, Conseil (Peter Lorre) were invited by the US government to find. They were attacked by the 'so called' monster, and found themselves shipwreck with Ned Land (Kirk Douglas) a sailor. Captured by the monster, they found out, it's not a monster at all, but a submarine the Naultius, captain by the mysterious Nemo. (James Mason) explorer of the ocean bottom, '20,000 Leagues Under the Sea'. What Pierre and the survivors doesn't know at first, is that Captain Nemo is border-lining between genius and madness. A man who is at war at the surface world, while being tired of war. Arrnoax knows of this, but due to his lust of knowledge, he continue to take the side of the captain, while Ned Land tries to escape. 20,000 Leagues Under the Sea is based on the science fiction novel by French writer Jules Verne with the same name. There are some big differences between the film, and the novel. The film tends to cut outs or combinded such in case-- the treasure scene and the shark. Much praise for keeping much of Captain Nemo's reasons to attack the surface world and keeping the violence and death in, for a PG movie. Without it, it wouldn't be much of a adventure. The film can be a bit outdated, thus some action scenes with the limited special effects might be a bit cheesy, but at the time, well made. It's far superior to the majority of genre efforts from the period (or any period, for that matter), with production design and technical effects that have dated hardly at all. The soundtrack is spellbinding, mysterious, and glam. The haunting classic organ music plays well into the film. |'A Whale of a Tale' by Al Hoffman and Norman Gimbel as sung by Kirk Douglas sound as real as a sailor's hymn. Kirk Douglas is the perfect fit for Ned Land. Land is everything that Nemo hates about the surface, self-centered, greedy, and ego driven. While all of the actors did great in their respectable roles, it was James Mason, that got singled out for his performance of Captain Nemo. Even the point, that Nemo's last words to Aronnax echo: is a strong message. There is hope for the future. And when the world is ready for a new and better life, all this will someday come to pass, in God's good time." It's a great adventure, so give it a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great adventure and some very strong characters.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    teryolaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great adventure. I was kinda taken aback by how cozy this movie is. I am really surprised that it was made in 1954 because the special effects are really well made for an old movie and the underwater footage is just fantastic. The movie looks great and plays great. There is something special with these older types of movies. There isn't really such a thing as mediocre acting and substance-less characters. The characters are all strong and stand out in their own special way. Whether they are taking the front or stand more in the background, like the little weasel that is the professors apprentice. I particularly like Captain Nemo's character. He is a misanthrope and the embodiment of a person who is so intelligent that there isn't much for him to do but to suffer in a cruel and inhumane world, where the rest of mankind aren't on his level. Throughout the movie we learn that while what he was saying is depressing, he was right. Ned is one proof of that. One day he saves Nemo's life. But on the day before, he made sure to act in such a way that in the end would lead to Nemo's death. As Nemo says, goodness needs to be consistent. It can't be done on impulse. The dialogue is well-written and provides insight in a natural way as to why Nemo is the way that he is. It opens up discussion rather then makes statements that can't be reflected upon. After Nemo's life is saved by Ted, I like how when the professor was trying to "talk sense" into Nemo and make him be a bit more cheerful about the world, Nemo could actually defend his point of view instead of it being just another clich&eacute; Hollywood moment where the "bad guy" is shown off as weak and fallible in his perspective of the world. And Nemo defending his view opens up a new perspective on things and makes everything about the movies morale more ambiguous, rather then it being a typical hopeful movie where everything works out great in the end. The movie is hopeful in it's own way, but it's in a way that shows you something bad and lets the audience want to make a change for the future. And in the end, he makes a point. The world isn't ready for destructive power of that kind. It is said that science fiction movies (as well as movies in general) are a reflection of the society in the era that they are being made in. And this movie was made in 54. The atom-bomb on Hirosima and Nagasaki was executed on 1945. I think that I can see a parallel there about mankind's destructive nature and immaturity. How the authorities take everything good and use it for destructive means. This is a movie about misanthropy and mankind's destructive nature. Precisely the kind of deeper themes that a science fiction is supposed to touch upon, and it does it well. Great movie. A new-found classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mighty adventure based on Jules Verne's novel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie tells about three men that have to travel against their own will in Captain Nemo's submarine called Nautilus.20000 Leagues Under the Sea (1954) is directed by Richard Fleischer.It's based on Jules Verne's novel from 1870, which I read last week.There are some differences between the book and the movie, like Esmeralda the seal, that wasn't in the book.This was the first science fiction movie produced by Walt Disney Productions.And it was also the only science fiction movie produced by Walt Disney himself.As it was the first feature length Disney movie to be distributed by Buena Vista Distribution.There is a terrific cast inside the submarine.Kirk Douglas is really something as the harpoonist Ned Land.An outstanding performance by James Mason in the role of Captain Nemo.Paul Lukas as Prof. Pierre Aronnax and Peter Lorre as his assistant Conseil are excellent.The movie has many incredible scenes, like the battle against the giant squids.The duet between Kirk Douglas and the seal is a riot.This is an adventure you don't want to miss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful fascinating futuristic adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spamobile
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wonderful adventure taking you away on the high seas to meet a mad man and his mad machine. Jules Verne is a masterful story writer. He "invented" a lot of fantastic machines and wrote his stories based on them. Although nothing was technically possible the way he invented the machines the ideas were totally back to the future, things man would take an other century to actually build. The movie is raw adventure, sailing ships, sea monsters, hero's, comedy at times, fascinating story telling. It's made when CGI was still just a bunch of letters hustled together. Special effect was still simple and so fake. But, that does not matter, the story is very entertaining. A man's man, the one and only Kirk Douglas, is one of the leading characters. You can hardly go wrong then. Keep an open mind when watching, it's an old movie, it's not perfect, it's not Oscar winning material, but it's highly entertaining fantasy world. Watch it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The singing seal delivers the most entertaining performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Buena Vista wisely opens the movie by showing the cover of 19th century edition of Jules Verne's work, and then opening to the first page. This solves the problem of explaining to the audience that this is a story set long ago about a once-futuristic submarine. The problem for contemporary audiences is that the movie is six decades old, so it is an old movie about an old story about what was once a vision of the future that is now a bit frayed. I am sympathetic to the concept, given that as a child I loved to read old books like this, as a sort of time travel into the past. And I saw this movie in a theater as a boy, though not in its first run, perhaps around the age of 8. I enjoyed it because it is a fantasy trip into imagining being aboard an ancient submarine traveling the distant oceans and down into the deep. How can a young boy resist? Children can enter into the fantasy of a movie like this. But as an adult, it didn't work, partly because I had seen it, but mainly because I'm an adult, and it takes more than a movie with mediocre acting to engross me in the experience. It took me several tries to make it through the movie this time, because every time I put it on, I looked at the acting and said, Eewwww! Many movies in the 1950s had really shallow acting, perhaps because studios found that a segment of the public actually preferred it. Here I assume, given that it is Disney, the acting is geared to children, so it is shallower still. It is a formula that worked at the time. Disney seems to have discovered this formula of simplistic, over-baked acting, and we still see it in some modern children's movies. I know it worked because I remember how I responded to movies like this as a kid. Kids generally are not looking for Laurence Olivier level acting, and are not analyzing technique. I finally made it through the movie, mainly by trying to view it through the uncritical mind of the 1950s. With the right mindset, James Mason's performance actually looks pretty good, and almost sophisticated next to Kirk Douglass' hyper-enthusiasm. They delivered the right performance for the youthful audience; Douglas was perfectly cast, and his singing was remarkably good. Paul Lukas delivers a performance of what a child might imagine a "professor" to be. The great Peter Lorre appears to be sleep walking. The best, or at least most entertaining, performance is delivered by Esmeralda, the seal, especially in the musical number with Douglas. What saves the film, at least for someone who has not previously seen it, is the story line. The question is whether it works for modern youth, particularly girls? There are some glowing reviews here, but how old are the reviewers? Frankly, I'm not impressed with Richard Fleischer's directing; a better director would have delivered a film that appeals to both children and their parents. While I am not a fan of heavy handed CGI, this is a movie that could benefit from a remake, as long as they don't try to modernize the story. But perhaps one day, when this movie is old enough, children will see in it what I saw in reading old books: a window into the past. Perhaps in 50 years, "20,000 Leagues Under the Sea" will be old enough to be interesting again. But for me, now it just looks tired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Fifties Sci-Fi Movie That Has Stood the Test of Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jules Verne's novel "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is set aboard an ocean-going submarine, something which did not exist when he wrote it in 1870, so it can be regarded as an early example of science fiction. (Verne had a record of making predictions which later came true; he also, for example, foresaw a journey from the Earth to the Moon). This film can be seen as an early example of the genre now called steampunk, that sub-genre of science-fiction which delights in 19th century technology, real or invented. The story tells of the adventures of Captain Nemo, the commander and designer of the submarine "Nautilus". Nemo's name, derived from the Latin for "no man", is an appropriate one, because he is a strange, mysterious figure. He is a brilliant inventor and engineer, but serves no government and no country, preferring to sail the seas with a crew who owe loyalty only to him. He is, at one and the same time, a humanitarian and a misanthropist, hating tyranny but regarding most men as unworthy of freedom. He claims to hate war, but his greatest passion is a desire for revenge on an unnamed "hated nation" whose government were responsible for the deaths of his wife and son and for his own imprisonment in a penal colony. The other main characters in the film are Professor Pierre Aronnax, a French scientist, his assistant Conseil and a sailor named Ned Land. These three are the only survivors of a shipwreck and have been reluctantly rescued by&nbsp;Nemo who sank their vessel after it fired on the "Nautilus", believing it to be a&nbsp;sea monster. Much of the dramatic tension in the film arises from the contrasting personalities of Nemo and his captives. Aronnax, a gentlemanly intellectual, initially believes Nemo to be mad, but later comes to sympathise, at least partially, with his world-view. The cocky and more plebeian Land distrusts both Aronnax and Nemo and spends most of his time formulating plans of escape. "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is therefore unusually character-driven for a science fiction film, so it is hardly surprising that four major stars, James Mason, Kirk Douglas, Paul Lukas&nbsp;and&nbsp;Peter Lorre were cast in the leading roles. (Interestingly, none of these men were of the same nationality as their characters. The Englishman Mason plays Nemo, whom Verne originally envisaged as Polish but later described as Indian. The American&nbsp;Douglas plays Land, who was originally Canadian. The Frenchmen Aronnax and Conseil are played by Lukas and Lorre, both Hungarian by birth). All four are good, but Mason is especially good as the tormented Nemo, a man who appears to be at war with the rest of humanity but who is really at war with himself, torn between his desire for revenge and his better nature which tells him that revenge is a futile pursuit. The film was directed by Richard Fleischer, a versatile director who seemed able to work in virtually any genre, including film noir ("The Armoured Car Robbery"), true crime ("Ten Rillington Place", "The Girl in the Red Velvet Swing"), the historical epic ("The Vikings"), and sword- and-sorcery fantasy ("Conan the Destroyer", "Red Sonja"). He also made a number of science-fiction films, including this one, "Fantastic Voyage" (which also involves a submarine) and "Soylent Green". Fifties sci-fi has&nbsp;a rather unenviable reputation; many films in the genre from this decade were made on a low budget, with clich&eacute;d scripts and low-quality special effects; some examples, such as the notorious "Plan 9 from Outer Space" are frequently to be found on lists of the "worst films ever made". There were, however, some very good science fiction&nbsp;films from the period,&nbsp;such as&nbsp;"Forbidden Planet", with a plot based on Shakespeare's "The Tempest", or the 1953 version of "The War of the Worlds", and "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is another in the same category. Not only does it have a humane and intelligent script and some first-rate acting performances, the special effects- so often sci-fi's Achilles heel- are actually rather good, especially during the scene where the&nbsp;"Nautilus"&nbsp; is attacked by&nbsp;a giant squid. The vessel itself looks realistic enough to be convincing, while different enough from a modern submarine to make us realised that we are watching a Victorian fantasy. This is one science fiction film that has stood the test of time. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You'll pray for a torpedo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If I were on this voyage I'd jump overboard. Harpooner Kirk Douglas, professor Paul Lukas and his apprentice Peter Lorre are taken on board the Nautilus, a submarine helmed by James Mason's Captain Nemo, after he destroys their ship. Then nothing of interest happens for an hour. Then we hit the island of cannibals and an attack by a giant squid... Nope, still not interesting. There's some fun to be had courtesy of Douglas's likable performance, but other than that there's little to recommend this flat adventure, which could do with being a good deal shorter and wastes Peter Lorre in a thankless role. In the plus column, it's better than 'Mysterious Island'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    best Disney movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bailey-86
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    my favorite Disney movie. Love it and i wish that Disney would make more Disney movies like 20,000 Leagues Under the Sea. Great movie what I love about the movie is that it's live action and animation that Walt Disney was the producer of the movie. I still watch the movie even though I am in my 20's. Great and Clean Disney movie. Love the cast including Peter Lorree, James Mason, Kirk Douglas, and Paul Lukas. Best Disney movie and appropriate for all ages and family. The movie is one of my favorite Disney movies ever made. I love it that Richard Fleschier who directed Dr. Doolittle did the perfect job directing the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic among classic adventure tales
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By 1954, Disney already had a name for itself with producing quality entertainment. So it shouldn't shock many (now) that Walt Disney decided to take on this project and adapt Jules Verne's story to the big screen. But here's the game changer, the cast has big name actors, the special effects are fantastic, the props are spectacular and the screenplay was well revised. The story takes place in the late 1800's where a Professor Aronnax (Paul Lukas) and his assistant Conseil (Peter Lorre) are put their knowledge and well being to the test when they are given the opportunity of a life time. Recently, there have been sightings of a "sea monster" attacking vessels out on the open sea. The offer, is to sail with the US navy to track down the monster and destroy it. At first the professor and his assistant were curious, but soon audiences will watch them grow and understand that the answers they were hoping for, were not even close to what they thought they could be. Aboard this ship is Ned Land (Kirk Douglas), a master harpooner who seems to have an attitude with authority but in the most lighthearted and high-spirited way. But another character that is one of the most intriguing and hard to figure out characters is Captain Nemo, brilliantly played by James Mason. The way Mason portrays his character makes it so hard to read. Mason acts with a controlled yet ferocious hatred, but it never seems like that. In fact, he may seem a little mad (crazy), but he will always use a sophisticated vocabulary. Also, for 1954 the special effects and props were so convincing. Wait until you see that giant squid! Absolutely phenomenal! And because the film is in wide screen, it looks even better. The sets either on the ships, in the water beside the choral reefs or on an island looks great. The music provided by Paul L. Smith was much welcomed too. Since Smith has worked with Disney before on various other projects like Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937), his score emits all the right feelings for each scene. The reason why I titled this as the classic among classic adventure tales because that's what it is. This is the purest of the pure in what this genre is. Setting out on a journey with no idea of what the end result may be is exactly what an adventure is. I mean, what else could you ask for? Sailing out to sea to find a monster sounds exciting and scary at the same time, plus you have cannons, island natives, underwater treasure and so on. There's just so many things to explore! Because of the top-notch acting, amazing set pieces, adventurous music and spectacular special effects, this is by far Disney's most famous live-action piece from the 1950s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Wonder of 1954
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Whitney
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this film is best appreciated when watched empowered with an education of film history, taking into consideration the technological challenges which were overcome to make it all happen successfully, appreciating the risks it entailed for the Disney Studios, and imagining how it felt for audiences who experienced it for the first time as what was truly an unprecedented under-water cinematic feat. It was the most expensive film ever made up to that time, and if you look closely you can tell that no expense was spared. Nevertheless, in our modern era of Hollywood indulgence and computer generated graphics, 20,000 Leagues under the Sea inevitably ends up feeling slightly dated & hokey at times. The movie boasts many timeless strengths though, among them being interesting characters, excellent performances, and some great intellectual dialogue/debate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Come aboard the Naultius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before there was Bio Shock. Before Steampunk became cool. There was this movie. The year is 1868, a number of sea monsters attacks in the Pacific, has cause fear among sailors. Professor Pierre M. Arrnoax (Paul Lakas) and his assistant, Conseil (Peter Lorre) were invited by the US government to find. They were attacked by the 'so called' monster, and found themselves shipwreck with Ned Land (Kirk Douglas) a sailor. Captured by the monster, they found out, it's not a monster at all, but a submarine the Naultius, captain by the mysterious Nemo. (James Mason) explorer of the ocean bottom, '20,000 Leagues Under the Sea'. What Pierre and the survivors doesn't know at first, is that Captain Nemo is border-lining between genius and madness. A man who is at war at the surface world, while being tired of war. Arrnoax knows of this, but due to his lust of knowledge, he continue to take the side of the captain, while Ned Land tries to escape. 20,000 Leagues Under the Sea is based on the science fiction novel by French writer Jules Verne with the same name. There are some big differences between the film, and the novel. The film tends to cut outs or combinded such in case-- the treasure scene and the shark. Much praise for keeping much of Captain Nemo's reasons to attack the surface world and keeping the violence and death in, for a PG movie. Without it, it wouldn't be much of a adventure. The film can be a bit outdated, thus some action scenes with the limited special effects might be a bit cheesy, but at the time, well made. It's far superior to the majority of genre efforts from the period (or any period, for that matter), with production design and technical effects that have dated hardly at all. The soundtrack is spellbinding, mysterious, and glam. The haunting classic organ music plays well into the film. |'A Whale of a Tale' by Al Hoffman and Norman Gimbel as sung by Kirk Douglas sound as real as a sailor's hymn. Kirk Douglas is the perfect fit for Ned Land. Land is everything that Nemo hates about the surface, self-centered, greedy, and ego driven. While all of the actors did great in their respectable roles, it was James Mason, that got singled out for his performance of Captain Nemo. Even the point, that Nemo's last words to Aronnax echo: is a strong message. There is hope for the future. And when the world is ready for a new and better life, all this will someday come to pass, in God's good time." It's a great adventure, so give it a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great adventure and some very strong characters.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    teryolaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great adventure. I was kinda taken aback by how cozy this movie is. I am really surprised that it was made in 1954 because the special effects are really well made for an old movie and the underwater footage is just fantastic. The movie looks great and plays great. There is something special with these older types of movies. There isn't really such a thing as mediocre acting and substance-less characters. The characters are all strong and stand out in their own special way. Whether they are taking the front or stand more in the background, like the little weasel that is the professors apprentice. I particularly like Captain Nemo's character. He is a misanthrope and the embodiment of a person who is so intelligent that there isn't much for him to do but to suffer in a cruel and inhumane world, where the rest of mankind aren't on his level. Throughout the movie we learn that while what he was saying is depressing, he was right. Ned is one proof of that. One day he saves Nemo's life. But on the day before, he made sure to act in such a way that in the end would lead to Nemo's death. As Nemo says, goodness needs to be consistent. It can't be done on impulse. The dialogue is well-written and provides insight in a natural way as to why Nemo is the way that he is. It opens up discussion rather then makes statements that can't be reflected upon. After Nemo's life is saved by Ted, I like how when the professor was trying to "talk sense" into Nemo and make him be a bit more cheerful about the world, Nemo could actually defend his point of view instead of it being just another clich&eacute; Hollywood moment where the "bad guy" is shown off as weak and fallible in his perspective of the world. And Nemo defending his view opens up a new perspective on things and makes everything about the movies morale more ambiguous, rather then it being a typical hopeful movie where everything works out great in the end. The movie is hopeful in it's own way, but it's in a way that shows you something bad and lets the audience want to make a change for the future. And in the end, he makes a point. The world isn't ready for destructive power of that kind. It is said that science fiction movies (as well as movies in general) are a reflection of the society in the era that they are being made in. And this movie was made in 54. The atom-bomb on Hirosima and Nagasaki was executed on 1945. I think that I can see a parallel there about mankind's destructive nature and immaturity. How the authorities take everything good and use it for destructive means. This is a movie about misanthropy and mankind's destructive nature. Precisely the kind of deeper themes that a science fiction is supposed to touch upon, and it does it well. Great movie. A new-found classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mighty adventure based on Jules Verne's novel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie tells about three men that have to travel against their own will in Captain Nemo's submarine called Nautilus.20000 Leagues Under the Sea (1954) is directed by Richard Fleischer.It's based on Jules Verne's novel from 1870, which I read last week.There are some differences between the book and the movie, like Esmeralda the seal, that wasn't in the book.This was the first science fiction movie produced by Walt Disney Productions.And it was also the only science fiction movie produced by Walt Disney himself.As it was the first feature length Disney movie to be distributed by Buena Vista Distribution.There is a terrific cast inside the submarine.Kirk Douglas is really something as the harpoonist Ned Land.An outstanding performance by James Mason in the role of Captain Nemo.Paul Lukas as Prof. Pierre Aronnax and Peter Lorre as his assistant Conseil are excellent.The movie has many incredible scenes, like the battle against the giant squids.The duet between Kirk Douglas and the seal is a riot.This is an adventure you don't want to miss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful fascinating futuristic adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spamobile
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wonderful adventure taking you away on the high seas to meet a mad man and his mad machine. Jules Verne is a masterful story writer. He "invented" a lot of fantastic machines and wrote his stories based on them. Although nothing was technically possible the way he invented the machines the ideas were totally back to the future, things man would take an other century to actually build. The movie is raw adventure, sailing ships, sea monsters, hero's, comedy at times, fascinating story telling. It's made when CGI was still just a bunch of letters hustled together. Special effect was still simple and so fake. But, that does not matter, the story is very entertaining. A man's man, the one and only Kirk Douglas, is one of the leading characters. You can hardly go wrong then. Keep an open mind when watching, it's an old movie, it's not perfect, it's not Oscar winning material, but it's highly entertaining fantasy world. Watch it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The singing seal delivers the most entertaining performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Buena Vista wisely opens the movie by showing the cover of 19th century edition of Jules Verne's work, and then opening to the first page. This solves the problem of explaining to the audience that this is a story set long ago about a once-futuristic submarine. The problem for contemporary audiences is that the movie is six decades old, so it is an old movie about an old story about what was once a vision of the future that is now a bit frayed. I am sympathetic to the concept, given that as a child I loved to read old books like this, as a sort of time travel into the past. And I saw this movie in a theater as a boy, though not in its first run, perhaps around the age of 8. I enjoyed it because it is a fantasy trip into imagining being aboard an ancient submarine traveling the distant oceans and down into the deep. How can a young boy resist? Children can enter into the fantasy of a movie like this. But as an adult, it didn't work, partly because I had seen it, but mainly because I'm an adult, and it takes more than a movie with mediocre acting to engross me in the experience. It took me several tries to make it through the movie this time, because every time I put it on, I looked at the acting and said, Eewwww! Many movies in the 1950s had really shallow acting, perhaps because studios found that a segment of the public actually preferred it. Here I assume, given that it is Disney, the acting is geared to children, so it is shallower still. It is a formula that worked at the time. Disney seems to have discovered this formula of simplistic, over-baked acting, and we still see it in some modern children's movies. I know it worked because I remember how I responded to movies like this as a kid. Kids generally are not looking for Laurence Olivier level acting, and are not analyzing technique. I finally made it through the movie, mainly by trying to view it through the uncritical mind of the 1950s. With the right mindset, James Mason's performance actually looks pretty good, and almost sophisticated next to Kirk Douglass' hyper-enthusiasm. They delivered the right performance for the youthful audience; Douglas was perfectly cast, and his singing was remarkably good. Paul Lukas delivers a performance of what a child might imagine a "professor" to be. The great Peter Lorre appears to be sleep walking. The best, or at least most entertaining, performance is delivered by Esmeralda, the seal, especially in the musical number with Douglas. What saves the film, at least for someone who has not previously seen it, is the story line. The question is whether it works for modern youth, particularly girls? There are some glowing reviews here, but how old are the reviewers? Frankly, I'm not impressed with Richard Fleischer's directing; a better director would have delivered a film that appeals to both children and their parents. While I am not a fan of heavy handed CGI, this is a movie that could benefit from a remake, as long as they don't try to modernize the story. But perhaps one day, when this movie is old enough, children will see in it what I saw in reading old books: a window into the past. Perhaps in 50 years, "20,000 Leagues Under the Sea" will be old enough to be interesting again. But for me, now it just looks tired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Fifties Sci-Fi Movie That Has Stood the Test of Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jules Verne's novel "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is set aboard an ocean-going submarine, something which did not exist when he wrote it in 1870, so it can be regarded as an early example of science fiction. (Verne had a record of making predictions which later came true; he also, for example, foresaw a journey from the Earth to the Moon). This film can be seen as an early example of the genre now called steampunk, that sub-genre of science-fiction which delights in 19th century technology, real or invented. The story tells of the adventures of Captain Nemo, the commander and designer of the submarine "Nautilus". Nemo's name, derived from the Latin for "no man", is an appropriate one, because he is a strange, mysterious figure. He is a brilliant inventor and engineer, but serves no government and no country, preferring to sail the seas with a crew who owe loyalty only to him. He is, at one and the same time, a humanitarian and a misanthropist, hating tyranny but regarding most men as unworthy of freedom. He claims to hate war, but his greatest passion is a desire for revenge on an unnamed "hated nation" whose government were responsible for the deaths of his wife and son and for his own imprisonment in a penal colony. The other main characters in the film are Professor Pierre Aronnax, a French scientist, his assistant Conseil and a sailor named Ned Land. These three are the only survivors of a shipwreck and have been reluctantly rescued by&nbsp;Nemo who sank their vessel after it fired on the "Nautilus", believing it to be a&nbsp;sea monster. Much of the dramatic tension in the film arises from the contrasting personalities of Nemo and his captives. Aronnax, a gentlemanly intellectual, initially believes Nemo to be mad, but later comes to sympathise, at least partially, with his world-view. The cocky and more plebeian Land distrusts both Aronnax and Nemo and spends most of his time formulating plans of escape. "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is therefore unusually character-driven for a science fiction film, so it is hardly surprising that four major stars, James Mason, Kirk Douglas, Paul Lukas&nbsp;and&nbsp;Peter Lorre were cast in the leading roles. (Interestingly, none of these men were of the same nationality as their characters. The Englishman Mason plays Nemo, whom Verne originally envisaged as Polish but later described as Indian. The American&nbsp;Douglas plays Land, who was originally Canadian. The Frenchmen Aronnax and Conseil are played by Lukas and Lorre, both Hungarian by birth). All four are good, but Mason is especially good as the tormented Nemo, a man who appears to be at war with the rest of humanity but who is really at war with himself, torn between his desire for revenge and his better nature which tells him that revenge is a futile pursuit. The film was directed by Richard Fleischer, a versatile director who seemed able to work in virtually any genre, including film noir ("The Armoured Car Robbery"), true crime ("Ten Rillington Place", "The Girl in the Red Velvet Swing"), the historical epic ("The Vikings"), and sword- and-sorcery fantasy ("Conan the Destroyer", "Red Sonja"). He also made a number of science-fiction films, including this one, "Fantastic Voyage" (which also involves a submarine) and "Soylent Green". Fifties sci-fi has&nbsp;a rather unenviable reputation; many films in the genre from this decade were made on a low budget, with clich&eacute;d scripts and low-quality special effects; some examples, such as the notorious "Plan 9 from Outer Space" are frequently to be found on lists of the "worst films ever made". There were, however, some very good science fiction&nbsp;films from the period,&nbsp;such as&nbsp;"Forbidden Planet", with a plot based on Shakespeare's "The Tempest", or the 1953 version of "The War of the Worlds", and "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is another in the same category. Not only does it have a humane and intelligent script and some first-rate acting performances, the special effects- so often sci-fi's Achilles heel- are actually rather good, especially during the scene where the&nbsp;"Nautilus"&nbsp; is attacked by&nbsp;a giant squid. The vessel itself looks realistic enough to be convincing, while different enough from a modern submarine to make us realised that we are watching a Victorian fantasy. This is one science fiction film that has stood the test of time. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You'll pray for a torpedo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If I were on this voyage I'd jump overboard. Harpooner Kirk Douglas, professor Paul Lukas and his apprentice Peter Lorre are taken on board the Nautilus, a submarine helmed by James Mason's Captain Nemo, after he destroys their ship. Then nothing of interest happens for an hour. Then we hit the island of cannibals and an attack by a giant squid... Nope, still not interesting. There's some fun to be had courtesy of Douglas's likable performance, but other than that there's little to recommend this flat adventure, which could do with being a good deal shorter and wastes Peter Lorre in a thankless role. In the plus column, it's better than 'Mysterious Island'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    best Disney movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bailey-86
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    my favorite Disney movie. Love it and i wish that Disney would make more Disney movies like 20,000 Leagues Under the Sea. Great movie what I love about the movie is that it's live action and animation that Walt Disney was the producer of the movie. I still watch the movie even though I am in my 20's. Great and Clean Disney movie. Love the cast including Peter Lorree, James Mason, Kirk Douglas, and Paul Lukas. Best Disney movie and appropriate for all ages and family. The movie is one of my favorite Disney movies ever made. I love it that Richard Fleschier who directed Dr. Doolittle did the perfect job directing the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic among classic adventure tales
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By 1954, Disney already had a name for itself with producing quality entertainment. So it shouldn't shock many (now) that Walt Disney decided to take on this project and adapt Jules Verne's story to the big screen. But here's the game changer, the cast has big name actors, the special effects are fantastic, the props are spectacular and the screenplay was well revised. The story takes place in the late 1800's where a Professor Aronnax (Paul Lukas) and his assistant Conseil (Peter Lorre) are put their knowledge and well being to the test when they are given the opportunity of a life time. Recently, there have been sightings of a "sea monster" attacking vessels out on the open sea. The offer, is to sail with the US navy to track down the monster and destroy it. At first the professor and his assistant were curious, but soon audiences will watch them grow and understand that the answers they were hoping for, were not even close to what they thought they could be. Aboard this ship is Ned Land (Kirk Douglas), a master harpooner who seems to have an attitude with authority but in the most lighthearted and high-spirited way. But another character that is one of the most intriguing and hard to figure out characters is Captain Nemo, brilliantly played by James Mason. The way Mason portrays his character makes it so hard to read. Mason acts with a controlled yet ferocious hatred, but it never seems like that. In fact, he may seem a little mad (crazy), but he will always use a sophisticated vocabulary. Also, for 1954 the special effects and props were so convincing. Wait until you see that giant squid! Absolutely phenomenal! And because the film is in wide screen, it looks even better. The sets either on the ships, in the water beside the choral reefs or on an island looks great. The music provided by Paul L. Smith was much welcomed too. Since Smith has worked with Disney before on various other projects like Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937), his score emits all the right feelings for each scene. The reason why I titled this as the classic among classic adventure tales because that's what it is. This is the purest of the pure in what this genre is. Setting out on a journey with no idea of what the end result may be is exactly what an adventure is. I mean, what else could you ask for? Sailing out to sea to find a monster sounds exciting and scary at the same time, plus you have cannons, island natives, underwater treasure and so on. There's just so many things to explore! Because of the top-notch acting, amazing set pieces, adventurous music and spectacular special effects, this is by far Disney's most famous live-action piece from the 1950s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Wonder of 1954
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Whitney
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this film is best appreciated when watched empowered with an education of film history, taking into consideration the technological challenges which were overcome to make it all happen successfully, appreciating the risks it entailed for the Disney Studios, and imagining how it felt for audiences who experienced it for the first time as what was truly an unprecedented under-water cinematic feat. It was the most expensive film ever made up to that time, and if you look closely you can tell that no expense was spared. Nevertheless, in our modern era of Hollywood indulgence and computer generated graphics, 20,000 Leagues under the Sea inevitably ends up feeling slightly dated & hokey at times. The movie boasts many timeless strengths though, among them being interesting characters, excellent performances, and some great intellectual dialogue/debate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Come aboard the Naultius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before there was Bio Shock. Before Steampunk became cool. There was this movie. The year is 1868, a number of sea monsters attacks in the Pacific, has cause fear among sailors. Professor Pierre M. Arrnoax (Paul Lakas) and his assistant, Conseil (Peter Lorre) were invited by the US government to find. They were attacked by the 'so called' monster, and found themselves shipwreck with Ned Land (Kirk Douglas) a sailor. Captured by the monster, they found out, it's not a monster at all, but a submarine the Naultius, captain by the mysterious Nemo. (James Mason) explorer of the ocean bottom, '20,000 Leagues Under the Sea'. What Pierre and the survivors doesn't know at first, is that Captain Nemo is border-lining between genius and madness. A man who is at war at the surface world, while being tired of war. Arrnoax knows of this, but due to his lust of knowledge, he continue to take the side of the captain, while Ned Land tries to escape. 20,000 Leagues Under the Sea is based on the science fiction novel by French writer Jules Verne with the same name. There are some big differences between the film, and the novel. The film tends to cut outs or combinded such in case-- the treasure scene and the shark. Much praise for keeping much of Captain Nemo's reasons to attack the surface world and keeping the violence and death in, for a PG movie. Without it, it wouldn't be much of a adventure. The film can be a bit outdated, thus some action scenes with the limited special effects might be a bit cheesy, but at the time, well made. It's far superior to the majority of genre efforts from the period (or any period, for that matter), with production design and technical effects that have dated hardly at all. The soundtrack is spellbinding, mysterious, and glam. The haunting classic organ music plays well into the film. |'A Whale of a Tale' by Al Hoffman and Norman Gimbel as sung by Kirk Douglas sound as real as a sailor's hymn. Kirk Douglas is the perfect fit for Ned Land. Land is everything that Nemo hates about the surface, self-centered, greedy, and ego driven. While all of the actors did great in their respectable roles, it was James Mason, that got singled out for his performance of Captain Nemo. Even the point, that Nemo's last words to Aronnax echo: is a strong message. There is hope for the future. And when the world is ready for a new and better life, all this will someday come to pass, in God's good time." It's a great adventure, so give it a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great adventure and some very strong characters.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    teryolaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great adventure. I was kinda taken aback by how cozy this movie is. I am really surprised that it was made in 1954 because the special effects are really well made for an old movie and the underwater footage is just fantastic. The movie looks great and plays great. There is something special with these older types of movies. There isn't really such a thing as mediocre acting and substance-less characters. The characters are all strong and stand out in their own special way. Whether they are taking the front or stand more in the background, like the little weasel that is the professors apprentice. I particularly like Captain Nemo's character. He is a misanthrope and the embodiment of a person who is so intelligent that there isn't much for him to do but to suffer in a cruel and inhumane world, where the rest of mankind aren't on his level. Throughout the movie we learn that while what he was saying is depressing, he was right. Ned is one proof of that. One day he saves Nemo's life. But on the day before, he made sure to act in such a way that in the end would lead to Nemo's death. As Nemo says, goodness needs to be consistent. It can't be done on impulse. The dialogue is well-written and provides insight in a natural way as to why Nemo is the way that he is. It opens up discussion rather then makes statements that can't be reflected upon. After Nemo's life is saved by Ted, I like how when the professor was trying to "talk sense" into Nemo and make him be a bit more cheerful about the world, Nemo could actually defend his point of view instead of it being just another clich&eacute; Hollywood moment where the "bad guy" is shown off as weak and fallible in his perspective of the world. And Nemo defending his view opens up a new perspective on things and makes everything about the movies morale more ambiguous, rather then it being a typical hopeful movie where everything works out great in the end. The movie is hopeful in it's own way, but it's in a way that shows you something bad and lets the audience want to make a change for the future. And in the end, he makes a point. The world isn't ready for destructive power of that kind. It is said that science fiction movies (as well as movies in general) are a reflection of the society in the era that they are being made in. And this movie was made in 54. The atom-bomb on Hirosima and Nagasaki was executed on 1945. I think that I can see a parallel there about mankind's destructive nature and immaturity. How the authorities take everything good and use it for destructive means. This is a movie about misanthropy and mankind's destructive nature. Precisely the kind of deeper themes that a science fiction is supposed to touch upon, and it does it well. Great movie. A new-found classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mighty adventure based on Jules Verne's novel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie tells about three men that have to travel against their own will in Captain Nemo's submarine called Nautilus.20000 Leagues Under the Sea (1954) is directed by Richard Fleischer.It's based on Jules Verne's novel from 1870, which I read last week.There are some differences between the book and the movie, like Esmeralda the seal, that wasn't in the book.This was the first science fiction movie produced by Walt Disney Productions.And it was also the only science fiction movie produced by Walt Disney himself.As it was the first feature length Disney movie to be distributed by Buena Vista Distribution.There is a terrific cast inside the submarine.Kirk Douglas is really something as the harpoonist Ned Land.An outstanding performance by James Mason in the role of Captain Nemo.Paul Lukas as Prof. Pierre Aronnax and Peter Lorre as his assistant Conseil are excellent.The movie has many incredible scenes, like the battle against the giant squids.The duet between Kirk Douglas and the seal is a riot.This is an adventure you don't want to miss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful fascinating futuristic adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spamobile
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wonderful adventure taking you away on the high seas to meet a mad man and his mad machine. Jules Verne is a masterful story writer. He "invented" a lot of fantastic machines and wrote his stories based on them. Although nothing was technically possible the way he invented the machines the ideas were totally back to the future, things man would take an other century to actually build. The movie is raw adventure, sailing ships, sea monsters, hero's, comedy at times, fascinating story telling. It's made when CGI was still just a bunch of letters hustled together. Special effect was still simple and so fake. But, that does not matter, the story is very entertaining. A man's man, the one and only Kirk Douglas, is one of the leading characters. You can hardly go wrong then. Keep an open mind when watching, it's an old movie, it's not perfect, it's not Oscar winning material, but it's highly entertaining fantasy world. Watch it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The singing seal delivers the most entertaining performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Buena Vista wisely opens the movie by showing the cover of 19th century edition of Jules Verne's work, and then opening to the first page. This solves the problem of explaining to the audience that this is a story set long ago about a once-futuristic submarine. The problem for contemporary audiences is that the movie is six decades old, so it is an old movie about an old story about what was once a vision of the future that is now a bit frayed. I am sympathetic to the concept, given that as a child I loved to read old books like this, as a sort of time travel into the past. And I saw this movie in a theater as a boy, though not in its first run, perhaps around the age of 8. I enjoyed it because it is a fantasy trip into imagining being aboard an ancient submarine traveling the distant oceans and down into the deep. How can a young boy resist? Children can enter into the fantasy of a movie like this. But as an adult, it didn't work, partly because I had seen it, but mainly because I'm an adult, and it takes more than a movie with mediocre acting to engross me in the experience. It took me several tries to make it through the movie this time, because every time I put it on, I looked at the acting and said, Eewwww! Many movies in the 1950s had really shallow acting, perhaps because studios found that a segment of the public actually preferred it. Here I assume, given that it is Disney, the acting is geared to children, so it is shallower still. It is a formula that worked at the time. Disney seems to have discovered this formula of simplistic, over-baked acting, and we still see it in some modern children's movies. I know it worked because I remember how I responded to movies like this as a kid. Kids generally are not looking for Laurence Olivier level acting, and are not analyzing technique. I finally made it through the movie, mainly by trying to view it through the uncritical mind of the 1950s. With the right mindset, James Mason's performance actually looks pretty good, and almost sophisticated next to Kirk Douglass' hyper-enthusiasm. They delivered the right performance for the youthful audience; Douglas was perfectly cast, and his singing was remarkably good. Paul Lukas delivers a performance of what a child might imagine a "professor" to be. The great Peter Lorre appears to be sleep walking. The best, or at least most entertaining, performance is delivered by Esmeralda, the seal, especially in the musical number with Douglas. What saves the film, at least for someone who has not previously seen it, is the story line. The question is whether it works for modern youth, particularly girls? There are some glowing reviews here, but how old are the reviewers? Frankly, I'm not impressed with Richard Fleischer's directing; a better director would have delivered a film that appeals to both children and their parents. While I am not a fan of heavy handed CGI, this is a movie that could benefit from a remake, as long as they don't try to modernize the story. But perhaps one day, when this movie is old enough, children will see in it what I saw in reading old books: a window into the past. Perhaps in 50 years, "20,000 Leagues Under the Sea" will be old enough to be interesting again. But for me, now it just looks tired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Fifties Sci-Fi Movie That Has Stood the Test of Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jules Verne's novel "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is set aboard an ocean-going submarine, something which did not exist when he wrote it in 1870, so it can be regarded as an early example of science fiction. (Verne had a record of making predictions which later came true; he also, for example, foresaw a journey from the Earth to the Moon). This film can be seen as an early example of the genre now called steampunk, that sub-genre of science-fiction which delights in 19th century technology, real or invented. The story tells of the adventures of Captain Nemo, the commander and designer of the submarine "Nautilus". Nemo's name, derived from the Latin for "no man", is an appropriate one, because he is a strange, mysterious figure. He is a brilliant inventor and engineer, but serves no government and no country, preferring to sail the seas with a crew who owe loyalty only to him. He is, at one and the same time, a humanitarian and a misanthropist, hating tyranny but regarding most men as unworthy of freedom. He claims to hate war, but his greatest passion is a desire for revenge on an unnamed "hated nation" whose government were responsible for the deaths of his wife and son and for his own imprisonment in a penal colony. The other main characters in the film are Professor Pierre Aronnax, a French scientist, his assistant Conseil and a sailor named Ned Land. These three are the only survivors of a shipwreck and have been reluctantly rescued by&nbsp;Nemo who sank their vessel after it fired on the "Nautilus", believing it to be a&nbsp;sea monster. Much of the dramatic tension in the film arises from the contrasting personalities of Nemo and his captives. Aronnax, a gentlemanly intellectual, initially believes Nemo to be mad, but later comes to sympathise, at least partially, with his world-view. The cocky and more plebeian Land distrusts both Aronnax and Nemo and spends most of his time formulating plans of escape. "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is therefore unusually character-driven for a science fiction film, so it is hardly surprising that four major stars, James Mason, Kirk Douglas, Paul Lukas&nbsp;and&nbsp;Peter Lorre were cast in the leading roles. (Interestingly, none of these men were of the same nationality as their characters. The Englishman Mason plays Nemo, whom Verne originally envisaged as Polish but later described as Indian. The American&nbsp;Douglas plays Land, who was originally Canadian. The Frenchmen Aronnax and Conseil are played by Lukas and Lorre, both Hungarian by birth). All four are good, but Mason is especially good as the tormented Nemo, a man who appears to be at war with the rest of humanity but who is really at war with himself, torn between his desire for revenge and his better nature which tells him that revenge is a futile pursuit. The film was directed by Richard Fleischer, a versatile director who seemed able to work in virtually any genre, including film noir ("The Armoured Car Robbery"), true crime ("Ten Rillington Place", "The Girl in the Red Velvet Swing"), the historical epic ("The Vikings"), and sword- and-sorcery fantasy ("Conan the Destroyer", "Red Sonja"). He also made a number of science-fiction films, including this one, "Fantastic Voyage" (which also involves a submarine) and "Soylent Green". Fifties sci-fi has&nbsp;a rather unenviable reputation; many films in the genre from this decade were made on a low budget, with clich&eacute;d scripts and low-quality special effects; some examples, such as the notorious "Plan 9 from Outer Space" are frequently to be found on lists of the "worst films ever made". There were, however, some very good science fiction&nbsp;films from the period,&nbsp;such as&nbsp;"Forbidden Planet", with a plot based on Shakespeare's "The Tempest", or the 1953 version of "The War of the Worlds", and "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is another in the same category. Not only does it have a humane and intelligent script and some first-rate acting performances, the special effects- so often sci-fi's Achilles heel- are actually rather good, especially during the scene where the&nbsp;"Nautilus"&nbsp; is attacked by&nbsp;a giant squid. The vessel itself looks realistic enough to be convincing, while different enough from a modern submarine to make us realised that we are watching a Victorian fantasy. This is one science fiction film that has stood the test of time. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You'll pray for a torpedo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If I were on this voyage I'd jump overboard. Harpooner Kirk Douglas, professor Paul Lukas and his apprentice Peter Lorre are taken on board the Nautilus, a submarine helmed by James Mason's Captain Nemo, after he destroys their ship. Then nothing of interest happens for an hour. Then we hit the island of cannibals and an attack by a giant squid... Nope, still not interesting. There's some fun to be had courtesy of Douglas's likable performance, but other than that there's little to recommend this flat adventure, which could do with being a good deal shorter and wastes Peter Lorre in a thankless role. In the plus column, it's better than 'Mysterious Island'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    best Disney movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bailey-86
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    my favorite Disney movie. Love it and i wish that Disney would make more Disney movies like 20,000 Leagues Under the Sea. Great movie what I love about the movie is that it's live action and animation that Walt Disney was the producer of the movie. I still watch the movie even though I am in my 20's. Great and Clean Disney movie. Love the cast including Peter Lorree, James Mason, Kirk Douglas, and Paul Lukas. Best Disney movie and appropriate for all ages and family. The movie is one of my favorite Disney movies ever made. I love it that Richard Fleschier who directed Dr. Doolittle did the perfect job directing the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic among classic adventure tales
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By 1954, Disney already had a name for itself with producing quality entertainment. So it shouldn't shock many (now) that Walt Disney decided to take on this project and adapt Jules Verne's story to the big screen. But here's the game changer, the cast has big name actors, the special effects are fantastic, the props are spectacular and the screenplay was well revised. The story takes place in the late 1800's where a Professor Aronnax (Paul Lukas) and his assistant Conseil (Peter Lorre) are put their knowledge and well being to the test when they are given the opportunity of a life time. Recently, there have been sightings of a "sea monster" attacking vessels out on the open sea. The offer, is to sail with the US navy to track down the monster and destroy it. At first the professor and his assistant were curious, but soon audiences will watch them grow and understand that the answers they were hoping for, were not even close to what they thought they could be. Aboard this ship is Ned Land (Kirk Douglas), a master harpooner who seems to have an attitude with authority but in the most lighthearted and high-spirited way. But another character that is one of the most intriguing and hard to figure out characters is Captain Nemo, brilliantly played by James Mason. The way Mason portrays his character makes it so hard to read. Mason acts with a controlled yet ferocious hatred, but it never seems like that. In fact, he may seem a little mad (crazy), but he will always use a sophisticated vocabulary. Also, for 1954 the special effects and props were so convincing. Wait until you see that giant squid! Absolutely phenomenal! And because the film is in wide screen, it looks even better. The sets either on the ships, in the water beside the choral reefs or on an island looks great. The music provided by Paul L. Smith was much welcomed too. Since Smith has worked with Disney before on various other projects like Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937), his score emits all the right feelings for each scene. The reason why I titled this as the classic among classic adventure tales because that's what it is. This is the purest of the pure in what this genre is. Setting out on a journey with no idea of what the end result may be is exactly what an adventure is. I mean, what else could you ask for? Sailing out to sea to find a monster sounds exciting and scary at the same time, plus you have cannons, island natives, underwater treasure and so on. There's just so many things to explore! Because of the top-notch acting, amazing set pieces, adventurous music and spectacular special effects, this is by far Disney's most famous live-action piece from the 1950s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Wonder of 1954
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Whitney
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this film is best appreciated when watched empowered with an education of film history, taking into consideration the technological challenges which were overcome to make it all happen successfully, appreciating the risks it entailed for the Disney Studios, and imagining how it felt for audiences who experienced it for the first time as what was truly an unprecedented under-water cinematic feat. It was the most expensive film ever made up to that time, and if you look closely you can tell that no expense was spared. Nevertheless, in our modern era of Hollywood indulgence and computer generated graphics, 20,000 Leagues under the Sea inevitably ends up feeling slightly dated & hokey at times. The movie boasts many timeless strengths though, among them being interesting characters, excellent performances, and some great intellectual dialogue/debate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Come aboard the Naultius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before there was Bio Shock. Before Steampunk became cool. There was this movie. The year is 1868, a number of sea monsters attacks in the Pacific, has cause fear among sailors. Professor Pierre M. Arrnoax (Paul Lakas) and his assistant, Conseil (Peter Lorre) were invited by the US government to find. They were attacked by the 'so called' monster, and found themselves shipwreck with Ned Land (Kirk Douglas) a sailor. Captured by the monster, they found out, it's not a monster at all, but a submarine the Naultius, captain by the mysterious Nemo. (James Mason) explorer of the ocean bottom, '20,000 Leagues Under the Sea'. What Pierre and the survivors doesn't know at first, is that Captain Nemo is border-lining between genius and madness. A man who is at war at the surface world, while being tired of war. Arrnoax knows of this, but due to his lust of knowledge, he continue to take the side of the captain, while Ned Land tries to escape. 20,000 Leagues Under the Sea is based on the science fiction novel by French writer Jules Verne with the same name. There are some big differences between the film, and the novel. The film tends to cut outs or combinded such in case-- the treasure scene and the shark. Much praise for keeping much of Captain Nemo's reasons to attack the surface world and keeping the violence and death in, for a PG movie. Without it, it wouldn't be much of a adventure. The film can be a bit outdated, thus some action scenes with the limited special effects might be a bit cheesy, but at the time, well made. It's far superior to the majority of genre efforts from the period (or any period, for that matter), with production design and technical effects that have dated hardly at all. The soundtrack is spellbinding, mysterious, and glam. The haunting classic organ music plays well into the film. |'A Whale of a Tale' by Al Hoffman and Norman Gimbel as sung by Kirk Douglas sound as real as a sailor's hymn. Kirk Douglas is the perfect fit for Ned Land. Land is everything that Nemo hates about the surface, self-centered, greedy, and ego driven. While all of the actors did great in their respectable roles, it was James Mason, that got singled out for his performance of Captain Nemo. Even the point, that Nemo's last words to Aronnax echo: is a strong message. There is hope for the future. And when the world is ready for a new and better life, all this will someday come to pass, in God's good time." It's a great adventure, so give it a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great adventure and some very strong characters.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    teryolaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great adventure. I was kinda taken aback by how cozy this movie is. I am really surprised that it was made in 1954 because the special effects are really well made for an old movie and the underwater footage is just fantastic. The movie looks great and plays great. There is something special with these older types of movies. There isn't really such a thing as mediocre acting and substance-less characters. The characters are all strong and stand out in their own special way. Whether they are taking the front or stand more in the background, like the little weasel that is the professors apprentice. I particularly like Captain Nemo's character. He is a misanthrope and the embodiment of a person who is so intelligent that there isn't much for him to do but to suffer in a cruel and inhumane world, where the rest of mankind aren't on his level. Throughout the movie we learn that while what he was saying is depressing, he was right. Ned is one proof of that. One day he saves Nemo's life. But on the day before, he made sure to act in such a way that in the end would lead to Nemo's death. As Nemo says, goodness needs to be consistent. It can't be done on impulse. The dialogue is well-written and provides insight in a natural way as to why Nemo is the way that he is. It opens up discussion rather then makes statements that can't be reflected upon. After Nemo's life is saved by Ted, I like how when the professor was trying to "talk sense" into Nemo and make him be a bit more cheerful about the world, Nemo could actually defend his point of view instead of it being just another clich&eacute; Hollywood moment where the "bad guy" is shown off as weak and fallible in his perspective of the world. And Nemo defending his view opens up a new perspective on things and makes everything about the movies morale more ambiguous, rather then it being a typical hopeful movie where everything works out great in the end. The movie is hopeful in it's own way, but it's in a way that shows you something bad and lets the audience want to make a change for the future. And in the end, he makes a point. The world isn't ready for destructive power of that kind. It is said that science fiction movies (as well as movies in general) are a reflection of the society in the era that they are being made in. And this movie was made in 54. The atom-bomb on Hirosima and Nagasaki was executed on 1945. I think that I can see a parallel there about mankind's destructive nature and immaturity. How the authorities take everything good and use it for destructive means. This is a movie about misanthropy and mankind's destructive nature. Precisely the kind of deeper themes that a science fiction is supposed to touch upon, and it does it well. Great movie. A new-found classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mighty adventure based on Jules Verne's novel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie tells about three men that have to travel against their own will in Captain Nemo's submarine called Nautilus.20000 Leagues Under the Sea (1954) is directed by Richard Fleischer.It's based on Jules Verne's novel from 1870, which I read last week.There are some differences between the book and the movie, like Esmeralda the seal, that wasn't in the book.This was the first science fiction movie produced by Walt Disney Productions.And it was also the only science fiction movie produced by Walt Disney himself.As it was the first feature length Disney movie to be distributed by Buena Vista Distribution.There is a terrific cast inside the submarine.Kirk Douglas is really something as the harpoonist Ned Land.An outstanding performance by James Mason in the role of Captain Nemo.Paul Lukas as Prof. Pierre Aronnax and Peter Lorre as his assistant Conseil are excellent.The movie has many incredible scenes, like the battle against the giant squids.The duet between Kirk Douglas and the seal is a riot.This is an adventure you don't want to miss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful fascinating futuristic adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spamobile
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wonderful adventure taking you away on the high seas to meet a mad man and his mad machine. Jules Verne is a masterful story writer. He "invented" a lot of fantastic machines and wrote his stories based on them. Although nothing was technically possible the way he invented the machines the ideas were totally back to the future, things man would take an other century to actually build. The movie is raw adventure, sailing ships, sea monsters, hero's, comedy at times, fascinating story telling. It's made when CGI was still just a bunch of letters hustled together. Special effect was still simple and so fake. But, that does not matter, the story is very entertaining. A man's man, the one and only Kirk Douglas, is one of the leading characters. You can hardly go wrong then. Keep an open mind when watching, it's an old movie, it's not perfect, it's not Oscar winning material, but it's highly entertaining fantasy world. Watch it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The singing seal delivers the most entertaining performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Buena Vista wisely opens the movie by showing the cover of 19th century edition of Jules Verne's work, and then opening to the first page. This solves the problem of explaining to the audience that this is a story set long ago about a once-futuristic submarine. The problem for contemporary audiences is that the movie is six decades old, so it is an old movie about an old story about what was once a vision of the future that is now a bit frayed. I am sympathetic to the concept, given that as a child I loved to read old books like this, as a sort of time travel into the past. And I saw this movie in a theater as a boy, though not in its first run, perhaps around the age of 8. I enjoyed it because it is a fantasy trip into imagining being aboard an ancient submarine traveling the distant oceans and down into the deep. How can a young boy resist? Children can enter into the fantasy of a movie like this. But as an adult, it didn't work, partly because I had seen it, but mainly because I'm an adult, and it takes more than a movie with mediocre acting to engross me in the experience. It took me several tries to make it through the movie this time, because every time I put it on, I looked at the acting and said, Eewwww! Many movies in the 1950s had really shallow acting, perhaps because studios found that a segment of the public actually preferred it. Here I assume, given that it is Disney, the acting is geared to children, so it is shallower still. It is a formula that worked at the time. Disney seems to have discovered this formula of simplistic, over-baked acting, and we still see it in some modern children's movies. I know it worked because I remember how I responded to movies like this as a kid. Kids generally are not looking for Laurence Olivier level acting, and are not analyzing technique. I finally made it through the movie, mainly by trying to view it through the uncritical mind of the 1950s. With the right mindset, James Mason's performance actually looks pretty good, and almost sophisticated next to Kirk Douglass' hyper-enthusiasm. They delivered the right performance for the youthful audience; Douglas was perfectly cast, and his singing was remarkably good. Paul Lukas delivers a performance of what a child might imagine a "professor" to be. The great Peter Lorre appears to be sleep walking. The best, or at least most entertaining, performance is delivered by Esmeralda, the seal, especially in the musical number with Douglas. What saves the film, at least for someone who has not previously seen it, is the story line. The question is whether it works for modern youth, particularly girls? There are some glowing reviews here, but how old are the reviewers? Frankly, I'm not impressed with Richard Fleischer's directing; a better director would have delivered a film that appeals to both children and their parents. While I am not a fan of heavy handed CGI, this is a movie that could benefit from a remake, as long as they don't try to modernize the story. But perhaps one day, when this movie is old enough, children will see in it what I saw in reading old books: a window into the past. Perhaps in 50 years, "20,000 Leagues Under the Sea" will be old enough to be interesting again. But for me, now it just looks tired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Fifties Sci-Fi Movie That Has Stood the Test of Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jules Verne's novel "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is set aboard an ocean-going submarine, something which did not exist when he wrote it in 1870, so it can be regarded as an early example of science fiction. (Verne had a record of making predictions which later came true; he also, for example, foresaw a journey from the Earth to the Moon). This film can be seen as an early example of the genre now called steampunk, that sub-genre of science-fiction which delights in 19th century technology, real or invented. The story tells of the adventures of Captain Nemo, the commander and designer of the submarine "Nautilus". Nemo's name, derived from the Latin for "no man", is an appropriate one, because he is a strange, mysterious figure. He is a brilliant inventor and engineer, but serves no government and no country, preferring to sail the seas with a crew who owe loyalty only to him. He is, at one and the same time, a humanitarian and a misanthropist, hating tyranny but regarding most men as unworthy of freedom. He claims to hate war, but his greatest passion is a desire for revenge on an unnamed "hated nation" whose government were responsible for the deaths of his wife and son and for his own imprisonment in a penal colony. The other main characters in the film are Professor Pierre Aronnax, a French scientist, his assistant Conseil and a sailor named Ned Land. These three are the only survivors of a shipwreck and have been reluctantly rescued by&nbsp;Nemo who sank their vessel after it fired on the "Nautilus", believing it to be a&nbsp;sea monster. Much of the dramatic tension in the film arises from the contrasting personalities of Nemo and his captives. Aronnax, a gentlemanly intellectual, initially believes Nemo to be mad, but later comes to sympathise, at least partially, with his world-view. The cocky and more plebeian Land distrusts both Aronnax and Nemo and spends most of his time formulating plans of escape. "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is therefore unusually character-driven for a science fiction film, so it is hardly surprising that four major stars, James Mason, Kirk Douglas, Paul Lukas&nbsp;and&nbsp;Peter Lorre were cast in the leading roles. (Interestingly, none of these men were of the same nationality as their characters. The Englishman Mason plays Nemo, whom Verne originally envisaged as Polish but later described as Indian. The American&nbsp;Douglas plays Land, who was originally Canadian. The Frenchmen Aronnax and Conseil are played by Lukas and Lorre, both Hungarian by birth). All four are good, but Mason is especially good as the tormented Nemo, a man who appears to be at war with the rest of humanity but who is really at war with himself, torn between his desire for revenge and his better nature which tells him that revenge is a futile pursuit. The film was directed by Richard Fleischer, a versatile director who seemed able to work in virtually any genre, including film noir ("The Armoured Car Robbery"), true crime ("Ten Rillington Place", "The Girl in the Red Velvet Swing"), the historical epic ("The Vikings"), and sword- and-sorcery fantasy ("Conan the Destroyer", "Red Sonja"). He also made a number of science-fiction films, including this one, "Fantastic Voyage" (which also involves a submarine) and "Soylent Green". Fifties sci-fi has&nbsp;a rather unenviable reputation; many films in the genre from this decade were made on a low budget, with clich&eacute;d scripts and low-quality special effects; some examples, such as the notorious "Plan 9 from Outer Space" are frequently to be found on lists of the "worst films ever made". There were, however, some very good science fiction&nbsp;films from the period,&nbsp;such as&nbsp;"Forbidden Planet", with a plot based on Shakespeare's "The Tempest", or the 1953 version of "The War of the Worlds", and "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is another in the same category. Not only does it have a humane and intelligent script and some first-rate acting performances, the special effects- so often sci-fi's Achilles heel- are actually rather good, especially during the scene where the&nbsp;"Nautilus"&nbsp; is attacked by&nbsp;a giant squid. The vessel itself looks realistic enough to be convincing, while different enough from a modern submarine to make us realised that we are watching a Victorian fantasy. This is one science fiction film that has stood the test of time. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You'll pray for a torpedo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If I were on this voyage I'd jump overboard. Harpooner Kirk Douglas, professor Paul Lukas and his apprentice Peter Lorre are taken on board the Nautilus, a submarine helmed by James Mason's Captain Nemo, after he destroys their ship. Then nothing of interest happens for an hour. Then we hit the island of cannibals and an attack by a giant squid... Nope, still not interesting. There's some fun to be had courtesy of Douglas's likable performance, but other than that there's little to recommend this flat adventure, which could do with being a good deal shorter and wastes Peter Lorre in a thankless role. In the plus column, it's better than 'Mysterious Island'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    best Disney movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bailey-86
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    my favorite Disney movie. Love it and i wish that Disney would make more Disney movies like 20,000 Leagues Under the Sea. Great movie what I love about the movie is that it's live action and animation that Walt Disney was the producer of the movie. I still watch the movie even though I am in my 20's. Great and Clean Disney movie. Love the cast including Peter Lorree, James Mason, Kirk Douglas, and Paul Lukas. Best Disney movie and appropriate for all ages and family. The movie is one of my favorite Disney movies ever made. I love it that Richard Fleschier who directed Dr. Doolittle did the perfect job directing the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic among classic adventure tales
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By 1954, Disney already had a name for itself with producing quality entertainment. So it shouldn't shock many (now) that Walt Disney decided to take on this project and adapt Jules Verne's story to the big screen. But here's the game changer, the cast has big name actors, the special effects are fantastic, the props are spectacular and the screenplay was well revised. The story takes place in the late 1800's where a Professor Aronnax (Paul Lukas) and his assistant Conseil (Peter Lorre) are put their knowledge and well being to the test when they are given the opportunity of a life time. Recently, there have been sightings of a "sea monster" attacking vessels out on the open sea. The offer, is to sail with the US navy to track down the monster and destroy it. At first the professor and his assistant were curious, but soon audiences will watch them grow and understand that the answers they were hoping for, were not even close to what they thought they could be. Aboard this ship is Ned Land (Kirk Douglas), a master harpooner who seems to have an attitude with authority but in the most lighthearted and high-spirited way. But another character that is one of the most intriguing and hard to figure out characters is Captain Nemo, brilliantly played by James Mason. The way Mason portrays his character makes it so hard to read. Mason acts with a controlled yet ferocious hatred, but it never seems like that. In fact, he may seem a little mad (crazy), but he will always use a sophisticated vocabulary. Also, for 1954 the special effects and props were so convincing. Wait until you see that giant squid! Absolutely phenomenal! And because the film is in wide screen, it looks even better. The sets either on the ships, in the water beside the choral reefs or on an island looks great. The music provided by Paul L. Smith was much welcomed too. Since Smith has worked with Disney before on various other projects like Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937), his score emits all the right feelings for each scene. The reason why I titled this as the classic among classic adventure tales because that's what it is. This is the purest of the pure in what this genre is. Setting out on a journey with no idea of what the end result may be is exactly what an adventure is. I mean, what else could you ask for? Sailing out to sea to find a monster sounds exciting and scary at the same time, plus you have cannons, island natives, underwater treasure and so on. There's just so many things to explore! Because of the top-notch acting, amazing set pieces, adventurous music and spectacular special effects, this is by far Disney's most famous live-action piece from the 1950s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Wonder of 1954
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Whitney
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this film is best appreciated when watched empowered with an education of film history, taking into consideration the technological challenges which were overcome to make it all happen successfully, appreciating the risks it entailed for the Disney Studios, and imagining how it felt for audiences who experienced it for the first time as what was truly an unprecedented under-water cinematic feat. It was the most expensive film ever made up to that time, and if you look closely you can tell that no expense was spared. Nevertheless, in our modern era of Hollywood indulgence and computer generated graphics, 20,000 Leagues under the Sea inevitably ends up feeling slightly dated & hokey at times. The movie boasts many timeless strengths though, among them being interesting characters, excellent performances, and some great intellectual dialogue/debate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Come aboard the Naultius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before there was Bio Shock. Before Steampunk became cool. There was this movie. The year is 1868, a number of sea monsters attacks in the Pacific, has cause fear among sailors. Professor Pierre M. Arrnoax (Paul Lakas) and his assistant, Conseil (Peter Lorre) were invited by the US government to find. They were attacked by the 'so called' monster, and found themselves shipwreck with Ned Land (Kirk Douglas) a sailor. Captured by the monster, they found out, it's not a monster at all, but a submarine the Naultius, captain by the mysterious Nemo. (James Mason) explorer of the ocean bottom, '20,000 Leagues Under the Sea'. What Pierre and the survivors doesn't know at first, is that Captain Nemo is border-lining between genius and madness. A man who is at war at the surface world, while being tired of war. Arrnoax knows of this, but due to his lust of knowledge, he continue to take the side of the captain, while Ned Land tries to escape. 20,000 Leagues Under the Sea is based on the science fiction novel by French writer Jules Verne with the same name. There are some big differences between the film, and the novel. The film tends to cut outs or combinded such in case-- the treasure scene and the shark. Much praise for keeping much of Captain Nemo's reasons to attack the surface world and keeping the violence and death in, for a PG movie. Without it, it wouldn't be much of a adventure. The film can be a bit outdated, thus some action scenes with the limited special effects might be a bit cheesy, but at the time, well made. It's far superior to the majority of genre efforts from the period (or any period, for that matter), with production design and technical effects that have dated hardly at all. The soundtrack is spellbinding, mysterious, and glam. The haunting classic organ music plays well into the film. |'A Whale of a Tale' by Al Hoffman and Norman Gimbel as sung by Kirk Douglas sound as real as a sailor's hymn. Kirk Douglas is the perfect fit for Ned Land. Land is everything that Nemo hates about the surface, self-centered, greedy, and ego driven. While all of the actors did great in their respectable roles, it was James Mason, that got singled out for his performance of Captain Nemo. Even the point, that Nemo's last words to Aronnax echo: is a strong message. There is hope for the future. And when the world is ready for a new and better life, all this will someday come to pass, in God's good time." It's a great adventure, so give it a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great adventure and some very strong characters.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    teryolaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great adventure. I was kinda taken aback by how cozy this movie is. I am really surprised that it was made in 1954 because the special effects are really well made for an old movie and the underwater footage is just fantastic. The movie looks great and plays great. There is something special with these older types of movies. There isn't really such a thing as mediocre acting and substance-less characters. The characters are all strong and stand out in their own special way. Whether they are taking the front or stand more in the background, like the little weasel that is the professors apprentice. I particularly like Captain Nemo's character. He is a misanthrope and the embodiment of a person who is so intelligent that there isn't much for him to do but to suffer in a cruel and inhumane world, where the rest of mankind aren't on his level. Throughout the movie we learn that while what he was saying is depressing, he was right. Ned is one proof of that. One day he saves Nemo's life. But on the day before, he made sure to act in such a way that in the end would lead to Nemo's death. As Nemo says, goodness needs to be consistent. It can't be done on impulse. The dialogue is well-written and provides insight in a natural way as to why Nemo is the way that he is. It opens up discussion rather then makes statements that can't be reflected upon. After Nemo's life is saved by Ted, I like how when the professor was trying to "talk sense" into Nemo and make him be a bit more cheerful about the world, Nemo could actually defend his point of view instead of it being just another clich&eacute; Hollywood moment where the "bad guy" is shown off as weak and fallible in his perspective of the world. And Nemo defending his view opens up a new perspective on things and makes everything about the movies morale more ambiguous, rather then it being a typical hopeful movie where everything works out great in the end. The movie is hopeful in it's own way, but it's in a way that shows you something bad and lets the audience want to make a change for the future. And in the end, he makes a point. The world isn't ready for destructive power of that kind. It is said that science fiction movies (as well as movies in general) are a reflection of the society in the era that they are being made in. And this movie was made in 54. The atom-bomb on Hirosima and Nagasaki was executed on 1945. I think that I can see a parallel there about mankind's destructive nature and immaturity. How the authorities take everything good and use it for destructive means. This is a movie about misanthropy and mankind's destructive nature. Precisely the kind of deeper themes that a science fiction is supposed to touch upon, and it does it well. Great movie. A new-found classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mighty adventure based on Jules Verne's novel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie tells about three men that have to travel against their own will in Captain Nemo's submarine called Nautilus.20000 Leagues Under the Sea (1954) is directed by Richard Fleischer.It's based on Jules Verne's novel from 1870, which I read last week.There are some differences between the book and the movie, like Esmeralda the seal, that wasn't in the book.This was the first science fiction movie produced by Walt Disney Productions.And it was also the only science fiction movie produced by Walt Disney himself.As it was the first feature length Disney movie to be distributed by Buena Vista Distribution.There is a terrific cast inside the submarine.Kirk Douglas is really something as the harpoonist Ned Land.An outstanding performance by James Mason in the role of Captain Nemo.Paul Lukas as Prof. Pierre Aronnax and Peter Lorre as his assistant Conseil are excellent.The movie has many incredible scenes, like the battle against the giant squids.The duet between Kirk Douglas and the seal is a riot.This is an adventure you don't want to miss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful fascinating futuristic adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spamobile
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wonderful adventure taking you away on the high seas to meet a mad man and his mad machine. Jules Verne is a masterful story writer. He "invented" a lot of fantastic machines and wrote his stories based on them. Although nothing was technically possible the way he invented the machines the ideas were totally back to the future, things man would take an other century to actually build. The movie is raw adventure, sailing ships, sea monsters, hero's, comedy at times, fascinating story telling. It's made when CGI was still just a bunch of letters hustled together. Special effect was still simple and so fake. But, that does not matter, the story is very entertaining. A man's man, the one and only Kirk Douglas, is one of the leading characters. You can hardly go wrong then. Keep an open mind when watching, it's an old movie, it's not perfect, it's not Oscar winning material, but it's highly entertaining fantasy world. Watch it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The singing seal delivers the most entertaining performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Buena Vista wisely opens the movie by showing the cover of 19th century edition of Jules Verne's work, and then opening to the first page. This solves the problem of explaining to the audience that this is a story set long ago about a once-futuristic submarine. The problem for contemporary audiences is that the movie is six decades old, so it is an old movie about an old story about what was once a vision of the future that is now a bit frayed. I am sympathetic to the concept, given that as a child I loved to read old books like this, as a sort of time travel into the past. And I saw this movie in a theater as a boy, though not in its first run, perhaps around the age of 8. I enjoyed it because it is a fantasy trip into imagining being aboard an ancient submarine traveling the distant oceans and down into the deep. How can a young boy resist? Children can enter into the fantasy of a movie like this. But as an adult, it didn't work, partly because I had seen it, but mainly because I'm an adult, and it takes more than a movie with mediocre acting to engross me in the experience. It took me several tries to make it through the movie this time, because every time I put it on, I looked at the acting and said, Eewwww! Many movies in the 1950s had really shallow acting, perhaps because studios found that a segment of the public actually preferred it. Here I assume, given that it is Disney, the acting is geared to children, so it is shallower still. It is a formula that worked at the time. Disney seems to have discovered this formula of simplistic, over-baked acting, and we still see it in some modern children's movies. I know it worked because I remember how I responded to movies like this as a kid. Kids generally are not looking for Laurence Olivier level acting, and are not analyzing technique. I finally made it through the movie, mainly by trying to view it through the uncritical mind of the 1950s. With the right mindset, James Mason's performance actually looks pretty good, and almost sophisticated next to Kirk Douglass' hyper-enthusiasm. They delivered the right performance for the youthful audience; Douglas was perfectly cast, and his singing was remarkably good. Paul Lukas delivers a performance of what a child might imagine a "professor" to be. The great Peter Lorre appears to be sleep walking. The best, or at least most entertaining, performance is delivered by Esmeralda, the seal, especially in the musical number with Douglas. What saves the film, at least for someone who has not previously seen it, is the story line. The question is whether it works for modern youth, particularly girls? There are some glowing reviews here, but how old are the reviewers? Frankly, I'm not impressed with Richard Fleischer's directing; a better director would have delivered a film that appeals to both children and their parents. While I am not a fan of heavy handed CGI, this is a movie that could benefit from a remake, as long as they don't try to modernize the story. But perhaps one day, when this movie is old enough, children will see in it what I saw in reading old books: a window into the past. Perhaps in 50 years, "20,000 Leagues Under the Sea" will be old enough to be interesting again. But for me, now it just looks tired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Fifties Sci-Fi Movie That Has Stood the Test of Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jules Verne's novel "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is set aboard an ocean-going submarine, something which did not exist when he wrote it in 1870, so it can be regarded as an early example of science fiction. (Verne had a record of making predictions which later came true; he also, for example, foresaw a journey from the Earth to the Moon). This film can be seen as an early example of the genre now called steampunk, that sub-genre of science-fiction which delights in 19th century technology, real or invented. The story tells of the adventures of Captain Nemo, the commander and designer of the submarine "Nautilus". Nemo's name, derived from the Latin for "no man", is an appropriate one, because he is a strange, mysterious figure. He is a brilliant inventor and engineer, but serves no government and no country, preferring to sail the seas with a crew who owe loyalty only to him. He is, at one and the same time, a humanitarian and a misanthropist, hating tyranny but regarding most men as unworthy of freedom. He claims to hate war, but his greatest passion is a desire for revenge on an unnamed "hated nation" whose government were responsible for the deaths of his wife and son and for his own imprisonment in a penal colony. The other main characters in the film are Professor Pierre Aronnax, a French scientist, his assistant Conseil and a sailor named Ned Land. These three are the only survivors of a shipwreck and have been reluctantly rescued by&nbsp;Nemo who sank their vessel after it fired on the "Nautilus", believing it to be a&nbsp;sea monster. Much of the dramatic tension in the film arises from the contrasting personalities of Nemo and his captives. Aronnax, a gentlemanly intellectual, initially believes Nemo to be mad, but later comes to sympathise, at least partially, with his world-view. The cocky and more plebeian Land distrusts both Aronnax and Nemo and spends most of his time formulating plans of escape. "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is therefore unusually character-driven for a science fiction film, so it is hardly surprising that four major stars, James Mason, Kirk Douglas, Paul Lukas&nbsp;and&nbsp;Peter Lorre were cast in the leading roles. (Interestingly, none of these men were of the same nationality as their characters. The Englishman Mason plays Nemo, whom Verne originally envisaged as Polish but later described as Indian. The American&nbsp;Douglas plays Land, who was originally Canadian. The Frenchmen Aronnax and Conseil are played by Lukas and Lorre, both Hungarian by birth). All four are good, but Mason is especially good as the tormented Nemo, a man who appears to be at war with the rest of humanity but who is really at war with himself, torn between his desire for revenge and his better nature which tells him that revenge is a futile pursuit. The film was directed by Richard Fleischer, a versatile director who seemed able to work in virtually any genre, including film noir ("The Armoured Car Robbery"), true crime ("Ten Rillington Place", "The Girl in the Red Velvet Swing"), the historical epic ("The Vikings"), and sword- and-sorcery fantasy ("Conan the Destroyer", "Red Sonja"). He also made a number of science-fiction films, including this one, "Fantastic Voyage" (which also involves a submarine) and "Soylent Green". Fifties sci-fi has&nbsp;a rather unenviable reputation; many films in the genre from this decade were made on a low budget, with clich&eacute;d scripts and low-quality special effects; some examples, such as the notorious "Plan 9 from Outer Space" are frequently to be found on lists of the "worst films ever made". There were, however, some very good science fiction&nbsp;films from the period,&nbsp;such as&nbsp;"Forbidden Planet", with a plot based on Shakespeare's "The Tempest", or the 1953 version of "The War of the Worlds", and "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is another in the same category. Not only does it have a humane and intelligent script and some first-rate acting performances, the special effects- so often sci-fi's Achilles heel- are actually rather good, especially during the scene where the&nbsp;"Nautilus"&nbsp; is attacked by&nbsp;a giant squid. The vessel itself looks realistic enough to be convincing, while different enough from a modern submarine to make us realised that we are watching a Victorian fantasy. This is one science fiction film that has stood the test of time. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You'll pray for a torpedo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If I were on this voyage I'd jump overboard. Harpooner Kirk Douglas, professor Paul Lukas and his apprentice Peter Lorre are taken on board the Nautilus, a submarine helmed by James Mason's Captain Nemo, after he destroys their ship. Then nothing of interest happens for an hour. Then we hit the island of cannibals and an attack by a giant squid... Nope, still not interesting. There's some fun to be had courtesy of Douglas's likable performance, but other than that there's little to recommend this flat adventure, which could do with being a good deal shorter and wastes Peter Lorre in a thankless role. In the plus column, it's better than 'Mysterious Island'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    best Disney movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bailey-86
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    my favorite Disney movie. Love it and i wish that Disney would make more Disney movies like 20,000 Leagues Under the Sea. Great movie what I love about the movie is that it's live action and animation that Walt Disney was the producer of the movie. I still watch the movie even though I am in my 20's. Great and Clean Disney movie. Love the cast including Peter Lorree, James Mason, Kirk Douglas, and Paul Lukas. Best Disney movie and appropriate for all ages and family. The movie is one of my favorite Disney movies ever made. I love it that Richard Fleschier who directed Dr. Doolittle did the perfect job directing the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic among classic adventure tales
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By 1954, Disney already had a name for itself with producing quality entertainment. So it shouldn't shock many (now) that Walt Disney decided to take on this project and adapt Jules Verne's story to the big screen. But here's the game changer, the cast has big name actors, the special effects are fantastic, the props are spectacular and the screenplay was well revised. The story takes place in the late 1800's where a Professor Aronnax (Paul Lukas) and his assistant Conseil (Peter Lorre) are put their knowledge and well being to the test when they are given the opportunity of a life time. Recently, there have been sightings of a "sea monster" attacking vessels out on the open sea. The offer, is to sail with the US navy to track down the monster and destroy it. At first the professor and his assistant were curious, but soon audiences will watch them grow and understand that the answers they were hoping for, were not even close to what they thought they could be. Aboard this ship is Ned Land (Kirk Douglas), a master harpooner who seems to have an attitude with authority but in the most lighthearted and high-spirited way. But another character that is one of the most intriguing and hard to figure out characters is Captain Nemo, brilliantly played by James Mason. The way Mason portrays his character makes it so hard to read. Mason acts with a controlled yet ferocious hatred, but it never seems like that. In fact, he may seem a little mad (crazy), but he will always use a sophisticated vocabulary. Also, for 1954 the special effects and props were so convincing. Wait until you see that giant squid! Absolutely phenomenal! And because the film is in wide screen, it looks even better. The sets either on the ships, in the water beside the choral reefs or on an island looks great. The music provided by Paul L. Smith was much welcomed too. Since Smith has worked with Disney before on various other projects like Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937), his score emits all the right feelings for each scene. The reason why I titled this as the classic among classic adventure tales because that's what it is. This is the purest of the pure in what this genre is. Setting out on a journey with no idea of what the end result may be is exactly what an adventure is. I mean, what else could you ask for? Sailing out to sea to find a monster sounds exciting and scary at the same time, plus you have cannons, island natives, underwater treasure and so on. There's just so many things to explore! Because of the top-notch acting, amazing set pieces, adventurous music and spectacular special effects, this is by far Disney's most famous live-action piece from the 1950s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Wonder of 1954
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Whitney
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this film is best appreciated when watched empowered with an education of film history, taking into consideration the technological challenges which were overcome to make it all happen successfully, appreciating the risks it entailed for the Disney Studios, and imagining how it felt for audiences who experienced it for the first time as what was truly an unprecedented under-water cinematic feat. It was the most expensive film ever made up to that time, and if you look closely you can tell that no expense was spared. Nevertheless, in our modern era of Hollywood indulgence and computer generated graphics, 20,000 Leagues under the Sea inevitably ends up feeling slightly dated & hokey at times. The movie boasts many timeless strengths though, among them being interesting characters, excellent performances, and some great intellectual dialogue/debate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Come aboard the Naultius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before there was Bio Shock. Before Steampunk became cool. There was this movie. The year is 1868, a number of sea monsters attacks in the Pacific, has cause fear among sailors. Professor Pierre M. Arrnoax (Paul Lakas) and his assistant, Conseil (Peter Lorre) were invited by the US government to find. They were attacked by the 'so called' monster, and found themselves shipwreck with Ned Land (Kirk Douglas) a sailor. Captured by the monster, they found out, it's not a monster at all, but a submarine the Naultius, captain by the mysterious Nemo. (James Mason) explorer of the ocean bottom, '20,000 Leagues Under the Sea'. What Pierre and the survivors doesn't know at first, is that Captain Nemo is border-lining between genius and madness. A man who is at war at the surface world, while being tired of war. Arrnoax knows of this, but due to his lust of knowledge, he continue to take the side of the captain, while Ned Land tries to escape. 20,000 Leagues Under the Sea is based on the science fiction novel by French writer Jules Verne with the same name. There are some big differences between the film, and the novel. The film tends to cut outs or combinded such in case-- the treasure scene and the shark. Much praise for keeping much of Captain Nemo's reasons to attack the surface world and keeping the violence and death in, for a PG movie. Without it, it wouldn't be much of a adventure. The film can be a bit outdated, thus some action scenes with the limited special effects might be a bit cheesy, but at the time, well made. It's far superior to the majority of genre efforts from the period (or any period, for that matter), with production design and technical effects that have dated hardly at all. The soundtrack is spellbinding, mysterious, and glam. The haunting classic organ music plays well into the film. |'A Whale of a Tale' by Al Hoffman and Norman Gimbel as sung by Kirk Douglas sound as real as a sailor's hymn. Kirk Douglas is the perfect fit for Ned Land. Land is everything that Nemo hates about the surface, self-centered, greedy, and ego driven. While all of the actors did great in their respectable roles, it was James Mason, that got singled out for his performance of Captain Nemo. Even the point, that Nemo's last words to Aronnax echo: is a strong message. There is hope for the future. And when the world is ready for a new and better life, all this will someday come to pass, in God's good time." It's a great adventure, so give it a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great adventure and some very strong characters.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    teryolaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great adventure. I was kinda taken aback by how cozy this movie is. I am really surprised that it was made in 1954 because the special effects are really well made for an old movie and the underwater footage is just fantastic. The movie looks great and plays great. There is something special with these older types of movies. There isn't really such a thing as mediocre acting and substance-less characters. The characters are all strong and stand out in their own special way. Whether they are taking the front or stand more in the background, like the little weasel that is the professors apprentice. I particularly like Captain Nemo's character. He is a misanthrope and the embodiment of a person who is so intelligent that there isn't much for him to do but to suffer in a cruel and inhumane world, where the rest of mankind aren't on his level. Throughout the movie we learn that while what he was saying is depressing, he was right. Ned is one proof of that. One day he saves Nemo's life. But on the day before, he made sure to act in such a way that in the end would lead to Nemo's death. As Nemo says, goodness needs to be consistent. It can't be done on impulse. The dialogue is well-written and provides insight in a natural way as to why Nemo is the way that he is. It opens up discussion rather then makes statements that can't be reflected upon. After Nemo's life is saved by Ted, I like how when the professor was trying to "talk sense" into Nemo and make him be a bit more cheerful about the world, Nemo could actually defend his point of view instead of it being just another clich&eacute; Hollywood moment where the "bad guy" is shown off as weak and fallible in his perspective of the world. And Nemo defending his view opens up a new perspective on things and makes everything about the movies morale more ambiguous, rather then it being a typical hopeful movie where everything works out great in the end. The movie is hopeful in it's own way, but it's in a way that shows you something bad and lets the audience want to make a change for the future. And in the end, he makes a point. The world isn't ready for destructive power of that kind. It is said that science fiction movies (as well as movies in general) are a reflection of the society in the era that they are being made in. And this movie was made in 54. The atom-bomb on Hirosima and Nagasaki was executed on 1945. I think that I can see a parallel there about mankind's destructive nature and immaturity. How the authorities take everything good and use it for destructive means. This is a movie about misanthropy and mankind's destructive nature. Precisely the kind of deeper themes that a science fiction is supposed to touch upon, and it does it well. Great movie. A new-found classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mighty adventure based on Jules Verne's novel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie tells about three men that have to travel against their own will in Captain Nemo's submarine called Nautilus.20000 Leagues Under the Sea (1954) is directed by Richard Fleischer.It's based on Jules Verne's novel from 1870, which I read last week.There are some differences between the book and the movie, like Esmeralda the seal, that wasn't in the book.This was the first science fiction movie produced by Walt Disney Productions.And it was also the only science fiction movie produced by Walt Disney himself.As it was the first feature length Disney movie to be distributed by Buena Vista Distribution.There is a terrific cast inside the submarine.Kirk Douglas is really something as the harpoonist Ned Land.An outstanding performance by James Mason in the role of Captain Nemo.Paul Lukas as Prof. Pierre Aronnax and Peter Lorre as his assistant Conseil are excellent.The movie has many incredible scenes, like the battle against the giant squids.The duet between Kirk Douglas and the seal is a riot.This is an adventure you don't want to miss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful fascinating futuristic adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spamobile
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wonderful adventure taking you away on the high seas to meet a mad man and his mad machine. Jules Verne is a masterful story writer. He "invented" a lot of fantastic machines and wrote his stories based on them. Although nothing was technically possible the way he invented the machines the ideas were totally back to the future, things man would take an other century to actually build. The movie is raw adventure, sailing ships, sea monsters, hero's, comedy at times, fascinating story telling. It's made when CGI was still just a bunch of letters hustled together. Special effect was still simple and so fake. But, that does not matter, the story is very entertaining. A man's man, the one and only Kirk Douglas, is one of the leading characters. You can hardly go wrong then. Keep an open mind when watching, it's an old movie, it's not perfect, it's not Oscar winning material, but it's highly entertaining fantasy world. Watch it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The singing seal delivers the most entertaining performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Buena Vista wisely opens the movie by showing the cover of 19th century edition of Jules Verne's work, and then opening to the first page. This solves the problem of explaining to the audience that this is a story set long ago about a once-futuristic submarine. The problem for contemporary audiences is that the movie is six decades old, so it is an old movie about an old story about what was once a vision of the future that is now a bit frayed. I am sympathetic to the concept, given that as a child I loved to read old books like this, as a sort of time travel into the past. And I saw this movie in a theater as a boy, though not in its first run, perhaps around the age of 8. I enjoyed it because it is a fantasy trip into imagining being aboard an ancient submarine traveling the distant oceans and down into the deep. How can a young boy resist? Children can enter into the fantasy of a movie like this. But as an adult, it didn't work, partly because I had seen it, but mainly because I'm an adult, and it takes more than a movie with mediocre acting to engross me in the experience. It took me several tries to make it through the movie this time, because every time I put it on, I looked at the acting and said, Eewwww! Many movies in the 1950s had really shallow acting, perhaps because studios found that a segment of the public actually preferred it. Here I assume, given that it is Disney, the acting is geared to children, so it is shallower still. It is a formula that worked at the time. Disney seems to have discovered this formula of simplistic, over-baked acting, and we still see it in some modern children's movies. I know it worked because I remember how I responded to movies like this as a kid. Kids generally are not looking for Laurence Olivier level acting, and are not analyzing technique. I finally made it through the movie, mainly by trying to view it through the uncritical mind of the 1950s. With the right mindset, James Mason's performance actually looks pretty good, and almost sophisticated next to Kirk Douglass' hyper-enthusiasm. They delivered the right performance for the youthful audience; Douglas was perfectly cast, and his singing was remarkably good. Paul Lukas delivers a performance of what a child might imagine a "professor" to be. The great Peter Lorre appears to be sleep walking. The best, or at least most entertaining, performance is delivered by Esmeralda, the seal, especially in the musical number with Douglas. What saves the film, at least for someone who has not previously seen it, is the story line. The question is whether it works for modern youth, particularly girls? There are some glowing reviews here, but how old are the reviewers? Frankly, I'm not impressed with Richard Fleischer's directing; a better director would have delivered a film that appeals to both children and their parents. While I am not a fan of heavy handed CGI, this is a movie that could benefit from a remake, as long as they don't try to modernize the story. But perhaps one day, when this movie is old enough, children will see in it what I saw in reading old books: a window into the past. Perhaps in 50 years, "20,000 Leagues Under the Sea" will be old enough to be interesting again. But for me, now it just looks tired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Fifties Sci-Fi Movie That Has Stood the Test of Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jules Verne's novel "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is set aboard an ocean-going submarine, something which did not exist when he wrote it in 1870, so it can be regarded as an early example of science fiction. (Verne had a record of making predictions which later came true; he also, for example, foresaw a journey from the Earth to the Moon). This film can be seen as an early example of the genre now called steampunk, that sub-genre of science-fiction which delights in 19th century technology, real or invented. The story tells of the adventures of Captain Nemo, the commander and designer of the submarine "Nautilus". Nemo's name, derived from the Latin for "no man", is an appropriate one, because he is a strange, mysterious figure. He is a brilliant inventor and engineer, but serves no government and no country, preferring to sail the seas with a crew who owe loyalty only to him. He is, at one and the same time, a humanitarian and a misanthropist, hating tyranny but regarding most men as unworthy of freedom. He claims to hate war, but his greatest passion is a desire for revenge on an unnamed "hated nation" whose government were responsible for the deaths of his wife and son and for his own imprisonment in a penal colony. The other main characters in the film are Professor Pierre Aronnax, a French scientist, his assistant Conseil and a sailor named Ned Land. These three are the only survivors of a shipwreck and have been reluctantly rescued by&nbsp;Nemo who sank their vessel after it fired on the "Nautilus", believing it to be a&nbsp;sea monster. Much of the dramatic tension in the film arises from the contrasting personalities of Nemo and his captives. Aronnax, a gentlemanly intellectual, initially believes Nemo to be mad, but later comes to sympathise, at least partially, with his world-view. The cocky and more plebeian Land distrusts both Aronnax and Nemo and spends most of his time formulating plans of escape. "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is therefore unusually character-driven for a science fiction film, so it is hardly surprising that four major stars, James Mason, Kirk Douglas, Paul Lukas&nbsp;and&nbsp;Peter Lorre were cast in the leading roles. (Interestingly, none of these men were of the same nationality as their characters. The Englishman Mason plays Nemo, whom Verne originally envisaged as Polish but later described as Indian. The American&nbsp;Douglas plays Land, who was originally Canadian. The Frenchmen Aronnax and Conseil are played by Lukas and Lorre, both Hungarian by birth). All four are good, but Mason is especially good as the tormented Nemo, a man who appears to be at war with the rest of humanity but who is really at war with himself, torn between his desire for revenge and his better nature which tells him that revenge is a futile pursuit. The film was directed by Richard Fleischer, a versatile director who seemed able to work in virtually any genre, including film noir ("The Armoured Car Robbery"), true crime ("Ten Rillington Place", "The Girl in the Red Velvet Swing"), the historical epic ("The Vikings"), and sword- and-sorcery fantasy ("Conan the Destroyer", "Red Sonja"). He also made a number of science-fiction films, including this one, "Fantastic Voyage" (which also involves a submarine) and "Soylent Green". Fifties sci-fi has&nbsp;a rather unenviable reputation; many films in the genre from this decade were made on a low budget, with clich&eacute;d scripts and low-quality special effects; some examples, such as the notorious "Plan 9 from Outer Space" are frequently to be found on lists of the "worst films ever made". There were, however, some very good science fiction&nbsp;films from the period,&nbsp;such as&nbsp;"Forbidden Planet", with a plot based on Shakespeare's "The Tempest", or the 1953 version of "The War of the Worlds", and "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is another in the same category. Not only does it have a humane and intelligent script and some first-rate acting performances, the special effects- so often sci-fi's Achilles heel- are actually rather good, especially during the scene where the&nbsp;"Nautilus"&nbsp; is attacked by&nbsp;a giant squid. The vessel itself looks realistic enough to be convincing, while different enough from a modern submarine to make us realised that we are watching a Victorian fantasy. This is one science fiction film that has stood the test of time. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You'll pray for a torpedo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If I were on this voyage I'd jump overboard. Harpooner Kirk Douglas, professor Paul Lukas and his apprentice Peter Lorre are taken on board the Nautilus, a submarine helmed by James Mason's Captain Nemo, after he destroys their ship. Then nothing of interest happens for an hour. Then we hit the island of cannibals and an attack by a giant squid... Nope, still not interesting. There's some fun to be had courtesy of Douglas's likable performance, but other than that there's little to recommend this flat adventure, which could do with being a good deal shorter and wastes Peter Lorre in a thankless role. In the plus column, it's better than 'Mysterious Island'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    best Disney movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bailey-86
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    my favorite Disney movie. Love it and i wish that Disney would make more Disney movies like 20,000 Leagues Under the Sea. Great movie what I love about the movie is that it's live action and animation that Walt Disney was the producer of the movie. I still watch the movie even though I am in my 20's. Great and Clean Disney movie. Love the cast including Peter Lorree, James Mason, Kirk Douglas, and Paul Lukas. Best Disney movie and appropriate for all ages and family. The movie is one of my favorite Disney movies ever made. I love it that Richard Fleschier who directed Dr. Doolittle did the perfect job directing the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic among classic adventure tales
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By 1954, Disney already had a name for itself with producing quality entertainment. So it shouldn't shock many (now) that Walt Disney decided to take on this project and adapt Jules Verne's story to the big screen. But here's the game changer, the cast has big name actors, the special effects are fantastic, the props are spectacular and the screenplay was well revised. The story takes place in the late 1800's where a Professor Aronnax (Paul Lukas) and his assistant Conseil (Peter Lorre) are put their knowledge and well being to the test when they are given the opportunity of a life time. Recently, there have been sightings of a "sea monster" attacking vessels out on the open sea. The offer, is to sail with the US navy to track down the monster and destroy it. At first the professor and his assistant were curious, but soon audiences will watch them grow and understand that the answers they were hoping for, were not even close to what they thought they could be. Aboard this ship is Ned Land (Kirk Douglas), a master harpooner who seems to have an attitude with authority but in the most lighthearted and high-spirited way. But another character that is one of the most intriguing and hard to figure out characters is Captain Nemo, brilliantly played by James Mason. The way Mason portrays his character makes it so hard to read. Mason acts with a controlled yet ferocious hatred, but it never seems like that. In fact, he may seem a little mad (crazy), but he will always use a sophisticated vocabulary. Also, for 1954 the special effects and props were so convincing. Wait until you see that giant squid! Absolutely phenomenal! And because the film is in wide screen, it looks even better. The sets either on the ships, in the water beside the choral reefs or on an island looks great. The music provided by Paul L. Smith was much welcomed too. Since Smith has worked with Disney before on various other projects like Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937), his score emits all the right feelings for each scene. The reason why I titled this as the classic among classic adventure tales because that's what it is. This is the purest of the pure in what this genre is. Setting out on a journey with no idea of what the end result may be is exactly what an adventure is. I mean, what else could you ask for? Sailing out to sea to find a monster sounds exciting and scary at the same time, plus you have cannons, island natives, underwater treasure and so on. There's just so many things to explore! Because of the top-notch acting, amazing set pieces, adventurous music and spectacular special effects, this is by far Disney's most famous live-action piece from the 1950s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Wonder of 1954
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Whitney
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this film is best appreciated when watched empowered with an education of film history, taking into consideration the technological challenges which were overcome to make it all happen successfully, appreciating the risks it entailed for the Disney Studios, and imagining how it felt for audiences who experienced it for the first time as what was truly an unprecedented under-water cinematic feat. It was the most expensive film ever made up to that time, and if you look closely you can tell that no expense was spared. Nevertheless, in our modern era of Hollywood indulgence and computer generated graphics, 20,000 Leagues under the Sea inevitably ends up feeling slightly dated & hokey at times. The movie boasts many timeless strengths though, among them being interesting characters, excellent performances, and some great intellectual dialogue/debate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Come aboard the Naultius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before there was Bio Shock. Before Steampunk became cool. There was this movie. The year is 1868, a number of sea monsters attacks in the Pacific, has cause fear among sailors. Professor Pierre M. Arrnoax (Paul Lakas) and his assistant, Conseil (Peter Lorre) were invited by the US government to find. They were attacked by the 'so called' monster, and found themselves shipwreck with Ned Land (Kirk Douglas) a sailor. Captured by the monster, they found out, it's not a monster at all, but a submarine the Naultius, captain by the mysterious Nemo. (James Mason) explorer of the ocean bottom, '20,000 Leagues Under the Sea'. What Pierre and the survivors doesn't know at first, is that Captain Nemo is border-lining between genius and madness. A man who is at war at the surface world, while being tired of war. Arrnoax knows of this, but due to his lust of knowledge, he continue to take the side of the captain, while Ned Land tries to escape. 20,000 Leagues Under the Sea is based on the science fiction novel by French writer Jules Verne with the same name. There are some big differences between the film, and the novel. The film tends to cut outs or combinded such in case-- the treasure scene and the shark. Much praise for keeping much of Captain Nemo's reasons to attack the surface world and keeping the violence and death in, for a PG movie. Without it, it wouldn't be much of a adventure. The film can be a bit outdated, thus some action scenes with the limited special effects might be a bit cheesy, but at the time, well made. It's far superior to the majority of genre efforts from the period (or any period, for that matter), with production design and technical effects that have dated hardly at all. The soundtrack is spellbinding, mysterious, and glam. The haunting classic organ music plays well into the film. |'A Whale of a Tale' by Al Hoffman and Norman Gimbel as sung by Kirk Douglas sound as real as a sailor's hymn. Kirk Douglas is the perfect fit for Ned Land. Land is everything that Nemo hates about the surface, self-centered, greedy, and ego driven. While all of the actors did great in their respectable roles, it was James Mason, that got singled out for his performance of Captain Nemo. Even the point, that Nemo's last words to Aronnax echo: is a strong message. There is hope for the future. And when the world is ready for a new and better life, all this will someday come to pass, in God's good time." It's a great adventure, so give it a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great adventure and some very strong characters.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    teryolaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great adventure. I was kinda taken aback by how cozy this movie is. I am really surprised that it was made in 1954 because the special effects are really well made for an old movie and the underwater footage is just fantastic. The movie looks great and plays great. There is something special with these older types of movies. There isn't really such a thing as mediocre acting and substance-less characters. The characters are all strong and stand out in their own special way. Whether they are taking the front or stand more in the background, like the little weasel that is the professors apprentice. I particularly like Captain Nemo's character. He is a misanthrope and the embodiment of a person who is so intelligent that there isn't much for him to do but to suffer in a cruel and inhumane world, where the rest of mankind aren't on his level. Throughout the movie we learn that while what he was saying is depressing, he was right. Ned is one proof of that. One day he saves Nemo's life. But on the day before, he made sure to act in such a way that in the end would lead to Nemo's death. As Nemo says, goodness needs to be consistent. It can't be done on impulse. The dialogue is well-written and provides insight in a natural way as to why Nemo is the way that he is. It opens up discussion rather then makes statements that can't be reflected upon. After Nemo's life is saved by Ted, I like how when the professor was trying to "talk sense" into Nemo and make him be a bit more cheerful about the world, Nemo could actually defend his point of view instead of it being just another clich&eacute; Hollywood moment where the "bad guy" is shown off as weak and fallible in his perspective of the world. And Nemo defending his view opens up a new perspective on things and makes everything about the movies morale more ambiguous, rather then it being a typical hopeful movie where everything works out great in the end. The movie is hopeful in it's own way, but it's in a way that shows you something bad and lets the audience want to make a change for the future. And in the end, he makes a point. The world isn't ready for destructive power of that kind. It is said that science fiction movies (as well as movies in general) are a reflection of the society in the era that they are being made in. And this movie was made in 54. The atom-bomb on Hirosima and Nagasaki was executed on 1945. I think that I can see a parallel there about mankind's destructive nature and immaturity. How the authorities take everything good and use it for destructive means. This is a movie about misanthropy and mankind's destructive nature. Precisely the kind of deeper themes that a science fiction is supposed to touch upon, and it does it well. Great movie. A new-found classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mighty adventure based on Jules Verne's novel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie tells about three men that have to travel against their own will in Captain Nemo's submarine called Nautilus.20000 Leagues Under the Sea (1954) is directed by Richard Fleischer.It's based on Jules Verne's novel from 1870, which I read last week.There are some differences between the book and the movie, like Esmeralda the seal, that wasn't in the book.This was the first science fiction movie produced by Walt Disney Productions.And it was also the only science fiction movie produced by Walt Disney himself.As it was the first feature length Disney movie to be distributed by Buena Vista Distribution.There is a terrific cast inside the submarine.Kirk Douglas is really something as the harpoonist Ned Land.An outstanding performance by James Mason in the role of Captain Nemo.Paul Lukas as Prof. Pierre Aronnax and Peter Lorre as his assistant Conseil are excellent.The movie has many incredible scenes, like the battle against the giant squids.The duet between Kirk Douglas and the seal is a riot.This is an adventure you don't want to miss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful fascinating futuristic adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spamobile
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wonderful adventure taking you away on the high seas to meet a mad man and his mad machine. Jules Verne is a masterful story writer. He "invented" a lot of fantastic machines and wrote his stories based on them. Although nothing was technically possible the way he invented the machines the ideas were totally back to the future, things man would take an other century to actually build. The movie is raw adventure, sailing ships, sea monsters, hero's, comedy at times, fascinating story telling. It's made when CGI was still just a bunch of letters hustled together. Special effect was still simple and so fake. But, that does not matter, the story is very entertaining. A man's man, the one and only Kirk Douglas, is one of the leading characters. You can hardly go wrong then. Keep an open mind when watching, it's an old movie, it's not perfect, it's not Oscar winning material, but it's highly entertaining fantasy world. Watch it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The singing seal delivers the most entertaining performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Buena Vista wisely opens the movie by showing the cover of 19th century edition of Jules Verne's work, and then opening to the first page. This solves the problem of explaining to the audience that this is a story set long ago about a once-futuristic submarine. The problem for contemporary audiences is that the movie is six decades old, so it is an old movie about an old story about what was once a vision of the future that is now a bit frayed. I am sympathetic to the concept, given that as a child I loved to read old books like this, as a sort of time travel into the past. And I saw this movie in a theater as a boy, though not in its first run, perhaps around the age of 8. I enjoyed it because it is a fantasy trip into imagining being aboard an ancient submarine traveling the distant oceans and down into the deep. How can a young boy resist? Children can enter into the fantasy of a movie like this. But as an adult, it didn't work, partly because I had seen it, but mainly because I'm an adult, and it takes more than a movie with mediocre acting to engross me in the experience. It took me several tries to make it through the movie this time, because every time I put it on, I looked at the acting and said, Eewwww! Many movies in the 1950s had really shallow acting, perhaps because studios found that a segment of the public actually preferred it. Here I assume, given that it is Disney, the acting is geared to children, so it is shallower still. It is a formula that worked at the time. Disney seems to have discovered this formula of simplistic, over-baked acting, and we still see it in some modern children's movies. I know it worked because I remember how I responded to movies like this as a kid. Kids generally are not looking for Laurence Olivier level acting, and are not analyzing technique. I finally made it through the movie, mainly by trying to view it through the uncritical mind of the 1950s. With the right mindset, James Mason's performance actually looks pretty good, and almost sophisticated next to Kirk Douglass' hyper-enthusiasm. They delivered the right performance for the youthful audience; Douglas was perfectly cast, and his singing was remarkably good. Paul Lukas delivers a performance of what a child might imagine a "professor" to be. The great Peter Lorre appears to be sleep walking. The best, or at least most entertaining, performance is delivered by Esmeralda, the seal, especially in the musical number with Douglas. What saves the film, at least for someone who has not previously seen it, is the story line. The question is whether it works for modern youth, particularly girls? There are some glowing reviews here, but how old are the reviewers? Frankly, I'm not impressed with Richard Fleischer's directing; a better director would have delivered a film that appeals to both children and their parents. While I am not a fan of heavy handed CGI, this is a movie that could benefit from a remake, as long as they don't try to modernize the story. But perhaps one day, when this movie is old enough, children will see in it what I saw in reading old books: a window into the past. Perhaps in 50 years, "20,000 Leagues Under the Sea" will be old enough to be interesting again. But for me, now it just looks tired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Fifties Sci-Fi Movie That Has Stood the Test of Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jules Verne's novel "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is set aboard an ocean-going submarine, something which did not exist when he wrote it in 1870, so it can be regarded as an early example of science fiction. (Verne had a record of making predictions which later came true; he also, for example, foresaw a journey from the Earth to the Moon). This film can be seen as an early example of the genre now called steampunk, that sub-genre of science-fiction which delights in 19th century technology, real or invented. The story tells of the adventures of Captain Nemo, the commander and designer of the submarine "Nautilus". Nemo's name, derived from the Latin for "no man", is an appropriate one, because he is a strange, mysterious figure. He is a brilliant inventor and engineer, but serves no government and no country, preferring to sail the seas with a crew who owe loyalty only to him. He is, at one and the same time, a humanitarian and a misanthropist, hating tyranny but regarding most men as unworthy of freedom. He claims to hate war, but his greatest passion is a desire for revenge on an unnamed "hated nation" whose government were responsible for the deaths of his wife and son and for his own imprisonment in a penal colony. The other main characters in the film are Professor Pierre Aronnax, a French scientist, his assistant Conseil and a sailor named Ned Land. These three are the only survivors of a shipwreck and have been reluctantly rescued by&nbsp;Nemo who sank their vessel after it fired on the "Nautilus", believing it to be a&nbsp;sea monster. Much of the dramatic tension in the film arises from the contrasting personalities of Nemo and his captives. Aronnax, a gentlemanly intellectual, initially believes Nemo to be mad, but later comes to sympathise, at least partially, with his world-view. The cocky and more plebeian Land distrusts both Aronnax and Nemo and spends most of his time formulating plans of escape. "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is therefore unusually character-driven for a science fiction film, so it is hardly surprising that four major stars, James Mason, Kirk Douglas, Paul Lukas&nbsp;and&nbsp;Peter Lorre were cast in the leading roles. (Interestingly, none of these men were of the same nationality as their characters. The Englishman Mason plays Nemo, whom Verne originally envisaged as Polish but later described as Indian. The American&nbsp;Douglas plays Land, who was originally Canadian. The Frenchmen Aronnax and Conseil are played by Lukas and Lorre, both Hungarian by birth). All four are good, but Mason is especially good as the tormented Nemo, a man who appears to be at war with the rest of humanity but who is really at war with himself, torn between his desire for revenge and his better nature which tells him that revenge is a futile pursuit. The film was directed by Richard Fleischer, a versatile director who seemed able to work in virtually any genre, including film noir ("The Armoured Car Robbery"), true crime ("Ten Rillington Place", "The Girl in the Red Velvet Swing"), the historical epic ("The Vikings"), and sword- and-sorcery fantasy ("Conan the Destroyer", "Red Sonja"). He also made a number of science-fiction films, including this one, "Fantastic Voyage" (which also involves a submarine) and "Soylent Green". Fifties sci-fi has&nbsp;a rather unenviable reputation; many films in the genre from this decade were made on a low budget, with clich&eacute;d scripts and low-quality special effects; some examples, such as the notorious "Plan 9 from Outer Space" are frequently to be found on lists of the "worst films ever made". There were, however, some very good science fiction&nbsp;films from the period,&nbsp;such as&nbsp;"Forbidden Planet", with a plot based on Shakespeare's "The Tempest", or the 1953 version of "The War of the Worlds", and "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is another in the same category. Not only does it have a humane and intelligent script and some first-rate acting performances, the special effects- so often sci-fi's Achilles heel- are actually rather good, especially during the scene where the&nbsp;"Nautilus"&nbsp; is attacked by&nbsp;a giant squid. The vessel itself looks realistic enough to be convincing, while different enough from a modern submarine to make us realised that we are watching a Victorian fantasy. This is one science fiction film that has stood the test of time. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You'll pray for a torpedo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If I were on this voyage I'd jump overboard. Harpooner Kirk Douglas, professor Paul Lukas and his apprentice Peter Lorre are taken on board the Nautilus, a submarine helmed by James Mason's Captain Nemo, after he destroys their ship. Then nothing of interest happens for an hour. Then we hit the island of cannibals and an attack by a giant squid... Nope, still not interesting. There's some fun to be had courtesy of Douglas's likable performance, but other than that there's little to recommend this flat adventure, which could do with being a good deal shorter and wastes Peter Lorre in a thankless role. In the plus column, it's better than 'Mysterious Island'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    best Disney movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bailey-86
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    my favorite Disney movie. Love it and i wish that Disney would make more Disney movies like 20,000 Leagues Under the Sea. Great movie what I love about the movie is that it's live action and animation that Walt Disney was the producer of the movie. I still watch the movie even though I am in my 20's. Great and Clean Disney movie. Love the cast including Peter Lorree, James Mason, Kirk Douglas, and Paul Lukas. Best Disney movie and appropriate for all ages and family. The movie is one of my favorite Disney movies ever made. I love it that Richard Fleschier who directed Dr. Doolittle did the perfect job directing the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic among classic adventure tales
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By 1954, Disney already had a name for itself with producing quality entertainment. So it shouldn't shock many (now) that Walt Disney decided to take on this project and adapt Jules Verne's story to the big screen. But here's the game changer, the cast has big name actors, the special effects are fantastic, the props are spectacular and the screenplay was well revised. The story takes place in the late 1800's where a Professor Aronnax (Paul Lukas) and his assistant Conseil (Peter Lorre) are put their knowledge and well being to the test when they are given the opportunity of a life time. Recently, there have been sightings of a "sea monster" attacking vessels out on the open sea. The offer, is to sail with the US navy to track down the monster and destroy it. At first the professor and his assistant were curious, but soon audiences will watch them grow and understand that the answers they were hoping for, were not even close to what they thought they could be. Aboard this ship is Ned Land (Kirk Douglas), a master harpooner who seems to have an attitude with authority but in the most lighthearted and high-spirited way. But another character that is one of the most intriguing and hard to figure out characters is Captain Nemo, brilliantly played by James Mason. The way Mason portrays his character makes it so hard to read. Mason acts with a controlled yet ferocious hatred, but it never seems like that. In fact, he may seem a little mad (crazy), but he will always use a sophisticated vocabulary. Also, for 1954 the special effects and props were so convincing. Wait until you see that giant squid! Absolutely phenomenal! And because the film is in wide screen, it looks even better. The sets either on the ships, in the water beside the choral reefs or on an island looks great. The music provided by Paul L. Smith was much welcomed too. Since Smith has worked with Disney before on various other projects like Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937), his score emits all the right feelings for each scene. The reason why I titled this as the classic among classic adventure tales because that's what it is. This is the purest of the pure in what this genre is. Setting out on a journey with no idea of what the end result may be is exactly what an adventure is. I mean, what else could you ask for? Sailing out to sea to find a monster sounds exciting and scary at the same time, plus you have cannons, island natives, underwater treasure and so on. There's just so many things to explore! Because of the top-notch acting, amazing set pieces, adventurous music and spectacular special effects, this is by far Disney's most famous live-action piece from the 1950s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Wonder of 1954
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Whitney
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this film is best appreciated when watched empowered with an education of film history, taking into consideration the technological challenges which were overcome to make it all happen successfully, appreciating the risks it entailed for the Disney Studios, and imagining how it felt for audiences who experienced it for the first time as what was truly an unprecedented under-water cinematic feat. It was the most expensive film ever made up to that time, and if you look closely you can tell that no expense was spared. Nevertheless, in our modern era of Hollywood indulgence and computer generated graphics, 20,000 Leagues under the Sea inevitably ends up feeling slightly dated & hokey at times. The movie boasts many timeless strengths though, among them being interesting characters, excellent performances, and some great intellectual dialogue/debate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Come aboard the Naultius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before there was Bio Shock. Before Steampunk became cool. There was this movie. The year is 1868, a number of sea monsters attacks in the Pacific, has cause fear among sailors. Professor Pierre M. Arrnoax (Paul Lakas) and his assistant, Conseil (Peter Lorre) were invited by the US government to find. They were attacked by the 'so called' monster, and found themselves shipwreck with Ned Land (Kirk Douglas) a sailor. Captured by the monster, they found out, it's not a monster at all, but a submarine the Naultius, captain by the mysterious Nemo. (James Mason) explorer of the ocean bottom, '20,000 Leagues Under the Sea'. What Pierre and the survivors doesn't know at first, is that Captain Nemo is border-lining between genius and madness. A man who is at war at the surface world, while being tired of war. Arrnoax knows of this, but due to his lust of knowledge, he continue to take the side of the captain, while Ned Land tries to escape. 20,000 Leagues Under the Sea is based on the science fiction novel by French writer Jules Verne with the same name. There are some big differences between the film, and the novel. The film tends to cut outs or combinded such in case-- the treasure scene and the shark. Much praise for keeping much of Captain Nemo's reasons to attack the surface world and keeping the violence and death in, for a PG movie. Without it, it wouldn't be much of a adventure. The film can be a bit outdated, thus some action scenes with the limited special effects might be a bit cheesy, but at the time, well made. It's far superior to the majority of genre efforts from the period (or any period, for that matter), with production design and technical effects that have dated hardly at all. The soundtrack is spellbinding, mysterious, and glam. The haunting classic organ music plays well into the film. |'A Whale of a Tale' by Al Hoffman and Norman Gimbel as sung by Kirk Douglas sound as real as a sailor's hymn. Kirk Douglas is the perfect fit for Ned Land. Land is everything that Nemo hates about the surface, self-centered, greedy, and ego driven. While all of the actors did great in their respectable roles, it was James Mason, that got singled out for his performance of Captain Nemo. Even the point, that Nemo's last words to Aronnax echo: is a strong message. There is hope for the future. And when the world is ready for a new and better life, all this will someday come to pass, in God's good time." It's a great adventure, so give it a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great adventure and some very strong characters.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    teryolaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great adventure. I was kinda taken aback by how cozy this movie is. I am really surprised that it was made in 1954 because the special effects are really well made for an old movie and the underwater footage is just fantastic. The movie looks great and plays great. There is something special with these older types of movies. There isn't really such a thing as mediocre acting and substance-less characters. The characters are all strong and stand out in their own special way. Whether they are taking the front or stand more in the background, like the little weasel that is the professors apprentice. I particularly like Captain Nemo's character. He is a misanthrope and the embodiment of a person who is so intelligent that there isn't much for him to do but to suffer in a cruel and inhumane world, where the rest of mankind aren't on his level. Throughout the movie we learn that while what he was saying is depressing, he was right. Ned is one proof of that. One day he saves Nemo's life. But on the day before, he made sure to act in such a way that in the end would lead to Nemo's death. As Nemo says, goodness needs to be consistent. It can't be done on impulse. The dialogue is well-written and provides insight in a natural way as to why Nemo is the way that he is. It opens up discussion rather then makes statements that can't be reflected upon. After Nemo's life is saved by Ted, I like how when the professor was trying to "talk sense" into Nemo and make him be a bit more cheerful about the world, Nemo could actually defend his point of view instead of it being just another clich&eacute; Hollywood moment where the "bad guy" is shown off as weak and fallible in his perspective of the world. And Nemo defending his view opens up a new perspective on things and makes everything about the movies morale more ambiguous, rather then it being a typical hopeful movie where everything works out great in the end. The movie is hopeful in it's own way, but it's in a way that shows you something bad and lets the audience want to make a change for the future. And in the end, he makes a point. The world isn't ready for destructive power of that kind. It is said that science fiction movies (as well as movies in general) are a reflection of the society in the era that they are being made in. And this movie was made in 54. The atom-bomb on Hirosima and Nagasaki was executed on 1945. I think that I can see a parallel there about mankind's destructive nature and immaturity. How the authorities take everything good and use it for destructive means. This is a movie about misanthropy and mankind's destructive nature. Precisely the kind of deeper themes that a science fiction is supposed to touch upon, and it does it well. Great movie. A new-found classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mighty adventure based on Jules Verne's novel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie tells about three men that have to travel against their own will in Captain Nemo's submarine called Nautilus.20000 Leagues Under the Sea (1954) is directed by Richard Fleischer.It's based on Jules Verne's novel from 1870, which I read last week.There are some differences between the book and the movie, like Esmeralda the seal, that wasn't in the book.This was the first science fiction movie produced by Walt Disney Productions.And it was also the only science fiction movie produced by Walt Disney himself.As it was the first feature length Disney movie to be distributed by Buena Vista Distribution.There is a terrific cast inside the submarine.Kirk Douglas is really something as the harpoonist Ned Land.An outstanding performance by James Mason in the role of Captain Nemo.Paul Lukas as Prof. Pierre Aronnax and Peter Lorre as his assistant Conseil are excellent.The movie has many incredible scenes, like the battle against the giant squids.The duet between Kirk Douglas and the seal is a riot.This is an adventure you don't want to miss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful fascinating futuristic adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spamobile
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wonderful adventure taking you away on the high seas to meet a mad man and his mad machine. Jules Verne is a masterful story writer. He "invented" a lot of fantastic machines and wrote his stories based on them. Although nothing was technically possible the way he invented the machines the ideas were totally back to the future, things man would take an other century to actually build. The movie is raw adventure, sailing ships, sea monsters, hero's, comedy at times, fascinating story telling. It's made when CGI was still just a bunch of letters hustled together. Special effect was still simple and so fake. But, that does not matter, the story is very entertaining. A man's man, the one and only Kirk Douglas, is one of the leading characters. You can hardly go wrong then. Keep an open mind when watching, it's an old movie, it's not perfect, it's not Oscar winning material, but it's highly entertaining fantasy world. Watch it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The singing seal delivers the most entertaining performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Buena Vista wisely opens the movie by showing the cover of 19th century edition of Jules Verne's work, and then opening to the first page. This solves the problem of explaining to the audience that this is a story set long ago about a once-futuristic submarine. The problem for contemporary audiences is that the movie is six decades old, so it is an old movie about an old story about what was once a vision of the future that is now a bit frayed. I am sympathetic to the concept, given that as a child I loved to read old books like this, as a sort of time travel into the past. And I saw this movie in a theater as a boy, though not in its first run, perhaps around the age of 8. I enjoyed it because it is a fantasy trip into imagining being aboard an ancient submarine traveling the distant oceans and down into the deep. How can a young boy resist? Children can enter into the fantasy of a movie like this. But as an adult, it didn't work, partly because I had seen it, but mainly because I'm an adult, and it takes more than a movie with mediocre acting to engross me in the experience. It took me several tries to make it through the movie this time, because every time I put it on, I looked at the acting and said, Eewwww! Many movies in the 1950s had really shallow acting, perhaps because studios found that a segment of the public actually preferred it. Here I assume, given that it is Disney, the acting is geared to children, so it is shallower still. It is a formula that worked at the time. Disney seems to have discovered this formula of simplistic, over-baked acting, and we still see it in some modern children's movies. I know it worked because I remember how I responded to movies like this as a kid. Kids generally are not looking for Laurence Olivier level acting, and are not analyzing technique. I finally made it through the movie, mainly by trying to view it through the uncritical mind of the 1950s. With the right mindset, James Mason's performance actually looks pretty good, and almost sophisticated next to Kirk Douglass' hyper-enthusiasm. They delivered the right performance for the youthful audience; Douglas was perfectly cast, and his singing was remarkably good. Paul Lukas delivers a performance of what a child might imagine a "professor" to be. The great Peter Lorre appears to be sleep walking. The best, or at least most entertaining, performance is delivered by Esmeralda, the seal, especially in the musical number with Douglas. What saves the film, at least for someone who has not previously seen it, is the story line. The question is whether it works for modern youth, particularly girls? There are some glowing reviews here, but how old are the reviewers? Frankly, I'm not impressed with Richard Fleischer's directing; a better director would have delivered a film that appeals to both children and their parents. While I am not a fan of heavy handed CGI, this is a movie that could benefit from a remake, as long as they don't try to modernize the story. But perhaps one day, when this movie is old enough, children will see in it what I saw in reading old books: a window into the past. Perhaps in 50 years, "20,000 Leagues Under the Sea" will be old enough to be interesting again. But for me, now it just looks tired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Fifties Sci-Fi Movie That Has Stood the Test of Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jules Verne's novel "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is set aboard an ocean-going submarine, something which did not exist when he wrote it in 1870, so it can be regarded as an early example of science fiction. (Verne had a record of making predictions which later came true; he also, for example, foresaw a journey from the Earth to the Moon). This film can be seen as an early example of the genre now called steampunk, that sub-genre of science-fiction which delights in 19th century technology, real or invented. The story tells of the adventures of Captain Nemo, the commander and designer of the submarine "Nautilus". Nemo's name, derived from the Latin for "no man", is an appropriate one, because he is a strange, mysterious figure. He is a brilliant inventor and engineer, but serves no government and no country, preferring to sail the seas with a crew who owe loyalty only to him. He is, at one and the same time, a humanitarian and a misanthropist, hating tyranny but regarding most men as unworthy of freedom. He claims to hate war, but his greatest passion is a desire for revenge on an unnamed "hated nation" whose government were responsible for the deaths of his wife and son and for his own imprisonment in a penal colony. The other main characters in the film are Professor Pierre Aronnax, a French scientist, his assistant Conseil and a sailor named Ned Land. These three are the only survivors of a shipwreck and have been reluctantly rescued by&nbsp;Nemo who sank their vessel after it fired on the "Nautilus", believing it to be a&nbsp;sea monster. Much of the dramatic tension in the film arises from the contrasting personalities of Nemo and his captives. Aronnax, a gentlemanly intellectual, initially believes Nemo to be mad, but later comes to sympathise, at least partially, with his world-view. The cocky and more plebeian Land distrusts both Aronnax and Nemo and spends most of his time formulating plans of escape. "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is therefore unusually character-driven for a science fiction film, so it is hardly surprising that four major stars, James Mason, Kirk Douglas, Paul Lukas&nbsp;and&nbsp;Peter Lorre were cast in the leading roles. (Interestingly, none of these men were of the same nationality as their characters. The Englishman Mason plays Nemo, whom Verne originally envisaged as Polish but later described as Indian. The American&nbsp;Douglas plays Land, who was originally Canadian. The Frenchmen Aronnax and Conseil are played by Lukas and Lorre, both Hungarian by birth). All four are good, but Mason is especially good as the tormented Nemo, a man who appears to be at war with the rest of humanity but who is really at war with himself, torn between his desire for revenge and his better nature which tells him that revenge is a futile pursuit. The film was directed by Richard Fleischer, a versatile director who seemed able to work in virtually any genre, including film noir ("The Armoured Car Robbery"), true crime ("Ten Rillington Place", "The Girl in the Red Velvet Swing"), the historical epic ("The Vikings"), and sword- and-sorcery fantasy ("Conan the Destroyer", "Red Sonja"). He also made a number of science-fiction films, including this one, "Fantastic Voyage" (which also involves a submarine) and "Soylent Green". Fifties sci-fi has&nbsp;a rather unenviable reputation; many films in the genre from this decade were made on a low budget, with clich&eacute;d scripts and low-quality special effects; some examples, such as the notorious "Plan 9 from Outer Space" are frequently to be found on lists of the "worst films ever made". There were, however, some very good science fiction&nbsp;films from the period,&nbsp;such as&nbsp;"Forbidden Planet", with a plot based on Shakespeare's "The Tempest", or the 1953 version of "The War of the Worlds", and "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is another in the same category. Not only does it have a humane and intelligent script and some first-rate acting performances, the special effects- so often sci-fi's Achilles heel- are actually rather good, especially during the scene where the&nbsp;"Nautilus"&nbsp; is attacked by&nbsp;a giant squid. The vessel itself looks realistic enough to be convincing, while different enough from a modern submarine to make us realised that we are watching a Victorian fantasy. This is one science fiction film that has stood the test of time. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You'll pray for a torpedo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If I were on this voyage I'd jump overboard. Harpooner Kirk Douglas, professor Paul Lukas and his apprentice Peter Lorre are taken on board the Nautilus, a submarine helmed by James Mason's Captain Nemo, after he destroys their ship. Then nothing of interest happens for an hour. Then we hit the island of cannibals and an attack by a giant squid... Nope, still not interesting. There's some fun to be had courtesy of Douglas's likable performance, but other than that there's little to recommend this flat adventure, which could do with being a good deal shorter and wastes Peter Lorre in a thankless role. In the plus column, it's better than 'Mysterious Island'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    best Disney movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bailey-86
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    my favorite Disney movie. Love it and i wish that Disney would make more Disney movies like 20,000 Leagues Under the Sea. Great movie what I love about the movie is that it's live action and animation that Walt Disney was the producer of the movie. I still watch the movie even though I am in my 20's. Great and Clean Disney movie. Love the cast including Peter Lorree, James Mason, Kirk Douglas, and Paul Lukas. Best Disney movie and appropriate for all ages and family. The movie is one of my favorite Disney movies ever made. I love it that Richard Fleschier who directed Dr. Doolittle did the perfect job directing the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic among classic adventure tales
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By 1954, Disney already had a name for itself with producing quality entertainment. So it shouldn't shock many (now) that Walt Disney decided to take on this project and adapt Jules Verne's story to the big screen. But here's the game changer, the cast has big name actors, the special effects are fantastic, the props are spectacular and the screenplay was well revised. The story takes place in the late 1800's where a Professor Aronnax (Paul Lukas) and his assistant Conseil (Peter Lorre) are put their knowledge and well being to the test when they are given the opportunity of a life time. Recently, there have been sightings of a "sea monster" attacking vessels out on the open sea. The offer, is to sail with the US navy to track down the monster and destroy it. At first the professor and his assistant were curious, but soon audiences will watch them grow and understand that the answers they were hoping for, were not even close to what they thought they could be. Aboard this ship is Ned Land (Kirk Douglas), a master harpooner who seems to have an attitude with authority but in the most lighthearted and high-spirited way. But another character that is one of the most intriguing and hard to figure out characters is Captain Nemo, brilliantly played by James Mason. The way Mason portrays his character makes it so hard to read. Mason acts with a controlled yet ferocious hatred, but it never seems like that. In fact, he may seem a little mad (crazy), but he will always use a sophisticated vocabulary. Also, for 1954 the special effects and props were so convincing. Wait until you see that giant squid! Absolutely phenomenal! And because the film is in wide screen, it looks even better. The sets either on the ships, in the water beside the choral reefs or on an island looks great. The music provided by Paul L. Smith was much welcomed too. Since Smith has worked with Disney before on various other projects like Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937), his score emits all the right feelings for each scene. The reason why I titled this as the classic among classic adventure tales because that's what it is. This is the purest of the pure in what this genre is. Setting out on a journey with no idea of what the end result may be is exactly what an adventure is. I mean, what else could you ask for? Sailing out to sea to find a monster sounds exciting and scary at the same time, plus you have cannons, island natives, underwater treasure and so on. There's just so many things to explore! Because of the top-notch acting, amazing set pieces, adventurous music and spectacular special effects, this is by far Disney's most famous live-action piece from the 1950s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Wonder of 1954
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Whitney
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this film is best appreciated when watched empowered with an education of film history, taking into consideration the technological challenges which were overcome to make it all happen successfully, appreciating the risks it entailed for the Disney Studios, and imagining how it felt for audiences who experienced it for the first time as what was truly an unprecedented under-water cinematic feat. It was the most expensive film ever made up to that time, and if you look closely you can tell that no expense was spared. Nevertheless, in our modern era of Hollywood indulgence and computer generated graphics, 20,000 Leagues under the Sea inevitably ends up feeling slightly dated & hokey at times. The movie boasts many timeless strengths though, among them being interesting characters, excellent performances, and some great intellectual dialogue/debate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Come aboard the Naultius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before there was Bio Shock. Before Steampunk became cool. There was this movie. The year is 1868, a number of sea monsters attacks in the Pacific, has cause fear among sailors. Professor Pierre M. Arrnoax (Paul Lakas) and his assistant, Conseil (Peter Lorre) were invited by the US government to find. They were attacked by the 'so called' monster, and found themselves shipwreck with Ned Land (Kirk Douglas) a sailor. Captured by the monster, they found out, it's not a monster at all, but a submarine the Naultius, captain by the mysterious Nemo. (James Mason) explorer of the ocean bottom, '20,000 Leagues Under the Sea'. What Pierre and the survivors doesn't know at first, is that Captain Nemo is border-lining between genius and madness. A man who is at war at the surface world, while being tired of war. Arrnoax knows of this, but due to his lust of knowledge, he continue to take the side of the captain, while Ned Land tries to escape. 20,000 Leagues Under the Sea is based on the science fiction novel by French writer Jules Verne with the same name. There are some big differences between the film, and the novel. The film tends to cut outs or combinded such in case-- the treasure scene and the shark. Much praise for keeping much of Captain Nemo's reasons to attack the surface world and keeping the violence and death in, for a PG movie. Without it, it wouldn't be much of a adventure. The film can be a bit outdated, thus some action scenes with the limited special effects might be a bit cheesy, but at the time, well made. It's far superior to the majority of genre efforts from the period (or any period, for that matter), with production design and technical effects that have dated hardly at all. The soundtrack is spellbinding, mysterious, and glam. The haunting classic organ music plays well into the film. |'A Whale of a Tale' by Al Hoffman and Norman Gimbel as sung by Kirk Douglas sound as real as a sailor's hymn. Kirk Douglas is the perfect fit for Ned Land. Land is everything that Nemo hates about the surface, self-centered, greedy, and ego driven. While all of the actors did great in their respectable roles, it was James Mason, that got singled out for his performance of Captain Nemo. Even the point, that Nemo's last words to Aronnax echo: is a strong message. There is hope for the future. And when the world is ready for a new and better life, all this will someday come to pass, in God's good time." It's a great adventure, so give it a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great adventure and some very strong characters.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    teryolaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great adventure. I was kinda taken aback by how cozy this movie is. I am really surprised that it was made in 1954 because the special effects are really well made for an old movie and the underwater footage is just fantastic. The movie looks great and plays great. There is something special with these older types of movies. There isn't really such a thing as mediocre acting and substance-less characters. The characters are all strong and stand out in their own special way. Whether they are taking the front or stand more in the background, like the little weasel that is the professors apprentice. I particularly like Captain Nemo's character. He is a misanthrope and the embodiment of a person who is so intelligent that there isn't much for him to do but to suffer in a cruel and inhumane world, where the rest of mankind aren't on his level. Throughout the movie we learn that while what he was saying is depressing, he was right. Ned is one proof of that. One day he saves Nemo's life. But on the day before, he made sure to act in such a way that in the end would lead to Nemo's death. As Nemo says, goodness needs to be consistent. It can't be done on impulse. The dialogue is well-written and provides insight in a natural way as to why Nemo is the way that he is. It opens up discussion rather then makes statements that can't be reflected upon. After Nemo's life is saved by Ted, I like how when the professor was trying to "talk sense" into Nemo and make him be a bit more cheerful about the world, Nemo could actually defend his point of view instead of it being just another clich&eacute; Hollywood moment where the "bad guy" is shown off as weak and fallible in his perspective of the world. And Nemo defending his view opens up a new perspective on things and makes everything about the movies morale more ambiguous, rather then it being a typical hopeful movie where everything works out great in the end. The movie is hopeful in it's own way, but it's in a way that shows you something bad and lets the audience want to make a change for the future. And in the end, he makes a point. The world isn't ready for destructive power of that kind. It is said that science fiction movies (as well as movies in general) are a reflection of the society in the era that they are being made in. And this movie was made in 54. The atom-bomb on Hirosima and Nagasaki was executed on 1945. I think that I can see a parallel there about mankind's destructive nature and immaturity. How the authorities take everything good and use it for destructive means. This is a movie about misanthropy and mankind's destructive nature. Precisely the kind of deeper themes that a science fiction is supposed to touch upon, and it does it well. Great movie. A new-found classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mighty adventure based on Jules Verne's novel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie tells about three men that have to travel against their own will in Captain Nemo's submarine called Nautilus.20000 Leagues Under the Sea (1954) is directed by Richard Fleischer.It's based on Jules Verne's novel from 1870, which I read last week.There are some differences between the book and the movie, like Esmeralda the seal, that wasn't in the book.This was the first science fiction movie produced by Walt Disney Productions.And it was also the only science fiction movie produced by Walt Disney himself.As it was the first feature length Disney movie to be distributed by Buena Vista Distribution.There is a terrific cast inside the submarine.Kirk Douglas is really something as the harpoonist Ned Land.An outstanding performance by James Mason in the role of Captain Nemo.Paul Lukas as Prof. Pierre Aronnax and Peter Lorre as his assistant Conseil are excellent.The movie has many incredible scenes, like the battle against the giant squids.The duet between Kirk Douglas and the seal is a riot.This is an adventure you don't want to miss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful fascinating futuristic adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spamobile
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wonderful adventure taking you away on the high seas to meet a mad man and his mad machine. Jules Verne is a masterful story writer. He "invented" a lot of fantastic machines and wrote his stories based on them. Although nothing was technically possible the way he invented the machines the ideas were totally back to the future, things man would take an other century to actually build. The movie is raw adventure, sailing ships, sea monsters, hero's, comedy at times, fascinating story telling. It's made when CGI was still just a bunch of letters hustled together. Special effect was still simple and so fake. But, that does not matter, the story is very entertaining. A man's man, the one and only Kirk Douglas, is one of the leading characters. You can hardly go wrong then. Keep an open mind when watching, it's an old movie, it's not perfect, it's not Oscar winning material, but it's highly entertaining fantasy world. Watch it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The singing seal delivers the most entertaining performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Buena Vista wisely opens the movie by showing the cover of 19th century edition of Jules Verne's work, and then opening to the first page. This solves the problem of explaining to the audience that this is a story set long ago about a once-futuristic submarine. The problem for contemporary audiences is that the movie is six decades old, so it is an old movie about an old story about what was once a vision of the future that is now a bit frayed. I am sympathetic to the concept, given that as a child I loved to read old books like this, as a sort of time travel into the past. And I saw this movie in a theater as a boy, though not in its first run, perhaps around the age of 8. I enjoyed it because it is a fantasy trip into imagining being aboard an ancient submarine traveling the distant oceans and down into the deep. How can a young boy resist? Children can enter into the fantasy of a movie like this. But as an adult, it didn't work, partly because I had seen it, but mainly because I'm an adult, and it takes more than a movie with mediocre acting to engross me in the experience. It took me several tries to make it through the movie this time, because every time I put it on, I looked at the acting and said, Eewwww! Many movies in the 1950s had really shallow acting, perhaps because studios found that a segment of the public actually preferred it. Here I assume, given that it is Disney, the acting is geared to children, so it is shallower still. It is a formula that worked at the time. Disney seems to have discovered this formula of simplistic, over-baked acting, and we still see it in some modern children's movies. I know it worked because I remember how I responded to movies like this as a kid. Kids generally are not looking for Laurence Olivier level acting, and are not analyzing technique. I finally made it through the movie, mainly by trying to view it through the uncritical mind of the 1950s. With the right mindset, James Mason's performance actually looks pretty good, and almost sophisticated next to Kirk Douglass' hyper-enthusiasm. They delivered the right performance for the youthful audience; Douglas was perfectly cast, and his singing was remarkably good. Paul Lukas delivers a performance of what a child might imagine a "professor" to be. The great Peter Lorre appears to be sleep walking. The best, or at least most entertaining, performance is delivered by Esmeralda, the seal, especially in the musical number with Douglas. What saves the film, at least for someone who has not previously seen it, is the story line. The question is whether it works for modern youth, particularly girls? There are some glowing reviews here, but how old are the reviewers? Frankly, I'm not impressed with Richard Fleischer's directing; a better director would have delivered a film that appeals to both children and their parents. While I am not a fan of heavy handed CGI, this is a movie that could benefit from a remake, as long as they don't try to modernize the story. But perhaps one day, when this movie is old enough, children will see in it what I saw in reading old books: a window into the past. Perhaps in 50 years, "20,000 Leagues Under the Sea" will be old enough to be interesting again. But for me, now it just looks tired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Fifties Sci-Fi Movie That Has Stood the Test of Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jules Verne's novel "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is set aboard an ocean-going submarine, something which did not exist when he wrote it in 1870, so it can be regarded as an early example of science fiction. (Verne had a record of making predictions which later came true; he also, for example, foresaw a journey from the Earth to the Moon). This film can be seen as an early example of the genre now called steampunk, that sub-genre of science-fiction which delights in 19th century technology, real or invented. The story tells of the adventures of Captain Nemo, the commander and designer of the submarine "Nautilus". Nemo's name, derived from the Latin for "no man", is an appropriate one, because he is a strange, mysterious figure. He is a brilliant inventor and engineer, but serves no government and no country, preferring to sail the seas with a crew who owe loyalty only to him. He is, at one and the same time, a humanitarian and a misanthropist, hating tyranny but regarding most men as unworthy of freedom. He claims to hate war, but his greatest passion is a desire for revenge on an unnamed "hated nation" whose government were responsible for the deaths of his wife and son and for his own imprisonment in a penal colony. The other main characters in the film are Professor Pierre Aronnax, a French scientist, his assistant Conseil and a sailor named Ned Land. These three are the only survivors of a shipwreck and have been reluctantly rescued by&nbsp;Nemo who sank their vessel after it fired on the "Nautilus", believing it to be a&nbsp;sea monster. Much of the dramatic tension in the film arises from the contrasting personalities of Nemo and his captives. Aronnax, a gentlemanly intellectual, initially believes Nemo to be mad, but later comes to sympathise, at least partially, with his world-view. The cocky and more plebeian Land distrusts both Aronnax and Nemo and spends most of his time formulating plans of escape. "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is therefore unusually character-driven for a science fiction film, so it is hardly surprising that four major stars, James Mason, Kirk Douglas, Paul Lukas&nbsp;and&nbsp;Peter Lorre were cast in the leading roles. (Interestingly, none of these men were of the same nationality as their characters. The Englishman Mason plays Nemo, whom Verne originally envisaged as Polish but later described as Indian. The American&nbsp;Douglas plays Land, who was originally Canadian. The Frenchmen Aronnax and Conseil are played by Lukas and Lorre, both Hungarian by birth). All four are good, but Mason is especially good as the tormented Nemo, a man who appears to be at war with the rest of humanity but who is really at war with himself, torn between his desire for revenge and his better nature which tells him that revenge is a futile pursuit. The film was directed by Richard Fleischer, a versatile director who seemed able to work in virtually any genre, including film noir ("The Armoured Car Robbery"), true crime ("Ten Rillington Place", "The Girl in the Red Velvet Swing"), the historical epic ("The Vikings"), and sword- and-sorcery fantasy ("Conan the Destroyer", "Red Sonja"). He also made a number of science-fiction films, including this one, "Fantastic Voyage" (which also involves a submarine) and "Soylent Green". Fifties sci-fi has&nbsp;a rather unenviable reputation; many films in the genre from this decade were made on a low budget, with clich&eacute;d scripts and low-quality special effects; some examples, such as the notorious "Plan 9 from Outer Space" are frequently to be found on lists of the "worst films ever made". There were, however, some very good science fiction&nbsp;films from the period,&nbsp;such as&nbsp;"Forbidden Planet", with a plot based on Shakespeare's "The Tempest", or the 1953 version of "The War of the Worlds", and "20,000 Leagues under the Sea" is another in the same category. Not only does it have a humane and intelligent script and some first-rate acting performances, the special effects- so often sci-fi's Achilles heel- are actually rather good, especially during the scene where the&nbsp;"Nautilus"&nbsp; is attacked by&nbsp;a giant squid. The vessel itself looks realistic enough to be convincing, while different enough from a modern submarine to make us realised that we are watching a Victorian fantasy. This is one science fiction film that has stood the test of time. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You'll pray for a torpedo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If I were on this voyage I'd jump overboard. Harpooner Kirk Douglas, professor Paul Lukas and his apprentice Peter Lorre are taken on board the Nautilus, a submarine helmed by James Mason's Captain Nemo, after he destroys their ship. Then nothing of interest happens for an hour. Then we hit the island of cannibals and an attack by a giant squid... Nope, still not interesting. There's some fun to be had courtesy of Douglas's likable performance, but other than that there's little to recommend this flat adventure, which could do with being a good deal shorter and wastes Peter Lorre in a thankless role. In the plus column, it's better than 'Mysterious Island'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    best Disney movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bailey-86
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    my favorite Disney movie. Love it and i wish that Disney would make more Disney movies like 20,000 Leagues Under the Sea. Great movie what I love about the movie is that it's live action and animation that Walt Disney was the producer of the movie. I still watch the movie even though I am in my 20's. Great and Clean Disney movie. Love the cast including Peter Lorree, James Mason, Kirk Douglas, and Paul Lukas. Best Disney movie and appropriate for all ages and family. The movie is one of my favorite Disney movies ever made. I love it that Richard Fleschier who directed Dr. Doolittle did the perfect job directing the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic among classic adventure tales
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By 1954, Disney already had a name for itself with producing quality entertainment. So it shouldn't shock many (now) that Walt Disney decided to take on this project and adapt Jules Verne's story to the big screen. But here's the game changer, the cast has big name actors, the special effects are fantastic, the props are spectacular and the screenplay was well revised. The story takes place in the late 1800's where a Professor Aronnax (Paul Lukas) and his assistant Conseil (Peter Lorre) are put their knowledge and well being to the test when they are given the opportunity of a life time. Recently, there have been sightings of a "sea monster" attacking vessels out on the open sea. The offer, is to sail with the US navy to track down the monster and destroy it. At first the professor and his assistant were curious, but soon audiences will watch them grow and understand that the answers they were hoping for, were not even close to what they thought they could be. Aboard this ship is Ned Land (Kirk Douglas), a master harpooner who seems to have an attitude with authority but in the most lighthearted and high-spirited way. But another character that is one of the most intriguing and hard to figure out characters is Captain Nemo, brilliantly played by James Mason. The way Mason portrays his character makes it so hard to read. Mason acts with a controlled yet ferocious hatred, but it never seems like that. In fact, he may seem a little mad (crazy), but he will always use a sophisticated vocabulary. Also, for 1954 the special effects and props were so convincing. Wait until you see that giant squid! Absolutely phenomenal! And because the film is in wide screen, it looks even better. The sets either on the ships, in the water beside the choral reefs or on an island looks great. The music provided by Paul L. Smith was much welcomed too. Since Smith has worked with Disney before on various other projects like Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937), his score emits all the right feelings for each scene. The reason why I titled this as the classic among classic adventure tales because that's what it is. This is the purest of the pure in what this genre is. Setting out on a journey with no idea of what the end result may be is exactly what an adventure is. I mean, what else could you ask for? Sailing out to sea to find a monster sounds exciting and scary at the same time, plus you have cannons, island natives, underwater treasure and so on. There's just so many things to explore! Because of the top-notch acting, amazing set pieces, adventurous music and spectacular special effects, this is by far Disney's most famous live-action piece from the 1950s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Wonder of 1954
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Whitney
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this film is best appreciated when watched empowered with an education of film history, taking into consideration the technological challenges which were overcome to make it all happen successfully, appreciating the risks it entailed for the Disney Studios, and imagining how it felt for audiences who experienced it for the first time as what was truly an unprecedented under-water cinematic feat. It was the most expensive film ever made up to that time, and if you look closely you can tell that no expense was spared. Nevertheless, in our modern era of Hollywood indulgence and computer generated graphics, 20,000 Leagues under the Sea inevitably ends up feeling slightly dated & hokey at times. The movie boasts many timeless strengths though, among them being interesting characters, excellent performances, and some great intellectual dialogue/debate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Come aboard the Naultius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before there was Bio Shock. Before Steampunk became cool. There was this movie. The year is 1868, a number of sea monsters attacks in the Pacific, has cause fear among sailors. Professor Pierre M. Arrnoax (Paul Lakas) and his assistant, Conseil (Peter Lorre) were invited by the US government to find. They were attacked by the 'so called' monster, and found themselves shipwreck with Ned Land (Kirk Douglas) a sailor. Captured by the monster, they found out, it's not a monster at all, but a submarine the Naultius, captain by the mysterious Nemo. (James Mason) explorer of the ocean bottom, '20,000 Leagues Under the Sea'. What Pierre and the survivors doesn't know at first, is that Captain Nemo is border-lining between genius and madness. A man who is at war at the surface world, while being tired of war. Arrnoax knows of this, but due to his lust of knowledge, he continue to take the side of the captain, while Ned Land tries to escape. 20,000 Leagues Under the Sea is based on the science fiction novel by French writer Jules Verne with the same name. There are some big differences between the film, and the novel. The film tends to cut outs or combinded such in case-- the treasure scene and the shark. Much praise for keeping much of Captain Nemo's reasons to attack the surface world and keeping the violence and death in, for a PG movie. Without it, it wouldn't be much of a adventure. The film can be a bit outdated, thus some action scenes with the limited special effects might be a bit cheesy, but at the time, well made. It's far superior to the majority of genre efforts from the period (or any period, for that matter), with production design and technical effects that have dated hardly at all. The soundtrack is spellbinding, mysterious, and glam. The haunting classic organ music plays well into the film. |'A Whale of a Tale' by Al Hoffman and Norman Gimbel as sung by Kirk Douglas sound as real as a sailor's hymn. Kirk Douglas is the perfect fit for Ned Land. Land is everything that Nemo hates about the surface, self-centered, greedy, and ego driven. While all of the actors did great in their respectable roles, it was James Mason, that got singled out for his performance of Captain Nemo. Even the point, that Nemo's last words to Aronnax echo: is a strong message. There is hope for the future. And when the world is ready for a new and better life, all this will someday come to pass, in God's good time." It's a great adventure, so give it a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great adventure and some very strong characters.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    teryolaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great adventure. I was kinda taken aback by how cozy this movie is. I am really surprised that it was made in 1954 because the special effects are really well made for an old movie and the underwater footage is just fantastic. The movie looks great and plays great. There is something special with these older types of movies. There isn't really such a thing as mediocre acting and substance-less characters. The characters are all strong and stand out in their own special way. Whether they are taking the front or stand more in the background, like the little weasel that is the professors apprentice. I particularly like Captain Nemo's character. He is a misanthrope and the embodiment of a person who is so intelligent that there isn't much for him to do but to suffer in a cruel and inhumane world, where the rest of mankind aren't on his level. Throughout the movie we learn that while what he was saying is depressing, he was right. Ned is one proof of that. One day he saves Nemo's life. But on the day before, he made sure to act in such a way that in the end would lead to Nemo's death. As Nemo says, goodness needs to be consistent. It can't be done on impulse. The dialogue is well-written and provides insight in a natural way as to why Nemo is the way that he is. It opens up discussion rather then makes statements that can't be reflected upon. After Nemo's life is saved by Ted, I like how when the professor was trying to "talk sense" into Nemo and make him be a bit more cheerful about the world, Nemo could actually defend his point of view instead of it being just another clich&eacute; Hollywood moment where the "bad guy" is shown off as weak and fallible in his perspective of the world. And Nemo defending his view opens up a new perspective on things and makes everything about the movies morale more ambiguous, rather then it being a typical hopeful movie where everything works out great in the end. The movie is hopeful in it's own way, but it's in a way that shows you something bad and lets the audience want to make a change for the future. And in the end, he makes a point. The world isn't ready for destructive power of that kind. It is said that science fiction movies (as well as movies in general) are a reflection of the society in the era that they are being made in. And this movie was made in 54. The atom-bomb on Hirosima and Nagasaki was executed on 1945. I think that I can see a parallel there about mankind's destructive nature and immaturity. How the authorities take everything good and use it for destructive means. This is a movie about misanthropy and mankind's destructive nature. Precisely the kind of deeper themes that a science fiction is supposed to touch upon, and it does it well. Great movie. A new-found classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mighty adventure based on Jules Verne's novel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie tells about three men that have to travel against their own will in Captain Nemo's submarine called Nautilus.20000 Leagues Under the Sea (1954) is directed by Richard Fleischer.It's based on Jules Verne's novel from 1870, which I read last week.There are some differences between the book and the movie, like Esmeralda the seal, that wasn't in the book.This was the first science fiction movie produced by Walt Disney Productions.And it was also the only science fiction movie produced by Walt Disney himself.As it was the first feature length Disney movie to be distributed by Buena Vista Distribution.There is a terrific cast inside the submarine.Kirk Douglas is really something as the harpoonist Ned Land.An outstanding performance by James Mason in the role of Captain Nemo.Paul Lukas as Prof. Pierre Aronnax and Peter Lorre as his assistant Conseil are excellent.The movie has many incredible scenes, like the battle against the giant squids.The duet between Kirk Douglas and the seal is a riot.This is an adventure you don't want to miss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful fascinating futuristic adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spamobile
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wonderful adventure taking you away on the high seas to meet a mad man and his mad machine. Jules Verne is a masterful story writer. He "invented" a lot of fantastic machines and wrote his stories based on them. Although nothing was technically possible the way he invented the machines the ideas were totally back to the future, things man would take an other century to actually build. The movie is raw adventure, sailing ships, sea monsters, hero's, comedy at times, fascinating story telling. It's made when CGI was still just a bunch of letters hustled together. Special effect was still simple and so fake. But, that does not matter, the story is very entertaining. A man's man, the one and only Kirk Douglas, is one of the leading characters. You can hardly go wrong then. Keep an open mind when watching, it's an old movie, it's not perfect, it's not Oscar winning material, but it's highly entertaining fantasy world. Watch it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The singing seal delivers the most entertaining performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Buena Vista wisely opens the movie by showing the cover of 19th century edition of Jules Verne's work, and then opening to the first page. This solves the problem of explaining to the audience that this is a story set long ago about a once-futuristic submarine. The problem for contemporary audiences is that the movie is six decades old, so it is an old movie about an old story about what was once a vision of the future that is now a bit frayed. I am sympathetic to the concept, given that as a child I loved to read old books like this, as a sort of time travel into the past. And I saw this movie in a theater as a boy, though not in its first run, perhaps around the age of 8. I enjoyed it because it is a fantasy trip into imagining being aboard an ancient submarine traveling the distant oceans and down into the deep. How can a young boy resist? Children can enter into the fantasy of a movie like this. But as an adult, it didn't work, partly because I had seen it, but mainly because I'm an adult, and it takes more than a movie with mediocre acting to engross me in the experience. It took me several tries to make it through the movie this time, because every time I put it on, I looked at the acting and said, Eewwww! Many movies in the 1950s had really shallow acting, perhaps because studios found that a segment of the public actually preferred it. Here I assume, given that it is Disney, the acting is geared to children, so it is shallower still. It is a formula that worked at the time. Disney seems to have discovered this formula of simplistic, over-baked acting, and we still see it in some modern children's movies. I know it worked because I remember how I responded to movies like this as a kid. Kids generally are not looking for Laurence Olivier level acting, and are not analyzing technique. I finally made it through the movie, mainly by trying to view it through the uncritical mind of the 1950s. With the right mindset, James Mason's performance actually looks pretty good, and almost sophisticated next to Kirk Douglass' hyper-enthusiasm. They delivered the right performance for the youthful audience; Douglas was perfectly cast, and his singing was remarkably good. Paul Lukas delivers a performance of what a child might imagine a "professor" to be. The great Peter Lorre appears to be sleep walking. The best, or at least most entertaining, performance is delivered by Esmeralda, the seal, especially in the musical number with Douglas. What saves the film, at least for someone who has not previously seen it, is the story line. The question is whether it works for modern youth, particularly girls? There are some glowing reviews here, but how old are the reviewers? Frankly, I'm not impressed with Richard Fleischer's directing; a better director would have delivered a film that appeals to both children and their parents. While I am not a fan of heavy handed CGI, this is a movie that could benefit from a remake, as long as they don't try to modernize the story. But perhaps one day, when this movie is old enough, children will see in it what I saw in reading old books: a window into the past. Perhaps in 50 years, "20,000 Leagues Under the Sea" will be old enough to be interesting again. But for me, now it just looks tired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
